<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 01:38:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Density functional theory investigation of telluride materials for HER/ORR/OER multifunctional electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150812</link>
      <description>F. Jia, Zhengrui Li, Xinran Li, Yikang Gu, Ping Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 166(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413114483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>F. Jia, Zhengrui Li, Xinran Li, Yikang Gu, Ping Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directly synthesized cobalt oxyhydroxide as an oxygen evolution catalyst in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62744-4</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Zheyu Zhang, Chiara Spezzati, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Nina S. Genz, Ni&#233;li Daff&#233;, Radim Skoup&#253;, Lorenz Gubler, Ivano E. Castelli, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413116188

                Abstract The limited choice of oxygen evolution reaction catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers hinders their large-scale commercialization. Cobalt-based catalysts are promising candidates and usually undergo surface reconstruction into CoOOH-like structures. However, the directly synthesized CoOOH has not yet been investigated in acidic environments. Here, we show that the CoOOH is active across the whole pH range, while its redox features are pH dependent. Operando hard X-ray absorption spectroscopy characterizations show a pH-induced change in Co oxidation onset, but no change in the coverage of redox-active Co species before the oxygen evolution reaction. The pH-dependent catalytic performance is connected to the interfacial Co oxidative transformations under electrocatalytic conditions. By combining the kinetic isotope effect and the apparent activation energy with theoretical verification, we offer the mechanistic discussion of the possible reaction pathway for CoOOH. In addition, CoOOH demonstrates a stable cell potential of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for 400 h in a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer. These results shed light on both the fundamental electrochemical properties of CoOOH and its potential for practical device applications.</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Zheyu Zhang, Chiara Spezzati, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Nina S. Genz, Ni&#233;li Daff&#233;, Radim Skoup&#253;, Lorenz Gubler, Ivano E. Castelli, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62744-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring metals, axial ligands, and carbon substrates in TMN4&#8211;graphene for direct seawater electrolysis: A synergistic approach using density functional theory and machine learning algorithms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138657</link>
      <description>Weirong Miao, Qiuling Jiang, Xiuli Hou, Cheng Lin, Shize Liu, Ying Cheng, Ying Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413118500

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weirong Miao, Qiuling Jiang, Xiuli Hou, Cheng Lin, Shize Liu, Ying Cheng, Ying Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic CO2 reduction to CH4 with near-unity selectivity over CsPbBr3 nanocrystals enabled by the synergetic effect between Au and PANI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164299</link>
      <description>Ziquan Li, Fuwei Chen, Lin Zheng, Zhen Li, Yuan Liu, Qi Pang, Binbin Luo, Applied Surface Science. 713(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413118634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziquan Li, Fuwei Chen, Lin Zheng, Zhen Li, Yuan Liu, Qi Pang, Binbin Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Fe atom substitutionally doped Janus MoSSe monolayer as a cost-effective electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction to HCOOH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112887</link>
      <description>Yu-Pu He, Tian-Hao Guo, Ping Zhu, Jihua Zhang, Shao-Yi Wu, Chemical Physics. 599(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413119728

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Pu He, Tian-Hao Guo, Ping Zhu, Jihua Zhang, Shao-Yi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive screening of transition metal-C4N4 monolayers for optimized oxygen reduction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107383</link>
      <description>Hanqing Li, Jinlong Chen, Jueyi Ye, Yongzhi Wu, Li Ma, Keyuan Chen, Ju Rong, Zhaohua Liu, Xiaohua Yu, Surfaces and Interfaces. 72(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413119746

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hanqing Li, Jinlong Chen, Jueyi Ye, Yongzhi Wu, Li Ma, Keyuan Chen, Ju Rong, Zhaohua Liu, Xiaohua Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107383</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial ligand engineering of MnN&#8324; single-atom catalysts for enhanced ORR and OER performance: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115421</link>
      <description>Zeyu Wang, Lili Sun, Wolong Li, Junda Qin, Yongcun Li, Yong Wang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. 1253(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413119747

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyu Wang, Lili Sun, Wolong Li, Junda Qin, Yongcun Li, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&#8322; reduction to C1 products on metal-free carbon nitride&#8211;modified HRG photocatalysts: insights from first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.115253</link>
      <description>Abdulraheem K. Bello, Abdulaziz A. Al&#8208;Saadi, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. 181(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413119818

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulraheem K. Bello, Abdulaziz A. Al&#8208;Saadi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.115253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of single atom coupled nitrogen doped graphene/molybdenum sulfide interface significantly improves water splitting property</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166979</link>
      <description>Kai Chen, Sunny Yadav, Elisabetta Inico, Yonghua Cao, Giovanni Di Liberto, Vandung Dao, Periyayya Uthirakumar, Gianfranco Pacchioni, In&#8208;Hwan Lee, Chemical Engineering Journal. 521(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413121025

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Chen, Sunny Yadav, Elisabetta Inico, Yonghua Cao, Giovanni Di Liberto, Vandung Dao, Periyayya Uthirakumar, Gianfranco Pacchioni, In&#8208;Hwan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the activity of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Single Transition Metal Atoms Embedded on BN/&#945;-In2Se3 Ferroelectric van der Waals Heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107396</link>
      <description>Zi-Qiang Deng, Xingchen Ding, B. Wang, Jing Xu, Rui Tan, Yulou Ouyang, Zhen&#8208;Kun Tang, Hui Zhang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413122113

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zi-Qiang Deng, Xingchen Ding, B. Wang, Jing Xu, Rui Tan, Yulou Ouyang, Zhen&#8208;Kun Tang, Hui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Durable MRuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; direct seawater electrolysis enabled by the synergistic effect between p-block dopants and active site Ru</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02836a</link>
      <description>Lu Wang, Ying Wang, Kai Li, Zhijian Wu, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413125422

                Sustainable hydrogen production via durable direct seawater electrolysis enabled by the synergistic effect between p-block M and active site Ru.</description>
      <author>Lu Wang, Ying Wang, Kai Li, Zhijian Wu, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02836a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Smart Workflow for Performing the Electrochemical Evaluation of Fuel Cell Catalysts in a Precise Way with Ultra-High Reproducibility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.5c00245</link>
      <description>Xinyu Wu, Liuhong Zhang, Deying Kong, Ping He, Tong Zhang, Chao Sun, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413128627

                The reproducibility of the rotating disk electrode (RDE) tests has been decisively limited by environmental and process variability in conventional manual sample preparation. To address this challenge, we present autoRDE-film, an automated platform that integrates force-controlled robotic polishing and process-controlled drop-coating to facilitate highly consistent RDE sample preparation. This mechanism reduces the standard deviation of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) limiting current from 0.7 mA cm&#8211;2 (traditional scheme) to 0.07 mA cm&#8211;2 and the standard deviation of the ORR half-wave potential (E1/2) from 0.038 to 0.004 V, ensuring exceptional batch-to-batch consistency. With the help of 480 RDE sample datasets generated by autoRDE-film, we have developed a ResNet-18-based deep learning model that correlates the film morphology with their electrochemical performance, enabling rapid quality classification with an accuracy of 96.3%. The combined workflow achieves a success rate of 90% for uniform coatings in batch preparations, far surpassing those of traditional approaches. By quantitatively controlling all preparation parameters, autoRDE-film establishes a universal and high-efficiency framework for evaluating ORR catalysts, which can be extended to the evaluation of fuel cell and water electrolysis catalysts and offers a transformative tool for AI-aided electrocatalyst optimization.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Wu, Liuhong Zhang, Deying Kong, Ping He, Tong Zhang, Chao Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.5c00245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unprecedented robustness of physics-informed atomic energy models at and beyond room temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7048965/v1</link>
      <description>Paul L. A. Popelier, Bienfait Kabuyaya Isamura, Olivia Aten, Mo Nosratjoo, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413129529

                Abstract Machine-learned potentials have become widely adopted alternatives to traditional electronic structure and molecular mechanics methods. However, despite excelling on fixed test sets, machine-learned potentials remain prone to instability when deployed in molecular dynamics simulations, particularly at elevated temperatures. Here we present the first physics-informed Gaussian process (GP)-based atomic energy models that achieve practically unlimited stability in NVT simulations at temperatures as high as 1000 K. Our findings highlight the importance of the GP prior mean function and demonstrate the models' ability to predict restoring forces that preserve the system&#8217;s physical integrity. The quantum chemical topology information embedded in these models acts as an inductive bias to mitigate arbitrary fluctuations in the predicted atomic energies. Finally, the models' robustness is evidenced by 50 successful simulations of four flexible organic molecules (peptide-capped glycine and serine, malondialdehyde and aspirin) yielding a cumulative simulation time of 0.5 microsecond completed within two CPU days.</description>
      <author>Paul L. A. Popelier, Bienfait Kabuyaya Isamura, Olivia Aten, Mo Nosratjoo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7048965/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electrochemical Shono Oxidation of &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;Formylpyrrolidine: Mechanistic Insights from the Computational Ferrocene Electrode Model and Cyclic Voltammetry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500202</link>
      <description>L. A. Savintseva, Paul Neugebauer, Dmitry Sharapa, Philipp R&#246;se, Ulrike Krewer, Felix Studt, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413130854

                Electrochemical processes are of particular interest in modern chemical technologies as they have numerous advantages over classical approaches. While computational support for investigating thermochemical reaction mechanisms is well established, there is still no consistent methodology for modeling electrochemical processes beyond the computational hydrogen electrode. This work addresses this gap through the study of the Shono&#8208;type oxidation of N &#8208;formylpyrrolidine. Combining density functional theory calculations, the concept of computational Fc + /Fc electrode, Marcus&#8211;Hush approach, and Butler&#8211;Volmer model, the reaction mechanism is elucidated, including the identification of the role and position of proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer process. Additionally, simulated cyclic voltammograms are in excellent agreement with experimental studies performed in parallel.</description>
      <author>L. A. Savintseva, Paul Neugebauer, Dmitry Sharapa, Philipp R&#246;se, Ulrike Krewer, Felix Studt</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Intricacies of Computational Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00748</link>
      <description>Nitish Govindarajan, Georg Kastlunger, Joseph A. Gauthier, Jun Cheng, Ivo A. W. Filot, Arthur Hagopian, Heine Anton Hansen, Jun Huang, Piotr M. Kowalski, Jinwen Liu, Juan M. Lombardi, Mikael Maraschin, Andrew A. Peterson, Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, H&#232;ctor Prats, Conor Jason Price, Ren&#233; van Roij, Jan Rossmeisl, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Audrey D. Smith, Jiaxin Zhu, Katharina Doblhoff-Dier, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413131289

                Computational electrochemistry is hard&#9472;anybody who has ever tried will know. We argue that the reasons for its complexity lie not only in the multiscale nature of electrochemical processes but also in the rapid, ongoing method development in the field. This has resulted in a lack of clear guidelines and many open discussions in the community. These issues were also the topic of a recent Lorentz Center workshop, the key take-away messages of which are highlighted in this Perspective. In particular, we discuss why the choice between constant potential and constant charge simulations is less trivial than it may seem, why interpreting electrochemical reaction free energy diagrams can be challenging, why the Poisson&#8211;Nernst&#8211;Planck equation is not all there is, and why we desperately need more benchmarking in the field.</description>
      <author>Nitish Govindarajan, Georg Kastlunger, Joseph A. Gauthier, Jun Cheng, Ivo A. W. Filot, Arthur Hagopian, Heine Anton Hansen, Jun Huang, Piotr M. Kowalski, Jinwen Liu, Juan M. Lombardi, Mikael Maraschin, Andrew A. Peterson, Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, H&#232;ctor Prats, Conor Jason Price, Ren&#233; van Roij, Jan Rossmeisl, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Audrey D. Smith, Jiaxin Zhu, Katharina Doblhoff-Dier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(&lt;i&gt;h K l&lt;/i&gt;) Interface in Hydrogen and Water Splitting: A DFT Perspective on Reactivity and Limitations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c01650</link>
      <description>Ericson H. N. S. Thaines, Aline C. Oliveira, Leandro Aparecido Pocrifka, Gustavo Doubek, Leonardo M. Da Silva, Hudson Zanin, Renato G. Freitas, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413134855

                The Pt/TiO2 interface has shown promise as a photocatalyst for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER). However, understanding hydrogen and water splitting reactions on the Pt surface of the Pt/TiO2 interface remains a significant challenge. The Pt3/TiO2(h k l) interface was characterized using X-ray diffraction (XRD) with Rietveld refinement analysis, which revealed reflections attributed to Pt(1 1 1) and anatase TiO2(h k l). Theoretical modeling of the Pt3/TiO2(h k l) interface consists of approximately 60% TiO2 and 40% Pt, as determined by Rietveld refinement. The electronic properties were obtained using density functional theory (DFT)/plane-wave calculations on a model consisting of 39 atoms. The band structure and projected density of states (PDOS) of Pt3/TiO2(h k l) showed a new state between the valence and conduction bands, with contributions from the Pt 5d state, indicating metallic behavior. The initial steps of hydrogen and water splitting, as well as the transition states, were determined using the nudged elastic band (NEB) method for the reactions H2&#8594;Hads*+Hads* and H2Oads&#8594;OHads*+Hads* on the Pt3 surface of the Pt3/TiO2(h k l) interface. The Pt3/TiO2(1 0 1) interface exhibited the lowest activation energy (0.19 eV) for hydrogen molecule splitting, an exothermic reaction. Both Pt3/TiO2(h k l) interfaces exhibited an activation energy of approximately 1.4 eV for water splitting, an endothermic reaction. Therefore, hydrogen molecule splitting on the Pt3 surface is favorable, whereas water splitting is not, which may limit the hydrogen production rate (HGR) compared to other catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ericson H. N. S. Thaines, Aline C. Oliveira, Leandro Aparecido Pocrifka, Gustavo Doubek, Leonardo M. Da Silva, Hudson Zanin, Renato G. Freitas</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c01650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Engineering of Complex Oxide Membranes on Flexible Metallic Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/apxr.202500075</link>
      <description>Eric Brand, Pol Sall&#233;s, Alessandro Palliotto, Haiyuan Wang, Wei Chen, Edwin Dollekamp, M. K. Ramis, Quan Li, Jakub Drnec, J. M. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Lastra, Mariona Coll, Nini Pryds, Daesung Park, Advanced Physics Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413135178

                Abstract Controlling material functionalities via external stimuli is a cornerstone of modern science and technology. One effective strategy involves tuning mechanical strain, which can be induced through lattice mismatch, electric fields, or applied mechanical force. Recent advances in fabricating freestanding single&#8208;crystalline complex oxide membranes have opened new opportunities for integrating these materials onto previously incompatible platforms such as metals and flexible polymers for next&#8208;generation device applications. A key step in strain engineering is understanding and controlling the integration of such materials with flexible substrates. In this study, the integration and adhesion of freestanding single&#8208;crystalline La 0.7 Sr 0.3 MnO 3 (LSMO(001)) membranes onto metallic surfaces (Au, Pt, and TiN) coated on flexible polymer substrates is demonstrated. It is found that the choice of metal underlayer significantly influences the ability to strain the membrane. Using TiN&#8208;coated polymer support, a uniform strain of &#8776;1% in LSMO membranes, along with strong adhesion between the membrane and substrate, is achieved. Theoretical calculations reveal that strong Ti&#9472;O bonding and compact in&#8208;plane lattice matching at the LSMO(001)/TiN(111) interface lower the interface formation energy compared to noble metals. These findings offer valuable insights for selecting suitable platforms to apply external mechanical stress to freestanding oxide membranes, facilitating their integration into flexible electronic systems.</description>
      <author>Eric Brand, Pol Sall&#233;s, Alessandro Palliotto, Haiyuan Wang, Wei Chen, Edwin Dollekamp, M. K. Ramis, Quan Li, Jakub Drnec, J. M. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Lastra, Mariona Coll, Nini Pryds, Daesung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/apxr.202500075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoconfined impulse synthesis of high-entropy nanocarbides for active and stable electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00854-z</link>
      <description>Chenyu Li, Zhichao Zhang, Kunlei Zhu, Mingda Liu, J. J. Chen, Liang Zhou, Qinghua Zhang, Yonghuang Wu, Jing Guo, Run Shi, Zeqin Xin, Yinghui Sun, Peng Liu, Hui Wu, Lin Gu, Dingsheng Wang, Rongming Wang, Yadong Li, Shoushan Fan, Jia Li, Kai Liu, Nature Synthesis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413143695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenyu Li, Zhichao Zhang, Kunlei Zhu, Mingda Liu, J. J. Chen, Liang Zhou, Qinghua Zhang, Yonghuang Wu, Jing Guo, Run Shi, Zeqin Xin, Yinghui Sun, Peng Liu, Hui Wu, Lin Gu, Dingsheng Wang, Rongming Wang, Yadong Li, Shoushan Fan, Jia Li, Kai Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00854-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional FeCoNiCrM High-Entropy Alloy Nanoparticles for Coupled Hydrogen Evolution and Glycerol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.138019</link>
      <description>Jiace Hao, Shuhui Sun, Ying Zhou, Xiaodan Pan, Mingliang Du, Han Zhu, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413144027

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiace Hao, Shuhui Sun, Ying Zhou, Xiaodan Pan, Mingliang Du, Han Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.138019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into Biomass-Derived Dual Hydrogen Generation via Vacancy-Engineered NiO Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125828</link>
      <description>Subin Moon, Hyungsoo Lee, So Yeon Yun, Sanguk Son, Wooyong Jeong, Chang-Seop Jeong, Young Sun Park, Juwon Yun, Soo&#8208;Bin Lee, Jun Hwan Kim, Dong&#8208;Hyun Kim, Hyoung&#8722;il Kim, Seong&#8208;Ju Hwang, Sooyeon Kim, Jooho Moon, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413144236

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subin Moon, Hyungsoo Lee, So Yeon Yun, Sanguk Son, Wooyong Jeong, Chang-Seop Jeong, Young Sun Park, Juwon Yun, Soo&#8208;Bin Lee, Jun Hwan Kim, Dong&#8208;Hyun Kim, Hyoung&#8722;il Kim, Seong&#8208;Ju Hwang, Sooyeon Kim, Jooho Moon</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the structural, catalytic properties and dehydrogenated behavior of Nb2C MXene for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2025.102022</link>
      <description>Yong Pan, Jiahao Gao, I.P. Jain, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413149212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Pan, Jiahao Gao, I.P. Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2025.102022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Study of Sn-Doped RuO2 as Efficient Electrocatalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15080770</link>
      <description>Caiyan Zheng, Qian Gao, Zhenpeng Hu, Catalysts. 15(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413160089

                Improving the catalytic performance of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for water splitting in acidic media is crucial for the production of clean and renewable hydrogen energy. Herein, we study the OER electrocatalytic properties of various active sites on four exposed (110) and (1&#175;10) surfaces of Sn-doped RuO2 (Sn/RuO2) with antiferromagnetic arrangements in acidic environments. The Sn/RuO2 bulk structure with the Cm space group exhibits favorable thermodynamic stability. The coordinatively unsaturated metal (Mcus) sites distributed on the right branch of the volcano plot are generally more active than the bridge-bonded lattice oxygen (Obr) sites located on the left. Different from the conventional knowledge that the most active site is located in the nearest neighbor of the doped atom, it has a lower OER overpotential when the active site is 3.6 &#197; away from the doped Sn atom. Among the sites studied, the 46-Rucus site exhibits the optimal OER catalytic performance. The inherent factors affecting the OER activity of each site on the Sn/RuO2 surface are further analyzed, including the center of the d/p band at the active sites, the average electrostatic potential of the ions, and the number of transferred electrons. This work provides a reminder for the selection of active sites used to evaluate catalytic performance, which will benefit the development of efficient OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Caiyan Zheng, Qian Gao, Zhenpeng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15080770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superlattice ordering Pt2CoNi intermetallic nanocatalysts with surface microstrain for efficient hydrogen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3525-6</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Xin Wang, Wanqing Song, Jiahui Feng, Xinyi Yang, Haozhi Wang, Jia Ding, Wenbin Hu, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413160984

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Xin Wang, Wanqing Song, Jiahui Feng, Xinyi Yang, Haozhi Wang, Jia Ding, Wenbin Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3525-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterometallic doping regulation in two-dimensional metal&#8211;organic frameworks for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction: a computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164331</link>
      <description>Xiaofei Wei, Shoufu Cao, Shaohua Cheng, Chunyu Lu, Xinhui Chen, Xiaoqing L&#252;, Peng Wang, Fangna Dai, Applied Surface Science. 713(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413167385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaofei Wei, Shoufu Cao, Shaohua Cheng, Chunyu Lu, Xinhui Chen, Xiaoqing L&#252;, Peng Wang, Fangna Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164331</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom embedded ZnO monolayers as bifunctional electrocatalysts for the ORR/OER: a machine learning-assisted DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5qm00437c</link>
      <description>Siyao Wang, Dongxu Jiao, Jingxiang Zhao, Materials Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413168894

                Combining DFT constant-potential calculations and machine learning, we identify Ni&#8211;ZnO as a low-overpotential bifunctional ORR/OER single-atom catalyst and reveal N e , E i and R TM as primary activity descriptors.</description>
      <author>Siyao Wang, Dongxu Jiao, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5qm00437c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Study of Metal&#8211;Biphenylene Nanoscale Interfaces: Structural, Electronic, and Catalytic Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c02590</link>
      <description>Maicon P. Lebre, Dominike Pacine de Andrade Deus, Erika N. Lima, Alexandre Alberto Chaves Cotta, I. S. Santos de Oliveira, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413173192

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maicon P. Lebre, Dominike Pacine de Andrade Deus, Erika N. Lima, Alexandre Alberto Chaves Cotta, I. S. Santos de Oliveira</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c02590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT Study of the Hydroacylation Reaction Catalyzed by Rhodium Complexes with Small-Bite-Angle Diphosphine Ligands: The Crucial Role of External Lewis Bases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.5c00179</link>
      <description>Andrew S. Weller, Michael C. Willis, Libero J. Bartolotti, Andrew T. Morehead, Andrew L. Sargent, Organometallics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413174833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrew S. Weller, Michael C. Willis, Libero J. Bartolotti, Andrew T. Morehead, Andrew L. Sargent</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.organomet.5c00179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights into nitrogen activation on atomic Ru clusters in self-pillared pentasil using operando atomistic models and experimental kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116374</link>
      <description>Geet Gupta, Weiye Qu, Zihao Gao, Weilin Huang, Xiang Zhou, Lu Ma, Ning-ning Kang, Paul Haghi Ashtiani, Fan Bu, Jeffrey T. Miller, Michael Tsapatsis, Chao Wang, Brandon C. Bukowski, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413183503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Geet Gupta, Weiye Qu, Zihao Gao, Weilin Huang, Xiang Zhou, Lu Ma, Ning-ning Kang, Paul Haghi Ashtiani, Fan Bu, Jeffrey T. Miller, Michael Tsapatsis, Chao Wang, Brandon C. Bukowski</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCu/NC Dual-Atom Catalysts via Template-Assisted Stepwise Pyrolysis for Efficient ORR and Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.138014</link>
      <description>Ruishen Huang, Tianyou Zhao, Xiaoming Gao, Yunfeng Zhan, Aiwen Wu, Haofeng Lin, Shuangshuang Yuan, Xiufeng Tang, Zongwen Zhang, Jianyi Luo, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413185104

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruishen Huang, Tianyou Zhao, Xiaoming Gao, Yunfeng Zhan, Aiwen Wu, Haofeng Lin, Shuangshuang Yuan, Xiufeng Tang, Zongwen Zhang, Jianyi Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.138014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing PtCo2.7M0.3 Intermetallic Compounds for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysis by Synergizing Doping and Annealing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147138</link>
      <description>Chuanqi Luo, Kechuang Wan, Jue Wang, Daijun Yang, Pingwen Ming, Bing Li, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413186319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuanqi Luo, Kechuang Wan, Jue Wang, Daijun Yang, Pingwen Ming, Bing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigate of Mechanism of Flowing Electrolyte Channel on Reducing Methanol Crossover of Direct Methanol Fuel Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5388720</link>
      <description>Zemu TIAN, Hongxiu Zhou, Junhao Zhu, Qingyun Su, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413187419

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zemu TIAN, Hongxiu Zhou, Junhao Zhu, Qingyun Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5388720</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergent B2 chemical orderings in the AlTiVNb and AlTiCrMo refractory high-entropy superalloys studied via first-principles theory and atomistic modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7639/adf468</link>
      <description>Christopher D. Woodgate, Hubert J Naguszewski, David Redka, J. Min&#225;&#345;, David Quigley, J. B. Staunton, Journal of Physics Materials. 8(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413196871

                Abstract We study the thermodynamics and phase stability of the AlTiVNb and AlTiCrMo refractory high-entropy superalloys using a combination of ab initio electronic structure theory&#8212;namely a concentration wave analysis&#8212;and atomistic Monte Carlo simulations. Our multiscale approach is suitable both for examining atomic short-range order in the solid solution, as well as for studying the emergence of long-range crystallographic order with decreasing temperature. In both alloys considered in this work, in alignment with experimental observations, we predict a B2 (CsCl) chemical ordering emerging at high temperatures, which is driven primarily by Al and Ti, with other elements expressing weaker site preferences. The predicted B2 ordering temperature for AlTiVNb is higher than that for AlTiCrMo. These chemical orderings are discussed in terms of the alloys&#8217; electronic structure, with hybridisation between the sp states of Al and the d states of the transition metals understood to play an important role. Within our modelling, the chemically ordered B2 phases for both alloys have an increased predicted residual resistivity compared to the A2 (disordered bcc) phases. These increased resistivity values are understood to originate in a reduction in the electronic density of states at the Fermi level, in conjunction with qualitative changes to the alloys&#8217; smeared-out Fermi surfaces. These results highlight the close connections between composition, structure, and physical properties in this technologically relevant class of materials.</description>
      <author>Christopher D. Woodgate, Hubert J Naguszewski, David Redka, J. Min&#225;&#345;, David Quigley, J. B. Staunton</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7639/adf468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First-Principles Screening for Axial Ligand Regulation of Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction on Dual-Metal Atomic Catalysts (M&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;-R)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05014</link>
      <description>Yousong Gu, Hualin Chen, Jiangnan Shen, Qiuju Zhang, Liang Chen, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413199175

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yousong Gu, Hualin Chen, Jiangnan Shen, Qiuju Zhang, Liang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Formation of V@C Core-Shell and Interfacial Synergy for Low-Temperature Green Synthesis of Vanadium Nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5388307</link>
      <description>Wenbin Bo, Yimin Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413202477

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenbin Bo, Yimin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5388307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review of H2O2 electrosynthesis by 2-electron ORR and 2-electron WOR: From catalysts to electrochemical cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.217042</link>
      <description>Erzhuo Zhao, Wendan Xue, Shiyong Qin, Yang Guo, Xin Xin, Huijiao Wang, Yinqiao Zhang, Sijin Zuo, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 545(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413204345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Erzhuo Zhao, Wendan Xue, Shiyong Qin, Yang Guo, Xin Xin, Huijiao Wang, Yinqiao Zhang, Sijin Zuo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.217042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy-output electrosynthesis and downstream conversion of hydrogen peroxide in a unified system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.08.003</link>
      <description>J. Q. Zhang, Yiming Li, Jingfang Zhang, Shuoao Wang, Zhengshun Wu, Yi Huang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413209338

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Q. Zhang, Yiming Li, Jingfang Zhang, Shuoao Wang, Zhengshun Wu, Yi Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.08.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning interatomic potentials in biomolecular modeling: principles, architectures, and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12551-025-01351-5</link>
      <description>P.P. Kobchikova, B. A. Bakirov, R. E. Ryltsev, Xiao He, Ilya A. Khodov, Biophysical Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413239123

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P.P. Kobchikova, B. A. Bakirov, R. E. Ryltsev, Xiao He, Ilya A. Khodov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12551-025-01351-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the catalytic activity of Pt and NiPt clusters in methane decomposition for hydrogen production: Insights from molecular simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1557/s43580-025-01363-z</link>
      <description>Rizal Arifin, Abdurrouf, Zulkarnain Zulkarnain, Ida Widaningrum, Yoyok Winardi, Norhasnidawani Johari, Darminto Darminto, MRS Advances. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413244613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rizal Arifin, Abdurrouf, Zulkarnain Zulkarnain, Ida Widaningrum, Yoyok Winardi, Norhasnidawani Johari, Darminto Darminto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1557/s43580-025-01363-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAFFLE: active learning accelerated interface structure prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01749-5</link>
      <description>Ned Thaddeus Taylor, Joe Pitfield, Francis H. Davies, S. P. Hepplestone, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413248207

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ned Thaddeus Taylor, Joe Pitfield, Francis H. Davies, S. P. Hepplestone</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01749-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface chlorine doping activates highly stable Cu2O(111) facets for enhanced CO2 photoreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166908</link>
      <description>Ning Li, Ping Zhang, Reyila Tuerhong, Yongchong Yu, Yapeng Lan, Yu Zhang, Xiaoping Su, Lian&#8208;Biao Zhao, Lijuan Han, Xiaotian Wang, Hengjiao Gao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413253174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Li, Ping Zhang, Reyila Tuerhong, Yongchong Yu, Yapeng Lan, Yu Zhang, Xiaoping Su, Lian&#8208;Biao Zhao, Lijuan Han, Xiaotian Wang, Hengjiao Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph Neural Networks for Sustainable Energy: Predicting Adsorption in Aromatic Molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering9040085</link>
      <description>Hasan Imani Parashkooh, Cuiying Jian, ChemEngineering. 9(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413256406

                The growing need for rapid screening of adsorption energies in organic materials has driven substantial progress in developing various architectures of equivariant graph neural networks (eGNNs). This advancement has largely been enabled by the availability of extensive Density Functional Theory (DFT)-generated datasets, sufficiently large to train complex eGNN models effectively. However, certain material groups with significant industrial relevance, such as aromatic compounds, remain underrepresented in these large datasets. In this work, we aim to bridge the gap between limited, domain-specific DFT datasets and large-scale pretrained eGNNs. Our methodology involves creating a specialized dataset by segregating aromatic compounds after a targeted ensemble extraction process, then fine-tuning a pretrained model via approaches that include full retraining and systematically freezing specific network sections. We demonstrate that these approaches can yield accurate energy and force predictions with minimal domain-specific training data and computation. Additionally, we investigate the effects of augmenting training datasets with chemically related but out-of-domain groups. Our findings indicate that incorporating supplementary data that closely resembles the target domain, even if approximate, would enhance model performance on domain-specific tasks. Furthermore, we systematically freeze different sections of the pretrained models to elucidate the role each component plays during adaptation to new domains, revealing that relearning low-level representations is critical for effective domain transfer. Overall, this study contributes valuable insights and practical guidelines for efficiently adapting deep learning models for accurate adsorption energy predictions, significantly reducing reliance on extensive training datasets.</description>
      <author>Hasan Imani Parashkooh, Cuiying Jian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering9040085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel-structured IrO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62861-0</link>
      <description>Mingyu Zhang, Wei An, Qianqian Liu, Yun Jiang, Xiao Zhao, Hui Chen, Yongcun Zou, Xiao Liang, Xiaoxin Zou, PubMed. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413257353

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyu Zhang, Wei An, Qianqian Liu, Yun Jiang, Xiao Zhao, Hui Chen, Yongcun Zou, Xiao Liang, Xiaoxin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62861-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computing anharmonic infrared spectra of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons using machine learning molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/staf1156</link>
      <description>Xinghong Mai, Zhao Wang, Lijun Pan, Johannes Sch&#246;rghuber, P&#233;ter Kov&#225;cs, Jes&#250;s Carrete, Georg K. H. Madsen, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. 541(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413271010

                ABSTRACT We introduce a machine learning molecular dynamics (MLMD) approach to calculate the anharmonic infrared (IR) absorption spectra of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs), key carriers of interstellar aromatic IR bands. This method accounts for temperature effects in a molecule-specific way and achieves accuracy comparable to conventional quantum chemical calculations at a fraction of the cost, scaling linearly with system size. We applied MLMD to calculate the anharmonic spectra of 1704 PAHs in the NASA Ames PAH IR Spectroscopic Data base with up to 216 carbon atoms at different temperatures, demonstrating its capability for high-throughput spectral calculations of large molecular systems. Our results highlight MLMD&#8217;s potential to enable the development of extensive molecular spectral data sets, enhancing data-driven analyses of astronomical IR spectra, particularly in anticipation of upcoming observations from the James Webb Space Telescope.</description>
      <author>Xinghong Mai, Zhao Wang, Lijun Pan, Johannes Sch&#246;rghuber, P&#233;ter Kov&#225;cs, Jes&#250;s Carrete, Georg K. H. Madsen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/staf1156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights and predictive screening of M@C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N catalysts for urea electrosynthesis from N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta03783b</link>
      <description>Nuttapon Yodsin, Tannatorn Potale, Yuwanda Injongkol, Pimjai Pimbaotham, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413271739

                A descriptor-guided screening of single-atom M@C 2 N catalysts enables identification of Nb as a top candidate for ambient electrocatalytic urea synthesis from CO 2 and N 2 , with high activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Nuttapon Yodsin, Tannatorn Potale, Yuwanda Injongkol, Pimjai Pimbaotham, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta03783b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of vanadium and rhenium co-doped TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for enhanced photocatalytic performance via first principle density functional theory investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1402-4896/adf156</link>
      <description>Fikadu Takele Geldasa, F.B. Dejene, Physica Scripta. 100(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413273058

                Abstract Elemental doping is an effective strategy to enhance the photocatalytic performance of TiO 2 by modifying its electronic structure through the introduction of impurity states near the valence or conduction bands. In this study, we employ density functional theory (DFT) with Hubbard U correction (DFT+U) to investigate the effects of vanadium (V) and rhenium (Re) mono-doping and co-doping on the structural, electronic, and optical properties of rutile TiO 2 . Structural optimizations reveal slight reductions in lattice constants and bond lengths in doped systems, attributed to the marginal ionic radius differences between the dopants and Ti 4+ ions. Formation energy analysis indicated that V&#8211;Re co-doping is energetically more favorable than mono-doping, suggesting high structural stability. Electronic structure analysis indicates a significant bandgap narrowing in V-doped (2.62 eV) and V&#8211;Re co-doped TiO 2 (2.75 eV), suggesting enhanced absorption in the visible region and improved photocatalytic activity. In contrast, Re mono-doping slightly increases the bandgap to 3.10 eV, limiting its activity to the UV region. Optical properties, including the dielectric function and absorption spectra, further confirm a redshift in V and V&#8211;Re doped systems, while Re doping results in a blueshift. Band edge alignment with respect to the normal hydrogen electrode (NHE) shows that all doped systems satisfy the thermodynamic criteria for water splitting, with V&#8211;Re co-doping exhibiting the most favorable band positions for hydrogen evolution. Finally, this work demonstrates that co-doping with V and Re is a promising strategy to engineer TiO 2 with improved visible-light photocatalytic performance, offering valuable insights for the design and synthesis of efficient photocatalysts for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Fikadu Takele Geldasa, F.B. Dejene</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1402-4896/adf156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating the Pt triangular chain of Janus Pt2C monolayer forms multiple active sites for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164148</link>
      <description>Huan Lou, Chi Ma, Applied Surface Science. 712(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413273062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Lou, Chi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamics of Molecular Binding and Clustering in the Atmosphere Revealed through Conventional and ML-Enhanced Umbrella Sampling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05634</link>
      <description>Jakub Kube&#269;ka, Yosef Knattrup, Georg Baadsgaard Trolle, Bernhard Reischl, August Smart Lykke-M&#248;ller, Jonas Elm, Ivo Neefjes, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413273850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jakub Kube&#269;ka, Yosef Knattrup, Georg Baadsgaard Trolle, Bernhard Reischl, August Smart Lykke-M&#248;ller, Jonas Elm, Ivo Neefjes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling size and surface effects of intermetallic CuPd nanocrystals for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101492</link>
      <description>Liyue Zhang, Zaheer Masood, Qiang Gao, Min&#8208;Chul Kang, Xiangru Wei, Yulu Zhang, Zhanrong Guo, Yizhen Chen, Lu Ma, Huiyuan Zhu, Ling Zhou, Bin Wang, Sen Zhang, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413274467

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liyue Zhang, Zaheer Masood, Qiang Gao, Min&#8208;Chul Kang, Xiangru Wei, Yulu Zhang, Zhanrong Guo, Yizhen Chen, Lu Ma, Huiyuan Zhu, Ling Zhou, Bin Wang, Sen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electron Modulation with Ionic Liquids: Dual Optimization of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Confinement and Charge Transfer for Enhanced Electroreduction on Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c02334</link>
      <description>Chuanhui Wang, Mingyue Qiu, Guizeng Liang, Hui Yan, Jiamin Ma, Lijuan Shi, Congyun Zhang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413274626

                The high-rate electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to afford multicarbon products (C2) holds transformative potential for advancing sustainable energy systems. Ionic liquids (ILs) have emerged as dynamic modulators to promote the C2 pathway, yet the underlying atomistic mechanisms of ILs in modulating this CO2RR process remain fundamentally unclear. Here, by integrating molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, density functional theory (DFT) calculations, and experimental validations, we systematically elucidate the critical influence of 1-(3-aminopropyl)-3-methylimidazole chloride ILs in optimizing the CO2RR pathway on Cu surfaces through electronic structure engineering. MD simulations demonstrate that ILs establish a CO2-enriched interfacial microenvironment that restricts bulk-phase CO2 diffusion through the confinement effect. Electron structure analyses reveal that ILs synergistically enhance interfacial electron accumulation and directional charge transfer for adsorbed CO2 and key intermediates (*CO, *COH, *CHO, and *C), collectively stabilizing them through IL-induced strengthening of Cu-C bonding. More importantly, the introduction of ILs dramatically reduces the activation barrier of the rate-determining C-C coupling step and thermodynamically favors the CO2RR to C2H4 and C2H5OH pathways through atom orbital hybridization. Additionally, the ILs not only enhance the CO2RR but also suppress the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) through proton confinement. This work provides molecular-level insights into the dynamic role of ILs in optimizing CO2RR processes and offers a foundation for designing advanced IL-mediated electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Chuanhui Wang, Mingyue Qiu, Guizeng Liang, Hui Yan, Jiamin Ma, Lijuan Shi, Congyun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c02334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The structure and migration of twin boundaries in tetragonal &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1443" altimg="si48.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;&#946;&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-Sn: An application of machine learning based interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121390</link>
      <description>Ian Chesser, Mashroor S. Nitol, Esther C. Hessong, Himanshu Joshi, Nikhil Chandra Admal, Brandon Runnels, Daniel N. Blaschke, Khanh Dang, Abigail Hunter, Saryu Fensin, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413275600

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ian Chesser, Mashroor S. Nitol, Esther C. Hessong, Himanshu Joshi, Nikhil Chandra Admal, Brandon Runnels, Daniel N. Blaschke, Khanh Dang, Abigail Hunter, Saryu Fensin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Te Vacancy Defect Engineering on Fe3GeTe2 (001) Basal Planes for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15161272</link>
      <description>Yufei Gao, Wei Su, Yuan Qiu, Dan Shan, Jing Pan, Nanomaterials. 15(16)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413286721

                Photocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen production is an attractive renewable energy technology, but the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode is severely constrained by a high overpotential. The two-dimensional vdW ferromagnetic material Fe3GeTe2, with its good stability and excellent metallic conductivity, has potential as an electrocatalyst, but its sluggish surface catalytic reactivity limits its large-scale application. In this work, we adapted DFT calculations to introduce surface Te vacancies to boost OER performance of the Fe3GeTe2 (001) surface. Te vacancies induce the charge redistribution of active sites, optimizing the adsorption and desorption of oxygen-containing intermediates. Consequently, the overpotential of the rate-determining step in the OER process of Fe3GeTe2 is reduced to 0.34 V, bringing the performance close to that of the benchmark IrO2 catalyst (0.56 V). Notably, the vacancies&#8217; concentration and configuration significantly modify the electronic structure and thus influence OER activity. This study provides important theoretical evidence for defect engineering in OER catalysis and offers new design strategies for developing efficient and stable electrocatalysts for sustainable energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Yufei Gao, Wei Su, Yuan Qiu, Dan Shan, Jing Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15161272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An automated framework for exploring and learning potential-energy surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62510-6</link>
      <description>Yuanbin Liu, Joe D. Morrow, Christina Ertural, Natascia L. Fragapane, John L. A. Gardner, Aakash Ashok Naik, Yuxing Zhou, Janine George, Volker L. Deringer, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413288367

                Machine learning has become ubiquitous in materials modelling and now routinely enables large-scale atomistic simulations with quantum-mechanical accuracy. However, developing machine-learned interatomic potentials requires high-quality training data, and the manual generation and curation of such data can be a major bottleneck. Here, we introduce an automated framework for the exploration and fitting of potential-energy surfaces, implemented in an openly available software package that we call autoplex ('automatic potential-landscape explorer'). We discuss design choices, particularly the interoperability with existing software architectures, and the ability for the end user to easily use the computational workflows provided. We show wide-ranging capability demonstrations: for the titanium-oxygen system, SiO2, crystalline and liquid water, as well as phase-change memory materials. More generally, our study illustrates how automation can speed up atomistic machine learning in computational materials science.</description>
      <author>Yuanbin Liu, Joe D. Morrow, Christina Ertural, Natascia L. Fragapane, John L. A. Gardner, Aakash Ashok Naik, Yuxing Zhou, Janine George, Volker L. Deringer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62510-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Orbital&#8208;Driven SERS Enhancement Via D&#8208;Band Engineering in High&#8208;Entropy Alloy Aerogels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/lpor.202501214</link>
      <description>Di Liu, Pengwei Duan, Junjie Chen, Ming Mu, Yumei Yang, Fuqiu Ma, Zhao Bing, Wei Song, Laser &amp; Photonics Review. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413289925

                Abstract Understanding atomic orbital&#8208;level interactions at material&#8208;molecule interfaces is crucial for advancing surface&#8208;enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS). While conventional mechanisms focus on electromagnetic effects or interfacial charge transfer (CT), the role of orbital hybridization in multimetallic systems remains underexplored. Here, a d&#8208;band&#8208;mediated CT mechanism is proposed through the engineering high&#8208;entropy alloy aerogels (HEAAs). A face&#8208;centered cubic AuAgCuMnInBi HEAAs synthesized via one&#8208;step coreduction achieves ultrasensitive SERS detection of crystal violet. Density of states analyses reveal that Mn&#8208;3d orbitals bridge electron reservoirs (Au/Ag/Cu) and In/Bi&#8208;p orbitals, enabling efficient charge delocalization. Voltage&#8208;tunable SERS signals in MnInBi subsystems confirm d&#8208;band&#8208;dependent CT enhancement. Beyond molecular sensing, this mechanism allows direct capture of reactive intermediates (OH&#183;, O 2 &#183; &#8211; ) and 5 n M uranium detection, bridging SERS enhancement dynamics with catalytic pathway elucidation. These findings establish d&#8208;band engineering as a paradigm for designing multifunctional SERS substrates, bridging atomic&#8208;scale electronic interactions with ultrasensitive sensing and catalytic mechanism elucidation.</description>
      <author>Di Liu, Pengwei Duan, Junjie Chen, Ming Mu, Yumei Yang, Fuqiu Ma, Zhao Bing, Wei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/lpor.202501214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selectively passivated core-satellite cobalt-iron bimetallic phosphide with optimized &#8270;OH adsorption for boosting oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167382</link>
      <description>B. H. Liu, Wangshu Zheng, Zhaoxi Zhang, Jiarui Yang, Yanqi Yuan, Li Feng, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Yixing Luo, Han Chen, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413292311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. H. Liu, Wangshu Zheng, Zhaoxi Zhang, Jiarui Yang, Yanqi Yuan, Li Feng, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Yixing Luo, Han Chen, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Model for Efficient Nonthermal Tuning of the Charge Density Wave in Monolayer NbSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00959</link>
      <description>Luka Beni&#263;, Federico Grasselli, Chiheb Ben Mahmoud, Dino Novko, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413292815

                Understanding and controlling the charge density wave (CDW) phase diagram of transition-metal dichalcogenides are long-studied problems in condensed matter physics. However, due to the complex involvement of electron and lattice degrees of freedom and pronounced anharmonicity, theoretical simulations of the CDW phase diagram at the density-functional-theory level are often numerically demanding. To reduce the computational cost of first-principles modeling by orders of magnitude, we have developed an electronic free-energy machine learning model for monolayer NbSe2 that allows us to control the electronic temperature as a parameter of the model. The ionic temperature is modeled via the stochastic self-consistent harmonic approximation. Our approach relies on a machine learning model of the electronic density of states and zero-temperature interatomic potential. This allows us to explore the CDW phase diagram of monolayer NbSe2 both under thermal and laser-induced nonthermal conditions. Our study provides an accurate estimate of the CDW transition temperature at low cost and can disentangle the role of hot electrons and phonons in the nonthermal ultrafast melting process of the CDW phase in NbSe2.</description>
      <author>Luka Beni&#263;, Federico Grasselli, Chiheb Ben Mahmoud, Dino Novko, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>p-d orbital coupling and interfacial water regulation synergistically promote alkaline hydrogen electrocatalysis on Ru/VC heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167317</link>
      <description>Hao Hu, Nuo Sun, Jie Gao, Li Wang, Zhangrong Lou, Xuejing Cui, Jing Liu, Luhua Jiang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413292830

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Hu, Nuo Sun, Jie Gao, Li Wang, Zhangrong Lou, Xuejing Cui, Jing Liu, Luhua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mg-Al layered double hydroxides derived from secondary aluminum ash for soil remediation contaminated with Cd(&#8545;) and Cr(&#8549;)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.139585</link>
      <description>Shikai Li, Hanbing Gao, Rui Xu, Zhaohui Guo, Journal of Hazardous Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413295529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shikai Li, Hanbing Gao, Rui Xu, Zhaohui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.139585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom doping FeS for nitrogen fixation: High-throughput DFT calculation screening and bio-preparation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147149</link>
      <description>Xingfu Zheng, Shi Sun, Jin&#8208;lan Xia, Zhen&#8208;yuan Nie, Rui Hu, Hongchang Liu, Yuting Liang, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413297901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingfu Zheng, Shi Sun, Jin&#8208;lan Xia, Zhen&#8208;yuan Nie, Rui Hu, Hongchang Liu, Yuting Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;/scp&gt; Nanoclusters Regulated Charge Asymmetric Fe Dual Atomic Sites for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.70221</link>
      <description>Ying Lei, Jiaxin Li, Yi Cheng, Chuanlan Xu, Honglin Li, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413307023

                Comprehensive Summary Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) show attractive prospects for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), yet face challenges in precise charge modulation that balances the activity and durability. Herein, we present a N,S&#8208;coordinated Fe dual atomic catalyst modified by Fe 3 C nanoclusters (Fe 3 C/Fe 2 N x S) through pyrolyzing the mixtures of ZIF&#8208;8&#8208;encapsulated iron dimers and sulfur&#8208;doped C 3 N 4 . Aberration&#8208;corrected STEM and synchrotron X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) validated that the catalyst was composed of Fe dual atomic sites and Fe 3 C nanoclusters, in which Fe dual atoms were coordinated by five N atoms and one S atom. Fe 3 C/Fe 2 N x S exhibited excellent ORR activity in alkaline media, displaying a high half&#8208;wave potential ( E 1/2 = 0.894 V vs . RHE) with near 4e &#8211; selectivity ( n = 3.92) and maintaining 86.8% retention after 20000 s, superior to commercial Pt/C. Impressively, the assembled zinc&#8208;air battery delivered exceptional peak power density (163 mW&#183;cm &#8211;2 ) and 200&#8208;hour robust stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed that electron transfer from Fe of Fe 2 N x S to neighboring Fe 3 C induced local charge asymmetry, shifting the d&#8208;band center closer to Fermi level, thereby enhancing O 2 activation. Moreover, the OOH * formation energy barrier was reduced to 0.52 eV in Fe 3 C/Fe 2 N x S, accelerating ORR reaction kinetics. This work establishes nanocluster&#8208;mediated electronic redistribution to tailor charge asymmetry for high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Ying Lei, Jiaxin Li, Yi Cheng, Chuanlan Xu, Honglin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.70221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymorph-Induced Reducibility and Electron Trapping Energetics of Nb and W Dopants in TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04364</link>
      <description>A.K. Chaudhari, Andrew J. Logsdail, Andrea Folli, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413307261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A.K. Chaudhari, Andrew J. Logsdail, Andrea Folli</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Nuclearity Copper Molecular Catalysts for Electrocatalytic CO-to-Acetate Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08144</link>
      <description>Mohammad Bodiuzzaman, Lizhou Fan, M. Naveen, Yiqing Chen, Yushan Yan, Simil Thomas, Rui Kai Miao, Yurou Celine Xiao, Jinhong Wu, Roham Dorakhan, Mutalifu Abulikemu, Omar El Tall, David Sinton, Husam N. Alshareef, Omar F. Mohammed, Edward H. Sargent, Osman M. Bakr, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413317245

                Ligand-modified metal nanoclusters (NCs) have emerged as candidate materials for catalysis owing to their well-defined yet tunable structure and their metal centers' high nuclearity. We posited that NC-based catalytic behavior will depend on ligand properties, the accessibility of active sites, and their atomic configuration. We synthesized a series of Cu NC-based catalysts, tuned local hydrophobicity through ligand adjustment, balanced the ligand coverage and active site exposure, and found that we were, in this way, able to engender efficient electrosynthesis of acetate via CO electroreduction. Computation and operando spectroscopy show that asymmetric Cu-Cu sites, which determine the CO binding strength, impact the bifurcation step after C-C coupling. The best of these catalysts, Cu13Nap, achieved an acetate Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 86% and an energy efficiency of 29% in a 5 bar system, exceeding the single C2+ FE of &lt;50% previously achieved by NC-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Bodiuzzaman, Lizhou Fan, M. Naveen, Yiqing Chen, Yushan Yan, Simil Thomas, Rui Kai Miao, Yurou Celine Xiao, Jinhong Wu, Roham Dorakhan, Mutalifu Abulikemu, Omar El Tall, David Sinton, Husam N. Alshareef, Omar F. Mohammed, Edward H. Sargent, Osman M. Bakr</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interaction strength of carbon dioxide on graphene from periodic quantum diffusion Monte Carlo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0283254</link>
      <description>Flaviano Della Pia, Giaan Kler-Young, Andrea Zen, Fabian Berger, Dario Alf&#232;, Angelos Michaelides, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413318216

                Despite the importance of graphene based carbon capture devices, an accurate estimate of the interaction strength of a carbon dioxide molecule with graphene from periodic calculations is lacking. In this work, we compute a fixed node quantum diffusion Monte Carlo reference value for the interaction energy of a carbon dioxide molecule with a periodic free-standing graphene sheet, obtaining a value of -152 &#177; 15 meV. In addition, we evaluate the performance of several widely used density functional theory approximations and foundation machine learning interatomic potentials, for both carbon dioxide and water adsorption on graphene, competitive processes that play an important role in carbon capture technologies. Among the approaches tested, the B86bPBE-XDM, PBE-D3, revPBE-D3, rev-vdW-DF2, SCAN+rVV10, and PBE0-D3-ATM functionals achieve the closest agreement with DMC for the carbon dioxide-graphene interaction. The vdW-DF2, rev-vdW-DF2, and PBE0-D4-ATM functionals perform better for the competitive adsorption of water and carbon dioxide.</description>
      <author>Flaviano Della Pia, Giaan Kler-Young, Andrea Zen, Fabian Berger, Dario Alf&#232;, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0283254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of curvature and spin exchange in electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction on Co2@N6CNTs catalysts: A grand canonical density functional theory simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115422</link>
      <description>Ming Chen, Zhi-rui Luo, Dahu Lin, Liping Han, Wen&#8208;Xian Chen, Gui&#8208;Lin Zhuang, Molecular Catalysis. 586(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413324997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming Chen, Zhi-rui Luo, Dahu Lin, Liping Han, Wen&#8208;Xian Chen, Gui&#8208;Lin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Janus silicon-based pentagonal monolayers for enhanced photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150901</link>
      <description>Chenghao Yang, Yanqing Shen, Kexin Wang, Yu Zhang, Xiangqian Jiang, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 167(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413326105

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenghao Yang, Yanqing Shen, Kexin Wang, Yu Zhang, Xiangqian Jiang, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-metal single atoms anchored on defective MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: a novel electrocatalyst for NO reduction to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra04718h</link>
      <description>Yifan Liu, Mamutjan Tursun, Guangzhi Hu, Abdukader Abdukayum, Chao Wu, RSC Advances. 15(36)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413327714

                The eNORR performance of the MoS 2 catalyst doped with non-metal atoms has been studied. The Si, C, N, B, and P@MoS 2 catalysts demonstrated great potential for eNORR. The Si, C, and B@MoS 2 catalysts inhibited the formation of byproducts and HER.</description>
      <author>Yifan Liu, Mamutjan Tursun, Guangzhi Hu, Abdukader Abdukayum, Chao Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra04718h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Barrier: How Alkali Cations Promote Enhanced N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Adsorption and *NNH Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04857</link>
      <description>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413334168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review on the Applications of &#8220;Catalysis Under 2D-Cover&#8221; for Small Molecule Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41745-025-00481-9</link>
      <description>Athira Jayasankar, Sooraj Kunnikuruvan, Journal of the Indian Institute of Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413334433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Athira Jayasankar, Sooraj Kunnikuruvan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41745-025-00481-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of the Current Status of Global Electric Vehicle Charging Infrastructure Development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5379356</link>
      <description>Zhi&#8208;Yun Li, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413193038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhi&#8208;Yun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5379356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilized ionic liquids/deep eutectic solvents in carbon capture: current progress and future potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-025-03276-9</link>
      <description>Sahar Foorginezhad, Xiaoyan Ji, Clean Technologies and Environmental Policy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413269547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sahar Foorginezhad, Xiaoyan Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-025-03276-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Aluminum Doping in Enhancing High-Temperature Stability of Lithium-Rich Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5397423</link>
      <description>Min&#8208;Ho Kim, Aditya Narayan Singh, Miran Ha, Wang&#8208;Geun Lee, Saeed Pourasad, Abhishek Meena, Haeseong Jang, Jeongwoo Seo, Jaehyun Park, Seok Ju Kang, Kyung&#8208;Wan Nam, Tae Joo Shin, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Kwang S. Kim, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413324865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min&#8208;Ho Kim, Aditya Narayan Singh, Miran Ha, Wang&#8208;Geun Lee, Saeed Pourasad, Abhishek Meena, Haeseong Jang, Jeongwoo Seo, Jaehyun Park, Seok Ju Kang, Kyung&#8208;Wan Nam, Tae Joo Shin, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Kwang S. Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5397423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Role of the Electrical Double Layer in Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03725</link>
      <description>Alex J. King, Justin C. Bui, Adam Z. Weber, Alexis T. Bell, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413120355

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alex J. King, Justin C. Bui, Adam Z. Weber, Alexis T. Bell</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03725</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
