<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:25:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Machine Learning&#8208;Assisted Multiscale Design of Energy Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403876</link>
      <description>Bohayra Mortazavi, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405257673

                Abstract This review highlights recent advances in machine learning (ML)&#8208;assisted design of energy materials. Initially, ML algorithms were successfully applied to screen materials databases by establishing complex relationships between atomic structures and their resulting properties, thus accelerating the identification of candidates with desirable properties. Recently, the development of highly accurate ML interatomic potentials and generative models has not only improved the robust prediction of physical properties, but also significantly accelerated the discovery of materials. In the past couple of years, ML methods have enabled high&#8208;precision first&#8208;principles predictions of electronic and optical properties for large systems, providing unprecedented opportunities in materials science. Furthermore, ML&#8208;assisted microstructure reconstruction and physics&#8208;informed solutions for partial differential equations have facilitated the understanding of microstructure&#8211;property relationships. Most recently, the seamless integration of various ML platforms has led to the emergence of autonomous laboratories that combine quantum mechanical calculations, large language models, and experimental validations, fundamentally transforming the traditional approach to novel materials synthesis. While highlighting the aforementioned recent advances, existing challenges are also discussed. Ultimately, ML is expected to fully integrate atomic&#8208;scale simulations, reverse engineering, process optimization, and device fabrication, empowering autonomous and generative energy system design. This will drive transformative innovations in energy conversion, storage, and harvesting technologies.</description>
      <author>Bohayra Mortazavi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coaxial Metal&#8208;Nitrogen&#8211;Carbon Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts Boost Acid Hydrogen Peroxide Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419220</link>
      <description>Hongshang Hu, Chang Zhang, Shiyuan Liu, Hangyu Qi, Haoyu Wang, Xinyu Wang, Lilong Zhang, Lei Liu, Lipiao Bao, Muneerah Alomar, Jian Zhang, Xing L&#252;, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405258100

                Abstract Electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) by two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e &#8722; ORR) under acidic conditions is promising. However, constructing a highly efficient acid&#8208;resistant 2e &#8722; ORR electrocatalyst is critical but challenging. Herein, a coaxial cobalt single&#8208;atom catalyst on carbon nanotubes (Co SA &#8208;N&#8208;C/CNTs) is designed and synthesized by an ingenious separation chemical vapor deposition (SCVD) strategy, which achieves higher ORR activity, dominated 2e &#8722; selectivity, and superior stability in acid, compared to the counterpart nanoparticle catalyst prepared by traditional mixture pyrolysis. The as&#8208;assembled electrode using Co SA &#8208;N&#8208;C/CNTs catalyst demonstrates a high H 2 O 2 yield in excess of 2000 mmol g cat &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 with a Faraday efficiency of &gt;90% over 100 h without decay in a flow cell, as superior to the most reported acidic H 2 O 2 production catalysts. Experimental characterization and theoretical calculations reveal that such excellent 2e &#8722; ORR performance of Co SA &#8208;N&#8208;C/CNTs originate from the combined advantages of strongly coupled coaxial core&#8211;shell structure and highly dispersed single&#8208;atom property. Most importantly, a series of other coaxial transition metal single&#8208;atom catalysts (M SA &#8208;N&#8208;C/CNTs, M = Fe, Cu, or Ni) are prepared through this SCVD strategy, and they all show enhanced ORR performance, demonstrating universality.</description>
      <author>Hongshang Hu, Chang Zhang, Shiyuan Liu, Hangyu Qi, Haoyu Wang, Xinyu Wang, Lilong Zhang, Lei Liu, Lipiao Bao, Muneerah Alomar, Jian Zhang, Xing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive Review based on the synthesis, properties, morphology, functionalization, and potential applications of transition metals nitrides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216353</link>
      <description>Hamid Ali, Yasin Orooji, Zeeshan Ajmal, Mohamed Abboud, Ahmed M. Abu&#8208;Dief, Khulood A. Abu Al&#8208;Ola, Hassan M.A. Hassan, Dewu Yue, Shengrong Guo, Asif Hayat, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 526(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405266578

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hamid Ali, Yasin Orooji, Zeeshan Ajmal, Mohamed Abboud, Ahmed M. Abu&#8208;Dief, Khulood A. Abu Al&#8208;Ola, Hassan M.A. Hassan, Dewu Yue, Shengrong Guo, Asif Hayat</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkene Epoxidation and Oxygen Evolution Reactions Compete for Reactive Surface Oxygen Atoms on Gold Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08948</link>
      <description>Richa Ghosh, Geoffrey M. Hopping, Jiong Lu, Drew W. Hollyfield, David W. Flaherty, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274268

                Rates and selectivities for the partial oxidation of organic molecules on reactive electrodes depend on the identity and prevalence of reactive and spectator species. Here, we investigate the mechanism for the epoxidation of 1-hexene (C</description>
      <author>Richa Ghosh, Geoffrey M. Hopping, Jiong Lu, Drew W. Hollyfield, David W. Flaherty</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Polymerization Electrospinning of Amine&#8211;Epoxy/Poly(vinyl alcohol) Nanofiber Webs for Direct CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture from the Air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07631</link>
      <description>Chisato Okada, Zongzi Hou, Hiroaki Imoto, Kensuke Naka, Takeshi Kikutani, Midori Takasaki, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405277088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chisato Okada, Zongzi Hou, Hiroaki Imoto, Kensuke Naka, Takeshi Kikutani, Midori Takasaki</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond conventional structures: emerging complex metal oxides for efficient oxygen and hydrogen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01020a</link>
      <description>Yinlong Zhu, Zheng Tang, Ling Yuan, Bowen Li, Zongping Shao, Wanlin Guo, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405281726

                The core of clean energy technologies such as fuel cells, water electrolyzers, and metal-air batteries depends on a series of oxygen and hydrogen-based electrocatalysis reactions, including the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), which necessitate cost-effective electrocatalysts to improve their energy efficiency. In the recent decade, complex metal oxides (beyond simple transition metal oxides, spinel oxides and ABO</description>
      <author>Yinlong Zhu, Zheng Tang, Ling Yuan, Bowen Li, Zongping Shao, Wanlin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01020a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable machine learning for chiral induced symmetry breaking of spin density boosting hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.066</link>
      <description>Xin Song, Zhonghua Li, Sheng Li, Yang Liu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405283541

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Song, Zhonghua Li, Sheng Li, Yang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the scales within transport-coupled kinetic models for heterogeneous electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101631</link>
      <description>Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Hendrik H. Heenen, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa J. Bukas, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405286845

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Hendrik H. Heenen, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa J. Bukas</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bismuth mediated tuning of electronic structure and enhanced adhesion in molybdenum based bifunctional catalysts for efficient water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131037</link>
      <description>Junzi Huang, Weitao Han, Li Liang, Bingbing Gong, Lin He, Wei Peng, Yahong Xie, Yi Zhang, Zhiyu Wang, Ying Qi, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405286921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junzi Huang, Weitao Han, Li Liang, Bingbing Gong, Lin He, Wei Peng, Yahong Xie, Yi Zhang, Zhiyu Wang, Ying Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Design of Dual-Site Metallo-Covalent Organic Frameworks for Efficient CO2 Photoreduction into C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124933</link>
      <description>K.M Chen, Wei Wang, Yuqi Dong, Zhihao Zhao, Ying Zang, Guiling Zhang, Yang Liu, Fengming Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405287328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K.M Chen, Wei Wang, Yuqi Dong, Zhihao Zhao, Ying Zang, Guiling Zhang, Yang Liu, Fengming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled deposition of trimetallic Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;V oxides on nickel foam as high-performance electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.044</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ali Ehsan, Rashida Batool, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Sameer Ali, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Zaka Ullah, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405318518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ali Ehsan, Rashida Batool, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Sameer Ali, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Zaka Ullah</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Composite Infrared Spectroscopy: Combining the Double-Harmonic Approximation with Machine Learning Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01157</link>
      <description>Philipp Pracht, Yuthika Pillai, Venkat Kapil, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Nils G&#246;nnheimer, Martin Vondr&#225;k, Johannes T. Margraf, David J. Wales, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405319422

                Vibrational spectroscopy is a cornerstone technique for molecular characterization and offers an ideal target for the computational investigation of molecular materials. Building on previous comprehensive assessments of efficient methods for infrared (IR) spectroscopy, this study investigates the predictive accuracy and computational efficiency of gas-phase IR spectra calculations, accessible through a combination of modern semiempirical quantum mechanical and transferable machine learning potentials. A composite approach for IR spectra prediction based on the double-harmonic approximation, utilizing harmonic vibrational frequencies in combination squared derivatives of the molecular dipole moment, is employed. This approach allows for methodical flexibility in the calculation of IR intensities from molecular dipoles and the corresponding vibrational modes. Various methods are systematically tested to suggest a suitable protocol with an emphasis on computational efficiency. Among these methods, semiempirical extended tight-binding (xTB) models, classical charge equilibrium models, and machine learning potentials trained for dipole moment prediction are assessed across a diverse data set of organic molecules. We particularly focus on the recently reported foundational machine learning potential MACE-OFF23 to address the accuracy limitations of conventional low-cost quantum mechanical and force-field methods. This study aims to establish a standard for the efficient computational prediction of IR spectra, facilitating the rapid and reliable identification of unknown compounds and advancing automated high-throughput analytical workflows in chemistry.</description>
      <author>Philipp Pracht, Yuthika Pillai, Venkat Kapil, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Nils G&#246;nnheimer, Martin Vondr&#225;k, Johannes T. Margraf, David J. Wales</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDF CO2 Lab: A New Facility to Advance CO2 Capture from Flue Gases and Ambient Air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5019579</link>
      <description>Nicolas Jourdan, Antony Vanheghe, Serena Delgado, Christophe Castel, &#201;ric Favre, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405323199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicolas Jourdan, Antony Vanheghe, Serena Delgado, Christophe Castel, &#201;ric Favre</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5019579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal atom supported on N-terminated diamond (100) surface as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution and reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242133</link>
      <description>Gaoxian Li, Yuanhang Wang, Nan Gao, Hongdong Li, Applied Physics Letters. 125(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405323235

                To alleviate the increasingly serious energy issues, it is essential to develop highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we employed density functional theory to investigate a broad spectrum of transition metal (TM = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Y, Zr, Mo, Ru, Rh, Ag, W, Ir, and Pt) atoms supported on N-terminated diamond (100) surface (TM@ND) as single-atom catalysts for their OER and ORR performances. TM atoms (Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Y, Zr, and Ir) show large binding energy with substrate and thermal stability, which is advantageous for electrocatalytic reactions. Especially, Ir@ND demonstrates high efficacy as an OER electrocatalyst, and Mn@ND is identified as an efficient ORR electrocatalyst, exhibiting the theoretical overpotentials smaller than 1 V. Consequently, it suggests that diamond-based catalysts could serve as promising candidates for energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Gaoxian Li, Yuanhang Wang, Nan Gao, Hongdong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cathode-mediated electrochemical conversion of phenol to benzoquinone in wastewater: High yield rate and low energy consumption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.122967</link>
      <description>Zonglin Li, Zhiyuan Feng, Min Chen, Yankai Song, Yongkang Dai, Shun Mao, Hongying Zhao, Water Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405338488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zonglin Li, Zhiyuan Feng, Min Chen, Yankai Song, Yongkang Dai, Shun Mao, Hongying Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.122967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Based Materials for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch8</link>
      <description>Congli Qin, Aixin Fan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405357959

                Rational design and development of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts with high activity, high stability, and high toxicity resistance is the key to promoting the commercialization and large-scale application of fuel cells. The main purpose of this chapter is to provide a comprehensive overview of the latest strategies and developments in metal-based materials for ORR from both theoretical and experimental perspectives, especially the Pt-based catalysts with excellent ORR activity are summarized, including structural design, surface modification, size regulation, electron configurations modulation, and lattice facets modulation. In addition, the synthesis strategy, relationship between structure and performance, and catalytic mechanism of the latest Pt-based metal catalyst for ORR are systematically discussed. Finally, the opportunities and challenges of metal-based catalysts in electrocatalytic ORR are proposed.</description>
      <author>Congli Qin, Aixin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Reaction Mechanism for Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch3</link>
      <description>Hao Ma, Yuanmiao Sun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405358246

                Electrocatalysis holds paramount significance in driving the progress of sustainable energy technologies, such as fuel cells, water electrolyzers, and batteries. The presence of various species on the electrode surface, such as reactants, intermediates, and products during electrocatalysis' usually gives rise to complex reaction pathways. A systematic understanding of various electrocatalytic processes in chemical reactions is required to untangle the complicated interaction of species on the catalyst's surface and their influence on the electrocatalytic process. Taking hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), and nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) as examples, this chapter introduces electrocatalytic mechanisms, feasible reaction pathways, and fundamental concepts to readers and stimulates their interest in the various fields of electrocatalysts and their applications.</description>
      <author>Hao Ma, Yuanmiao Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory for Electrocatalytic Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch2</link>
      <description>Wei Li, Yi Ding, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405358277

                Electrocatalytic technology plays an important role in advancing green and sustainable energy. Various significant electrocatalytic reactions, such as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR), have huge potential in green energy conversion. However, the conversion efficiency is limited by slow kinetic processes and high reaction overpotentials. Therefore, the development of electrocatalysts with high catalytic activity and selectivity is of paramount importance. Based on density functional theory (DFT), theoretical calculations can not only analyze the electrocatalytic reaction processes from the perspective of molecular structure and energy but also provide an in-depth understanding of the electronic structures of the catalysts and establish the structure&#8211;activity relationships between catalysts and electrocatalytic reactions. Thus, DFT calculations can offer theoretical basis and guidance for the design and preparation of efficient electrocatalysts. In this chapter, we will introduce some DFT calculation methods and several electrocatalytic reactions, aiming to help readers understand how DFT calculations are applied to electrocatalytic energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Wei Li, Yi Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the Electronic Structure and Spin State of Iron-based metal-organic frameworks for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.125144</link>
      <description>Dongyu Gu, Yue Yao, Xin Zhang, Yuanjing Cui, Guodong Qian, Journal of Solid State Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405364412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongyu Gu, Yue Yao, Xin Zhang, Yuanjing Cui, Guodong Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.125144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering atomic Pt-N3 sites on CdS nanorods for overcoming the rate-determining organic dehydrogenation in photocatalytic coproduction of H2 and value-added chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158618</link>
      <description>Huanmin Liu, Jiayi Peng, Shouxin Zhang, Kun Zheng, Lirong Zheng, Kangle Lv, Qin Li, Peng Zhou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405365290

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huanmin Liu, Jiayi Peng, Shouxin Zhang, Kun Zheng, Lirong Zheng, Kangle Lv, Qin Li, Peng Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CatTestHub: A benchmarking database of experimental heterogeneous catalysis for evaluating advanced materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115902</link>
      <description>Atharva S. Burte, Advaith Nair, Lars C. Grabow, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Susannah L. Scott, Omar Abdelrahman, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405365777

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Atharva S. Burte, Advaith Nair, Lars C. Grabow, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Susannah L. Scott, Omar Abdelrahman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115902</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantity effect of heteroatom incorporation on the oxygen evolution mechanism in ruthenium oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chempr.2024.11.005</link>
      <description>Hyunwoo Jun, Eunseo Kang, Jinuk Moon, Hoyoung Kim, Sunghoon Han, Seokhyun Choung, Seongbeen Kim, Seung Yeop Yi, Eunae Kang, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jeong Woo Han, Jinwoo Lee, Chem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405367030

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyunwoo Jun, Eunseo Kang, Jinuk Moon, Hoyoung Kim, Sunghoon Han, Seokhyun Choung, Seongbeen Kim, Seung Yeop Yi, Eunae Kang, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jeong Woo Han, Jinwoo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chempr.2024.11.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron-activated ruthenium nanoparticles for hydrogen oxidation reaction in anion exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101197</link>
      <description>Yingdan Cui, Yian Wang, Fei Yang, Weiwei Chen, Guimei Liu, Shangqian Zhu, Xiaoyi Qiu, Fei Xiao, Guanghao Chen, Yanzhi Sun, Mohammad Farhadpour, Dong Su, William E. Mustain, Yoonseob Kim, Minhua Shao, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405367200

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingdan Cui, Yian Wang, Fei Yang, Weiwei Chen, Guimei Liu, Shangqian Zhu, Xiaoyi Qiu, Fei Xiao, Guanghao Chen, Yanzhi Sun, Mohammad Farhadpour, Dong Su, William E. Mustain, Yoonseob Kim, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A bifunctional electrolyser for energy-efficient hydrogen generation and synchronous HCHO degradation: Influences of H and HCHO adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.165</link>
      <description>Hanming Zhang, Yuan Chen, Yiran Teng, Gangya Cheng, Chengyue Han, Tongguang Xu, Fei Teng, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405372312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hanming Zhang, Yuan Chen, Yiran Teng, Gangya Cheng, Chengyue Han, Tongguang Xu, Fei Teng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental understanding of fluorophenol-derived dual organocatalysts for ring-opening polymerization of lactide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04115a</link>
      <description>Guo Fengzhen, Jiawen Dai, Shaoju Cao, Yaling Yin, Zhenjiang Li, Jie Sun, Jin Huang, Kai Guo, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405374566

                The integral investigation on metal-free catalytic ring-opening polymerization of lactide facilitates the structural understanding of the reaction.</description>
      <author>Guo Fengzhen, Jiawen Dai, Shaoju Cao, Yaling Yin, Zhenjiang Li, Jie Sun, Jin Huang, Kai Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04115a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anionic Oxidation Activity/Stability Regulated by Transition Metals in Multimetallic (Oxy)hydroxides for Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03718</link>
      <description>Shuhao Wang, Kamran Dastafkan, Sicheng Wu, Qian Sun, Chengli Rong, Dazhi Yao, Chuan Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405378470

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuhao Wang, Kamran Dastafkan, Sicheng Wu, Qian Sun, Chengli Rong, Dazhi Yao, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Sn/SnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Mott&#8211;Schottky Heterojunction on Biomass-Derived Carbon Boosting Highly Selective and Robust Formate Production for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07981</link>
      <description>Tiyao Ren, Yan Zheng, Ruikuan Xie, Guoliang Chai, Dong Xia, Huan Xie, Changlei Xia, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405378518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tiyao Ren, Yan Zheng, Ruikuan Xie, Guoliang Chai, Dong Xia, Huan Xie, Changlei Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First Principles exploration of pristine and p-block doped triangulene carbon dots for Hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114766</link>
      <description>Ashvin Kanzariya, Narayan N. Som, Shardul Vadalkar, Sourav Kanti Jana, L. K. Saini, Prafulla K. Jha, Molecular Catalysis. 572(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405386249

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashvin Kanzariya, Narayan N. Som, Shardul Vadalkar, Sourav Kanti Jana, L. K. Saini, Prafulla K. Jha</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Machine learning and active motifs-based catalyst design for discovery of oxygen reduction electrocatalysts for hydrogen peroxide production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115906</link>
      <description>G. Yu, Dong Hyeon Mok, Ho Yeon Jang, Hyun Dong Jung, Samira Siahrostami, Seoin Back, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405394547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. Yu, Dong Hyeon Mok, Ho Yeon Jang, Hyun Dong Jung, Samira Siahrostami, Seoin Back</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascade protection strategy for anchoring atomic FeN3 sites within defect-rich wood carbon aerogel for high-performance Zn-air batteries and versatile application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158551</link>
      <description>Jiaojiao Sun, Mengxia Shen, A. C. Chang, Chanjuan Liang, Chuanyin Xiong, Chen Hou, Jinbao Li, Pengbo Wang, Jiayin Li, Jianfeng Huang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405395385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaojiao Sun, Mengxia Shen, A. C. Chang, Chanjuan Liang, Chuanyin Xiong, Chen Hou, Jinbao Li, Pengbo Wang, Jiayin Li, Jianfeng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A FIB-TEM study on evolution of passive film during deactivation processes of Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145528</link>
      <description>Mingshuai Guo, Likun Xu, Yonglei Xin, Lili Xue, Tigang Duan, Rongrong Zhao, Penghe Liu, Shuai Zhou, Li Li, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405409001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingshuai Guo, Likun Xu, Yonglei Xin, Lili Xue, Tigang Duan, Rongrong Zhao, Penghe Liu, Shuai Zhou, Li Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8210;organic framework/graphene-based nanocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction: A comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.132</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ahmad Mudassir, Zainab Tazeen, Shazia Kousar, Muhan Li, Xiaoyu Zhao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405409464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ahmad Mudassir, Zainab Tazeen, Shazia Kousar, Muhan Li, Xiaoyu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the interaction of Ta atoms with Pt(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105640</link>
      <description>Kevin Bertrang, Tobias Hinke, Sebastian Kaiser, Matthias Knechtges, Federico Loi, Luca Sbuelz, Paolo Lacovig, Luca Bignardi, Friedrich Esch, Alessandro Baraldi, Sergio Tosoni, Aras Kartouzian, Ueli Heiz, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405418537

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kevin Bertrang, Tobias Hinke, Sebastian Kaiser, Matthias Knechtges, Federico Loi, Luca Sbuelz, Paolo Lacovig, Luca Bignardi, Friedrich Esch, Alessandro Baraldi, Sergio Tosoni, Aras Kartouzian, Ueli Heiz</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elevating CO2 selective conversion: Insights into copper-based single atom alloy catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-024-01105-z</link>
      <description>Di Tian, Zefeng Wang, Zhou Xu, Zhu Yi-quan, Yan Yan, Jifeng Yang, Siyuan He, Zhichao Xue, Li Wang, Shuo Li, Wenxuan Fan, Miaomiao Xue, Zehua Qu, Wei Xia, Mingkai Liu, Advanced Composites and Hybrid Materials. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405421670

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Di Tian, Zefeng Wang, Zhou Xu, Zhu Yi-quan, Yan Yan, Jifeng Yang, Siyuan He, Zhichao Xue, Li Wang, Shuo Li, Wenxuan Fan, Miaomiao Xue, Zehua Qu, Wei Xia, Mingkai Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-024-01105-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;CoTCNQ&lt;/scp&gt; as a Catalyst for &lt;scp&gt;CO&lt;/scp&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction: A First Principles r&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;scp&gt;SCAN&lt;/scp&gt; Meta&#8208;&lt;scp&gt;GGA&lt;/scp&gt; Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27528</link>
      <description>Oliver J. Conquest, Yijiao Jiang, Catherine Stampfl, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405424833

                ABSTRACT Using first principles calculations we investigate cobalt&#8208;coordinated tetracyanoquinodimethane (R&#8208;CoTCNQ) as a potential catalyst for the CO 2 electroreduction reaction (CO 2 ERR). We determine that exchange&#8211;correlation functionals beyond the generalized gradient approximation (GGA) are required to accurately describe the spin properties of R&#8208;CoTCNQ, therefore, the meta&#8208;GGA r 2 SCAN functional is used in this study. The free energy CO 2 ERR reaction pathways are calculated for the reduced catalyst ([R&#8208;CoTCNQ] &#8722;1 e ) with reaction products HCOOH and HCHO predicted depending on our choice of electrode potential. Calculations are also performed for [R&#8208;CoTCNQ] &#8722;1 e supported on a H&#8208;terminated diamond (1 1 0) surface with reaction pathways being qualitatively similar to the [R&#8208;CoTCNQ] &#8722;1 e monolayer. The inclusion of boron&#8208;doping in the diamond support shows a slightly improved CO 2 ERR reaction pathway. Furthermore, structurally, supported R&#8208;CoTCNQ provide a high specific area of active Co active sites and could be promising catalysts for future experimental consideration.</description>
      <author>Oliver J. Conquest, Yijiao Jiang, Catherine Stampfl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep eutectic solvent-derived carbon-based FeNi bimetallic catalysts for selective hydrogenation of furfural</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158676</link>
      <description>Siyi Pu, Zhouxiao Zhai, Chunyan Yang, Zirui Dao, Wei Yan, Changfu Zhuang, Chungang Min, Jie Zhao, Ying Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405430033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siyi Pu, Zhouxiao Zhai, Chunyan Yang, Zirui Dao, Wei Yan, Changfu Zhuang, Chungang Min, Jie Zhao, Ying Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 capture using Resin-Based solid Amines: Characteristic, Application, regeneration and deactivation mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131125</link>
      <description>Endian Hu, Li Lin, Kailun Chen, Jinglin Li, Yuchen Gao, Jingwen Chang, Weikai Qin, Yukun Zhao, Jianguo Jiang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405436896

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Endian Hu, Li Lin, Kailun Chen, Jinglin Li, Yuchen Gao, Jingwen Chang, Weikai Qin, Yukun Zhao, Jianguo Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial Growth of Atomic-Layer Cu on Pd Nanocatalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02541</link>
      <description>Shikai Liu, Chuqiao Shi, Chaokai Xu, Haichuan Zhang, Wenqi Li, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Qian He, Yimo Han, Yao Yang, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405437565

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shikai Liu, Chuqiao Shi, Chaokai Xu, Haichuan Zhang, Wenqi Li, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Qian He, Yimo Han, Yao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Activity and Stability through Compositional Engineering of Ternary PtNi&#8211;Au Alloy ORR Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05269</link>
      <description>Xianxian Xie, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Pere Alemany, Athira Lekshmi Mohandas Sandhya, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Milan Dopita, Michael Vorochta, Albert Bruix, Serhiy Cherevko, Konstantin M. Neyman, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Ivan Khalakhan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405439103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianxian Xie, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Pere Alemany, Athira Lekshmi Mohandas Sandhya, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Milan Dopita, Michael Vorochta, Albert Bruix, Serhiy Cherevko, Konstantin M. Neyman, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Ivan Khalakhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Modulated by B-Doped Cu Promotes Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction for Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05954</link>
      <description>Jia-Jia Wang, Zhuodong Ou, Chenglin Dong, Mengying Su, Amjad Ali, Artem V. Kuklin, Hans &#197;gren, Glib Baryshnikov, Yang Liu, Xue Zhao, Haibo Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443274

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia-Jia Wang, Zhuodong Ou, Chenglin Dong, Mengying Su, Amjad Ali, Artem V. Kuklin, Hans &#197;gren, Glib Baryshnikov, Yang Liu, Xue Zhao, Haibo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Computer-Aided Review of Trends in Heterogeneous Catalysis and Its Theoretical Modelling for Engineering Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00219592.2024.2360928</link>
      <description>Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Kaoru Hisama, Michihisa Koyama, JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL ENGINEERING OF JAPAN. 57(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443753

                Writing scientific literature reviews is highly challenging, especially for broad topics like "heterogeneous catalysis" due to the explosion of knowledge. In this article, we introduce a machine-assisted approach aimed to facilitating this process. It integrates an automated summarization of several sources into the conventional method of writing a literature review. Our approach represents an initial trial to compile recent trends in heterogeneous catalysis. We chose the topic of heterogeneous catalysis due to its significance in various industrial processes and its multidisciplinary nature, which makes reviewing it challenging. The review highlights the pursuit of more advanced and complex catalysts to enhance catalytic performance. These advances significantly influence chemical reaction engineering, which combines reaction chemistry and chemical engineering. The trend of developing complex catalysts faces feasibility challenges, underscoring the importance of balancing practicality and potential benefits. In this interplay, the role of atomistic understanding becomes more important as it provides insights into the fundamental mechanisms governing catalyst behavior. Therefore, this review also covers advances in computational studies, particularly density functional theory calculations and the incorporation of new techniques. The wide scope of knowledge presented in this initial trial will facilitate further development in the field of chemical reaction engineering.</description>
      <author>Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Kaoru Hisama, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00219592.2024.2360928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum transport study of transition-metal dichalcogenide top-contacted geometries investigating the impact of nonuniform doping, dielectric environment, and image-force barrier lowering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.22.064058</link>
      <description>Pranay Baikadi, William G. Vandenberghe, Peter D. Reyntjens, Raseong Kim, Maarten L. Van de Put, Physical Review Applied. 22(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443859

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pranay Baikadi, William G. Vandenberghe, Peter D. Reyntjens, Raseong Kim, Maarten L. Van de Put</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.22.064058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Properties of Nanoporous Graphenes: Transferability of Graph Machine&#8208;Learned Force Fields Compared to Local and Reactive Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417891</link>
      <description>Adil M. Kabylda, Bohayra Mortazavi, Xiaoying Zhuang, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405456044

                Abstract Nanoporous and chemically&#8208;bridged graphene nanosheets span a wide chemical space with a broad set of applications in sensing and electronics. Modeling the structure and dynamics of such nanosheets is challenging, as chemical bond making and breaking as well as non&#8208;covalent interactions must be captured accurately and on equal footing. Here it is showed that recent graph&#8208;based machine&#8208;learned force field (MLFF) SO3krates [J. T. Frank et al. , Nat. Commun. 15 , 6539 (2024)] is able to reliably model the dynamics and mechanical response for a broad class of nanoporous graphenes when trained on accurate density functional theory data that includes long&#8208;range many&#8208;body dispersion (MBD) interactions. In contrast, local moment tensor potentials and empirical reactive potentials are much less accurate. It is also found that recent MLFFs trained on solid&#8208;state datasets must be used with care, since even empirical potentials occasionally yield more accurate results. These findings highlight the potential of properly&#8208;trained graph MLFFs in modeling the properties of whole chemical spaces of complex functional materials.</description>
      <author>Adil M. Kabylda, Bohayra Mortazavi, Xiaoying Zhuang, Alexandre Tkatchenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-Learning-Enabled Thermochemistry Estimator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00989</link>
      <description>Tianjun Xie, Gerhard R. Wittreich, Matthew T. Curnan, Geun Ho Gu, Kevin Seals, Justin S. Tolbert, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405457459

                Modeling adsorbates on single-crystal metals is critical in rational catalyst design and other research that requires detailed thermochemistry. First-principles simulations via density functional theory (DFT) are among the prevalent tools to acquire such information about surface species. While they are highly dependable, DFT calculations often require intensive computational resources and runtime. These limiting factors become particularly pronounced when investigating large sets of complex molecules on heavy noble metals. Consequently, our ability to explore these species and their corresponding energetics is limited. In this work, we establish a novel framework that utilizes techniques including molecular encoding, descriptor synthesis, and machine learning to overcome the limitation of costly DFT simulations. Simultaneously, we estimate thermochemical information efficiently at the DFT accuracy level. More specifically, we translated our training molecules into text-based identifiers through a simplified molecular-input line-entry system. Following that, we parametrize our training matrices with sets of short-range descriptors based on group methods, applying first the nearest neighbors to account for linear contributions. This is coupled with the long-range descriptors characterizing second nearest neighbors to account for nonlinear corrections. Finally, we use linear regression and machine learning techniques, such as Gaussian process regressions to regress over the linear and nonlinear matrix systems, respectively. This is the first work to our knowledge that encompasses both the first and second nearest neighbors based on the group theory throughout the featurization, training, and deployment stages. We trained and validated our models with 459 surface species on Pt(111), Ru(0001), and Ir(111) surfaces. Results exhibit robust performance to reproduce the energetics of interest, such as enthalpies, entropies, and heat capacities, at various temperatures. Notably, the mean absolute errors can be reduced by 48% during training and 19% during prediction at a minimum, when compared to the classical group method. Leveraging the novel framework, our machine-learning-enabled thermochemistry estimator significantly empowers us to research the thermochemistry of complex species on metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tianjun Xie, Gerhard R. Wittreich, Matthew T. Curnan, Geun Ho Gu, Kevin Seals, Justin S. Tolbert</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unavoidable Silicon Oxidation&#8212;the Key to Understanding the High Catalytic Activity of Si,N-Doped Carbon Nanotubes in Oxygen Electroreduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s107036322411015x</link>
      <description>Anton V. Kuzmin, Bagrat A. Shainyan, Russian Journal of General Chemistry. 94(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405461357

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anton V. Kuzmin, Bagrat A. Shainyan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s107036322411015x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically precise MOF-Based electrocatalysts by design: Hydrogen evolution applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134021</link>
      <description>Aneeqa Areeb Amjad, Maida Murtaza, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, Iftikhar Ahmad, Hussain Alawadhi, Waqas Ali Shah, Amir Waseem, Fuel. 385(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405463967

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aneeqa Areeb Amjad, Maida Murtaza, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, Iftikhar Ahmad, Hussain Alawadhi, Waqas Ali Shah, Amir Waseem</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Electrochemical Oxidation and Reduction of Nickel Oxide Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13187</link>
      <description>Wenyu Sun, Nitish Govindarajan, Aditya Prajapati, Jiayi Huang, Hossein Bemana, Jeremy T. Feaster, Sneha A. Akhade, Nikolay Kornienko, Christopher Hahn, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405465554

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenyu Sun, Nitish Govindarajan, Aditya Prajapati, Jiayi Huang, Hossein Bemana, Jeremy T. Feaster, Sneha A. Akhade, Nikolay Kornienko, Christopher Hahn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Poisoning of CN&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07363</link>
      <description>A. S. RAO, Vance Gustin, Jonathan Hightower, Seval G&#252;nd&#252;z, Dishari Basu, Yehia Khalifa, Anant Sohale, Anne C. Co, Aravind Asthagiri, Umit S. Ozkan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405474872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. S. RAO, Vance Gustin, Jonathan Hightower, Seval G&#252;nd&#252;z, Dishari Basu, Yehia Khalifa, Anant Sohale, Anne C. Co, Aravind Asthagiri, Umit S. Ozkan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Synergistic Role of Sm&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;3+&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Doped NiFe&#8208;LDH as High&#8208;Performance Electrocatalysts for Improved Anion Exchange Membrane and Water Splitting Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401655</link>
      <description>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Hemalatha Gurusamy, Harpriya Minhas, Arun Karmakar, S. Ravichandran, Biswarup Pathak, Subrata Kundu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476280

                Abstract Effective first&#8208;row transition metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts are crucial for large&#8208;scale hydrogen energy generation and anion exchange membrane (AEM) devices in water splitting. The present work describes that SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH nanosheets on nickel foam are used as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting and AEM water electrolyzer study. Tuning the Ni&#8208;to&#8208;Fe ratios in NiFe&#8208;LDH and doping with Sm ions improves the electrical structure and intrinsic activity. SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH has higher oxygen evolution reaction (OER), HER, and TWS activity, achieving 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 current density at lower overpotentials (230 mV, 95 mV, and 1.62 V, respectively). In AEMWE cells, SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH as a cathode and anode pair exhibits outstanding activity (0.9 A cm&#8315; 2 at 2 V) and stability over 120 h. Density Functional Theory (DFT) investigations reveal that the Sm doping in NiFe&#8208;LDH surface enhances its bifunctional activity toward OER and HER. These findings emphasize the potential of non&#8208;noble composites for long&#8208;term water electrolysis in total water splitting and AEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Hemalatha Gurusamy, Harpriya Minhas, Arun Karmakar, S. Ravichandran, Biswarup Pathak, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Design and Synthesis of Metal&#8211;Inorganic Frameworks Using Host Atom&#8208;Centered Building Blocks for Efficient Catalysis with Diverse Reactive Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418750</link>
      <description>Chao He, Xingxing Dong, Junqiu Zhang, Shao-Gang Xu, Xiang Huang, Hui Wang, Changchun He, Xiaowei Liang, Maohai Xie, Hu Xu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476300

                Abstract The modular assembly of organic molecules commonly guides the design of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), yet the systematic exploration of inorganic building blocks remains limited. Given the promising applications in catalytic reactions and topological materials, the study of metal&#8211;inorganic frameworks (MIFs)&#8212;which fundamentally differ from the well&#8208;established MOFs&#8212;has become urgent. This study introduces a strategy for designing MIFs using host atom&#8208;centered building blocks, applied to the platinum&#8211;Phosphorus (Pt&#8211;P) system. By combining experimental observations with theoretical calculations, a Pt 18 P 18 framework utilizing PtP 3 building blocks, demonstrating significant energetic benefits is proposed. PtP 3 units are employed to characterize Pt 3 P 6 clusters within the pores, leading to a &#8220;compass&#8221; model that aligns with experimental findings. To address computational challenges associated with the large periodicity of the superstructure, a robust machine learning force field is developed. The analysis, combining surface nucleation studies, first&#8208;principles calculations, and machine learning techniques, provides a comprehensive understanding of MIF structure. This validated Pt&#8211;P MIF exhibits exceptional catalytic properties with diverse reaction sites, significantly outperforming Pt(111) in the hydrogen evolution reaction. The findings not only present additional candidates for practical applications of metal phosphides but also highlight the vast potential of MIFs, paving the way for the discovery of numerous promising materials.</description>
      <author>Chao He, Xingxing Dong, Junqiu Zhang, Shao-Gang Xu, Xiang Huang, Hui Wang, Changchun He, Xiaowei Liang, Maohai Xie, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart Compositional Design of B&#8208;Site Ordered Double Perovskite for Advanced Oxygen Catalysis at Ultra&#8208;High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401480</link>
      <description>Maria Christy, Jiseok Kwon, S. Subramanian, Seunggun Choi, Junghyun Choi, Jung Ho Kim, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476385

                Abstract Perovskite oxides have been considered promising oxygen catalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER), owing to structural and compositional flexibility, and tailorable properties. Ingenious B&#8208;site ordered La 1.5 Sr 0.5 NiMn 0.5 Fe 0.5 O 6 (LSNMF) double perovskite is strategically designed by simultaneously interposing Ni 0.5 Mn 0.5 and Ni 0.5 Fe 0.5 into B&#8242; and B&#8243; sites. Controlling B&#8208;site cation systematically tailors the electronic structure of the B&#8208;site cation with a d&#8208;band center (M d ) upshift close to the Fermi level, increasing the overlap of the M d center and O 2p center (O P ). The strong interaction of M d and O p facilitates the adsorption of oxygen and activates the lattice oxygen to participate in the OER process, thereby enhancing the ORR and OER activity. For ORR, LSNMF exhibited an onset potential of 0.9 V along with a high limiting current of &#8722;8.05 mA cm &#8722;2 . At the same time, for OER at 1 m KOH, LSNMF effectively reached a maximum current density of 3000 mA cm &#8722;2 . Most importantly, the difference between E ORR (at &#8722;1 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and E OER (at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), &#916;E is 0.69 V, which stands among the best of recently reported perovskites. The as&#8208;designed LSNMF is stable, efficient, lucrative, and a promising candidate for practical application.</description>
      <author>Maria Christy, Jiseok Kwon, S. Subramanian, Seunggun Choi, Junghyun Choi, Jung Ho Kim, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture through Aqueous Carbonation Using Green Liquor Dregs as the Absorbent</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.4c00373</link>
      <description>Eduarda C. Queiroz, Emmanouela Leventaki, Christian Kugge, Diana Bernin, ACS Sustainable Resource Management. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405483958

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eduarda C. Queiroz, Emmanouela Leventaki, Christian Kugge, Diana Bernin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.4c00373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lewis Acid-Mediated Interfacial Water Supply for Sustainable Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14529</link>
      <description>Liming Deng, Hongjun Chen, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ying Zhang, Hanzhi Yu, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405275902

                The catalyst-electrolyte interface plays a crucial role in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). However, optimizing the interfacial hydrogen bonding to enhance both catalytic activity and stability remains a significant challenge. Here, a novel catalyst design strategy is proposed based on the hard-soft acid-base principle, employing hard Lewis acids (LAs = ZrO</description>
      <author>Liming Deng, Hongjun Chen, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ying Zhang, Hanzhi Yu, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient parameterization of adsorbate-adsorbate interactions on metal surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122678</link>
      <description>Willem Vanmoerkerke, Rasmus Svensson, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405317176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Willem Vanmoerkerke, Rasmus Svensson, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyoxometalates based transition metal sulfide composites for hydrodesulfurization and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.048</link>
      <description>Ghulam Murtaza, Tayyaba Najam, Naseem Ahmad Khan, Muhammad Sher, Muhammad Kashif Aslam, Ibrahim A. Shaaban, Muhammad Altaf Nazir, Manzar Sohail, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405285487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ghulam Murtaza, Tayyaba Najam, Naseem Ahmad Khan, Muhammad Sher, Muhammad Kashif Aslam, Ibrahim A. Shaaban, Muhammad Altaf Nazir, Manzar Sohail, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Palladium-Based Membrane Research: High-Throughput Techniques and Machine Learning Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12122855</link>
      <description>Eric Kolor, Muhammad Usman, Sasipa Boonyubol, K&#246;ichi Mikami, Jeffrey S. Cross, Processes. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405314867

                The separation of high-purity hydrogen from mixed gasses using dense metallic alloy membranes is essential for advancing a hydrogen-based economy. Palladium-based membranes exhibit outstanding catalytic activity and theoretically infinite hydrogen selectivity, but their high cost and limited performance in contaminant-rich environments restrict their widespread use. This study addresses these limitations by exploring strategies to develop cost-effective, high-performance alternatives. Key challenges include the vast compositional design space, lack of systematic design principles, and the slow pace of traditional material development. This review emphasizes the potential of high-throughput and combinatorial techniques, such as composition-spread alloy films and the statistical design of experiments (DoE), combined with machine learning and materials informatics, to accelerate the discovery, optimization, and characterization of palladium-based membranes. These approaches reduce development time and costs while improving efficiency. Focusing on critical properties such as surface catalytic activity, resistance to chemical and physical stresses, and the incorporation of low-cost base metals, this study introduces domain-specific descriptors to address data scarcity and improve material screening. By integrating computational and experimental methods, future research can identify hidden material correlations and expedite the rational design of next-generation hydrogen separation membranes.</description>
      <author>Eric Kolor, Muhammad Usman, Sasipa Boonyubol, K&#246;ichi Mikami, Jeffrey S. Cross</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12122855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen production from ammonia decomposition: Advances in Ru- and Ni-based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.136</link>
      <description>Neng Zhu, Chaoho Ouyang, Yu Hong, Junjie Liang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405391243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Neng Zhu, Chaoho Ouyang, Yu Hong, Junjie Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Observed Data and Reaction Mechanisms in Deep Learning for Designing Sustainable Glycolic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527845491.ch4</link>
      <description>Xin Zhou, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405352480

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527845491.ch4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measurement of surface segregation via He+ ion scattering in Cu Ag Au1-- composition spread thin films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122682</link>
      <description>Zhitao Guo, Robert A. Burnley, Andrew J. Gellman, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405386390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhitao Guo, Robert A. Burnley, Andrew J. Gellman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porosity prediction using bagging ensemble machine learning in CCUS reservoirs. A case study: Darling Basin, Australia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12145-024-01583-1</link>
      <description>Kushan Sandunil, Ziad Bennour, Saaveethya Sivakumar, Hisham Ben Mahmud, Ausama Giwelli, Earth Science Informatics. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405386406

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kushan Sandunil, Ziad Bennour, Saaveethya Sivakumar, Hisham Ben Mahmud, Ausama Giwelli</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12145-024-01583-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into structural and magnetic properties of Lanthanum Manganite ceramic co-doped with calcium and cobalt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5451975/v1</link>
      <description>Rohit Sharma, Pawan Kumar, Anil Jakhar, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405369492

                Abstract A polycryst alline ceramic sample of calcium and cobalt co-doped Lanthanum Manganite (LCMCO) was synthesized via the autocombustion route and subjected to comprehensive characterization using various analytical techniques, namely XRD, SEM, FTIR and VSM. The sharp peaks are observed on XRD analysis conducted at room temperature, confirming the formation of single-phase compound with orthorhombic crystal structure and Pbnm space group. The lattice parameters were calculated using the Rietveld refinement tool Fullprof and are as follows: a = 5.4989 &#197;, b = 5.4265 &#197;, and c = 7.7217 &#197;. The XRD data also provided information on interplanar d spacing, atomic locations and other structural factors. Further examination through FESEM affirmed the diverse shapes and sizes of the prepared samples. Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy unveiled a broad peak at 615 cm-1, corroborating the presence of metal-oxygen bonds organized into MnO6 octahedral structures. Magnetic studies employing VSM disclosed the antiferromagnetic nature of the prepared samples. The AFM nature and precise lattice structure make this compound a potential candidate for magnetic refrigeration system. Moreover, the diverse morphology along with AFM nature make them suitable for magnetic sensor applications.</description>
      <author>Rohit Sharma, Pawan Kumar, Anil Jakhar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5451975/v1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
