<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:50:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles modeling of corrosion potential/current and its application in AZ and AZ-RE Magnesium Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108771</link>
      <description>Yuhao Huang, Xumin Zhang, Jiawei Wang, Y. Zeng, Xi Zhang, Luo Li, Yong Liu, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393346570

                First-principles modeling for magnesium corrosion potential/current has been established in this work. The corrosion potential formulation should be UaSHE=ln10RTlgnFkTh+Gv+NAN&#215;S&#215;Esurf+(10ln10)RT+0.65&#955;2nF&#8722;(&#955;1+&#955;2)nF(the intersection point of anodic and cathodic branch). And the one for the corrosion current density should belgJtot=lgJm+km&#215;&#8721;(fm&#215;&#8710;Em)+ki&#215;&#8721;(fi&#215;&#8710;Ei)(including matrix corrosion lgJm, matrix interplane galvanic corrosion km&#215;&#8721;(fm&#215;&#8710;Em), second phase galvanic corrosionki&#215;&#8721;(fi&#215;&#8710;Ei) and &#8710;E is the intergranular potential difference between phase/matrix planes and Mg(0001)). Applied the modeling to simulate AZ and AZ-RE electrochemical corrosion, the predicted potential/current values are quite coherent with the experimental polarization ones. The role of alloying element on corrosion have also been discussed at atomic level. The main alloying element (such as Al or Zn in AZ, or AZ-RE) would affect work function &#934;, surface energy density Esurf/&#961;, and hydrogen atom adsorption free energy &#8710;GH*, so it influences anode/cathode reaction greatly and works a lot on Ua and lgJm. Furthermore, main alloy and minor alloy (such as RE in AZ-RE) would make their own contribution on galvanic corrosion by holding the potential difference &#8710;Em or &#8710;Ei and keeping mole fraction fm or fi. The work provide the modeling which could predict the corrosion potential/current values for magnesium alloy, which are directly correspond to the polarization curves. It also could give a theoretical understanding for alloying effect on corrosion. It suggests a more flexible way for seeking corrosion-resistant alloys.</description>
      <author>Yuhao Huang, Xumin Zhang, Jiawei Wang, Y. Zeng, Xi Zhang, Luo Li, Yong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methanol&#8208;Facilitated Surface Reconstruction Catalysts for Near 200% Faradaic Efficiency in a Coupled System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314596</link>
      <description>Xia Qin, Chengkai Jin, Yu Lun Huang, Yanjie Zhai, Wenkai Han, Cheng Cheng, Chuan Xia, Chun Che Lin, Xunhua Zhao, Xiao Zhang, Advanced functional materials (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393345338

                Abstract The coupling of the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) and methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) holds great promise for the energy&#8208;efficient production of HCOO &#8722; . However, anode catalysts' limited selectivity (&lt;80%) and stability (&lt;15 h) have impeded electron utilization and HCOO &#8722; production rates. To overcome it, copper&#8208;copper(I) oxide&#8208;copper(II) oxide nanowires (Cu&#9472;CuO&#9472;Cu 2 O NWs) catalysts have been developed, which exhibit exceptional performance in promoting the MOR with a faradic efficiency of nearly 100% at commercially viable current densities, and long stability over 100 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Interestingly, the unique structure of the catalysts, when exposed to methanol, facilitates a transition from Cu/CuO to Cu 2 O. This phenomenon promotes the MOR while inhibiting the competitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER). By coupling the anodic reaction with cathodic CO 2 reduction, the system demonstrates exceptional performance in HCOO &#8722; production, achieving an overall faradic efficiency of nearly 200% at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 with a low cell voltage of 2.382 V. Techno&#8208;economic analysis indicates that the production costs of HCOOH are &#8776;US$0.37 and 0.35 kg &#8722;1 at 100 and 150 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively, significantly lower than those associated with traditional electrochemical methods.</description>
      <author>Xia Qin, Chengkai Jin, Yu Lun Huang, Yanjie Zhai, Wenkai Han, Cheng Cheng, Chuan Xia, Chun Che Lin, Xunhua Zhao, Xiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Cu-Doped Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Aqueous Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00571</link>
      <description>Ashis Kumar Behera, Deepak Seth, Manish Agarwal, M. Ali Haider, Aninda J. Bhattacharyya, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393363876

                The efficiency of oxygen electrocatalysis is a key factor in diverse energy domain applications, including the performance of metal&#8211;air batteries, such as aqueous Zinc (Zn)&#8211;air batteries. We demonstrate here that the doping of cobalt oxide with optimal amounts of copper (abbreviated as Cu-doped Co3O4) results in a stable and efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction (ORR) and evolution (OER) reactions in aqueous Zn&#8211;air batteries. At high Cu-doping concentrations (&#8805;5%), phase segregation occurs with the simultaneous presence of Co3O4 and copper oxide (CuO). At Cu-doping concentrations &#8804;5%, the Cu ion resides in the octahedral (Oh) site of Co3O4, as revealed by X-ray diffraction (XRD)/Raman spectroscopy investigations and molecular dynamics (MD) calculations. The residence of Cu@Oh sites leads to an increased concentration of surface Co3+-ions (at catalytically active planes) and oxygen vacancies, which is beneficial for the OER. Temperature-dependent magnetization measurements reveal favorable d-orbital configuration (high eg occupancy &#8776; 1) and a low &#8594; high spin-state transition of the Co3+-ions, which are beneficial for the ORR in the alkaline medium. The influence of Cu-doping on the ORR activity of Co3O4 is additionally accounted in DFT calculations via interactions between solvent water molecules and oxygen vacancies. The application of the bifunctional Cu-doped (&#8804;5%) Co3O4 electrocatalyst resulted in an aqueous Zn&#8211;air battery with promising power density (=84 mW/cm2), stable cyclability (over 210 cycles), and low charge/discharge overpotential (=0.92 V).</description>
      <author>Ashis Kumar Behera, Deepak Seth, Manish Agarwal, M. Ali Haider, Aninda J. Bhattacharyya</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Surface Reconstruction During Oxygen Evolution Reaction on the Defined Spinel Oxide Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401095</link>
      <description>Kyungbeen Yeom, Jung Hyun Jo, Hyun-Seop Shin, Hyunsoo Ji, Sun-Young Moon, Ji&#8208;Eun Park, Seongbeom Lee, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Dong Hyeon Mok, Megalamane S. Bootharaju, Seoin Back, Taeghwan Hyeon, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Advanced functional materials (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393364585

                Abstract The reconstructed surface structure of Co&#8208;based spinel oxides serves as the active site for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the structural complexity of spinel oxides and surface dynamics during the OER hinder the understanding of the reconstruction mechanism and electronic structure of the active site. In this study, spinel Co 3 O 4 @(CoFeV) 3 O 4 nanocube (CoFeV) is reported, a (001) facet&#8208;defined spinel oxide comprising Co, Fe, and V deposited on the Co 3 O 4 nanocube template to exclude facet&#8208;dependent factors. Introducing highly dissoluble V cations accelerates the reconstruction process to enhance the electrocatalytic activity. CoFeV exhibited enhanced electrocatalytic activity (266 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 M KOH) and durability (maintained stable electrocatalytic activity during a 200 h chronopotentiometry (CP) test at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ) with significantly enlarged electrochemically active surface area (ECSA). The experimental and theoretical results demonstrated that V dissolution during catalysis induced oxygen vacancies, accelerating the surface reconstruction to highly active oxyhydroxide. Consequently, the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) of CoFeV as the anode exhibited a remarkable performance of 6.19 A cm &#8722;2 at 2.0 V cell in 1 M KOH and robust durability for 96 h at a constant current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Kyungbeen Yeom, Jung Hyun Jo, Hyun-Seop Shin, Hyunsoo Ji, Sun-Young Moon, Ji&#8208;Eun Park, Seongbeom Lee, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Dong Hyeon Mok, Megalamane S. Bootharaju, Seoin Back, Taeghwan Hyeon, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Data-Driven Discovery and Screening of Two-Dimensional Magnets Using Graph Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07246</link>
      <description>Ahmed Elrashidy, James Della-Giustina, Jia-An Yan, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393378496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ahmed Elrashidy, James Della-Giustina, Jia-An Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and lifetime of diffusion-trapped oxygen in oxide-derived copper CO2 reduction electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01132-5</link>
      <description>Zan Lian, Federico Dattila, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393379673

                Abstract Oxide-derived Cu has an excellent ability to promote C&#8211;C coupling in the electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction. However, these materials largely rearrange under reaction conditions; therefore, the nature of the active site remains controversial. Here we study the reduction process of oxide-derived Cu via large-scale molecular dynamics with a precise neural network potential trained on first-principles data and introducing experimental conditions. The oxygen concentration in the most stable oxide-derived Cu increases with an increase of the pH, potential or specific surface area. In long electrochemical experiments, the catalyst would be fully reduced to Cu, but removing all the trapped oxygen takes a considerable amount of time. Although the highly reconstructed Cu surface provides various sites to adsorb oxygen more strongly, the surface oxygen atoms are not stable under common experimental conditions. This work provides insight into the evolution of oxide-derived Cu catalysts and residual oxygen during reaction and also a deep understanding of the nature of active sites.</description>
      <author>Zan Lian, Federico Dattila, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01132-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Search and Theoretical Study of Silicene Grain Boundaries&#8217; Mechanical Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07294</link>
      <description>Jianan Zhang, Aditya Koneru, Subramanian K. R. S. Sankaranarayanan, Carmen M. Lilley, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393380298

                Defects such as grain boundaries (GBs) are almost inevitable during the synthesis process of 2D materials. To take advantage of the fascinating properties of 2D materials, understanding the nature and impact of various GB structures on pristine 2D sheets is crucial. In this work, using an evolutionary algorithm search, we predict a wide variety of silicene GB structures with very different atomic structures compared with those found in graphene or hexagonal boron-nitride. Twenty-one GBs with the lowest energy were validated by density functional theory (DFT), a majority of which were previously unreported to our best knowledge. Based on the diversity of the GB predictions, we found that the formation energy and mechanical properties can be dramatically altered by adatom positions within a GB and certain types of atomic structures, such as four-atom rings. To study the mechanical behavior of these GBs, we apply strain to the GB structures stepwise and use DFT calculations to investigate the mechanical properties of 9 representative structures. It is observed that GB structures based on pentagon-heptagon pairs are likely to have similar or higher in-plane stiffness and strength compared to the zigzag orientation of pristine silicene. However, an adatom located at the hollow site of a heptagon ring can significantly deteriorate the mechanical strength. For all of the structures, the in-plane stiffness and strength were found to decrease with increasing formation energy. For the failure behavior of GB structures, it was found that GB structures based on pentagon-heptagon pairs have failure behavior similar to that of graphene. We also found that the GB structures with atoms positioned outside of the 2D plane tend to experience phase transitions before failure. Utilizing the evolutionary algorithm, we locate diverse silicene GBs and obtain useful information about their mechanical properties.</description>
      <author>Jianan Zhang, Aditya Koneru, Subramanian K. R. S. Sankaranarayanan, Carmen M. Lilley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment Regulation Breaks the Trade-Off between the Faradaic Efficiency and the Current Density for Electrocatalytic Deuteration Using D2O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4023036/v1</link>
      <description>Bin Zhang, Meng He, Rui Li, Chuanqi Cheng, Cuibo Liu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393381349

                Abstract The high Faradaic efficiency (FE) of the deuteration of organics with D 2 O at large current densities is significant for developing a feasible and promising room-temperature deuteration strategy. However, the FE and current density are the two ends of a seesaw because of the severe D 2 evolution side reaction at nearly industrial current densities (&#8722; 100 mA cm &#8722; 2 ). Herein, we report a combined scenario of a nanotip-enhanced electric field and surfactant-modified interface microenvironment to enable electrocatalytic deuteration of arylacetonitrile in D 2 O with an 80% FE at &#8722; 100 mA cm &#8722; 2 , which are both the best records for electrocatalytic deuteration. The increased reactant concentration with low activation energy due to the large electric field along the tips and the accelerated reactant transfer and suppressed D 2 evolution by the surfactant-created deuterophobic microenvironment contribute to breaking the trade-off between high FE and current density. Furthermore, the application of our strategy in other deuteration reactions with improved FE at &#8722; 100 mA cm &#8722; 2 rationalizes the design concept.</description>
      <author>Bin Zhang, Meng He, Rui Li, Chuanqi Cheng, Cuibo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4023036/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing d Electrons&#8217; Delocalization of the Single-Atom Ni&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Site to Boost Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to CO by Axial d&#8211;d Orbital Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00493</link>
      <description>Xiaohang Wang, Zhongzheng Mao, Guanghua Wei, Lingli Liu, Hao Tang, Baolei Li, Ling Zhu, Simin Xu, Shaobin Tang, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393381512

                Atomically dispersed nitrogen-coordinated transition metal (TM) anchored on graphene (TM&#8211;Nx&#8211;C) provides a promising potential for an electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, it is still a challenge to precisely control the electronic structures of TM single-atom catalysts (SACs) for optimizing the catalytic performance. Using first-principles calculations, we propose a novel strategy to regulate the electronic structure of the Ni&#8211;N4&#8211;C site by vertically coupling the 3-fold N atom-coordinated TM atom on graphene (TM&#8211;N3&#8211;C) for promoting CO2 reduction to CO. In contrast to the traditional TM&#8211;N4&#8211;C substrate that is weakly coupled with the N&#8211;N4&#8211;C site, the raised TM atoms on the TM&#8211;N3&#8211;C substrate relative to the basal plane of graphene shorten the distance from TM to Ni atoms and strengthen d orbital hybridization between them, thus leading to more delocalized charge distribution of the Ni active site. As a result, the improved axial d&#8211;d orbital coupling largely enhances the adsorption of the key *COOH intermediate on Ni SACs and, more importantly, maintains the facile desorption of adsorbed *CO. In particular, these Ni&#8211;N4&#8211;C SACs with axial coupling of Tc&#8211; and Ru&#8211;N3&#8211;C substrates not only exhibit high catalytic activity toward CO production, with low limiting potentials of &#8722;0.68 and &#8722;0.61 V, respectively, but also effectively suppress the competing hydrogen evolution (HER).</description>
      <author>Xiaohang Wang, Zhongzheng Mao, Guanghua Wei, Lingli Liu, Hao Tang, Baolei Li, Ling Zhu, Simin Xu, Shaobin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of electrocatalytic urea synthesis through CO2 and N2 on metal cluster decorated C2N</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09547-y</link>
      <description>Wenxi Zhang, Mengnan Qu, Aijun Du, Qiao Sun, Journal of materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393386671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenxi Zhang, Mengnan Qu, Aijun Du, Qiao Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09547-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretically Insight into Co and S Pairs Dispersed on N&#8208;Doped Graphene: Promising Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400076</link>
      <description>Ji Zhang, Aimin Yu, Dongsheng Li, Chenghua Sun, Advanced theory and simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393388274

                Abstract Single atom catalysts (SACs) are considered as efficient catalysts for hydrogen&#8208;based energy conversion and storage because of their excellent catalytic performance for oxygen evolution reactions (OER) and oxygen reduction reactions (ORR). In the present work, a new concept of SACs is proposed with the capacity to form d &#8208; p orbital hybridization. These computationally designed SACs contain a metal and non&#8208;metal pair embedded in the N&#8208;doped graphene framework (MX@N 6 ). Based on the overpotential evaluation by the first principle theory calculations, CoS@N 6 containing Co and S atom pair possessed a low overpotential of 0.37 V/0.29 V when used as a bifunctional ORR/OER catalyst. These overpotentials are much lower than Co@N 6 without S atom. The electronic structure analysis revealed that non&#8208;metal atoms of the catalyst can regulate the electronic structure of active metal sites and facilitate the adsorption and charge transfer between intermediates and the catalyst resulting in enhanced catalytic performance. This work demonstrates an alternative way to further improve the catalytic activity of SACs by introducing a non&#8208;metal atom that may shed light on the rational design of advanced SACs for ORR/OER with high efficiency and stability.</description>
      <author>Ji Zhang, Aimin Yu, Dongsheng Li, Chenghua Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional activity and theoretical study of transition metal molybdates for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.254</link>
      <description>Namita Dalai, Manikandan Kandasamy, Shraddhanjali Senapati, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Bijayalaxmi Jena, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393393474

                Effective, sturdy and cheap electrocatalysts are extremely desirable for water electrolysis. In this work, transition metal molybdates (MMoO4, M = Fe, Co, Ni) with extraordinary oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in basic electrolyte solution was reported. &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 catalyst exhibits better electrocatalytic performance and robustness for both HER and OER compared to NiMoO4 and CoMoO4. Theoretical study (DFT calculation) disclose that the Fe atoms increase the energy states near the Fermi level in &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 which makes it more conductive leading to superior OER and HER activity. Compared to CoMoO4 and NiMoO4, &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 have well defined multiple Mo 4d orbitals at the conduction band. These are empty states in conduction band, ready to receive the electrons. Further, the computed overpotential values for NiMoO4, CoMoO4, and &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 surfaces follow the trend, &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 &lt; NiMoO4 &lt; CoMoO4, corroborating with the experimental results.</description>
      <author>Namita Dalai, Manikandan Kandasamy, Shraddhanjali Senapati, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Bijayalaxmi Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are (100) facets of transition metal carbonitrides suitable as electrocatalysts for nitrogen reduction to ammonia at ambient conditions?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.282</link>
      <description>Atef Iqbal, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Younes Abghoui, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393393578

                Sustainable and energy-efficient ammonia production requires facile nitrogen reduction for hydrogen preservation and inorganic fertilizers. A nitrogen reduction apparatus with optimal stability, selectivity, and activity for ambient temperatures and pressure is needed to catalyze ammonia synthesis. This paper describes the investigation of using transition metal carbonitrides as catalyst to reduce molecular nitrogen electrochemically to NH3 at room temperature and atmospheric pressure. Density functional theory calculations determine the competition among associative, dissociative, and Mars-van Krevelen mechanisms where in most cases the Mars-van Krevelen is a more favorable reaction pathway. VCN and NbCN are the best candidates for ammonia production via the Mars-van Krevelen mechanism at low onset potentials of &#8722;0.52 V and &#8722;0.53 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode on the (100) facets. These carbonitrides are predicted to favor nitrogen reduction reaction rather than hydrogen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Atef Iqbal, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/Crystalline Phases Mixed Nanosheets Array Rich in Oxygen Vacancies Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Spinel Oxides in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401504</link>
      <description>Ying Liu, Liyang Xiao, Haiwen Tan, Jingtong Zhang, Cunku Dong, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Jing Yang, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393403940

                Abstract As promising oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, spinel&#8208;type oxides face the bottleneck of weak adsorption for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates, so it is challenging to make a further breakthrough in remarkably lowering the OER overpotential. In this study, a novel strategy is proposed to substantially enhance the OER activity of spinel oxides based on amorphous/crystalline phases mixed spinel FeNi 2 O 4 nanosheets array, enriched with oxygen vacancies, in situ grown on a nickel foam (NF). This unique architecture is achieved through a one&#8208;step millisecond laser direct writing method. The presence of amorphous phases with abundant oxygen vacancies significantly enhances the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and changes the rate&#8208;determining step from OH*&#8594;O* to O*&#8594;OOH*, which greatly reduces the thermodynamic energy barrier. Moreover, the crystalline phase interweaving with amorphous domains serves as a conductive shortcut to facilitate rapid electron transfer from active sites in the amorphous domain to NF, guaranteeing fast OER kinetics. Such an anodic electrode exhibits a nearly ten fold enhancement in OER intrinsic activity compared to the pristine counterpart. Remarkably, it demonstrates record&#8208;low overpotentials of 246 and 315 mV at 50 and 500 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH with superior long&#8208;term stability, outperforming other NiFe&#8208;based spinel oxides catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ying Liu, Liyang Xiao, Haiwen Tan, Jingtong Zhang, Cunku Dong, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Jing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing the Hydrogen Bonding Interaction with *Ooh Toward Efficient H2o2 Electrosynthesis Via Remote Electronic Tuning of Co-N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4781821</link>
      <description>Jiawei Zhang, Hongwei Zeng, Bingling He, Ying Liu, Jingcheng Xu, Tianye Niu, Chengsi Pan, Ying Zhang, Lei Yang, Yao Wang, Yuanhua Dong, Yongfa Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393408035

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Zhang, Hongwei Zeng, Bingling He, Ying Liu, Jingcheng Xu, Tianye Niu, Chengsi Pan, Ying Zhang, Lei Yang, Yao Wang, Yuanhua Dong, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4781821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the ORR/OER Activity of Cobalt&#8208;Based Nano&#8208;Catalysts by Co 3d Orbital Regulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400855</link>
      <description>Nan Meng, Feng Yan, Zhenwei Zhao, Fang Lian, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393409592

                Abstract The transition metal oxides/sulfides are considered promising catalysts due to their abundant resources, facile synthesis, and reasonable electrocatalytic activity. Herein, a significantly improved intrinsic catalytic activity is achieved for constructing a Co&#8208;based nanocrystal (Co&#8208;S@NC) with the coordination of Co&#9472;S, Co&#9472;S&#9472;C, and Co&#9472;N x &#9472;C. The calculational and experimental results demonstrate that the diversified chemical environment of Co&#8208;cations induces the transition of 3d orbitals to a high spin&#8208;state that exhibits the coexistence of Co 2+ with fully occupied d &#960; orbitals and Co 3+ with unpaired electrons in d &#960; orbitals. The diverse d &#960; orbitals occupation contributes to an elevated d&#8208;band center of Co ions, which accelerates oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalytic kinetics of the Co&#8208;S@NC nanocrystal. Therefore, the Li&#8211;O 2 batteries with Co&#8208;S@NC as cathode catalyst exhibit 300 cycles at the current density of 500 mA g &#8722;1 with a cut&#8208;off capacity of 1000 mAh g &#8722;1 . Moreover, the ultrahigh discharge specific capacity of 34 587 mAh g &#8722;1 is obtained at a current density of 1000 mA g &#8722;1 , corresponding to the energy density 949 Wh kg &#8722;1 of a prototype Li&#8211;O 2 battery. The study on 3d orbital regulation of nanocrystals provides an innovative strategy for bifunctional electrocatalysts toward the practical application of metal&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Nan Meng, Feng Yan, Zhenwei Zhao, Fang Lian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards improved online dissolution evaluation of Pt-alloy PEMFC electrocatalysts via electrochemical flow cell - ICP-MS setup upgrades</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144200</link>
      <description>L&#233;onard Moriau, Tina &#272;uki&#263;, Vojtech Domin, Roman Kod&#253;m, Martin Prokop, Karel Bouzek, Matija Gatalo, Martin &#352;ala, Nejc Hodnik, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393428641

                Electrochemical flow cell coupled with an inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometer (EFC-ICP-MS) is a powerful electroanalytical technique to monitor in-situ dissolution of metallic electrocatalysts and to understand mechanism of degradation under operating conditions. Its utilisation has witnessed a notable increase in the electrocatalyst field in the last decade where it has been extensively used to study the stability of platinum group metals (PGMs) under oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction conditions. Online ICP-MS has allowed the scientific and industrial community to optimise the activity and stability of PGMs thanks to a better understanding of the complex metal corrosion processes. Among the different setups, the electrochemical flow cell design is the most common as it is based on a commercially available design. Nonetheless, besides different materials and different electrochemical protocols, the impact of the geometry and various parameters of the setup on the recorded dissolution signal has not been studied until now. Such parameters can influence the results obtained with an EFC-ICP-MS and thus the interpretation of the dissolution mechanism and/or stability assessment. Hereby, we demonstrate that the length of the tubing between the outlet of the cell and the inlet of the ICP-MS impacts the resolution of the PtCo catalyst dissolution peaks. This, in turn, facilitates studies where the detection of extremely low concentrations is necessary, such as under a very narrow potential window. Similarly, a reduced internal volume of the cell restricts Pt redeposition, contributing to a more precise evaluation of stability. These claims were supported by dynamic continuum mechanics modelling of the ion concentration in a model EFC. Finally, we provide guidelines and advice to properly measure dissolution with an electrochemical cell coupled with ICP-MS.</description>
      <author>L&#233;onard Moriau, Tina &#272;uki&#263;, Vojtech Domin, Roman Kod&#253;m, Martin Prokop, Karel Bouzek, Matija Gatalo, Martin &#352;ala, Nejc Hodnik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electro-Catalysis for H$$_2$$O Oxidation and Chlorine Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46870-4_7</link>
      <description>Travis E. Jones, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393433643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Travis E. Jones</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46870-4_7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical Chemistry Education and Research in an Open-Sourced Future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.3c00078</link>
      <description>Jeffrey T. DuBose, Sheila Scott, Benjamin Moss, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393436798

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jeffrey T. DuBose, Sheila Scott, Benjamin Moss</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.3c00078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal clusters with precise numbers of atoms anchored on graphdiyne as multifunctional electrocatalysts for OER/ORR/HER: a computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02611-7</link>
      <description>Xin-Yang Liu, J. W. Liu, Gang Li, Jingxiang Zhao, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393850997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Yang Liu, J. W. Liu, Gang Li, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02611-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration on Machine-Learned Potentials with IPSuite: A Modular Framework for Learning-on-the-Fly</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c07187</link>
      <description>Fabian Zills, Moritz Sch&#228;fer, Nico Segreto, Johannes K&#228;stner, Christian Holm, Samuel Tovey, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. B (1997 : Online). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393854049

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fabian Zills, Moritz Sch&#228;fer, Nico Segreto, Johannes K&#228;stner, Christian Holm, Samuel Tovey</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c07187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning A&#8208;Site Cation Deficiency in Pr&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;La&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;BaCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5+&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Perovskite to Realize Large&#8208;Scale Hydrogen Evolution at 2000 mA cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;2&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400760</link>
      <description>Kaiqian Li, Tian Xia, Ruiping Deng, Yingnan Dou, Jingping Wang, Qiang Li, Liping Sun, Li-Hua Huo, Hui Zhao, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393865235

                Abstract Industrial&#8208;level hydrogen production from the water electrolysis requires reducing the overpotential ( &#951; ) as much as possible at high current density, which is closely related to intrinsic activity of the electrocatalysts. Herein, A&#8208;site cation deficiency engineering is proposed to screen high&#8208;performance catalysts, demonstrating effective Pr 0.5&#8208; x La 0.5 BaCo 2 O 5+ &#948; (P 0.5&#8208; x LBC) perovskites toward alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Among all perovskite compositions, Pr 0.4 La 0.5 BaCo 2 O 5+ &#948; (P0.4LBC) exhibits superior HER performance along with unique operating stability at large current densities ( J = 500&#8211;2000 mA cm&#8722;2 geo). The overpotential of &#8776;636 mV is achieved in P0.4LBC at 2000 mA cm&#8722;2 geo, which outperforms commercial Pt/C benchmark (&#8776;974 mV). Furthermore, the Tafel slope of P0.4LBC (34.1 mV dec &#8722;1 ) is close to that of Pt/C (35.6 mV dec &#8722;1 ), reflecting fast HER kinetics on the P0.4LBC catalyst. Combined with experimental and theoretical results, such catalytic activity may benefit from enhanced electrical conductivity, enlarged Co&#8208;O covalency, and decreased desorption energy of H * species. This results highlight effective A&#8208;site cation&#8208;deficient strategy for promoting electrochemical properties of perovskites, highlighting potential water electrolysis at ampere&#8208;level current density.</description>
      <author>Kaiqian Li, Tian Xia, Ruiping Deng, Yingnan Dou, Jingping Wang, Qiang Li, Liping Sun, Li-Hua Huo, Hui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique production strategy of Pt/C electrocatalysts via pulsed laser for hydrogen generation: Insights screening by DFT calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144218</link>
      <description>Yujeong Jeong, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Seung Jun Lee, Ramesh Kumar Chitumalla, Cheol Joo Moon, Ahreum Min, Soorathep Kheawhom, Joonkyung Jang, Myong Yong Choi, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393865560

                Design and optimizing the components and structure of highly-active electrocatalysts is a prevalent approach for reducing the input electrical energy consumption and concurrently H2 fuel production. An efficient and sustainable method is a water-electrolyzer for H2 generation, but still restricted by the stable electrode materials. In this study, a green chemistry approach for one-pot production of Pt/C nanospherical with controllable ratios of Pt and C was demonstrated using simple pulsed laser ablation in liquid (PLAL) process, during which Pt target ablation in diverse solvents (water, methanol, ethanol, and 1-propanol) without external carbon source and reducing/capping agents. The carbon-rich solvents are acted as both C-source and solvent, which are decomposed during the PLA process, producing C, H, and OH ions inside the cavitation bubble which condenses as C-shells on the Pt surface. The optimal Pt/C proportions have the highest electrochemical H2-evolution in acidic media with an overpotential of 59 mV at 10 mA/cm2, Tafel slope of 41 mV/dec, and j0 of 0.686 mA/cm2. The exceptional electrocatalytic concert of optimal Pt/C was further supported by the density functional theory. Optimized C-content in Pt/C reveals good dispersion and strong interaction of C with Pt can make efficient electron transfer, structural stability, and electrochemical durability, resulting in superior electrocatalytic performance in electrolyzer devices.</description>
      <author>Yujeong Jeong, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Seung Jun Lee, Ramesh Kumar Chitumalla, Cheol Joo Moon, Ahreum Min, Soorathep Kheawhom, Joonkyung Jang, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Advances of Non-Noble Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071637</link>
      <description>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Gang Li, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Xianjie Yuan, Yingjia Wang, Bin Cao, Materials (Basel). 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393871266

                Water splitting is an important way to obtain hydrogen applied in clean energy, which mainly consists of two half-reactions: hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the kinetics of the OER of water splitting, which occurs at the anode, is slow and inefficient, especially in acid. Currently, the main OER catalysts are still based on noble metals, such as Ir and Ru, which are the main active components. Hence, the exploration of new OER catalysts with low cost, high activity, and stability has become a key issue in the research of electrolytic water hydrogen production technology. In this paper, the reaction mechanism of OER in acid was discussed and summarized, and the main methods to improve the activity and stability of non-noble metal OER catalysts were summarized and categorized. Finally, the future prospects of OER catalysts in acid were made to provide a little reference idea for the development of advanced OER catalysts in acid in the future.</description>
      <author>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Gang Li, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Xianjie Yuan, Yingjia Wang, Bin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric coordination engineering of active centers in MXene-based single atom catalysts for high-performance ECO2RR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119094</link>
      <description>Shoufu Cao, Hongyu Chen, Xiaofei Wei, Jiao Li, Chunyu Yang, Zengxuan Chen, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393898802

                Asymmetric coordination effect is an important concept in heterogeneous catalysis where both catalytic activity and product selectivity are serious influenced. However, this effect has rarely been understood because of the difficult in characterizing detailed coordination information. Here, by employing a theoretical study on electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR) towards HCOOH over Ti3C2O2-based NS/NN co-coordinated transition metal single atom catalysts (TM-NS/NN-Ti3C2O2 SACs), we show that asymmetric coordination environments have great impact on the electronic structure of the active center. Both electron transferring ability and spin polarization of the active center are vital to optimize the adsorption and hydrogenation of key intermediates. As a result, both catalytic activity and product selectivity can be maximized. V-NN-Ti3C2O2 are predicted to promote high-throughput HCOOH generation process at operation applied potential of &#8722;0.32 with considerable electrochemical stability, surpassing most reported catalysts. This work demonstrates V-NN-Ti3C2O2 as high-performance ECO2RR catalysts, and highlights that the introduction of the concept of asymmetric coordination effect may offer a new insight into the rational design of more efficient SACs.</description>
      <author>Shoufu Cao, Hongyu Chen, Xiaofei Wei, Jiao Li, Chunyu Yang, Zengxuan Chen, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validation workflow for machine learning interatomic potentials for complex ceramics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</link>
      <description>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash, Computational materials science. 239(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393373529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing lithium-silver alloy phases for enhanced energy density and electrochemical performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</link>
      <description>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu, Next materials. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393925878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolytic Regeneration of Spent Caustic Soda from CO2 Capture Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</link>
      <description>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho, Processes. 12(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393866132

                The traditional electrochemical caustic soda recovery system uses the generated pH gradient across the ion exchange membrane for the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent from CO2 capture. This electrochemical CO2 capture system releases the by-products H2 and O2 at the cathode and anode, respectively. Although effective for capturing CO2, the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limit the energy efficiency of this technique. Hence, this study proposed and validated a hybrid electrochemical cell based on the H2-cycling from the cathode to the anode to eliminate the reliance on anodic oxygen generation. The results show that our lab-scale prototype enabled effective spent caustic soda recovery with an electron utilisation efficiency of 90%, and a relative carbonate/bicarbonate diffusional flux of approximately 40%. The system also enabled the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent with a minimum electrochemical energy input of 0.19 kWh/kg CO2 at a CO2 recovery rate of 0.7 mol/m2/h, accounting for 30% lower energy demand than a control system without H2-recycling, making this technique a promising alternative to the conventional thermal regeneration technology.</description>
      <author>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
