<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 01:23:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Catalytic Performance of Oxygen-Coordinated Single-Atom Catalysts for Nitric Oxide Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07612</link>
      <description>Shiya Zhu, Yu Zhang, Wenbin Liu, Deshuai Yang, Guobing Zhou, Zhen Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407292269

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiya Zhu, Yu Zhang, Wenbin Liu, Deshuai Yang, Guobing Zhou, Zhen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Weak-Binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C Single-Atom Catalysts Possess Anomalously High Oxygen Reduction Activity?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16733</link>
      <description>Di Zhang, Fangxin She, Jiaxiang Chen, Li Wei, Hao Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407293609

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) with metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) structures are widely recognized as promising candidates in oxygen reduction reactions (ORR). According to the classical Sabatier principle, optimal 3d metal catalysts, such as Fe/Co&#8211;N&#8211;C, achieve superior catalytic performance due to the moderate binding strength. However, the substantial ORR activity demonstrated by weakly binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts such as Ni/Cu&#8211;N&#8211;C challenges current understandings, emphasizing the need to explore new underlying mechanisms. In this work, we integrated a pH-field coupled microkinetic model with detailed experimental electron state analyses to verify a novel key step in the ORR reaction pathway of weak-binding SACs&#9472;the oxygen adsorption at the metal&#8211;nitrogen bridge site. This step significantly altered the adsorption scaling relations, electric field responses, and solvation effects, further impacting the key kinetic reaction barrier from HOO* to O* and pH-dependent performance. Synchrotron spectra analysis further provides evidence for the new weak-binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C model, showing an increase in electron density on the antibonding &#960; orbitals of N atoms in weak-binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts and confirming the presence of N&#8211;O bonds. These findings redefine the understanding of weak-binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst behavior, opening up new perspectives for their application in clean energy.</description>
      <author>Di Zhang, Fangxin She, Jiaxiang Chen, Li Wei, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Heterojunction Construction and Interaction Mechanism of Ru1-LaOx-NiMnOx Nanocomposite for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.179115</link>
      <description>Qianzuo Liu, Yunping Ma, Nan Ma, Yingyi Wang, Sifan Sun, Binqi He, Ting Zhang, Xuehua Yan, Tie Li, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407302411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianzuo Liu, Yunping Ma, Nan Ma, Yingyi Wang, Sifan Sun, Binqi He, Ting Zhang, Xuehua Yan, Tie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.179115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of direct ammonia solid oxide fuel cells: Low temperature cell structure and ammonia decomposition strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115350</link>
      <description>Yuchen Ya, Ying Xu, Ahmed Mohammed Elbanna, Yimin Liu, Boyu Sun, Xiaobei Cheng, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 213(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407308347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuchen Ya, Ying Xu, Ahmed Mohammed Elbanna, Yimin Liu, Boyu Sun, Xiaobei Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet Engineering of Weyl Semimetals for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100091</link>
      <description>Ting Wai Lau, Qiong Lei, Jun Yin, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407309182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Wai Lau, Qiong Lei, Jun Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Numerical Energy Hessians with Graph Neural Network Potentials and Their Application in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07477</link>
      <description>Brook Wander, Joseph Musielewicz, Raffaele Cheula, John R. Kitchin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407310889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brook Wander, Joseph Musielewicz, Raffaele Cheula, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crash testing machine learning force fields for molecules, materials, and interfaces: model analysis in the TEA Challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06529h</link>
      <description>Igor Poltavsky, Anton Charkin-Gorbulin, Mirela Puleva, Gr&#233;gory Fonseca, Ilyes Batatia, Nicholas J. Browning, Stefan Chmiela, Mengnan Cui, J. Thorben Frank, Stefan Heinen, Bing Huang, Silvan K&#228;ser, Adil Kabylda, Danish Khan, Carolin M&#252;ller, Alastair J. A. Price, Kai Riedmiller, Kai T&#246;pfer, Tsz Wai Ko, Markus Meuwly, Matthias Rupp, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Johannes T. Margraf, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407320154

                Assessing the performance of modern machine learning force fields across diverse chemical systems to identify their strengths and limitations within the TEA Challenge 2023.</description>
      <author>Igor Poltavsky, Anton Charkin-Gorbulin, Mirela Puleva, Gr&#233;gory Fonseca, Ilyes Batatia, Nicholas J. Browning, Stefan Chmiela, Mengnan Cui, J. Thorben Frank, Stefan Heinen, Bing Huang, Silvan K&#228;ser, Adil Kabylda, Danish Khan, Carolin M&#252;ller, Alastair J. A. Price, Kai Riedmiller, Kai T&#246;pfer, Tsz Wai Ko, Markus Meuwly, Matthias Rupp, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Johannes T. Margraf, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller, Alexandre Tkatchenko</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06529h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical prediction of disulfide defects (S22&#8722;) in molybdenum disulfide monolayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06306-x</link>
      <description>Maxim R. Ryzhikov, S. G. Kozlova, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 31(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407340873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maxim R. Ryzhikov, S. G. Kozlova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06306-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Surface Reconstruction and Metal Dissolution on Ru&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ti&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Acidic Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08119</link>
      <description>Francisco Ospina&#8208;Acevedo, Jos&#233; Fernando God&#237;nez-Salom&#243;n, Zachary G. Naymik, Kevin C. Matthews, Jamie H. Warner, Christopher P. Rhodes, Perla B. Balbuena, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407340979

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Francisco Ospina&#8208;Acevedo, Jos&#233; Fernando God&#237;nez-Salom&#243;n, Zachary G. Naymik, Kevin C. Matthews, Jamie H. Warner, Christopher P. Rhodes, Perla B. Balbuena</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-layer group III-IV-VI semiconductors: potential photocatalysts for water splitting with high carrier mobilities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08157a</link>
      <description>Qiu Yang, Qi-Dong Hao, Cui-E Hu, Hua-Yun Geng, Xiang-Rong Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407341215

                Strong optical absorption, high carrier mobility, and potential photocatalytic water splitting properties of MSiX (M = Ga, In; X = S, Se, Te) monolayers.</description>
      <author>Qiu Yang, Qi-Dong Hao, Cui-E Hu, Hua-Yun Geng, Xiang-Rong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08157a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Scanning Microwave Microscopy Reveals Ion Intercalation Dynamics and Maps Active Sites in 2D Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500043</link>
      <description>Mohamed Awadein, Abhishek Kumar, Yuqing Wang, Mingdong Dong, Stefan M&#252;llegger, Georg Gramse, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407348632

                The accelerated demand for electrochemical energy storage urges the need for new, sustainable, and lightweight materials able to store high energy densities rapidly and efficiently. Development of these functional materials requires specialized techniques that can provide a close insight into the electrochemical properties at the nanoscale. For this reason, the electrochemical scanning microwave microscopy (EC-SMM) enabling local measurement of electrochemical properties with nanometer spatial resolution and sensitivity down to atto-Ampere electrochemical currents is introduced. Its power is demonstrated by studying NiCo-layered double hydroxide flakes, revealing active site locations and providing atomistic insights into the catalytic process. EC-SMM's spatial resolution of 16 &#177; 1 nm allows detailed analysis of edge effects in this 2D material, including localized electrochemical impedance spectroscopy and cyclic voltammetry. Coupled with advanced numerical modeling of diffusion and migration dynamics at the material interface, the findings elucidate the previously hypothesized processes responsible for localized enhancements in electrochemical activity, while pinpointing essential parameters for tuning the thermodynamics of ion intercalation and optimizing surface adsorption.</description>
      <author>Mohamed Awadein, Abhishek Kumar, Yuqing Wang, Mingdong Dong, Stefan M&#252;llegger, Georg Gramse</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory of Electro-Ionic Perturbations at Supported Electrocatalyst Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.066201</link>
      <description>Yufan Zhang, Tobias Binninger, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling, Physical Review Letters. 134(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407362343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yufan Zhang, Tobias Binninger, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.066201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Modeling of Interfacial Adhesion Strength of Epoxy Resins on Copper Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07792</link>
      <description>Uchenna A. Anene, S. P. Alpay, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407364814

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Uchenna A. Anene, S. P. Alpay</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadening the Scope of Neural Network Potentials through Direct Inclusion of Additional Molecular Attributes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01625</link>
      <description>Guillem Simeon, Antonio Mirarchi, Ra&#250;l P. Pel&#225;ez, Raimondas Galvelis, Gianni De Fabritiis, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407364879

                Most state-of-the-art neural network potentials do not account for molecular attributes other than atomic numbers and positions, which limits its range of applicability by design. In this work, we demonstrate the importance of including additional electronic attributes in neural network potential representations with a minimal architectural change to TensorNet, a state-of-the-art equivariant model based on Cartesian rank-2 tensor representations. By performing experiments on both custom-made and public benchmarking data sets, we show that this modification resolves input degeneracy issues stemming from the use of atomic numbers and positions alone, while enhancing the model's predictive accuracy across diverse chemical systems with different charge or spin states. This is accomplished without tailored strategies or the inclusion of physics-based energy terms, while maintaining efficiency and accuracy. These findings should furthermore encourage researchers to train and use models incorporating these additional representations.</description>
      <author>Guillem Simeon, Antonio Mirarchi, Ra&#250;l P. Pel&#225;ez, Raimondas Galvelis, Gianni De Fabritiis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01625</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exceptional Pt4+ ion substituted zinc cobaltite spinel oxide nanoelectrocatalysts for enhanced electrochemical hydrogen performance supported by DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.375</link>
      <description>Refah Saad Alkhaldi, Mubarak A. Adebunmi, M.A. Gondal, Mohamed Jaffer Sadiq Mohamed, M.A. Almessiere, A. Baykal, Abduljabar Q. Alsayoud, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 109(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407367202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Refah Saad Alkhaldi, Mubarak A. Adebunmi, M.A. Gondal, Mohamed Jaffer Sadiq Mohamed, M.A. Almessiere, A. Baykal, Abduljabar Q. Alsayoud</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.375</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Approaches for Designing Heterostructured Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400544</link>
      <description>Miyeon Kim, Kyu In Shim, Jeong Woo Han, Small Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407371559

                Electrocatalysts for oxidation and reduction reactions are crucial for sustainable energy production and carbon reduction. While precious metal catalysts exhibit superior activity, reducing reliance on them is necessary for large&#8208;scale applications. To address this, transition metal&#8208;based catalysts are studied with strategies to enhance catalytic performance. One promising strategy is heterostructures, which integrate multiple materials to harness synergistic effects. Developing efficient heterostructured electrocatalysts requires understanding their intricate characteristics, which poses challenges. While in situ and operando spectroscopy provides insights, computational materials science is essential for capturing reaction mechanisms, analyzing the origins at the atomic scale, and efficiently exploring innovative heterostructures. Despite growing recognition of computational materials science, standardized criteria for these systems remain lacking. This review consolidates case studies to propose approaches for modeling and analyzing heterostructures. It categorizes heterostructure types into vertical, semivertical, and lateral, defines their characteristics, and propose insights into minimizing or exploiting strain effects from lattice mismatches. Furthermore, it summarizes computational analyses of heterostructure stability and activity across reactions, including oxygen evolution, hydrogen evolution, oxygen reduction, carbon dioxide reduction, nitrogen reduction, and urea oxidation. This review provides an overview to refine heterostructure designs and establish a framework for systematic modeling and analysis to develop efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Miyeon Kim, Kyu In Shim, Jeong Woo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realizing Electrochemical Energy Conversion and Storage with Borophene: Science, Engineering, Obstacles, and Future Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411311</link>
      <description>Saira Ajmal, Junfeng Huang, Monika Singh, Anuj Kumar, Jianwen Guo, Mohammad Tabish, Muhammad Mushtaq, Mohammed Mujahid Alam, Xinrui Song, Ghulam Yasin, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407380039

                Abstract A novel 2D material that is a formidable opponent to graphene (Gr) is borophene, which stands as 2D boron sheets. This innovative material has gained interest in the energy sector due to its wide range of chemical properties, intricate structural geometries, possession of massless Dirac fermions, outstanding hardness, and high carrier mobility. Unlike Gr, which lacks a band gap, borophene exhibits a band gap, endowing it with distinct advantages. Although many advancements in borophene materials, including their synthesis, structural and electronic characterization, and applications, have been discussed in the literature, there is still a need for a quantitative and qualitative assessment from both the experimental and theoretical perspectives, as well as the learned lesson implication in real&#8208;world applications of this material. This review highlights recent theoretical and experimental discoveries about borophene, focusing on key scientific findings, structural and electronic properties, and diverse applications, particularly in energy conversion processes and energy storage systems such as batteries and supercapacitors. Finally, the paper discusses current research challenges and future opportunities for large&#8208;scale borophene synthesis and its potential uses.</description>
      <author>Saira Ajmal, Junfeng Huang, Monika Singh, Anuj Kumar, Jianwen Guo, Mohammad Tabish, Muhammad Mushtaq, Mohammed Mujahid Alam, Xinrui Song, Ghulam Yasin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411311</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527843565.ch7</link>
      <description>Shichao Ding, Zhaoyuan Lyu, Meng Yu, Yuehe Lin, Jincheng Li, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407383576

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shichao Ding, Zhaoyuan Lyu, Meng Yu, Yuehe Lin, Jincheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527843565.ch7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI in single-atom catalysts: a review of design and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/jmi.2024.78</link>
      <description>Qiumei Yu, Ninggui Ma, Chihon Leung, Han Liu, Y. Ren, Zhanhua Wei, Journal of Materials Informatics. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407386277

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as a research frontier in catalytic materials, distinguished by their unique atom-level dispersion, which significantly enhances catalytic activity, selectivity, and stability. SACs demonstrate substantial promise in electrocatalysis applications, such as fuel cells, CO2 reduction, and hydrogen production, due to their ability to maximize utilization of active sites. However, the development of efficient and stable SACs involves intricate design and screening processes. In this work, artificial intelligence (AI), particularly machine learning (ML) and neural networks (NNs), offers powerful tools for accelerating the discovery and optimization of SACs. This review systematically discusses the application of AI technologies in SACs development through four key stages: (1) Density functional theory (DFT) and ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations: DFT and AIMD are used to investigate catalytic mechanisms, with high-throughput applications significantly expanding accessible datasets; (2) Regression models: ML regression models identify key features that influence catalytic performance, streamlining the selection of promising materials; (3) NNs: NNs expedite the screening of known structural models, facilitating rapid assessment of catalytic potential; (4) Generative adversarial networks (GANs): GANs enable the prediction and design of novel high-performance catalysts tailored to specific requirements. This work provides a comprehensive overview of the current status of AI applications in SACs and offers insights and recommendations for future advancements in the field.</description>
      <author>Qiumei Yu, Ninggui Ma, Chihon Leung, Han Liu, Y. Ren, Zhanhua Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/jmi.2024.78</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Performance Nickel&#8211;Bismuth Oxide Electrocatalysts Applicable to Both the HER and OER in Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15514</link>
      <description>Seunghyun Jo, Byeol Kang, SiEon An, Hye Bin Jung, JunHwa Kwon, Hyunjun Oh, Jieun Lim, Pilsoo Choi, Je-Myung Oh, Ki&#8208;Yeop Cho, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, MinJoong Kim, Joo&#8208;Hyoung Lee, KwangSup Eom, Thomas F. Fuller, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407386303

                As an electrocatalyst for water electrolysis, nickel oxide (NiO) has received significant attention due to its cost-effectiveness and high reactivity among non-noble-metal-based catalytic materials. However, NiO still exhibits poor alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics compared to conventional noble metal-based catalysts. This is because NiO has a strong interaction with protons for the HER and too low free energy of the OH* state, resulting in slower rate-determining step (RDS) kinetics for the OER. To address these issues, adding a dopant is suggested as an efficient method to modify the electron structure of the NiO electrocatalyst favorably for each reaction kinetics. In this context, we demonstrate that Bismuth (Bi), due to its higher electronegativity than that of Nickel (Ni), induces a positive charge on Ni sites. This enhances the catalytic activity by reducing the number of excessive cation interactions with the NiO electrocatalyst. Moreover, as the Bi ratio increases, the Ni reaction sites in NiO become more positively charged, and these changes in the electronic structure directly impact the free energy of the reaction mechanism. Particularly, it is confirmed that for the HER, Bi additives increase the proton-adsorbed free energy toward a near-zero value and, additionally, decrease the free energy difference of the second step considered as the RDS in the OER, as calculated by density functional theory. The positive effects of Bi in both the HER and the OER are demonstrated in practical electrochemical evaluations of half/single cells. Notably, the Bi-containing catalysts Bi05:NiO and Bi02:NiO exhibit remarkable alkaline HER and OER kinetics, showing performance improvements of 97.0% and 21.9%, respectively.</description>
      <author>Seunghyun Jo, Byeol Kang, SiEon An, Hye Bin Jung, JunHwa Kwon, Hyunjun Oh, Jieun Lim, Pilsoo Choi, Je-Myung Oh, Ki&#8208;Yeop Cho, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, MinJoong Kim, Joo&#8208;Hyoung Lee, KwangSup Eom, Thomas F. Fuller</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multienzyme-Activity Sulfur Quantum Dot Nanozyme-Mediated Cascade Reactions in Whole-Stage Symptomatic Therapy of Infected Bone Defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c12343</link>
      <description>Jiangshan Liu, Jiawei Wei, Shiqi Xiao, Yuan Li, Huan Liu, Yi Zuo, Yubao Li, Jidong Li, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407388731

                Integrating the therapeutic efficacy of early bacterial clearance, midstage inflammatory remission, and late-stage effective tissue healing is considered a pivotal challenge in symptomatic treatment of infected bone defects (IBDs). Herein, a microenvironment-adaptive nanoplatform based on a sulfur quantum dot (SQD) nanozyme was proposed for whole-stage symptomatic therapy of IBDs by mediating the sequence of enzyme cascade reactions. The SQD nanozyme prepared by a size-engineering modification strategy exhibits enhanced multienzyme activity compared to conventional micrometer- and nanometer-sized sulfur particles. In the early stages of bacterial infection, the SQD nanozyme self-activates superoxide dismutase-peroxidase activity, resulting in the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) that effectively eliminate bacteria. After disinfection, the SQD nanozyme self-switched to superoxide dismutase-catalase mimetic behavior and eliminated excess ROS, efficiently promoting macrophage polarization to an anti-inflammatory phenotype in the midinflammatory microenvironment. Importantly, SQD nanozyme-mediated M2 macrophage polarization significantly improved the damaged bone immune microenvironment, accelerating bone repair at late-stage tissue healing. Therefore, this strategy offers a promising and viable approach for the treatment of infectious tissue healing by developing multienzyme-activity nanozymes that respond intelligently to the microenvironment at different stages, effectively fighting bacteria, reducing inflammation, and promoting tissue regeneration for whole-stage symptomatic therapy.</description>
      <author>Jiangshan Liu, Jiawei Wei, Shiqi Xiao, Yuan Li, Huan Liu, Yi Zuo, Yubao Li, Jidong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c12343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Metal-Phthalocyanine 2D Covalent Organic Frameworks for the Nitrogen Reduction Reaction: Cooperativity of Transition Metals and Organic Linkers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20810</link>
      <description>Yuji Zhao, Jiawei Xu, Ziyue Huang, Yu Wang, Yafei Li, Hai&#8208;Yan Wei, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407389752

                Two-dimensional covalent organic frameworks (2D-COFs) exhibit high activity in the electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR), while the structure-performance relationship toward which remains an unsolved problem, therefore hindering the development of efficient catalysts. In this work, a total of 145 candidate transition metal phthalocyanine (TMPc-DX) materials comprised of 29 transition metals and X-phthalocyanine (X = N, O, F, S, and Cl) are evaluated for their capabilities in the NRR by density functional theory calculations. Our computations showed that metal atoms in TMPc-DN/DF/DCl materials could efficiently activate N2 molecules by doping with electron-withdrawing groups. The catalysts MoPc-DN and NbPc-DN are recognized to exhibit the highest electrocatalytic performance for the NRR with the lowest limit potentials of 0.31 and 0.32 V, respectively. Moreover, NbPc-DN showed a significant advantage by suppressing the hydrogen evolution reaction, making it a top contender among TMPc-DX materials for the electrocatalytic NRR. Through detailed orbital interaction analysis, our research has demonstrated that embedding transition metals into the substrate (Pc-DX) results in a direct correlation between the number of electrons transferred to the substrate and the reduction of energy splitting of the metal's d orbital, which directly causes a decrease in the metal's magnetic moment. Consequently, the affinity of the metal for N2 adsorption is directly proportional to the extent of the electron transfer. Our findings underscore the significance of the material's magnetic moment as a preliminary indicator for gauging the effectiveness of N2 adsorption.</description>
      <author>Yuji Zhao, Jiawei Xu, Ziyue Huang, Yu Wang, Yafei Li, Hai&#8208;Yan Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20810</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Reactive Force Field for the Molecular Dynamics Simulation of Borate Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s0022476625010159</link>
      <description>L. A. Avakyan, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1057;&#1082;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Ya. A. Vakulenko, Evgeny Tretyakov, G. Yu. Shakhgyldyan, &#1042;. &#1053;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1075;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, &#1051;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1075;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, Journal of Structural Chemistry. 66(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407393777

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. A. Avakyan, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1057;&#1082;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Ya. A. Vakulenko, Evgeny Tretyakov, G. Yu. Shakhgyldyan, &#1042;. &#1053;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1075;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, &#1051;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1075;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s0022476625010159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ordered Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Mn Intermetallic Setting the Maximum Threshold Activity of Disordered Variants for Glycerol Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c16468</link>
      <description>Xuedong Zhang, Xiaowen Sun, Mingtao Li, Yujie Shi, Zhe Wang, Kepeng Song, Egon Campos dos Santos, Hong Liu, Xiaowen Yu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407394750

                Glycerol electrolysis is a promising strategy for generating hydrogen at the cathode and value-added products at the anode. However, the effect of the atomic distribution within catalysts on their catalytic performance remains largely unexplored, primarily because of the inherent complexity of the glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR). Herein, an ordered Pt3Mn (O-Pt3Mn) intermetallic compound and a disordered Pt3Mn (D-Pt3Mn) alloy are used as model catalysts, and their performance in the GOR and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is studied. O-Pt3Mn consistently outperforms D-Pt3Mn and commercial Pt/C catalysts. It can generate high-value glycerate at a notable production rate of 17 mM h&#8211;1 while achieving an impressively low cell voltage of 0.76 V for glycerol electrolysis, which is &#8764;0.98 V lower than that required for water electrolysis. Statistical analysis using theoretical calculations reveals that Pt&#8211;Pt&#8211;Pt hollow sites are crucial for the catalytic GOR and HER. The averaged adsorption energies of key intermediates (simplified as C*, O*, and H*) on diverse catalysts closely correlate with their experimentally observed activity. Our proposed linear models accurately predict these adsorption energies, exhibiting high correlation coefficients ranging from 0.97 to 0.99 and highlighting the significance of the distribution of the topmost and subsurface-corner Mn atoms in determining these adsorption energies. By sampling all possible Mn configurations within the fitted linear models, we confirm that O-Pt3Mn establishes the maximum activity threshold for the GOR and HER compared with any disordered variant. This study presents an innovative framework for exploring the effect of the atomic distribution within catalysts on their catalytic performance and designing high-performance catalysts for complex reactions.</description>
      <author>Xuedong Zhang, Xiaowen Sun, Mingtao Li, Yujie Shi, Zhe Wang, Kepeng Song, Egon Campos dos Santos, Hong Liu, Xiaowen Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c16468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Conformational Sampling to Model Spectral and Structural Changes of Molecules at Elevated Pressures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c08065</link>
      <description>Felix Zeller, Philipp Pracht, Tim Stauch, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407406136

                Conformational sampling is nowadays a standard routine in computational chemistry. Within this work, we present a method to perform conformational sampling for systems exposed to elevated pressures within the CREST program, allowing us to model pressure-induced changes of molecular ensembles and structural parameters. For this purpose, we extend the molecular Hamiltonian with the PV (pressure times volume) term, using the solvent-accessible volume. The volume computation is performed within the new standalone library libpvol. A first application shows good agreement with experimental data and provides a reasonable explanation for severe pressure-induced structural and spectroscopic changes of the molecules dichloroethane and tetra(4-methoxyphenyl)ethylene.</description>
      <author>Felix Zeller, Philipp Pracht, Tim Stauch</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c08065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles design of a superior electrocatalyst to Pt for hydrogen production in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08250h</link>
      <description>Haeshik Lee, Jinwoo Park, Jae&#8208;Min Myoung, Byungchan Han, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407407344

                Elucidation of the key mechanism of the inactive Pt catalyst for hydrogen production in alkaline media and description of two control factors for the catalytic activity of a pseudo-binary Pt&#8211;M catalyst.</description>
      <author>Haeshik Lee, Jinwoo Park, Jae&#8208;Min Myoung, Byungchan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08250h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Band-Gap Regression with Architecture-Optimized Message-Passing Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01988</link>
      <description>Tim Bechtel, Daniel T. Speckhard, Jonathan Godwin, Claudia Draxl, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407410240

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tim Bechtel, Daniel T. Speckhard, Jonathan Godwin, Claudia Draxl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density of States and Binding Energy Informatics for Exploring Early Disease Detection in MOF&#8208;Metal Oxide Chemiresistive Sensors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202401404</link>
      <description>Maryam Nurhuda, Ken&#8208;ichi Otake, Susumu Kitagawa, Daniel M. Packwood, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407411165

                Abstract Human breath contains over 3000 volatile organic compounds, abnormal concentrations of which can indicate the presence of certain diseases. Recently, metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF)&#8208;metal oxide composite materials have been explored for chemiresistive sensor applications, however their ability to detect breath compounds associated with specific diseases remains unknown. In this work, a new high&#8208;throughput computational protocol for evaluating the sensing ability of MOF&#8208;metal oxide toward small organic compounds is presented. This protocol uses a cluster&#8208;based method for accelerated structure relaxation, and a combination of binding energies and density&#8208;of&#8208;states analysis to evaluate sensing ability, the latter measured using Wasserstein distances. This protocol is applied to the case of the MOF&#8208;metal oxide composite material NM125&#8208;TiO 2 and is shown to be consistent with previously reported experimental results for this system. The sensing ability of NM125&#8208;TiO 2 for over 100 human&#8208;breath compounds spanning 13 different diseases is examined. Statistical inference is then used to identify diseases which subsequent experimental efforts should focus on. Overall, this work provides new tools for computational sensor research, while also illustrating how computational materials science can be integrated into the field of preventative medicine.</description>
      <author>Maryam Nurhuda, Ken&#8208;ichi Otake, Susumu Kitagawa, Daniel M. Packwood</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202401404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalyst anchoring on 8-16-4-graphyne nanosheet: An efficient electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.079</link>
      <description>Ghazaleh Jafari, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 109(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407413030

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ghazaleh Jafari, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect modeling in semiconductors: the role of first principles simulations and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7639/adb181</link>
      <description>Md. Habibur Rahman, Arun Mannodi&#8208;Kanakkithodi, Journal of Physics Materials. 8(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407417086

                Abstract Point defects in semiconductors dictate their electronic and optical properties. Vacancies, interstitials, substitutional defects, and defect complexes can form in the semiconductor lattice and significantly impact its performance in applications such as solar absorption, light emission, electronics, and catalysis. Understanding the nature and energetics of point defects is essential for the design and optimization of next-generation semiconductor technologies. Here, we provide a comprehensive overview of the current state of research on point defects in semiconductors, focusing on the application of density functional theory (DFT) and machine learning (ML) in accelerating the prediction and understanding of defect properties. DFT has been instrumental in accurately calculating defect formation energies, charge transition levels, and other defect-related properties such as carrier recombination rates and lifetimes, and ion migration barriers. ML techniques, particularly neural networks, have emerged as powerful tools for enabling rapid prediction of defect properties at DFT-accuracy in order to overcome the expense of using large supercells and advanced functionals. We begin this article with a discussion of different types of point defects and complexes, their impact on semiconductor properties, and the experimental and DFT approaches typically used for their characterization. Through multiple case studies, we explore how DFT has been successfully applied to understand defect behavior across a variety of semiconductors, and how ML approaches integrated with DFT can efficiently predict defect properties and facilitate the discovery of new materials with tailored defect behavior. Overall, the advent of &#8216;DFT+ML&#8217; promises to drive advancements in semiconductor technology, catalysis, and renewable energy applications, paving the way for the development of high-performance semiconductors which are defect-tolerant or have desirable dopability.</description>
      <author>Md. Habibur Rahman, Arun Mannodi&#8208;Kanakkithodi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7639/adb181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Oxygen Evolution on Ni-Doped MoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;: Overcoming Activity&#8211;Stability Trade-Off in Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/cbe.4c00160</link>
      <description>Ankit Kumar Verma, Shahan Atif, Abhisek Padhy, Tej S. Choksi, Prabeer Barpanda, Ananth Govind Rajan, Chem &amp; Bio Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407417191

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ankit Kumar Verma, Shahan Atif, Abhisek Padhy, Tej S. Choksi, Prabeer Barpanda, Ananth Govind Rajan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/cbe.4c00160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Bridged&#8208;H* Bond Structure for Boosting Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution via Phosphorus&#8208;Doped Iridium Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412338</link>
      <description>Ruiqi Guo, Shujuan Wang, Minqi Sheng, Xingli Zou, Mingzhi Zhang, Guangcheng Li, Yi Cao, Zhenglong Fan, Jinxin Chen, Wenxiang Zhu, Fan Liao, Tao Ling, Hao Ren, Fan Lv, Zhenhui Kang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407421061

                Abstract Iridium (Ir) is recognized to have extremely high catalytic activity in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, there are still technical challenges in maximizing the utilization of Ir atoms in the catalytic reaction process through dimensional regulation strategies. Herein, an innovative strategy is utilized to fabricate porous phosphorus&#8208;doped iridium (P&#8208;Ir) with a 2D structure, specifically the reduction of 1T phase&#8208;IrO 2 (1T&#8208;IrO 2 ) nanosheets using phosphine gas. The optimized P&#8208;Ir achieves an overpotential of 17.2 mV (vs RHE without i R&#8208;correction) in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 during the HER process, outperforming benchmark Pt/C (27.0 mV) and most reported Ir&#8208;based electrocatalysts. During the long&#8208;term stability tests, P&#8208;Ir maintains stable operation for more than 100 h at both &#8722;10 and &#8722;100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. Moreover, the HER activity and transient potential scanning results of Ir&#8208;based phosphides prove that doping P atoms in the Ir lattice promotes the reaction kinetic rate and charge transport capacity during hydrogen evolution. Theoretical calculations reveal that P atoms doping weakens the adsorption energy of H intermediates (H*) by regulating the d &#8208;band center of the Ir sites. Simultaneously, the desorption process of H* is also facilitated by forming a special bridged&#8208;H* bond structure, eventually accelerating the HER kinetics.</description>
      <author>Ruiqi Guo, Shujuan Wang, Minqi Sheng, Xingli Zou, Mingzhi Zhang, Guangcheng Li, Yi Cao, Zhenglong Fan, Jinxin Chen, Wenxiang Zhu, Fan Liao, Tao Ling, Hao Ren, Fan Lv, Zhenhui Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative study on Co3+, Co2+, and oxygen vacancies in the photocatalytic ozonation of VOCs on Co3O4 crystal facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.132072</link>
      <description>Jinze Lyu, Ting Zhang, Ji Li, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407423537

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinze Lyu, Ting Zhang, Ji Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.132072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain boundary engineering on Cu-based electrocatalysts promotes nitrate reduction to ammonia production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.01.036</link>
      <description>Xiaotian Guo, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Zehua Gao, Lei Wang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407425162

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaotian Guo, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Zehua Gao, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.01.036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspired by nitrogenase: Who is the better electron donor for FeMo active site in nitrogen reduction reaction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2025.101839</link>
      <description>Yizhen Zhang, Hui Zhang, Xin Chen, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407437960

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yizhen Zhang, Hui Zhang, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2025.101839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of Two New Janus materials MgZnS and MgZnSe with a Sandwich Configuration for Photocatalytic Water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.optmat.2025.116810</link>
      <description>Abdelmajid Es-saadi, Zakaryae Haman, Moussa Kibbou, Aznague Lahcen, I. Essaoudi, A. Ainane, Optical Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407438671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdelmajid Es-saadi, Zakaryae Haman, Moussa Kibbou, Aznague Lahcen, I. Essaoudi, A. Ainane</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.optmat.2025.116810</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ammonia Synthesis via Nitric Oxide Electrochemical Reduction on OH-MXenes: A Universal Descriptor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07568</link>
      <description>Lu Liu, Yuncai Zhao, Xuan Lin, Chun-Xia Ren, Yijing Gao, Weidong Zhu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407451847

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Liu, Yuncai Zhao, Xuan Lin, Chun-Xia Ren, Yijing Gao, Weidong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-row transition metal/N-doped Boron Phosphide monolayer as single-atom catalysts for electrochemical reduction of CO2 towards CO: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoes.2025.100970</link>
      <description>Hefei Gao, Quande Che, International Journal of Electrochemical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407482224

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hefei Gao, Quande Che</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoes.2025.100970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the effect of active site's coordination number on the oxygen reduction reaction activity of Fe-Co dual-atom catalysts: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.124</link>
      <description>Anuj Kumar, Mohd Ubaidullah, Ghulam Yasin, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 109(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407485711

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anuj Kumar, Mohd Ubaidullah, Ghulam Yasin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prospects of using High Entropy Oxides as Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101670</link>
      <description>Katrine L. Svane, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407509475

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Katrine L. Svane</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical and Experimental Studies of the Structural Chameleon EuYCuTe3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18040820</link>
      <description>&#1040;nna V. Ruseikina, Maxim V. Grigoriev, V. A. Chernyshev, E. M. Roginski&#301;, Alexander A. Garmonov, Ralf J. C. Locke, Thomas Schleid, Materials. 18(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407531841

                Layered orthorhombic single crystals of EuYCuTe3 are synthesized using the ampoule method from the elemental precursors taken in the ratio of 1 Eu:1 Y:1 Cu:3 Te by heating up to 1120 K with an excess of CsI as flux. The orthorhombic structure of EuYCuTe3 is established, and structural parameters are obtained using X-ray diffraction. At ambient conditions, the sample crystallizes in the space group Pnma with the unit cell parameters a = 11.2730(7) &#197;, b = 4.3214(3) &#197;, c = 14.3271(9) &#197;. The structure is composed of vertex-connected [CuTe4]7&#8722; tetrahedra, which form chains along the [010] direction, and of edge-connected [YTe6]9&#8722; octahedra, which form layers parallel to the (010) plane. The Eu2+ cations are found in a capped trigonal prismatic coordination of Te2&#8722; anions. The structural phase transition from the &#945; to the &#946; phase is discovered upon heating the sample to 323 K, which comes accompanied with a decrease of [CuTe4]7&#8722; tetrahedral distortion. The symmetry of the high-temperature phase is established as ordered in the space group Cmcm (a = 4.3231(3) &#197;, b = 14.3328(9) &#197;, c = 11.2843(7) &#197;). The nature and microscopic mechanism of the phase transition is discussed. By cooling it down below 3 K, the soft ferromagnetic properties of EuYCuTe3 are discovered. The correlation of the ferromagnetic transition temperature in the series of chalcogenides EuYCuCh3 (Ch = S, Se, Te) with the ionic radius of the chalcogenide anion is established. The structural dynamical elastic properties of &#945;- and &#946;-EuYCuTe3 were calculated within the ab initio approach. The vibrational mode frequencies and decomposition on irreducible representations, as well as the degree of ion involvement in each mode, were determined. The calculations reveal an imaginary mode in the Y-point of the Brillouin zone in the high symmetry &#946;-EuYCuTe3 phase. This finding explains the nature of structural reconstruction in EuYCuTe3 crystal as a second-order phase transition induced by soft mode condensation at the edge of the Brillouin zone. The exfoliation of a single layer is simulated theoretically. The exfoliation energy is estimated, and the dynamical properties of EuYCuTe3 single layers are studied.</description>
      <author>&#1040;nna V. Ruseikina, Maxim V. Grigoriev, V. A. Chernyshev, E. M. Roginski&#301;, Alexander A. Garmonov, Ralf J. C. Locke, Thomas Schleid</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18040820</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Doping in Precious Metal Oxides: Accelerating Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms26041582</link>
      <description>Guoxin Ma, Fei Wang, Rui Jin, Bingrong Guo, Haohao Huo, Yilong Dai, Jefferson Zhe Liu, Jia Liu, Siwei Li, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 26(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407534851

                Developing a highly active and stable catalyst for acidic oxygen evolution reactions (OERs), the key half-reaction for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis, has been one of the most cutting-edge topics in electrocatalysis. A dual-doping strategy optimizes the catalyst electronic environment, modifies the coordination environment, generates vacancies, and introduces strain effects through the synergistic effect of two elements to achieve high catalytic performance. In this review, we summarize the progress of dual doping in RuO2 or IrO2 for acidic OERs. The three main mechanisms of OERs are dicussed firstly, followed by a detailed examination of the development history of dual-doping catalysts, from experimentally driven dual-doping systems to machine learning (ML) and theoretical screening of dual-doping systems. Lastly, we provide a summary of the remaining challenges and future prospects, offering valuable insights into dual doping for acidic OERs.</description>
      <author>Guoxin Ma, Fei Wang, Rui Jin, Bingrong Guo, Haohao Huo, Yilong Dai, Jefferson Zhe Liu, Jia Liu, Siwei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms26041582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Mo@&#947;-GDY triatomic catalyst for electrocatalytic urea synthesis of N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CO: a theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/jmi.2024.49</link>
      <description>Linyuan Chi, Tonghui Wang, Qing Jiang, Journal of Materials Informatics. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407555758

                While urea is widely used as a chemical raw material, its precursor ammonia (NH3) has traditionally been synthesized under high-temperature/pressure conditions, leading to not only huge energy consumption but also serious CO2 emission. Here, we present a groundbreaking catalyst design approach, which optimizes adsorption configurations and reaction pathways by controlling the adsorption energies of each intermediate in the reaction, thus enhancing catalytic performance. Via density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we designed a triatomic catalyst [i.e., Fe2Mo@&#947;-graphdiyne (&#947;-GDY)] with a limiting potential of -0.22 V and a C-N coupling energy barrier of 0.34 eV. Notably, the Fe2Mo@&#947;-GDY catalyst presents a high selectivity and robust antioxidation capabilities under applied potentials. Our comprehensive analysis elucidates the factors affecting the limiting potential and C-N coupling energy barrier. These insights significantly contribute to the advancement of catalyst design strategies for electrocatalytic urea synthesis, offering a more efficient and eco-friendly alternative to traditional methods.</description>
      <author>Linyuan Chi, Tonghui Wang, Qing Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/jmi.2024.49</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence&#8208;Assisted Experimental Optimization of Water Oxidation Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cite.202400156</link>
      <description>Henrik Spitzenpfeil, Marius Neumann, Nick Hausen, Regina Palkovits, Stefan Palkovits, Chemie Ingenieur Technik. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407560244

                Abstract Artificial intelligence (AI) methods are very often used to make predictions for datasets that were created externally in arbitrary experiments or on already literature known datasets. In this work, we try to make use of active learning techniques to search for an optimal strategy for the startup&#8208;phase of bulk nickel electrodes in the oxygen evolution reaction. The data collected was afterwards reduced in dimensions and used to extract additional information that were learned via an artificial neural network (ANN) on the dataset, respectively.</description>
      <author>Henrik Spitzenpfeil, Marius Neumann, Nick Hausen, Regina Palkovits, Stefan Palkovits</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cite.202400156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in Sustainable Electrolytic Manganese Recovery: Techniques, Mechanisms, and Future Trends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling10010026</link>
      <description>Yunyu Li, Xuhai Pan, Bahman Amini Horri, Recycling. 10(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407561961

                Electrolytic manganese metal (EMM) produced from recyclable resources has recently gained increasing attention due to the scarcity of high-quality manganese natural resources and its broad range of applications. This review has summarised recent progress in manganese recovery techniques, including pyrometallurgy and hydrometallurgy. It has also critically assessed the processes and mechanisms involved in manganese electrodeposition for the Mn chloride- and Mn sulphate-based systems, with a major focus on electrode reactions and Mn nucleation growth. The key optimisation factors influencing manganese electrodeposition, such as electrolytes, power consumption, additives, cell structures, and electrode materials, were analysed, with particular attention to their impact on current efficiency, specific energy consumption, and product quality. The recent research directions were also highlighted to address practical challenges and enhance the sustainability of the EMM process, which mainly includes improving the ecological outcomes and reducing both the operating and investment costs. Promising strategies for the simultaneous production of EMM and electrolytic manganese dioxide (EMD) were also identified, which mainly comprised applying membrane technology, electrodeposition from ionic liquids, recycling and reusing waste materials, and exploring hybrid techniques. The results of this study showed that the prospective optimisation approaches for EMM are mainly driven by the need to enhance efficiency, reduce costs, and improve product quality through sustainable technological advancements. This review can be used as a comprehensive guide for manganese electrodeposition approaches for both practical and scientific research communities.</description>
      <author>Yunyu Li, Xuhai Pan, Bahman Amini Horri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/recycling10010026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional materials-based cathodes for high-performance microbial fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.432</link>
      <description>Lina Jaya Diguna, R.R.S.P.S. Dewi, Tobias Haposan, Fidelis Stefanus Hubertson Simanjuntak, Arramel Arramel, Marcelinus Christwardana, Muhammad Danang Birowosuto, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 109(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407564512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lina Jaya Diguna, R.R.S.P.S. Dewi, Tobias Haposan, Fidelis Stefanus Hubertson Simanjuntak, Arramel Arramel, Marcelinus Christwardana, Muhammad Danang Birowosuto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective adsorption, structure and dynamics of CO2 &#8211; CH4 mixture in mg-MOF-74 and the influence of Intercrystalline disorder</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112661</link>
      <description>Indu Dhiman, David R. Cole, Siddharth Gautam, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407568053

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Indu Dhiman, David R. Cole, Siddharth Gautam</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112661</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reliable Modeling of Co-Copper Catalysis: Hubbard and Dispersion Effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5138423</link>
      <description>M. Olu&#351; &#214;zbek, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407572499

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Olu&#351; &#214;zbek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5138423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton Relay in Hydrogen-Bond Networks Promotes Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c00318</link>
      <description>Yuefei Li, Shishi Zhang, Boyang Li, Yaqiong Su, Jie Kong, Jiayuan Li, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407572951

                Common O-/H-down orientation of H2O molecules on electrocatalysts brings favorable OH/H delivery; however, adverse H/OH delivery in their dissociation process hampers the H2O dissociation kinetics of the alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). To overcome this challenge, we raised a synergetic H2O dissociation concept of metal-supported electrocatalysts involving efficient OH delivery from O-down H2O to the metal, timely proton relay from O-down H2O on the metal to H-down H2O on the support through the hydrogen-bond network, and prompt H delivery from H-down H2O to the support. After theoretically profiling that a high work function difference between the metal and the support (&#916;&#934;) induces a strong electric field at the metal&#8211;support interface that increases hydrogen-bond connectivity to promote proton relay, we practiced this concept over cobalt phosphide-supported ruthenium (Ru/CoP) catalysts with a high &#916;&#934; = 0.4 eV, achieving a record-high Ru utilization HER activity of 66.1 A mgRu&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.1 V vs RHE. The insights into this synergetic H2O dissociation mechanism provide opportunity for the design of bicomponent alkaline HER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuefei Li, Shishi Zhang, Boyang Li, Yaqiong Su, Jie Kong, Jiayuan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c00318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycine electrosynthesis by the co-reduction of oxalic and nitric acids on rutile TiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101266</link>
      <description>Shiming Li, Lin Li, Wei Du, Tao Jiang, Ming Gong, Jianping Xiao, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407578931

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiming Li, Lin Li, Wei Du, Tao Jiang, Ming Gong, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic Understanding of Hydrogen Coverage on RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110) Surface under Electrochemical Conditions from &lt;i&gt;Ab Initio&lt;/i&gt; Statistical Thermodynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07229</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, Jan Kloppenburg, Chia&#8208;Yi Lin, Luka Mitrovic, Simon Gelin, Ismaila Dabo, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich, Geoffroy Hautier, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407582575

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, Jan Kloppenburg, Chia&#8208;Yi Lin, Luka Mitrovic, Simon Gelin, Ismaila Dabo, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich, Geoffroy Hautier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Independent Tuning of Intermediate Energetics for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution via Synergistic Defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417098</link>
      <description>Ding Yuan, Xiaoyi Dou, Qing Zhang, Chun&#8208;Ting He, Chao Wu, Yang Li, Weijie Li, Linping Yu, Lei Zhang, Huan Liu, Shi Xue Dou, Ji Liang, Yuhai Dou, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407584253

                Abstract Electronic structure engineering via integrating different defects is the key to achieving independent tuning of intermediate energetics for efficient electrocatalyst design. Such a combination of defects is at the forefront of current research. Herein, W is etched from Co(OH) 2 to generate Co vacancies, which are then partially filled with La to form Co(OH) 2 &#8208;Co V &#8208;La D for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The results show that Co vacancy and La dopant induce more high&#8208;valence Co species under OER conditions and the most active center is a surface Co site that is adjacent to a surface Co vacancy and a subsurface La dopant on different sides, where the optimized electronic structure narrows the gap between Gibbs free energies of OH* (&#916;G OH* ) and OOH* (&#916;G OOH* ) and modifies &#916;G O* close to the midpoint, leading to high catalytic activity. The integration of synergistic defects offers an effective strategy to generate a range of defect atomic configurations and diverse electronic states, which enable the independent tuning of intermediate energetics, thereby unlocking the catalyst's full catalytic potential.</description>
      <author>Ding Yuan, Xiaoyi Dou, Qing Zhang, Chun&#8208;Ting He, Chao Wu, Yang Li, Weijie Li, Linping Yu, Lei Zhang, Huan Liu, Shi Xue Dou, Ji Liang, Yuhai Dou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janus MoSi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;As&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Decorated with Transition Metal Atoms as Efficient Bifunctional HER/OER and OER/ORR Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c21412</link>
      <description>Yazhao Yuan, Chunling Zhang, Xunzhe Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407586502

                It is of great importance to develop bifunctional electrocatalysts with high efficiency and low cost for water splitting and fuel cells. Herein, based on the new emerging two-dimensional material of MoSi2N4, we explore the potentials of novel Janus MoSi2P2As2 (labeled as MSPA) in electrocatalytic applications. We conduct a comprehensive study using first-principles calculations to explore the potential of Janus MoSi2P2As2 decorated with 13 kinds of transition metal atoms as efficient bifunctional catalysts for the hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction (HER/OER) and oxygen evolution/reduction reaction (OER/ORR). After screening, results show that Rh@MSPA and Au@MSPA can serve as bifunctional catalysts for OER/ORR with overpotentials of 0.27/0.29 V and 0.42/0.37 V, and Pt@MSPA exhibit great potential as HER/OER catalyst with an overpotential of -0.004/0.51 V. The solvation effect on catalytic activity is also investigated. The volcano diagrams are employed to depict the activity trends toward HER, OER, and ORR. The d-band center, ICOHP and intrinsic descriptor &#966; can serve as quantitative descriptors of ORR/OER activity and reveal the activity origin of OER/ORR. This study presents a viable approach for developing advanced electrocatalysts with multiple functionalities, thereby expanding the utilization of Janus MoSi2P2As2 in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Yazhao Yuan, Chunling Zhang, Xunzhe Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c21412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia over Cu-based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2025.121123</link>
      <description>Zhibin Zhang, Kailun Yu, Hui Wang, Zhaoyong Bian, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407587699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhibin Zhang, Kailun Yu, Hui Wang, Zhaoyong Bian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2025.121123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction: Advances, Insights, Challenges, and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101089</link>
      <description>Asghar Ali, Muhammad Qasim, S. Sakhi, Govindhan Maduraiveeran, Ali S. Alnaser, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407596623

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asghar Ali, Muhammad Qasim, S. Sakhi, Govindhan Maduraiveeran, Ali S. Alnaser</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategies to maximize the oxygen evolution reaction in layered double hydroxides by electronic defect engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100380</link>
      <description>Heyu Zhou, Jinjin Ban, Yonglong Shen, Yonghong Ning, Shanshan Zhang, Fanfan Liu, Guoqin Cao, Guosheng Shao, S. Ravi P. Silva, Junhua Hu, eScience. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407597464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Heyu Zhou, Jinjin Ban, Yonglong Shen, Yonghong Ning, Shanshan Zhang, Fanfan Liu, Guoqin Cao, Guosheng Shao, S. Ravi P. Silva, Junhua Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the Electron Density of Charged Systems Using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c08583</link>
      <description>Sherif Abdulkader Tawfik, Sunil Gupta, Svetha Venkatesh, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407451128

                The prediction of the electron density in molecules and crystals is a key pillar in the first-principles computation of their properties. Using machine learning to predict the electron density by using the atomic structure alone can save the computational cost of performing first-principles computations. While various machine learning approaches have been introduced for predicting the electron density, none of them predict the electron density for charged systems. This work extends a recent machine learning charge density model, DeepDFT, by including the charge of the structure as an input parameter into the model. We establish an input charge representation approach that successfully predicts the charged electron densities for several test cases, including charged defective perovskites, LiCoO2 supercells with multiple Li vacancies, diamond-based defects, metal-organic frameworks, and molecular crystals.</description>
      <author>Sherif Abdulkader Tawfik, Sunil Gupta, Svetha Venkatesh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c08583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supercapacitor Materials Database Generated using Web Scrapping and Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2025.108980</link>
      <description>Tikam C. Soni, Manoranjan Kumar Manoj, Mahima Verma, Manwendra K. Tripathi, Journal of Molecular Graphics and Modelling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407510795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tikam C. Soni, Manoranjan Kumar Manoj, Mahima Verma, Manwendra K. Tripathi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2025.108980</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
