<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 01:26:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Substitution and coordination effects of boron in Fe C and Fe N C single-atom catalysts for ORR: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115192</link>
      <description>Liang Sun, Zhiyu Wang, Yusu Wang, Yong Wang, Li Y, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408597576

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Sun, Zhiyu Wang, Yusu Wang, Yong Wang, Li Y</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposition of oxy-carbide of CrMnFeCoNi and measurement of catalytic activity on oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10800-025-02295-0</link>
      <description>Rongguang Wang, Ayumu Okawa, Mohammed Bazzaoui, Yunhan Ling, Journal of Applied Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408598548

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rongguang Wang, Ayumu Okawa, Mohammed Bazzaoui, Yunhan Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10800-025-02295-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational toolkit for predicting thickness of 2D materials using machine learning and autogenerated dataset by large language model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241511</link>
      <description>Chinedu Ekuma, AIP Advances. 15(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408612999

                The thickness of 2D materials not only plays a crucial role in determining the performance of nanoelectronic and optoelectronic devices but also introduces complexities in predicting volume-dependent properties, such as energy storage capacity, due to the intrinsic vacuum within these materials. Although a plethora of experimental techniques, including but not limited to optical contrast, Raman spectroscopy, nonlinear optical spectroscopy, near-field optical imaging, and hyperspectral imaging, facilitate the measurement of 2D material thickness, comprehensive data for many materials remain elusive. Over the past decade, the exponential proliferation of 2D materials and their heterostructures has outstripped the capabilities of conventional experimental and computational approaches. In this evolving landscape, machine learning (ML) has emerged as an indispensable tool, offering a scalable approach to augment these traditional methodologies. Addressing the critical gap, we introduce THICK2D&#8212;Thickness Hierarchy Inference and Calculation Kit for 2D Materials. This Python-based computational framework harnesses an autogenerated thickness database, developed using large language models, and advanced ML algorithms to facilitate the rapid and scalable estimation of material thickness, relying solely on crystallographic data. To demonstrate the utility and robustness of THICK2D, we successfully used the toolkit to predict the thickness of more than 8000 2D-based materials, sourced from two extensive 2D materials databases. THICK2D is disseminated as an open-source utility, accessible on GitHub at https://github.com/gmp007/THICK2D, and archived on Zenodo at https://10.5281/zenodo.11216648.</description>
      <author>Chinedu Ekuma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of order of transfer matrix exceptional points on transport at band edges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.125412</link>
      <description>Madhumita Saha, Bijay Kumar Agarwalla, Manas Kulkarni, Archak Purkayastha, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408614195

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Madhumita Saha, Bijay Kumar Agarwalla, Manas Kulkarni, Archak Purkayastha</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.125412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An overview of design strategies and recent advancements in complex 3d transition metal-based electrocatalysts for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44405-025-00001-4</link>
      <description>Seongbeom Lee, Yoojin Shin, Kyungbeen Yeom, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, No host. 1(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408622797

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical half-reaction in numerous electrochemical processes, such as water electrolysis, CO 2 reduction, and metal-air batteries, yet its sluggish kinetics significantly limit overall efficiency, requiring advanced catalysts. Earth-abundant transition metal-based multi-metal catalysts have emerged as promising alternatives to precious metal-based systems, offering tunable properties and enhanced catalytic performance, particularly in alkaline environments. Given the promising potential of these catalysts, an in-depth understanding of the relationship between their catalytic properties and activity is essential for enabling rational catalyst design. This review outlines fundamental OER mechanisms, followed by a discussion of design principles for multi-metal catalysts, focusing on activity descriptors and dynamic surface reconstruction. Recent advancements in multi-metal catalysts are evaluated, highlighting innovative strategies and breakthroughs. Lastly, the review addresses remaining challenges and future directions, emphasizing the need for deeper insights into synergistic interactions among catalyst components and the development of catalysts to meet practical-scale performance demands.</description>
      <author>Seongbeom Lee, Yoojin Shin, Kyungbeen Yeom, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44405-025-00001-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Layer Thickness Modulated the Catalytic Activity of Platinum for Oxygen Reduction and Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401978</link>
      <description>Sheng&#8208;Yao Lv, Jin Liu, Zhuoyang Xie, Li Li, Zidong Wei, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408633871

                Abstract Reducing platinum (Pt) usage and enhancing its catalytic performance in the hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are vital for advancing fuel cell technology. This study presents the design and investigation of monolayer and few&#8208;layer Pt structures with high platinum utilization, developed through theoretical calculations. By minimizing the metal thickness from 1 to 3 atomic layers, an atomic utilization rate ranging from 66.66% to 100% is achieved, in contrast to conventional multilayer Pt structures. This reduction resulted in a unique surface coordination environment. These thinner structures exhibited nonlinear fluctuations in key electronic characteristics&#8212;such as the d&#8208;band center, surface charge, and work function&#8212;as the atomic layer thickness decreased. These variations significantly impacted species adsorption and the Pt&#8208;H 2 O interfacial structure, which in turn affected the catalytic activity. Notably, 1&#8208;layer Pt exhibited the best performance for HOR, while 3&#8208;layer Pt showed high activity for both HOR and ORR. The findings establish a clear relationship between atomic layer thickness, surface characteristics, adsorption behavior, electric double&#8208;layer structure, and catalytic performance in Pt systems. This research contributes to a deeper understanding of precision atomic&#8208;structured electrocatalyst design and paves the way for the development of highly effective, low&#8208;loading Pt&#8208;based catalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Sheng&#8208;Yao Lv, Jin Liu, Zhuoyang Xie, Li Li, Zidong Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable B&#8208;Doped Cobalt Phosphide Nanosheets Engineered via Phosphorus Activation of Co&#8208;MOFs for High Efficiency Alkaline Water&#8208;Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500334</link>
      <description>Dun Chan, Jun Ho Seok, Seong Chan Cho, Manjinder Singh, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Sang Uck Lee, Seunghyun Lee, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408634657

                Abstract Introducing secondary heteroatoms and simultaneous in situ surface modification can enhance electrocatalysts by affecting their porosity for adjusting electrochemically active surface area (ECSA), number of active sites, and electronic properties, thus mitigating the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline media. Here, mesoporous 3D heterostructures of boron&#8208;doped cobalt phosphide@nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanosheet network arrays are successfully grown on Ni foam as free&#8208;standing bifunctional electrocatalysts with controlled phosphorous levels (B&#8208;CoP x @NC/NF, x = 0.25, 0.5, and 1). Boron doping induces the Co active sites to bind O* and OOH* intermediates. Meanwhile, an optimal phosphorous content also leads to ideal adsorption strength at each reaction step, satisfying the Sabatier principle well. The optimal B&#8208;CoP 0.5 @NC/NF requires low overpotentials of 248 mV for OER and 95 mV for HER with long&#8208;term stability. The B&#8208;CoP 0.5 @NC/NF (+/&#8722;) electrolyzer exhibits a low cell potential of 1.59 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for overall water&#8208;splitting, with superior activity compared to the RuO 2 /NF(+)//20%Pt/NF(&#8722;) electrolyzer at high current densities above 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . Such exceptional bifunctional activities are attributed to the modulated electronic structure, lower charge&#8208;transfer resistance, higher ECSA, and inductive effect of B&#8208;doping, thus boosting both OER and HER activities in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Dun Chan, Jun Ho Seok, Seong Chan Cho, Manjinder Singh, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Sang Uck Lee, Seunghyun Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale designing principle of M-N-C towards high performance PEMFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.91</link>
      <description>Wenxin Guo, Yinghuan Liu, Huang Zhou, Yuen Wu, Microstructures. 5(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408646567

                Among the reported non-precious-metal catalysts, metal-nitrogen-carbon (M-N-C) catalysts have emerged as a research cornerstone in the field of electrocatalysis, showcasing unparalleled activity in oxygen reduction reactions that rivals or even exceeds that of commercial Pt catalysts. Despite boasting high atom utilization and adjustable effective activity centers, M-N-C catalysts suffer from inadequate long-term stability under high-pressure and harshly acidic conditions within proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). This drawback poses a significant challenge that critically limits their potential for widespread applications. From this perspective, we commence by delineating the pivotal strategies to augment the performance of M-N-C catalysts at the microscopic level, including the tuning of the intrinsic activity of individual active sites and the manipulation of their quantity. Furthermore, we delve into the benefits derived from the synergistic effects unleashed by the incorporation of multi-component active sites. At the mesoscopic level, this perspective engages with the design principles aimed at enhancing the activity and stability of M-N-C catalysts within the intricate three-phase boundary of PEMFCs. Ultimately, we prospect the opportunities and challenges facing the future evolution of M-N-C catalysts, with the aim of offering comprehensive guidance for the design and advancement of highly stable M-N-C catalysts tailored for PEMFC applications.</description>
      <author>Wenxin Guo, Yinghuan Liu, Huang Zhou, Yuen Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.91</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orbital Matching Mechanism&#8208;Guided Synthesis of Cu&#8208;Based Single Atom Alloys for Acidic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500343</link>
      <description>Yi Xu, Jia&#8208;hui Li, Jia Chen Wu, Wenbo Li, Yuwei Yang, Haoran Wu, Huai Qin Fu, Minghui Zhu, Xue Lu Wang, Sheng Dai, Cheng Lian, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408648421

                Abstract Recent advancements in alloy catalysis have yield novel materials with tailored functionalities. Among these, Cu&#8208;based single&#8208;atom alloy (SAA) catalysts have attracted significant attention in catalytic applications for their unique electronic structure and geometric ensemble effects. However, selecting alloying atoms with robust dispersion stability on the Cu substrate is challenging, and has mostly been practiced empirically. The fundamental bottleneck is that the microscopic mechanism that governs the dispersion stability is unclear, and a comprehensive approach for designing Cu&#8208;based SAA systems with simultaneous dispersion stability and high catalytic activity is still missing. Here, combining theory and experiment, a simple yet intuitive d &#8208; p orbital matching mechanism is discovered for rapid assessment of the atomic dispersion stability of Cu&#8208;based SAAs, exhibiting its universality and extensibility for screening effective SAAs across binary, ternary and multivariant systems. The catalytic selectivity of the newly designed SAAs is demonstrated in a prototype reaction&#8208;acidic CO 2 electroreduction, where all SAAs achieve single&#8208;carbon product selectivity exceeding 70%, with Sb 1 Cu reaching a peak CO faradaic efficiency of 99.73 &#177; 2.5% at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work establishes the fundamental design principles for Cu&#8208;based SAAs with excellent dispersion stability and selectivity, and will boost the development of ultrahigh&#8208;performance SAAs for advanced applications such as electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Yi Xu, Jia&#8208;hui Li, Jia Chen Wu, Wenbo Li, Yuwei Yang, Haoran Wu, Huai Qin Fu, Minghui Zhu, Xue Lu Wang, Sheng Dai, Cheng Lian, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen evolution reaction mechanism of Ni3Mo3N catalyst with fast water dissociation kinetics in alkaline solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135083</link>
      <description>Xuehua Liu, Xiaohan Hu, Liming Cai, Song Chen, Y. T. Lin, Xiaoyun Ye, Weiguo Wang, Fuel. 394(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408650987

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuehua Liu, Xiaohan Hu, Liming Cai, Song Chen, Y. T. Lin, Xiaoyun Ye, Weiguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization strategies for carbon dioxide electroreduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161665</link>
      <description>Yingying Duan, Weidong Ruan, Jingqi Guan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408661982

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingying Duan, Weidong Ruan, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Proton Source for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electro-Reduction on Cu(100) Using Many-Body Perturbation Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14108</link>
      <description>Dongfang Cheng, Ziyang Wei, Philippe Sautet, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408666044

                The protonation of CO is recognized as the rate-determining step in the generation of C1 products during the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) on Cu surfaces. However, the detailed mechanism and the precise proton source remain elusive. While density functional theory (DFT) calculations at the GGA level have been widely used, they struggle to accurately describe adsorbate-metal interactions and surface stability. Here, we employed the Random Phase Approximation (RPA), a method based on many-body perturbation theory, to overcome these limitations. We coupled the RPA framework with the linearized Poisson&#8211;Boltzmann equation to model solvation effects and a surface charging method to account for the influence of the electrochemical potential. Our study reveals that in neutral or alkaline electrolytes, adsorbed surface water acts as the proton source for *CO reduction to *COH over a broad potential range via the Grotthuss mechanism. At highly negative potentials, solvent water becomes the primary proton donor, with multiple competing mechanisms observed. In contrast, DFT-GGA functionals significantly underestimate the reaction barriers for *COH formation and consistently predict solvent water as the proton source across all potentials of interest. Additionally, RPA offers distinct insights into H2O adsorption and highlights the significant range of reducing potentials within which surface *OH can exist, which is crucial for accurate CO2RR modeling. These insights illustrate a pronounced divergence between RPA and DFT-GGA results. Our findings offer a fresh perspective on proton transfer in CO2RR and establish a framework for future theoretical studies on electrochemical processes.</description>
      <author>Dongfang Cheng, Ziyang Wei, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Calculations of Hydrogen Absorption and Diffusivity in Bulk CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c11470</link>
      <description>J.C. Stimac, Nir Goldman, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408667030

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J.C. Stimac, Nir Goldman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c11470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase Engineering Modulates the Electronic Structure of the IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction for Efficient and Stable Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c18288</link>
      <description>Shougang Sun, Ziqi Wan, Yingying Xu, Xuemei Zhou, Wei Gao, Jinjie Qian, Jie Gao, Dong Cai, Yongjie Ge, Huagui Nie, Zhi Yang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408667767

                The engineering of dual-functional catalytic systems capable of driving complete water dissociation in acidic environments represents a critical requirement for advancing proton exchange membrane electrolyzer technology, yet significant challenges remain. In this work, we investigate an IrO2/MoS2/CNT heterostructure catalyst demonstrating enhanced bifunctional performance for both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under acidic conditions. Strategic incorporation of IrO2 into the MoS2/CNT heterojunction induces a partial phase transformation from 2H to the metastable 1T configuration in MoS2, thereby modulating the electronic structure of IrO2 and improving the catalytic performance for overall water splitting. The optimized IrO2/MoS2/CNT catalyst exhibited exceptional overpotentials of 9 mV (HER) and 182 mV (OER) at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in acidic media. Full-cell evaluations further confirmed its practical potential, showing a 1.47 V operation voltage that outperforms standard Pt/C||IrO2 counterparts by 120 mV. The experimental results revealed that the n&#8211;n heterojunction between IrO2/CNT and MoS2/CNT generates a built-in electric field, enhancing charge redistribution and electron transport. Moreover, density functional theory simulations further identify iridium centers as dominant catalytic loci, with a metastable 1T-MoS2 phase mediating charge equilibration at atomic interfaces. This modification facilitates *OH adsorption and *OOH deprotonation and lowers the kinetic barrier during the water-splitting process.</description>
      <author>Shougang Sun, Ziqi Wan, Yingying Xu, Xuemei Zhou, Wei Gao, Jinjie Qian, Jie Gao, Dong Cai, Yongjie Ge, Huagui Nie, Zhi Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c18288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive-precision potentials for large-scale atomistic simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245877</link>
      <description>David Immel, Ralf Drautz, Godehard Sutmann, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408672723

                Large-scale atomistic simulations rely on interatomic potentials, providing an efficient representation of atomic energies and forces. Modern machine-learning (ML) potentials provide the most precise representation compared to electronic structure calculations, while traditional potentials provide a less precise but computationally much faster representation and, thus, allow simulations of larger systems. We present a method to combine a traditional and a ML potential into a multi-resolution description, leading to an adaptive-precision potential with an optimum of performance and precision in large, complex atomistic systems. The required precision is determined per atom by a local structure analysis and updated automatically during simulation. We use copper as demonstrator material with an embedded atom model as classical force field and an atomic cluster expansion (ACE) as ML potential, but, in principle, a broader class of potential combinations can be coupled by this method. The approach is developed for the molecular-dynamics simulator LAMMPS and includes a load-balancer to prevent problems due to the atom dependent force-calculation times, which makes it suitable for large-scale atomistic simulations. The developed adaptive-precision copper potential represents the ACE-forces with a precision of 10 me V/&#197; and the ACE-energy exactly for the precisely calculated atoms in a nanoindentation of 4 &#215; 106 atoms calculated for 100 ps and shows a speedup of 11.3 compared with a full ACE simulation.</description>
      <author>David Immel, Ralf Drautz, Godehard Sutmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unassisted electrochemical H2O2 production coupled to glycerol oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00774-y</link>
      <description>Dongrak Oh, Seon Woo Hwang, Dong Yeon Kim, Jesse E. Matthews, Jin&#8208;Young Lee, Jaime E. Avil&#233;s Acosta, Sang&#8208;Won Lee, Yi Xu, Ara Cho, Dong Un Lee, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Dong&#8208;Hwa Seo, Ji&#8208;Wook Jang, Nature Synthesis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408672915

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongrak Oh, Seon Woo Hwang, Dong Yeon Kim, Jesse E. Matthews, Jin&#8208;Young Lee, Jaime E. Avil&#233;s Acosta, Sang&#8208;Won Lee, Yi Xu, Ara Cho, Dong Un Lee, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Dong&#8208;Hwa Seo, Ji&#8208;Wook Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00774-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNT&#8208;Supported RuNi Composites Enable High Round&#8208;Trip Efficiency in Regenerative Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500416</link>
      <description>Chunfeng Li, Danning Li, Lubing Li, Haozhou Yang, Yan Zhang, Jinzhan Su, Lei Wang, Bin Liu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408674747

                Abstract Regenerative fuel cells hold significant potential for efficient, large&#8208;scale energy storage by reversibly converting electrical energy into hydrogen and vice versa, making them essential for leveraging intermittent renewable energy sources. However, their practical implementation is hindered by the unsatisfactory efficiency. Addressing this challenge requires the development of cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts. In this study, a carbon nanotube (CNT)&#8208;supported RuNi composite with low Ru loading is developed as an efficient and stable catalyst for alkaline hydrogen and oxygen electrocatalysis, including hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, hydrogen oxidation, and oxygen reduction reaction. Furthermore, a regenerative fuel cell using this catalyst composite is assembled and evaluated under practical relevant conditions. As anticipated, the system exhibits outstanding performance in both the electrolyzer and fuel cell modes. Specifically, it achieves a low cell voltage of 1.64 V to achieve a current density of 1 A cm &#8722; 2 for the electrolyzer mode and delivers a high output voltage of 0.52 V at the same current density in fuel cell mode, resulting in a round&#8208;trip efficiency (RTE) of 31.6% without further optimization. The multifunctionality, high activity, and impressive RTE resulted by using the RuNi catalyst composites underscore its potential as a single catalyst for regenerative fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Chunfeng Li, Danning Li, Lubing Li, Haozhou Yang, Yan Zhang, Jinzhan Su, Lei Wang, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Intricacies of Glycerol Hydrodeoxygenation on Copper Surface: A Comprehensive Investigation with the Aid of Machine Learning Force Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00302</link>
      <description>Srishti Gupta, Ajin Rajan, Edvin Fako, Tiago J. Goncalves, Imke B. M&#252;ller, Jithin John Varghese, Ansgar Sch&#228;fer, Sandip De, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408682965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Srishti Gupta, Ajin Rajan, Edvin Fako, Tiago J. Goncalves, Imke B. M&#252;ller, Jithin John Varghese, Ansgar Sch&#228;fer, Sandip De</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient exploration of reaction pathways using reaction databases and active learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235715</link>
      <description>Domantas Kuryla, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Adri C. T. van Duin, Angelos Michaelides, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408687121

                The fast and accurate simulation of chemical reactions is a major goal of computational chemistry. Recently, the pursuit of this goal has been aided by machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs), which provide energies and forces at quantum mechanical accuracy but at a fraction of the cost of the reference quantum mechanical calculations. Assembling the training set of relevant configurations is key to building the MLIP. Here, we demonstrate two approaches to training reactive MLIPs based on reaction pathway information. One approach exploits reaction datasets containing reactant, product, and transition state structures. Using an SN2 reaction dataset, we accurately locate reaction pathways and transition state geometries of up to 170 unseen reactions. In another approach, which does not depend on data availability, we present an efficient active learning procedure that yields an accurate MLIP and converged minimum energy path given only the reaction end point structures, avoiding quantum mechanics driven reaction pathway search at any stage of training set construction. We demonstrate this procedure on an SN2 reaction in the gas phase and with a small number of solvating water molecules, predicting reaction barriers within 20 meV of the reference quantum chemistry method. We then apply the active learning procedure on a more complex reaction involving a nucleophilic aromatic substitution and proton transfer, comparing the results against the reactive ReaxFF force field. Our active learning procedure, in addition to rapidly finding reaction paths for individual reactions, provides an approach to building large reaction path databases for training transferable reactive machine learning potentials.</description>
      <author>Domantas Kuryla, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Adri C. T. van Duin, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Study of Tri-Atomic Catalyst-Loaded Two-Dimensional Graphenylene for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040296</link>
      <description>Zhenghao Li, Haifeng Wang, Yan Gao, Catalysts. 15(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408689546

                As the energy crisis and environmental pollution continue to intensify, the demand for clean energy has increased. Using two-dimensional materials to catalyze overall water splitting is an important pathway for clean energy production. This study investigated the catalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) of tri-atomic clusters supported on a two-dimensional material, graphenylene (GPN). The structural stability of GPN was thoroughly investigated, and materials were employed as substrates to support a series of 28 distinct trimer clusters composed of 3d, 4d, and 5d transition metals. Ideal combinations of these systems were screened and designed. The loading configurations of TM3@GPN in two different systems were systematically studied. The stability of the catalyst was assessed by calculating the binding and cohesive energies and by performing molecular dynamics simulations, to confirm the catalyst stability. The optimal bifunctional catalysts for overall water splitting were identified as Au3@GPN, Pt3@GPN, and Pd3@GPN, all of which demonstrated superior overall water splitting performance. As a novel two-dimensional material, biphenylene-based materials, when used to support metal clusters as bifunctional catalysts for water splitting, represent an efficient and innovative approach.</description>
      <author>Zhenghao Li, Haifeng Wang, Yan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender Inequality in Scientific Production at Unicamp: a scientometric analysis of female participation essential for equity (2019&#8211;2023)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/2331186x.2025.2480502</link>
      <description>M&#225;rcio Souza Martins, Francisco Tadeu Gon&#231;alves de Oliveira Foz, Oscar Eliel, Marilda Solon Teixeira Bottesi, Cogent Education. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408694460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M&#225;rcio Souza Martins, Francisco Tadeu Gon&#231;alves de Oliveira Foz, Oscar Eliel, Marilda Solon Teixeira Bottesi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/2331186x.2025.2480502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auxetic &#947;-SnO monolayer as a high-performance catalyst for light-driven water splitting and oxygen reduction: Unveiling screening descriptors via machine learning-assisted dimensionality reduction strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236811</link>
      <description>Renxian Qin, Yali Lu, Xihang Zhang, Yu-Ling Song, Qingjun Zhou, Qiang Zhang, Journal of Power Sources. 641(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408705851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Renxian Qin, Yali Lu, Xihang Zhang, Yu-Ling Song, Qingjun Zhou, Qiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Charge Dynamics in a Silver Single-Atom Catalyst During the Light-Driven Oxidation of Benzyl Alcohol to Benzaldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05208</link>
      <description>Areti Moutsiou, Andrea Olivati, Luis A. Cipriano, Alessandra Sivo, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Giovanni Di Liberto, M. A. Kanso, Robert Wojcieszak, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Annamaria Petrozza, Gianvito Vil&#233;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408706893

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Areti Moutsiou, Andrea Olivati, Luis A. Cipriano, Alessandra Sivo, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Giovanni Di Liberto, M. A. Kanso, Robert Wojcieszak, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Annamaria Petrozza, Gianvito Vil&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selectivity Control in the Nitrogen Reduction Reaction over Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C MXene by a Nitrogen-Rich Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04878</link>
      <description>Divya Singh, Samad Razzaq, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408707244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Divya Singh, Samad Razzaq, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Oxide Thermodynamics and Site-Blocking: A Computational Study of ORR Activity on Platinum Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00321</link>
      <description>Tom Demeyere, Tom Ellaby, Misbah Sarwar, David Thompsett, Chris&#8208;Kriton Skylaris, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408722053

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tom Demeyere, Tom Ellaby, Misbah Sarwar, David Thompsett, Chris&#8208;Kriton Skylaris</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design the transition metal dichalcogenides supported single-atom catalysts for electroreduction of nitrate to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121573</link>
      <description>Yawen Tong, Ning Yan, Chenghao Ye, Heng Liang, Ting Zeng, Jinzhe Zhang, Juntao Dai, Xiang&#8208;Kui Gu, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408723236

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yawen Tong, Ning Yan, Chenghao Ye, Heng Liang, Ting Zeng, Jinzhe Zhang, Juntao Dai, Xiang&#8208;Kui Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H&#8208;Embedding Induced Electron Localization in Pd Lattice for Improving Electrochemical Hydrogen Purification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500249</link>
      <description>Xuanwei Yin, Cong Wei, Chongyang Tang, Zenan Bian, B. Liu, Xinqiang Wang, Yaxiong Yang, Yanyan Fang, Hongge Pan, Gongming Wang, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408724624

                Electrochemical hydrogen purification (EHP) technology with high-efficiency and easy-operation holds great potential in blended hydrogen transportation, which is currently restricted to proton exchange membrane system and Pt-based catalysts. As promising candidates used in alkaline anion exchange membrane system, Pd-based catalysts are hampered by the intense interaction between H* and delocalized 4d electrons, resulting in unsatisfactory catalytic activity. In this study, a marked enhancement of the alkaline membrane-based EHP performance is achieved, with hydrogen purity up to 99.96% separated from a CH4-H2 mixture, by strategically incorporating interstitial H atoms into Pd lattices for improving the anodic hydrogen oxidation reaction. Detailed characterizations and density functional theory calculations elucidate that the presence of interstitial H localizes free electrons into Pd-H covalent bonds, thereby weakening the interaction between surface-adsorbed H* and the catalytic surface. Moreover, operando spectroscopies and ab initio molecular dynamic simulations reveal that the enhanced interaction between the catalyst surface and interfacial water by electron delocalization, facilitates the desorption of H* to the interfacial water layer during catalysis. This research highlights the pivotal role of electronic localization in modulating the adsorption strength of key reaction intermediates for the design of efficient Pd-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xuanwei Yin, Cong Wei, Chongyang Tang, Zenan Bian, B. Liu, Xinqiang Wang, Yaxiong Yang, Yanyan Fang, Hongge Pan, Gongming Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Prospects, Costs, and Risks of Carbon Capture and Storage Implementation in Germany</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100418</link>
      <description>Nicol&#225;s Malz, Pao-Yu Oei, Philipp Herpich, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408733460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicol&#225;s Malz, Pao-Yu Oei, Philipp Herpich</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing CoNiRuIrMn High-entropy Alloy Network for Boosting Electrocatalytic Activity toward Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.120964</link>
      <description>Yan Su, Linfeng Zhang, Weimo Li, Ruikai Qi, Mengxiao Zhong, Meijiao Xu, Wei Song, Xiaofeng Lu, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408735398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Su, Linfeng Zhang, Weimo Li, Ruikai Qi, Mengxiao Zhong, Meijiao Xu, Wei Song, Xiaofeng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.120964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different capture methods for various feed CO2 concentrations and flow rates from flue gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-025-03152-6</link>
      <description>Ph&#7841;m Th&#7883; Lan H&#432;&#417;ng, Y. B. N. Tran, Tuan B.H. Nguyen, Clean Technologies and Environmental Policy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408746088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ph&#7841;m Th&#7883; Lan H&#432;&#417;ng, Y. B. N. Tran, Tuan B.H. Nguyen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-025-03152-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D Borophene Nanostructures: Recent Advances in Synthesis, Characterization, and Emerging Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106296</link>
      <description>Maria Batool, Jahangir Ahmad Rather, Akhtar Hussain Malik, Waheed Ahmad Khanday, Waseem Ahmad Wani, Abdul Haleem Wani, Rakesh Bhaskar, Palanisamy Kannan, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408746543

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maria Batool, Jahangir Ahmad Rather, Akhtar Hussain Malik, Waheed Ahmad Khanday, Waseem Ahmad Wani, Abdul Haleem Wani, Rakesh Bhaskar, Palanisamy Kannan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel two-dimensional ZnO materials for enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163068</link>
      <description>Peixian Wang, Bin Song, Gaoling Zhao, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408755952

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peixian Wang, Bin Song, Gaoling Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-activated oxophilic surface of porous molybdenum carbide nanosheets promotes hydrogen evolution activity in alkaline environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137423</link>
      <description>Yong Li, Weining Song, Teng Gai, Lipeng Wang, Zhen Li, Peng He, Qi Liu, Lawrence Yoon Suk Lee, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408756062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Li, Weining Song, Teng Gai, Lipeng Wang, Zhen Li, Peng He, Qi Liu, Lawrence Yoon Suk Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Supported Annealing for Prediction of Grand Canonical Crystal Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7566/jpsj.94.044802</link>
      <description>Yannick Couzini&#233;, Yuya Seki, Yusuke Nishiya, Hirofumi Nishi, Taichi Kosugi, Shu Tanaka, Yu&#8208;ichiro Matsushita, Journal of the Physical Society of Japan. 94(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408757120

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yannick Couzini&#233;, Yuya Seki, Yusuke Nishiya, Hirofumi Nishi, Taichi Kosugi, Shu Tanaka, Yu&#8208;ichiro Matsushita</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7566/jpsj.94.044802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical Significance of Descriptors to Predict the Band Center of High&#8208;Entropy Nanoalloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70086</link>
      <description>Y&#363;suke Nanba, Michihisa Koyama, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408748740

                ABSTRACT The band center of d orbitals ( d &#8208;band center) has been widely used as an effective descriptor for analyzing material properties. However, in high&#8208;entropy nanoalloys, the diverse atomic environments present challenges in systematically exploring all possible combinations. Due to computational resource limitations, generating a sufficient number of samples is infeasible. Consequently, the d &#8208;band center should be treated as a response variable in machine&#8208;learning models. We calculated the d &#8208;band center for individual atoms and applied supervised learning techniques to identify key factors influencing its behavior. While several factors were identified, their physical significance in predicting d &#8208;band centers remained unclear. To address this issue, we incorporated various interatomic distance terms as descriptors, along with element&#8208;based coordination numbers (ECN). The resulting model closely resembled the overlap integral of the Slater&#8208;type orbital, and the regression coefficients of the ECN exhibited sensitivity to the effective principal quantum number and nuclear charge. Understanding the physical significance of these descriptors is crucial for improving property predictions and facilitating data collection on novel materials.</description>
      <author>Y&#363;suke Nanba, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic transition metal dichalcogenides NixMo1-xSSe as efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction in protic electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135035</link>
      <description>R. Shwetharani, Samriti Mehta, Bhuneshwar Paswan, Itika Kainthla, Sumanth Dongre S, Amitava Banerjee, R. Geetha Balakrishna, Fuel. 394(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408751279

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Shwetharani, Samriti Mehta, Bhuneshwar Paswan, Itika Kainthla, Sumanth Dongre S, Amitava Banerjee, R. Geetha Balakrishna</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying &#960;-electron delocalization as a universal descriptor for ORR activity in MN4 catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116093</link>
      <description>Miao&#8208;Ying Chen, Jiabo Le, Haoran Wu, Weidong Li, Jianan Zhang, Bang&#8208;An Lu, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408768117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miao&#8208;Ying Chen, Jiabo Le, Haoran Wu, Weidong Li, Jianan Zhang, Bang&#8208;An Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur doping activated metal&#8211;support interaction drives Pt nanoparticles to achieve acid&#8211;base hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08499c</link>
      <description>Yagang Li, Jiaqing Luo, Peilin Liu, Liangkun Zhang, Weiyu Song, Yuechang Wei, Zhen Zhao, Xiao Zhang, Jian Liu, Yuanqing Sun, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408769162

                The sulfur doping strategy activates the interfacial effect, thereby promoting Pt NPs to attain efficient acid&#8211;base hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Yagang Li, Jiaqing Luo, Peilin Liu, Liangkun Zhang, Weiyu Song, Yuechang Wei, Zhen Zhao, Xiao Zhang, Jian Liu, Yuanqing Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08499c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice thermal conductivity in the anharmonic overdamped regime</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.104314</link>
      <description>&#272;or&#273;e Dangi&#263;, Giovanni Caldarelli, Raffaello Bianco, Ivana Savi&#263;, Ion Errea, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408776904

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#272;or&#273;e Dangi&#263;, Giovanni Caldarelli, Raffaello Bianco, Ivana Savi&#263;, Ion Errea</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.104314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spillover Dynamics in Heterogeneous Catalysis on Singe&#8208;Atom Alloys: A Theoretical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.70011</link>
      <description>Shuyu Lin, Rui Xiong, Jun Chen, Sen Lin, Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews Computational Molecular Science. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408778659

                ABSTRACT Recent advances in single&#8208;atom alloy ( SAA ) catalysts provide a unique platform for understanding spillover, due to the well&#8208;defined nature of the active site for dissociative chemisorption. In particular, the use of spilled adsorbates following molecular dissociation on the host metal surface facilitates the generation of high&#8208;value chemicals in subsequent catalytic reactions. Nevertheless, the factors that control the spillover process remain to be fully elucidated. This perspective discusses recent theoretical advances in the spillover dynamics on SAAs , with a particular focus on the dissociation and spillover processes of H 2 and CH 4 . It provides valuable insights into how various factors, such as energy transfer, nuclear quantum effects, gas&#8208;adsorbate interactions, and adsorbate size, impact the diffusion behavior of hydrogen and methyl species on SAA surfaces. The article concludes with a discussion of future prospects. This perspective underscores the significance of spillover dynamics in heterogeneous catalysis, with important implications for improving catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Shuyu Lin, Rui Xiong, Jun Chen, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.70011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Catalytic Selectivity of Reverse Water&#8211;Gas Shift Reaction Catalyzed by Ru/CeO2 Through the Addition of Yttrium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040301</link>
      <description>Alfredo Sol&#237;s-Garc&#237;a, Karina Portillo-Cortez, D. Dom&#237;nguez, S. Fuentes, J.N. D&#237;az de Le&#243;n, T.A. Zepeda, Uriel Caudillo&#8208;Flores, Catalysts. 15(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408778954

                This study reports the synthesis, characterization, and catalytic performance of a series of catalysts of Ru supported on CeO2-Y2O3 composites (Ru/CeYX; X = 0, 33, 66, and 100 wt.% Y2O3) for CO2 hydrogenation. Supported material modification (Y2O3-CeO2), by the Y2O3 incorporation, allowed a change in selectivity from methane to RWGS of the CO2 hydrogenation reaction. This change in selectivity is correlated with the variation in the physicochemical properties caused by Y2O3 addition. X-ray diffraction (XRD) analysis confirmed the formation of crystalline fluorite-phase CeO2 and &#945;-Y2O3. High-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM) and energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS) elemental mapping revealed the formation of a homogeneous CeO2-Y2O3 nanocomposite. As the Y2O3 content increased, the specific surface area, measured by BET, showed a decreasing trend from 106.3 to 51.7 m2 g&#8722;1. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) of Ce3d indicated a similar Ce3+/Ce4+ ratio across all CeO2-containing materials, while the O1s spectra showed a reduction in oxygen vacancies with increasing Y2O3 content, which is attributed to the decreased surface area upon composite formation. Catalytically, the addition of Y2O3 influenced both conversion and selectivity. CO2 conversion decreased with increasing Y2O3 content, with the lowest conversion observed for Ru/CeY100. Regarding selectivity, methane was the dominant product for Ru/CeY0 (pure CeO2), while CO was the main product for Ru/CeY33, Ru/CeY66, and Ru/CeY100, indicating a shift towards the reverse water&#8211;gas shift (RWGS) reaction. The highest RWGS reaction rate was observed with the Ru/CeY33 catalyst under all tested conditions. The observed differences in conversion and selectivity are attributed to a reduction in active sites due to the decrease in surface area and oxygen vacancies, both of which are important for CO2 adsorption. In order to verify the surface species catalytically active for RWGS, the samples were characterized by FTIR spectroscopy under reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Alfredo Sol&#237;s-Garc&#237;a, Karina Portillo-Cortez, D. Dom&#237;nguez, S. Fuentes, J.N. D&#237;az de Le&#243;n, T.A. Zepeda, Uriel Caudillo&#8208;Flores</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Promoting NO electrochemical reduction via N-N coupling by Surface-Adsorbed *NH intermediates on Mo2C nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116097</link>
      <description>Xiang Huang, Xiangting Hu, Jiong Wang, Hu Xu, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408782209

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Huang, Xiangting Hu, Jiong Wang, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedding transition metal atoms in S- modified porphyrin-expanded porphyrin tandem carbon-rich conjugated frameworks for efficient synthesis of C3 sugars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.112333</link>
      <description>Huan Xing, Ling Guo, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408783757

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Xing, Ling Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.112333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sol&#8211;Gel-Synthesized Pt, Ni and Co-Based Electrocatalyst Effects of the Support Type, Characterization, and Possible Application in AEM-URFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/gels11040229</link>
      <description>Elitsa Petkucheva, Borislava Mladenova, Mohsin Muhyuddin, Mariela Dimitrova, G. Borisov, Carlo Santoro, E. Slavcheva, Gels. 11(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408793889

                This study explores the synthesis and characterization of platinum (Pt), nickel (Ni), and cobalt (Co)-based electrocatalysts using the sol&#8211;gel method. The focus is on the effect of different support materials on the catalytic performance in alkaline media. The sol&#8211;gel technique enables the production of highly uniform electrocatalysts, supported on carbon-based substrates, metal oxides, and conductive polymers. Various characterization techniques, including X-ray diffraction (XRD) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM), were used to analyze the structure of the synthesized materials, while their electrochemical properties, which are relevant to their application in unitized regenerative fuel cells (URFCs), were investigated using cyclic voltammetry (CV) and linear sweep voltammetry (LSV). This hydrogen energy-converting device integrates water electrolyzers and fuel cells into a single system, reducing weight, volume, and cost. However, their performance is constrained by the electrocatalyst&#8217;s oxygen bifunctional activity. To improve URFC efficiency, an ideal electrocatalyst should exhibit high oxygen evolution (OER) and oxygen reduction (ORR) activity with a low bifunctionality index (BI). The present study evaluated the prepared electrocatalysts in an alkaline medium, finding that Pt25-Co75/XC72R and Pt75-Co25/N82 demonstrated promising bifunctional activity. The results suggest that these electrocatalysts are well-suited for both electrolysis and fuel cell operation in anion exchange membrane-unitized regenerative fuel cells (AEM-URFCs), contributing to improved round-trip efficiency.</description>
      <author>Elitsa Petkucheva, Borislava Mladenova, Mohsin Muhyuddin, Mariela Dimitrova, G. Borisov, Carlo Santoro, E. Slavcheva</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/gels11040229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy Engineering Activates Cu&#8208;Fe Inertia Center From Prussian Blue Analogs With Micro&#8208;Strains for Oxygen Electrocatalysis in Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.693</link>
      <description>Han Man, Guanyu Chen, Fengmei Wang, Jiafeng Ruan, Yihao Liu, Yang Liu, Fang Fang, Renchao Che, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408806535

                ABSTRACT By the random distribution of metals in a single phase, entropy engineering is applied to construct dense neighboring active centers with diverse electronic and geometric structures, realizing the continuous optimization of multiple primary reactions for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Many catalysts developed through entropy engineering have been built in nearly equimolar ratios to pursue high entropy, hindering the identification of the active sites and potentially diluting the concentration of real active sites while weakening their electronic interactions with reaction intermediates. Herein, this work proposes an entropy&#8208;engineering strategy in metal nanoparticle&#8208;embedded nitrogen carbon electrocatalysts, implemented by entropy&#8208;engineered Prussian blue analogs (PBA) as precursors to enhance the catalytic activity of primary Cu&#8208;Fe active sites. Through the introduction of the micro&#8208;strains driven by entropy engineering, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and geometric phase analysis (GPA) using Lorentz electron microscopy further elucidate the optimization of the adsorption/desorption of intermediates. Furthermore, the multi&#8208;dimensional morphology and the size diminishment of the nanocrystals serve to expand the electrochemical area, maximizing the catalytic activity for both ORR and OER. Notably, the Zn&#8208;air battery assembled with CuFeCoNiZn&#8208;NC operated for over 1300 h with negligible decay. This work presents a paradigm for the design of low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts with entropy engineering for multi&#8208;step reactions.</description>
      <author>Han Man, Guanyu Chen, Fengmei Wang, Jiafeng Ruan, Yihao Liu, Yang Liu, Fang Fang, Renchao Che</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Methanol Oxidation Catalysis by PtNi Nanowires with Controllable Element Distribution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c03303</link>
      <description>Xiaojie Jiang, Zhenyu Zhang, Xing Hu, Xu Zhen, Pei Zhang, Shan Zhu, Feng Liu, Kezhu Jiang, Shijian Zheng, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408810241

                Pt-based alloys with precisely controllable element distribution are highly sought after in catalysis. This study focuses on optimizing elemental distribution and alloying in PtNi alloy nanowires (NWs) through high-temperature heat treatment. The resulting PtNi alloy NWs with uniform elemental distribution (U-PtNi NWs) demonstrate exceptional stability, attributed to facilitated electron transfer and a denser Pt shell, in stark contrast to untreated NWs that suffer from elemental segregation and subsequent performance degradation during electrochemical testing. In methanol oxidation reaction tests, U-PtNi NWs demonstrated exceptional mass activity (1562.0 mA mg&#8211;1) and specific activity (5.38 mA cm&#8211;2), with minimal activity loss after 1000 cycles. This work emphasizes the significance of precise component control in developing high-performance catalysts and presents a strategy to enhance fuel cell performance through one-dimensional nanocomponent adjustment.</description>
      <author>Xiaojie Jiang, Zhenyu Zhang, Xing Hu, Xu Zhen, Pei Zhang, Shan Zhu, Feng Liu, Kezhu Jiang, Shijian Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c03303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystallization Instead of Amorphization in Collision Cascades in Gallium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.126101</link>
      <description>J. Zhao, Javier Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Alexander Azarov, Ru He, &#216;ystein Prytz, K. Nordlund, Mengyuan Hua, Flyura Djurabekova, Andrej Kuznetsov, Physical Review Letters. 134(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408815345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Zhao, Javier Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Alexander Azarov, Ru He, &#216;ystein Prytz, K. Nordlund, Mengyuan Hua, Flyura Djurabekova, Andrej Kuznetsov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.126101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Physicochemical Investigation on the Interaction of Aloe vera Extracts with Ascorbic Acid and Deoxyribonucleic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s0012501625600019</link>
      <description>Abbas Khan, Saira Naz, Muhammad Humayun, Noor Rehman, M. Bououdina, Nasrullah Shah, Khair Zaman, Khurram Shahzad Munawar, Doklady Physical Chemistry. 518(1-2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4408718269

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abbas Khan, Saira Naz, Muhammad Humayun, Noor Rehman, M. Bououdina, Nasrullah Shah, Khair Zaman, Khurram Shahzad Munawar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s0012501625600019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-specific stabilizing effect of single atoms on spinel oxides for acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100402</link>
      <description>Zhirong Zhang, Peiyu Ma, Chuanyi Jia, Wenting Gao, Mingkai Liu, Kwun Nam Hui, Ming J. Zuo, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng, eScience. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408608961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhirong Zhang, Peiyu Ma, Chuanyi Jia, Wenting Gao, Mingkai Liu, Kwun Nam Hui, Ming J. Zuo, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning interatomic potential for the low-modulus Ti-Nb-Zr alloys in the vicinity of dynamical instability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2025.113865</link>
      <description>B. O. Mukhamedov, Ferenc Tasn&#225;di, Igor A. Abrikosov, Materials &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408702791

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. O. Mukhamedov, Ferenc Tasn&#225;di, Igor A. Abrikosov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2025.113865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk-based process design and operations through an operability approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2025.03.010</link>
      <description>Beatriz Dantas, Austin Braniff, Claudemi A. Nascimento, Theodore Malencia, Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian, Process Safety and Environmental Protection. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408703185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Beatriz Dantas, Austin Braniff, Claudemi A. Nascimento, Theodore Malencia, Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2025.03.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Catalysis: Applying Graph Neural Networks for Intelligent Catalyst Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.70010</link>
      <description>Zhihao Wang, Wentao Li, Siying Wang, Xiaonan Wang, Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews Computational Molecular Science. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408782647

                ABSTRACT With the increasing global demand for energy transition and environmental sustainability, catalysts play a vital role in mitigating global climate change, as they facilitate over 90% of chemical and material conversions. It is important to investigate the complex structures and properties of catalysts for enhanced performance, for which artificial intelligence (AI) methods, especially graph neural networks (GNNs) could be useful. In this article, we explore the cutting&#8208;edge applications and future potential of GNNs in intelligent catalyst design. The fundamental theories of GNNs and their practical applications in catalytic material simulation and inverse design are first reviewed. We analyze the critical roles of GNNs in accelerating material screening, performance prediction, reaction pathway analysis, and mechanism modeling. By leveraging graph convolution techniques to accurately represent molecular structures, integrating symmetry constraints to ensure physical consistency, and applying generative models to efficiently explore the design space, these approaches work synergistically to enhance the efficiency and accuracy of catalyst design. Furthermore, we highlight high&#8208;quality databases crucial for catalysis research and explore the innovative application of GNNs in thermocatalysis, electrocatalysis, photocatalysis, and biocatalysis. In the end, we highlight key directions for advancing GNNs in catalysis: dynamic frameworks for real&#8208;time conditions, hierarchical models linking atomic details to catalyst features, multi&#8208;task networks for performance prediction, and interpretability mechanisms to reveal critical reaction pathways. We believe these advancements will significantly broaden the role of GNNs in catalysis science, paving the way for more efficient, accurate, and sustainable catalyst design methodologies.</description>
      <author>Zhihao Wang, Wentao Li, Siying Wang, Xiaonan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.70010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel and efficient In2O3@RhPt catalyst for solvent-free transfer hydrogenation of TDC to HTDC: Catalytic performance and mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161742</link>
      <description>Yaqi Qu, Min He, Hualiang An, Xinqiang Zhao, Yanji Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408704559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaqi Qu, Min He, Hualiang An, Xinqiang Zhao, Yanji Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161742</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
