<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 01:18:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>TM@MoSSe (TM = Ni, Fe) as novel electrocatalysts for reduction of CO2to CO: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114929</link>
      <description>Yu-Pu He, Tian-Hao Guo, Shao-Yi Wu, Shungui Zuo, Jinming Fu, Xiaoyu Li, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403527857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Pu He, Tian-Hao Guo, Shao-Yi Wu, Shungui Zuo, Jinming Fu, Xiaoyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the overpotential of overall water spitting by micro-pump-like electrode engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156788</link>
      <description>Tianbiao Zeng, Jie Lin, Biao Wang, Binbin Guo, Yi&#8208;hong Ding, Chang Q. Sun, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403529736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianbiao Zeng, Jie Lin, Biao Wang, Binbin Guo, Yi&#8208;hong Ding, Chang Q. Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Different Morphologies on the Catalytic Activity of Pt-Pd Nanostructures for Methanol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145241</link>
      <description>Dara Silva Santos, Aline B. Trench, I. M. Costa, Mauro C. Santos, Katlin I.B. Eguiluz, Giancarlo R. Salazar&#8208;Banda, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403531691

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dara Silva Santos, Aline B. Trench, I. M. Costa, Mauro C. Santos, Katlin I.B. Eguiluz, Giancarlo R. Salazar&#8208;Banda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu surface plasmon resonance promoted charge transfer in S-scheme system enhanced visible light photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.087</link>
      <description>Xingyan Yang, Nan Yang, Zhishi Qiu, Guoyang Qiu, Tong Zhou, Weijie Zhan, Yuandong Shen, Ke Wang, Chunting Zhao, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Jianhong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Qingju Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403531720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingyan Yang, Nan Yang, Zhishi Qiu, Guoyang Qiu, Tong Zhou, Weijie Zhan, Yuandong Shen, Ke Wang, Chunting Zhao, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Jianhong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly stable and active catalyst in fuel cells through surface atomic ordering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado4935</link>
      <description>Ma Yanling, Jiaheng Peng, Jiakang Tian, Wenpei Gao, Jialiang Xu, Fan Li, Peter Tieu, Hao Hu, Yi Wu, Yuanlong Zhao, Lei Pan, Wen Shang, Peng Tao, Chengyi Song, Hong Zhu, Xiaoqing Pan, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu, Science Advances. 10(42)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533158

                Shape-controlled alloy nanoparticle catalysts have been shown to exhibit improved performance in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in liquid half-cells. However, translating the success to catalyst layers in fuel cells faces challenges due to the more demanding operation conditions in membrane electrode assembly (MEA). Balancing durability and activity is crucial. Here, we developed a strategy that limits the atomic diffusion within surface layers, fostering the phase transition and shape retention during thermal treatment. This enables selective transformation of platinum-iron nanowire surfaces into intermetallic structures via atomic ordering at a low temperature. The catalysts exhibit enhanced MEA stability with 50% less Fe loss while maintaining high catalytic activity comparable to that in half-cells. Density functional calculations suggest that the ordered intermetallic surface stabilizes morphology against rapid corrosion and improves the ORR activity. The surface engineering through atomic ordering presents potential for practical application in fuel cells with shape-controlled Pt-based alloy catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ma Yanling, Jiaheng Peng, Jiakang Tian, Wenpei Gao, Jialiang Xu, Fan Li, Peter Tieu, Hao Hu, Yi Wu, Yuanlong Zhao, Lei Pan, Wen Shang, Peng Tao, Chengyi Song, Hong Zhu, Xiaoqing Pan, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado4935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Van der Waals semiconductor InSe plastifies by martensitic transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado9593</link>
      <description>Yandong Sun, Yupeng Ma, Jinyu Zhang, Tian&#8208;Ran Wei, Xun Shi, David Rodney, Ben Xu, Science Advances. 10(42)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533295

                Inorganic semiconductor materials are crucial for modern technologies, but their brittleness and limited processability hinder the development of flexible, wearable, and miniaturized electronics. The recent discovery of room-temperature plasticity in some inorganic semiconductors offers a promising solution, but the deformation mechanisms remain controversial. Here, we investigate the deformation of indium selenide, a two-dimensional van der Waals semiconductor with substantial plasticity. By developing a machine-learned deep potential, we perform atomistic simulations that capture the deformation features of hexagonal indium selenide upon out-of-plane compression. Unexpectedly, we find that indium selenide plastifies through a martensitic transformation; that is, the layered hexagonal structure is converted to a tetragonal lattice with specific orientation relationship. This observation is corroborated by high-resolution experimental observations and theory. It suggests a change of paradigm, where the design of new plastically deformable inorganic semiconductors can focus on compositions and structures that facilitate phase transformations, going beyond the conventional dislocation slip.</description>
      <author>Yandong Sun, Yupeng Ma, Jinyu Zhang, Tian&#8208;Ran Wei, Xun Shi, David Rodney, Ben Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado9593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review for MXene-based Hybrid Nanocomposites toward Electro-/Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114483</link>
      <description>Latiful Kabir, Karna Wijaya, Jianjun Li, Junjuda Unruangsri, Won&#8208;Chun Oh, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403538511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Latiful Kabir, Karna Wijaya, Jianjun Li, Junjuda Unruangsri, Won&#8208;Chun Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Underpotential Deposition at Specific Sites of N-Doped Graphene for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205082</link>
      <description>Haofei Wu, Qiwen Zhang, Shufen Chu, Hao Du, Yanyue Wang, Pan Liu, Materials. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403545133

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have the advantages of good active site uniformity, high atom utilization, and high catalytic activity. However, the study of its controllable synthesis still needs to be thoroughly investigated. In this paper, we deposited Cu SAs on nanoporous N-doped graphene by underpotential deposition and further obtained a Pt SAC by a galvanic process. Electrochemical and spectroscopic analyses showed that the pyridine-like N defect sites are the specific sites for the underpotential-deposited SAs. The obtained Pt SAC exhibits a good activity in a hydrogen evolution reaction with a turnover frequency of 25.1 s&#8722;1. This work reveals the specific sites of UPD of SAs on N-doped graphene and their potential applications in HERs, which provides a new idea for the design and synthesis of SACs.</description>
      <author>Haofei Wu, Qiwen Zhang, Shufen Chu, Hao Du, Yanyue Wang, Pan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Potential of Bimetallic PtPd/C Cathode Catalysts to Enhance the Performance of PEM Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14201672</link>
      <description>&#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Vladislav Menshikov, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, Irina Gerasimova, Kirill Paperzh, Ilya Pankov, Nanomaterials. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403546602

                Bimetallic platinum-containing catalysts are deemed promising for electrolyzers and proton-exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). A significant number of laboratory studies and commercial offers are related to PtNi/C and PtCo/C electrocatalysts. The behavior of PtPd/C catalysts has been studied much less, although palladium itself is the metal closest to platinum in its properties. Using a series of characterization methods, this paper presents a comparative study of structural characteristics of the commercial PtPd/C catalysts containing 38% wt. of precious metals and the well-known HiSpec4000 Pt/C catalyst. The electrochemical behavior of the catalysts was studied both in a three-electrode electrochemical cell and in the membrane electrode assemblies (MEAs) of hydrogen&#8211;air PEMFCs. Both PtPd/C samples demonstrated higher values of the electrochemically active surface area, as well as greater specific and mass activity in the oxygen reduction reaction in comparison with conventional Pt/C, while not being inferior to the latter in durability. The MEA based on the best of the PtPd/C catalysts also exhibited higher performance in single tests and long-term durability testing. The results of this study conducted indicate the prospects of using bimetallic PtPd/C materials for cathode catalysts in PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>&#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Vladislav Menshikov, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, Irina Gerasimova, Kirill Paperzh, Ilya Pankov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14201672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass Transportation Facilitated Porous Fe/Co Dual&#8208;Site Catalytic Cathodes for Ultrahigh&#8208;Power&#8208;Density Al&#8211;Air Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404140</link>
      <description>Kai Chen, Yiqi Liang, Duo Pan, Junheng Huang, Jiyuan Gao, Zhiwen Lu, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Junxiang Chen, Hao Zhang, Xiang Hu, Zhenhai Wen, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403547980

                Abstract The development of oxygen&#8208;dependent fuel cells is frequently hindered by the high cost of cathode materials and the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). It is thus crucial to explore low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;activity catalysts with accelerated mass transport. Here, a high&#8208;throughput screening method is developed by integrating an explicit solvation model with machine learning potential&#8208;based molecular dynamics simulations, which enables the efficient evaluation of a vast array of diverse diatomic combinations and ultimately identifying Fe&#8211;Co dual&#8208;atomic sites as the optimal ORR electrocatalysts. The superior electrocatalytic performance of the diatomic Fe/Co sites loaded on 3D&#8208;interconnected ordered macroporous carbon (FeCo&#8208;3DMNC) is experimentally verified, achieving high ORR activity with half&#8208;wave potentials of 0.806 V in acidic and 0.905 V in alkaline environments. Additionally, innovative hybrid acid/alkali aluminum&#8211;air fuel cells (hA/A&#8208;AAFCs) incorporating FeCo&#8208;3DMNC as the cathode catalyst demonstrate a notably high open&#8208;circuit voltage of 2.72 V and a record&#8208;breaking power density of 827 mW cm &#8722;2 , significantly outperforming conventional alkaline aluminum&#8211;air fuel cells. This work marks a significant advancement by combining cutting&#8208;edge computational screening with rigorous experimental validation to develop promising electrocatalysts, potentially paving the way for the advanced energy storage and conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Kai Chen, Yiqi Liang, Duo Pan, Junheng Huang, Jiyuan Gao, Zhiwen Lu, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Junxiang Chen, Hao Zhang, Xiang Hu, Zhenhai Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active learning accelerated exploration of single-atom local environments in multimetallic systems for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01432-1</link>
      <description>Hoje Chun, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jeung Ku Kang, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Byungchan Han, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403560061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hoje Chun, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jeung Ku Kang, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Byungchan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01432-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing the Complexity of Endogenous Technological Learning for Energy System Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.adapen.2024.100192</link>
      <description>Johannes Behrens, Elisabeth Zeyen, Maximilian Hoffmann, Detlef Stolten, Jann Michael Weinand, Advances in Applied Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403561700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Johannes Behrens, Elisabeth Zeyen, Maximilian Hoffmann, Detlef Stolten, Jann Michael Weinand</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.adapen.2024.100192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the role of foreign atoms in &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e419" altimg="si139.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;CO&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; reduction on CuSn single-atom surface alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118718</link>
      <description>Vitaliy A. Kislenko, Sergey A. Kislenko, Victoria A. Nikitina, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403563779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vitaliy A. Kislenko, Sergey A. Kislenko, Victoria A. Nikitina</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial anchoring cobalt species mediated advanced oxidation: Degradation performance and mechanism of organic pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.097</link>
      <description>Z. Chen, Guanghao Meng, Zenghui Han, Hongjiang Li, Shao&#8208;Ming Chi, Guangzhi Hu, Xue Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403563889

                The development of highly catalytic activity, low-cost and environmentally friendly catalysts is crucial for the use of advanced oxidation processes (AOPs) to treat organic pollutants. In this study, to reduce costs, enhance catalytic activity and avoid secondary pollution form metal ions, pomelo peel was used as raw material, combined with surface crystallization, carbon layer protection and heat treatment technology to effectively construct AOPs catalyst that can efficiently activate peroxymonosulfate (PMS) to degrade harmful organic pollutants. Under the optimal conditions, the Co/BC-PMS system can degrade about 100 % of tetracycline (TC, a spectral antibiotic) within 5 min, and the degradation rate of TC can still reach 100 % even if Co/BC (cobalt anchored on biochar) was reused for 6 times. The Co/BC-PMS system can resist complex environmental conditions, including acidic solution, alkaline solution, coexisting ions, different water quality, and is universal for the degradation of most organic pollutants. The integrated purification column with Co/BC as the core realizes the continuous and complete degradation of organic pollutants and has the ability of practical application. Radical capture and monitoring combined with density-functional-theory calculations confirmed that the Co(111) and amorphous CoO sites in Co/BC are the key to driving PMS to degrade organic pollutants, Co/BC can efficiently adsorb PMS and promote the dissociation of PMS into highly active OH, SO</description>
      <author>Z. Chen, Guanghao Meng, Zenghui Han, Hongjiang Li, Shao&#8208;Ming Chi, Guangzhi Hu, Xue Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1-Dimensional metal Nitride-Supported platinum nanoclusters for Low-Temperature hydrogen production from formic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156940</link>
      <description>Liang Qiu, Bowen Sheng, Haotian Ye, Ping Wang, Jinglin Li, Ying Li, Yixin Li, Tianqi Yu, Muhammad Salman Nasir, Xinqiang Wang, Pan Hu, Zhen Huang, Baowen Zhou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403574280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Qiu, Bowen Sheng, Haotian Ye, Ping Wang, Jinglin Li, Ying Li, Yixin Li, Tianqi Yu, Muhammad Salman Nasir, Xinqiang Wang, Pan Hu, Zhen Huang, Baowen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonized-nitridated Mo2N-MoC heterostructures towards universal-medium hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156908</link>
      <description>Xiang Chen, Song Xie, Fang Zhou, Biao Gao, Xuming Zhang, Shuangjie Wu, Li Huang, Yun Li, Paul K. Chu, Xiang Peng, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403574389

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Chen, Song Xie, Fang Zhou, Biao Gao, Xuming Zhang, Shuangjie Wu, Li Huang, Yun Li, Paul K. Chu, Xiang Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure simulations in the cloud computing environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0226437</link>
      <description>Eric J. Bylaska, Ajay Panyala, Nicholas P. Bauman, Bo Peng, Himadri Pathak, Daniel Mej&#305;&#769;a-Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Niranjan Govind, David B. Williams&#8208;Young, Edoardo Apr&#224;, Abhishek Bagusetty, Erdal Mutlu, Koblar Alan Jackson, Tunna Baruah, Yoh Yamamoto, Mark R. Pederson, Kushantha P. K. Withanage, Jes&#250;s N. Pedroza-Montero, Jenna Pope, Sutanay Choudhury, Jesun Firoz, Kristina M. Herman, Sotiris S. Xantheas, Paul Rigor, Fernando D. Vila, J. J. Rehr, Mimi Fung, Adam Grofe, Conrad Johnston, Nathan Baker, K. Kaneko, Hongbin Liu, Karol Kowalski, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403585557

                The transformative impact of modern computational paradigms and technologies, such as high-performance computing (HPC), quantum computing, and cloud computing, has opened up profound new opportunities for scientific simulations. Scalable computational chemistry is one beneficiary of this technological progress. The main focus of this paper is on the performance of various quantum chemical formulations, ranging from low-order methods to high-accuracy approaches, implemented in different computational chemistry packages and libraries, such as NWChem, NWChemEx, Scalable Predictive Methods for Excitations and Correlated Phenomena, ExaChem, and Fermi&#8211;L&#246;wdin orbital self-interaction correction on Azure Quantum Elements, Microsoft's cloud services platform for scientific discovery. We pay particular attention to the intricate workflows for performing complex chemistry simulations, associated data curation, and mechanisms for accuracy assessment, which is demonstrated with the Arrows automated workflow for high throughput simulations. Finally, we provide a perspective on the role of cloud computing in supporting the mission of leadership computational facilities.</description>
      <author>Eric J. Bylaska, Ajay Panyala, Nicholas P. Bauman, Bo Peng, Himadri Pathak, Daniel Mej&#305;&#769;a-Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Niranjan Govind, David B. Williams&#8208;Young, Edoardo Apr&#224;, Abhishek Bagusetty, Erdal Mutlu, Koblar Alan Jackson, Tunna Baruah, Yoh Yamamoto, Mark R. Pederson, Kushantha P. K. Withanage, Jes&#250;s N. Pedroza-Montero, Jenna Pope, Sutanay Choudhury, Jesun Firoz, Kristina M. Herman, Sotiris S. Xantheas, Paul Rigor, Fernando D. Vila, J. J. Rehr, Mimi Fung, Adam Grofe, Conrad Johnston, Nathan Baker, K. Kaneko, Hongbin Liu, Karol Kowalski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0226437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening of Group V&#8546;@C5N4 single-atom electrocatalysts for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114619</link>
      <description>Cuimei Li, Dong Cao, Dandan Guo, Chun&#8208;Ran Chang, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403590090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cuimei Li, Dong Cao, Dandan Guo, Chun&#8208;Ran Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supramolecular Catalyzed Cascade Reduction of Azaarenes Interrogated via Data Science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11482</link>
      <description>Sean M. Treacy, Andrew L. Smith, Robert G. Bergman, Kenneth N. Raymond, F. Dean Toste, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403596888

                Catalysis of multicomponent transformations requires controlled assembly of reactants within the active site. Supramolecular scaffolds possess synthetic microenvironments that enable precise modulation over noncovalent interactions (NCIs) engaged by reactive, encapsulated species. While molecular properties that describe the behavior of single guests in host cavities have been studied extensively, multicomponent transformations remain challenging to design and deploy. Here, simple univariate regression and threshold analyses are employed to model reactivity in a cascade reduction of azaarenes catalyzed by water-soluble metal organic cages. Yield and stereoselectivity models help deduce unknown mechanisms of reactivity by the multicomponent, host&#8211;guest complexes. Furthermore, a comprehensive model is established for NCIs driving stereoselectivity in the reported host&#8211;guest adducts.</description>
      <author>Sean M. Treacy, Andrew L. Smith, Robert G. Bergman, Kenneth N. Raymond, F. Dean Toste</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11482</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrode Materials for NO Electroreduction Based on Dithiolene Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks: A Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100739</link>
      <description>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Lixin Ye, Mengyun Mei, Weihua Zhu, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403601369

                To quickly and efficiently screen catalytic materials with both activity and selectivity for the nitric oxide reduction reaction (NORR), we adopted a strategy that considers the activity of the side reaction hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) first. It can be seen that Fe3(THT)2 (THT = triphenylene-2,3,6,7,10,11-hexathiol) has extremely excellent HER activity, with a Gibbs free energy change (&#916;G) of 0.007 eV. Based on the relationship between &#916;G and theoretical exchange current density, all TM3(THT)2 can be divided into two regions: one is the absolute values of &#916;G greater than 1 eV, the other is the absolute values of &#916;G greater than 0 eV and less than 1eV. Obviously, the candidates with the absolute values of &#916;G greater than 1 eV have poor HER performance, but this precisely provides the possibility of obtaining NORR catalytic materials with both excellent selectivity and activity. Subsequent calculation results show that the maximum &#916;G change of the rate-determining step of Ta3(THT)2 is unexpectedly only 0.05 eV. Therefore, Ta3(THT)2 may be regarded as the NORR catalytic material with both excellent performance and selectivity. Based on the electron transfer and partial density of states (PDOS) analysis, it can be seen that Ta plays a crucial role in the activation stage of NO. The approach that considers the activity of the side reaction HER first may provide a new idea for rapidly screening highly selective and active NORR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Lixin Ye, Mengyun Mei, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton exchange membrane&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems for hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.629</link>
      <description>Yangyang Zhou, H. Zhong, Shanhu Chen, Guobin Wen, Liang Shen, Yanyong Wang, Ru Chen, Li Tao, Wang Shuangyin, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403602672

                Abstract Hydrogen energy from electrocatalysis driven by sustainable energy has emerged as a solution against the background of carbon neutrality. Proton exchange membrane (PEM)&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems represent a promising technology for hydrogen production, which is equipped to combine efficiently with intermittent electricity from renewable energy sources. In this review, PEM&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems for H 2 production are summarized systematically from low to high operating temperature systems. When the operating temperature is below 130&#176;C, the representative device is a PEM water electrolyzer; its core components and respective functions, research status, and design strategies of key materials especially in electrocatalysts are presented and discussed. However, strong acidity, highly oxidative operating conditions, and the sluggish kinetics of the anode reaction of PEM water electrolyzers have limited their further development and shifted our attention to higher operating temperature PEM systems. Increasing the temperature of PEM&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems can cause an increase in current density, accelerate reaction kinetics and gas transport and reduce the ohmic value, activation losses, &#916; G H* , and power consumption. Moreover, further increasing the operating temperature (120&#8211;300&#176;C) of PEM&#8208;based devices endows various hydrogen carriers (e.g., methanol, ethanol, and ammonia) with electrolysis, offering a new opportunity to produce hydrogen using PEM&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems. Finally, several future directions and prospects for developing PEM&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems for H 2 production are proposed through devoting more efforts to the key components of devices and reduction of costs.</description>
      <author>Yangyang Zhou, H. Zhong, Shanhu Chen, Guobin Wen, Liang Shen, Yanyong Wang, Ru Chen, Li Tao, Wang Shuangyin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASIMTools: A lightweight framework for scalable and reproducible atomic simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07085</link>
      <description>Mgcini Keith Phuthi, Emil Annevelink, Venkatasubramanian Viswanathan, The Journal of Open Source Software. 9(102)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403614018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mgcini Keith Phuthi, Emil Annevelink, Venkatasubramanian Viswanathan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Site-Enabled O&#8211;O Coupling in Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</link>
      <description>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403624087

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring pyrolusite &#946;-MnO2 as a robust support for noble metal catalysts in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.246</link>
      <description>Nur Tursina, Ashish Gaur, Min Su Cho, Mingony Kim, Kyung Yoon Chung, Sungwook Mhin, H. Han, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403626456

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nur Tursina, Ashish Gaur, Min Su Cho, Mingony Kim, Kyung Yoon Chung, Sungwook Mhin, H. Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir Doping Modulates the Electronic Structure of Flower-Shaped Phosphides for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</link>
      <description>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633322

                Electrolysis of water to produce hydrogen is an efficient, clean, and environmentally friendly hydrogen production method with unlimited development prospects. However, its overall efficiency is hampered by the slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with complex electron transfer processes. Therefore, designing efficient and low-cost OER catalysts is the key to solving this problem. In this paper, Ir-doped Co</description>
      <author>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into efficient electrocatalysts for nitrogen reduction reaction by transition metal atoms supported on g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114932</link>
      <description>Pengfei Ma, Rui Wang, Chengsong Liu, Pengfei Liu, Chaozheng He, Wei Song, Tao Zhang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403645722

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Ma, Rui Wang, Chengsong Liu, Pengfei Liu, Chaozheng He, Wei Song, Tao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114932</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single&#8208;Nanometer Spinel with Precise Cation Distribution for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202413141</link>
      <description>Long Shang, Youxuan Ni, Yuankun Wang, Wenxuan Yang, Linyue Wang, Haixia Li, Kai Zhang, Zhenhua Yan, Jun Chen, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403646233

                Abstract Designing spinel nanocrystals (NCs) with tailored structural composition and cation distribution is crucial for superior catalytic performance but remarkably challenging due to their intricate nature. Here, an aggregation growth restricted hot&#8208;injection method is presented by meticulously investigating the fundamental nucleation and aggregation&#8208;driven growth kinetics governing spinel NC formation to address this challenge. Through controlled collision probability of nuclei during growth, this approach enables the synthesis of spinel NCs with unprecedented, single nanometer (1.2 nm). Single&#8208;nanometer CoMn 2 O 4 spinel via this method exhibits a highly tailored structure with a maximized population of highly active octahedral Mn atoms, thereby optimizing oxygen intermediate adsorption during oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Consequently, it exhibits a remarkable half&#8208;wave potential of 0.88 V in ORR and leads to a superior power density (170.9 mW cm &#8722;2 ) in zinc&#8211;air battery, outperforming commercial Pt/C and most reported spinel oxides, revealing a clear structure&#8211;property relationship. This structure design strategy is readily adaptable for the precise synthesis and engineering of various spinel structures, opening new avenues for developing advanced electrocatalysts and energy storage materials.</description>
      <author>Long Shang, Youxuan Ni, Yuankun Wang, Wenxuan Yang, Linyue Wang, Haixia Li, Kai Zhang, Zhenhua Yan, Jun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202413141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of unique electronic structures of single-atom alloys unraveled by interpretable deep learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232141</link>
      <description>Yang Huang, Shih&#8208;Han Wang, Luke E. K. Achenie, Kamal Choudhary, Hongliang Xin, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403649617

                We uncover the origin of unique electronic structures of single-atom alloys (SAAs) by interpretable deep learning. The approach integrates tight-binding moment theory with graph neural networks to accurately describe the local electronic structure of transition and noble metal sites upon perturbation. We emphasize the complex interplay of interatomic orbital coupling and on-site orbital resonance, which shapes the d-band characteristics of an active site, shedding light on the origin of free-atom-like d-states that are often observed in SAAs involving d10 metal hosts. This theory-infused neural network approach significantly enhances our understanding of the electronic properties of single-site catalytic materials beyond traditional theories.</description>
      <author>Yang Huang, Shih&#8208;Han Wang, Luke E. K. Achenie, Kamal Choudhary, Hongliang Xin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress and challenges in structural, &lt;i&gt;in situ&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;operando&lt;/i&gt; characterization of single-atom catalysts by X-ray based synchrotron radiation techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00967j</link>
      <description>Yuhang Liu, Xiaozhi Su, Jie Ding, Jing Zhou, Zhen Liu, Xiangjun Wei, Hong Bin Yang, Bin Liu, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403655107

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) represent the ultimate size limit of nanoscale catalysts, combining the advantages of homogeneous and heterogeneous catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Liu, Xiaozhi Su, Jie Ding, Jing Zhou, Zhen Liu, Xiangjun Wei, Hong Bin Yang, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00967j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring reactivity of small Ag/Pt bimetallic cluster for ORR: A comprehensive study using density functional theory approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115102</link>
      <description>Sandeep Nigam, Chiranjib Majumder, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403656378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sandeep Nigam, Chiranjib Majumder</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the multifaceted potential of copper sulfide heterojunctions for sustainable energy solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.042</link>
      <description>Ahmad Farhan, Aman Khalid, Wajeeha Qayyum, Saima Noreen, Asim Jilani, Rizwan Haider, Qamar Abbas, Muhammad Zahid, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403672940

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ahmad Farhan, Aman Khalid, Wajeeha Qayyum, Saima Noreen, Asim Jilani, Rizwan Haider, Qamar Abbas, Muhammad Zahid</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reaction Activity of Transition Metal-Doped T-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Monolayer: A Density Functional Theory Study Assisted by Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04467</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Lin Ju, Zhenjie Tang, Shu Zhang, Genqiang Zhang, Wentao Wang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403674764

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Lin Ju, Zhenjie Tang, Shu Zhang, Genqiang Zhang, Wentao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest advances in the deep reconstruction of pre-catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177225</link>
      <description>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403679718

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemistry In Rechargeable Zinc-Air battery: A Mechanistic Overview</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115108</link>
      <description>Arkaj Singh, Ravinder Sharma, A. K. Gautam, Bindey Kumar, Sneha Mittal, Aditi Halder, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403679884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arkaj Singh, Ravinder Sharma, A. K. Gautam, Bindey Kumar, Sneha Mittal, Aditi Halder</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pythonic Chemistry: The Beginner&#8217;s Guide to Digital Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jchemed.4c00840</link>
      <description>Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Diego Garay&#8208;Ruiz, Journal of Chemical Education. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403685033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Diego Garay&#8208;Ruiz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jchemed.4c00840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diatomic Active Sites Embedded Graphyne as Electrocatalysts for Ammonia Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13025</link>
      <description>Xiaoting Chen, Man-Rong Zhao, Bingyi Song, Guoliang Li, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403685995

                Ammonia (NH</description>
      <author>Xiaoting Chen, Man-Rong Zhao, Bingyi Song, Guoliang Li, Li&#8208;Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Doping Effects in a V-Doped Ni Catalyst for Hydrogen Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03785</link>
      <description>Siguang Lu, Luhong Fu, Fulin Yang, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403686539

                The improved performance of soluble metal-doped Ni catalysts is perplexed by the evolvable surface structures in the alkaline electrolytes for hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR). Herein, V-doped Ni nanoparticles, as a proof of concept, were carefully evaluated to explore the intrinsic function of the enthetic V-species in assisting the HOR kinetic improvement. As expected, it exhibits a mass-normalized kinetic current density of 50.34 mA mg</description>
      <author>Siguang Lu, Luhong Fu, Fulin Yang, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combining Hammett &lt;i&gt;&#963;&lt;/i&gt; constants for &#916;-machine learning and catalyst discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00228h</link>
      <description>V. Diana Rakotonirina, Marco Bragato, Stefan Heinen, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403687003

                We present a simple and fast linear model for discovering organometallic catalysts for the Suzuki&#8211;Miyaura cross-coupling reaction, using a combinatorial approach.</description>
      <author>V. Diana Rakotonirina, Marco Bragato, Stefan Heinen, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00228h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Activity on Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C and Promoting C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Product by Grain Boundary Engineering: Insights from First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03202</link>
      <description>Yuxing Lin, Fang-Qi Yu, Lei Li, Yameng Li, Rao Huang, Yu&#8208;Hua Wen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403687778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxing Lin, Fang-Qi Yu, Lei Li, Yameng Li, Rao Huang, Yu&#8208;Hua Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Two&#8208;Electron Water Oxidation Reaction for Hydrogen Peroxide Production: Catalyst Design and Interface Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401100</link>
      <description>Hu Cao, Guangming Chen, Yong Yan, Dong Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403689728

                Abstract Hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) is a versatile and zero&#8208;emission material that is widely used in the industrial, domestic, and healthcare sectors. It is clear that it plays a critical role in advancing environmental sustainability, acting as a green energy source, and protecting human health. Conventional production techniques focused on anthraquinone oxidation, however, electrocatalytic synthesis has arisen as a means of utilizing renewable energy sources in conjunction with available resources like oxygen and water. These strides represent a substantial change toward more environmentally and energy&#8208;friendly H 2 O 2 manufacturing techniques that are in line with current environmental and energy goals. This work reviews recent advances in two&#8208;electron water oxidation reaction (2e&#8208;WOR) electrocatalysts, including design principles and reaction mechanisms, examines catalyst design alternatives and experimental characterization techniques, proposes standardized assessment criteria, investigates the impact of the interfacial milieu on the reaction, and discusses the value of in situ characterization and molecular dynamics simulations as a supplement to traditional experimental techniques and theoretical simulations, as shown in Figure 1. The review also emphasizes the importance of device design, interface, and surface engineering in improving the production of H 2 O 2 . Through adjustments to the chemical microenvironment, catalysts can demonstrate improved performance, opening the door for commercial applications that are scalable through tandem cell development.</description>
      <author>Hu Cao, Guangming Chen, Yong Yan, Dong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Chemical and Catalytic Activity of Metal Surface Sites by Controlling Strain and Ligand Effects in Nonmodel Nanoparticle Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03857</link>
      <description>Bill Yan, Suljo Linic, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403692782

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bill Yan, Suljo Linic</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru/MgO Catalysts Modified with Various Alkali Metals (Na, Cs, K) for CO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-Free H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production from NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03658</link>
      <description>Tianxu Su, Bin Guan, Chunzheng Zheng, Jiefei Zhou, Zhen Huang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403692862

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianxu Su, Bin Guan, Chunzheng Zheng, Jiefei Zhou, Zhen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Surface Dealloying for Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co/C Catalysts with a Pt-Enriched Surface for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02062</link>
      <description>Mingjie Xu, Ye Xiao, Jingxi Zhang, Yuting Xia, Tianli Liu, Yanhao Dong, Chang&#8208;An Wang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403693496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingjie Xu, Ye Xiao, Jingxi Zhang, Yuting Xia, Tianli Liu, Yanhao Dong, Chang&#8208;An Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Machine Learning to Expedite Screening of Single-atom Catalysts in Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177180</link>
      <description>Zhongli Lu, Jiming Liu, Houfen Li, Rui Li, Xiao Zhang, Juan Jian, Xiaoming Gao, Xuqian Zhang, Yanze Wu, Xiuping Yue, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403695068

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongli Lu, Jiming Liu, Houfen Li, Rui Li, Xiao Zhang, Juan Jian, Xiaoming Gao, Xuqian Zhang, Yanze Wu, Xiuping Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sliding catalysis for on-off switching of the hydrogen evolution reaction on two-dimensional van der Waals bilayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.22.044061</link>
      <description>Kun Liu, Xingju Zhao, Xiaoyan Ren, Shunfang Li, Physical Review Applied. 22(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403705961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kun Liu, Xingju Zhao, Xiaoyan Ren, Shunfang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.22.044061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Assisted Selection of Catalyst for &#947;-Valerolactone Hydrogenation from Levulinic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05941</link>
      <description>Liu Dongyu, Zhen Jia, Lu Shen, Wenman Liu, Ronald T.K. Pang, Shitao Yu, Shiwei Liu, Lu Li, Yue Liu, Longzhen Yu, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403716968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liu Dongyu, Zhen Jia, Lu Shen, Wenman Liu, Ronald T.K. Pang, Shitao Yu, Shiwei Liu, Lu Li, Yue Liu, Longzhen Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction on Cu-Decorated Biphenylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08499</link>
      <description>Radha N Somaiya, Muhammad Sajjad, Nirpendra Singh, Aftab Alam, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Radha N Somaiya, Muhammad Sajjad, Nirpendra Singh, Aftab Alam</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mild polarization electric field in ultra-thin BN-Fe-graphene sandwich structure for efficient nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60114-2</link>
      <description>Ziyuan Xiu, Wei Mu, Xin Zhou, Xiaojun Han, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyuan Xiu, Wei Mu, Xin Zhou, Xiaojun Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60114-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miniaturized Electrochemical Gas Sensor with a Functional Nanocomposite and Thin Ionic Liquid Interface for Highly Sensitive and Rapid Detection of Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c02561</link>
      <description>Zhuoru Huang, Wenjian Yang, Yanchi Zhang, Jiaxi Yin, Xianyou Sun, Jiaying Sun, Guangqing Ren, Shichao Tian, Ping Wang, Hao Wan, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403732719

                Hydrogen has been widely used in industrial and commercial applications as a carbon-free, efficient energy source. Due to the high flammability and explosion risk of hydrogen&#8211;air mixtures, it is vital to develop sensors featuring fast-responding and high sensitivity for hydrogen leakage detection. This paper presents a miniaturized electrochemical gas sensor by elaborately establishing a nanocomposite and thin ionic liquid interface for highly sensitive and rapid electrochemical detection of hydrogen, in which a remarkable response time and recovery time of approximately 6 s was achieved at room temperature. A screen-printed carbon electrode was modified with a reduced graphene oxide&#8211;carbon nanotube (rGO-CNT) hybrid and platinum&#8211;palladium (Pt&#8211;Pd) bimetallic nanoparticles to realize high sensitivity. To achieve miniaturization and high stability of the sensor, a thin-film room-temperature ionic liquid (RTIL) was employed as the electrolyte with a significantly decreased response time. The fast-responding hydrogen sensor demonstrates excellent performance with high sensitivity, linearity, and repeatability at concentrations below the lower explosive limit of 4 vol %. The engineered high-performance interface and gas sensor provide a promising and effective strategy for gas sensor design and rapid hazardous gas monitoring.</description>
      <author>Zhuoru Huang, Wenjian Yang, Yanchi Zhang, Jiaxi Yin, Xianyou Sun, Jiaying Sun, Guangqing Ren, Shichao Tian, Ping Wang, Hao Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c02561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D single-faceted IrO2(101) monolayer enabling high-performing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis beyond 8,000 h stability at 1.5 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</link>
      <description>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745568

                Abstract Both commercially available and laboratory-synthesized IrO2 catalysts typically possess rutile-type structures and diverse facet orientations. According to the theoretical results from density functional theory calculations, distinct IrO2 facets will result in divergent electrocatalytic properties, among which the (101) crystal facet is theoretically predicted as the most energetically favorable for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) owing to its lowest energy barrier. Maintaining a single-unit-cell thickness while exposing a desired facet of 2D IrO2 presents a significant opportunity and challenge for the development of high-performance OER anode catalysts. Herein, we develop an ammonia-induced facet engineering for oriented modulation of crystal facets in the ultimate limit of monolayer thickness, and successfully synthesize 2D monolayer IrO2 exposing unique (101) facet. At the current density of 10 mA cm-2geo, an ultralow overpotential of 230 mV has been achieved on the highly activated (101) facet in a three-electrode system. More importantly, in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, the IrO2 anode reaches a low voltage of 1.74 V at an industrial-level current density of 2 A cm-2geo, much lower than that of all commercial IrO2 electrocatalysts. Though facet engineering primarily contributes to modulating the intrinsic activity rather than stability, the as-prepared IrO2(101) monolayer performs over 8,000 hours of PEM water electrolysis (PEMWE) stability at constant 1.5 A cm-2geo, with a negligible decay rate of 4.0 mV kh-1. Furthermore, even a long-term PEMWE test of 1000 h using the membrane electrode assembly (MEA) with ultra-low Ir loading of 0.2 mgIr cm-2geo under fluctuating operating conditions is performed, ECell remains highly electrochemically stable over time at 1.5 A cm-2geo, without any signs of catalyst degradation. This work proposes that ammonia-induced facet engineering of 2D monolayer IrO2 could represent a novel approach to selectively expose the desired (101) facet, thereby enabling unique facet-dependent OER performance and ultrahigh stability in industrial-scale PEM electrolysis, even under voltage fluctuations generated by solar and wind power.</description>
      <author>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chirality Engineering of Nanostructured Copper Oxide for Enhancing Oxygen Evolution from Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</link>
      <description>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745745

                Abstract The exploration of a new conceptual strategy for improving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) of earth&#8208;abundant electrocatalysts is critical. In this study, chiral copper oxide nanoflower is explored by a self&#8208;assembly method. The characterization suggests the chiral structure originates from the crystal plane&#8208;level helical stack of the secondary nanosheets. Of note, the assembly illustrates a record&#8208;high degree of spin polarization of 96%, indicating the ideal alignment of electron spin. Moreover, density function theory calculations show the chiral structure reducing the reaction energy barrier (REB) while switching the potential&#8208;determining step from *O&#8594;*OOH to *OH&#8594;*O. Together with the enhanced electrochemical active surface area and accelerated charge transfer, the production of ground&#8208;state triplet O 2 is improved via a spin&#8208;forbidden route that involves the singlet H 2 O/OH&#8226;. Consequently, the chiral nanoflower shows a overpotential of 308 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 93.5 mV dec &#8722;1 , which is even superior to the commercial RuO 2 (310 mV, 101 mV dec &#8722;1 ). This study presents a new strategy for improving the OER activity by simultaneously enhancing electronic properties and lowering the REB of an non&#8208;noble electrocatalyst via chirality engineering.</description>
      <author>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Modulation of RuCo Catalysts on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanotubes Promoting Durable Acidic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</link>
      <description>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745765

                Abstract The development of efficient and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts is essential for hydrogen production from acidic water splitting. Herein, a TiO 2 nanotube&#8208;loaded Co&#8208;doped Ru nanoparticle catalyst (RuCo/TiO 2 NTs) is reported that exhibits excellent activity and stability toward acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The Ru&#9472;O&#9472;Ti bonding is enhanced by Co doping, and the metal carrier interaction between Ru nanoparticles and TiO 2 NTs is enhanced, which effectively stabilizes Ru species during OER and initiates hydrogen spillover accelerating HER kinetics. As a result, RuCo/TiO 2 NTs catalyst requires only 156 mV OER overpotential and 17 mV HER overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a stability more than 500 h in acidic conditions. More importantly, benefiting from the excellent bifunctional activities, the proton exchange membrane electrolyte assembled from RuCo/TiO 2 NTs has excellent activity and robust stability (1000 h). This work opens a new avenue for the efficient energy conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;ROBERT&lt;/scp&gt;: Bridging the Gap Between Machine Learning and Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.1733</link>
      <description>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena, Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews Computational Molecular Science. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403697375

                ABSTRACT Beyond addressing technological demands, the integration of machine learning (ML) into human societies has also promoted sustainability through the adoption of digitalized protocols. Despite these advantages and the abundance of available toolkits, a substantial implementation gap is preventing the widespread incorporation of ML protocols into the computational and experimental chemistry communities. In this work, we introduce ROBERT, a software carefully crafted to make ML more accessible to chemists of all programming skill levels, while achieving results comparable to those of field experts. We conducted benchmarking using six recent ML studies in chemistry containing from 18 to 4149 entries. Furthermore, we demonstrated the program's ability to initiate workflows directly from SMILES strings, which simplifies the generation of ML predictors for common chemistry problems. To assess ROBERT's practicality in real&#8208;life scenarios, we employed it to discover new luminescent Pd complexes with a modest dataset of 23 points, a frequently encountered scenario in experimental studies.</description>
      <author>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.1733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption of CO2 on mechanochemically synthesized silicon oxycarbide composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112486</link>
      <description>S Grishin Il'Ya, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533456

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S Grishin Il'Ya</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO2-conjugated CoFe layered double oxides as efficient non-noble metal catalysts for NH3-decomposition enabling carbon-free hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156986</link>
      <description>Su&#8208;Un Lee, Thien An Le, Youngmin Kim, You&#8208;Jin Lee, Jeong-Rang Kim, Tae&#8208;Wan Kim, Kwang-Eun Jeong, Ho&#8208;Jeong Chae, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403656953

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Su&#8208;Un Lee, Thien An Le, Youngmin Kim, You&#8208;Jin Lee, Jeong-Rang Kim, Tae&#8208;Wan Kim, Kwang-Eun Jeong, Ho&#8208;Jeong Chae</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the involvement/exclusion paradox in disaster volunteering from a field-theoretical perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2024.104913</link>
      <description>Sandra Maria Pfister, International Journal of Disaster Risk Reduction. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sandra Maria Pfister</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2024.104913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active and Stable Plasma-Enhanced ALD Pt@Ni-YSZ Hydrogen Electrode for Steam Reversible Solid Oxide Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124740</link>
      <description>Hyong June Kim, Haoyu Li, Dae&#8208;Hyun Kim, Geonwoo Park, Sung Eun Jo, Kyoungjae Ju, Geongu Han, Yongchai Kwon, Haesun Park, Min Hwan Lee, Jihwan An, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403601128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyong June Kim, Haoyu Li, Dae&#8208;Hyun Kim, Geonwoo Park, Sung Eun Jo, Kyoungjae Ju, Geongu Han, Yongchai Kwon, Haesun Park, Min Hwan Lee, Jihwan An</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124740</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
