<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 01:17:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Key role of nonprecious oxygen-evolving active site in NiOOH electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161066</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Na Song, Ming Fang, Yixing Li, Xuedi Chen, Yue Li, Lei He, Wenbiao Zhang, Xiaoyu Ma, Xianzhang Lei, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401858995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Na Song, Ming Fang, Yixing Li, Xuedi Chen, Yue Li, Lei He, Wenbiao Zhang, Xiaoyu Ma, Xianzhang Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain engineering of CoSAN C catalyst toward enhancing the oxygen reduction reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.165</link>
      <description>Hong Yin, Yuehong Deng, Zhe He, Wenyuan Xu, Zhaohui Hou, Binhong He, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Jo&#227;o Cunha, Maryam Karimi, Zhipeng Yu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401862691

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Yin, Yuehong Deng, Zhe He, Wenyuan Xu, Zhaohui Hou, Binhong He, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Jo&#227;o Cunha, Maryam Karimi, Zhipeng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site heterogeneity and broad surface-binding isotherms in modern catalysis: Building intuition beyond the Sabatier principle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115725</link>
      <description>James M. Mayer, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401892778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>James M. Mayer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxyl group modification improves the selectivity of metal single atom on poly(heptazine imide) for electrocatalytic acetylene semi-hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161075</link>
      <description>Xiaoxiao Chen, Yi Li, Yaofeng Yuan, Yidong Hou, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401922753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxiao Chen, Yi Li, Yaofeng Yuan, Yidong Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing the competing hydrogen evolution reaction in CO2 electroreduction: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114869</link>
      <description>Munawar Khalil, Grandprix T.M. Kadja, Ferry Anggoro Ardy Nugroho, Laurencia G. Sutanto, Prastika Krisma Jiwanti, Fatwa F. Abdi, Farihahusnah Hussin, Mohamed Kheireddine Aroua, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 206(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401936017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munawar Khalil, Grandprix T.M. Kadja, Ferry Anggoro Ardy Nugroho, Laurencia G. Sutanto, Prastika Krisma Jiwanti, Fatwa F. Abdi, Farihahusnah Hussin, Mohamed Kheireddine Aroua</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facilitation of Pd&#8211;Ru Mixing in Nanoalloys of Immiscible Palladium and Ruthenium by NO Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03350</link>
      <description>Y&#363;suke Nanba, Masaaki Haneda, Michihisa Koyama, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401939920

                Surface formation markedly influences the stability and properties of nanoalloys. The surface states of nanoalloys are sensitive to the constituent elements and to the surrounding environment. In this study, Fourier transform-infrared (FT-IR) spectroscopy and an evolution strategy (ES) combined with density functional theory calculations and multivariate analysis were used to explore the stable configuration of NO-adsorbed PdRu nanoalloys. FT-IR analysis indicated that the NO molecules were adsorbed on the Ru-related sites, which was inconsistent with the stable surface state of the isolated PdRu nanoalloy models. The ES revealed that the stable surface state consisted mainly of Ru atoms owing to molecular adsorption. In addition, the Pd&#8211;Ru mixing was facilitated by the adsorption. According to the multivariate analysis, the adsorption energies on the Ru-related sites were more negative than those on the Pd-related sites and became more negative as the number of neighboring Pd atoms increased. These adsorption characteristics are opposite to those of the stability of the isolated PdRu nanoalloys. The energy gain owing to NO adsorption overcomes the energy loss due to the Pd&#8211;Ru bonds and placement of Ru atoms at the surface. This study highlights the importance of understanding stable surface states in a reactive atmosphere for the application of nanoalloys.</description>
      <author>Y&#363;suke Nanba, Masaaki Haneda, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Photo/Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400169</link>
      <description>Sheriff A. Balogun, Dina Thole, Daniel Masekela, Kwena D. Modibane, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401957318

                Cobalt phthalocyanine (CoPc)&#8208;based catalysts have garnered significant interest as efficient materials for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) due to their abundant availability, low cost, tunable electronic structures, and unique light absorption performance. This review offers a thorough examination of the latest developments in CoPc&#8208;based catalysts for HER. It entails a wide range of synthesis approaches, intrinsic characteristics, and catalytic mechanisms associated with these catalysts for HER. We also compare the photo/electrocatalytic performance of these catalysts using parameters like Tafel slope, exchange current density, overpotential, hydrogen yield, turnover frequency, stability, specific surface area, etc. The review shows that the commonly used electrolytes for electrocatalytic HER are KOH, LiClO 4 /PBS, and H 2 SO 4 , while for photocatalytic HER, triethylamine, water, and triethanolamine are frequently used. Among all the electrocatalysts understudied, poly[CoOTPc]&#8208;KB and GO/4N&#8208;CoPc are the best, owing to their lowest overpotentials and Tafel slopes. In terms of photocatalytic hydrogen production, CoPc/TiO 2 /Pt has better photocatalytic HER performance compared to its counterparts. This review also highlights the effects of incorporating CoPc with different materials on the photo/electrocatalytic HER performance. Furthermore, the review discusses the challenges and prospects, emphasizing the chances for improving and incorporating CoPc&#8208;based catalysts as a viable option for hydrogen production in the future.</description>
      <author>Sheriff A. Balogun, Dina Thole, Daniel Masekela, Kwena D. Modibane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of graphdiyne-based single-atom catalysts for electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04643a</link>
      <description>Liyun Jiang, Mengdie Zhao, Qi Yu, RSC Advances. 14(37)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401959655

                Graphdiyne (GDY) has achieved great success in the application of two-dimensional carbon materials in recent years due to its excellent electrochemical catalytic capacity.</description>
      <author>Liyun Jiang, Mengdie Zhao, Qi Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04643a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837674497-part2</link>
      <description>, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401960484

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837674497-part2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Embedded MoS2 as efficient Trifunctional Electrocatalyst: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144968</link>
      <description>K. Simmy Joseph, Shweta D. Dabhi, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402034466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Simmy Joseph, Shweta D. Dabhi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Potential-Determining Steps of Reduction of Nitrate to Ammonia on Transition Metal Porphyrins Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105022</link>
      <description>Chun&#8208;Ying Wu, Yanqing Shen, Xiaogang Wang, Lingling Lv, Xianghui Meng, Xiangqian Jiang, Dewei Gong, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402096483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chun&#8208;Ying Wu, Yanqing Shen, Xiaogang Wang, Lingling Lv, Xianghui Meng, Xiangqian Jiang, Dewei Gong, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Embedding Techniques in Multimodal Retrieval Augmented Generation A Comprehensive Study on Cross Modal AI Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/h8wf8vah</link>
      <description>Zhou Ren, Journal of Computing and Electronic Information Management. 13(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402026964

                Our study presents significant advancements in the handling of multimodal data through an extended Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) model. By integrating advanced embedding techniques, efficient retrieval mechanisms, and robust generative capabilities, our model demonstrates notable improvements in retrieval accuracy, real-time efficiency, generative quality, and scalability. The retrieval accuracy of our model reached 85%, showing a 10% improvement over existing benchmarks. Furthermore, the retrieval time was reduced by 40%, enhancing real-time application performance. The model's generative quality was also significantly improved, with BLEU and ROUGE scores increasing by 15% and 12%, respectively. These results validate the effectiveness of our approach and its applicability to various AI applications, including information retrieval, recommendation systems, and content creation. Future research directions include the integration of additional modalities and further optimization of retrieval mechanisms to broaden the applicability of our model.</description>
      <author>Zhou Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/h8wf8vah</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and Comparative Analysis of CO2 Absorption Columns in Electrochemical and Thermochemical Carbon Capture Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x7xkz-v2</link>
      <description>Katelyn M. Ripley, Fikile R. Brushett, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402072119

                Deployment of post-combustion carbon dioxide (CO2) capture technologies is needed to reduce emissions from power and industrial sources. Comparisons between existing thermochemical CO2 capture methods and emerging electrochemical concepts can help contextualize the promise of these new approaches. Here, we investigate the required absorber sizes for three capture systems: amine scrubbing using monoethanolamine (MEA), direct electrochemical (redox-active sorbent), and indirect electrochemical (pH-swing). For the electrochemical systems, we study how column size varies as a function of molecular properties and operating conditions, finding that parameters most closely related to CO2 uptake rates (i.e., rate constants and pKa) have the greatest impact. Through a Monte Carlo analysis, we find that the direct process can be designed to have column sizes similar to the thermochemical process, however, the CO2 uptake rate in the indirect process is too slow to enable smaller columns. Broadly, this work connects system input parameters to absorber performance for electrochemical CO2 capture and provides a foundation for technoeconomic and engineering analyses.</description>
      <author>Katelyn M. Ripley, Fikile R. Brushett</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x7xkz-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Predictive Control Strategies for Water-Gas Shift Membrane Reactors Using Data-Driven Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33915/etd.12598</link>
      <description>Bernardo de Oliveira Vecchio, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401953006

                As demand for more efficient processes keeps rising and more restrictive environmental legislation requires higher levels of both yield and purity, the process industry has now, more than ever, been looking for new ways to achieve these goals. One approach has been the implementation of Process Intensification (PI). PI aims to combine multiple unit operations into a single one, promoting efficiency gains on multiple levels. This combination, however, leads to complex process dynamics, and controlling such processes, particularly when setup as multi-input-multi-output (MIMO) systems, presents a great challenge due to highly interactive complex process dynamics and the imposition of many operating constraints. The objectives of this research are to generate first-principles and data-driven water-gas shift membrane reactor (WGS-MR) models and to create predictive control schemes to perform effective setpoint tracking under a MIMO framework. The AVEVA Process Simulation platform is chosen for simulating the first-principles model and both Gaussian Processes using a Squared Exponential kernel (GP-SE) and Bayesian Smoothing Spline Analysis of Variance (BSS-ANOVA) are explored as possible frameworks for data-driven models. A Proportional&#8211;Integral&#8211; Derivative (PID) controller is created as a benchmark and a Quadratic Dynamic Matrix Controller (QDMC) is developed for advanced control of the system. The GP model is later used as a digital twin of the plant for calculating a control action trajectory that could be applied to the physical system in case of a desired setpoint change. The results demonstrate the superiority of the BSS-ANOVA model over the GP-SE, especially under open-loop simulation conditions. Also, both PID and QDMC perform well under the tested conditions, but the QDMC is able to deliver smoother control action, specially under noisy signals. Finally, when operating under closed-loop control, the BSS-ANOVA model is capable of providing a good representation of one of the variables being studied, namely carbon capture, with Integral of the Absolute Error (IAE) values ranging from 0.39 to 12.6, while creating a fit for the other variable, namely hydrogen recovery, with IAE measurements ranging from 3.71 to 26.7. These results indicate that the proposed framework is viable, although not universal, as each variable desired to be modeled and controlled should be tested and have its viability carefully assessed.</description>
      <author>Bernardo de Oliveira Vecchio</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33915/etd.12598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anion-Exchange Membrane Oxygen Separator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsorginorgau.4c00052</link>
      <description>Maisa Faour, Karam Yassin, Dario R. Dekel, ACS Organic &amp; Inorganic Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401991440

                Anion-exchange membranes (AEMs), known for enabling the high conductivity of hydroxide anions through dense polymeric structures, are pivotal components in fuel cells, electrolyzers, and other important electrochemical systems. This paper unveils an unprecedented utilization of AEMs in an electrochemical oxygen separation process, a new technology able to generate enriched oxygen from an O2/N2 mixture using a small voltage input. We demonstrate a first-of-its-kind AEM-based electrochemical device that operates under mild conditions, is free of liquid electrolytes or sweep gases, and produces oxygen of over 96% purity. Additionally, we develop and apply a one-dimensional time-dependent and isothermal model, which accurately captures the unique operational dynamics of our device, demonstrates good agreement with the experimental data, and allows us to explore the device's potential capabilities. This novel technology has far-reaching applications in many industrial processes, medical oxygen therapy, and other diverse fields while reducing operational complexity and environmental impact, thereby paving the way for sustainable on-site oxygen generation.</description>
      <author>Maisa Faour, Karam Yassin, Dario R. Dekel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsorginorgau.4c00052</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
