<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 01:19:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Microhabitat mechanisms induced by cationic amino-functionalized ionic liquid electrolytes on CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131672</link>
      <description>Kuilin Peng, Shaojuan Zeng, Haifei Zhang, Haiyan Jiang, Guilin Li, Lei Yuan, Xin Li, Min Wang, Xiangping Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406450483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kuilin Peng, Shaojuan Zeng, Haifei Zhang, Haiyan Jiang, Guilin Li, Lei Yuan, Xin Li, Min Wang, Xiangping Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Confinement Effects on the Dynamical Aspects of CO Oxidation over Pt(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06593</link>
      <description>Nidhi Tiwari, Sandip Ghosh, Ashwani K. Tiwari, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406465179

                This study investigates the effects of two-dimensional (2D) confinement on CO oxidation reaction over Pt(111) surfaces, emphasizing the structural, electronic, and dynamical aspects of CO2 formation and desorption. Using pristine and single-defect hexagonal boron nitride (h-BN) and graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) as overlayers, we found that confinement by nitrogen-vacancy h-BN (NV) induces a significant reduction, greater than that of graphene (Gr), in the activation energy barrier for CO2 formation. The confinement effect on adsorption depends on the reference states chosen for adsorption energy calculations. Reference states, such as stable or original intersurface gaps, can yield either positive or negative confinement energy values, indicating adsorption weakening or strengthening, respectively. Importantly, adsorption weakening correlates better with barrier reduction. Post-transition-state dynamical simulations of CO2 desorption revealed pronounced vibrational oscillations. NV and Gr confinement led to complex vibrational features, indicating stronger interactions between CO2 and the 2D cover. This study highlights the profound impact of 2D confinement on catalytic processes, providing insights into how 2D materials modulate the electronic structure and vibrational dynamics of reactions. The findings could guide the design of efficient catalysts for industrial applications, particularly in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Nidhi Tiwari, Sandip Ghosh, Ashwani K. Tiwari</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrOx Supported on Submicron-Sized Anatase TiO2 as a Catalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010079</link>
      <description>Josep Boter-Carbonell, Carlos Calabr&#233;s-Casellas, M. Sarret, Teresa Andreu, Pere Llu&#305;&#769;s Cabot, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406465519

                Ir-based catalysts are the best in terms of activity and stability for oxygen evolution reactions (OERs) in proton exchange water electrolysis. Due to their cost, efforts have been made to decrease their load without a loss of activity. In this paper, Ir nanoparticles measuring 2&#8211;3 nm were loaded on TiO2 anatase supports of submicrometric size in different amounts using the microwave polyol method to optimize their mass activity. Using anatase particles with a diameter of about 100 nm and titania nanotubes (TNTs), Ir/TiO2 catalysts with Ir contents of 5, 10, 20, and 40 wt.% were synthesized and characterized via structural and electrochemical techniques. It was shown that the amount of Ir must be regulated to obtain continuous coverage on titania with strong Ir&#8211;TiO2 interactions which, for the 100 nm diameter anatase, is limited to about 20 wt.%. A higher percentage of Ir over 40 wt.% can be dispersed over the TNTs. Exceeding one layer of coverage leads to a decrease in the catalyst&#8217;s utilization. Ir/TiO2(10:90), Ir/TiO2(20:80), and Ir/TiO2(40:60) presented the highest pseudocapacitive currents per unit of Ir mass. The electrochemical active areas and mass activities for these later catalysts were also the highest compared to Ir/TiO2(05:95), Ir/TNT(40:60), and the unsupported catalysts and increased from 40 to 10 wt.% Ir. They also presented the lowest overpotentials of about 300 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for the OER, with Ir/TiO2(10:90) presenting the best specific activities and surface turnover frequencies, thus showing that the size of the support can be regulated to decrease the Ir content of the catalyst without a loss of activity.</description>
      <author>Josep Boter-Carbonell, Carlos Calabr&#233;s-Casellas, M. Sarret, Teresa Andreu, Pere Llu&#305;&#769;s Cabot</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid synthesis of an aluminum-doped ultrathin Ru&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; heterostructure optimized through combined wet&#8211;dry microwave radiation for efficient acidic and alkaline overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07453j</link>
      <description>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Shaorou Ke, Bozhi Yang, Shujie Yang, Yanghong Li, Meiling Zhan, Xin Min, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406477985

                By employing an efficient &#8220;wet-dry&#8221; microwave strategy, we have developed Al-doped Ru x /RuO 2 (A-RRO@G) in just 110 s. Its unique structure optimizes electronic configurations, enhancing water-splitting activity in both acidic and alkaline conditions.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Shaorou Ke, Bozhi Yang, Shujie Yang, Yanghong Li, Meiling Zhan, Xin Min</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07453j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysts via Direct Oxygen&#8211;Oxygen Radical Coupling Pathway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202416362</link>
      <description>Chengli Rong, Xinyi Huang, Hamidreza Arandiyan, Zongping Shao, Yuan Wang, Yuan Chen, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406482848

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a cornerstone of various electrochemical energy conversion and storage systems, including water splitting, CO 2 /N 2 reduction, reversible fuel cells, and rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries. OER typically proceeds through three primary mechanisms: adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM), lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM), and oxide path mechanism (OPM). Unlike AEM and LOM, the OPM proceeds via direct oxygen&#8211;oxygen radical coupling that can bypass linear scaling relationships of reaction intermediates in AEM and avoid catalyst structural collapse in LOM, thereby enabling enhanced catalytic activity and stability. Despite its unique advantage, electrocatalysts that can drive OER via OPM remain nascent and are increasingly recognized as critical. This review discusses recent advances in OPM&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts. It starts by analyzing three reaction mechanisms that guide the design of electrocatalysts. Then, several types of novel materials, including atomic ensembles, metal oxides, perovskite oxides, and molecular complexes, are highlighted. Afterward, operando characterization techniques used to monitor the dynamic evolution of active sites and reaction intermediates are examined. The review concludes by discussing several research directions to advance OPM&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts toward practical applications.</description>
      <author>Chengli Rong, Xinyi Huang, Hamidreza Arandiyan, Zongping Shao, Yuan Wang, Yuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202416362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus&#8208;Mediated Selenium Dual Atoms for Bifunctional Oxygen Reactions and Long&#8208;Life Low&#8208;Temperature Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423476</link>
      <description>Lingzhi Xia, Jianhua Zhang, Pengfei Yan, Kailing Zhou, Yuhong Jin, Xiaoxing Ke, Jingbin Liu, Hao Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406493485

                Abstract Rapid kinetics and stable atom configuration of the catalysts are essential and greatly sought after for bifunctional oxygen reactions and energy conversion devices, but remain unsatisfactory. Herein, the Se dual atoms structure consisting of the periodically arranged Se&#8208;P&#8208;Se configurations within graphitic nitrogen carbon framework (P&#8208;Se dual atoms&#8208;NC) is constructed by P directionally mediated single atoms deposition strategy. The in situ/ex situ experiments combining the theoretical calculations reveal that both the inter&#8208;site distance effect of the adjacent Se atoms in the NC and the Se&#8208;P binding effect endow P&#8208;Se dual atoms&#8208;NC with a stable atom configuration and ultra&#8208;durable lifespan, and the locally polarized electronic micro&#8208;environment built by P 2 p &#8208;Se 3 d &#8208;C 2 p orbital hybridization and the electrons transfer significantly promotes H 2 O&#8208;O 2 coupling, boosts the adsorption/desorption of O&#8208;intermediates and accelerates the electron transport kinetics. Moreover, the adjacent Se atoms with a periodically arranged structure could provide more sites for the absorption and conversion of reactants. Thus, the as&#8208;prepared catalyst exhibits the top&#8208;level bifunctional activity with an ultra&#8208;low potential difference (&#916; E ) of 0.58 V and delivers the outstandingly low&#8208;temperature specific capacity of 796.41 mAh g Zn &#8722;1 and the ultra&#8208;durable lifespan over 1000 h for assembled zinc&#8208;air batteries at &#8722;40 &#176;C.</description>
      <author>Lingzhi Xia, Jianhua Zhang, Pengfei Yan, Kailing Zhou, Yuhong Jin, Xiaoxing Ke, Jingbin Liu, Hao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of Fe2O3-based nanoparticles on nitrogen-incorporated carbon as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.212</link>
      <description>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, Selvam Mathi, Shankara S. Kalanur, T. Maiyalagan, Mohammed Ali Alshehri, Nagaraj P. Shetti, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 103(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406504119

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, Selvam Mathi, Shankara S. Kalanur, T. Maiyalagan, Mohammed Ali Alshehri, Nagaraj P. Shetti</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-based catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolysers: The need to look beyond just another catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.485</link>
      <description>Shailendra Kumar Sharma, Chang Wu, Niall Malone, Laura J. Titheridge, Chuan Zhao, Prasanth Gupta, Hicham Idriss, J. Kennedy, Vedran Jovic, Aaron T. Marshall, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406522527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shailendra Kumar Sharma, Chang Wu, Niall Malone, Laura J. Titheridge, Chuan Zhao, Prasanth Gupta, Hicham Idriss, J. Kennedy, Vedran Jovic, Aaron T. Marshall</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of &#946;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Ir/Ru Co-substitution for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</link>
      <description>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406534076

                The efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media is severely limited by the poor stability, low activity, and high cost of available catalysts. Enhancing intrinsic activity while maintaining stability and reducing reliance on precious metals is crucial. The typical adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) leads to high overpotentials and low activity, making the transition to alternative mechanisms, such as the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) or oxide path mechanism (OPM), highly desirable due to their lower overpotentials. Here, we combine density functional theory (DFT) calculations with experimental validation to enhance the activity and stability of &#946;-MnO2 via co-substitution with ruthenium (Ru) and iridium (Ir), enabling the transition from AEM to OPM. DFT calculations reveal that AEM is hindered by the weak nucleophilicity of water, while LOM suffers from high kinetic barriers due to structural distortions. In contrast, OPM demonstrates a significantly lower kinetic barrier, facilitated by the synergistic interaction between Ru and Ir. Experimentally, IrRuMnOx was synthesized through co-precipitation and hydrothermal methods, showing an 80-fold improvement in mass activity and a 96-fold increase in stability compared to commercial IrO2, with minimal noble metal leaching, as confirmed by inductively coupled plasma optical emission spectroscopy (ICP-OES). IrRuMnOx exhibited an ultralow overpotential of 475 mV at 1 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 44.26 mV&#183;dec&#8211;1 in 0.5 M H2SO4, maintaining stable performance for over 100 h. Moreover, the IrRuMnOx-based membrane electrode, with a low Ir loading of 0.075 mgIr&#183;cm&#8211;2, achieved remarkable current densities of 1.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.66 V and 2.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.91 V at 80 &#176;C. This performance surpasses that of both unsupported and conventional supported Ir-based catalysts at comparable Ir loading levels. This study offers critical insights into OER mechanisms in acidic media and paves the way for developing efficient and durable OER electrocatalysts for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase&#8208;Engineered Bi&#8208;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Single&#8208;Atom Alloy Oxide Boosting Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417777</link>
      <description>Zhichao Yang, Yutian Ding, Wen Chen, Shuiping Luo, Daofan Cao, Xin Long, Lei Xie, Xincheng Zhou, Xinyi Cai, Ke Liu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406543620

                Abstract Engineering nanomaterials at single&#8208;atomic sites can enable unprecedented catalytic properties for broad applications, yet it remains challenging to do so on RuO 2 &#8208;based electrocatalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE). Herein, the rational design and construction of Bi&#8208;RuO 2 single&#8208;atom alloy oxide (SAAO) are presented to boost acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), via phase engineering a novel hexagonal close packed ( hcp ) RuBi single&#8208;atom alloy. This Bi&#8208;RuO 2 SAAO electrocatalyst exhibits a low overpotential of 192 mV and superb stability over 650 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , enabling a practical PEMWE that needs only 1.59 V to reach 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 under industrial conditions. Operando differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy analysis, coupled with density functional theory studies, confirmed the adsorbate&#8208;evolving mechanism on Bi&#8208;RuO 2 SAAO and that the incorporation of Bi 1 improves the activity by electronic density optimization and the stability by hindering surface Ru demetallation. This work not only introduces a new strategy to fabricate high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts at atomic&#8208;level, but also demonstrates their potential use in industrial electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Zhichao Yang, Yutian Ding, Wen Chen, Shuiping Luo, Daofan Cao, Xin Long, Lei Xie, Xincheng Zhou, Xinyi Cai, Ke Liu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable adsorption configuration searching in hetero-catalysis based on similar distribution and active learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115971</link>
      <description>Jiaqiang Yang, Xiaofei Zhang, Xiaofeng Zhang, Bingbo Niu, Feifeng Wu, Ning Luo, Jilin He, Chengduo Wang, Bin Shan, Qingkui Li, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406559764

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqiang Yang, Xiaofei Zhang, Xiaofeng Zhang, Bingbo Niu, Feifeng Wu, Ning Luo, Jilin He, Chengduo Wang, Bin Shan, Qingkui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyrrole-type TM-N3 sites as high-efficient bifunctional oxygen reactions electrocatalysts: From theoretical prediction to experimental validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.01.002</link>
      <description>Chunxia Wu, Yanhui Yu, Yiming Song, Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Ying Liang, Liqiang Jing, Kai Zhang, Zhenjie Zhang, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406560069

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunxia Wu, Yanhui Yu, Yiming Song, Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Ying Liang, Liqiang Jing, Kai Zhang, Zhenjie Zhang, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.01.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing energy and economic costs in post-combustion carbon capture with intelligent amine selection system: A case study on the Abadan power plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2025.01.034</link>
      <description>Farzin Hosseinifard, Amir Mohsen Soufeh, Mohsen Salimi, Milad Hosseinpour, Majid Amidpour, Energy Reports. 13(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406561569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Farzin Hosseinifard, Amir Mohsen Soufeh, Mohsen Salimi, Milad Hosseinpour, Majid Amidpour</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2025.01.034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of the onset voltage of water adsorption on Pt(111) surface using density functional theory/Implicit model calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105809</link>
      <description>Maxim Shishkin, Takeo Yamaguchi, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406562334

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maxim Shishkin, Takeo Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor for electro-oxidation of glycerol with high-efficiency bifunctional Cu-N single atom catalyst and coupled with hydrogen evolution/carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.122</link>
      <description>Mingyue Lv, Hao Sun, Hui Wang, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyue Lv, Hao Sun, Hui Wang, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of transition metal atom doped MoS2 as single-atom electrocatalysts for nitrogen fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115090</link>
      <description>Wei Song, Zhe Fu, Jiale Liu, Jinqiang Li, Chaozheng He, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Song, Zhe Fu, Jiale Liu, Jinqiang Li, Chaozheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ growth of Ni2.86Te2 and Mo6Te8 telluride catalysts on foam NiMo substrates for enhanced oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</link>
      <description>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406570335

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridinic&#8208;N Seized Co in Biphasic Nanoarchitecture for Reversible Oxygen Electrocatalysis Enabling Longevous (&amp;gt;1200 h) Aqueous and Dual&#8208;Anion Kosmotropic Electrolyte Stabilized High Power Quasisolid&#8208;State Zn&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401874</link>
      <description>Srijib Das, Saikat Bolar, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, A. J. Pathak, Ranjit Thapa, Ujjwal Phadikar, Haradhan Kolya, Chun&#8211;Won Kang, Tapas Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Aniruddha Kundu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406593979

                Abstract Integration of different active sites by heterostructure engineering is pivotal to optimize the intrinsic activities of an oxygen electrocatalyst and much needed to enhance the performance of rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, a biphasic nanoarchitecture encased in in situ grown N&#8208;doped graphitic carbon (MnO/Co&#8208;NGC) with heterointerfacial sites are constructed. The density functional theory model reveals formation of lattice oxygen bridged heterostructure with pyridinic nitrogen atoms anchored Co species, which facilitate adsorption of oxygen intermediates. Consequently, the well&#8208;designed catalyst with accessible active sites, abundant oxygen vacant sites, and heterointerfacial coupling effects, simultaneously accelerate the electron/mass transfer and thus promotes the trifunctional electrocatalysis. The assembled aqueous ZAB delivers maximum power density of &#8776;268 mW cm &#8722;2 and a specific capacity of 797.8 mAh g zn &#8722;1 along with excellent rechargeability and extremely small voltage gap decay rate of 0.0007 V h &#8722;1 . Further, the fabricated quasisolid&#8208;state ZAB owns a remarkable power density of 163 mW cm &#8722;2 and long cycle life, outperforming the benchmark air&#8208;electrode and many recent reports, underlining its robustness and suitability for practical utilization in diverse portable applications.</description>
      <author>Srijib Das, Saikat Bolar, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, A. J. Pathak, Ranjit Thapa, Ujjwal Phadikar, Haradhan Kolya, Chun&#8211;Won Kang, Tapas Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Aniruddha Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ electrochemical production of solid peroxide from urine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01277-3</link>
      <description>Xinjian Shi, Yue Jiang, Bailin Zeng, Zhuo-Yue Sun, Maojin Yun, Peng Lv, Yu Jia, Xiaolin Zheng, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406602061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinjian Shi, Yue Jiang, Bailin Zeng, Zhuo-Yue Sun, Maojin Yun, Peng Lv, Yu Jia, Xiaolin Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01277-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Adsorption of Small Molecule Inhibitors and Trimethylaluminum Precursors on the Cu(111) Surface during Area-Selective Atomic Layer Deposition: A GCMC Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04323</link>
      <description>Chen Li, Yichun Li, Jian Weng, Jiafeng Chen, Xiaoyong Cao, Chunlei Wei, Nan Xu, Yi He, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406605724

                In area-selective atomic layer deposition (AS-ALD), small molecule inhibitors (SMIs) play a critical role in directing surface selectivity, preventing unwanted deposition on non-growth surfaces, and enabling precise thin-film formation essential for semiconductor and advanced manufacturing processes. This study utilizes grand canonical Monte Carlo (GCMC) simulations to investigate the competitive adsorption characteristics of three SMIs&#9472;aniline, 3-hexyne, and propanethiol (PT)&#9472;alongside trimethylaluminum (TMA) precursors on a Cu(111) surface. Single-component adsorption analyses reveal that aniline attains the highest coverage among the SMIs, attributed to its strong interaction with the Cu surface; however, this coverage decreases by approximately 42% in the presence of TMA, underscoring its susceptibility to competitive adsorption effects. By contrast, 3-hexyne displays minimal alteration in adsorption when it is in competition with TMA, effectively inhibiting TMA adsorption and indicating its suitability as a robust SMI for AS-ALD. PT also demonstrates moderate inhibitory capability against TMA, although it is less effective than 3-hexyne in this regard. These findings highlight the importance of intermolecular forces and adsorption energies in determining SMI effectiveness in blocking TMA on non-growth surfaces. Mechanistic insights from this study reveal the nuanced influence of specific SMI&#8211;precursor interactions, emphasizing the necessity of selecting SMIs tailored to precursor characteristics and surface interactions. This work provides essential contributions to the rational design of SMIs in AS-ALD, with implications for improving deposition precision and optimizing AS-ALD parameters in nanomanufacturing applications.</description>
      <author>Chen Li, Yichun Li, Jian Weng, Jiafeng Chen, Xiaoyong Cao, Chunlei Wei, Nan Xu, Yi He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient chromium-based transition metal nitrides catalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115385</link>
      <description>Muhammad Faizan, Humaira A. Bibi, Erum Aamir, Roheen Saeed, Sieh Kiong Tiong, Hua Song, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 212(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406605754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Faizan, Humaira A. Bibi, Erum Aamir, Roheen Saeed, Sieh Kiong Tiong, Hua Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De novo-design of highly exposed Co&#8722;N&#8722;C single-atom catalyst for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5813(24)60481-0</link>
      <description>Dan Zhou, Haolin Zhu, Yang Zhao, Yiming Liu, Journal of Fuel Chemistry and Technology. 53(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406608127

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Zhou, Haolin Zhu, Yang Zhao, Yiming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5813(24)60481-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of palladium core size on the activity and durability of Pt-Monolayer electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162477</link>
      <description>Jiye Choi, Eunjik Lee, Seung-min Woo, Youngjoo Whang, Yongmin Kwon, Min Ho Seo, Eunae Cho, Gu&#8208;Gon Park, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615391

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiye Choi, Eunjik Lee, Seung-min Woo, Youngjoo Whang, Yongmin Kwon, Min Ho Seo, Eunae Cho, Gu&#8208;Gon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;Layered Double Hydroxide Heterostructures as Efficient Alkaline Water Splitting (Photo)Electro&#8208;catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409097</link>
      <description>Kayvan Moradi, Maysam Ashrafi, Abdollah Salimi, Marko Melander, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406617906

                Abstract Designing cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts with fast reaction kinetics and high stability is an outstanding challenge in green hydrogen generation through overall water splitting (OWS). Layered double hydroxide (LDH) heterostructure materials are promising candidates to catalyze both oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the two OWS half&#8208;cell reactions. This work develops a facile hydrothermal route to synthesiz hierarchical heterostructure MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;LDH and MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH electrocatalysts, which exhibit extremely good OER and HER performance as witnessed by their low IR&#8208;corrected overpotentials of 156 and 61 mV with at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 under light assistance. The MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH&#8208;MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;LDH OWS cell achieves a low cell voltage of 1.46V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 during light&#8208;assisted water electrolysis. Both materials exhibited exceptional stability under industrially relevant HER and OER conditions, maintaining a current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 with minimal alterations in their potential and performance. The experimental and computational results demonstrate that doping the LDH matrix with high&#8208;valence Mo atoms and MoS 2 quantum dots improves the electrocatalytic activity by 1) enhancing electron transfer, 2) making the electrocatalyst metallic, 3) increasing the number of active sites, 4) lowering the thermodynamic overpotential, and 5) changing the OER mechanism. Overall, this work develops a facile synthesis method to design highly active and stable MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH heterostructure electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Kayvan Moradi, Maysam Ashrafi, Abdollah Salimi, Marko Melander</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-tunable cobalt borides with amorphous shell toward highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236255</link>
      <description>Yuxin Gao, Xiaowei Yang, Yuyang Zong, Lihong Bao, Ruguang Ma, Jijun Zhao, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406618795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Gao, Xiaowei Yang, Yuyang Zong, Lihong Bao, Ruguang Ma, Jijun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of In2+ doping in MoS2 nanosheets for rapid hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118032</link>
      <description>Sanjay A. Bhakhar, G. K. Solanki, Shweta D. Dabhi, Trupti K. Gajaria, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh, Materials Science and Engineering B. 314(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406629707

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sanjay A. Bhakhar, G. K. Solanki, Shweta D. Dabhi, Trupti K. Gajaria, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Nitrogen and Phosphorus Doping of Reduced Graphene Oxide in the Hydrogen Evolution Catalytic Activity of Supported Ru Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15547</link>
      <description>Laura Mall&#243;n, Javier Navarro&#8208;Ruiz, Christian Cerezo-Navarrete, Nuria Romero, Iker Del Rosal, Jordi Garc&#237;a&#8208;Ant&#243;n, Roger Bofill, Luis M. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Prieto, Karine Philippot, Romuald Poteau, Xavier Sala, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406632336

                Three different cathodic materials for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) consisting of Ru nanoparticles (NPs) supported onto a bare and two doped reduced graphene oxides (r-GO) have been studied. Ru NPs have been synthesized in situ by means of the organometallic approach in the presence of each reduced graphene support (bare (rGO), N-doped (NH2-rGO) and P-doped (P-rGO)). (HR)TEM, EDX, EA, ICP-OES, XPS, Raman and NMR techniques have been used to fully characterize the obtained rGO-supported Ru materials. These materials have been deposited onto a glassy carbon rotating disk electrode (GC-RDE) to assess their HER electrocatalytic activity at acidic pH. The results show that all three materials are stable under reductive conditions for at least 12 h, and that the heteroatom-doping of the graphene structure extremely increases the activity of the electrodes, especially for the case of Ru@P-rGO, where the overpotential at &#8722;10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 decreases to only 2 mV. Realistic (based on experimental compositional data) modeling of the three rGO supports combined with DFT computational analysis of the electronic and electrocatalytic properties of the hybrid nanocatalysts allows attributing the observed electrocatalytic performances to a combination of interrelated factors such as the distance of the Ru atoms to the dopped rGO support and the hydride content at the Ru NP surface.</description>
      <author>Laura Mall&#243;n, Javier Navarro&#8208;Ruiz, Christian Cerezo-Navarrete, Nuria Romero, Iker Del Rosal, Jordi Garc&#237;a&#8208;Ant&#243;n, Roger Bofill, Luis M. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Prieto, Karine Philippot, Romuald Poteau, Xavier Sala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrostatic and Electronic Effects on Doped Nickel Oxide Nanofilms for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14493</link>
      <description>Ina &#216;str&#248;m, Marco Favaro, Moein Seyfouri, Patrick A. Burr, Bram Hoex, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406632531

                An ideal water-splitting electrocatalyst is inexpensive, abundant, highly active, stable, selective, and durable. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the main bottleneck for H2 production with a complex and not fully resolved mechanism, slow kinetics, and high overpotential. Nickel oxide-based catalysts (NiOx) are highly active and cheaper than precious metal catalysts. However, rigorous catalyst tests and DFT calculations are still needed to rationally optimize NiOx catalysts. In this work, we combine plasma-enhanced atomic layer deposition (PE-ALD) and density functional theory (DFT) to address the role of dopants in promoting NiOx OER activity. Ultrathin films of NiOx doped with Zn2+, Al3+, and Sn4+ presented improved intrinsic activity, stability, and durability for the OER. The results show a low to high catalytic performance of ZnNiOx &lt; NiOx &lt; AlNiOx &lt; SnNiOx, which we attribute to an increase in the concentration of valence band (VB) holes combined with conduction band (CB) electron conductivity, characterized by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The influence of doping on the electronic structure and catalytic activity was investigated using advanced characterization techniques and density functional theory (DFT) calculations (PEB0/pob-TZVP). DFT complements the experimental results, showing that the dopant charge states and orbital hybridization enhance the OER by improving the charge carrier concentration and mobility, thus allowing optimal binding energies and charge dynamics and delocalization. Our findings demonstrate the potential of PE-ALD-doped nanofilms NiOx and DFT to rationally design and develop catalysts for sustainable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Ina &#216;str&#248;m, Marco Favaro, Moein Seyfouri, Patrick A. Burr, Bram Hoex</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The InP(100) Surface Phase Diagram: From the Gas Phase to the Electrochemical Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20370</link>
      <description>Holger Euchner, Vibhav Yadav, Matthias M. May, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406636092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Holger Euchner, Vibhav Yadav, Matthias M. May</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20370</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-round enhancement induced by oxophilic single Ru and W atoms for alkaline hydrogen oxidation of tiny Pt nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56240-y</link>
      <description>Wensheng Jiao, Zhanghao Ren, Zhibo Cui, Chao Ma, Ziang Shang, Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Tao Gan, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406639376

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wensheng Jiao, Zhanghao Ren, Zhibo Cui, Chao Ma, Ziang Shang, Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Tao Gan, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56240-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Mechanism on Pristine and Defective Nickel Phosphate Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsurfi.2025.100431</link>
      <description>Dyah Puspasari Wijayanti, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Damar Rastri Adhika, Hamad AlMohamadi, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Results in Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406642017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dyah Puspasari Wijayanti, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Damar Rastri Adhika, Hamad AlMohamadi, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsurfi.2025.100431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical approaches for CO2 point source, direct air, and seawater capture: identifying opportunities and synergies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-025-35890-x</link>
      <description>Mehar U Nisa, Haris Ishaq, Curran Crawford, Environmental Science and Pollution Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406500378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mehar U Nisa, Haris Ishaq, Curran Crawford</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-025-35890-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress of porous covalent organic frameworks membranes for gas- and liquid-phase separation towards environmental chemical engineering applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115487</link>
      <description>Xiaojian Yang, Wenxuan Li, Shenglin Wang, Honglei Shuai, Han Zhang, Xinsheng Zhao, Yanan Gao, Hui L&#252;, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406560945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojian Yang, Wenxuan Li, Shenglin Wang, Honglei Shuai, Han Zhang, Xinsheng Zhao, Yanan Gao, Hui L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for metal additive manufacturing process optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-22145-3.00006-2</link>
      <description>Harpreet Kaur Channi, Raman Kumar, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406568255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harpreet Kaur Channi, Raman Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-22145-3.00006-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Solid-Supported Amines for Thermocatalytic Reactive CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10049</link>
      <description>W. Wilson McNeary, Nathan C. Ellebracht, Melinda L. Jue, Mathew J. Rasmussen, James M. Crawford, Matthew M. Yung, Anh T. To, Simon H. Pang, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406468596

                Reactive CO2 capture (RCC) is a promising strategy for process intensification of carbon capture and conversion for production of low-carbon fuels and chemicals. As state-of-the-art sorbent materials in point source and direct air capture systems, solid-supported amines are a natural choice to pair with supported CO2 hydrogenation catalysts (e.g., metallic nanoparticles) for developing high-capacity sorbent-catalyst materials for use in RCC. In this Perspective, we summarize the relevant literature combining solid-supported amines with metallic nanoparticles for thermocatalytic RCC and detail two of our own case studies using RCC to synthesize methane and methanol. Our observations suggest that the temperature mismatch between CO2 desorption and reaction, along with potential catalyst site poisoning by grafted aminosilanes, is a significant obstacle to realizing the potential of amine-based RCC materials in the decarbonization of chemical production. This stands in contrast to literature detailing successful RCC using liquid amines and solid catalysts, which may benefit from more favorable mass transfer dynamics, as well as early stage reports into RCC solid-phase amine-Pd materials, whose findings we were not able to replicate. More judicious reaction selection and synthetic design strategies to match materials with process conditions offer alternative pathways for future research.</description>
      <author>W. Wilson McNeary, Nathan C. Ellebracht, Melinda L. Jue, Mathew J. Rasmussen, James M. Crawford, Matthew M. Yung, Anh T. To, Simon H. Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficacy of biochar as a catalyst for a Fenton-like reaction: Experimental, statistical and mathematical modeling analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2025.107014</link>
      <description>Oscar M. Rodr&#237;guez-Narv&#225;ez, Bhuman Pandita, Omesh Goyal, Srinivas Rallapalli, Mahinda I. Ranasinghe, Alain S. Conejo-D&#225;vila, Erick R. Bandala, Ashantha Goonetilleke, Journal of Water Process Engineering. 70(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406561020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oscar M. Rodr&#237;guez-Narv&#225;ez, Bhuman Pandita, Omesh Goyal, Srinivas Rallapalli, Mahinda I. Ranasinghe, Alain S. Conejo-D&#225;vila, Erick R. Bandala, Ashantha Goonetilleke</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2025.107014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Optoelectronic Properties of SrVO3 via Strain and Transition-Metal Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-025-11735-8</link>
      <description>P. V. Manivannan, Sudatta Giri, Debolina Misra, Journal of Electronic Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406610752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P. V. Manivannan, Sudatta Giri, Debolina Misra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-025-11735-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development and Thermo-Mechanical Testing of Low Hysteresis Shape Memory Alloy for Satellite Actuators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12794/metadc2048636</link>
      <description>Andre Montagnoli, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4406530876

                Shape memory alloys (SMAs) have gained much attention as a powerful source of actuation due to their improved performance, reduced size, and reduced complexity between components as well as having a high work output density. Their primary mechanism of actuation relies on a non-diffusional cyclic phase transformation from martensite to austenite, where the amount of thermal energy needed per cycle is directly associated with the hysteresis width between the austenite final and martensite final temperatures. Consequently, a narrower gap between those two temperature ranges requires a much lower energy demand to produce the actuation needed. Previous studies have indicated that the hysteresis width is linked to a strong coherence between the austenite/martensite interface. It has been shown that elemental additions to NiTi-based SMAs can further improve this coherency. Another huge challenge facing this unique technology is linked with its thermo-mechanical stability. Binary NiTi SMAs often exhibit significant transformation temperature shifts after each thermo-mechanical cycle, which can contribute to a shorter lifespan. The primary goal of this project is to identify and develop thermo-mechanically stable, low hysteresis shape memory alloys (LHSMAs) for actuator applications. To accomplish this goal, elemental additions of Cu, Co, Hf, and Pd were incorporated into NiTi-based SMAs and the results were compared in respect to their hysteresis width and thermo-mechanical stability through differential scanning calorimetry, scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive spectroscopy, and compressive thermo-mechanical testing. Two quaternary SMAs containing small additions of Cu and Pd were shown to exhibit promising results with respect to hysteresis width and good thermo-mechanical stability.</description>
      <author>Andre Montagnoli</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12794/metadc2048636</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
