<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 01:45:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Transition States Energies from Machine Learning: An Application to Reverse Water&#8211;Gas Shift on Single-Atom Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02818</link>
      <description>Raffaele Cheula, Mie Andersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411369078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Raffaele Cheula, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi&#8208;Task Learning in Homogeneous Catalysis: A Case Study for Predicting the Catalytic Performance in Ethylene Polymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70157</link>
      <description>Zubair Sadiq, Wenhong Yang, Weishen Yang, Wen&#8208;Hua Sun, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411371031

                ABSTRACT This study focuses on training a multi&#8208;task learning (MTL) type machine learning (ML) model to predict diverse catalytic performance of 195 bis(imino)pyridine transition metal complexes toward ethylene polymerization, with comparison to their single&#8208;task learning (STL) counterparts. The CatBoost MTL model outperforms all other models, showing predictions and generalization errors for the properties of catalytic activity ( R t 2 =0.741, R 2 = 0.985, Q 2 = 0.600), molecular weight ( R t 2 =0.873, R 2 = 0.997, Q 2 = 0.846), molecular weight distribution ( R t 2 =0.831, R 2 = 0.999, Q 2 = 0.839), and melting temperature ( R t 2 =0.813, R 2 = 0.992, Q 2 = 0.625) of the produced polymer. The interpretation of the model reveals that complexes with electron&#8208;donating groups, simple alkyl groups (such as methyl groups etc.), and a higher degree of unsaturation (presence of double or triple bonds) positively influence the predicted properties. Subsequently, providing insights into the underlying mechanisms of variation in catalytic performance, new complexes are designed with superior catalytic performances.</description>
      <author>Zubair Sadiq, Wenhong Yang, Weishen Yang, Wen&#8208;Hua Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Fe Electrocatalysts: Unlocking Sustainable, Selective, and Durable Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202506186</link>
      <description>Diab Khalafallah, Libei Feng, Zhiyuan Sun, Shengfu Tong, Jue Wang, Qinfang Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411374857

                Abstract Seawater electrolysis (SWE) serves as a renewable alternative, significantly lowering the costs of electrolyzer technologies by eliminating the need for supplementary water purification operations, hence facilitating marine offshore H 2 generation and providing pure drinking water. Nonetheless, the intricate composition of seawater and the challenges associated with commercial SWE are significant, including local pH variations, solid impurities and precipitates, and the competition between the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). To reshape the energy landscape and achieve carbon neutrality, the development of cost&#8208;efficient electrocatalysts for SWE with adjustable electrocatalytic activity, enhanced OER selectivity, and sustained stability under elevated current densities is a crucial consideration and pragmatic option. This review systematically elucidates the principles and mechanisms of SWE, analyzes corrosion resistance strategies, and identifies difficulties related to activity and durability to enhance comprehensive research and practical application of Fe&#8208;based electrocatalysts. It critically examines diverse contemporary methodologies for tailoring advanced Fe nanomaterials and summarizes the latest developments in various electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), OER in seawater, and overall seawater splitting (OSWS), supported by significant studies from recent literature. Furthermore, current challenges, opportunities, and distinctive insights for developing efficient and durable electrocatalysts and integrated seawater electrolyzers are well emphasized.</description>
      <author>Diab Khalafallah, Libei Feng, Zhiyuan Sun, Shengfu Tong, Jue Wang, Qinfang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202506186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Nanofilms Mediate Adhesion and Heat Transfer at Hematite&#8208;Hydrocarbon Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500267</link>
      <description>Fionn Carman, Fernando Bresme, Billy Wu, Daniele Dini, James P. Ewen, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411376896

                Abstract A detailed understanding of nanoscale heat transport at metal oxide&#8208;hydrocarbon interfaces is critical for many applications that require efficient thermal management. Under ambient conditions, water nanofilms are expected to form at these interfaces, but these are rarely accounted for in simulations. Using molecular dynamics simulations, it is shown that water nanofilms at the hydroxylated hematite/poly&#8208;&#945;&#8208;olefin (PAO) interface significantly affect wettability and thermal transport. Including water nanofilms improves agreement with experimental work of adhesion, which cannot be replicated with anhydrous systems using realistic solid&#8211;liquid interactions. For water films thicker than one monolayer, interfacial thermal resistance (ITR) converges to a consistent value, independent of solid&#8211;liquid interaction strength. This value is dominated by the ITR at the water/PAO interface. The ITR at the water/PAO interface is dependent on the surface area between the water film and the PAO and the magnitude of the interfacial potential. These simulations provide a more precise estimate of ITR at the hematite/PAO interface by accounting for surface hydration expected in experiments under ambient conditions. This study offers crucial insights into the roles of surface hydroxylation and water nanofilms in controlling wettability and thermal transport at industrially important interfaces.</description>
      <author>Fionn Carman, Fernando Bresme, Billy Wu, Daniele Dini, James P. Ewen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axiomatic Design for Analysis and Noniterative Engineering of Photoelectrochemical Cells for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion at High Photon to Product Yield</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/aps.5c00004</link>
      <description>Suzanne Assen, G. J. A. Sevink, Huub J. M. de Groot, Artificial photosynthesis.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411377550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suzanne Assen, G. J. A. Sevink, Huub J. M. de Groot</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/aps.5c00004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-guided discovery of thermodynamically stable single-atom catalysts on functionalized MXenes for enhanced oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02929e</link>
      <description>Hengquan Guo, Seung Geol Lee, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411378272

                DFT and machine learning are combined to screen transition-metal-doped MXene (Ti 3 C 2 T 2 ) catalysts for oxygen electrocatalysis. Ni&#8211;Ti 3 C 2 S 2 and Cu&#8211;Ti 3 C 2 S 2 show low ORR/OER overpotentials, highlighting the power of ML-accelerated catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Hengquan Guo, Seung Geol Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02929e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir&#8211;Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/CoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction Enables Efficient Alkaline Oxygen Evolution through Binuclear Ir&#8211;Co Active Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c00603</link>
      <description>Zheheng Jiang, Wei Liu, Muzammil Hussain, Hao Sun, Yun Kuang, Yaping Li, Wen Liu, Daojin Zhou, Xiaoming Sun, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411383367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheheng Jiang, Wei Liu, Muzammil Hussain, Hao Sun, Yun Kuang, Yaping Li, Wen Liu, Daojin Zhou, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c00603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diastereoselectivity Controlled by the Hydrogenation Mechanisms during the Electrochemical Reduction of a Carbonyl Group</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06733</link>
      <description>Xin Yuan, Kwanpyung Lee, J. R. Schmidt, Kyoung&#8208;Shin Choi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411401811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Yuan, Kwanpyung Lee, J. R. Schmidt, Kyoung&#8208;Shin Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab initio calculation of the effect of phosphorus substitution on MgAl&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e697" altimg="si21.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;S&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e705" altimg="si31.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; monolayer for electrocatalytic and water-splitting &#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112880</link>
      <description>Tarik Ouahrani, David Dell&#8217;Angelo, Ali Esquembre Ku&#269;ukali&#263;, Reda M. Boufatah, Micha&#235;l Badawi, Alfonso Mu&#241;oz, Daniel Errandonea, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411405303

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tarik Ouahrani, David Dell&#8217;Angelo, Ali Esquembre Ku&#269;ukali&#263;, Reda M. Boufatah, Micha&#235;l Badawi, Alfonso Mu&#241;oz, Daniel Errandonea</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112880</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Senescent Alveolar Type 2 Cells with a Gene-Editable FePt Dual-Atom Catalyst for Mitigating Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c04686</link>
      <description>Qianglan Lu, Chengwei Ye, Wei Mao, Fei Zeng, Zhiyong Liu, Ruiyue Chen, Xiao Cheng, Yanfeng Gao, Meng Wang, Mei Liu, Shaochun Tang, Yujun Song, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411407384

                Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) remains an age-related, fatal, incurable, epithelial-driven fibrotic lung disease despite the availability of approved antifibrotic drugs. The medical need for effective antipulmonary fibrotic therapies is thus very high. A promising therapeutic intervention for IPF is to target key cellular senescence processes in alveolar type 2 (AT2) cells. Herein, we introduce an inhalable gene-editable nanoplatform, comprising a CRISPR-Cas9 gene-editing system linked to a core FePt diatomic catalyst, encapsulated within a biocompatible hyaluronic acid (HA) surface layer (FePtR@HA). The FePt diatomic site facilitates H2O2 bridge adsorption, enabling efficient O-O bond cleavage and rapid catalytic conversion. The strong Fe-Pt interaction modulates the metal's d-band center, optimizing the adsorption of oxygen-containing intermediates. This precise regulation efficiently clears ROS, delivering robust antioxidant and antisenescence effects to AT2 cells. Simultaneously, the CRISPR-Cas9 gene editing system knocks down the pro-aging gene KAT7, reducing senescence-associated secretory phenotype (SASP) factors and further reversing AT2 cell senescence. Additionally, we demonstrated the antifibrotic efficacy of FePtR@HA in a lung-on-a-chip model, where it reprogrammed the fibrotic microenvironment, prevented myofibroblast recruitment to AT2 cells. Moreover, FePtR@HA showed satisfactory results in IPF mouse models, alleviating fibrosis and presenting a highly promising approach to combat the progression of IPF.</description>
      <author>Qianglan Lu, Chengwei Ye, Wei Mao, Fei Zeng, Zhiyong Liu, Ruiyue Chen, Xiao Cheng, Yanfeng Gao, Meng Wang, Mei Liu, Shaochun Tang, Yujun Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c04686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction on Gold without Metal or Organic Cations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02785</link>
      <description>Hansaem Jang, Christopher John O'Brien, Nathaniel J. D. Hill, Adrian M. Gardner, Iv&#225;n Scivetti, Gilberto Teobaldi, Alexander J. Cowan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411411737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hansaem Jang, Christopher John O'Brien, Nathaniel J. D. Hill, Adrian M. Gardner, Iv&#225;n Scivetti, Gilberto Teobaldi, Alexander J. Cowan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Force Fields in Electrochemistry: From Fundamentals to Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c05553</link>
      <description>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Saori Minami, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411424580

                This article reviews the foundations and applications of machine learning force fields (MLFFs) in electrochemistry, highlighting their role as a transformative tool in materials science. We first provide an overview of MLFFs, then discuss their applications in ionics and electrochemical reactions, and finally outline future directions. Most MLFF approaches use invariant or equivariant descriptors derived from body-order expansions to represent many-body atomic interactions. These descriptors feed into linear regression models, kernel methods, or neural networks to construct potential energy surfaces for gases, liquids, solids, and interfaces involving inorganic and organic materials. MLFFs have enabled a wide range of advances, including all-atom molecular dynamics (MD), data extraction from MD, and accelerated materials discovery. In MD simulations, MLFFs allow accurate evaluation of ionic conductivity via the fluctuation-dissipation theorem and nonequilibrium MD under electric fields, applied to both solid and polymer electrolytes. For electrochemical reactions, MLFFs and &#916;-ML models have been used to predict redox potentials in homogeneous and interfacial systems through thermodynamic integration. MLFFs also enable the extraction of key thermodynamic and kinetic information-such as free energy landscapes and local transport coefficients-from atomic trajectories, facilitating coarse-grained modeling of mass transport and reactions in complex electrolytes. In materials discovery, MLFFs have allowed high-throughput screening of 107 to 108 crystal structures, leading to the identification of promising Li-ion and Na-ion solid electrolytes. MLFFs are expected to continue evolving as a core technology in computational materials science, spanning a wide range from high-precision calculations to large-scale materials exploration.</description>
      <author>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Saori Minami</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c05553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study on the Electronic Structure and Efficient Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution of Boron-Doped Fibrous Red Phosphorene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.74.20250540</link>
      <description>Lu Yi-Lin, Dong Shengjie, Cui Fangchao, Dongming Chen, M.J. Zhuo, Acta Physica Sinica. 74(16)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411431553

                Under the dual challenges of the energy crisis and environmental pollution, the technology of photocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen production has become a research hotspot in clean energy due to its green and sustainable characteristics. As a novel quasi-one-dimensional semiconductor material, fibrous red phosphorene (FRP) exhibits remarkable photocatalytic hydrogen evolution potential, owing to its moderate bandgap, high carrier mobility, and excellent air stability. Based on first-principles calculations, we systematically investigated the regulatory mechanisms of a series of non-metallic elements &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; (B, C, N, O, Si, S, As, and Se) doping on the electronic structure and catalytic performance of single-layer FRP. The results show that the element &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; can effectively enhance the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity of single-layer FRP. Among them, four doped systems (S-doped at site 1, B-doped at sites 1/2/5) exhibit excellent catalytic activity for HER. In particular, the B-doped system at site 2 has the most ideal free energy of hydrogen adsorption (&#916;&lt;i&gt;G&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;H*&lt;/sub&gt;), and its overpotential (&lt;i&gt;&#951;&lt;/i&gt; = -0.074 V) is comparable to that of the noble metal Pt catalyst. Through the analysis of the electronic structure, it is found that the enhancement of the HER catalytic activity is closely related to the downward shift of the &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; pz-band center at the adsorption site. There is a direct proportional relationship between &#916;&lt;i&gt;G&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;H*&lt;/sub&gt; and the &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;z&lt;/sub&gt;-band center (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; &#8805; 0.78), indicating that the &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;z&lt;/sub&gt;-band center can serve as a key electronic descriptor for regulating the HER activity. Further verification by calculations using the HSE06 hybrid functional shows that the band edge positions of the B-doped system can span both sides of the redox potential of water, and the light absorption range covers the visible light region, indicating the thermodynamic feasibility and spectral response advantages of this system in the application of photocatalytic overall water splitting. This study provides important theoretical guidance for the design of efficient FRP-based photocatalytic materials based on the non-metallic doping strategy.</description>
      <author>Lu Yi-Lin, Dong Shengjie, Cui Fangchao, Dongming Chen, M.J. Zhuo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.74.20250540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of pz band in hybrid carbon-bimetallic subnanocluster PtM (M = 3d, 4d, 5d block metals) catalysts to boost electrochemical oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsadv.2025.100792</link>
      <description>Eoyoon Lee, Sangyong Shin, Hyunjoo Lee, Hyung Chul Ham, Applied Surface Science Advances. 28(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411438679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eoyoon Lee, Sangyong Shin, Hyunjoo Lee, Hyung Chul Ham</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsadv.2025.100792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aqueous Stability of Metallic Materials and Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00455</link>
      <description>Yizhan Zhang, Lin Wang, Elena Scivally, Kenneth James, Evelyn McBride, Mahesh Jagathpriya Dheerasinghe, Michael Shatruk, Yan Zeng, Bin Ouyang, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411459298

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yizhan Zhang, Lin Wang, Elena Scivally, Kenneth James, Evelyn McBride, Mahesh Jagathpriya Dheerasinghe, Michael Shatruk, Yan Zeng, Bin Ouyang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00455</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polaronic Competition Triggers the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Evolution on Perovskite Oxides during Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02069</link>
      <description>Mohsen Sotoudeh, Axel Gro&#223;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411466009

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Sotoudeh, Axel Gro&#223;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability Investigation on NiFeO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution During on and off Cycles in Harsh Alkaline Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500081</link>
      <description>Reika Suzuki, Keisuke Obata, Yutaka Sasaki, Kiyohiro Adachi, Kazuhiro Takanabe, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411466250

                Water electrolysis powered by renewable energy sources is a mature and practical technique to produce green hydrogen. Its production cost is heavily influenced by efficiency and durability, with a particular concern being the durability of anodes for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in highly oxidative and acidic/alkaline environments at elevated temperatures. Durability during intermittent operations with renewable sources, factoring in on/off cycling, is also a consideration. This study investigates the durability of NiFeO x , one of the most active electrocatalysts in alkaline conditions, under various conditions including industrially relevant conditions: 7 M KOH at 80 &#176;C and 600 mA cm &#8722;2 . The results show that on/off operations with extensive potential variation caused severe degradations compared to constant OER operations. However, stability improves slightly with the addition of saturated Fe 3+ ions into the electrolyte, preventing Fe leaching. By dissecting the degradation mechanism step&#8208;by&#8208;step, this study illuminates the limitations and assists in creating strategies for highly durable electrolysis systems.</description>
      <author>Reika Suzuki, Keisuke Obata, Yutaka Sasaki, Kiyohiro Adachi, Kazuhiro Takanabe</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging LLMs to identify patent-free glass materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114022</link>
      <description>Shingo Urata, N. Miya, Ryota Hashimoto, Teppei Konishi, Kensuke Fujii, Yumiko Katayama, Kazuki Kanehara, Computational Materials Science. 258(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411466319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shingo Urata, N. Miya, Ryota Hashimoto, Teppei Konishi, Kensuke Fujii, Yumiko Katayama, Kazuki Kanehara</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Crystalline CoNi Selenite for Investigating a Metal Synergic Effect in Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02941</link>
      <description>Ting Wang, Zhuoya Pei, Dandan Chen, Shujiao Yang, Xiaohan Liu, Jiwu Zhao, Xuepeng Zhang, Rui Cao, Wei Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411466968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Wang, Zhuoya Pei, Dandan Chen, Shujiao Yang, Xiaohan Liu, Jiwu Zhao, Xuepeng Zhang, Rui Cao, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Cobalt on N-Doped Reduced Graphene Oxide Pushes the Oxygen Reduction Reaction toward 4-Electron Pathway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6904882/v1</link>
      <description>Francesca Risplendi, Nadia Garino, Juqin Zeng, Adriano Sacco, Shweta Mehta, Chiara Deriu, Laura Fabris, M. Fontana, Angelica Chiodoni, Giancarlo Cicero, Micaela Castellino, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411467810

                Abstract We present a cobalt-based single-atom catalyst (SAC) anchored on nitrogen-doped reduced graphene oxide (Co-N-rGO), synthesized via a rapid, one-pot microwave-assisted method. Comprehensive characterization by FESEM, TEM, Raman spectroscopy, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy confirms the successful formation of atomically dispersed Co(II) centers, coordinated to oxygen-containing functional groups within the graphene matrix, with no evidence of metallic clusters or oxide nanoparticles. The atomically dispersed Co sites act as highly active centers for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in alkaline media, delivering near four-electron transfer efficiency, a positive onset potential, and outstanding durability that surpasses commercial Pt/C catalysts. First-principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations corroborate the XPS findings and reveal the electronic structure of the Co&#8211;O coordination environment, offering atomistic insight into the catalytic mechanism. The synergy between precise site isolation, optimized local coordination, and electronic modulation enables the superior electrocatalytic performance of this Co SAC. This study establishes a versatile and scalable framework for engineering high-performance ORR catalysts featuring non-noble metal single-atom active sites.</description>
      <author>Francesca Risplendi, Nadia Garino, Juqin Zeng, Adriano Sacco, Shweta Mehta, Chiara Deriu, Laura Fabris, M. Fontana, Angelica Chiodoni, Giancarlo Cicero, Micaela Castellino</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6904882/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atom Engineering for Electrocatalysis: Fundamentals and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c08027</link>
      <description>Mario Urso, Xiaohui Ju, Radhika Nittoor&#8208;Veedu, Hyesung Lee, Dagmar Zaoralov&#225;, Michal Otyepka, Martin Pumera, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411469722

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mario Urso, Xiaohui Ju, Radhika Nittoor&#8208;Veedu, Hyesung Lee, Dagmar Zaoralov&#225;, Michal Otyepka, Martin Pumera</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c08027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfer Learning for Predictive Molecular Simulations: Data-Efficient Potential Energy Surfaces at CCSD(T) Accuracy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00523</link>
      <description>Silvan K&#228;ser, Jeremy O. Richardson, Markus Meuwly, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411472096

                Accurate potential energy surfaces (PESs) are critical for predictive molecular simulations. However, obtaining a PES at the highest levels of quantum chemical accuracy, such as CCSD(T), becomes computationally infeasible as molecular size increases. This work presents CCSD(T)-quality PESs using data-efficient techniques based on transfer learning to obtain state-of-the-art accuracy at a fraction of the computational cost for systems that would otherwise be intractable. Most importantly, the framework for accurate molecular simulations pursued here extends beyond specific observables and follows a rational strategy to obtain highest-accuracy PESs, which can be used for applications to spectroscopy and other experiments. As rigorous tests of the PESs, semiclassical tunnelling splittings for tropolone and the (propiolic acid)-(formic acid) dimer (PFD) as well as anharmonic frequencies for tropolone were determined. For tropolone, all observables are in excellent agreement with the experiment using the high-level PES, whereas for PFD, the agreement is less good but still orders of magnitude better than previous calculations.</description>
      <author>Silvan K&#228;ser, Jeremy O. Richardson, Markus Meuwly</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe-based Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Conditions: Recent Trends in the Design and Structure-Activity Correlations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2025.100161</link>
      <description>Anju C. Mathew, Sivaraj Rajendran, Thomas Mathew, N. Raveendran Shiju, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411476546

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anju C. Mathew, Sivaraj Rajendran, Thomas Mathew, N. Raveendran Shiju</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2025.100161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Catalytic Properties of ZEZ N&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; for Oxygen Reduction Reactions in Both Alkaline and Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c00882</link>
      <description>Safa Alzaim, Haizheng Zhuang, Joshua Young, Xianqin Wang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411483772

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Safa Alzaim, Haizheng Zhuang, Joshua Young, Xianqin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c00882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential of water splitting in the global energy future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-29064-0.00005-x</link>
      <description>Sajith Kurian, Lu&#237;s Paulo Mour&#227;o dos Santos, Soney C. George, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411485463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajith Kurian, Lu&#237;s Paulo Mour&#227;o dos Santos, Soney C. George</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-29064-0.00005-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photovoltaic electrochemical integration for water-splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-29064-0.00016-4</link>
      <description>P. Philip, Ajesh K. Zachariah, Anju K. Nair, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411485711

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P. Philip, Ajesh K. Zachariah, Anju K. Nair</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-29064-0.00016-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the state-of-the-art advancements in morphology and electronic structure engineering on cobalt diselenide-based nanomaterials for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150049</link>
      <description>Trung Hieu Bui, Thi Anh Nga Nguyen, Vu Khac Hoang Bui, Huy Du Nguyen, Vinh Van Tran, Ha Huu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 148(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411487390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Trung Hieu Bui, Thi Anh Nga Nguyen, Vu Khac Hoang Bui, Huy Du Nguyen, Vinh Van Tran, Ha Huu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu&#8210;S Covalent Bonds Enable the Anchoring of Single&#8208;atom Cu on Layered MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Highly Selective and Active Photothermal Catalytic Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8722;H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O to Ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202504167</link>
      <description>Yang Luo, Gaoli Chen, Zhongliao Wang, Sujuan Zhang, Xiuzhen Zheng, Sugang Meng, Shifu Chen, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411492211

                Abstract The catalytic conversion of CO 2 into high&#8208;value C 2+ products offers a sustainable path toward carbon neutrality. However, traditional photocatalytic and thermal catalytic methods face challenges like low selectivity and yields. Herein, a novel Cu/MoS 2 photothermal catalyst is synthesized via a two&#8208;step hydrothermal method, anchoring single&#8208;atom Cu on layered MoS 2 for CO 2 and H 2 O reduction into C 2 products (ethanol, acetylene, and ethane). Under optimal conditions (250 &#176;C, 903 mW&#183;cm &#8722;2 , 320&#8211;780 nm), the Cu 5% &#8211;MoS 2 catalyst achieves an ethanol yield of 3.1 mmol&#183;g &#8722;1 &#183;h &#8722;1 , 4.6 times higher than blank MoS 2 . Mechanistic studies reveal that Cu improves light absorption and enhances CO 2 adsorption and *COOH accumulation at MoS 2 edge S sites, as confirmed by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Mo&#8211;Cu dual sites stabilize *CHO intermediates, boosting C 2 product selectivity. The synergistic photothermal effect accelerates charge migration and surface reactions. This work provides cost&#8208;effective insights into photothermal CO 2 conversion for fuel production.</description>
      <author>Yang Luo, Gaoli Chen, Zhongliao Wang, Sujuan Zhang, Xiuzhen Zheng, Sugang Meng, Shifu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202504167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering of RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Ru&#8211;Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; heterostructures for high-efficiency oxygen evolution in acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ce00474h</link>
      <description>Y. Yuan, Chang Liu, Shanshan Liu, Ruimin Ding, Xi Yin, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411495626

                Schematic illustration of the structure&#8211;activity relationship of RCO_ T catalysts for OER.</description>
      <author>Y. Yuan, Chang Liu, Shanshan Liu, Ruimin Ding, Xi Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ce00474h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning nitrate reduction reaction selectivity via selective adsorption in electrified membranes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-025-00237-3</link>
      <description>Yingzheng Fan, Yu Yan, Obinna Nwokonkwo, Daniel J. Rivera, Weiyi Pan, Eric Chen, Ji-Yong Kim, Julia Simon, Max Saffer-Meng, X.W. Wang, Christopher L. Muhich, Lea R. Winter, Nature Chemical Engineering. 2(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411497363

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingzheng Fan, Yu Yan, Obinna Nwokonkwo, Daniel J. Rivera, Weiyi Pan, Eric Chen, Ji-Yong Kim, Julia Simon, Max Saffer-Meng, X.W. Wang, Christopher L. Muhich, Lea R. Winter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-025-00237-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Strain and Ligand Effects Boosting the Activity of Pt-Based Peroxidase Nanozymes for Femtomolar-Level Colorimetric Immunoassay of Protein Biomarkers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.5c01825</link>
      <description>Han Zhang, Yan Zhang, Xiang Peng, W Qiu, Y. H. Tan, Jing Xu, Qunfang Li, Dianyong Tang, Zhuangqiang Gao, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411498190

                Sensitive detection of protein biomarkers is crucial for advancing biomedical research and clinical management. Although colorimetric enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (CELISAs) have been widely recognized as a benchmark technique for protein biomarker detection, their sensitivity is fundamentally constrained by the intrinsic catalytic limitations of conventional enzyme labels. In this study, we present the engineering of high-performance Pt-based peroxidase nanozymes leveraging the synergistic effects of strain and ligand interactions. This advancement enables the development of an ultrasensitive CELISA platform capable of detecting protein biomarkers at femtomolar levels, providing a promising solution to address the existing sensitivity limitations. These Pt-based peroxidase nanozymes are precisely engineered by conformally coating Pd nanocubes with uniform, ultrathin Pt shells consisting of just four atomic layers (Pd@Pt4L nanocubes). The atomic-level Pt shells endow the Pd@Pt4L nanocubes with the strain and ligand effects, resulting in a &#8764;2000-fold enhancement in peroxidase-like catalytic activity compared to traditional horseradish peroxidase (HRP), and thus making them highly efficient as catalytic labels for enhancing the sensitivity of CELISAs. Taking interleukin-6 (IL-6) detection as an example, we demonstrate that the Pd@Pt4L nanocube-based CELISA enables quantitative analysis within a dynamic range of 0.05-5 pg mL-1 and achieves an impressive limit of detection (LOD) of 0.046 pg mL-1 (1.8 fM), representing a &#8764;20-fold enhancement in sensitivity over the conventional HRP-based CELISA. These discoveries underscore the impact of strain and ligand modulation on enhancing the catalytic activity of nanozymes and highlight their potential as catalytic labels for advancing ultrasensitive bioassay technologies.</description>
      <author>Han Zhang, Yan Zhang, Xiang Peng, W Qiu, Y. H. Tan, Jing Xu, Qunfang Li, Dianyong Tang, Zhuangqiang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.5c01825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Degradation Mechanisms in PtCu/C&#8211;N Bimetallic ORR Catalysts: IL-TEM Study Applied to Current Accelerated Stress Testing Protocols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146743</link>
      <description>Angelina Pavlets, Elizaveta Moguchikh, Ilya Pankov, Ya. V. Astravukh, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411504355

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angelina Pavlets, Elizaveta Moguchikh, Ilya Pankov, Ya. V. Astravukh, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a cascade catalytic strategy with base metals for hydrodeoxygenation of lignin derivatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136055</link>
      <description>Peng Gao, Xuewu Ji, Chunyang Dong, Min Zheng, Zhen Fang, Guirong Bao, Fuel. 402(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411506558

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Gao, Xuewu Ji, Chunyang Dong, Min Zheng, Zhen Fang, Guirong Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical and Electrocatalytic Behavior of Platinum&#8211;Palladium Bulk Alloy Single Crystal Electrodes in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02416</link>
      <description>Gabriel Melle, Juan M. Feli&#250;, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais, Enrique Herrero, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411515934

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gabriel Melle, Juan M. Feli&#250;, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais, Enrique Herrero</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence-Driven Catalyst Design for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Production: Paradigm Innovation and Challenges in Material Discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scenem.2025.100010</link>
      <description>Zhaoyong Jin, Dongxu Gu, Panpan Li, Guilin Ye, Haiou Zhu, Kailun Wei, Chunxiang Li, Wenhui Zhong, Wenjie Du, Qing Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411516850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaoyong Jin, Dongxu Gu, Panpan Li, Guilin Ye, Haiou Zhu, Kailun Wei, Chunxiang Li, Wenhui Zhong, Wenjie Du, Qing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scenem.2025.100010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Synthesis to Functionality: Borophene's Transformative Potential in Next&#8208;Generation Electrocatalysis and Battery Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202500186</link>
      <description>Ozden Gunes Yildiz, Asli Ceren Can, Naeimeh Sadat Peighambardoust, Umut Aydemir, Small Structures. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411530039

                Borophene, a novel two&#8208;dimensional boron allotrope, has rapidly emerged as a transformative material due to its unique atomic configurations and tunable properties. Its intrinsic electron deficiency gives rise to a diverse range of structural motifs from atomically thin flat sheets to corrugated and striped architectures that underpin remarkable mechanical strength, high electrical conductivity, and superior ion transport. This review comprehensively examines recent advances in borophene synthesis, stabilization, and functionalization. Special emphasis is placed on understanding how defect engineering, heteroatom doping, and the formation of heterostructures can mitigate borophene's inherent instability while enhancing its catalytic and electrochemical performance. In particular, borophene's potential in electrocatalytic water splitting is highlighted, where its abundant active sites facilitate efficient hydrogen evolution and oxygen evolution reactions as well as for high&#8208;capacity anodes in lithium&#8208;ion batteries, where storage capacities far exceed those of conventional materials. Though targeting distinct functions, both of these applications rely on shared electrochemical fundamentals and structural design strategies, supporting a unified treatment of borophene's energy applications. Despite promising theoretical and experimental results, challenges in scalable synthesis, stability, and integration persist, highlighting the need for advanced interdisciplinary strategies to fully harness borophene's potential in next&#8208;generation energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Ozden Gunes Yildiz, Asli Ceren Can, Naeimeh Sadat Peighambardoust, Umut Aydemir</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202500186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Reduction of Nitric Oxide to Ammonia on Defective ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202500152</link>
      <description>M. T. Nasir, Qingchao Fang, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Xiuwen Zhou, Aijun Du, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411531005

                The electrocatalytic nitric oxide reduction reaction (NORR) is a sustainable approach for converting the gas pollutant nitric oxide (NO) into value&#8208;added ammonia (NH 3 ). Currently, electrocatalytic synthesis remains a significant challenge due to the limited understanding of theoretical principles for designing highly active and selective catalysts. Herein, for the first time, hexagonal ZnIn 2 S 4 with a sulfur vacancy (V S ) as a potential NORR catalyst is systematically investigated using first&#8208;principles calculations. The hybridization between 5 p orbital of the indium (In) atom and absorbed NO leads to a strong interaction between the substrate and the adsorbate. The catalyst demonstrates excellent performance with a low limiting potential and prevents the formation of byproducts. Additionally, the hydrogen evolution reaction can be completely inhibited due to the deviation of the proton adsorption from the optimal zero value. Different from conventional d &#8208;block transitional metal catalysts, here, the exposed p &#8208;block indium acts catalytically active center for NORR. This work not only highlights a new sustainable catalyst for NORR but also offers an effective strategy for designing novel catalysts.</description>
      <author>M. T. Nasir, Qingchao Fang, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Xiuwen Zhou, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202500152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature-Driven Prediction of HOMO&#8211;LUMO Gaps in Transition-Metal Complexes Using the SLEET Model: A SMILES-Based Transformer Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00085</link>
      <description>Sheng-Hsuan Hung, Zong-Rong Ye, Chi&#8208;Feng Cheng, An-Cheng Yang, Berlin Chen, Ming&#8208;Kang Tsai, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411531753

                A feature-driven model, SLEET, built upon the early reported SchNet-bs-RAN framework, that combines the approaches of SchNet and the bond-step representation weighted by the reduced atom number, is reported for evaluating the molecular electronic structure properties of transition-metal complexes (TMCs). Ligands were derived by segmenting purely two-dimensional SMILES representations, and metal-ligand interactions were modeled by using a Transformer-like architecture to construct a property prediction framework that aligns closely with chemical knowledge. This approach effectively captures the characteristics of the ligand field within TMCs. Consequently, the SLEET model delivers precise HOMO-LUMO gap predictions comparable to those achieved by three-dimensional information-based models while also demonstrating strong performance in predicting the molecular-weight-independent electronic properties.</description>
      <author>Sheng-Hsuan Hung, Zong-Rong Ye, Chi&#8208;Feng Cheng, An-Cheng Yang, Berlin Chen, Ming&#8208;Kang Tsai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhibiting overoxidation of an &#945;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrocatalyst by the lattice strain effect for efficient water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ey00106d</link>
      <description>Fangyi Li, Shan Guan, Jianming Liu, Changhao Liu, Junfeng Zhang, Ju Gu, Zhaosheng Li, Zhigang Zou, Zhen&#8208;Tao Yu, EES Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411536551

                The development of low-cost transition metal catalysts for use in alkaline water electrolysis (AWE) at high current densities is essential for achieving high-performance water splitting.</description>
      <author>Fangyi Li, Shan Guan, Jianming Liu, Changhao Liu, Junfeng Zhang, Ju Gu, Zhaosheng Li, Zhigang Zou, Zhen&#8208;Tao Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ey00106d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Manganese Oxide Nanosheets in Pyrolyzed Carbonaceous Supports for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00212</link>
      <description>Andr&#233; Wark, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Richard W. Haid, Regina M. Kluge, Shinya Suzuki, Zyun Siroma, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Jun Maruyama, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411538125

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andr&#233; Wark, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Richard W. Haid, Regina M. Kluge, Shinya Suzuki, Zyun Siroma, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Jun Maruyama</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning high-throughput screening of double perovskites for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165258</link>
      <description>Dong Hyeon Mok, Jaehyoung Lim, Hyunju Chang, Jungho Shin, Jiwoo Jang, Uk Sim, Geun Ho Gu, Seoin Back, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411541201

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dong Hyeon Mok, Jaehyoung Lim, Hyunju Chang, Jungho Shin, Jiwoo Jang, Uk Sim, Geun Ho Gu, Seoin Back</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diverse MOFs-derived carbon-based materials for advanced electrochemical energy applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2025.100163</link>
      <description>Chunyan Yang, Jian&#8208;Ping Lang, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411545479

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunyan Yang, Jian&#8208;Ping Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2025.100163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Engineering Modulates Spin-Polarization in Ruthenium Oxide to Enhance Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125630</link>
      <description>Lei Tan, Huilin Fan, Siyi Ding, Zian Zhao, Xiaotong Wu, Faiza Meharban, Yonghui Zhao, Qian Xu, Haojie Zhang, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Ralf B. Wehrspohn, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411545654

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Tan, Huilin Fan, Siyi Ding, Zian Zhao, Xiaotong Wu, Faiza Meharban, Yonghui Zhao, Qian Xu, Haojie Zhang, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Ralf B. Wehrspohn</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triggering Exothermic Water Dissociation on Copper via Rhenium Implantation for Enhanced Alkaline Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202504300</link>
      <description>Bhargav Rajbongshi, Pragyan Tripathi, Abhishek Kumar Singh, Manikoth M. Shaijumon, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411571727

                Abstract Implantation of foreign elements into a host lattice can enhance catalytic activity by modulating electronic properties. Copper (Cu), a low&#8208;cost and abundant material, shows great potential in energy conversion applications. However, its high water dissociation energy barrier limits its catalytic performance in alkaline hydrogen evolution reactions (HER). Herein, a highly scalable co&#8208;electrodeposition method is presented to enhance the electrocatalytic performance of copper for alkaline HER by incorporating rhenium (Re) into the copper lattice. The incorporated Re improves electrocatalytic activity by promoting exothermic water dissociation and enhancing water adsorption. The optimized catalyst, CuRe&#8208;10/CP, achieves an overpotential of 46 mV to drive a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , demonstrating excellent electrochemical stability for 450 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 in an alkaline medium (1.0 m KOH). Additionally, the electrochemical activity of the CuRe&#8208;10/CP is evaluated in simulated seawater and alkaline seawater, where it exhibited exceptional activity and stability. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), electrochemical surface area measurement (ECSA), and turnover frequency (TOF) analyses confirm the significant enhancement in catalytic performance following Re incorporation. Furthermore, in situ Raman spectroscopy, EIS, and density functional theory (DFT) studies reveal that the Re incorporation into the copper lattice significantly improves the water dissociation and intermediate adsorption. This study gives a scalable strategy for designing platinum group element free electrocatalysts for alkaline hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Bhargav Rajbongshi, Pragyan Tripathi, Abhishek Kumar Singh, Manikoth M. Shaijumon</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202504300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prospects of precious metal based single-atom catalysts in selective hydrogenation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135998</link>
      <description>Xiuli Dong, Xiaowen Meng, Fengping Jiao, Shuohui Li, Ting Liang, Cuiyuan Liang, Huan Wang, Fuel. 403(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411574011

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiuli Dong, Xiaowen Meng, Fengping Jiao, Shuohui Li, Ting Liang, Cuiyuan Liang, Huan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135998</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential&#8208;Dependent Kinetics and Reaction Pathways of Low&#8208;Potential Furfural Electrooxidation with Anodic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202500132</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Wu, Guihao Liu, Ziheng Song, Yihang Hu, Tianqi Nie, Yu&#8208;Fei Song, Small Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411575159

                The low&#8208;potential furfural electrooxidation reaction (FFOR) on copper&#8208;based catalysts provides a novel pathway to upgrade biomass and produce H 2 simultaneously on anode. Herein, a series of oxide&#8208;derived copper catalysts (OD&#8208;Cu&#8208;x, x represents electroreduction time) with distinct Cu 0 /Cu + ratios and residual content of lattice oxygen are successfully constructed by tuning in&#8208;situ electroreduction time. When applied for FFOR, the OD&#8208;Cu&#8208;600 with a Cu 0 /Cu + ratio of 83.3% shows the Faradaic efficiency of 96.1% for furoic acid (FA) and 97.4% for H 2 , which can be achieved at a lowest potential of 0.081 V versus RHE at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in continuous 10 cycles, outperforming the state&#8208;of&#8208;art Cu&#8208;based catalysts reported so far. Detailed characterization and density functional theory (DFT) calculations prove that the moderate coverage (25% based on DFT models) of Cu(OH) ads surface species generated by Cu + during the electrooxidation process endows the optimal furfural molecule adsorption and activation. Moreover, this potential&#8208;dependent coverage of surface OH can promote the kinetics of *H transfer to the Cu surface, allowing the H 2 evolution from the anode. The Cu 0 /Cu + ratio (83.8%) and suitable applied potential windows (0 to 0.4 V vs RHE) are both responsible for the co&#8208;production of FA and H 2 with high intrinsic activity and efficient H atom utilization.</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Wu, Guihao Liu, Ziheng Song, Yihang Hu, Tianqi Nie, Yu&#8208;Fei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202500132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the morphology of cobalt, copper, and ruthenium on TaN for interconnect metal deposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0256958</link>
      <description>Karl R&#246;nnby, Michael Nolan, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(24)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411577203

                Downscaling of metal interconnects has become a bottleneck in the back-end-of-line processing of CMOS semiconductor devices. The conductivity of the commonly used Cu metal drastically reduces at nanoscale, limiting its use as the devices shrink, as the metal starts forming non-conductive islands. This has led to the requirement for new interconnect metals such as Co and Ru, as they have a much higher tendency to form conductive films with horizontal growth at nanoscale. Understanding how the morphology of interconnects depends on the metals&#8217; atomistic properties and their interactions at diffusion barrier layers is necessary to continue the rapid development of interconnects. In this study, we have used first-principles density functional theory (DFT) relaxations, ab initio molecular dynamics, and neural network machine learning potentials (MLPs) to investigate how the morphology of Cu, Co, and Ru differs on TaN substrates. We investigate the binding of single metal atoms and four atom clusters to obtain the metals&#8217; substrate binding energy and metal&#8211;metal interaction energies. The morphology of the metals was then investigated by 15 ps molecular dynamics simulations with DFT and 5 ns with MLPs using larger metal structures that can display 2D and 3D morphologies. Comparing the binding energies with the obtained morphology allows us to demonstrate how the balance of metal&#8211;substrate and metal&#8211;metal interactions determines the morphology, while the MLP simulations allow longer timescale processes to be included. These insights help in the development of morphology predictors, allowing a rapid method for screening new interconnect materials with targeted horizontal growth on substrates used in semiconductors.</description>
      <author>Karl R&#246;nnby, Michael Nolan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0256958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT investigation on bi-functional {1 2 1} faceted orthorhombic &#946;&#8722;Sb2O3 for water splitting application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100862</link>
      <description>Harshada A. Barve, Ravindra R. Deshmukh, Zeenat A. Shaikh, Balaji G. Ghule, Shoyebmohamad F. Shaikh, Ji&#8208;Hyun Jang, Rajaram S. Mane, Krishna Chaitanya Gunturu, Next Materials. 8(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411579520

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harshada A. Barve, Ravindra R. Deshmukh, Zeenat A. Shaikh, Balaji G. Ghule, Shoyebmohamad F. Shaikh, Ji&#8208;Hyun Jang, Rajaram S. Mane, Krishna Chaitanya Gunturu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Behavior of Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;TM&lt;/i&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (&lt;i&gt;TM&lt;/i&gt; = Fe, Co, Ni) upon the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.5c00035</link>
      <description>Fatma Aras, Ulrich Burkhardt, Alim Ormeci, Horst Borrmann, S. G. Altendorf, Yuri Grin, Iryna Antonyshyn, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411583072

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fatma Aras, Ulrich Burkhardt, Alim Ormeci, Horst Borrmann, S. G. Altendorf, Yuri Grin, Iryna Antonyshyn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.5c00035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in heteroatom-doped RuO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrocatalysts for efficient acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/14686996.2025.2520159</link>
      <description>Yihao Zheng, Tao Zhou, Quan Zhang, Haixin Guo, Jianxun Yang, Baofu Ding, Huaiyu Shao, Xinchun Yang, Science and Technology of Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411426184

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yihao Zheng, Tao Zhou, Quan Zhang, Haixin Guo, Jianxun Yang, Baofu Ding, Huaiyu Shao, Xinchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/14686996.2025.2520159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction and reactor designs for improving electrochemical CO2 capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.device.2025.100837</link>
      <description>Xinzhong Wang, Jiashu Chen, Yen&#8208;Hsun Su, Jie Wu, Qing Xia, Shanhe Gong, Jingyu Sun, Guangping Zheng, Shi Xue Dou, Xiao Zhang, Device. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411451309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinzhong Wang, Jiashu Chen, Yen&#8208;Hsun Su, Jie Wu, Qing Xia, Shanhe Gong, Jingyu Sun, Guangping Zheng, Shi Xue Dou, Xiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.device.2025.100837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global universal scaling and ultrasmall parameterization in machine-learning interatomic potentials with superlinearity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2503439122</link>
      <description>Yanxiao Hu, Sheng Ye, Jing Huang, Xiaoxin Xu, Yuyan Yang, Mingqiang Zhang, Yabei Wu, Caichao Ye, Jiong Yang, Wenqing Zhang, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(25)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411472404

                Using machine learning (ML) to construct interatomic interactions and thus potential energy surface (PES) has become a common strategy for materials design and simulations. However, those current models of machine-learning interatomic potential (MLIP) consider no relevant physical constraints or global scaling and thus may owe intrinsic out-of-domain difficulty which underlies the challenges of model generalizability and physical scalability. Here, by incorporating the global universal scaling law, we develop an ultrasmall parameterized MLIP with superlinear expressive capability, named SUS 2 -MLIP. Due to the global scaling derived from the universal equation of state (UEOS), SUS 2 -MLIP not only has significantly reduced parameters by decoupling the element space from coordinate space but also naturally outcomes the out-of-domain difficulty and endows the model with inherent generalizability and scalability even with relatively small training dataset. The non-linearity-embedding transformation in radial function endows the model with superlinear expressive capability. SUS 2 -MLIP outperforms the state-of-the-art MLIP models with its exceptional computational efficiency, especially for multiple-element materials and physical scalability in property prediction. This work not only presents a highly efficient universal MLIP model but also sheds light on incorporating physical constraints into AI&#8211;aided materials simulation.</description>
      <author>Yanxiao Hu, Sheng Ye, Jing Huang, Xiaoxin Xu, Yuyan Yang, Mingqiang Zhang, Yabei Wu, Caichao Ye, Jiong Yang, Wenqing Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2503439122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sp &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; /sp &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; &#8211;Hybridized nitrogen&#8211;mediated electrochemical CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; capture and utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adw6592</link>
      <description>Zhenfang Zhang, Yitong Li, Yiwen Zhong, Peng Li, Lingfeng Zhu, Zhi Zheng, Baohua Jia, Marie&#8208;Laure David, Yang Fu, Hai Yu, Tianyi Ma, Science Advances. 11(25)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411472744

                Electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) capture and utilization, powered by renewable energy, are essential to achieving net-zero emissions and CO 2 valorization. While remarkable progress has been made in catalysts, solution design, and system engineering, recent breakthroughs reveal that nitrogen-containing molecules&#8212;specifically sp 2 -hybridized structures (e.g., pyridine) and sp 3 -hybridized moieties (e.g., ethanolamine) &#8212;hold untapped potential to revolutionize both CO 2 capture and conversion. These structures have been demonstrated as the Holy Grail in facilitating CO 2 activation, stabilizing key intermediates, and streamlining reaction pathways&#8212;capabilities rarely achievable with conventional strategies. However, limited mechanistic understanding of their physicochemical properties and interactions with CO 2 hampers broader application. This review highlights recent advances in leveraging sp 2 /sp 3 -hybridized nitrogen structures, unpacks their molecular roles in electrochemical CO 2 management, and offers a unifying framework for their dual-functionality across capture and conversion. By illuminating these nitrogen-based motifs, we uncover practical design principles and open avenues for integrating expanded N-containing compounds into energy technologies&#8212;paving the way for next-generation carbon management strategies.</description>
      <author>Zhenfang Zhang, Yitong Li, Yiwen Zhong, Peng Li, Lingfeng Zhu, Zhi Zheng, Baohua Jia, Marie&#8208;Laure David, Yang Fu, Hai Yu, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adw6592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption Characteristics of an AlGaN/GaN Heterojunction on Potassium Ions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30132669</link>
      <description>Yan Dong, Mengmeng Li, Yanli Liu, Jianming Lei, Haineng Bai, Yanmei Sun, Dunjun Chen, Dongjie Zhu, Rigao Wang, Yi Sun, Molecules. 30(13)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411494789

                Slight changes in potassium levels can affect health. Therefore, rapid, reliable, and quantitative determination of potassium ion content is important for medical diagnosis. AlGaN, as a semiconductor material with good biocompatibility, has many advantages in the development of new potassium ion sensors. Understanding the adsorption behavior of a specific ion on the AlGaN surface and the eventual effect on AlGaN/GaN&#8217;s heterostructure interface is the key to obtaining high-performance nitride sensors. In this paper, we calculated the changes in the density of states and energy bands of the material after AlGaN adsorbed potassium ions through first-principles simulation. Combined with two-dimensional device simulation software, the changes in device performance caused by the changes in material properties are presented. The simulation results show that the adsorption of a single potassium ion can cause a current change in the order of milliamperes, providing a theoretical reference for the subsequent development of high-sensitivity potassium ion sensors.</description>
      <author>Yan Dong, Mengmeng Li, Yanli Liu, Jianming Lei, Haineng Bai, Yanmei Sun, Dunjun Chen, Dongjie Zhu, Rigao Wang, Yi Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30132669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Monte Carlo-Based Reactor Model Including Catalyst Shape Changes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01592</link>
      <description>Yuqi Yang, Anders Hellman, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411394183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuqi Yang, Anders Hellman, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic investigation of NH3 decomposition over Ru-based catalysts: The limiting role of H* surface coverage and its impact on reactor engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2025.108270</link>
      <description>Yi Qiu, Federico Sascha Franchi, Nicola Usberti, Alessandra Beretta, Fuel Processing Technology. 276(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411440199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Qiu, Federico Sascha Franchi, Nicola Usberti, Alessandra Beretta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2025.108270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distance-Aware Molecular Property Prediction in Nonlinear Structure&#8211;Property Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01037</link>
      <description>Jae Young Kim, Dionisios G. Vlachos, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411549233

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jae Young Kim, Dionisios G. Vlachos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Methylcellulose Chain Design on Gelation and Fibril Structure Using Coarse-Grained Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00862</link>
      <description>Stephen Kronenberger, Arthi Jayaraman, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411531326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stephen Kronenberger, Arthi Jayaraman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00862</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
