<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 01:42:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Computing anharmonic infrared spectra of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons using machine learning molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/staf1156</link>
      <description>Xinghong Mai, Zhao Wang, Lijun Pan, Johannes Sch&#246;rghuber, P&#233;ter Kov&#225;cs, Jes&#250;s Carrete, Georg K. H. Madsen, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. 541(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413271010

                ABSTRACT We introduce a machine learning molecular dynamics (MLMD) approach to calculate the anharmonic infrared (IR) absorption spectra of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs), key carriers of interstellar aromatic IR bands. This method accounts for temperature effects in a molecule-specific way and achieves accuracy comparable to conventional quantum chemical calculations at a fraction of the cost, scaling linearly with system size. We applied MLMD to calculate the anharmonic spectra of 1704 PAHs in the NASA Ames PAH IR Spectroscopic Data base with up to 216 carbon atoms at different temperatures, demonstrating its capability for high-throughput spectral calculations of large molecular systems. Our results highlight MLMD&#8217;s potential to enable the development of extensive molecular spectral data sets, enhancing data-driven analyses of astronomical IR spectra, particularly in anticipation of upcoming observations from the James Webb Space Telescope.</description>
      <author>Xinghong Mai, Zhao Wang, Lijun Pan, Johannes Sch&#246;rghuber, P&#233;ter Kov&#225;cs, Jes&#250;s Carrete, Georg K. H. Madsen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/staf1156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights and predictive screening of M@C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N catalysts for urea electrosynthesis from N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta03783b</link>
      <description>Nuttapon Yodsin, Tannatorn Potale, Yuwanda Injongkol, Pimjai Pimbaotham, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413271739

                A descriptor-guided screening of single-atom M@C 2 N catalysts enables identification of Nb as a top candidate for ambient electrocatalytic urea synthesis from CO 2 and N 2 , with high activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Nuttapon Yodsin, Tannatorn Potale, Yuwanda Injongkol, Pimjai Pimbaotham, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta03783b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of vanadium and rhenium co-doped TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for enhanced photocatalytic performance via first principle density functional theory investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1402-4896/adf156</link>
      <description>Fikadu Takele Geldasa, F.B. Dejene, Physica Scripta. 100(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413273058

                Abstract Elemental doping is an effective strategy to enhance the photocatalytic performance of TiO 2 by modifying its electronic structure through the introduction of impurity states near the valence or conduction bands. In this study, we employ density functional theory (DFT) with Hubbard U correction (DFT+U) to investigate the effects of vanadium (V) and rhenium (Re) mono-doping and co-doping on the structural, electronic, and optical properties of rutile TiO 2 . Structural optimizations reveal slight reductions in lattice constants and bond lengths in doped systems, attributed to the marginal ionic radius differences between the dopants and Ti 4+ ions. Formation energy analysis indicated that V&#8211;Re co-doping is energetically more favorable than mono-doping, suggesting high structural stability. Electronic structure analysis indicates a significant bandgap narrowing in V-doped (2.62 eV) and V&#8211;Re co-doped TiO 2 (2.75 eV), suggesting enhanced absorption in the visible region and improved photocatalytic activity. In contrast, Re mono-doping slightly increases the bandgap to 3.10 eV, limiting its activity to the UV region. Optical properties, including the dielectric function and absorption spectra, further confirm a redshift in V and V&#8211;Re doped systems, while Re doping results in a blueshift. Band edge alignment with respect to the normal hydrogen electrode (NHE) shows that all doped systems satisfy the thermodynamic criteria for water splitting, with V&#8211;Re co-doping exhibiting the most favorable band positions for hydrogen evolution. Finally, this work demonstrates that co-doping with V and Re is a promising strategy to engineer TiO 2 with improved visible-light photocatalytic performance, offering valuable insights for the design and synthesis of efficient photocatalysts for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Fikadu Takele Geldasa, F.B. Dejene</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1402-4896/adf156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating the Pt triangular chain of Janus Pt2C monolayer forms multiple active sites for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164148</link>
      <description>Huan Lou, Chi Ma, Applied Surface Science. 712(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413273062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Lou, Chi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamics of Molecular Binding and Clustering in the Atmosphere Revealed through Conventional and ML-Enhanced Umbrella Sampling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05634</link>
      <description>Jakub Kube&#269;ka, Yosef Knattrup, Georg Baadsgaard Trolle, Bernhard Reischl, August Smart Lykke-M&#248;ller, Jonas Elm, Ivo Neefjes, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413273850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jakub Kube&#269;ka, Yosef Knattrup, Georg Baadsgaard Trolle, Bernhard Reischl, August Smart Lykke-M&#248;ller, Jonas Elm, Ivo Neefjes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling size and surface effects of intermetallic CuPd nanocrystals for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101492</link>
      <description>Liyue Zhang, Zaheer Masood, Qiang Gao, Min&#8208;Chul Kang, Xiangru Wei, Yulu Zhang, Zhanrong Guo, Yizhen Chen, Lu Ma, Huiyuan Zhu, Ling Zhou, Bin Wang, Sen Zhang, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413274467

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liyue Zhang, Zaheer Masood, Qiang Gao, Min&#8208;Chul Kang, Xiangru Wei, Yulu Zhang, Zhanrong Guo, Yizhen Chen, Lu Ma, Huiyuan Zhu, Ling Zhou, Bin Wang, Sen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electron Modulation with Ionic Liquids: Dual Optimization of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Confinement and Charge Transfer for Enhanced Electroreduction on Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c02334</link>
      <description>Chuanhui Wang, Mingyue Qiu, Guizeng Liang, Hui Yan, Jiamin Ma, Lijuan Shi, Congyun Zhang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413274626

                The high-rate electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to afford multicarbon products (C2) holds transformative potential for advancing sustainable energy systems. Ionic liquids (ILs) have emerged as dynamic modulators to promote the C2 pathway, yet the underlying atomistic mechanisms of ILs in modulating this CO2RR process remain fundamentally unclear. Here, by integrating molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, density functional theory (DFT) calculations, and experimental validations, we systematically elucidate the critical influence of 1-(3-aminopropyl)-3-methylimidazole chloride ILs in optimizing the CO2RR pathway on Cu surfaces through electronic structure engineering. MD simulations demonstrate that ILs establish a CO2-enriched interfacial microenvironment that restricts bulk-phase CO2 diffusion through the confinement effect. Electron structure analyses reveal that ILs synergistically enhance interfacial electron accumulation and directional charge transfer for adsorbed CO2 and key intermediates (*CO, *COH, *CHO, and *C), collectively stabilizing them through IL-induced strengthening of Cu-C bonding. More importantly, the introduction of ILs dramatically reduces the activation barrier of the rate-determining C-C coupling step and thermodynamically favors the CO2RR to C2H4 and C2H5OH pathways through atom orbital hybridization. Additionally, the ILs not only enhance the CO2RR but also suppress the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) through proton confinement. This work provides molecular-level insights into the dynamic role of ILs in optimizing CO2RR processes and offers a foundation for designing advanced IL-mediated electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Chuanhui Wang, Mingyue Qiu, Guizeng Liang, Hui Yan, Jiamin Ma, Lijuan Shi, Congyun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c02334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The structure and migration of twin boundaries in tetragonal &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1443" altimg="si48.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;&#946;&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-Sn: An application of machine learning based interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121390</link>
      <description>Ian Chesser, Mashroor S. Nitol, Esther C. Hessong, Himanshu Joshi, Nikhil Chandra Admal, Brandon Runnels, Daniel N. Blaschke, Khanh Dang, Abigail Hunter, Saryu Fensin, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413275600

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ian Chesser, Mashroor S. Nitol, Esther C. Hessong, Himanshu Joshi, Nikhil Chandra Admal, Brandon Runnels, Daniel N. Blaschke, Khanh Dang, Abigail Hunter, Saryu Fensin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Te Vacancy Defect Engineering on Fe3GeTe2 (001) Basal Planes for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15161272</link>
      <description>Yufei Gao, Wei Su, Yuan Qiu, Dan Shan, Jing Pan, Nanomaterials. 15(16)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413286721

                Photocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen production is an attractive renewable energy technology, but the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode is severely constrained by a high overpotential. The two-dimensional vdW ferromagnetic material Fe3GeTe2, with its good stability and excellent metallic conductivity, has potential as an electrocatalyst, but its sluggish surface catalytic reactivity limits its large-scale application. In this work, we adapted DFT calculations to introduce surface Te vacancies to boost OER performance of the Fe3GeTe2 (001) surface. Te vacancies induce the charge redistribution of active sites, optimizing the adsorption and desorption of oxygen-containing intermediates. Consequently, the overpotential of the rate-determining step in the OER process of Fe3GeTe2 is reduced to 0.34 V, bringing the performance close to that of the benchmark IrO2 catalyst (0.56 V). Notably, the vacancies&#8217; concentration and configuration significantly modify the electronic structure and thus influence OER activity. This study provides important theoretical evidence for defect engineering in OER catalysis and offers new design strategies for developing efficient and stable electrocatalysts for sustainable energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Yufei Gao, Wei Su, Yuan Qiu, Dan Shan, Jing Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15161272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An automated framework for exploring and learning potential-energy surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62510-6</link>
      <description>Yuanbin Liu, Joe D. Morrow, Christina Ertural, Natascia L. Fragapane, John L. A. Gardner, Aakash Ashok Naik, Yuxing Zhou, Janine George, Volker L. Deringer, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413288367

                Machine learning has become ubiquitous in materials modelling and now routinely enables large-scale atomistic simulations with quantum-mechanical accuracy. However, developing machine-learned interatomic potentials requires high-quality training data, and the manual generation and curation of such data can be a major bottleneck. Here, we introduce an automated framework for the exploration and fitting of potential-energy surfaces, implemented in an openly available software package that we call autoplex ('automatic potential-landscape explorer'). We discuss design choices, particularly the interoperability with existing software architectures, and the ability for the end user to easily use the computational workflows provided. We show wide-ranging capability demonstrations: for the titanium-oxygen system, SiO2, crystalline and liquid water, as well as phase-change memory materials. More generally, our study illustrates how automation can speed up atomistic machine learning in computational materials science.</description>
      <author>Yuanbin Liu, Joe D. Morrow, Christina Ertural, Natascia L. Fragapane, John L. A. Gardner, Aakash Ashok Naik, Yuxing Zhou, Janine George, Volker L. Deringer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62510-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Orbital&#8208;Driven SERS Enhancement Via D&#8208;Band Engineering in High&#8208;Entropy Alloy Aerogels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/lpor.202501214</link>
      <description>Di Liu, Pengwei Duan, Junjie Chen, Ming Mu, Yumei Yang, Fuqiu Ma, Zhao Bing, Wei Song, Laser &amp; Photonics Review. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413289925

                Abstract Understanding atomic orbital&#8208;level interactions at material&#8208;molecule interfaces is crucial for advancing surface&#8208;enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS). While conventional mechanisms focus on electromagnetic effects or interfacial charge transfer (CT), the role of orbital hybridization in multimetallic systems remains underexplored. Here, a d&#8208;band&#8208;mediated CT mechanism is proposed through the engineering high&#8208;entropy alloy aerogels (HEAAs). A face&#8208;centered cubic AuAgCuMnInBi HEAAs synthesized via one&#8208;step coreduction achieves ultrasensitive SERS detection of crystal violet. Density of states analyses reveal that Mn&#8208;3d orbitals bridge electron reservoirs (Au/Ag/Cu) and In/Bi&#8208;p orbitals, enabling efficient charge delocalization. Voltage&#8208;tunable SERS signals in MnInBi subsystems confirm d&#8208;band&#8208;dependent CT enhancement. Beyond molecular sensing, this mechanism allows direct capture of reactive intermediates (OH&#183;, O 2 &#183; &#8211; ) and 5 n M uranium detection, bridging SERS enhancement dynamics with catalytic pathway elucidation. These findings establish d&#8208;band engineering as a paradigm for designing multifunctional SERS substrates, bridging atomic&#8208;scale electronic interactions with ultrasensitive sensing and catalytic mechanism elucidation.</description>
      <author>Di Liu, Pengwei Duan, Junjie Chen, Ming Mu, Yumei Yang, Fuqiu Ma, Zhao Bing, Wei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/lpor.202501214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selectively passivated core-satellite cobalt-iron bimetallic phosphide with optimized &#8270;OH adsorption for boosting oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167382</link>
      <description>B. H. Liu, Wangshu Zheng, Zhaoxi Zhang, Jiarui Yang, Yanqi Yuan, Li Feng, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Yixing Luo, Han Chen, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413292311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. H. Liu, Wangshu Zheng, Zhaoxi Zhang, Jiarui Yang, Yanqi Yuan, Li Feng, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Yixing Luo, Han Chen, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Model for Efficient Nonthermal Tuning of the Charge Density Wave in Monolayer NbSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00959</link>
      <description>Luka Beni&#263;, Federico Grasselli, Chiheb Ben Mahmoud, Dino Novko, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413292815

                Understanding and controlling the charge density wave (CDW) phase diagram of transition-metal dichalcogenides are long-studied problems in condensed matter physics. However, due to the complex involvement of electron and lattice degrees of freedom and pronounced anharmonicity, theoretical simulations of the CDW phase diagram at the density-functional-theory level are often numerically demanding. To reduce the computational cost of first-principles modeling by orders of magnitude, we have developed an electronic free-energy machine learning model for monolayer NbSe2 that allows us to control the electronic temperature as a parameter of the model. The ionic temperature is modeled via the stochastic self-consistent harmonic approximation. Our approach relies on a machine learning model of the electronic density of states and zero-temperature interatomic potential. This allows us to explore the CDW phase diagram of monolayer NbSe2 both under thermal and laser-induced nonthermal conditions. Our study provides an accurate estimate of the CDW transition temperature at low cost and can disentangle the role of hot electrons and phonons in the nonthermal ultrafast melting process of the CDW phase in NbSe2.</description>
      <author>Luka Beni&#263;, Federico Grasselli, Chiheb Ben Mahmoud, Dino Novko, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>p-d orbital coupling and interfacial water regulation synergistically promote alkaline hydrogen electrocatalysis on Ru/VC heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167317</link>
      <description>Hao Hu, Nuo Sun, Jie Gao, Li Wang, Zhangrong Lou, Xuejing Cui, Jing Liu, Luhua Jiang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413292830

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Hu, Nuo Sun, Jie Gao, Li Wang, Zhangrong Lou, Xuejing Cui, Jing Liu, Luhua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mg-Al layered double hydroxides derived from secondary aluminum ash for soil remediation contaminated with Cd(&#8545;) and Cr(&#8549;)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.139585</link>
      <description>Shikai Li, Hanbing Gao, Rui Xu, Zhaohui Guo, Journal of Hazardous Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413295529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shikai Li, Hanbing Gao, Rui Xu, Zhaohui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.139585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom doping FeS for nitrogen fixation: High-throughput DFT calculation screening and bio-preparation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147149</link>
      <description>Xingfu Zheng, Shi Sun, Jin&#8208;lan Xia, Zhen&#8208;yuan Nie, Rui Hu, Hongchang Liu, Yuting Liang, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413297901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingfu Zheng, Shi Sun, Jin&#8208;lan Xia, Zhen&#8208;yuan Nie, Rui Hu, Hongchang Liu, Yuting Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;/scp&gt; Nanoclusters Regulated Charge Asymmetric Fe Dual Atomic Sites for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.70221</link>
      <description>Ying Lei, Jiaxin Li, Yi Cheng, Chuanlan Xu, Honglin Li, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413307023

                Comprehensive Summary Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) show attractive prospects for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), yet face challenges in precise charge modulation that balances the activity and durability. Herein, we present a N,S&#8208;coordinated Fe dual atomic catalyst modified by Fe 3 C nanoclusters (Fe 3 C/Fe 2 N x S) through pyrolyzing the mixtures of ZIF&#8208;8&#8208;encapsulated iron dimers and sulfur&#8208;doped C 3 N 4 . Aberration&#8208;corrected STEM and synchrotron X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) validated that the catalyst was composed of Fe dual atomic sites and Fe 3 C nanoclusters, in which Fe dual atoms were coordinated by five N atoms and one S atom. Fe 3 C/Fe 2 N x S exhibited excellent ORR activity in alkaline media, displaying a high half&#8208;wave potential ( E 1/2 = 0.894 V vs . RHE) with near 4e &#8211; selectivity ( n = 3.92) and maintaining 86.8% retention after 20000 s, superior to commercial Pt/C. Impressively, the assembled zinc&#8208;air battery delivered exceptional peak power density (163 mW&#183;cm &#8211;2 ) and 200&#8208;hour robust stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed that electron transfer from Fe of Fe 2 N x S to neighboring Fe 3 C induced local charge asymmetry, shifting the d&#8208;band center closer to Fermi level, thereby enhancing O 2 activation. Moreover, the OOH * formation energy barrier was reduced to 0.52 eV in Fe 3 C/Fe 2 N x S, accelerating ORR reaction kinetics. This work establishes nanocluster&#8208;mediated electronic redistribution to tailor charge asymmetry for high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Ying Lei, Jiaxin Li, Yi Cheng, Chuanlan Xu, Honglin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.70221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymorph-Induced Reducibility and Electron Trapping Energetics of Nb and W Dopants in TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04364</link>
      <description>A.K. Chaudhari, Andrew J. Logsdail, Andrea Folli, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413307261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A.K. Chaudhari, Andrew J. Logsdail, Andrea Folli</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Nuclearity Copper Molecular Catalysts for Electrocatalytic CO-to-Acetate Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08144</link>
      <description>Mohammad Bodiuzzaman, Lizhou Fan, M. Naveen, Yiqing Chen, Yushan Yan, Simil Thomas, Rui Kai Miao, Yurou Celine Xiao, Jinhong Wu, Roham Dorakhan, Mutalifu Abulikemu, Omar El Tall, David Sinton, Husam N. Alshareef, Omar F. Mohammed, Edward H. Sargent, Osman M. Bakr, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413317245

                Ligand-modified metal nanoclusters (NCs) have emerged as candidate materials for catalysis owing to their well-defined yet tunable structure and their metal centers' high nuclearity. We posited that NC-based catalytic behavior will depend on ligand properties, the accessibility of active sites, and their atomic configuration. We synthesized a series of Cu NC-based catalysts, tuned local hydrophobicity through ligand adjustment, balanced the ligand coverage and active site exposure, and found that we were, in this way, able to engender efficient electrosynthesis of acetate via CO electroreduction. Computation and operando spectroscopy show that asymmetric Cu-Cu sites, which determine the CO binding strength, impact the bifurcation step after C-C coupling. The best of these catalysts, Cu13Nap, achieved an acetate Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 86% and an energy efficiency of 29% in a 5 bar system, exceeding the single C2+ FE of &lt;50% previously achieved by NC-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Bodiuzzaman, Lizhou Fan, M. Naveen, Yiqing Chen, Yushan Yan, Simil Thomas, Rui Kai Miao, Yurou Celine Xiao, Jinhong Wu, Roham Dorakhan, Mutalifu Abulikemu, Omar El Tall, David Sinton, Husam N. Alshareef, Omar F. Mohammed, Edward H. Sargent, Osman M. Bakr</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interaction strength of carbon dioxide on graphene from periodic quantum diffusion Monte Carlo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0283254</link>
      <description>Flaviano Della Pia, Giaan Kler-Young, Andrea Zen, Fabian Berger, Dario Alf&#232;, Angelos Michaelides, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413318216

                Despite the importance of graphene based carbon capture devices, an accurate estimate of the interaction strength of a carbon dioxide molecule with graphene from periodic calculations is lacking. In this work, we compute a fixed node quantum diffusion Monte Carlo reference value for the interaction energy of a carbon dioxide molecule with a periodic free-standing graphene sheet, obtaining a value of -152 &#177; 15 meV. In addition, we evaluate the performance of several widely used density functional theory approximations and foundation machine learning interatomic potentials, for both carbon dioxide and water adsorption on graphene, competitive processes that play an important role in carbon capture technologies. Among the approaches tested, the B86bPBE-XDM, PBE-D3, revPBE-D3, rev-vdW-DF2, SCAN+rVV10, and PBE0-D3-ATM functionals achieve the closest agreement with DMC for the carbon dioxide-graphene interaction. The vdW-DF2, rev-vdW-DF2, and PBE0-D4-ATM functionals perform better for the competitive adsorption of water and carbon dioxide.</description>
      <author>Flaviano Della Pia, Giaan Kler-Young, Andrea Zen, Fabian Berger, Dario Alf&#232;, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0283254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of curvature and spin exchange in electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction on Co2@N6CNTs catalysts: A grand canonical density functional theory simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115422</link>
      <description>Ming Chen, Zhi-rui Luo, Dahu Lin, Liping Han, Wen&#8208;Xian Chen, Gui&#8208;Lin Zhuang, Molecular Catalysis. 586(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413324997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming Chen, Zhi-rui Luo, Dahu Lin, Liping Han, Wen&#8208;Xian Chen, Gui&#8208;Lin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Janus silicon-based pentagonal monolayers for enhanced photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150901</link>
      <description>Chenghao Yang, Yanqing Shen, Kexin Wang, Yu Zhang, Xiangqian Jiang, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 167(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413326105

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenghao Yang, Yanqing Shen, Kexin Wang, Yu Zhang, Xiangqian Jiang, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-metal single atoms anchored on defective MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: a novel electrocatalyst for NO reduction to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra04718h</link>
      <description>Yifan Liu, Mamutjan Tursun, Guangzhi Hu, Abdukader Abdukayum, Chao Wu, RSC Advances. 15(36)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413327714

                The eNORR performance of the MoS 2 catalyst doped with non-metal atoms has been studied. The Si, C, N, B, and P@MoS 2 catalysts demonstrated great potential for eNORR. The Si, C, and B@MoS 2 catalysts inhibited the formation of byproducts and HER.</description>
      <author>Yifan Liu, Mamutjan Tursun, Guangzhi Hu, Abdukader Abdukayum, Chao Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra04718h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Barrier: How Alkali Cations Promote Enhanced N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Adsorption and *NNH Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04857</link>
      <description>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413334168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review on the Applications of &#8220;Catalysis Under 2D-Cover&#8221; for Small Molecule Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41745-025-00481-9</link>
      <description>Athira Jayasankar, Sooraj Kunnikuruvan, Journal of the Indian Institute of Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413334433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Athira Jayasankar, Sooraj Kunnikuruvan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41745-025-00481-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of Urea from Carbon Dioxide and Waste Nitrates: History, Recent Progress, and Future Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202515635</link>
      <description>Yi-Fan Zhou, Gaoshan Xing, Chenghan Sun, Zekun Chen, Shuying Li, Rui Yang, Meng Chen, Pan Zhang, Changrui Feng, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413337462

                Abstract Electrosynthesis of urea from carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) and waste nitrates has gained increasing attention as a sustainable alternative to conventional urea production methods, offering a promising route to simultaneously convert CO 2 and waste nitrates into value&#8208;added chemicals. However, current urea electrosynthesis still faces challenges such as low Faradaic efficiency and ultralow urea yield rate, which hinder its practical application. To address these limitations, extensive efforts have been devoted to developing more effective electrocatalysts with high activity and high selectivity through various strategies. This review systematically covers the history of urea electrosynthesis, particularly highlighting recent advances, focusing on the development of electrocatalysts and electrolyzers for the electrosynthesis of urea from CO 2 and waste nitrates. Furthermore, catalysis mechanisms and the theoretical prediction for the catalyst design are discussed. In addition, the key challenges in this field, along with perspectives on future research directions, are outlined.</description>
      <author>Yi-Fan Zhou, Gaoshan Xing, Chenghan Sun, Zekun Chen, Shuying Li, Rui Yang, Meng Chen, Pan Zhang, Changrui Feng, Abuliti Abudula, Guoqing Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202515635</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quasiaperiodic grain boundary phases of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;&#931;&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;5&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; tilt grain boundaries in refractory metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/vsgc-gkdx</link>
      <description>Enze Chen, Timofey Frolov, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 112(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413341001

                We report ground-state structures and phase transitions in $\mathrm{\ensuremath{\Sigma}}5[001]$ tilt grain boundaries (GBs) in body-centered-cubic (bcc) refractory metals Nb, Ta, Mo, and W. $\mathrm{\ensuremath{\Sigma}}5$ tilt GBs have been extensively investigated over the past several decades, with their ground-state structure---composed of kite-shaped structural units---previously thought to be well understood. By performing a rigorous GB structure search that optimizes the number of atoms in the boundary core, we predict different quasiaperiodic ``split kite'' phases analogous to those previously found in GBs in face-centered-cubic metals. Our results suggest that complex aperiodic phases of GBs appear to be a general phenomenon, as validated through density functional theory calculations. Moreover, the atoms in the split kite phase demonstrate distinct collective diffusion dynamics. Phase-contrast image simulations of split kites show better agreement with experimental observations, offering an alternative explanation for previous microscopy results and motivating future atomically resolved imaging of the GB structure.</description>
      <author>Enze Chen, Timofey Frolov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/vsgc-gkdx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial electrolyte effects on electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03505-6</link>
      <description>Pengpeng Wang, Haibo Chi, Wenfeng Yang, Xuefei Zhao, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Yu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413342815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengpeng Wang, Haibo Chi, Wenfeng Yang, Xuefei Zhao, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03505-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Caged-Yttria Catalysts for Stable Electrosynthesis of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Concentrated Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c09469</link>
      <description>Yong&#8208;Yan Zhao, Luming Zhang, Huawei Yang, Jianmei Lu, Yilin Zhao, Xiaoxuan Sun, Zhengyi Qian, Adnan Ozden, Yifan Li, Yu Gu, Jinghui He, Shaojun Guo, Mingchuan Luo, Jianmei Lu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413347173

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong&#8208;Yan Zhao, Luming Zhang, Huawei Yang, Jianmei Lu, Yilin Zhao, Xiaoxuan Sun, Zhengyi Qian, Adnan Ozden, Yifan Li, Yu Gu, Jinghui He, Shaojun Guo, Mingchuan Luo, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c09469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mainstream and Sidestream Modeling in Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.5c00439</link>
      <description>Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Accounts of Chemical Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413350643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.5c00439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-engineered direct Z-scheme HfS2/Ga2SSe heterostructure for efficient full-range photocatalytic water splitting: A first-principles insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115434</link>
      <description>Pan Kuang, Qingyi Feng, Bo Li, Peiyu Guo, Zhen Wang, Xia Xiang, Xiaotao Zu, Hongxiang Deng, Molecular Catalysis. 586(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413352771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pan Kuang, Qingyi Feng, Bo Li, Peiyu Guo, Zhen Wang, Xia Xiang, Xiaotao Zu, Hongxiang Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115434</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site proximity effects in FeN4&#8211;embedded graphene on the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138759</link>
      <description>Jiahang Li, Yizhe He, Benyuan Ma, Donghai Wu, Suhang Li, Chong Yan, Qinzhuang Liu, Zaiping Zeng, Dongwei Ma, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413355223

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahang Li, Yizhe He, Benyuan Ma, Donghai Wu, Suhang Li, Chong Yan, Qinzhuang Liu, Zaiping Zeng, Dongwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian learning-assisted catalyst discovery for efficient iridium utilization in electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adw0894</link>
      <description>Xiangfu Niu, Yanjun Chen, Mingze Sun, Satoshi Nagao, Yuki Aoki, Zhiqiang Niu, Liang Zhang, Science Advances. 11(34)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413362254

                Reducing noble metal dependence in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is essential for achieving sustainable and scalable green hydrogen production. Bimetallic oxides, with their potential for high catalytic performance and reduced noble metal content, represent promising alternatives to traditional IrO 2 -based OER catalysts. However, optimizing these materials remains challenging due to the complex interplay of elemental selection, composition, and chemical ordering. In this study, we integrate density functional theory (DFT) calculations with Bayesian learning to accelerate the discovery of high-performance, low-Ir bimetallic oxides, identifying surface Ir-doped TiO 2 as an optimal catalyst. Guided by theoretically optimized surface compositions and oxygen vacancies, we synthesized atomically dispersed Ir on TiO 2 , achieving a 23-fold increase in Ir mass-specific activity and a 115-millivolt reduction in overpotential compared to commercial IrO 2 . This work exemplifies a sustainable, data-driven pathway for electrocatalyst design that minimizes noble metal usage while maximizing efficiency, advancing scalable solutions in renewable energy and hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Xiangfu Niu, Yanjun Chen, Mingze Sun, Satoshi Nagao, Yuki Aoki, Zhiqiang Niu, Liang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adw0894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gallium modulated tin oxide for continuous production of formic acid via durable acidic CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adw7326</link>
      <description>Bingquan Jia, Zhe Chen, Kaili Zhu, Weili Shi, Zhuang Hu, Tao Wang, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang, Science Advances. 11(34)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413362564

                CO 2 reduction catalyst corrosion and H 2 evolution remain challenging under the strongly acidic electrolyte. Here, Ga-modulated SnO x was investigated to achieve a good Sn &#948;+ oxidation state stability for durable (&gt; 4000 hours) acidic CO 2 reduction to HCOOH. Under pH 1.7, catalysts achieved a partial current density of 440 mA cm &#8722;2 at &#8722;1.63 V RHE and the highest single-pass conversion efficiency (SPCE) of 91.9%. In a 10 cm 2 electrolyzer, a total current of ~986.3 milliampere is exhibited for more than 4000 hours with Faradaic efficiency of HCOOH (FE HCOOH ) higher than 82% and SPCE higher than 50%. Mechanism study indicates that lattice oxygen anchoring effect of Ga due to its strong oxygen affinity establishes a stable framework, reinforcing interface Sn&#9472;O bonds and protecting the Sn &#948;+ from the heavy self-reduction process. The robust structure of catalyst and modulated active Sn &#948;+ sites elevate the CO 2 reduction activity. The durable and highly efficient catalytic system exhibits the potential for industrial applications of the Ga-modulated SnO x .</description>
      <author>Bingquan Jia, Zhe Chen, Kaili Zhu, Weili Shi, Zhuang Hu, Tao Wang, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adw7326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Discovery of Refractory High-Entropy Alloys via Interpretable Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01616</link>
      <description>Jian Cao, Chang Liu, Zian Chen, Haichao Li, Lina Xu, Hong&#8208;Ping Xiao, Shun Wang, Xiao He, Guoyong Fang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413370596

                Due to the outstanding thermal stability, inherent high melting points, and elevated temperature strengths, refractory high-entropy alloys (RHEAs) have been widely used for extreme environments in aerospace, nuclear energy, and advanced propulsion systems. Herein, we present an integrated design and simulation framework for RHEAs, combining machine learning potentials, supervised regression models, and multiobjective optimization algorithms. Utilizing a universal neuroevolution potential version 1 (UNEP-v1), the framework significantly enhances the accuracy of atomic-scale simulation while substantially reducing computational cost. High-throughput molecular dynamics simulations generate melting points and ultimate tensile strengths at 1000 K for various alloy compositions. Supervised regression models enable a rapid performance prediction. Integrating Shapley Additive exPlanations, Partial Dependence Plots, Accumulated Local Effects, and Individual Conditional Expectation analysis can provide a comprehensive interpretability toolkit. Validation of the proposed method in the TiVCrZrMo alloy system demonstrates its efficacy in designing high-strength, high-temperature resistant alloys. We not only develop a precise and interpretable predictive modeling paradigm but also establish procedural frameworks, promoting the integration of atomic-scale simulations with data-driven approaches for RHEAs in extreme environments.</description>
      <author>Jian Cao, Chang Liu, Zian Chen, Haichao Li, Lina Xu, Hong&#8208;Ping Xiao, Shun Wang, Xiao He, Guoyong Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Atomic Iron Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202513188</link>
      <description>Qiuyue Lu, Zhenl&#252; Wang, Jingqi Guan, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413373235

                Abstract The severe environmental issues triggered by the overuse of fossil energy have propelled the development of energy conversion and storage technologies. Oxygen electrocatalysis, including oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), has attracted widespread attention as the key reaction of many energy devices. Increasing research has demonstrated the exceptional potential of atomic iron catalysts in oxygen electrocatalysis, offering promising prospects for advancing these technologies. Building upon an analysis of the mechanisms underlying oxygen electrocatalysis and integrating insights from characterization techniques and theoretical calculations, this paper systematically summarizes the strategies for regulating the electronic structure of atomic iron catalysts, including coordination environment, metal active center, and substrate modulation. Then, given that the stability of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts remains a fundamental bottleneck hindering their development, optimization strategies including adjusting the Fe&#9472;N bond length, reducing H 2 O 2 attack, and improving the graphitization degree of the carrier are proposed. Furthermore, the applications in energy storage and conversion devices are reviewed. Finally, the future challenges and opportunities for atomic iron catalysts are discussed, offering insights for the development of more advanced Fe&#8208;based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qiuyue Lu, Zhenl&#252; Wang, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202513188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and dielectric properties of BaTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35848/1347-4065/adf564</link>
      <description>Yuki Sakai, Yoshiki Iwazaki, Japanese Journal of Applied Physics. 64(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413376237

                Abstract We construct and employ a machine-learning potential to perform molecular dynamics simulations on BaTiO 3 nanoparticles. The potential constructed in this study successfully reproduce rhombohedral, orthorhombic, tetragonal, and cubic phases observed in bulk BaTiO 3 at different simulation temperatures, as well as surface properties. We consider cubic-shaped and spherical nanoparticles to study how the shape and surface structures influence the structural and dielectric properties. Based on our analysis of the displacement vectors of titanium atoms relative to the surrounding oxygen atoms (corresponding to dipole moments), the surface structure strongly affects the order of the displacement vectors even near the center of the particle. A tetragonal-like order appears in cubic-shaped nanoparticles around a diameter of 11.6 nm while a similar order cannot be seen in an 18 nm spherical nanoparticle.</description>
      <author>Yuki Sakai, Yoshiki Iwazaki</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35848/1347-4065/adf564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Strain Effects on IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5c01104</link>
      <description>Sedky H.A. Hassan, S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413378295

                Understanding how strain influences the electronic and geometric properties of surface active sites and the activity and stability of the iridium oxide-catalyzed oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has significant scientific and technological implications for designing next-generation electrocatalysts. In this study, we use density functional theory (DFT) calculations to systematically investigate the effect of compressive and tensile biaxial surface strains on the OER activity and stability of the IrO2(110), IrO2(100), and IrO2(101) surfaces. Our results reveal significant changes in the adsorption free energies of the OER intermediates due to strain, which in turn influences the OER activity. Furthermore, we evaluate how the electronic structure of IrO2 surface atoms varies with strain, leading to a fundamental theoretical understanding of strain effects. Our theoretical analysis further accounts for the effects of strain in the presence of a nearby surface Ir vacancy and high surface oxygen coverage, representing realistic surfaces under OER conditions. This work expands the current understanding of strain-assisted activity and stability enhancements in OER catalysts, paving the way for the development of strain-engineered electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Sedky H.A. Hassan, S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5c01104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Improving the Alkaline Oxygen Reduction Performance of Atomically Dispersed Metal&#8211;Nitrogen&#8211;Carbon Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15161257</link>
      <description>Jian Chen, Zheng Li, Xiong Du, Mengran Wang, Simin Li, Qiyu Wang, Yangen Zhou, Yanqing Lai, Nanomaterials. 15(16)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413379067

                Atomically dispersed metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M-N-C) catalysts are regarded as ideal catalytic materials for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) under alkaline conditions. Compared with other ORR catalysts, M-N-C catalysts exhibit notable advantages, including low cost, high atomic utilization efficiency, and considerable catalytic potential. We provide a systematic review of recent research advances in enhancing the ORR performance of M-N-C catalysts, focusing on catalytic activity and stability. First, the reaction mechanism of the ORR on the surfaces of the M-N-C catalysts is elucidated. Second, the primary strategies employed in recent years to improve their catalytic activity and stability are summarized. Finally, critical research directions that should be prioritized to expedite the commercialization of M-N-C catalysts are outlined.</description>
      <author>Jian Chen, Zheng Li, Xiong Du, Mengran Wang, Simin Li, Qiyu Wang, Yangen Zhou, Yanqing Lai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15161257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Accelerated First-Principles Molecular Dynamics Reveals C&#8211;C Coupling Mechanisms toward Ethylene on Cu(100)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02726</link>
      <description>Timothy T. Yang, Wissam A. Saidi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413381326

                The Cu(100) termination has been identified as the most effective facet for converting CO and CO2 into ethylene. To enhance both the activity and selectivity of ethylene production, we perform machine-learning-accelerated, first-principles molecular dynamics simulations at 298 K in an explicit solvent at pH 7 to elucidate the C&#8211;C coupling mechanism&#9472;the critical reaction step in forming C2+ products. Among the six potential C&#8211;C coupling pathways, the most feasible are CO* dimerization and CO &#8211; CHO* and CHO* &#8211; CHO* couplings. Using the computational hydrogen electrode method, we demonstrate that all three pathways are equally accessible at &#8722;0.6 V vs RHE. At a potential below &#8722;1.0 V vs RHE, the thermodynamic barriers for the CO &#8211; CHO* and CHO* &#8211; CHO* pathways become negligible. Our computational findings explain the experimental observations, particularly the absence of C2+ products above &#8722;0.4 V vs RHE and the peaks in ethylene production near &#8722;0.6 and &#8722;1.0 V vs RHE. Since CHO* acts as a key intermediate common to both C&#8211;C coupling and CH4 formation, we propose that suppressing CHO* hydrogenation would inhibit CH4 pathways, thereby maximizing ethylene selectivity.</description>
      <author>Timothy T. Yang, Wissam A. Saidi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PtCo/C Core&#8211;Shell Catalysts on Various Carbon Supports: Synthesis, Structure, and Activity in Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04462</link>
      <description>&#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1044;. &#1050;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1091;&#1101;&#1088;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1043;&#1072;&#1074;&#1088;&#1080;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Yulia Bayan, Alexey Konstantinov, Egor E. Aydakov, E. Yu. Gerasimov, V. S. Menshchikov, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413382082

                This study is concerned with examining the effect of carbon support type on the properties of PtCo/C core&#8211;shell materials synthesized via a three-step method for use as catalysts in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in low-temperature fuel cells. The PtCo/C catalysts were examined using thermogravimetry, X-ray powder diffraction, transmission electron microscopy, total reflection X-ray fluorescence, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, the low-temperature nitrogen adsorption technique, cyclic voltammetry, and linear sweep voltammetry. The results revealed variations in the composition, structure, and ORR catalytic activity of the materials depending on the type of initial support. The PtCo/C core&#8211;shell materials synthesized on an N-doped KetjenBlack EC-300J support exhibited the largest active surface area (over 100 m2/g(Pt)), a high specific activity of approximately 500 A/g(Pt) at a potential of 0.9 V, and the most positive half-wave potential of 0.93 V. These characteristics significantly surpass those of a commercial Pt/C analogue. Testing of the synthesized PtCo/C catalyst on a doped carbon support within a membrane electrode assembly confirmed enhanced catalytic activity compared to that of its commercial counterpart. Thus, this study demonstrates that the use of an N-doped support for depositing bimetallic PtCo core&#8211;shell nanoparticles through multistage wet synthesis significantly improves the performance of cathode catalysts for proton-exchange membrane fuel cells.</description>
      <author>&#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1044;. &#1050;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1091;&#1101;&#1088;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1043;&#1072;&#1074;&#1088;&#1080;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Yulia Bayan, Alexey Konstantinov, Egor E. Aydakov, E. Yu. Gerasimov, V. S. Menshchikov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Application in Thermal CO2 Hydrogenation: Catalyst Design, Process Optimization, and Mechanism Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmate.2025.100333</link>
      <description>Rasoul Salami, Tianlong Liu, Xue Han, Ying Zheng, Advanced Powder Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413384220

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rasoul Salami, Tianlong Liu, Xue Han, Ying Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmate.2025.100333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retention Count Based Material Reliability Calculation for Molecular Dyanmics of Tritium Plasma at Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17134/khosbd.1690717</link>
      <description>Alper Pahsa, Savunma Bilimleri Dergisi. None(ERKEN G&#214;R&#220;N&#220;M)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413386087

                Structural dependability of Tokamak fusion reactors has to be taken into account while selecting reactor components. Heat- and energy-producing fusion events can change reactor walls. Reactions thus produce less efficiently the energy needed. For example, graphene is the fundamental building block used in fusion reactors to create their walls. Among the newest high-tech materials is graphene. We investigated the effect of tritium plasma ions with energy ranging from 5 to 35 keV on graphene walls using molecular dynamics simulations. To study the surface topology, we calculate the tritium retention count, since molecular dynamics gives a snapshot of the actual world in the molecular model setup. The surface tritium plasma atom retention calculation is completed by determining the graphene's Weibull distribution reliability based on the retention count assumption.</description>
      <author>Alper Pahsa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17134/khosbd.1690717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exergy analysis of the Allam cycle: Assessing the impact of regenerator performance on the cycle efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120358</link>
      <description>Gnandjuet Gaston Brice Dago, Guido Francesco Frate, Andrea Baccioli, Lorenzo Ferrari, Emanuela Alfarano, Alessandro Colnago, Energy Conversion and Management. 345(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413388539

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gnandjuet Gaston Brice Dago, Guido Francesco Frate, Andrea Baccioli, Lorenzo Ferrari, Emanuela Alfarano, Alessandro Colnago</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Dual-Carbide Heterostructure Interface-Driven Broad pH Range Hydrogen Fuel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c02133</link>
      <description>Disha Sonwani, Bhojkumar Nayak, Neeraj Mishra, Sandeep C. Kanade, Hitesh Kumar, Ankita Chudiwal, Guy Makov, Musthafa Ottakam Thotiyl, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413397790

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Disha Sonwani, Bhojkumar Nayak, Neeraj Mishra, Sandeep C. Kanade, Hitesh Kumar, Ankita Chudiwal, Guy Makov, Musthafa Ottakam Thotiyl</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c02133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into Bimetallic CoFe Nanoparticles Incorporated on N-Doped Carbon Nanosheets toward Acidic Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02150</link>
      <description>Hariprasad Ranganathan, Hossein Bemana, Alexandre Terry, Shuai Chen, Nikolay Kornienko, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413398398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hariprasad Ranganathan, Hossein Bemana, Alexandre Terry, Shuai Chen, Nikolay Kornienko</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methodology of evaluating the activation energy of oxygen reduction reaction on Pt-based electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.119418</link>
      <description>Jan Buri&#225;nek, Tom&#225;&#353; Bystro&#328;, Karel Bouzek, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413401797

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jan Buri&#225;nek, Tom&#225;&#353; Bystro&#328;, Karel Bouzek</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.119418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring hydrogen evolution reactions under external electric fields on single-atom catalysts of transition metal anchored C24N24 nanocages: A DFT-D3 insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107475</link>
      <description>S. Abdel Aal, Emad M. Masoud, Kamal A. Soliman, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413406280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Abdel Aal, Emad M. Masoud, Kamal A. Soliman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Screening of High-Performance Electrocatalysts for Nitrogen Fixation with Single Metal Atoms Anchored on CuO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04865</link>
      <description>Wei Song, Pengfei Ma, Shaoting Lang, Xiao Liu, Chaozheng He, Jinlong Wang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413411486

                NH3 is an efficient hydrogen carrier and a crucial chemical in various industrial various applications. In comparison to the traditional Haber&#8211;Bosch process, the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) is a promising green alternative technology. Therefore, exploring NRR electrocatalysts with excellent performance is of great significance for sustainable development. Herein, density functional theory calculations were employed to explore the potential of transition metal (TM) atoms anchored on defective CuO surface formation TM@CuO catalysts. The thermodynamic stability of TM@CuO structures was confirmed through binding energy calculations. The high catalytic activity of Nb@CuO, Mo@CuO, Ru@CuO, and Ta@CuO was successfully determined by screening the free energy of the potential-determining step and comparing with the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction. The simulation of the entire pathway showed that the limiting potentials of Mo@CuO and Ru@CuO were &#8722;0.358 and &#8722;0.540 V, respectively. Furthermore, the charge density difference, Bader charge, density of states, and crystal orbital Hamiltonian population of Mo@CuO and Ru@CuO were analyzed, and the reasons for their excellent catalytic activity were identified. The research result of this study is expected to provide theoretical guidance for the rational design of new NRR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Wei Song, Pengfei Ma, Shaoting Lang, Xiao Liu, Chaozheng He, Jinlong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Oxygen Vacancy Distribution in Se&#8208;Doped RuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; to Enhance Its Stability in Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202512848</link>
      <description>Yongping Yang, Shulin Wang, Guikai Zhang, Xingyu Li, Qiang L&#252;, Hao Liu, Ziliang Deng, Xinyi Han, Shuailong Zhang, Wenbo Dong, Jiangnan Song, Yabin Chen, Gao Xiao, Yao Yang, Juncai Dong, Liang Cao, Zipeng Zhao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413412117

                Abstract Developing durable ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;based catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) remains challenging due to irreversible Ru dissolution and lattice oxygen instability. Although elemental doping is a general method to improve stability, it inadvertently induces oxygen vacancies (V O s), which are randomly distributed in the nanocatalyst. Notably, the impact of V O distribution on the stability of Ru&#8208;based catalysts remains unresolved. Herein, we synthesized the Se&#8208;doped Ru oxide via annealing the mixture of ruthenium (III) chloride and selenium (Se) in the air (Ur&#8208;Se&#8208;RuO x ) with the presence of urea, showing the V O s distributed away from Se dopants, which is significantly different from the Se&#8208;doped Ru oxide synthesized without urea (Se&#8208;RuO x ), showing V O s distributed relatively close to the Se dopants. The Ur&#8208;Se&#8208;RuO x demonstrates superior oxygen evolution reaction performance over Se&#8208;RuO x . Particularly, Ur&#8208;Se&#8208;RuO x delivers a low working voltage (1.62 V@1 A cm &#8722;2 ) and excellent durability (&gt;1000 h@200 mA cm &#8722;2 ) in PEMWE tests. Experimental and theoretical results reveal that V O s engage in long&#8208;range cooperation with spatially decoupled Se dopants in Ur&#8208;Se&#8208;RuO x , synergistically enhancing reaction kinetics via an intramolecular oxygen coupling mechanism, while inhibiting the lattice oxygen mechanism and suppressing Ru dissolution, which demonstrates a new strategy to break the activity&#8211;stability trade&#8208;off in promising Ru&#8208;based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yongping Yang, Shulin Wang, Guikai Zhang, Xingyu Li, Qiang L&#252;, Hao Liu, Ziliang Deng, Xinyi Han, Shuailong Zhang, Wenbo Dong, Jiangnan Song, Yabin Chen, Gao Xiao, Yao Yang, Juncai Dong, Liang Cao, Zipeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202512848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous multi-robot synthesis and optimization of metal halide perovskite nanocrystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63209-4</link>
      <description>Jinge Xu, Clifford M. Moran, Arup Ghorai, Fazel Bateni, James A. Bennett, Nikolai Mukhin, K.S.A. Latif, Andrew Cahn, Pragyan Jha, Fernando Delgado&#8208;Licona, Sina Sadeghi, Laura Politi, Milad Abolhasani, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413412394

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinge Xu, Clifford M. Moran, Arup Ghorai, Fazel Bateni, James A. Bennett, Nikolai Mukhin, K.S.A. Latif, Andrew Cahn, Pragyan Jha, Fernando Delgado&#8208;Licona, Sina Sadeghi, Laura Politi, Milad Abolhasani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63209-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging theory and practice: scalable prediction of alloy nanoparticle morphology and stability via machine-learned moment tensor potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03499-1</link>
      <description>Do Hung Manh, Chi H. Lee, Sang Uck Lee, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413412473

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Do Hung Manh, Chi H. Lee, Sang Uck Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03499-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced stability of spinel LiMn1.5Ni0.5O4 with V doping for high-voltage Li-ion batteries in organic and ionic liquid electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.183060</link>
      <description>H&#233;ctor D. Agudelo, F.A. V&#225;squez, Jorge A. Calder&#243;n, Roberto M. Torresi, Eduardo Carmine de Melo, Bikram Kumar Das, Henry A. Cort&#233;s, Mauricio R. Bonilla, Elena Akhmatskaya, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1039(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413417196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H&#233;ctor D. Agudelo, F.A. V&#225;squez, Jorge A. Calder&#243;n, Roberto M. Torresi, Eduardo Carmine de Melo, Bikram Kumar Das, Henry A. Cort&#233;s, Mauricio R. Bonilla, Elena Akhmatskaya</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.183060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-guided design of Fe-Ni bimetallic catalysts on sludge derived carbon for enhanced photo-Fenton degradation of ciprofloxacin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125832</link>
      <description>Chuang Yang, Qingyu Huang, Yu Yang, Yuchen Wang, Yi-Fei Sun, Fei Huang, Yongjun Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. 381(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413418577

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuang Yang, Qingyu Huang, Yu Yang, Yuchen Wang, Yi-Fei Sun, Fei Huang, Yongjun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-Learning-Driven Design of Tmcs Heterojunctions with Dual-Atom Synergy for Efficient Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5402313</link>
      <description>Jie Yang, Peilin Huang, Hanwen Zhang, Hongyang Ren, Jie Zhang, Hong Chen, Xiaotian Wang, Hongkuan Yuan, Biao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413421231

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Yang, Peilin Huang, Hanwen Zhang, Hongyang Ren, Jie Zhang, Hong Chen, Xiaotian Wang, Hongkuan Yuan, Biao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5402313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Oxygen Vacancy Distribution in Se&#8208;Doped RuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; to Enhance Its Stability in Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202512848</link>
      <description>Yongping Yang, Shulin Wang, Guikai Zhang, Xingyu Li, Qiang L&#252;, Hao Liu, Ziliang Deng, Xinyi Han, Shuailong Zhang, Wenbo Dong, Jiangnan Song, Yabin Chen, Gao Xiao, Yao Yang, Juncai Dong, Liang Cao, Zipeng Zhao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413428885

                Abstract Developing durable ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;based catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) remains challenging due to irreversible Ru dissolution and lattice oxygen instability. Although elemental doping is a general method to improve stability, it inadvertently induces oxygen vacancies (V O s), which are randomly distributed in the nanocatalyst. Notably, the impact of V O distribution on the stability of Ru&#8208;based catalysts remains unresolved. Herein, we synthesized the Se&#8208;doped Ru oxide via annealing the mixture of ruthenium (III) chloride and selenium (Se) in the air (Ur&#8208;Se&#8208;RuO x ) with the presence of urea, showing the V O s distributed away from Se dopants, which is significantly different from the Se&#8208;doped Ru oxide synthesized without urea (Se&#8208;RuO x ), showing V O s distributed relatively close to the Se dopants. The Ur&#8208;Se&#8208;RuO x demonstrates superior oxygen evolution reaction performance over Se&#8208;RuO x . Particularly, Ur&#8208;Se&#8208;RuO x delivers a low working voltage (1.62 V@1 A cm &#8722;2 ) and excellent durability (&gt;1000 h@200 mA cm &#8722;2 ) in PEMWE tests. Experimental and theoretical results reveal that V O s engage in long&#8208;range cooperation with spatially decoupled Se dopants in Ur&#8208;Se&#8208;RuO x , synergistically enhancing reaction kinetics via an intramolecular oxygen coupling mechanism, while inhibiting the lattice oxygen mechanism and suppressing Ru dissolution, which demonstrates a new strategy to break the activity&#8211;stability trade&#8208;off in promising Ru&#8208;based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yongping Yang, Shulin Wang, Guikai Zhang, Xingyu Li, Qiang L&#252;, Hao Liu, Ziliang Deng, Xinyi Han, Shuailong Zhang, Wenbo Dong, Jiangnan Song, Yabin Chen, Gao Xiao, Yao Yang, Juncai Dong, Liang Cao, Zipeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202512848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of P&#8211;D Orbital Hybridization in Pt-M(P-Block) Double-Atom Catalysts to Promote the Activity of Electrocatalytic Nitrobenzene Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5401638</link>
      <description>Kefeng Xie, Mingqiang Liu, Xiaoqing Gong, Yi Yang, Liang Yu, Xiaohong Song, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413429407

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kefeng Xie, Mingqiang Liu, Xiaoqing Gong, Yi Yang, Liang Yu, Xiaohong Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5401638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the d&#8208;Band Center via Strain and Ligand Effects in Core&#8211;Shell Pentatwinned Au@Pd Nanoparticles for Enhanced Ethanol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202514936</link>
      <description>Tanuja, S. S. Tomar, Tukai Singha, Biswarup Satpati, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413430628

                Abstract The successful commercialization of direct ethanol fuel cells (DEFCs) hinges on the development of highly efficient electrocatalysts capable of overcoming key performance limitations. In this study, the core&#8211;shell Au@Pd pentatwinned decahedral nanoparticles has been synthesized with controlled Pd shell thicknesses, varying in the average number of Pd monolayers over the Au core. This core&#8208;shell configuration promotes the epitaxial growth of Pd atoms with varying degrees of tensile strain. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that increasing tensile strain shifts the d&#8208;band center closer to the Fermi level. Notably, when the Pd shell is three monolayers, the upward shift of the d&#8208;band center is maximum, and this further amplified by the ligand effect from the underlying Au core. The synergistic influence of five twin boundaries, tensile strain, and ligand interactions collectively tunes the d&#8208;band center, resulting in the Au@Pd&#8208;3 catalyst achieving an exceptional mass activity of 25.67 A mg Pd &#8722;1 and a specific activity of 21.30 mA cm &#8722;2 , representing enhancements of 38.31&#8208;fold and 11.39&#8208;fold, respectively, over commercial Pd/C. This study highlights how the combined effects of strain and ligand interactions can be strategically harnessed to design high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts by tuning the position of d&#8208;band center.</description>
      <author>Tanuja, S. S. Tomar, Tukai Singha, Biswarup Satpati</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202514936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phytate-Induced Surface Reconstruction of Nickel Foam: Creating Active O* Species for Selective Electrooxidation of Benzylamine to Benzonitrile</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c05656</link>
      <description>Charles A. Su, Bin Hu, Qiang Tan, Xiaohe Tan, Yuxuan Jiang, Zhaoming Xia, Yongquan Qu, Yuanyuan Ma, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413434187

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Charles A. Su, Bin Hu, Qiang Tan, Xiaohe Tan, Yuxuan Jiang, Zhaoming Xia, Yongquan Qu, Yuanyuan Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c05656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Catalytic Efficiency by Thiolate-Protected Trimetallic (Cu, Pd, Au) Nanoclusters: Single-Atom Alloy Catalysts for Water&#8211;Gas Shift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04165</link>
      <description>Stephan Pollitt, Thomas Haunold, Sakiat Hossain, Gereon Behrendt, Michael St&#246;ger&#8208;Pollach, Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Noelia Barrab&#233;s, Malte Behrens, Yuichi Negishi, G&#252;nther Rupprechter, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413434678

                The "crude oil exodus" and energy transition will finally hinge on the availability of hydrogen. Catalytic processes like the water&#8211;gas shift (WGS) reaction may significantly contribute to its production and become crucial for utilizing alternative feedstocks. This work demonstrates how thiolate-protected gold nanoclusters can be employed as precursors for single-atom alloy (SAA) catalysts. The clusters serve as carriers of heteroatom dopants (Cu, Pd) while precisely maintaining 25 metal atoms per cluster (&lt;1 nm). Using the 2PET ligand during synthesis led to high yield and cluster stability, but ligand exchange was required to link clusters to a ZnO support efficiently. Introducing pMBA as a ligand enabled a homogeneous cluster distribution on the ZnO surface, creating a well-defined catalyst with dual functionality. This SAA catalyst, outperforming a Cu/ZnO/Al2O3 benchmark in WGS, may get industrial relevance when upscaled while still serving as a well-defined model system in catalysis. Thereby, it bridges the gap between practical applications and fundamental research. Pre- and postreaction analysis by XPS proved the presence of the dopants in the catalysts in the expected stoichiometry, showed changes in the electronic structures, but also revealed sulfur migration from the clusters/ligands to the support, forming ZnS. Furthermore, XPS unveiled a pretreatment-induced SMSI decoration effect, stabilizing the small particles during catalysis. (S)TEM indicated a homogeneous cluster distribution on ZnO after synthesis and proved small particle sizes throughout the experiments. In situ DRIFTS confirmed the accessibility of the dopant atoms by the reactant CO and also detected adsorbed byproducts. The precise size and doping control of thiolate-protected SAA nanoclusters, together with their catalytic performance, demonstrate the potential for targeted future investigations in a wide range of industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Stephan Pollitt, Thomas Haunold, Sakiat Hossain, Gereon Behrendt, Michael St&#246;ger&#8208;Pollach, Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Noelia Barrab&#233;s, Malte Behrens, Yuichi Negishi, G&#252;nther Rupprechter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilized ionic liquids/deep eutectic solvents in carbon capture: current progress and future potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-025-03276-9</link>
      <description>Sahar Foorginezhad, Xiaoyan Ji, Clean Technologies and Environmental Policy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413269547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sahar Foorginezhad, Xiaoyan Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-025-03276-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Aluminum Doping in Enhancing High-Temperature Stability of Lithium-Rich Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5397423</link>
      <description>Min&#8208;Ho Kim, Aditya Narayan Singh, Miran Ha, Wang&#8208;Geun Lee, Saeed Pourasad, Abhishek Meena, Haeseong Jang, Jeongwoo Seo, Jaehyun Park, Seok Ju Kang, Kyung&#8208;Wan Nam, Tae Joo Shin, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Kwang S. Kim, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413324865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min&#8208;Ho Kim, Aditya Narayan Singh, Miran Ha, Wang&#8208;Geun Lee, Saeed Pourasad, Abhishek Meena, Haeseong Jang, Jeongwoo Seo, Jaehyun Park, Seok Ju Kang, Kyung&#8208;Wan Nam, Tae Joo Shin, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Kwang S. Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5397423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface immobilization of base metal molecular catalysts for (photo)electrochemical hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.217071</link>
      <description>T. Sanjoy Singh, Sreetama Ghosh, Abir Sarbajna, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 546(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413406774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>T. Sanjoy Singh, Sreetama Ghosh, Abir Sarbajna</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.217071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing pharmacology: AI-powered approaches in molecular modeling and ADMET prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.medidd.2025.100223</link>
      <description>Irfan Pathan, Ali Raza, Adarsh Sahu, Mohit Joshi, Yogita Sahu, Yash Patil, Mohammad Adnan Raza, M. Ajazuddin, Medicine in Drug Discovery. 28(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413415103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Irfan Pathan, Ali Raza, Adarsh Sahu, Mohit Joshi, Yogita Sahu, Yash Patil, Mohammad Adnan Raza, M. Ajazuddin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.medidd.2025.100223</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
