<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 01:19:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Reliable Modeling of Co-Copper Catalysis: Hubbard and Dispersion Effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5138423</link>
      <description>M. Olu&#351; &#214;zbek, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407572499

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Olu&#351; &#214;zbek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5138423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton Relay in Hydrogen-Bond Networks Promotes Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c00318</link>
      <description>Yuefei Li, Shishi Zhang, Boyang Li, Yaqiong Su, Jie Kong, Jiayuan Li, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407572951

                Common O-/H-down orientation of H2O molecules on electrocatalysts brings favorable OH/H delivery; however, adverse H/OH delivery in their dissociation process hampers the H2O dissociation kinetics of the alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). To overcome this challenge, we raised a synergetic H2O dissociation concept of metal-supported electrocatalysts involving efficient OH delivery from O-down H2O to the metal, timely proton relay from O-down H2O on the metal to H-down H2O on the support through the hydrogen-bond network, and prompt H delivery from H-down H2O to the support. After theoretically profiling that a high work function difference between the metal and the support (&#916;&#934;) induces a strong electric field at the metal&#8211;support interface that increases hydrogen-bond connectivity to promote proton relay, we practiced this concept over cobalt phosphide-supported ruthenium (Ru/CoP) catalysts with a high &#916;&#934; = 0.4 eV, achieving a record-high Ru utilization HER activity of 66.1 A mgRu&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.1 V vs RHE. The insights into this synergetic H2O dissociation mechanism provide opportunity for the design of bicomponent alkaline HER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuefei Li, Shishi Zhang, Boyang Li, Yaqiong Su, Jie Kong, Jiayuan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c00318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycine electrosynthesis by the co-reduction of oxalic and nitric acids on rutile TiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101266</link>
      <description>Shiming Li, Lin Li, Wei Du, Tao Jiang, Ming Gong, Jianping Xiao, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407578931

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiming Li, Lin Li, Wei Du, Tao Jiang, Ming Gong, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic Understanding of Hydrogen Coverage on RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110) Surface under Electrochemical Conditions from &lt;i&gt;Ab Initio&lt;/i&gt; Statistical Thermodynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07229</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, Jan Kloppenburg, Chia&#8208;Yi Lin, Luka Mitrovic, Simon Gelin, Ismaila Dabo, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich, Geoffroy Hautier, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407582575

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, Jan Kloppenburg, Chia&#8208;Yi Lin, Luka Mitrovic, Simon Gelin, Ismaila Dabo, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich, Geoffroy Hautier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Independent Tuning of Intermediate Energetics for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution via Synergistic Defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417098</link>
      <description>Ding Yuan, Xiaoyi Dou, Qing Zhang, Chun&#8208;Ting He, Chao Wu, Yang Li, Weijie Li, Linping Yu, Lei Zhang, Huan Liu, Shi Xue Dou, Ji Liang, Yuhai Dou, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407584253

                Abstract Electronic structure engineering via integrating different defects is the key to achieving independent tuning of intermediate energetics for efficient electrocatalyst design. Such a combination of defects is at the forefront of current research. Herein, W is etched from Co(OH) 2 to generate Co vacancies, which are then partially filled with La to form Co(OH) 2 &#8208;Co V &#8208;La D for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The results show that Co vacancy and La dopant induce more high&#8208;valence Co species under OER conditions and the most active center is a surface Co site that is adjacent to a surface Co vacancy and a subsurface La dopant on different sides, where the optimized electronic structure narrows the gap between Gibbs free energies of OH* (&#916;G OH* ) and OOH* (&#916;G OOH* ) and modifies &#916;G O* close to the midpoint, leading to high catalytic activity. The integration of synergistic defects offers an effective strategy to generate a range of defect atomic configurations and diverse electronic states, which enable the independent tuning of intermediate energetics, thereby unlocking the catalyst's full catalytic potential.</description>
      <author>Ding Yuan, Xiaoyi Dou, Qing Zhang, Chun&#8208;Ting He, Chao Wu, Yang Li, Weijie Li, Linping Yu, Lei Zhang, Huan Liu, Shi Xue Dou, Ji Liang, Yuhai Dou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janus MoSi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;As&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Decorated with Transition Metal Atoms as Efficient Bifunctional HER/OER and OER/ORR Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c21412</link>
      <description>Yazhao Yuan, Chunling Zhang, Xunzhe Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407586502

                It is of great importance to develop bifunctional electrocatalysts with high efficiency and low cost for water splitting and fuel cells. Herein, based on the new emerging two-dimensional material of MoSi2N4, we explore the potentials of novel Janus MoSi2P2As2 (labeled as MSPA) in electrocatalytic applications. We conduct a comprehensive study using first-principles calculations to explore the potential of Janus MoSi2P2As2 decorated with 13 kinds of transition metal atoms as efficient bifunctional catalysts for the hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction (HER/OER) and oxygen evolution/reduction reaction (OER/ORR). After screening, results show that Rh@MSPA and Au@MSPA can serve as bifunctional catalysts for OER/ORR with overpotentials of 0.27/0.29 V and 0.42/0.37 V, and Pt@MSPA exhibit great potential as HER/OER catalyst with an overpotential of -0.004/0.51 V. The solvation effect on catalytic activity is also investigated. The volcano diagrams are employed to depict the activity trends toward HER, OER, and ORR. The d-band center, ICOHP and intrinsic descriptor &#966; can serve as quantitative descriptors of ORR/OER activity and reveal the activity origin of OER/ORR. This study presents a viable approach for developing advanced electrocatalysts with multiple functionalities, thereby expanding the utilization of Janus MoSi2P2As2 in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Yazhao Yuan, Chunling Zhang, Xunzhe Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c21412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia over Cu-based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2025.121123</link>
      <description>Zhibin Zhang, Kailun Yu, Hui Wang, Zhaoyong Bian, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407587699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhibin Zhang, Kailun Yu, Hui Wang, Zhaoyong Bian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2025.121123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO2 Reduction: Advances, Insights, Challenges, and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101089</link>
      <description>Asghar Ali, Muhammad Qasim, S. Sakhi, Govindhan Maduraiveeran, Ali S. Alnaser, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407596623

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asghar Ali, Muhammad Qasim, S. Sakhi, Govindhan Maduraiveeran, Ali S. Alnaser</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategies to maximize the oxygen evolution reaction in layered double hydroxides by electronic defect engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100380</link>
      <description>Heyu Zhou, Jinjin Ban, Yonglong Shen, Yonghong Ning, Shanshan Zhang, Fanfan Liu, Guoqin Cao, Guosheng Shao, S. Ravi P. Silva, Junhua Hu, eScience. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407597464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Heyu Zhou, Jinjin Ban, Yonglong Shen, Yonghong Ning, Shanshan Zhang, Fanfan Liu, Guoqin Cao, Guosheng Shao, S. Ravi P. Silva, Junhua Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outlier-detection for reactive machine learned potential energy surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01473-6</link>
      <description>Luis Itza Vazquez-Salazar, Silvan K&#228;ser, Markus Meuwly, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407602147

                Abstract Uncertainty quantification (UQ) to detect samples with large expected errors (outliers) is applied to reactive molecular potential energy surfaces (PESs). Three methods&#8211;Ensembles, deep evidential regression (DER), and Gaussian Mixture Models (GMM)&#8212;were applied to the H-transfer reaction between syn -Criegee and vinyl hydroxyperoxide. The results indicate that ensemble models provide the best results for detecting outliers, followed by GMM. For example, from a pool of 1000 structures with the largest uncertainty, the detection quality for outliers is ~90% and ~50%, respectively, if 25 or 1000 structures with large errors are sought. On the contrary, the limitations of the statistical assumptions of DER greatly impact its prediction capabilities. Finally, a structure-based indicator was found to be correlated with large average error, which may help to rapidly classify new structures into those that provide an advantage for refining the neural network.</description>
      <author>Luis Itza Vazquez-Salazar, Silvan K&#228;ser, Markus Meuwly</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01473-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin&#8208;Selective Catalysts for Oxygen&#8208;Involved Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400326</link>
      <description>Haifan Li, Quan Quan, Chun&#8208;Yuen Wong, Johnny C. Ho, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407606875

                The sluggish kinetics of oxygen&#8208;involved electrolysis, such as oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), hinders the efficiency of the pertaining energy conversion process, which can be promoted by using spin&#8208;selective materials to align the spin direction of oxygen&#8208;involved intermediates. This review delivers a thorough and timely overview of state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art spin&#8208;selective catalysts for OER and ORR. Primarily, the fundamental principle of spin&#8208;selective process is depicted by the spin&#8208;sensitive reaction pathways, pointing out that the existence of spin&#8208;polarized adsorption sites is necessary for the development of spin&#8208;selective catalysts. Subsequently, approaches for investigating the spin&#8208;related transition during electrocatalysis are introduced by reviewing in situ technologies and theoretical calculations. Then, the reported spin&#8208;selective catalysts are categorized into intrinsic spin&#8208;polarized materials, doping&#8208;induced spin&#8208;polarized materials, and multiple magnetic composites to discuss their application in electrocatalytic OER and ORR as well as their mechanism of spin polarization. Finally, the open questions and prospects in this field are concluded, aiming to offer a clear route for designing novel and highly&#8208;efficient spin&#8208;polarized materials for industrial oxygen&#8208;involved electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Haifan Li, Quan Quan, Chun&#8208;Yuen Wong, Johnny C. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the structure of interfacial water and its role in acidic and alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction at Au electrode by electrochemical in-situ infrared spectroscopy and theoretical simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116021</link>
      <description>Bai-Quan Zhu, Er-Fei Zhen, Bing-Yu Liu, Lidan Zhang, Yanxia Chen, Zhongfan Liu, Yanxia Chen, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407610935

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bai-Quan Zhu, Er-Fei Zhen, Bing-Yu Liu, Lidan Zhang, Yanxia Chen, Zhongfan Liu, Yanxia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper doping tunes d-band center to enhance hydrogen evolution in global minimum Fe clusters on FeN4&#8210;graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112640</link>
      <description>Jiu-Ning Wang, Qasim Qasim, Wei Xu, Wanglai Cen, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407614979

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiu-Ning Wang, Qasim Qasim, Wei Xu, Wanglai Cen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surrogate Models for Vibrational Entropy Based on a Spatial Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1137/24m165168x</link>
      <description>Tina Torabi, Christoph Ortner, Yangshuai Wang, Multiscale Modeling and Simulation. 23(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407615840

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tina Torabi, Christoph Ortner, Yangshuai Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1137/24m165168x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances of Electrocatalysts and Electrodes for Direct Formic Acid Fuel Cells: from Nano to Meter Scale Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-025-01648-w</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Ming&#8208;Shui Yao, Yanping He, Shangfeng Du, Nano-Micro Letters. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407624042

                Abstract Direct formic acid fuel cells are promising energy devices with advantages of low working temperature and high safety in fuel storage and transport. They have been expected to be a future power source for portable electronic devices. The technology has been developed rapidly to overcome the high cost and low power performance that hinder its practical application, which mainly originated from the slow reaction kinetics of the formic acid oxidation and complex mass transfer within the fuel cell electrodes. Here, we provide a comprehensive review of the progress around this technology, in particular for addressing multiscale challenges from catalytic mechanism understanding at the atomic scale, to catalyst design at the nanoscale, electrode structure at the micro scale and design at the millimeter scale, and finally to device fabrication at the meter scale. The gap between the highly active electrocatalysts and the poor electrode performance in practical devices is highlighted. Finally, perspectives and opportunities are proposed to potentially bridge this gap for further development of this technology.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Ming&#8208;Shui Yao, Yanping He, Shangfeng Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-025-01648-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recombination of Autodissociated Water Ions in a Nanoscale Pure Water Droplet</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15103</link>
      <description>Soonho Kwon, Prabhat Prakash, Yixiang Cao, Frances A. Houle, William A. Goddard, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407624611

                The recombination of water ions has diverse scientific and practical implications, ranging from acid&#8211;base chemistry and biological systems to planetary environments and applications in fuel cell and carbon conversion technologies. While spatial confinement affects the physicochemical properties of water dynamics, its impact on the recombination process has rarely been studied. In this work, we investigate the dynamics of water, the water ion distribution, and the ion recombination process in water droplets as a function of droplet size through molecular dynamics simulations and adaptive quantum mechanical/molecular mechanical calculations. We compare the dynamics of recombination in water droplet sizes ranging from 100 to 18 000 waters, both in their interiors and on their surfaces. We found that the self-diffusion of water dramatically decreases in droplets with a diameter below 2.2 nm. Using a classical RexPoN force-field, we found that the ions in 1000 H2O's spend almost 50% of the time on the surface and 0.5 nm beneath it with a slight preference for OH&#8211; ion to reside longer on the surface. We estimate that, on average, recombination in these drops occurs at 400 ps in 1000 H2O's and 1 ns in 3000 H2O's. We also found that recombination is not limited by the local structure of the surface or the size of the droplet but can be influenced by the geometry of the water wire connecting the ions as they approach each other, which can often prevent recombination. Our results provide insights to the reaction microenvironments presented by nanoscopic water droplets.</description>
      <author>Soonho Kwon, Prabhat Prakash, Yixiang Cao, Frances A. Houle, William A. Goddard</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically Driven Optical Dynamics of Reflectin Protein Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411005</link>
      <description>Yin&#8208;Chen Lin, Changxuan Yang, Seren Tochikura, Joshua R. Uzarski, Daniel E. Morse, Lior Sepunaru, Michael J. Gordon, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407637890

                Abstract Neuronally triggered phosphorylation drives the dynamic condensation of reflectin proteins, enabling squid to fine tune the colors reflected from specialized skin cells (iridocytes) for camouflage and communication. Reflectin, the primary component of iridocyte lamellae, forms alternating layers of protein and low refractive index extracellular space within membrane&#8208;encapsulated structures, acting as a biologically tunable distributed Bragg reflector. In vivo, reflectin condensation induces osmotic dehydration of these lamellae, reducing their thickness and shifting the wavelength of reflected light. Inspired by this natural mechanism, we demonstrate that electrochemical reduction of imidazolium moieties within the protein provides a reversible and tunable method to control the water volume fraction in reflectin thin films, allowing precise, dynamic modulation of the film&#8217;s refractive index and thickness &#8212; mimicking the squid&#8217;s dynamic color adaptation. To unravel the underlying mechanisms, we developed electrochemical correlative ellipsometry and surface plasmon resonance spectroscopy, enabling real&#8208;time analysis of optical property changes of reflectin films. This electrochemically driven approach offers unprecedented control over reflectin condensation dynamics. Our findings not only deepen the understanding of biophysical processes governing cephalopod coloration but also pave the way for bio&#8208;inspired materials and devices that seamlessly integrate biological principles with synthetic systems to bridge the biotic&#8208;abiotic gap.</description>
      <author>Yin&#8208;Chen Lin, Changxuan Yang, Seren Tochikura, Joshua R. Uzarski, Daniel E. Morse, Lior Sepunaru, Michael J. Gordon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Surface Passivation Mechanisms in CrCoNi Alloys via Interpretable Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03628</link>
      <description>Haoyu Wan, Yue Wu, Guanhua Qin, Deng Pan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407639677

                This study investigates the formation and stability of passivation films in medium-entropy CrCoNi alloy using an integrated approach combining first-principles calculations and Gaussian Approximation Potential (GAP). By performing extensive structural relaxations coupled with random occupancy of the alloy and multiple potential adsorption sites, the results based on surface reconstruction are analyzed. Our results demonstrate that disordered atomic structures in medium entropy CrCoNi alloy exhibit improved oxide film stability compared to ordered structures, with lower system energies correlating with more robust passivation layers. Furthermore, by constructing physically meaningful descriptors and employing symbolic regression in complex surface environments, simple yet highly correlated rules are obtained, providing insights into the passivation strengthening of CrCoNi alloy from both global and local perspectives. Our work paves the way for exploring surface regularities in complex medium-entropy alloys with the combination of quantum mechanical accuracy and machine learning efficiency.</description>
      <author>Haoyu Wan, Yue Wu, Guanhua Qin, Deng Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hammett Substituent Constant Guided Design of Ligand&#8208;Modified Ru Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202406034</link>
      <description>Zelin Zhao, De Wang, Jia Wang, Zhenyu He, Junsheng Li, ChemistrySelect. 10(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407645775

                Abstract The design of efficient alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalysts is crucial for the development of green hydrogen production. In this work, we report modulation the HER activity of Ru nanoparticles by functionalization using para&#8208;substituted phenylacetylenes (R = Cl, H, C 2 H 5 , and OCH 3 ), which have different electron donating/withdrawing capabilities. A close correlation between the Hammett substituent constant of the phenylacetylenes and HER activity of the functionalized Ru nanoparticles is revealed, and the underlying mechanism is investigated. Guided by such correlation, 4&#8208;ethylphenylacetylene&#8208;modified Ru nanoparticles (Ru&#9472;EPA) with a low HER overpotential of 17.7 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline solution is developed. The mechanistic understanding gained in this work will provide important guidelines for future development of high&#8208;performance nanostructured electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Zelin Zhao, De Wang, Jia Wang, Zhenyu He, Junsheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202406034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rendering the European neutron research landscape</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-88099-w</link>
      <description>E. V. Velichko, H. Abele, David J. Barlow, Antonio Benedetto, Stefano Deledda, Lambert van Eijck, M. T. Fern&#225;ndez&#8208;D&#237;az, M. Janoschek, Maths Karlsson, K. Lefmann, Natalie Malikova, M. Paula M. Marques, K. Mergia, J&#246;rg Pieper, H. M. R&#248;nnow, Jan &#352;aroun, A. Schneidewind, Frank Schreiber, K. Temst, Max Wolff, Wojciech Zaj&#261;c, M. Zanatta, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407653233

                Neutrons, owing to their unique properties, serve as indispensable probes for investigating the structure and dynamics of materials across various length scales. The scientific community utilizing neutron research infrastructures encompasses a diverse range of disciplines, making it challenging to quantify its scientific and societal impact. To address this challenge, we apply Natural Language Processing (NLP) and machine learning techniques to analyze the scientific output of the European neutron science community. Leveraging open-source software toolkits, our method allows for the quantitative assessment of community evolution and research focus. Our analysis reveals consistent growth in the neutron community despite a reduction in sources, underscoring the enduring significance of neutron methods in scientific research. Furthermore, an increase in unique authors and an even distribution of publications across diverse scientific topics highlight the community's interdisciplinary nature and collaborative spirit. While this study emphasizes neutron scattering, our methodology holds promise for a broad range of scientific communities reliant on Large Research Infrastructures (LRIs), offering opportunities for collaboration, optimization of experimental approaches, and informed decision-making by governmental and funding bodies.</description>
      <author>E. V. Velichko, H. Abele, David J. Barlow, Antonio Benedetto, Stefano Deledda, Lambert van Eijck, M. T. Fern&#225;ndez&#8208;D&#237;az, M. Janoschek, Maths Karlsson, K. Lefmann, Natalie Malikova, M. Paula M. Marques, K. Mergia, J&#246;rg Pieper, H. M. R&#248;nnow, Jan &#352;aroun, A. Schneidewind, Frank Schreiber, K. Temst, Max Wolff, Wojciech Zaj&#261;c, M. Zanatta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-88099-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the impact of structure and coverage on the reactivity of realistic heterogeneous catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-025-00179-w</link>
      <description>Benjamin W. J. Chen, Manos Mavrikakis, Nature Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407662259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benjamin W. J. Chen, Manos Mavrikakis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-025-00179-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra&#8208;fast and selective recycling of gold from electronic waste based on triiodide ionic &lt;scp&gt;liquids&lt;/scp&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18773</link>
      <description>Xiaolu Yin, Ronghao Liu, Ying Yue, Jun Li, Yanzhao Yang, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407665529

                Abstract This study introduces a pioneering application of triiodide ionic liquids (ILs) for the efficient and sustainable recovery of gold (Au) from real&#8208;world, various types of electronic wastes. Our method significantly reduces both environmental impact and reagent expenses, while operating under mild conditions. This technique is ideal for practical applications given its ultra&#8208;fast leaching (5 min) and room temperature (35&#176;C) reaction conditions, leading to an unprecedented 11&#8208;fold enhancement in the reaction kinetics relative to aqua regia. Notably, more than 99.3% of Au from e&#8208;waste can be selectively dissolved while excluding non&#8208;target elements like Cu. Compared with conventional dissolution&#8208;extraction processes, our method facilitates the process into a single step. Additionally, the triiodide ILs can be reused for up to six cycles, and have an impressive economic output&#8211;input ratio of 1969%, which demonstrates promising technoeconomic feasibility. This approach provides a valuable strategy for profit&#8208;efficient management of e&#8208;waste, promoting a circular economy.</description>
      <author>Xiaolu Yin, Ronghao Liu, Ying Yue, Jun Li, Yanzhao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation and electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide by transition metal atom-doped copper clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03795b</link>
      <description>Manish Kumar Mohanta, P. Jena, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407671770

                Doping transition metals in Cu 13 clusters enhance CO 2 reduction by altering electronic and magnetic properties, lowering overpotentials by &#8764;20%.</description>
      <author>Manish Kumar Mohanta, P. Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03795b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Dual-Atom Catalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to C&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; and C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Products with High Activity and Selectivity: A Density Functional Theory Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04831</link>
      <description>Zhongze Bai, Zhuo Zhi, Xi Zhuo Jiang, Kai Luo, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407671862

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) electroreduction using renewable energy provides a sustainable solution to mitigate greenhouse effects and achieve carbon neutrality. Developing high-performance electrocatalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is key to promoting such a technology. Herein, we systematically explored the CO2RR catalytic activity of 325 dual-metal-site catalysts (DMSCs) through density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Among them, the Sc/Tc DMSC is particularly advantageous for HCOOH, CH4, and CH3CH2OH production, with limiting potentials of &#8722;0.45 V, &#8722;0.45 V, and &#8722;0.46 V, respectively. The Ti/Rh DMSC can selectively convert CO2 to CH3CH2OH at ultralow overpotentials (UL = &#8722;0.21 V). HCOOH is the preferred product of the CO2RR on the Mn/Fe site with a UL of &#8722;0.30 V. Mn/Fe presents the highest inhibitory effects on the side reaction, the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), with a UL of &#8722;0.66 V. Moreover, electronic analysis was conducted to further explain the enhancement for the CO2RR of explored catalysts at the subatomic level. Our work offers a strategy for screening of high-performance DMSCs and reveals the mechanisms of the CO2RR to target products for selected catalysts, benefiting the further development of CO2RR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhongze Bai, Zhuo Zhi, Xi Zhuo Jiang, Kai Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable molecular dynamics simulations of halide perovskites from a temperature-ensemble gradient-domain machine learning approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.141964</link>
      <description>Oz Y. Mendelsohn, Michal Hartstein, Stefan Chmiela, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Leeor Kronik, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407673412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oz Y. Mendelsohn, Michal Hartstein, Stefan Chmiela, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Leeor Kronik</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.141964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical evaluation of nitrate reduction reaction on single&#8208;atom anchored boron nitride fullerene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jccs.202400390</link>
      <description>Faiza Shafiq, Lei Yang, Weihua Zhu, Journal of the Chinese Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407673629

                Abstract Nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) is a powerful technique for eliminating pollution. Here, NO 3 RRs on transition metal&#8208;doped boron nitride fullerene (TM/B 11 N 12 ) were thoroughly examined utilizing density functional theory (DFT). Co/B 11 N 12 , a potential single&#8208;atom catalyst (SAC) with a low thermal barrier for NO 3 RR toward NH 3 synthesis with good stability, activity, and selectivity, was successfully screened out. Co/B 11 N 12 has the lowest limiting potential ( U L ) of &#8722;0.45 V and good NO 3 RR performance. Due to the comparatively restrained adsorption of proton on Co/B 11 N 12 , competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is substantially limited. The excellent selectivity for the production of NH 3 is ensured by significant energy barrier prerequisite for the formation of by&#8208;products (NO, NO 2 , N 2 O, and N 2 ) on Co/B 11 N 12 . By ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations, Co/B 11 N 12 exhibits remarkable structural stability at 400 K with minimal distortion as compared to its initial shape. Our research may not only offer a fundamental understanding of the activity origin of NO 3 RR and catalytic mechanism on TM/B 11 N 12 but also open up opportunities for rational designing of SACs for NO 3 RR toward the NH 3 synthesis.</description>
      <author>Faiza Shafiq, Lei Yang, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jccs.202400390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-stage carburization of titanium and vanadium group metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.71267/mencom.7569</link>
      <description>A. N. Rogova, &#1043;. &#1055;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1095;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1048;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077;&#1074;, A. V. Shokod&#8217;ko, A. S. Chernyavskii, &#1050;. &#1040;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1083;&#1085;&#1094;&#1077;&#1074;, Mendeleev Communications. 35(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407709775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. N. Rogova, &#1043;. &#1055;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1095;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1048;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077;&#1074;, A. V. Shokod&#8217;ko, A. S. Chernyavskii, &#1050;. &#1040;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1083;&#1085;&#1094;&#1077;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.71267/mencom.7569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Icosahedra CoPd Bimetallic Nanoparticles for Magnetically Induced Aromatic Ketone Hydrodeoxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03359</link>
      <description>Felipe Quiroga-Suavita, V&#237;ctor Varela&#8208;Izquierdo, Teresa Hungr&#305;&#769;a, Damien Alloyeau, Nicolas Ratel&#8208;Ramond, Simon Cayez, Richard D. Tilley, Edwin A. Baquero, Bruno Chaudret, Lise&#8208;Marie Lacroix, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407720071

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Felipe Quiroga-Suavita, V&#237;ctor Varela&#8208;Izquierdo, Teresa Hungr&#305;&#769;a, Damien Alloyeau, Nicolas Ratel&#8208;Ramond, Simon Cayez, Richard D. Tilley, Edwin A. Baquero, Bruno Chaudret, Lise&#8208;Marie Lacroix</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Octahedral Tilt-Driven Phase Transitions in BaZrS&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Chalcogenide Perovskite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03517</link>
      <description>Prakriti Kayastha, Erik Fransson, Paul Erhart, Lucy D. Whalley, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407738216

                Chalcogenide perovskites are lead-free materials for potential photovoltaic or thermoelectric applications. BaZrS3 is the most-studied member of this family due to its superior thermal and chemical stability, desirable optoelectronic properties, and low thermal conductivity. Phase transitions in BaZrS3 remain underexplored in the literature, as most experimental characterizations of this material have been performed at ambient conditions where the orthorhombic Pnma phase is reported to be stable. In this work, we study the dynamics of BaZrS3 across a range of temperatures and pressures using an accurate machine learning interatomic potential trained with data from hybrid density functional theory calculations. At 0 Pa, we find a first-order phase transition from the orthorhombic to tetragonal I4/mcm phase at 610 K, and a second-order transition from the tetragonal to the cubic Pm3&#773;m phase at 880 K. The tetragonal phase is stable over a larger temperature range at higher pressures. To confirm the validity of our model we compare our results with a range of published experimental data and report a prediction for the X-ray diffraction pattern as a function of temperature.</description>
      <author>Prakriti Kayastha, Erik Fransson, Paul Erhart, Lucy D. Whalley</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-Learning-Accelerated Surface Exploration of Reconstructed BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;(010) and Characterization of Their Aqueous Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17739</link>
      <description>Yonghyuk Lee, Taehun Lee, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407740681

                Understanding the semiconductor-electrolyte interface in photoelectrochemical (PEC) systems is crucial for optimizing the stability and reactivity. Despite the challenges in establishing reliable surface structure models during PEC cycles, this study explores the complex surface reconstructions of BiVO4(010) by employing a computational workflow integrated with a state-of-the-art active learning protocol for a machine-learning interatomic potential and global optimization techniques. Within this workflow, we identified 494 unique reconstructed surface structures that surpass conventional chemical intuition-driven, bulk-truncated models. After constructing the surface Pourbaix diagram under Bi- and V-rich electrolyte conditions using density functional theory and hybrid functional calculations, we proposed structural models for the experimentally observed Bi-rich BiVO4 surfaces. By performing hybrid functional molecular dynamics simulations with the explicit treatment of water molecules on selected reconstructed BiVO4(010) surfaces, we observed water dissociation from molecular water. Our findings demonstrate significant water dissociation on reconstructed Bi-rich surfaces, highlighting the critical role of bare and undercoordinated Bi sites (only observable in reconstructed surfaces) in driving hydration processes. Our work establishes a foundation for understanding the role of complex, reconstructed Bi surfaces in surface hydration and reactivity. Additionally, our theoretical framework for exploring surface structures and predicting reactivity in multicomponent oxides offers a precise approach to describing complex surface and interface processes in PEC systems.</description>
      <author>Yonghyuk Lee, Taehun Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Periodic Table Exploration of MXenes for Efficient Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410105</link>
      <description>Radhika Nittoor&#8208;Veedu, Xiaohui Ju, Michal Langer, Wanli Gao, Michal Otyepka, Martin Pumera, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407754876

                Abstract Applying electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) to produce ammonia offers a sustainable alternative to the energy&#8208;intensive Haber&#8208;Bosch process, which is crucial for clean energy and agricultural applications. While 2D MXenes hold great promise as electrocatalysts for NO 3 RR, their application for ammonia production remains underexplored. This study combines experimental and theoretical approaches to evaluate the catalytic performance of a series of MXenes with different central metal atoms for NO 3 RR. Among the materials studied (Ti 3 C 2 T x , Ti 3 CNT x , Ti 2 CT x , V 2 CT x , Cr 2 CT x , Nb 2 CT x , and Ta 2 CT x ), Ti 3 &#8208;based MXenes exhibit superior faradaic efficiency, ammonia yield rate, and stability. Density functional theory calculations offer further insights explaining the structure&#8208;activity&#8208;based observations. This research establishes a foundation for future studies aimed at leveraging MXenes for electrochemical nitrate reduction for green synthesis of ammonia.</description>
      <author>Radhika Nittoor&#8208;Veedu, Xiaohui Ju, Michal Langer, Wanli Gao, Michal Otyepka, Martin Pumera</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Production &#8211; Catalyst Design Strategies Based on Crystal Structures of Multimetal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400246</link>
      <description>Yuuki Sugawara, Takeo Yamaguchi, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407756015

                Abstract Solid&#8208;state crystalline multimetal oxides have been widely studied for their applications as electrode materials, e. g., in fuel cells, water electrolyzer, lithium&#8208;ion batteries, and metal&#8208;air batteries. Particularly, hydrogen production via water electrolysis is considered a key technology for realizing a sustainable circular carbon society. Enhancing the activity of electrocatalysts is a critical challenge for improving the efficiency of the water electrolysis technology. Thus, strategies for designing prominent catalyst materials have drawn considerable attention. Our group has been conducting research aimed at establishing comprehensive design strategies for the rational and rapid development of highly active catalysts. In this Personal Account, we present our research efforts on enhancing the activity of cost&#8208;efficient nonprecious metal&#8208;based oxide catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction at the anode of water electrolysis. Specifically, we propose design strategies based on crystal structures of multimetal oxides and demonstrate how these strategies have contributed to the development of highly active electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuuki Sugawara, Takeo Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances and challenges in single-atom catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100553</link>
      <description>Wei Xia, Jinyang Zhang, Guangyu Xu, Ting Jin, Qing&#8208;Lun Wang, Lifang Jiao, Next Materials. 8(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407763613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Xia, Jinyang Zhang, Guangyu Xu, Ting Jin, Qing&#8208;Lun Wang, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Localized s electrons promote the hydrogen evolution catalysis of kagome metal Ag5Pb2O6</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.215</link>
      <description>Xiaohui Xu, Jun-Long Zhou, Chang&#8208;Chun Ding, Mengxin Wu, Min-Quan Kuang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 110(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4407670208

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaohui Xu, Jun-Long Zhou, Chang&#8208;Chun Ding, Mengxin Wu, Min-Quan Kuang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent developments in the use of machine learning in catalysis: A broad perspective with applications in kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160872</link>
      <description>Leandro Goulart de Araujo, L&#233;a Vilcocq, Pascal Fongarland, Y. Schuurman, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407761664

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leandro Goulart de Araujo, L&#233;a Vilcocq, Pascal Fongarland, Y. Schuurman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160872</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
