<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:43:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in the development of copper oxide-based materials for electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.377</link>
      <description>Muhammad Sajid, Wajeeha Qayyum, Ahmed Jadah Farhan, Muhammad Azam Qamar, Haq Nawaz, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392678378

                Carbon-containing fuels, major energy sources, pose environmental challenges with their greenhouse gas emissions. Addressing the imperative for clean energy in our industrialized era, copper oxide emerges as a viable electrocatalyst for hydrogen production through water splitting, offering an eco-friendly alternative to precious metals. Electrolytic water splitting using copper oxide proves highly efficient, ensuring rapid and uncontaminated hydrogen production. Researchers globally are actively pursuing economically viable implementations of this process. This study exclusively focuses on CuO-based nanostructures, exploring their role as efficient electrocatalysts in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). It investigates various environmentally friendly synthesis methods and analyzes the crystal structure of copper oxide under different parameters. Assessing CuO-based catalyst activity in OER and HER under diverse conditions, the study provides a comprehensive overview of their electrocatalytic performance in water splitting. Integrating this knowledge with catalyst developments holds promise for advancing sustainable hydrogen production. The study concludes by discussing future research aspects and pinpointing gaps to guide the development of cost-effective and efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Sajid, Wajeeha Qayyum, Ahmed Jadah Farhan, Muhammad Azam Qamar, Haq Nawaz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling the Collision Type and Frequency of Single Pt Nanoparticles at Chemically Modified Gold Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.3c04668</link>
      <description>Audrey Pumford, Raymond P. White, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392701778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Audrey Pumford, Raymond P. White</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.3c04668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Local and Directional Aspects of Catalytic Active Sites by the Nuclear and Surface Electrostatic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08512</link>
      <description>Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392701786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesizing Pd-based high entropy alloy nanoclusters for enhanced oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc00247d</link>
      <description>Fan Zhang, Shiwei Sun, Xiao Ge, Qingxin Guan, Miao Ling, Weiyong Yuan, Lian Ying Zhang, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392702081

                We report the synthesis of uniform Pd-based HEA clusters on an XC-72 carbon support using a rapid Joule heating method. The quinary PdMnFeCuNi clusters exhibit outstanding stability and 4.95 times higher mass activity than the Com Pt/C for the ORR.</description>
      <author>Fan Zhang, Shiwei Sun, Xiao Ge, Qingxin Guan, Miao Ling, Weiyong Yuan, Lian Ying Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc00247d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Oxygen Vacancy Site Mechanism of a Self-Assembly Hybrid Catalyst for Efficient Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05789</link>
      <description>Xinshui Lei, Jiang Chang, Qingjun Han, Xiao&#8208;Xin Zhang, Kai Zhao, Ning Yan, Haoxu Guo, Bing Tang, Yifan Li, Yi Cui, Shuhui Yu, Jianhui Li, Yanping Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392704093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinshui Lei, Jiang Chang, Qingjun Han, Xiao&#8208;Xin Zhang, Kai Zhao, Ning Yan, Haoxu Guo, Bing Tang, Yifan Li, Yi Cui, Shuhui Yu, Jianhui Li, Yanping Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and first-principles insights into an enhanced performance of Ru-doped copper phosphate electrocatalyst during oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sajce.2024.03.006</link>
      <description>Jasmin S. Shaikh, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Victor M&#225;rquez, Navajsharif S. Shaikh, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Sumayya C. Pathan, Mohammad Khaja Nazeeruddin, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, South African Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392713728

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jasmin S. Shaikh, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Victor M&#225;rquez, Navajsharif S. Shaikh, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Sumayya C. Pathan, Mohammad Khaja Nazeeruddin, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sajce.2024.03.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen doped leather waste-derived carbon materials as electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112295</link>
      <description>Afshin Abbasi, Musammir Khan, Fawad Ahmad, Muhammad Imran Khan, Abdallah Shanableh, R. P. S. Rajput, Suryyia Manzoor, Shabnam Shahida, Rafael Luque, Sameh M. Osman, Mushtaq Hussain Lashari, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392715055

                Nitrogen doped leather waste-derived carbon materials have been employed as eletrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction. Low current densities and complex synthesis routes of other carbon-based materials limit their practical applicability. We present herein a simple and cost-competitive design of a metal free nitrogen-doped carbon matrix (NCM). At 10 mA cm&#8722;2 of current density, the assembled NCM showed a low over potential of 330 mV. NCM provided 73 mV dec-1 of slope value according to Tafel analysis, with NCM slope value improved as compared to previously described electrocatalysts inclusive of graphene (113 mV dec&#8722;1) and carbon nanosheets (101 mV dec&#8722;1), under similar reaction conditions. Linear sweep voltamogram, stability test and electrochemical impedance spectra confirmed the potential of NCM in OER as a heterogeneous electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Afshin Abbasi, Musammir Khan, Fawad Ahmad, Muhammad Imran Khan, Abdallah Shanableh, R. P. S. Rajput, Suryyia Manzoor, Shabnam Shahida, Rafael Luque, Sameh M. Osman, Mushtaq Hussain Lashari</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic electronic structure modulation of Pt using V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; and V&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; for enhanced deuterium evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00150h</link>
      <description>Yanfeng Li, Shuofeng Yuan, Liangbin Shao, Yuanan Li, Wei Xu, Shijie Zhang, Fangjun Shao, Jianguo Wang, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392718810

                Synergistic electronic metal&#8211;support interaction between V 2 O 3 /V 8 C 7 and Pt realizes the development of a high-performance deuterium evolution catalyst.</description>
      <author>Yanfeng Li, Shuofeng Yuan, Liangbin Shao, Yuanan Li, Wei Xu, Shijie Zhang, Fangjun Shao, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00150h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remotely Controlled Electrochemical Degradation of Metallic Implants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202307742</link>
      <description>B. B. Rivkin, Farzin Akbar, Martin Otto, Lukas Beyer, Birgit Paul, Konrad Kosiba, Tobias Gustmann, J. Hufenbach, Mariana Medina&#8208;S&#225;nchez, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392732478

                Abstract Biodegradable medical implants promise to benefit patients by eliminating risks and discomfort associated with permanent implantation or surgical removal. The time until full resorption is largely determined by the implant's material composition, geometric design, and surface properties. Implants with a fixed residence time, however, cannot account for the needs of individual patients, thereby imposing limits on personalization. Here, an active Fe&#8208;based implant system is reported whose biodegradation is controlled remotely and in situ. This is achieved by incorporating a galvanic cell within the implant. An external and wireless signal is used to activate the on&#8208;board electronic circuit that controls the corrosion current between the implant body and an integrated counter electrode. This configuration leads to the accelerated degradation of the implant and allows to harvest electrochemical energy that is naturally released by corrosion. In this study, the electrochemical properties of the Fe&#8208;30Mn&#8208;1C/Pt galvanic cell model system is first investigated and high&#8208;resolution X&#8208;ray microcomputed tomography is used to evaluate the galvanic degradation of stent structures. Subsequently, a centimeter&#8208;sized active implant prototype is assembled with conventional electronic components and the remotely controlled corrosion is tested in vitro. Furthermore, strategies toward the miniaturization and full biodegradability of this system are presented.</description>
      <author>B. B. Rivkin, Farzin Akbar, Martin Otto, Lukas Beyer, Birgit Paul, Konrad Kosiba, Tobias Gustmann, J. Hufenbach, Mariana Medina&#8208;S&#225;nchez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202307742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UV&#8208;Induced Synthesis of Graphene Supported Iridium Catalyst with Multiple Active Sites for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202313530</link>
      <description>Liang Xu, Jianyun Cao, Jiexin Chen, Yongxu Zhu, Hua Xia, Zifan Xu, Chengding Gu, Jiyang Xie, M. Jones, Cheng Liu, Joel C. Corbin, Xiaohong Li, Wanbiao Hu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392732588

                Abstract Catalysts that can promote the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are in demand for efficient water splitting. Here, a general and practical UV&#8208;induced synthesis of noble metal catalysts supported on reduced electrochemical graphene oxide (M&#8208;rEGO, M = Ir, Pt or Pd) is proposed. The use of EGO with a low degree of oxidation and the generation of the highly reducing isopropanol radical from added isopropanol and acetone are crucial for this one&#8208;step, one&#8208;pot synthesis. Using Ir as a model material, the vacancies of rEGO allow the interaction of undercoordinated C with Ir, forming multiple active Ir species including single atoms (SAs), dual&#8208;atom pairs (DAs) and nanoparticles. This Ir&#8208;rEGO catalyst exhibits overpotentials of only 42.3 and 294 mV to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 &#1084; H 2 SO 4 for HER and 1 &#1084; KOH for OER, respectively, at an extremely low Ir loading (2.1 wt%). The water&#8208;splitting cells featuring Ir&#8208;rEGO catalyst outperform those using commercial Pt/C (20 wt%) and RuO 2 catalysts in both acidic and alkaline electrolytes. Density functional theory calculations confirm the stabilization of SAs and DAs at the vacancies of graphene lattice as well as the high activity of DAs in both HER and OER.</description>
      <author>Liang Xu, Jianyun Cao, Jiexin Chen, Yongxu Zhu, Hua Xia, Zifan Xu, Chengding Gu, Jiyang Xie, M. Jones, Cheng Liu, Joel C. Corbin, Xiaohong Li, Wanbiao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202313530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt molybdenum di-selenide surface modification: A path to improved trifunctional catalysis via partial oxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159834</link>
      <description>Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Applied Surface Science. 658(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392737749

                Efficient, stable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, and oxygen reduction reactions have been in demand for decades. Recently, layered transition metals (Co, Mo, Ni, and Fe) and chalcogen compounds (S/Se/Te) gained prominence in catalysis and device studies. Density functional theory identified the covalency of Co and Mo, oxygenated bimetallic selenium bond, crystal structure distortions, and adsorption properties as crucial for enhanced electrocatalytic activity. Hybridizing the Co and Mo d-orbitals around the Fermi level of 0.463 eV improves bonding with metal surface-adsorbate intermediates validated by partial density of states. Oxygenated cobalt molybdenum selenide (O-CoMoSe2) (2 1 0) exhibited remarkable electrocatalytic properties at various active sites, with Gibbs free energy and theoretical overpotential at an active site of Co = 0.086 eV, 0.41 V, and Se = 0.50 V.</description>
      <author>Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine&#8208;tuning electronic structure of N&#8208;doped graphitic carbon&#8208;supported Co&#8208; and Fe&#8208;incorporated Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C to achieve ultrahigh electrochemical water oxidation activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.488</link>
      <description>Md. Selim Arif Sher Shah, Hyeonjung Jung, Vinod K. Paidi, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Jeong Woo Han, Jae Hyung Park, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392740367

                Abstract Mo 2 C is an excellent electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, Mo 2 C is a poor electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, two different elements, namely Co and Fe, are incorporated in Mo 2 C that, therefore, has a finely tuned electronic structure, which is not achievable by incorporation of any one of the metals. Consequently, the resulting electrocatalyst Co 0.8 Fe 0.2 &#8211;Mo 2 C&#8208;80 displayed excellent OER catalytic performance, which is evidenced by a low overpotential of 214.0 (and 246.5) mV to attain a current density of 10 (and 50) mA cm &#8722;2 , an ultralow Tafel slope of 38.4 mV dec &#8722;1 , and long&#8208;term stability in alkaline medium. Theoretical data demonstrates that Co 0.8 Fe 0.2 &#8211;Mo 2 C&#8208;80 requires the lowest overpotential (1.00 V) for OER and Co centers to be the active sites. The ultrahigh catalytic performance of the electrocatalyst is attributed to the excellent intrinsic catalytic activity due to high Brunauer&#8211;Emmett&#8211;Teller specific surface area, large electrochemically active surface area, small Tafel slope, and low charge&#8208;transfer resistance.</description>
      <author>Md. Selim Arif Sher Shah, Hyeonjung Jung, Vinod K. Paidi, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Jeong Woo Han, Jae Hyung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress of electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215758</link>
      <description>Yuping Chen, Chunyan Shang, Xin Xiao, Weihua Guo, Qiang Xu, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 508(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392743186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuping Chen, Chunyan Shang, Xin Xiao, Weihua Guo, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect engineering in two-dimensional Janus pentagonal noble metal sulfide MXY (M=Pd, Pt; X, Y S, Se, Te; X&#8800;Y) materials for highly efficient electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.338</link>
      <description>Jinbo Hao, Yirong Ma, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Chunyu Zhang, Ge Wu, Wen Chen, Yuanzi Li, Pengfei Lu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392743218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinbo Hao, Yirong Ma, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Chunyu Zhang, Ge Wu, Wen Chen, Yuanzi Li, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Sustainable Lattice Strains of Morphology-Tuned Nanowires in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00451</link>
      <description>Zhi Hui Kong, Zhi Peng Wu, Yazan Maswadeh, Gang Yu, Jorge Vargas, Dominic Caracciolo, Valeri Petkov, Shuang&#8208;Quan Zang, Tao Li, Shuangyin Wang, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392748981

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhi Hui Kong, Zhi Peng Wu, Yazan Maswadeh, Gang Yu, Jorge Vargas, Dominic Caracciolo, Valeri Petkov, Shuang&#8208;Quan Zang, Tao Li, Shuangyin Wang, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO Hydrogenation Promoted by Oxygen Atoms Adsorbed onto Cu(100)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00666</link>
      <description>Kaito Nagita, Kazuhide Kamiya, Shuji Nakanishi, Yoshisuke Hamamoto, Yoshitada Morikawa, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392752465

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) on Cu-based catalysts is a promising method for converting anthropogenic CO2 to valuable chemical feedstocks and fuels. Although pure CO2 gas has been widely used as a reactant in CO2RR-related research, CO2 gas collected from the atmosphere inevitably includes some amount of various impurity gases in the actual application of this method. Among such impurities, O2 gas has high reactivity and can easily contaminate the reaction environment, thereby substantially affecting the reactivity of the CO2RR. Herein, we performed first-principles calculations for the CO2RR in the presence of O2 reduction reaction intermediates on the Cu(100) surface. Specifically, we calculated the reaction and activation free energies for the hydrogenation of adsorbed CO* to CHO* on a Cu(100) surface covered with O* or OH*. When the coverage of O* reached 25%, the initial state of CO hydrogenation became destabilized to a greater extent than the transition state, which decreased the reaction and activation free energies by 0.27 and 0.16 eV, respectively. The projected density of states analyses revealed that O* weakens the interaction between CO* and the Cu surface, whereas OH* less strongly affects CO hydrogenation.</description>
      <author>Kaito Nagita, Kazuhide Kamiya, Shuji Nakanishi, Yoshisuke Hamamoto, Yoshitada Morikawa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion-Limited Crystal Growth of Gallium Nitride Using Active Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.3c01504</link>
      <description>Xiangyu Chen, Nam Q. Le, Paulette Clancy, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392760776

                Gallium nitride (GaN) is an important semiconductor with properties that make it particularly suitable for high-temperature applications in power systems. Unfortunately, its crystalline synthesis involves an energy-intensive process requiring high temperatures and pressures. A new additive manufacturing process offers a lower-temperature alternative, but little is understood of the molecular-scale mechanisms that drive its crystallization from the melt. Traditional semiempirical force fields within a molecular dynamics (MD) simulation are typically unable to capture bond-making and -breaking, whereas ab initio MD, while more accurate, suffers from high computational expense. This paper uses a machine-learned force field based on the FLARE++ framework to mimic the liquid-phase epitaxy of GaN, simulating the diffusion of nitrogen atoms through liquid gallium to form GaN. We show that nitrogen diffusion through Ga is slow, and relatedly, there is a pronounced tendency for nitrogen to phase-segregate within liquid Ga. This leads to nitrogen being less available to react and form crystalline GaN. As a result, the predicted crystal growth at the melt/crystal interface is extremely slow, as seen experimentally. In this work, we demonstrate the potential of a MLFF to describe complex, multiphase behavior under different conditions. We also uncover the key atomistic-level mechanism of diffusion-limited GaN crystal growth, which is an important step toward further control of the additive manufacturing process.</description>
      <author>Xiangyu Chen, Nam Q. Le, Paulette Clancy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.3c01504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilizing Ultralow Loading Platinum Nanoparticles onto MXene through Defect Engineering to Enhance the Activity of the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03270</link>
      <description>Meng Xu, Jiahao Huang, Xin Yue, Shaoming Huang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763100

                Developing low-cost, highly active, and durable electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acidic medium is essential for achieving the large-scale utilization of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers. It has been demonstrated that non-precious-metal electrocatalysts are unable to substitute the most efficient platinum in a short period. Consequently, the fabrication of Pt-based heterogeneous electrocatalysts with ultralow loading and ultrahigh Pt utilization efficiency becomes a practical approach. Herein, an approach is reported to immobilize ultralow loading (&#8764;0.26 wt %) Pt NPs to Mo vacancies on the surface of Mo2Ti2C3Tx MXene. Because of the anchoring by Mo vacancies and the vast surface area of MXene, defect enriched Mo2Ti2C3Tx supported Pt nanoparticles (Pt NPs/d-Mo2Ti2C3Tx) possess ultrasmall particle sizes (&#8764;2.1 nm) and increased dispersity of Pt NPs. As a result, the as-prepared Pt NPs/d-Mo2Ti2C3Tx reaches a current density 100 mA cm&#8211;2 at an overpotential of 123 mV. When compared to Pt/C (20 wt %), the mass activity of Pt on Pt NPs/d-Mo2Ti2C3Tx is found to be 134 times higher. Meanwhile, it presents a high turnover frequency (8.49 H2 s&#8211;1 at overpotential of 50 mV) and fast kinetics (a Tafel slope of 30.1 mV dec&#8211;1) as well as high durability (maintaining the current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2 for more than 15 h). Theoretical simulations reveal that transferring electrons from Mo atoms regulated the d-band electronic structure of Pt NPs, resulting in a stronger interaction with adsorbed H species and ultimately boosting the HER activity.</description>
      <author>Meng Xu, Jiahao Huang, Xin Yue, Shaoming Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Spin-Valence States of Vanadium-Based Single-Atom Oxygen Reduction Catalysts through Substrate and Axial Ligand Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03756</link>
      <description>Jessie Manopo, Yudi Darma, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763690

                We study the effect of different carbon-based oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts on which atomically dispersed vanadium is anchored: graphene and graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4), by means of density functional theory. We found that different substrates and axial ligands modulate the spin and valence states of the vanadium metal center, thus modifying the catalytic activity. We observed that the magnetic moments of the metal center are related to the number of available electrons to be transferred from the catalyst to the adsorbate. The bare V-N4-graphene active site prefers a dissociative ORR mechanism due to strong binding between the vanadium metal center to oxygen-containing intermediates, and thus the OOH intermediate cannot be stably adsorbed. After the adsorption of the &#8211;OH ligand, the number of available electrons in the vanadium metal center is decreased, thus enhancing the ORR activity and shifting the ORR overpotential to 0.34 V, and the active site may prefer an associative mechanism. However, the magnetic moment of the catalysts is not the only factor affecting the adsorption behavior of the catalyst. Population analysis shows V-N4-graphene active site has the same number of available electrons in the d orbital of the vanadium metal center as the OH-V-g-C3N4. However, the V-N4-graphene active site exhibits stronger binding to oxygen-containing intermediates compared to OH-V-g-C3N4. We found that the valence states of the catalysts also affect the catalytic activity of the catalyst. The availability of an occupied dz2 orbital in the V-N4-graphene active site makes it have a stronger interaction with oxygen-containing intermediates compared to OH-V-g-C3N4. These combined effects lead to a spin-valence synergistic effect. These findings can pave the way to the design of better catalysts for efficient ORR in the future.</description>
      <author>Jessie Manopo, Yudi Darma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Inner- and Outer-Sphere Mechanistic Pathways of ORR on M&#8211;N&#8211;Cs with Pyrrolic MN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Motifs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00299</link>
      <description>Jian Liang Low, Christina Roth, Beate Paulus, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763821

                Metal- and nitrogen-doped carbon materials (M&#8211;N&#8211;Cs) have emerged as promising alternatives to costly platinum-group metals (PGMs) for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in renewable energy applications. Notably, there is increasing experimental and theoretical evidence supporting pyrrolic MN4 coordination over pyridinic MN4 in these materials, which aligns closer to the MN4 geometries found in nature. This study utilizes density functional theory (DFT) to elucidate the ability of each metal to catalyze various ORR mechanisms at the pyrrolic MN4 sites. Among the M&#8211;N&#8211;Cs of first&#8211;row transition metals, pyrrolic CrN4 and FeN4 exhibit exceptional 4e-ORR activity, promoting both inner- and outer-sphere mechanisms and H2O2 dissociation. Pyrrolic CoN4 is also promising for 2e-ORR catalysis due to its effective outer-sphere electron-transfer capabilities. These findings offer valuable insights for designing sustainable electrocatalysts to exploit the full potential of renewable energy sources, advancing the path toward carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Jian Liang Low, Christina Roth, Beate Paulus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structured Catalysts and Catalytic Processes: Transport and Reaction Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00081</link>
      <description>Pei Chen, Sai Chen, Donglong Fu, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763930

                The structure of catalysts determines the performance of catalytic processes. Intrinsically, the electronic and geometric structures influence the interaction between active species and the surface of the catalyst, which subsequently regulates the adsorption, reaction, and desorption behaviors. In recent decades, the development of catalysts with complex structures, including bulk, interfacial, encapsulated, and atomically dispersed structures, can potentially affect the electronic and geometric structures of catalysts and lead to further control of the transport and reaction of molecules. This review describes comprehensive understandings on the influence of electronic and geometric properties and complex catalyst structures on the performance of relevant heterogeneous catalytic processes, especially for the transport and reaction over structured catalysts for the conversions of light alkanes and small molecules. The recent research progress of the electronic and geometric properties over the active sites, specifically for theoretical descriptors developed in the recent decades, is discussed at the atomic level. The designs and properties of catalysts with specific structures are summarized. The transport phenomena and reactions over structured catalysts for the conversions of light alkanes and small molecules are analyzed. At the end of this review, we present our perspectives on the challenges for the further development of structured catalysts and heterogeneous catalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Pei Chen, Sai Chen, Donglong Fu, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Structural Optimization through Fingerprinting Space Integration on the Potential Energy Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00275</link>
      <description>Shuo Tao, Xuecheng Shao, Li Zhu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763962

                Structural optimization has been a crucial component in computational materials research, and structure predictions have relied heavily on this technique, in particular. In this study, we introduce a novel method that enhances the efficiency of local optimization by integrating extra fingerprint space into the optimization process. Our approach utilizes a mixed energy concept in the hyper potential energy surface (PES), combining real energy and a newly introduced fingerprint energy derived from the symmetry of the local atomic environment. This method strategically guides the optimization process toward high-symmetry, low-energy structures by leveraging the intrinsic symmetry of the atomic configurations. The effectiveness of our approach was demonstrated through structural optimizations of silicon, silicon carbide, and Lennard-Jones cluster systems. Our results show that the fingerprint space biasing technique significantly enhances the performance and probability of discovering energetically favorable, high-symmetry structures as compared to conventional optimizations. The proposed method is anticipated to streamline the search for new materials and facilitate the discovery of novel energetically favorable configurations.</description>
      <author>Shuo Tao, Xuecheng Shao, Li Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare earth modified carbon-based catalysts for oxygen electrode reactions: A machine learning assisted density functional theory investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119045</link>
      <description>Qiming Fu, Tao Xu, Daomiao Wang, Chao Liu, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392768636

                The oxygen electrode reactions (oxygen reduction reaction, ORR and oxygen evolution reaction, OER) are two key reactions in applications such as metal-air batteries, however, slow kinetics have a significant impact on the overall reaction efficiency of the batteries, thus emphasizing the profound significance of catalyst development. In this study, we systematically investigated the catalytic activity of rare-earth-doped graphene (RENxC4-x) as electrocatalysts using a combination of density functional theory (DFT) and machine learning (ML). Furthermore, we successfully screened and identified one ORR catalyst, four OER catalysts, and one bifunctional electrocatalyst from candidate materials. The origins of activity were elucidated in two dimensions using the SHAP (SHapley Additive exPlanation) analysis framework and DFT calculations, revealing that atomic/covalent radius and &#916;G*OH are an important characteristics for describing ORR electrocatalysts, while Pauling electronegativity is crucial for describing OER. Finally, the explicit relationship expression between properties and activity was obtained using the SISSO method, and its generalizability was verified. The interdisciplinary approach of DFT-ML provides insights into the complex origins of activity, offering a new pathway for the discovery and design of high-performance single-atom catalysts (SACs).</description>
      <author>Qiming Fu, Tao Xu, Daomiao Wang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting chemisorption strength with AutoML-based feature deletion experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2320232121</link>
      <description>Zhuo Li, Chenguang Zhao, Hai-Kun Wang, Yanqing Ding, Y Chen, Philippe Schwaller, Kai Yang, Hua Cheng, Yulian He, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392779374

                The chemisorption energy of reactants on a catalyst surface,   E  ads    , is among the most informative characteristics of understanding and pinpointing the optimal catalyst. The intrinsic complexity of catalyst surfaces and chemisorption reactions presents significant difficulties in identifying the pivotal physical quantities determining   E  ads    . In response to this, the study proposes a methodology, the feature deletion experiment, based on Automatic Machine Learning (AutoML) for knowledge extraction from a high-throughput density functional theory (DFT) database. The study reveals that, for binary alloy surfaces, the local adsorption site geometric information is the primary physical quantity determining   E  ads    , compared to the electronic and physiochemical properties of the catalyst alloys. By integrating the feature deletion experiment with instance-wise variable selection (INVASE), a neural network-based explainable AI (XAI) tool, we established the best-performing feature set containing 21 intrinsic, non-DFT computed properties, achieving an MAE of 0.23 eV across a periodic table-wide chemical space involving more than 1,600 types of alloys surfaces and 8,400 chemisorption reactions. This study demonstrates the stability, consistency, and potential of AutoML-based feature deletion experiment in developing concise, predictive, and theoretically meaningful models for complex chemical problems with minimal human intervention.</description>
      <author>Zhuo Li, Chenguang Zhao, Hai-Kun Wang, Yanqing Ding, Y Chen, Philippe Schwaller, Kai Yang, Hua Cheng, Yulian He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2320232121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDEP: Temperature Dependent Effective Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.06150</link>
      <description>Florian Knoop, Nina Shulumba, Alo&#239;s Castellano, Jos&#233; Batista, Roberta Farris, Matthieu J. Verstraete, Matthew Heine, David Broido, Dennis Kim, Johan Klarbring, Igor A. Abrikosov, Sergei I. Simak, Olle Hellman, Journal of open source software. 9(94)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392787419

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Florian Knoop, Nina Shulumba, Alo&#239;s Castellano, Jos&#233; Batista, Roberta Farris, Matthieu J. Verstraete, Matthew Heine, David Broido, Dennis Kim, Johan Klarbring, Igor A. Abrikosov, Sergei I. Simak, Olle Hellman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.06150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repulsive Lateral Interaction of Water Molecules at the Initial Stages of Adsorption in Microporous AlPO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-11 According to &lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;Al NMR and DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03969</link>
      <description>Ilya V. Yakovlev, A. A. Shubin, Evgeniy Papulovskiy, Alexander V. Toktarev, Olga B. Lapina, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392760814

                Lateral (adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate) interactions between adsorbed molecules affect various physical and chemical properties of microporous adsorbents and catalysts, influencing their functional properties. In this work, we studied the hydration of microporous AlPO4-11 aluminophosphate, which has an unusually ordered structure upon adsorption of water vapor, and according to 27Al NMR data, only tetrahedrally or octahedrally coordinated Al sites are present in the AlPO4-11. These 27Al NMR data are consistent with the results of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of hydrated AlPO4-11, which revealed the presence of a strong repulsive lateral interaction at the initial stage of adsorption, suppressing the adsorption of water on neighboring (separated by one &#8722;O&#8211;P&#8211;O&#8211; bridge) Al crystallographic sites. As a result, of all the different aluminum sites, only half of the Al1 sites adsorb two water molecules and acquire octahedral coordination.</description>
      <author>Ilya V. Yakovlev, A. A. Shubin, Evgeniy Papulovskiy, Alexander V. Toktarev, Olga B. Lapina</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03969</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
