<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 01:41:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Activity and Stability of Ba0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3-&#948; Cathode by Surface Engineering with SrCoO3-&#948; Nanoparticles in Protonic Ceramic Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.08.038</link>
      <description>Chenxiao Wang, Guangjun Zhang, Qiang Xue, Xiaoyu Zhang, Ting Chen, Lang Xu, Shaorong Wang, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413053103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenxiao Wang, Guangjun Zhang, Qiang Xue, Xiaoyu Zhang, Ting Chen, Lang Xu, Shaorong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.08.038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field-Driven Interface Hydroxylation via the Vibrational Stark Effect Boosts Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00585</link>
      <description>Xiayan Yao, Jianwei Guo, Zhi Wang, Guoyu Qian, X.P. Wang, Dong Wang, Xuzhong Gong, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413052677

                Tuning interfacial water structures is a fundamental yet underexplored strategy for advancing the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and broader electrocatalytic processes. Here, we demonstrate a universal and scalable catalytic optimization strategy via the magnetic field-driven reconfiguration of interfacial water at the molecular level. Unlike conventional magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) strategies focusing on mass transport, this work pioneers a molecular-level interfacial water structure modulation via the vibrational Stark effect (VSE), achieving intrinsic catalytic enhancement for HER. In situ Raman spectroscopy and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations reveal that the permanent magnetic field-induced amplification of the DDAA configuration population is governed by the VSE, leading to a restructured interfacial weak hydrogen bond (HB) network and enhanced charge transfer kinetics. As a result, under a 1 T permanent magnetic field and a controlled flow rate of 100 mL/min, the HER overpotential is reduced by 50 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2, with stable performance sustained for over 10 h, a level of enhancement far exceeding previous magnetic field-assisted HER studies. Beyond HER, this strategy offers a generalizable approach for tuning interfacial water structures, which could be extended to other electrocatalytic reactions, where HB networks and interfacial water structuring play a critical role. As a result, the overpotential was reduced by 50 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2, and a 15.40% increase in current density was achieved under industrial alkaline electrolysis conditions, demonstrating clear advantages over existing magnetic field-assisted HER strategies. This study provided a scalable, molecular-level catalytic interface engineering approach, offering valuable insights into advanced electrocatalytic processes and significant potential for industrial hydrogen production technologies.</description>
      <author>Xiayan Yao, Jianwei Guo, Zhi Wang, Guoyu Qian, X.P. Wang, Dong Wang, Xuzhong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling d-band synergy in anti-sandwich dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction: High-throughput DFT screening and machine learning insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164256</link>
      <description>Wentao Liang, Wenjun Xiao, Linxing Meng, Jinshun Bi, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xiaofeng Rong, Degui Wang, Xuefei Liu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413052776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wentao Liang, Wenjun Xiao, Linxing Meng, Jinshun Bi, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xiaofeng Rong, Degui Wang, Xuefei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cycloaddition of CO2 to epoxides catalyzed by homogeneous metalorganic complexes under ambient conditions: an update</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2025.123799</link>
      <description>Suthida Kaewsai, Valerio D&#8217;Elia, Journal of Organometallic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413053188

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suthida Kaewsai, Valerio D&#8217;Elia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2025.123799</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Metal&#8211;Support Interaction Dictates Cu Nanoparticle Sintering on Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c04622</link>
      <description>Jiayan Xu, Shreeja Das, Amar Deep Pathak, A. K. Patra, Sharan Shetty, Detlef Hohl, Roberto Car, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413054382

                Nanoparticle sintering remains a critical challenge in heterogeneous catalysis. In this work, we present a unified deep potential (DP) model based on the Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof approximation of density functional theory for Cu nanoparticles on three Al2O3 surfaces (&#947;-Al2O3(100), &#947;-Al2O3(110), and &#945;-Al2O3(0001)). Using DP-accelerated simulations, we reveal that the nanoparticle size-mobility relationship strongly depends on the supporting surface. The diffusion of nanoparticles on the two &#947;-Al2O3 surfaces is almost independent of the size of the nanoparticle, while the diffusion on &#945;-Al2O3(0001) decreases rapidly with increasing size. Interestingly, nanoparticles with fewer than 55 atoms diffuse several times faster on &#945;-Al2O3(0001) than on &#947;-Al2O3(100) at 800 K while expected to be more sluggish based on their larger binding energy at 0 K. The diffusion on &#945;-Al2O3(0001) is facilitated by dynamic metal-support interaction (MSI), where Al atoms move out of the surface plane to optimize contact with the nanoparticle and relax back to the plane as the nanoparticle moves away. In contrast, the MSI on &#947;-Al2O3(100) and on &#947;-Al2O3(110) is dominated by more stable and directional Cu-O bonds, consistent with the limited diffusion observed on these surfaces. Our extended MD simulations provide insight into the sintering processes, showing that the dispersity of the nanoparticles strongly influences the coalescence driven by nanoparticle diffusion. We observed that the coalescence of Cu13 nanoparticles on &#945;-Al2O3(0001) can occur in a short time (10 ns) at 800 K even with an initial internanoparticle distance increased to 3 nm, while the coalescence on the two &#947;-Al2O3 surfaces are inhibited significantly by increasing the initial internanoparticle distance. These findings demonstrate that the dynamics of the supporting surface is crucial to understanding the sintering mechanism and offer guidance for designing sinter-resistant catalysts by engineering the support morphology.</description>
      <author>Jiayan Xu, Shreeja Das, Amar Deep Pathak, A. K. Patra, Sharan Shetty, Detlef Hohl, Roberto Car</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c04622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training a Machine Learned Potential on the Cerebras Wafer Scale Engine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3708035.3736081</link>
      <description>Dana O&#8217;Connor, Wissam A. Saidi, Paola A. Buitrago, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413059244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dana O&#8217;Connor, Wissam A. Saidi, Paola A. Buitrago</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1145/3708035.3736081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semiempirical and interpretable machine learning of the oxygen interaction barriers in thousands of the two-dimensional materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1140/epjb/s10051-025-01001-5</link>
      <description>Raphael M. Tromer, The European Physical Journal B. 98(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413064406

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Raphael M. Tromer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1140/epjb/s10051-025-01001-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Literature-Based Machine Learning Framework for Yield Prediction in Cyclohexene Epoxidation: Toward a Digital Catalyst Concept</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5355788</link>
      <description>Alfonso Enrique Ram&#237;rez Sanabria, Fabian Ramirez, Juli&#225;n Mu&#241;oz-Ord&#243;&#241;ez, Cristian Mu&#241;oz, Nelson J. Castellanos, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413075752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alfonso Enrique Ram&#237;rez Sanabria, Fabian Ramirez, Juli&#225;n Mu&#241;oz-Ord&#243;&#241;ez, Cristian Mu&#241;oz, Nelson J. Castellanos</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5355788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core&#8208;Shell Structured V&#8208;Doped CoPx@FeOOH for Efficient Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500850</link>
      <description>Gai Li, Yanhui Yu, Chongtai Wang, Daoxiong Wu, Yingjie Hua, Peng Rao, Xinlong Tian, Jing Li, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413078233

                Abstract As a renewable energy conversion method, the hydrogen from seawater electrolysis needs to overcome problems such as chlorination reaction and corrosion resistance. Considering these questions, it is vital to design a highly efficient and corrosion&#8208;resistant catalyst. Here, we developed a vanadium&#8208;doped cobalt phosphide encapsulated within an iron oxyhydroxide shell (V&#8208;CoPx@FeOOH) as an efficient core&#8208;shell electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in seawater electrolytes. In particular, the OER overpotential of the V&#8208;CoPx@FeOOH catalyst at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 was 270 mV. Notably, V&#8208;CoPx||V&#8208;CoPx@FeOOH was able to operate in alkaline seawater at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for more than 1000 h, showing excellent stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that the enhanced HER activity is attributed to the introduction of V, which strengthens the bonding between Co sites and H atoms, and the optimized OER activity results from the presence of both V and Fe, which together optimize the bonding strength between Co sites and OOH intermediates. The highly efficient catalyst of the core&#8208;shell structure has great prospects for overall water/seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Gai Li, Yanhui Yu, Chongtai Wang, Daoxiong Wu, Yingjie Hua, Peng Rao, Xinlong Tian, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production via 2e&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; ORR on Alkalinized Tubular C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; from Melamine Waste Integrating with Fenton Wastewater Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.5c00228</link>
      <description>Hongyu Song, Huijing Ma, Haifei Wang, Yichan Wen, Chengcheng Cai, Jiyi Sun, Xufang Qian, Yixin Zhao, ACS Sustainable Resource Management. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413084227

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongyu Song, Huijing Ma, Haifei Wang, Yichan Wen, Chengcheng Cai, Jiyi Sun, Xufang Qian, Yixin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.5c00228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton&#8208;Driven Multistage System Enables Selective Recovery of Gold and Palladium from Electronic Waste Leachate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70085</link>
      <description>Ziwen Chang, Yingying Zhou, Penghui Shao, Liming Yang, Bo Li, Dewei Li, Lingrong Zeng, Yi Gong, Xubiao Luo, Shenglian Luo, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413084471

                Selective extraction of precious metals from urban mines plays a crucial role in mitigating the risk of depletion of precious metal resources and reducing waste pollution. However, a major obstacle in precious metal extraction lies in the difficulty of distinguishing the subtle differences in the physicochemical characteristics between them, especially gold and palladium. Herein, a proton&#8208;driven separation system was presented for cascade recovery of gold and palladium from waste&#8208;printed circuit boards (W&#8208;PCBs) leachate using poly(amidoxime) (PAO) hydrogel. This exhibits an ultra&#8208;high capacity, extra&#8208;fast rate, and excellent selectivity for the extraction of Au(III) and Pd(II). Notably, the separation of Au(III) and Pd(II) can be achieved with high selectivity at pH = 0, resulting in a remarkable separation factor of k Au(III)/Pd(II) = 36.5. This was demonstrated to originate from the differential mechanism of PAO hydrogel for the capture of Au(III) and Pd(II) under proton&#8208;mediated conditions. Drawing inspiration from the mechanism, the proton&#8208;driven cascade recovery system demonstrates remarkable efficiency in sequentially recovering 99.92% of gold and 99.05% of palladium from W&#8208;PCBs acid leachate. This research opens up a strategy to precisely separate and recover precious metals from e&#8208;waste of urban mines.</description>
      <author>Ziwen Chang, Yingying Zhou, Penghui Shao, Liming Yang, Bo Li, Dewei Li, Lingrong Zeng, Yi Gong, Xubiao Luo, Shenglian Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Outlook of Nickel&#8208;Based MOFs&#8211;LDHs Materials for Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500483</link>
      <description>Lincoln Einstein Kengne Fotso, Saad Mehmood, Vatsala Rani Jetti, Joydeep Dutta, Ujjwal Pal, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413087547

                Abstract This review focuses on the advances and outlook of integrated Ni&#8208;based MOFs (Metal&#8208;Organic Framework) and LDHs (Layered Double Hydroxides) photo(electro) catalysts, and addresses the pivotal gap in water splitting for sustainable energy generation application. MOFs and LDHs are two classes of materials with high potential for applications in photo(electro)catalytic water splitting reaction. However, challenges such as limited intrinsic activity, low electrical conductivity of a single material, lack of more exposed active sites, weak mass transport ability, and poor crystalline structure remain. State&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art strategies including doping, the development of composites, nano&#8208;structuration are used to solve these issues. Machine learning and artificial intelligence&#8208;assisted advanced in situ characterization techniques are proposed as unavoidable tools to address these challenges and optimize the catalyst design. This review outlines the key parameters involved in the assessment of the electrocatalytic and photocatalytic performance of water&#8208;splitting catalysts. The importance of density functional theory in Ni&#8208;based MOFs and LDHs for electrocatalytic water splitting is emphasized. Details about the balance of high activity along with long&#8208;term stability as a crucial requirement for large&#8208;scale applications are provided. This review will propel the knowledge and know&#8208;how in using Ni&#8208;based MOFs/LDHs as electro(photo)catalysts for hydrogen (H 2 ) production, and guide the researchers in the field.</description>
      <author>Lincoln Einstein Kengne Fotso, Saad Mehmood, Vatsala Rani Jetti, Joydeep Dutta, Ujjwal Pal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening of chalcogenides for intermediate band solar cells surpassing the Shockley-Queisser limit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/adf095</link>
      <description>Matteo Cagnoni, Journal of Physics Energy. 7(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413090529

                Abstract Intermediate band solar cells offer a promising avenue to surpass the Shockley&#8211;Queisser limit of    &#8764;  30   %    that constrains conventional single-junction devices, with the potential to approach an efficiency limit of    &#8764;  45   %    in terrestrial environments by incorporating a metallic band within the valence-conduction gap. Yet, their practical realization is challenged by difficulties in developing suitable intermediate band (IB) materials. Current approaches, which involve adding inclusions or utilizing highly mismatched alloys, often degrade material quality or present significant technological hurdles. A possible solution that remains underexplored, is to identify crystalline materials that inherently possess an IB and fine-tune their properties. In this work, thousands of crystalline chalcogenides are analyzed using a detailed balance model to quantitatively evaluate their expected efficacy as IB materials. Notably, orthorhombic     VB   1     VIA   2     and     IA   4     VIA   6     compounds, such as     Ta   1     Se   2     and     Cs   4     S   6     , are projected to achieve maximum efficiencies exceeding 35%, that is, surpassing the Shockley&#8211;Queisser limit. The interplay of IB filling and chemical substitution on the properties of these systems is analyzed, to unravel the impact on performance. This study not only identifies new material candidates for IB solar cells, but also provides insights into efficiency-property relations, hence advancing the understanding of these systems.</description>
      <author>Matteo Cagnoni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/adf095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice-matched antiperovskite-perovskite system toward all-solid-state batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62860-1</link>
      <description>Daisuke It&#244;, Naoaki Kuwata, Seiji Takemoto, Kazuhiro Kamiguchi, Gen Hasegawa, Kazunori Takada, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413094259

                Inorganic solid electrolytes have emerged as promising candidates for realizing all-solid-state batteries because they eliminate flammable, low boiling-point liquids in lithium-ion battery cells, improving safety and cycle life. In this study, we present a highly lattice-matched composite solid electrolyte consisting of an antiperovskite-perovskite system, offering the benefits of both antiperovskites as melt-infiltratable solid electrolytes and perovskites as fast-ion conductors. Atomistic simulations predict significant lithium-ion diffusion at the interface between cubic Li2OHCl and Li0.31La0.56TiO3. The incorporation of fluorine enables room-temperature operation by stabilizing the high-temperature cubic phase of Li2OHCl1-xFx and reduces the lattice mismatch ratio to 0.8% at the interface through lattice contractions. The composite solid electrolyte was synthesized via pressure-assisted melt infiltration. The solid electrolyte effectively infiltrates conventional lithium-ion battery electrodes while maintaining a stable interface structure. Electrochemical testing demonstrates promising charge-discharge characteristics, including long cycle life and rate performance. Intricate infiltration of the solid electrolyte into an electrode structure composed of active materials with microcracks and high surface area enables stable operation by mitigating degradation phenomena typically observed in liquid electrolyte-based lithium-ion batteries. Lithium-ion batteries face safety and capacity limitations. Here, authors develop a composite solid electrolyte combining anti-perovskite and perovskite phases, enabling low-temperature processing and stable interfaces. This advance supports safer, high-performance all-solid-state batteries.</description>
      <author>Daisuke It&#244;, Naoaki Kuwata, Seiji Takemoto, Kazuhiro Kamiguchi, Gen Hasegawa, Kazunori Takada</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62860-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the catalytic versatility of transition metal-doped coal char systems for hydrogen evolution reaction: a first-principles approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112882</link>
      <description>Abosede A. Badeji, Kowthaman Pathmanathan, Hewa Y. Abdullah, Ismail Hossain, Musa Runde, Chemical Physics. 599(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413097198

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abosede A. Badeji, Kowthaman Pathmanathan, Hewa Y. Abdullah, Ismail Hossain, Musa Runde</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics in enabling 2D materials: Optimization, predictive modelling, and data-driven discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2025.101814</link>
      <description>Johnson Kehinde Abifarin, Yuerui Lu, Materials Today Physics. 57(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413097860

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Johnson Kehinde Abifarin, Yuerui Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2025.101814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunability of Carbon Nitrides for Enhanced Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04006</link>
      <description>Shanping Liu, Valent&#237;n Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Haijian Tong, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Christian Mark Pelicano, Guillaume Maurin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413098894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shanping Liu, Valent&#237;n Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Haijian Tong, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Christian Mark Pelicano, Guillaume Maurin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPR_calculator: An on-the-fly surrogate model to accelerate massive nudged elastic band calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109781</link>
      <description>Isaac G. Onyango, Byungkyun Kang, Qiang Zhu, Computer Physics Communications. 316(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413099346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Isaac G. Onyango, Byungkyun Kang, Qiang Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balanced adsorbate interactions in CeVO4 nanosheets: A highly efficient and stable electrocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167107</link>
      <description>Youness El Issmaeli, Amina Lahrichi, Bruno G. Pollet, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413103336

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youness El Issmaeli, Amina Lahrichi, Bruno G. Pollet</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.167107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient one-step electrochemical synthesis of ammonia-hydrogen fuel for clean energy applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238065</link>
      <description>Zhongmei Yang, Xiaoyang Wang, Congjie Hong, Xiaojiang Mu, Lei Miao, Journal of Power Sources. 656(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413103418

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongmei Yang, Xiaoyang Wang, Congjie Hong, Xiaojiang Mu, Lei Miao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmonic Catalysis for Controlling Selectivity in the Hydrogenation of Cinnamaldehyde to Propylbenzene Under Visible&#8208;Light Irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202501054</link>
      <description>Sana Frindy, Shiqi Wang, Sam Sullivan&#8208;Allsop, Rongsheng Cai, Thomas J. A. Slater, Sarah J. Haigh, Pedro H. C. Camargo, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413103761

                The selective hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;&#8208;unsaturated aldehydes, such as cinnamaldehyde (CAL), into value&#8208;added aromatic hydrocarbons like propylbenzene (PPR) remains a formidable challenge due to competing C&#63742;C and C&#63742;O hydrogenation pathways. Here, a plasmon&#8208;enhanced catalytic strategy employing Au@Au 3 Pd core&#8211;shell nanoparticles supported on silica is reported. The catalyst features a plasmonic Au core and a 1 nm Au 3 Pd alloyed shell (25 at% Pd), enabling light&#8208;driven modulation of reaction selectivity. Under visible&#8208;light irradiation, the catalyst achieves complete CAL conversion with a &#8776;34% yield of PPR, corresponding to a 7.7&#8208;fold enhancement in turnover frequency relative to dark conditions. Density functional theory calculations reveal that interfacial electronic coupling between the Au core and Pd&#8208;rich shell upshifts the Pd d &#8208;band center and enhances charge transfer, promoting both C&#63742;C and C&#63742;O hydrogenation steps followed by hydrogenolysis to PPR. This study demonstrates a robust approach to overcome selectivity limitations in multifunctional molecule hydrogenation by harnessing localized surface plasmon resonance effects. The insights gained offer a foundation for the rational design of light&#8208;responsive bimetallic catalysts for selective and sustainable transformations.</description>
      <author>Sana Frindy, Shiqi Wang, Sam Sullivan&#8208;Allsop, Rongsheng Cai, Thomas J. A. Slater, Sarah J. Haigh, Pedro H. C. Camargo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202501054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Hydrogen Atom Transfer Rate Constants in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03905</link>
      <description>Noah South, Robert E. Warburton, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413105098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Noah South, Robert E. Warburton</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of dendrite formation at Li metal-electrolyte interface by a machine-learning enhanced constant potential framework.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62824-5</link>
      <description>Taiping Hu, Haichao Huang, Guobing Zhou, Xinyan Wang, Jiaxin Zhu, Zheng Cheng, Fangjia Fu, Xiaoxu Wang, Fu&#8208;Zhi Dai, Kuang Yu, Shenzhen Xu, PubMed. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413108997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Taiping Hu, Haichao Huang, Guobing Zhou, Xinyan Wang, Jiaxin Zhu, Zheng Cheng, Fangjia Fu, Xiaoxu Wang, Fu&#8208;Zhi Dai, Kuang Yu, Shenzhen Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62824-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the electrocatalytic behavior of Hf&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si17.svg" display="inline" id="d1e433"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;C&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si18.svg" display="inline" id="d1e441"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.113070</link>
      <description>Ouarda Azzi, Tarik Ouahrani, Chewki Ougherb, David Dell&#8217;Angelo, &#193;ngel Morales&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Micha&#235;l Badawi, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. 208(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413109650

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ouarda Azzi, Tarik Ouahrani, Chewki Ougherb, David Dell&#8217;Angelo, &#193;ngel Morales&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Micha&#235;l Badawi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.113070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waste lead paste for high-capacity lead&#8211;lithium aqueous batteries: A new method to recover waste lead paste</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.101038</link>
      <description>Chunxia Gong, Yosuke Amada, Hiroshi Sakurai, Manabu Takahashi, Kazuma Gotoh, Next Materials. 9(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413109782

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunxia Gong, Yosuke Amada, Hiroshi Sakurai, Manabu Takahashi, Kazuma Gotoh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.101038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density functional theory investigation of telluride materials for HER/ORR/OER multifunctional electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150812</link>
      <description>F. Jia, Zhengrui Li, Xinran Li, Yikang Gu, Ping Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 166(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413114483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>F. Jia, Zhengrui Li, Xinran Li, Yikang Gu, Ping Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150812</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
