<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 01:25:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Floating zone growth of large tetragonal Ruddlesden-Popper bilayer nickelate YySr3&#8722;yNi2&#8722;xAlxO7&#8722;&#948; single crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42005-025-02340-6</link>
      <description>Hasan Yilmaz, Pablo Sosa-Lizama, M. Knauft, Kathrin K&#252;ster, Ulrich Starke, Masahiko Isobe, Oliver Clemens, Peter A. van Aken, Y. Eren Suyolcu, Pascal Puphal, Communications Physics. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415260984

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hasan Yilmaz, Pablo Sosa-Lizama, M. Knauft, Kathrin K&#252;ster, Ulrich Starke, Masahiko Isobe, Oliver Clemens, Peter A. van Aken, Y. Eren Suyolcu, Pascal Puphal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42005-025-02340-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts for green hydrogen production in seawater: enhancement mechanism in catalytic activity and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5gc03577e</link>
      <description>Bingxu Wang, Xiao Tang, F.W. Sun, Sailong Wang, Xiaobin Liu, Jianping Lai, Jingqi Chi, Lei Wang, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415262798

                This study focuses on MSOEs as electrocatalysts for seawater oxygen evolution reaction (OER), summarizes strategies for improving the OER activity and durability, and discusses OER in seawater its improvement strategies based on sustainability.</description>
      <author>Bingxu Wang, Xiao Tang, F.W. Sun, Sailong Wang, Xiaobin Liu, Jianping Lai, Jingqi Chi, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5gc03577e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo&#8322;O&#8324;-Co&#8322;P Interfaces Inducing High-Spin Co&#178;&#8314; for Boosted Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147591</link>
      <description>Xu Fang, Zhonghai Zhang, Chen Hu, Lingjie Xuan, Bingbing Hong, Mengxue Sun, Yuhang Song, Jiang Wu, Jia Lin, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415269448

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu Fang, Zhonghai Zhang, Chen Hu, Lingjie Xuan, Bingbing Hong, Mengxue Sun, Yuhang Song, Jiang Wu, Jia Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultralow Ru Loading on Spinel Oxide Enhances Oxygen Coupling for Efficient Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c15539</link>
      <description>Mingxin Cai, Guopu Cai, Ke Liu, Degao Wang, Hongbin Zhao, Peilei He, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415272613

                The development of proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) technologies urgently demands electrocatalytic systems capable of maintaining exceptional activity and durability under harsh acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) conditions. Here, we present ultralow Ru loading on cobalt&#8211;manganese oxides (Ru&#8211;Co2MnO4.5) through a facile synthetic strategy. Ru and Co sites facilitate the direct coupling of the oxygen radicals, thereby exceeding the limitations of the scaling relation and triggering the oxide pathway mechanism. Structural characterizations and theoretical calculations demonstrate that the incorporation of Ru single atoms suppresses both lattice oxygen and metal dissolution while maintaining good coordination environments and crystal structures. Furthermore, Ru single-atom loading enhances the hydroxyl adsorption on the catalyst surface and promotes the OER kinetics. Consequently, the Ru&#8211;Co2MnO4.5 catalyst achieves an optimal trade-off between catalytic efficiency and structural durability. In 0.5 M H2SO4, the Ru&#8211;Co2MnO4.5 demonstrates a minimal overpotential of 176 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and exhibits excellent stability during 600 h. In the PEMWE device, the Ru&#8211;Co2MnO4.5 catalyst requires merely a voltage of 1.638 V to achieve 1 A cm&#8211;2, with an ultralow Ru loading of 20 &#956;g cm&#8211;2. The system can operate for over 100 h under a high current density of 1 A cm&#8211;2, showcasing its potential in a practical hydrogen production device. This work presents an innovative strategy for advancing the development of high-efficiency and large-scale green hydrogen production systems while elucidating the underlying reaction mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Mingxin Cai, Guopu Cai, Ke Liu, Degao Wang, Hongbin Zhao, Peilei He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c15539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Superhydrophobic Ni-W/GrPTFE by Reinforcing Ni-W with Graphene and Polytetrafluoroethylene to Enhance Fouling and Corrosion Resistance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/01457632.2025.2571271</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zafar Ullah, Ashfaq Ahmad, Mingyan Liu, Heat Transfer Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415274215

                Fouling and corrosion are critical challenges in heat transfer equipment. This study developed nickel-tungsten (Ni-W) composite coatings reinforced with micro- and nano-graphene (Gr) and polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) particles (Ni-W/Gr and Ni-W/GrPTFE) to enhance resistance to fouling and corrosion. The Ni-W/GrPTFE superhydrophobic coating exhibited a significantly greater water contact angle (152.1&#176;) compared to bare Q235 carbon steel (90.1&#176;) and a notably lower surface free energy of 3.48 mJ/m2, compared to 31.36 mJ/m2 for bare Q235 carbon steel. Surface roughness, chemical composition, and micromorphology were analyzed using atomic force microscopy, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy, and scanning electron microscopy. The electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results revealed superior corrosion resistance for the Ni-W/GrPTFE coating, with a minimal corrosion current density of 2.25 &#215; 10&#8722;5 &#181;A/cm2, a higher impedance modulus of 8.8 &#215; 104 &#937;&#183;cm2 at low frequencies, and substantial charge transfer resistance of 5.49 &#215; 104 &#937;&#183;cm2. Tafel polarization further confirmed a lower corrosion rate of 2.12x10&#8722;3 mm/a. Furthermore, fouling tests at various temperatures showed that the Ni-W/GrPTFE coating achieved a 90.74% fouling inhibition rate. Additionally, self-cleaning tests confirmed the absence of surface contaminants. These results indicate that the Ni-W/GrPTFE composite superhydrophobic coating offers exceptional durability, making it a promising solution for harsh conditions in heat transfer systems, geothermal applications, and chemical industries.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zafar Ullah, Ashfaq Ahmad, Mingyan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/01457632.2025.2571271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A survey of AI-supported materials informatics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cosrev.2025.100845</link>
      <description>Sanjay Chakraborty, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Martin Dahlqvist, Johanna Rosen, Fredrik Heintz, Computer Science Review. 59(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415278663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sanjay Chakraborty, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Martin Dahlqvist, Johanna Rosen, Fredrik Heintz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cosrev.2025.100845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cavity&#8208;Networked Copper Nanocatalysts with Acid&#8208;Tolerant Microenvironments for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202520743</link>
      <description>Zhongshuang Xu, Qikui Fan, Huanran Miao, Xinwei Zhang, Hongyu Zhang, Xi Cao, Pengxu Yan, Xiai Zhang, Zhimao Yang, Jian Yang, Chuncai Kong, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415279076

                Abstract Gasophilic/hydrophobic microstructured Cu nanomaterials address the multi&#8208;carbon (C 2+ ) selectivity bottleneck in electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), yet their morphological control is hindered by low reduction potentials and high surface atomic mobility. This study reports a bioinspired gas&#8208;trapping hydrophobic Cu nanostructure (BGH&#8208;Cu) via in situ electrochemical reconstruction, forming an interconnected cavity network that confers gasophilic/hydrophobic properties. Mechanistic studies reveal cavities act as dynamic electrolyte reservoirs, selectively retaining OH &#8722; /K + to suppress proton transport and create a local micro&#8208;alkaline environment, while cavity&#8208;enhanced cation enrichment synergizes with C&#9472;C coupling. BGH&#8208;Cu achieves C 2 H 4 Faradaic efficiency of 54.7% at current density of 600 mA cm &#8722;2 in strongly acidic conditions (pH 1), with 63.7% single&#8208;pass carbon efficiency and 40 h stability in a membrane electrode assembly configuration. This work provides a non&#8208;extreme synthesis strategy for gasophilic/hydrophobic Cu nanomaterials, elucidates the &#8220;cavity microenvironment modulation&#8221; mechanism for C 2+ selectivity, and offers a new paradigm for high&#8208;current&#8208;density acidic CO 2 RR to C 2+ products.</description>
      <author>Zhongshuang Xu, Qikui Fan, Huanran Miao, Xinwei Zhang, Hongyu Zhang, Xi Cao, Pengxu Yan, Xiai Zhang, Zhimao Yang, Jian Yang, Chuncai Kong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202520743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TorchANI 2.0: An Extensible, High-Performance Library for the Design, Training, and Use of NN-IPs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01853</link>
      <description>Ignacio Pickering, Jiangeng Xue, Kate Huddleston, Nicholas Terrel, Adri&#225;n E. Roitberg, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415285772

                In this work, we introduce TorchANI 2.0, a significantly improved version of the free and open source TorchANI software package for training and evaluation of ANI (ANAKIN-ME) deep learning models. TorchANI 2.0 builds upon the foundation of its predecessor, while addressing its limitations and introducing new features. These changes greatly enhance its extensibility, performance, and suitability as a framework for developing models ready for molecular dynamics applications. These improvements include the introduction of a modular system to add arbitrary pairwise potentials to models, CUDA-accelerated optimization for faster and more memory-efficient calculation of local atomic features, and a batched system for better performance of network ensembles, among others. Our benchmarks demonstrate that TorchANI 2.0 achieves significant speedup over previous versions in both training and inference, and the library enhancements allow users to train physically constrained models that better represent important qualities of chemical systems. We demonstrate this by introducing three new ANI models that incorporate these features and evaluating their capabilities.</description>
      <author>Ignacio Pickering, Jiangeng Xue, Kate Huddleston, Nicholas Terrel, Adri&#225;n E. Roitberg</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Modeling of Defects in Nanomaterials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527850273.ch7</link>
      <description>C.M. Ramos-Castillo, J. Hern&#225;ndez-Tecorralco, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415289901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C.M. Ramos-Castillo, J. Hern&#225;ndez-Tecorralco</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527850273.ch7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect and Interface Engineering in Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527850273.ch15</link>
      <description>J.C. Cruz, Blandy Pamplona-Solis, K. Garc&#237;a Uitz, M.P. Gurrola, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415290180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J.C. Cruz, Blandy Pamplona-Solis, K. Garc&#237;a Uitz, M.P. Gurrola</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527850273.ch15</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Synthesis and Device Integration of Long 17-Atom-Wide Armchair Graphene Nanoribbons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c11981</link>
      <description>Jeong Ha Hwang, Nicol&#242; Bassi, Mayada Fadel, Oliver Braun, Tim Dumslaff, Carlo A. Pignedoli, Michael Stiefel, Roman Furrer, Hironobu Hayashi, Hiroko Yamada, Akimitsu Narita, Kl&#228;us M&#252;llen, Michel Calame, Mickael L. Perrin, Rom&#225;n Fasel, Pascal Ruffieux, Vincent Meunier, Gabriela Borin Barin, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415297053

                Seventeen-carbon-atom-wide armchair graphene nanoribbons (17-AGNRs) are promising candidates for high-performance electronic devices due to their narrow electronic bandgap. Atomic precision in edge structure and width control is achieved through a bottom-up on-surface synthesis (OSS) approach from tailored molecular precursors in ultrahigh vacuum (UHV). This synthetic protocol must be optimized to meet the structural requirements for device integration, with the ribbon length being the most critical parameter. Here, we report optimized OSS conditions that produce 17-AGNRs with an average length of &#8764;17 nm. This length enhancement is achieved through a gradual temperature ramping during an extended annealing period, combined with a template-like effect driven by monomer assembly at high surface coverage. The resulting 17-AGNRs are comprehensively characterized in UHV by using scanning probe techniques and Raman spectroscopy. Raman measurements following substrate transfer enabled the characterization of GNRs' length distribution on the device substrate and confirmed their stability under ambient conditions and harsh chemical environments, including acid vapors and etchants. The increased length and ambient stability of the 17-AGNRs led to their reliable integration into device architectures. As a proof of concept, we integrate 17-AGNRs into field-effect transistors (FETs) with graphene electrodes and confirm that electronic transport occurs through the GNRs. This work demonstrates the feasibility of integrating narrow bandgap GNRs into functional devices and contributes to advancing the development of carbon-based nanoelectronics.</description>
      <author>Jeong Ha Hwang, Nicol&#242; Bassi, Mayada Fadel, Oliver Braun, Tim Dumslaff, Carlo A. Pignedoli, Michael Stiefel, Roman Furrer, Hironobu Hayashi, Hiroko Yamada, Akimitsu Narita, Kl&#228;us M&#252;llen, Michel Calame, Mickael L. Perrin, Rom&#225;n Fasel, Pascal Ruffieux, Vincent Meunier, Gabriela Borin Barin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c11981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Locking the Lattice Oxygen in Commercial RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for High Stable Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202523636</link>
      <description>Yanhui Yu, G. S. Huang, Wenjun Fan, Zihao Fan, Hanqing Gao, Daoxiong Wu, Tianjiao Wang, Jing Li, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang, Peilin Deng, Ying Liang, Xinlong Tian, Peng Rao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415304115

                Abstract Efficient and sustainable hydrogen production via proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) requires the development of robust low&#8208;cost oxygen evolution reaction catalysts. A robust acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst is fabricated, featuring single Co atoms incorporated into commercial RuO 2 (Co SA /RuO 2 ) and demonstrate that the Co sites suppress the mobility of lattice oxygen in commercial RuO 2 , thereby eliminating the stability&#8208;limited lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism and improving the catalyst stability. The theoretical calculations reveal that the atomically dispersed Co sites shifts the &#949;d&#8208;dn of RuO 2 downward, optimizing the adsorption of O * and * OOH, thereby changing the rate&#8208;determining step and improving the catalytic performance. In addition, atomically dispersed Co enhances the strength of the Ru&#8211;O lattice interaction, thereby alleviating the dissolution of Ru and effectively improving the stability of the catalyst under OER conditions. Specifically, the Co SA /RuO 2 &#8208;promoted PEMWE requires a voltage of 1.662 V to achieve a current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 and can be stably performed for &gt;550 h at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 with negligible performance decay. Thus, this work paves the way for the fabrication of highly active and stable ruthenium oxide&#8211;based OER catalysts and their use as alternatives to the costly Ir&#8208;based counterparts.</description>
      <author>Yanhui Yu, G. S. Huang, Wenjun Fan, Zihao Fan, Hanqing Gao, Daoxiong Wu, Tianjiao Wang, Jing Li, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang, Peilin Deng, Ying Liang, Xinlong Tian, Peng Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202523636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridinic-N Dominates ORR Performance: Decoding Configuration-Sensitive Electrocatalysis of N-Doped Graphene Quantum Dots</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04899</link>
      <description>Jiayu Yuan, Xiao&#8208;Bao Yang, Haofan Wang, Yonghai Cao, Hongjuan Wang, Guangxing Yang, Hao Yu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415309445

                Developing low-cost, high-performance metal-free oxygen reduction catalysts demands precise quantification of structure-performance relationships in nitrogen-doped carbons. Structural search algorithms combined with density functional theory (DFT) enable comprehensive analysis of catalytic performance versus structural features. Using nitrogen-doped graphene quantum dots (NGQDs) as models, we computationally resolve how nitrogen species types (pyridinic-N, graphitic-N) and substitution positions influence the stability and intrinsic activity. Boltzmann statistics quantify the contributions of all configurations to the current density during oxygen reduction. Furthermore, we identify dominant configurations grouping NGQDs into configuration lumps. Thermodynamically, nitrogen atoms preferentially occupy carbon atoms at defect-adjacent sites as pyridinic-N. Their spatial distribution controls local atomic charge redistribution and adsorption environments, thereby modulating intrinsic activity. These materials exhibit extreme configuration sensitivity: thermodynamically stable dominant configurations may contribute minimally to current density. Crucially, lumped pyridinic-N configurations dominate ORR performance. This work provides theoretical insights supporting carbon adjacent to pyridinic-N as the primary active site in N-doped carbon ORR catalysts. It establishes a universal framework for analyzing structure&#8211;activity relationships in nonmodel catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Jiayu Yuan, Xiao&#8208;Bao Yang, Haofan Wang, Yonghai Cao, Hongjuan Wang, Guangxing Yang, Hao Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Path-integral molecular dynamics with actively-trained and universal machine learning force fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109902</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1040;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1099;&#1093;, Nikita Rybin, Ivan Novikov, Alexander V. Shapeev, Computer Physics Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415313398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1040;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1099;&#1093;, Nikita Rybin, Ivan Novikov, Alexander V. Shapeev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109902</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C Catalyst Integrating Single&#8208;Atom Fe and Nanoscale CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; towards Efficient Oxygen Reduction Reaction for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries&lt;sup&gt;&#8224;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.70315</link>
      <description>Yukui Pei, Jianfeng Zuo, Xiannong Tang, Longbin Li, Ting Hu, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415313625

                Comprehensive Summary Developing high&#8208;performance, durable, and cost&#8208;effective oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts is essential for advancing next&#8208;generation energy devices like zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, we engineer a hybrid Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C catalyst (FeSA&#8208;Fe NP /CeO 2 @NC) integrating atomically dispersed Fe&#8208;N x sites, Fe nanoparticles, and oxygen vacancy&#8208;rich CeO 2 nanoparticles within a nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon matrix. Interfacial charge transfer and oxygen vacancy&#8208;mediated electron redistribution, synergistically enhanced by strong metal&#8208;support interactions (SMSI), optimize the electronic configuration of Fe&#8208;N x sites and reduce their electron density. The resulting catalyst exhibits exceptional ORR activity and stability, featuring a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.925 V (vs. RHE) in alkaline media and minimal degradation (1% and 2.8% negative shifts after 10,000/20,000 cycles). In ZABs, it achieves a peak power density of 310.29 mW&#183;cm &#8211;2 while sustaining stable operation for over 600 h. This work demonstrates dual role of CeO 2 in enhancing activity and stability, establishing a design principle for high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts in energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Yukui Pei, Jianfeng Zuo, Xiannong Tang, Longbin Li, Ting Hu, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.70315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Aluminum Distribution in Cu-MOR Systems on Methane-to-Methanol Conversion: A Combined Experimental and Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c06045</link>
      <description>Peter N. Njoroge, Bj&#248;rn Gading Solemsli, Asanka Wijerathne, Izar Capel Berdiell, Agnieszka Seremak, Mario Chiesa, Yu&#8208;Kai Liao, Beatrice Garetto, Nishant N. Patel, Karoline Kvande, Elisa Borfecchia, Christopher Paolucci, Unni Olsbye, Pablo Beato, Stian Svelle, Sebastian Prodinger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415313906

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peter N. Njoroge, Bj&#248;rn Gading Solemsli, Asanka Wijerathne, Izar Capel Berdiell, Agnieszka Seremak, Mario Chiesa, Yu&#8208;Kai Liao, Beatrice Garetto, Nishant N. Patel, Karoline Kvande, Elisa Borfecchia, Christopher Paolucci, Unni Olsbye, Pablo Beato, Stian Svelle, Sebastian Prodinger</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c06045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Accelerated Discovery of Electrocatalyst Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.5c00135</link>
      <description>Yifan Zeng, Jun Wang, Fengwang Li, Tongliang Liu, Aoni Xu, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415317511

                The rational exploration and design of high-performance, stable electrocatalysts are crucial for efficient renewable energy storage, conversion, and utilization. Artificial intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing this field by significantly reducing the time and cost associated with conventional trial-and-error experimentation and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Advancements in data quality, computing power, and algorithms have positioned AI as a key enabler in understanding electrocatalytic mechanisms, designing advanced materials, analyzing structures, and predicting performance. This review highlights the pivotal role of AI in electrocatalyst discovery, focusing on the critical aspects of data, descriptors, and machine learning models. We discuss various AI approaches, including their applications in accelerating DFT calculations, exploring reaction mechanisms, designing electrocatalysts, and predicting performance, providing a comprehensive overview of the current state-of-the-art. We also address the challenges and opportunities in leveraging AI for electrocatalyst development, emphasizing the importance of data quality, model selection, and collaborative research. This review aims to guide researchers in effectively utilizing AI to accelerate the discovery and optimization of electrocatalysts for a renewable energy future.</description>
      <author>Yifan Zeng, Jun Wang, Fengwang Li, Tongliang Liu, Aoni Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.5c00135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Infrared Spectra of OH&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;&#183;(H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;and OH&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;&#183;(H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; with Constrained Nuclear-Electronic Orbital Molecular Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c04334</link>
      <description>Zhe Liu, Yiwen Wang, Yuzhe Zhang, Nan Yang, Yang Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415320972

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhe Liu, Yiwen Wang, Yuzhe Zhang, Nan Yang, Yang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c04334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled synthesis of NiFe alloy nanoparticles confined in carbon matrices: study on the effect of morphology on enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.139301</link>
      <description>Xiang Li, Silvia Giordani, Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Devis Di Tommaso, Cristina Giordano, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415327059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Li, Silvia Giordani, Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Devis Di Tommaso, Cristina Giordano</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.139301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution electrocatalysis resilient to voltage fluctuations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01665-y</link>
      <description>Ailong Li, Hideshi Ooka, Shuang Kong, Kiyohiro Adachi, Yuchen Zhang, Kazuna Fushimi, Satoru Hamamoto, Masaki Oura, Sun Hee Kim, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415349311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ailong Li, Hideshi Ooka, Shuang Kong, Kiyohiro Adachi, Yuchen Zhang, Kazuna Fushimi, Satoru Hamamoto, Masaki Oura, Sun Hee Kim, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01665-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D Mo&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanowires for Sustainable Hydrogen Evolution: Size and Fermi-Level Driven Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c05646</link>
      <description>Xiaoqing Shang, Lingxiao Zhu, He Ma, Yue Liu, Yan Liu, Tian Cui, Da Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415352692

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoqing Shang, Lingxiao Zhu, He Ma, Yue Liu, Yan Liu, Tian Cui, Da Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c05646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic NiO-Pt heterostructure for enhanced hydrogen evolution: Boosting charge transfer and catalytic efficiency in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137226</link>
      <description>Faria Rafique, Shahzad Ameen, Muhammad Ali, Aleena Tahir, Aashaq Shah, A. U. Bhatti, Tanveer ul Haq, Mira Tul Zubaida Butt, Ammar Ahmed Khan, Saleh A. Ahmed, Irshad Hussain, Habib ur Rehman, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415355028

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faria Rafique, Shahzad Ameen, Muhammad Ali, Aleena Tahir, Aashaq Shah, A. U. Bhatti, Tanveer ul Haq, Mira Tul Zubaida Butt, Ammar Ahmed Khan, Saleh A. Ahmed, Irshad Hussain, Habib ur Rehman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dpdata: A Scalable Python Toolkit for Atomistic Machine Learning Data Sets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01767</link>
      <description>Jinzhe Zeng, Xulong Peng, Yong&#8208;Bin Zhuang, Haidi Wang, Fengbo Yuan, Duo Zhang, Renxi Liu, Yingze Wang, Ping Tuo, Yuzhi Zhang, Yixiao Chen, Yifan Li, Cao Thang Nguyen, Jiameng Huang, Anyang Peng, Mari&#225;n Rynik, Weihong Xu, Zezhong Zhang, Xuyuan Zhou, Tao Chen, Jiahao Fan, Wanrun Jiang, Bowen Li, Denan Li, Haoxi Li, Wenshuo Liang, Rundong Liao, Liping Liu, Chenxing Luo, Logan Ward, Kaiwei Wan, Junjie Wang, Pan Xiang, Chengqian Zhang, Jinchao Zhang, R. Zhou, Jiaxin Zhu, Linfeng Zhang, Han Wang, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415356660

                Seamless management of atomistic data sets is a critical prerequisite for the successful development and deployment of machine learning potentials (MLPs). Here, we present dpdata, an open-source Python library designed to streamline every aspect of MLP data handling. Built upon a flexible, plugin-based architecture, dpdata supports reading, writing, and converting between a broad range of file formats&#9472;from popular quantum-chemistry packages and molecular-dynamics engines to specialized MLP frameworks. Users may define custom data types, formats, drivers, and minimizers, enabling effortless extension to emerging software. Key utilities include automated train-test splitting, coordinate perturbation for active learning, outlier-energy removal, &#916;-learning data set generation, error-metric computation, and unit conversion. Through efficient NumPy-backed storage and system-level operations, dpdata achieves significant memory saving and inference speedups over configuration-by-configuration tools such as ASE. We also highlight practical impact, with dpdata used across published studies, for format conversion, data storage, coordinate perturbation, and utilization in other projects for data processing.</description>
      <author>Jinzhe Zeng, Xulong Peng, Yong&#8208;Bin Zhuang, Haidi Wang, Fengbo Yuan, Duo Zhang, Renxi Liu, Yingze Wang, Ping Tuo, Yuzhi Zhang, Yixiao Chen, Yifan Li, Cao Thang Nguyen, Jiameng Huang, Anyang Peng, Mari&#225;n Rynik, Weihong Xu, Zezhong Zhang, Xuyuan Zhou, Tao Chen, Jiahao Fan, Wanrun Jiang, Bowen Li, Denan Li, Haoxi Li, Wenshuo Liang, Rundong Liao, Liping Liu, Chenxing Luo, Logan Ward, Kaiwei Wan, Junjie Wang, Pan Xiang, Chengqian Zhang, Jinchao Zhang, R. Zhou, Jiaxin Zhu, Linfeng Zhang, Han Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01767</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature-dependent mechanism evolution on RhRu3Ox for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64286-1</link>
      <description>Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, Heng Liu, Sihua Feng, Xiaozhi Su, Jie Xu, Hengli Duan, Ruiqi Liu, Yingkang Qin, Wensheng Yan, Sheng Zhu, Rui Wu, Hao Li, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415358253

                The oxygen evolution reaction, as the anodic reaction of many electrochemical devices, plays a crucial role in energy conversion. However, the insufficient stability of non-iridium-based materials during the oxygen evolution reaction has severely limited the large-scale application of such devices. Here, using a home-made operando differential electrochemical mass spectrometry system, we show a temperature dependent mechanism evolution effect of RhRu3Ox in the oxygen evolution process, which highlights the role of temperature in triggering mechanism evolution. This effect enriches the strategies for pathway manipulation. Since different kinetic pathways can influence catalyst stability, this finding suggests that temperature-dependent pathway regulation may serve as an approach to optimize stability. To evaluate the potential of RhRu3Ox for practical applications, we assemble it into a proton exchange membrane electrolyzer and demonstrate its stability at room temperature for over 1000 hours at a current density of 200 mA cm&#8722;2. Density functional theory studies suggest that the existence of a kinetic barrier related to lattice oxygen activation might be the reason for the observed temperature dependent behavior of RhRu3Ox at elevated temperatures. The oxygen evolution reaction enables many clean energy technologies, but most acid-unstable catalysts still block deployment. Here the authors report a temperature dependent mechanistic evolution in RhRu3Ox that links reaction pathways to stability, enabling durable acidic water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, Heng Liu, Sihua Feng, Xiaozhi Su, Jie Xu, Hengli Duan, Ruiqi Liu, Yingkang Qin, Wensheng Yan, Sheng Zhu, Rui Wu, Hao Li, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64286-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen evolution performances of NiO-based electrocatalysts through synergistic plasma processing and laser treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ya00273g</link>
      <description>Davide Barreca, Alessandro Bellucci, Matteo Mastellone, D.M. Trucchi, Chiara Maccato, Elisa Sefora Pierobon, Alberto Gasparotto, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Energy Advances. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415369965

                Engineering of NiO-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution has been demonstrated by a combined plasma synthesis and ex situ laser treatment.</description>
      <author>Davide Barreca, Alessandro Bellucci, Matteo Mastellone, D.M. Trucchi, Chiara Maccato, Elisa Sefora Pierobon, Alberto Gasparotto, Gian Andrea Rizzi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ya00273g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Single-Step Synthesis of PVP-Stabilized Ru NPs for Electrochemical Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02899</link>
      <description>Rahul Bhise, Riddhi Kadrekar, Priti Singh, Nagapradeep Nidamanuri, Priyamvada Arte, Pinku Nath, Yu Wang, Arif D. Sheikh, Mudit Dixit, Sushant P. Sahu, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415376615

                An efficient electrochemical hydrogen generation catalyst composed of robust ruthenium nanoparticles (Ru NPs) was synthesized through a simple one-pot hydrothermal reaction, where formaldehyde was employed as a reductant and low-molecular-weight poly(vinylpyrrolidone) (PVP) was employed as a stabilizing agent. The as-synthesized nanoparticles were initially characterized by powder X-ray diffraction, which confirmed their hexagonal, close-packed ruthenium phase. Structural analysis was performed by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM), which disclosed PVP-stabilized nanoflowers composed of Ru NPs with an average diameter of 5 nm. Further, energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX) confirmed the presence of ruthenium and carbon, and their oxidation states were also studied with X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). The as-synthesized PVP-supported Ru NPs exhibited remarkable hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity, with overpotentials of 51 and 39 mV at a cathodic current density of &#8722;10 mA cm&#8211;2 and corresponding Tafel slopes of 23 and 40 mV dec&#8211;1 in acidic and alkaline conditions, respectively. Such a high performance of the PVP-protected Ru NPs was further evaluated in a continuous manner by using an electrolyzer flow cell, and our findings were supported by the corresponding density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Calculations of the Gibbs free energy for varied surface coverage on the (002) facet revealed that the individual site activity improved with an increase in surface coverage, enhancing the continuous HER performance. Besides reinforcing the exploitation of eco-friendly raw materials for nanocatalyst development, this work serves as a prelude to our upcoming systematic investigations on the influence of the molecular weight of the PVP polymer on the size of metallic nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>Rahul Bhise, Riddhi Kadrekar, Priti Singh, Nagapradeep Nidamanuri, Priyamvada Arte, Pinku Nath, Yu Wang, Arif D. Sheikh, Mudit Dixit, Sushant P. Sahu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable dioxin-linked metallophthalocyanine covalent organic frameworks as trifunctional electrocatalysts for overall water splitting and oxygen reduction: A combining density functional theory and machine learning study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.152132</link>
      <description>Lu Song, Yi Ding, Jiadi Ying, Tiancun Liu, Qiang Li, Yong Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 187(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415376829

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Song, Yi Ding, Jiadi Ying, Tiancun Liu, Qiang Li, Yong Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.152132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition-Metal Doped Armchair Hexagonal SiC Quantum Dots: Insights into Stability, Electronic Structure, and Optoelectronic Properties from First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7654081/v1</link>
      <description>Nahed H. Teleb, Mahmoud A.S. Sakr, Ghada M. Abdelrazek, Omar H. Abd&#8208;Elkader, M. Abdel Rafea, Hazem Abdelsalam, Qinfang Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415382862

                Abstract The rational design of stable, earth-abundant quantum dots with tunable electronic and optical properties is crucial for advancing sustainable optoelectronic and photocatalytic technologies. In this work, density functional theory (DFT) is employed to investigate pristine and 3d transition-metal (TM)-doped armchair hexagonal silicon carbide quantum dots (AH-SiC-QDs, Si&#8325;&#8327;C&#8325;&#8327;H&#8323;&#8320;). Structural analysis reveals that pristine AH-SiC-QDs exhibit high stability (5.612 eV), surpassing previously reported SiC- and AlN-based QDs. Upon TM incorporation, stability remains robust, with Ni-doping providing the strongest binding and Sc-doping the weakest. Electronic structure calculations show significant dopant-induced modifications in HOMO&#8211;LUMO distributions and bandgaps, where Ti- and Sc-doped systems achieve remarkable bandgap narrowing (1.056 and 0.919 eV), enhancing electronic coupling with the host lattice. Optical absorption studies demonstrate pronounced red-shifts into the visible and near-infrared regions, with Sc- and V-doped systems offering extended light-harvesting potential. Mulliken charge and natural bond orbital (NBO) analyses confirm strong donor&#8211;acceptor interactions, orbital rehybridization, and enhanced charge transfer, directly linking dopant chemistry to improved catalytic and optoelectronic behavior. These findings establish TM-doped AH-SiC-QDs as versatile and highly tunable platforms for next-generation photocatalysis and energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Nahed H. Teleb, Mahmoud A.S. Sakr, Ghada M. Abdelrazek, Omar H. Abd&#8208;Elkader, M. Abdel Rafea, Hazem Abdelsalam, Qinfang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7654081/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a scientific community? The WOEPS workshop and the evolution of the economics of science, 1994&#8211;2023</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10438599.2025.2571618</link>
      <description>Daniel Souza, Aldo Geuna, Cornelia Lawson, Economics of Innovation and New Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415387026

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Souza, Aldo Geuna, Cornelia Lawson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/10438599.2025.2571618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain&#8208;Tunable Bandgaps, Strong Light Absorption, and Active Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Light Metal&#8208;Decorated Borophene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pssr.202500326</link>
      <description>Zhen Gao, Fengxian Ma, Yalong Jiao, physica status solidi (RRL) - Rapid Research Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415387753

                Current strategies for stabilizing 2D borophene sheets and compensating for boron's electron deficiency primarily rely on transition metals, many of which are heavy and costly, thereby limiting their practical applications. In contrast, the use of light&#8208;metal elements to stabilize borophene has remained largely unexplored. This work demonstrates that the light&#8208;metal beryllium (Be) can effectively stabilize 2D boron sheets. Through swarm&#8208;intelligence structural searches combined with first&#8208;principles calculations, three stable monolayers of beryllium tetraboride (BeB 4 )&#8212;the &#945;&#8208;, &#946;&#8208;, and &#947;&#8208;phases&#8212;are predicted. The &#945;&#8208;BeB 4 phase is metallic, while &#946;&#8208; and &#947;&#8208;BeB 4 are indirect semiconductors with bandgaps of 0.39 and 1.65 eV, respectively. Notably, biaxial strain can reversibly tune &#946;&#8208;BeB 4 between semiconducting and metallic states. Furthermore, &#947;&#8208;BeB 4 exhibits a high visible&#8208;light absorption coefficient (3.80 &#215; 10 5 cm &#8722; 1 ) and an out&#8208;of&#8208;plane negative Poisson's ratio, indicating auxetic behavior. Remarkably, &#945;&#8208;BeB 4 demonstrates a near&#8208;zero Gibbs free energy for hydrogen adsorption, suggesting excellent catalytic activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction. These unique properties position BeB 4 monolayers as promising, lightweight, and cost&#8208;effective candidates for next&#8208;generation energy conversion and optoelectronic applications.</description>
      <author>Zhen Gao, Fengxian Ma, Yalong Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pssr.202500326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computation of a Quasiparticle Band Structure with the Quantum-Selected Configuration Interaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7566/jpsj.94.114002</link>
      <description>Takahiro Ohgoe, Hokuto Iwakiri, Kazuhide Ichikawa, Sho Koh, Masaya Kohda, Journal of the Physical Society of Japan. 94(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415388831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Takahiro Ohgoe, Hokuto Iwakiri, Kazuhide Ichikawa, Sho Koh, Masaya Kohda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7566/jpsj.94.114002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven optimization of boron-doped graphene work function for enhanced anode materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137168</link>
      <description>Qingwei Zhang, Lai Li, Yunhua Lu, Chao Zhang, Junan Zhang, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415390254

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingwei Zhang, Lai Li, Yunhua Lu, Chao Zhang, Junan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on MXene Materials via First-Principles Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03901</link>
      <description>Colton J. Lund, Jiayi Xu, Cong Liu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415396086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Colton J. Lund, Jiayi Xu, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulse-combustion-synthesized carbon-supported NiM (M = Co, Cu) nanoparticles: A framework for alkaline oxygen evolution studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116492</link>
      <description>Brend de Coen, Luis Fernando Le&#243;n&#8208;Fernandez, Kevin Van Daele, Nick Daems, Matija Gatalo, Miha Hotko, Nejc Hodnik, Tom Breugelmans, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415401262

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brend de Coen, Luis Fernando Le&#243;n&#8208;Fernandez, Kevin Van Daele, Nick Daems, Matija Gatalo, Miha Hotko, Nejc Hodnik, Tom Breugelmans</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physicochemical evolution of a Cu/Mn/Fe oxygen carrier in a 50 kWth chemical looping with oxygen uncoupling unit with solid fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137162</link>
      <description>Amirhossein Filsouf, Teresa Mendiara, I&#241;aki Ad&#225;nez-Rubio, M.T. Izquierdo, Juan Ad&#225;nez, Pilar Gay&#225;n, Alberto Abad, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415406642

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amirhossein Filsouf, Teresa Mendiara, I&#241;aki Ad&#225;nez-Rubio, M.T. Izquierdo, Juan Ad&#225;nez, Pilar Gay&#225;n, Alberto Abad</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace Ni-modified Cu Zn catalyst for efficient electrochemical CO2 reduction to tunable syngas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.135788</link>
      <description>Renhui Ruan, Kejie Zhang, Baochong Cui, Weijian Hua, Chenyan Yan, Jun Ji Piao, Hexin Liu, Shuanghui Deng, Xuebin Wang, Houzhang Tan, Zhongfa Hu, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415406889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Renhui Ruan, Kejie Zhang, Baochong Cui, Weijian Hua, Chenyan Yan, Jun Ji Piao, Hexin Liu, Shuanghui Deng, Xuebin Wang, Houzhang Tan, Zhongfa Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.135788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#960;&#8208;&#960; Conjugated g&#8208;C &lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt; N &lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt; Skeleton&#8208;Supported Single&#8208;Atom Catalyst for Nitrogen Reduction Reaction: A &#8220;Lock and Key&#8221; Coevaluation of Activity and Selectivity Involved in Constant Potential and pH Effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202502611</link>
      <description>Yali Lu, Zongjin Hu, Qiang Zhang, Chenglong Shi, Qingjun Zhou, Yu-Ling Song, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415411501

                Abstract The efficient development of electrocatalysts for the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) under ambient conditions has been greatly challenging due to the high stability of the N&#8801;N bond and the competitive interference from the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This work innovatively designs a graphitic carbon nitride substrate (g&#8208;C 16 N 19 ) with a super&#8208;large pore structure based on the self&#8208;doping strategy and first&#8208;principles calculations, and constructs TM@g&#8208;C 16 N 19 (TM = Ti &#8764; Au) single&#8208;atom catalyst systems. By establishing a &#8220;Four&#8208;Step&#8221; screening model, it is found that W@g&#8208;C 16 N 19 exhibits the best NRR catalytic performance, with an ultralow limiting potential (U L ) of &#8208;0.23 V. Combining electron structure analyses such as charge density difference, ICOHP value, Bader charge, and spin magnetic moment, the micro&#8208;mechanism of W@g&#8208;C 16 N 19 effectively activating the &#963;/&#960; bonds of N 2 molecules through strong d&#8208;p orbital hybridization is revealed. Furthermore, based on the pH&#8208; and potential&#8208;dependent adsorption&#8208;free energy results calculated by the constant potential model, pH&#8208;potential coupling analysis shows that the configuration has a decisive influence on activity: the E&#8208;I/S&#8208;V mode dominates in alkaline media, while the E&#8208;O/S&#8208;O pathway is predominant under acidic conditions. In the E&#8208;I configuration, the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step (PDS) of NRR decreases with the decrease of the electrode potential; conversely, the energy barrier of the PDS of NRR in the E&#8208;O/S&#8208;V/S&#8208;O configuration increases with the decrease of the electrode potential.</description>
      <author>Yali Lu, Zongjin Hu, Qiang Zhang, Chenglong Shi, Qingjun Zhou, Yu-Ling Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202502611</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Electrochemical Properties of Metal&#8208;Free Covalent Organic Frameworks Through Hydrogen&#8208;Bonding Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202520634</link>
      <description>Zhongping Li, Xinjiang Wang, Songlin Zhao, Changqing Li, Won&#8208;Yeong Kim, Yucheng Jin, Feng Tang, Jong&#8208;Pil Jeon, Siliu Lyu, Sang&#8208;Young Lee, Jong&#8208;Beom Baek, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415411542

                Abstract Accurately identifying and enhancing catalytic activity in metal&#8208;free, carbon&#8208;based electrocatalysts remains a fundamental challenge, largely due to the difficulty of concurrently optimizing hydrophilicity and oxygen affinity at active sites. Herein, a hydrogen&#8208;bonding&#8208;driven strategy is presented to boost oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance in covalent organic frameworks (COFs). By integrating hydrazone linkages with alkoxy&#8208;functionalized pore walls, a hydrophilic skeleton capable of forming tunable intramolecular hydrogen&#8208;bonding networks is constructed. These interactions induce asymmetric electron distributions that enhance the simultaneous adsorption of water and oxygen molecules. Consequently, the hydrazone&#8208;linked COFs exhibit a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.78 V, outperforming all previously reported metal&#8208;free COF&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the improved activity originates from favorable * OOH and * OH adsorption energies at hydrogen&#8208;bonding centers, along with stabilized O 2 /H 2 O binding. This synergistic modulation of the local microenvironment&#8212;through hydrogen bonding and electronic structure engineering&#8212;affords enhanced activity, selectivity, and long&#8208;term durability. This work offers a rational design paradigm for advancing metal&#8208;free COF electrocatalysts toward sustainable energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Zhongping Li, Xinjiang Wang, Songlin Zhao, Changqing Li, Won&#8208;Yeong Kim, Yucheng Jin, Feng Tang, Jong&#8208;Pil Jeon, Siliu Lyu, Sang&#8208;Young Lee, Jong&#8208;Beom Baek</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202520634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic CO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; reduction to CO enabled by Ni-N&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;x&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; high activity sites formed by three-dimensional porous foams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.205</link>
      <description>Anqi Wei, Xu Yang, Jiangfang Wang, Lei Shi, Chong Wang, Yingjie Wu, Song Liu, Chemical Synthesis. 5(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415420992

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) are widely used in carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR) due to their distinctive electronic configuration and coordination environment. However, designing catalysts with porous structures that provide more active sites is a challenge in practice. Herein, we utilized the porous network structure of melamine foam (MF) and high temperature calcination to increase the number of nickel atoms to promote the formation of Ni-N&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; active sites, resulting in nitrogen-coordinated nickel SACs with high catalytic activity. The X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy test demonstrates that the optimal calcination temperature of 900 &#176;C can achieve a Ni-N&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; site content of 9.47 at.%, which is significantly higher than that of other temperature conditions. This confirms that the calcination temperature has a decisive regulatory effect on the nitrogen-doped configuration and the formation of active sites. Furthermore, MF facilitated efficient electron transfer, resulting in improved catalytic performance. The Faradaic efficiency of CO (FE&lt;sub&gt;CO&lt;/sub&gt;) could reach 91% at -0.66 V vs. reversible hydrogen electrode. In situ Infrared Spectroscopy for real-time monitoring has demonstrated a linear relationship between Ni-N&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; and the reaction intermediate &lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;CO content, indicating that an elevated Ni-N&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; content may facilitate the generation of more active sites and expedite the kinetic process of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR. The density functional theory calculations reveal that the Ni-N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; coordination in the Ni-N&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; surface is responsible for the superior catalytic activity of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR due to the moderate adsorption strength of &lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;COOH with less negative U&lt;sub&gt;L&lt;/sub&gt; (-0.87 V). This experiment provides an innovative way to increase the active site content of SACs in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR.</description>
      <author>Anqi Wei, Xu Yang, Jiangfang Wang, Lei Shi, Chong Wang, Yingjie Wu, Song Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain engineering of heterogeneous catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111997</link>
      <description>Yuan Zhao, Hanqi Yu, Jiuchao Tang, Yingmei Li, Xue Yong, Xin Tu, Jing Wang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415422540

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan Zhao, Hanqi Yu, Jiuchao Tang, Yingmei Li, Xue Yong, Xin Tu, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111997</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interplay of water film dewetting and hydrogen evolution on Pt(111): Insights from a machine-generated interatomic potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0296498</link>
      <description>Michael E. Foster, N. C. Bartelt, Reese E. Jones, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(16)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415424923

                The processes that determine the kinetics of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) on metal surfaces remain a topic of discussion despite their long-standing importance in improving the efficiency of hydrogen generation. A major cause of this uncertainty is the extreme heterogeneity of the environment at the water&#8211;metal interface, which complicates the construction of simple models. To make progress, computationally efficient modeling methods need to be developed to handle the intricate nature of the water interface. In this paper, we use an implicit electrolyte approach suitable for ab initio dynamics, which allows the surface chemistry to be explicitly modeled with density functional theory while approximating the electrolyte with a continuum method. This approach incorporates ionic screening in the electrolyte via a Poisson&#8211;Boltzmann model, enabling the modeling of charged electrochemical interfaces in a dynamic, fluctuating environment. Our results qualitatively reveal a new factor that is likely important in understanding the HER: the location and structure of the interface where hydrogen is generated differ from where protons are exchanged between the water and metal. In particular, hydrogen is generated in regions where the water density is low (i.e., where the water film has dewetted from the substrate), while the adatom&#8211;water exchange reaction occurs in regions of high water density. Thus, the diffusion of hydrogen between these regions needs to be considered in the overall kinetics and may be a rate-limiting step.</description>
      <author>Michael E. Foster, N. C. Bartelt, Reese E. Jones</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0296498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial Fluorine-Modulated M-N &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; -C SACs for Electrochemical CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction: Mechanistic Insights into Ligand Interaction Strength</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c03490</link>
      <description>Shanlin Chen, Haiyan Zhu, Tingting Li, Chou Wu, Shaobo Jia, Zhifeng Ren, Jingzhi Shang, Muhammad Ghulam, Bingbing Suo, Wenli Zou, Yawei Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415432804

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) based on axial modification have received much attention with respect to the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR). Revealing the action mechanism of ligands and, at the same time, constructing the interaction relationship between ligands and the structure and activity of catalysts can provide important guidance for the design of highly efficient electrocatalysts for the CO2RR. In this paper, the mechanism of the reduction of CO2 to methanol (CH3OH) on 19 transition metal-coordinated nitrogen-doped carbon (M-N4-C) and axial F atom modified M-N4-C (M-N4F-C) was studied through density functional theory calculations. Moreover, the influence of axial F atoms on M-N4F-C catalytic activity was further revealed. The electrocatalytic reduction activity of M-N4-C SACs toward CO2 depends strongly on the outermost d-shell electron number and electronegativity of the selected metal. The incorporation of axial atoms alters the coordination structure and charge distribution of the central metal atoms, which not only enhances the stability (especially the electrochemical stability) of the M-N4F-C SACs but also modulates the adsorption strength of the intermediate species, thereby either increasing or decreasing the catalytic activity. The catalytic activity is determined by the intrinsic properties of the ligands and metal atoms. Four SACs (Mn-N4-C, Zn-N4-C, Co-N4F-C, and Ru-N4F-C) that can be utilized for the CO2RR are used in the experiments, exhibiting remarkable catalytic activity and stability. Importantly, the electronegativity of the ligands (&#951;ACL), the number of lone pairs of electrons in the ligand (m), and the electronegativity of the central metal atom (&#951;M) are proposed as key factors to describe the interaction relationship between the ligand and the metal center. Based on these parameters, a ligand interaction strength (&#955;) is introduced to quantitatively evaluate this interaction. Furthermore, several ligands with different &#955; values (CN &lt; F &lt; O &lt; N) were employed for axial modification, demonstrating that &#955; can effectively elucidate the influence of ligands on the geometric and electronic structures of SACs. By correlating &#955; with the adsorption energy of critical intermediate *OCHO, V-N4CN-C, Cr-N4CN-C, and Mo-N4CN-C were identified as promising electrocatalysts for the CO2RR. Our study provides useful guidance for understanding the influence of axial ligands on the electrocatalytic CO2RR and for designing highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Shanlin Chen, Haiyan Zhu, Tingting Li, Chou Wu, Shaobo Jia, Zhifeng Ren, Jingzhi Shang, Muhammad Ghulam, Bingbing Suo, Wenli Zou, Yawei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c03490</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Performance Fe&#8211;MoS &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst for Efficient Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia: Synergistic Design for Sustainable Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c04274</link>
      <description>N. Marino, G Milazzo, R. Farina, Corrado Bongiorno, Giuseppe Fisicaro, Sebania Libertino, S. Lombardo, S. Privitera, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415433211

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. Marino, G Milazzo, R. Farina, Corrado Bongiorno, Giuseppe Fisicaro, Sebania Libertino, S. Lombardo, S. Privitera</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c04274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential Catalytic Mechanism of Copper Foil-Supported Borophene-Loaded 4d Transition-Metal Single-Atom Catalysts in Hydrogen/Oxygen Electrode Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c03411</link>
      <description>S.S. Liu, Haiyan Liu, Chenggong He, Hong-Ye Hu, H. C. Ling, X. Lai, Chao Liu, Xunjun Chen, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415433407

                Combining the numerous advantages of copper foil and borophene, the electrochemical performance of copper foil-supported borophene loaded with 4d transition-metal single-atom catalysts (CF@&#945;-B_TM) in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) was investigated using density functional theory (DFT). We systematically analyze the CF@&#945;-B_TM catalyst stability, electronic properties, and catalytic activity in the hydrogen-oxygen electrode reaction. In the oxygen electrode reaction, as the atomic number of the loaded metal atoms increases, the adsorption energy of intermediates on CF@&#945;-B-TM gradually increases, while the adsorption ability gradually decreases. Afterward, it was calculated that the OH-modified CF@&#945;-B_Rh_OH exhibited excellent ORR and OER bifunctional catalytic activities with ORR and OER overpotentials of 0.35 and 0.47 V. In the hydrogen electrode reaction, CF@&#945;-B_Mo exhibited high HER catalytic activities with overpotentials of 0.05 V.</description>
      <author>S.S. Liu, Haiyan Liu, Chenggong He, Hong-Ye Hu, H. C. Ling, X. Lai, Chao Liu, Xunjun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c03411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Spatially Adjacent Sites with Synergistic Spin Polarization Effect to Promote Sulfur Redox Kinetics in Lithium&#8208;Sulfur Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202508033</link>
      <description>Shaobing Zhou, Xi Chen, Lanke Luo, Zuhong Xiong, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin, Wenbo Yue, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415436143

                Abstract The kinetics of sulfur catalytic reactions serve as a fundamental cornerstone for maximizing both the capacity and stability of lithium&#8208;sulfur batteries (LSBs). Recently, investigations into Li&#8208;S catalysts predominantly center around the optimization of energy levels to bolster adsorption and catalytic conversion processes. However, a significant oversight persists, as the profound influence of electron spin states on charge transfer dynamics and orbital interactions is frequently neglected. Herein, NH 4 MnF 3 is synthesized as a sulfur host due to the strongly polarized Mn&#8208;F bonds, which generate a stronger ligand field and endow it with remarkable electrochemical activity. By capitalizing on the electric field&#8208;induced effect exerted by adjacent Co atoms, the crystal structure of NH 4 MnF 3 is optimized, successfully inducing spin&#8208;orbit splitting at the Mn centers. This achievement significantly enhances the overlap with the p z orbitals of polysulfides, effectively expediting the kinetic processes of sulfur redox reactions within LSBs. Notably, the Co&#8208;NH 4 MnF 3 demonstrates exceptional electrochemical performance. Specifically, at a high rate of 2 C, it retains a remarkable specific capacity of 686 mAh g &#8722;1 even after 1000 cycles. This work unveils the pivotal role played by the electron spin states of active centers in sulfur catalytic conversion.</description>
      <author>Shaobing Zhou, Xi Chen, Lanke Luo, Zuhong Xiong, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin, Wenbo Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202508033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the electrocatalytic activity of B-doped Nb2CT2 (T = O, S, Se, Te) MXenes for nitrogen reduction: a DFT study on the synergistic effects of surface termination and strain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164915</link>
      <description>Xiaoqian Lin, Zhen-Hong Han, Xin Zhang, Jin&#8208;Xia Yang, Yuan&#8208;Gen Yao, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415436754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoqian Lin, Zhen-Hong Han, Xin Zhang, Jin&#8208;Xia Yang, Yuan&#8208;Gen Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of thermodynamic stability and catalytic activity on Pt single atoms and small Pt clusters anchoring on MXene supports for the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5tc03015c</link>
      <description>Minhui Song, Mei Yang, Kai Wang, Chenyang Cao, Lu Xie, Qing Liu, Haixia Cheng, Hongfei Li, Panpan Gao, Yanjing Su, Ping Qian, Journal of Materials Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415439273

                Catalysts with excellent hydrogen evolution reaction performance were designed by anchoring Pt clusters of different sizes on MXene supports.</description>
      <author>Minhui Song, Mei Yang, Kai Wang, Chenyang Cao, Lu Xie, Qing Liu, Haixia Cheng, Hongfei Li, Panpan Gao, Yanjing Su, Ping Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5tc03015c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism Insight into Protonated N&#8801;N Bond Breaking Promoting C&#8211;N Coupling on Synergistic Hybrid Dual-Atom Catalysts of Metal&#8211;Boron Anchored on g-C &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; N for Efficient Urea Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c03879</link>
      <description>Haoran Yuan, Yizhen Wu, Ruinan Di, Hui Shi, Jishu Li, Qiang Wang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415439631

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoran Yuan, Yizhen Wu, Ruinan Di, Hui Shi, Jishu Li, Qiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c03879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Robotic GIWAXS at ALS SAXS/WAXS Beamline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/photonsci.5c00017</link>
      <description>Eric Schaible, Ivan Galikeev, Matthew Roizin-Prior, Garret Birkel, Yunfei Wang, Wiebke K&#246;pp, Raja Vyshnavi Sriramoju, Harold Barnard, Chinweike Osubor, Camille Molsick-Gibson, Piotr Gach, Sujoy Roy, Xiaodan Gu, Dylan McReynolds, Alexander Hexemer, Lucas Kistulentz, Damon English, Dilworth Y. Parkinson, Chenhui Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415439868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eric Schaible, Ivan Galikeev, Matthew Roizin-Prior, Garret Birkel, Yunfei Wang, Wiebke K&#246;pp, Raja Vyshnavi Sriramoju, Harold Barnard, Chinweike Osubor, Camille Molsick-Gibson, Piotr Gach, Sujoy Roy, Xiaodan Gu, Dylan McReynolds, Alexander Hexemer, Lucas Kistulentz, Damon English, Dilworth Y. Parkinson, Chenhui Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/photonsci.5c00017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exocortex Network for AI-Augmented Human-Led Scientific Expedition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/photonsci.5c00009</link>
      <description>Esther H. R. Tsai, Kevin G. Yager, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415443294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Esther H. R. Tsai, Kevin G. Yager</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/photonsci.5c00009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven screening of single-atom catalysts supported on 2D transition metal dichalcogenides for oxygen evolution/reduction reactions (OER/ORR)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164976</link>
      <description>Lintao Xu, Yuhong Huang, Ruhai Du, Yinmin Wang, Haiping Lin, Fei Ma, Xiumei Wei, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415447716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lintao Xu, Yuhong Huang, Ruhai Du, Yinmin Wang, Haiping Lin, Fei Ma, Xiumei Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164976</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the O p band center in Co3O4 catalysts by Fe doping for Switching lattice Oxygen-Mediated mechanism in Acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137224</link>
      <description>Yangshuo Liu, Yaotian Yan, Feiyu Xu, Liang Qiao, Jiehe Sui, Weimin Cai, Xiaohang Zheng, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415448101

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yangshuo Liu, Yaotian Yan, Feiyu Xu, Liang Qiao, Jiehe Sui, Weimin Cai, Xiaohang Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation strategy of 1T-MoS2 catalyst and its application in electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction: A literature review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.152128</link>
      <description>Tingting Li, Haiyan Zhu, Shanlin Chen, Chou Wu, Shaobo Jia, Yawei Li, Yixuan Huang, Z. H. Jiang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 188(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415452449

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Li, Haiyan Zhu, Shanlin Chen, Chou Wu, Shaobo Jia, Yawei Li, Yixuan Huang, Z. H. Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.152128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative evaluation of isotherm and kinetic models for optimizing fixed-bed direct air capture systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169895</link>
      <description>Dana Marini&#269;, &#381;an Lavri&#269;, Matej Hu&#353;, Janvit Ter&#382;an, Bla&#382; Likozar, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415370898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dana Marini&#269;, &#381;an Lavri&#269;, Matej Hu&#353;, Janvit Ter&#382;an, Bla&#382; Likozar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Catalysis Understanding via Large Language Model Data Extraction and Shallow Machine Learning Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c01087</link>
      <description>Brianna R. Farris, Kevin C. Leonard, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415398029

                Catalysis is inherently complex. The lack of precise knowledge available to experimental researchers about the microenvironment, catalytic sites, mechanisms, and changes that occur under reaction conditions has hindered the effectiveness of deep-learning artificial intelligence algorithms to predict catalyst behavior under reaction conditions. Given the type and quality of data available in the scientific literature, there are still open questions on how machine learning can be used by experimentalists working in the field of catalysis to accelerate catalyst design. Here, we present a framework that leverages large language models to extract textual data from known and trusted sources to automatically generate large, but relatively low-fidelity, experimental catalysis data sets across many research groups. We also show that instead of using deep-learning models, which require high-quality data, shallow learning models with posthoc interpretability can extract valuable information about experimental catalytic systems from these low-fidelity data sets. The innovation of this work lies not in the model development but in the prompt engineering, data encoding, and question architectures employed to extract meaningful information. We applied this framework to two different model reactions: the electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide and the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction. We showcase that this framework has the ability to uncover known and established facts within the catalysis community, such as the catalytic properties of Cu, as well as novel insights, including the critical role of voltages above a certain threshold in producing multicarbon products from CO2. We anticipate that this proposed framework will serve as an entryway for experimental catalytic researchers to utilize machine learning to rapidly process literature, generate novel hypotheses, and design experiments to accelerate catalyst development.</description>
      <author>Brianna R. Farris, Kevin C. Leonard</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c01087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alchemical diastereomers from antisymmetric alchemical perturbations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0283286</link>
      <description>O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Giorgio Domenichini, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(16)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415425006

                The energy difference between two iso-electronic systems can be approximated by the first order Hellmann&#8211;Feynman derivative with respect to the linear alchemical coupling parameter, evaluated using the electron density of the corresponding averaged Hamiltonian. This approximation is exact up to third order because even-order contributions cancel out. This finding holds for any iso-electronic compound pair (dubbed &#8220;alchemical diastereomers&#8221;), regardless of differences in configuration, composition, or energy, and consequently, relative energy estimates for all possible iso-electronic alchemical diastereomer pairs require only O(1) self-consistent field cycles for any given averaging reference Hamiltonian. We discuss the relation to the Verlet algorithm, alchemical harmonic approximation (AHA) [Krug et al., J. Chem. Phys. 162, 044101 (2025)], relative properties such as forces, ionization potential or electron affinities, and Levy&#8217;s formula for relative energies among iso-electronic systems that uses the averaged electron density of the two systems [Levy, J. Chem. Phys. 70, 1573 (1979)]. Density functional theory based estimates accurately reflect trends in the charge-neutral iso-electronic diatomic molecule series with 14 protons (N2, CO, BF, BeNe, LiNa, HeMg, HAl), with systematically increasing errors. Using alchemical Hellmann&#8211;Feynman derivatives for toluene, we demonstrate the concept&#8217;s broader applicability by estimating relative energies for all 36 possible alchemical diastereomer pairs from vertical iso-electronic charge-neutral antisymmetric BN doping of toluene&#8217;s aromatic ring, with mean absolute errors of a few milli-Hartrees.</description>
      <author>O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Giorgio Domenichini</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0283286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00016-3</link>
      <description>, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415297692

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00016-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear deterministic hybrid dynamic modeling of time-to-event processes (LDHDM)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00007-2</link>
      <description>G.S. Ladde, Emmanuel A. Appiah, Jay G. Ladde, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415298230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G.S. Ladde, Emmanuel A. Appiah, Jay G. Ladde</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00007-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple and Scalable Kernel Density Approach for Reliable Uncertainty Quantification in Atomistic Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02595</link>
      <description>Daniel Willimetz, Luk&#225;&#353; Grajciar, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415262246

                Machine learning models are increasingly used to predict material properties and accelerate atomistic simulations, but the reliability of their predictions depends on the representativeness of the training data. We present a scalable, GPU-accelerated uncertainty quantification framework based on k-nearest-neighbor kernel density estimation (KDE) in a PCA-reduced descriptor space. This method efficiently detects sparsely sampled regions in large, high-dimensional data sets and provides a transferable, model-agnostic uncertainty metric without requiring retraining costly model ensembles. The framework is validated across diverse case studies varying in (i) chemistry, (ii) prediction models (including foundational neural network), (iii) descriptors used for KDE estimation, and (iv) properties whose uncertainty is sought. In all cases, the KDE-based score reliably flags extrapolative configurations, correlates well with conventional ensemble-based uncertainties, and highlights regions of reduced prediction trustworthiness. The approach offers a practical route for improving the interpretability, robustness, and deployment readiness of ML models in materials science.</description>
      <author>Daniel Willimetz, Luk&#225;&#353; Grajciar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02595</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
