<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 01:24:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A photovoltaic-electrolysis system with high solar-to-hydrogen efficiency under practical current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ads0836</link>
      <description>Qingran Zhang, Yihao Shan, Jian Pan, Priyank V. Kumar, Mark J. Keevers, John Lasich, Gurpreet Kour, Rahman Daiyan, Ivan Perez&#8208;W&#252;rfl, Lars Thomsen, Soshan Cheong, Junjie Jiang, Kuang&#8208;Hsu Wu, Chao&#8208;Lung Chiang, Kristian Grayson, Martin A. Green, Rose Amal, Xunyu Lu, Science Advances. 11(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407948630

                The photovoltaic-alkaline water (PV-AW) electrolysis system offers an appealing approach for large-scale green hydrogen generation. However, current PV-AW systems suffer from low solar-to-hydrogen (STH) conversion efficiencies (e.g., &lt;20%) at practical current densities (e.g., &gt;100 mA cm &#8722;2 ), rendering the produced H 2 not economical. Here, we designed and developed a highly efficient PV-AW system that mainly consists of a customized, state-of-the-art AW electrolyzer and concentrator photovoltaic (CPV) receiver. The highly efficient anodic oxygen evolving catalyst, consisting of an iron oxide/nickel (oxy)hydroxide (Fe 2 O 3 -NiO x H y ) composite, enables the customized AW electrolyzer with unprecedented catalytic performance (e.g., 1 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.8 V and 0.37 kgH 2 /m &#8722;2 hour &#8722;1 at 48 kWh/kgH 2 ). Benefiting from the superior water electrolysis performance, the integrated CPV-AW electrolyzer system reaches a very high STH efficiency of up to 29.1% (refer to 30.3% if the lead resistance losses are excluded) at large current densities, surpassing all previously reported PV-electrolysis systems.</description>
      <author>Qingran Zhang, Yihao Shan, Jian Pan, Priyank V. Kumar, Mark J. Keevers, John Lasich, Gurpreet Kour, Rahman Daiyan, Ivan Perez&#8208;W&#252;rfl, Lars Thomsen, Soshan Cheong, Junjie Jiang, Kuang&#8208;Hsu Wu, Chao&#8208;Lung Chiang, Kristian Grayson, Martin A. Green, Rose Amal, Xunyu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ads0836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Optimization of Compositions and Chemical Ordering for Bimetallic Alloy Catalysts Using Bayesian Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00467</link>
      <description>Xiangfu Niu, Shuwei Li, Zheyu Zhang, Haohong Duan, Rui Zhang, Jianqiu Li, Liang Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407953985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangfu Niu, Shuwei Li, Zheyu Zhang, Haohong Duan, Rui Zhang, Jianqiu Li, Liang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating adsorbed hydrogen for enhanced HMF electrocatalytic hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.02.010</link>
      <description>Yingjie Gao, Cheng Tang, Yao Zheng, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407954098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingjie Gao, Cheng Tang, Yao Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.02.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blocking Effect Retards Electron Release from Asymmetric Active Units for Selective Seawater Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c17958</link>
      <description>Zhipeng Li, Huimin Mao, Xiaobin Liu, Jun Wan, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Shaobo Huang, Qingliang Lv, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407958992

                During seawater electrolysis, chloride ion (Cl&#8211;) adsorption at the anode leads to an inevitable competitive chloride oxidation reaction (ClOR) with the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), compromising the long-term stability of the electrolysis process. Furthermore, Ni-based OER electrocatalysts are challenged by activity degradation due to the overoxidation of Ni3+. In response, we present a design of oxygen-vacancy-regulated asymmetric Nb&#8211;O&#8211;Ni bonds aimed at selective seawater oxidation. The experimental and in situ characterization results indicate that the blocking effect of oxygen vacancies effectively alleviates the electron release of Ni3+ and the electron enrichment of Nb5+ on asymmetric Nb&#8211;O&#8211;Ni bonds, achieving a stable and selective OER in alkaline seawater. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that oxygen vacancies in Nb&#8211;O&#8211;Ni bonds optimize the adsorption strength of reaction intermediates and break up the scaling relationship between *OH and *OOH intermediates. The constructed anion exchange membrane electrolysis cell achieves a cost efficiency of $1.07 per GGE (gasoline gallon equivalent) for H2 production at a current density of 1000 mA cm&#8211;2, maintaining operational stability for 100 h at 500 mA cm&#8211;2.</description>
      <author>Zhipeng Li, Huimin Mao, Xiaobin Liu, Jun Wan, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Shaobo Huang, Qingliang Lv, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c17958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum Carbide Nanoclusters on N-Doped Carbon Nanocages for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c07296</link>
      <description>Xue Bai, Haohua He, Biao Feng, Jingyi Tian, Yan Zhang, Yufan Zhang, Xizhang Wang, Zheng Hu, Qiang Wu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407961432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Bai, Haohua He, Biao Feng, Jingyi Tian, Yan Zhang, Yufan Zhang, Xizhang Wang, Zheng Hu, Qiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c07296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Descriptors in Predicting Catalysis Reaction Efficiency and Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03733</link>
      <description>Qin Zhu, Yuming Gu, Jing Ma, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407972183

                Accurately controlling the interactions and dynamic changes between multiple active sites (e.g., metals, vacancies, and lone pairs of heteroatoms) to achieve efficient catalytic performance is a key issue and challenge in the design of complex catalytic reactions involving 2D metal-supported catalysts, metal-zeolites, metal-organic catalysts, and metalloenzymes. With the aid of machine learning (ML), descriptors play a central role in optimizing the electrochemical performance of catalysts, elucidating the essence of catalytic activity, and predicting more efficient catalysts, thereby avoiding time-consuming trial-and-error processes. Three kinds of descriptors&#9472;active center descriptors, interfacial descriptors, and reaction pathway descriptors&#9472;are crucial for understanding and designing metal-supported catalysts. Specifically, vacancies, as active sites, synergize with metals to significantly promote the reduction reactions of energy-relevant small molecules. By combining some physical descriptors, interpretable descriptors can be constructed to evaluate catalytic performance. Future development of descriptors and ML models faces the challenge of constructing descriptors for vacancies in multicatalysis systems to rationally design the activity, selectivity, and stability of catalysts. Utilization of generative artificial intelligence and multimodal ML to automatically extract descriptors would accelerate the exploration of dynamic reaction mechanisms. The transferable descriptors from metal-supported catalysts to artificial metalloenzymes provide innovative solutions for energy conversion and environmental protection.</description>
      <author>Qin Zhu, Yuming Gu, Jing Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Method to Observe the Internal Amine Distribution in an Amine-Functionalized Resin Sorbent Particle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c05007</link>
      <description>Chenhuan Xu, Pengbo Liu, Yun&#8208;Lei Peng, Mingying Dou, Qiuqiao Jiang, Xiaohao Jia, Yongmin Zhang, Koyo Norinaga, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407980910

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenhuan Xu, Pengbo Liu, Yun&#8208;Lei Peng, Mingying Dou, Qiuqiao Jiang, Xiaohao Jia, Yongmin Zhang, Koyo Norinaga</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c05007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory-Guided Design of N-Confused Porphyrinic Covalent Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18645</link>
      <description>Pengpeng Shao, Zhixin Ren, Bo Zhao, Xiao Wang, Jie Li, Jing Xie, Bo Wang, Xiao Feng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407980914

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) enable the precise and controlled synthesis of single-atom catalysts with uniformly distributed active metal centers, offering opportunities to elucidate the impact of subtle coordination environment changes on the catalytic performance. Inspired by N-confused porphyrins, we designed 20 metalloporphyrin-based COFs with either M-N3C1 or M-N4 centers, where M refers to 3d transition metals from Sc to Zn, for the electrocatalysis of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Density functional theory calculations predicted Co-based COFs to be the best ORR catalysts among the screened catalysts. Hence, Co-N3C1-COF and Co-N4-COF with a high crystallinity were synthesized. The Co-N3C1-COF exhibited improved ORR performance over the parent Co-N4-COF, as it had a reduced overpotential and increased four-electron selectivity, corroborating theoretical predictions. The enhanced performance was ascribed to the increase in electron density on Co as the coordination environment transits from Co-N4 to Co-N3C1. This not only facilitated the adsorption of O2 and critical intermediates but also changed the potential-determining step, which in turn made the ORR free energy profile of Co-N3C1-COF approach equilibrium for all elementary steps, thus leading to a reduced overpotential. This combined theoretical and experimental work exemplified carbon coordination in porphyrin-based COFs as an effective strategy to facilitate the catalytic capability for ORR. A descriptor was also provided to guide the design of coordination-varied Por-COFs catalysts.</description>
      <author>Pengpeng Shao, Zhixin Ren, Bo Zhao, Xiao Wang, Jie Li, Jing Xie, Bo Wang, Xiao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable physics-informed machine learning approaches to accelerate electrocatalyst development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/jmi.2024.67</link>
      <description>Hao Wu, Mingxuan Chen, Hao Cheng, Tong Yang, Minggang Zeng, Ming Yang, Journal of Materials Informatics. 5(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407983602

                Identifying exceptional electrocatalysts from the vast materials space remains a formidable challenge. Machine learning (ML) has emerged as a powerful tool to address this challenge, offering high efficiency while maintaining good accuracy in predictions. From this perspective, we provide a brief overview of recent advancements in ML for electrocatalyst discoveries. We emphasize the applications of physics-informed ML (PIML) models and explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) to electrocatalyst development, through which valuable physical and chemical insights can be distilled. Additionally, we delve into the challenges faced by PIML approaches, explore future directions, and discuss potential breakthroughs that could revolutionize the field of electrocatalyst development.</description>
      <author>Hao Wu, Mingxuan Chen, Hao Cheng, Tong Yang, Minggang Zeng, Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/jmi.2024.67</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for discrimination of phase&#8208;change chalcogenide glasses</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/inf2.70006</link>
      <description>Qundao Xu, Meng Xu, Siqi Tang, Shaojie Yuan, Ming Xu, Wei Zhang, Xianbin Li, Zhongrui Wang, Xiangshui Miao, Chengliang Wang, Matthias Wuttig, InfoMat. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407985569

                Abstract Chalcogenides, despite their versatile functionality, share a notably similar local structure in their amorphous states. Particularly in electronic phase&#8208;change memory applications, distinguishing these glasses from neighboring compositions that do not possess memory capabilities is inherently difficult when employing traditional analytical methods. This has led to a dilemma in materials design since an atomistic view of the arrangement in the amorphous state is the key to understanding and optimizing the functionality of these glasses. To tackle this challenge, we present a machine learning (ML) approach to separate electronic phase&#8208;change materials (ePCMs) from other chalcogenides, based upon subtle differences in the short&#8208;range order inside the glassy phase. Leveraging the established structure&#8211;property relations in chalcogenide glasses, we select suitable features to train accurate machine learning models, even with a modestly sized dataset. The trained model accurately discerns the critical transition point between glass compositions suitable for use as ePCMs and those that are not, particularly for both GeTe&#8211;GeSe and Sb 2 Te 3 &#8211;Sb 2 Se 3 materials, in line with experiments. Furthermore, by extracting the physical knowledge that the ML model has offered, we pinpoint three pivotal structural features of amorphous chalcogenides, that is, the bond angle, packing efficiency, and the length of the fourth bond, which provide a map for materials design with the ability to &#8220;predict&#8221; and &#8220;explain&#8221;. All three of the above features point to the smaller Peierls&#8208;like distortion and more well&#8208;defined octahedral clusters in amorphous ePCMs than non&#8208;ePCMs. Our study delves into the mechanisms shaping these structural attributes in amorphous ePCMs, yielding valuable insights for the AI&#8208;powered discovery of novel materials. image</description>
      <author>Qundao Xu, Meng Xu, Siqi Tang, Shaojie Yuan, Ming Xu, Wei Zhang, Xianbin Li, Zhongrui Wang, Xiangshui Miao, Chengliang Wang, Matthias Wuttig</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/inf2.70006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning prediction of facet-dependent CO coverage on Cu electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/jmi.2024.77</link>
      <description>Shanglin Wu, Shisheng Zheng, Wentao Zhang, Mingzheng Zhang, Shunning Li, Feng Pan, Journal of Materials Informatics. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407986232

                Copper-based electrocatalysts, which hold great promise in selectively reducing CO2 into multicarbon products, have attracted significant recent interest, both experimentally and theoretically. While many studies have suggested a strong dependence of catalytic selectivity on the concentration of the *CO reaction intermediate on the Cu surface, it remains challenging for a direct experimental probe of the CO coverage. This necessitates a reliable computational method that can accurately establish the theoretical coverage-dependent phase diagram of CO adsorbates on the catalyst. Here we propose a scheme composed of density functional theory calculations, machine-learning force fields and graph neural networks as a solution. This method enables a fast screening of 7 million adsorption configurations based on a small set of density functional theory data, with a balance between accuracy and efficiency tuned by the combinatorial use of machine-learning force field and graph neural network models. We have investigated eight different Cu facets and discovered that the high-index facets such as (310), (210) and (322) exhibit a much higher CO coverage than the low-index counterparts such as (111), leading to an increased opportunity for C-C coupling for the former. Our results can provide a new perspective for the understanding of the fundamental role of CO coverage on the Cu surface for electrochemical CO2 reduction.</description>
      <author>Shanglin Wu, Shisheng Zheng, Wentao Zhang, Mingzheng Zhang, Shunning Li, Feng Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/jmi.2024.77</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance assessment of high-throughput Gibbs free energy predictions of crystalline solids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113770</link>
      <description>Rasmus Fromsejer, Bj&#248;rn Maribo&#8208;Mogensen, Georgios M. Kontogeorgis, Xiaodong Liang, Computational Materials Science. 252(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407989296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rasmus Fromsejer, Bj&#248;rn Maribo&#8208;Mogensen, Georgios M. Kontogeorgis, Xiaodong Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into performance descriptors and their impact on activity optimization strategies for cobalt-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216560</link>
      <description>Xinxin Zhang, Lei Wang, Ying Xie, Honggang Fu, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 533(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407992349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinxin Zhang, Lei Wang, Ying Xie, Honggang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overview on Building Blocks and Applications of Efficient and Robust Extended Tight Binding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c08263</link>
      <description>Abylay Katbashev, Marcel Stahn, Thomas Rose, Vahideh Alizadeh, Marvin Friede, Christoph Plett, Pit Steinbach, Sebastian Ehlert, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407997511

                The extended tight binding (xTB) family of methods opened many new possibilities in the field of computational chemistry. Within just 5 years, the GFN2-xTB parametrization for all elements up to Z = 86 enabled more than a thousand applications, which were previously not feasible with other electronic structure methods. The xTB methods provide a robust and efficient way to apply quantum mechanics-based approaches for obtaining molecular geometries, computing free energy corrections or describing noncovalent interactions and found applicability for many more targets. A crucial contribution to the success of the xTB methods is the availability within many simulation packages and frameworks, supported by the open source development of its program library and packages. We present a comprehensive summary of the applications and capabilities of xTB methods in different fields of chemistry. Moreover, we consider the main software packages for xTB calculations, covering their current ecosystem, novel features, and usage by the scientific community.</description>
      <author>Abylay Katbashev, Marcel Stahn, Thomas Rose, Vahideh Alizadeh, Marvin Friede, Christoph Plett, Pit Steinbach, Sebastian Ehlert</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c08263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-Enabled Band Structure Engineering in Layered PtSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Water Electrolysis under Ultralow Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c18077</link>
      <description>Hotae Jeon, Hyeonseok Kwon, Jae-Hyun Lee, Sun Kyung Han, Hyunjin Kim, Jaewon Heo, J.N Han, Seunghun Shin, Jiheon Park, Min Kyung Cho, Daniel J. Preston, In Soo Kim, Minho Kim, Won&#8208;Kyu Lee, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407999825

                This paper describes a simple design methodology to develop layered PtSe2 catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in water electrolysis operating under ultralow overpotentials. This approach relies on the transfer of mechanically exfoliated PtSe2 flakes to gold thin films on prestrained thermoplastic substrates. By relieving the prestrain, a tunable level of uniaxial internal compressive and tensile strain is developed in the flakes as a result of spontaneously formed surface wrinkles, giving rise to band structure modulations with overlapped values of the valence band maximum and conduction band minimum. This strain-engineered PtSe2 with an optimized level of internal tensile strain amplifies the HER performance of the PtSe2, with performance far greater than that of pure platinum due to significantly reduced charge transfer resistance. Density functional theory calculations provide fundamental insight into how strain-induced band structure engineering correlates with the promoted HER activity, especially at the atomic edge sites of the materials.</description>
      <author>Hotae Jeon, Hyeonseok Kwon, Jae-Hyun Lee, Sun Kyung Han, Hyunjin Kim, Jaewon Heo, J.N Han, Seunghun Shin, Jiheon Park, Min Kyung Cho, Daniel J. Preston, In Soo Kim, Minho Kim, Won&#8208;Kyu Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c18077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Fixation Enabled by Ferroelectric Switching in Doped Graphene/In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Dual-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c21092</link>
      <description>Mohammad Amin Akhound, Maryam Soleimani, Mahdi Pourfath, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408009676

                The electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) provides a sustainable alternative to ammonia synthesis. However, the development of catalysts with high activity and selectivity under ambient conditions remains a significant challenge. In this work, we propose a class of dual-atom catalysts (DACs), consisting of two metal atoms embedded in nitrogen-doped porous graphene (M2NPG) supported on a ferroelectric &#945;-In2Se3 monolayer. Using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we explore the effect of ferroelectric polarization switching on the structural stability, catalytic performance, and reaction mechanisms of these DACs. By computationally screening 27 metal atoms as active sites, we identify four promising candidates (V, Co, Ru, and Ta) with V2NPG@In2Se3 standing out due to its exceptional properties. The precise control of NRR pathways, along with tunable limiting potentials and selective product formation, can be achieved through the polarization switching of the &#945;-In2Se3 monolayer. The combination of low limiting potential, abundant active sites, tunable catalytic behavior, and high selectivity against the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) highlights the potential of V2NPG@In2Se3 as a promising alternative to traditional single-atom catalysts. This work demonstrates a versatile strategy for integrating DACs with ferroelectric materials, offering valuable insights into designing next-generation catalysts for NRR and beyond.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Amin Akhound, Maryam Soleimani, Mahdi Pourfath</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c21092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulations of oxidation behavior of the NbTiZr multicomponent alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130616</link>
      <description>Qingqing Wang, Xianggang Kong, You Yu, Tianyuan Xin, Lu Wu, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408011661

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingqing Wang, Xianggang Kong, You Yu, Tianyuan Xin, Lu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of dynamic oxygen vacancies in GQDs/NaNbO3 heterojunction for boosting photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.153</link>
      <description>Wei Shao, Fei Han, Yin Hu, Wei Chen, Yu Xie, Lingling Wang, Xuanye Chen, Fen Zhang, Lin Ding, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408014609

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Shao, Fei Han, Yin Hu, Wei Chen, Yu Xie, Lingling Wang, Xuanye Chen, Fen Zhang, Lin Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of the catalytic potential of platinum&#8209;antimony (Pt Sb) bimetallic catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction: Insights gained from density functional theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142002</link>
      <description>Manxi Leng, Pengyan Xue, Xin Chen, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408016484

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manxi Leng, Pengyan Xue, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Prediction of Novel Metastable MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00106</link>
      <description>Changle Zhang, Jie Feng, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408019782

                Manganese dioxide (MnO2) is a versatile material with numerous polymorphs that holds significant promise in catalysis and energy storage applications. Due to the different connection forms of Mn&#8211;O octahedra, the structural diversity of MnO2 exists in more than 20 crystal forms. Common crystal phases of MnO2 include traditional crystal phases such as &#945;-MnO2, &#946;-MnO2, &#947;-MnO2, R-MnO2. In this work, we employed the particle swarm optimization (PSO) method combined with first-principles calculations to predict 3 kinds of unreported metastable MnO2 crystals, P21/C&#8211;1-MnO2, Pbcn-MnO2, and P21/C&#8211;2-MnO2. We then systematically analyze these 3 structures have lower energy than &#945;-MnO2 which is widely used and stable in nature and they have better potential application in the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Notably, P21/C&#8211;2-MnO2 exhibited superior catalytic activity, featuring lower theoretical overpotentials than conventional MnO2 phases. These findings expand the known polymorphs of MnO2 and provide valuable insights into their potential in catalysis and energy storage, offering theoretical guidance for future experimental research.</description>
      <author>Changle Zhang, Jie Feng, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando-informed precatalyst programming towards reliable high-current-density electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-025-02128-7</link>
      <description>Lu Xia, Bruna Ferreira Gomes, Wulyu Jiang, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Yang Wang, Yang Hu, Alaa Y. Faid, Kaiwen Wang, T. T. Chen, Kaiqi Zhao, Xu Zhang, Yingtang Zhou, R.A. Mohan Ram, B&#225;rbara B. Polesso, Anku Guha, Jiaqi Su, Carlos Manuel Silva Lobo, Michael Haumann, Robert Spatschek, Svein Sunde, Lin Gan, Ming Huang, Xiaoyuan Zhou, Christina Roth, Werner Lehnert, Serhiy Cherevko, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer, Meital Shviro, Nature Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408034455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Xia, Bruna Ferreira Gomes, Wulyu Jiang, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Yang Wang, Yang Hu, Alaa Y. Faid, Kaiwen Wang, T. T. Chen, Kaiqi Zhao, Xu Zhang, Yingtang Zhou, R.A. Mohan Ram, B&#225;rbara B. Polesso, Anku Guha, Jiaqi Su, Carlos Manuel Silva Lobo, Michael Haumann, Robert Spatschek, Svein Sunde, Lin Gan, Ming Huang, Xiaoyuan Zhou, Christina Roth, Werner Lehnert, Serhiy Cherevko, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer, Meital Shviro</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-025-02128-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrified synthesis of n-propanol using a dilute alloy catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01301-0</link>
      <description>Yuanjun Chen, Xinyue Wang, Xiaoyan Li, Rui Kai Miao, Juncai Dong, Zilin Zhao, Chuhao Liu, Jianan Erick Huang, Jinhong Wu, Senlin Chu, Weiyan Ni, Zunmin Guo, Yi Xu, Pengfei Ou, Bingjun Xu, Yang Hou, David Sinton, Edward H. Sargent, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408034484

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanjun Chen, Xinyue Wang, Xiaoyan Li, Rui Kai Miao, Juncai Dong, Zilin Zhao, Chuhao Liu, Jianan Erick Huang, Jinhong Wu, Senlin Chu, Weiyan Ni, Zunmin Guo, Yi Xu, Pengfei Ou, Bingjun Xu, Yang Hou, David Sinton, Edward H. Sargent</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01301-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Research on the Anti-Poisoning Catalysts in the Catalytic Oxidation of VOCs: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15030234</link>
      <description>Longfei Wang, Chun Huang, Ziting Gao, Bing Cui, Mingqin Zhao, Menglan Xiao, Xiaolin Yu, Catalysts. 15(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408036094

                Volatile organic compounds (VOCs) from petrochemical, pharmaceutical, and other industries have serious damage to human health and the environment. Catalytic oxidation is a promising method to eliminate air pollution due to its high efficiency, wide application range, and environmental friendliness. However, in the actual industrial environment, the composition of industrial exhaust gases is complex, including VOCs, water vapour, chloride, sulfide and so on. The impurities would have competitive adsorption with reactants or react with the active sites, leading to the decline of catalytic activity, even the deactivation of catalysts. Therefore, this review summarises the recent research on the anti-poisoning ability of catalysts in the catalytic oxidation of VOCs, primarily focusing on the effect of water vapour, chloride, and sulfide. The catalytic oxidation mechanism manifested that the adsorption and activation of reactants are significant in VOCs degradation. On this basis, the mechanism of catalyst poisoning was analysed, and the inhibitory effect of impurities on the oxidation reaction was elucidated. According to the research status, three anti-poisoning strategies are proposed, including building a bimetallic system, modifying supports, and establishing the protected coating. This work provides a theoretical foundation and reference point for the rational construction of anti-poisoning catalysts in VOCs elimination.</description>
      <author>Longfei Wang, Chun Huang, Ziting Gao, Bing Cui, Mingqin Zhao, Menglan Xiao, Xiaolin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15030234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 reduction to CH4: Harnessing Fe1@B12N12 as single atom catalyst for environment restoration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106062</link>
      <description>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Khurshid Ayub, Abdulaziz A. Al&#8208;Saadi, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Tariq Mahmood, Surfaces and Interfaces. 61(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408036750

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Khurshid Ayub, Abdulaziz A. Al&#8208;Saadi, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Tariq Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abundant active sites in M2C12 monolayer as single-atom catalysts with efficient catalytic activity for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.249</link>
      <description>Shulong Li, Guo Tian, Yutao Chen, Yong Zhao, Fanggong Cai, Liang Qiao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408043584

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shulong Li, Guo Tian, Yutao Chen, Yong Zhao, Fanggong Cai, Liang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defects induce phase transition from dynamic to static rippling in graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2416932122</link>
      <description>Fabian L. Thiemann, Camille Scalliet, Erich A. M&#252;ller, Angelos Michaelides, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408045618

                Two-dimensional (2D) materials display nanoscale dynamic ripples that significantly impact their properties. Defects within the crystal lattice are the elementary building blocks to tailor the material&#8217;s morphology. While some studies have explored the link between defective structures and rippling dynamics in 2D materials, a comprehensive understanding of this relationship has yet to be achieved. Here, we address this using machine learning-driven molecular dynamics simulations. Specifically, we find that above a critical concentration of defects, free-standing graphene sheets undergo a dynamic transition from freely propagating to static ripples. Our computational approach captures the dynamics with atomic resolution, and reveals that the transition is driven by elastic interactions between defects. The strength of these interactions is found to vary across defect types and we identify a unifying set of principles driving the dynamic-to-static transition in 2D materials. Our work not only rationalizes puzzling experimental results for defective 2D materials, but also paves the way to design two-dimensional devices with tailored rippling dynamics. These insights could lay the foundations for a class of disorder-based catalytic and interfacial materials.</description>
      <author>Fabian L. Thiemann, Camille Scalliet, Erich A. M&#252;ller, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2416932122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot synthesis of hierarchical assembly of NiMoO4/MoS2/Ni3S2 on nickel foam for highly efficient and durable electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction in a wide pH range</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161095</link>
      <description>Senkai Han, Huiqin Yao, Jiayi Zhan, Chaonan Wang, Siqi Zhang, Qingyang Gu, Cheng Li, Shenghan Zhang, Hongliang Dong, Shulan Ma, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408073073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Senkai Han, Huiqin Yao, Jiayi Zhan, Chaonan Wang, Siqi Zhang, Qingyang Gu, Cheng Li, Shenghan Zhang, Hongliang Dong, Shulan Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and stable chlorine evolution reaction in a neutral environment using a low-ruthenium-doped CuMnRu/CC electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.417</link>
      <description>Yaoze Wang, Guangfei Qu, Yun Zhang, Linjin Li, Haiyan Wang, Ping Lu, Yuanchuan Ren, Minhua Cheng, Yingying Cai, Jun-Yan Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 112(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408080437

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaoze Wang, Guangfei Qu, Yun Zhang, Linjin Li, Haiyan Wang, Ping Lu, Yuanchuan Ren, Minhua Cheng, Yingying Cai, Jun-Yan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling co-acting effects of potassium and hydroxide ions on carbon dioxide reduction reaction selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.184</link>
      <description>Lin Liu, Dongxu Jiao, Zhaoyong Jin, Wenting Lu, Yilong Dong, Shuai Ding, L.-M. Duan, Mingguang Yao, Shan Xu, Yanhua Liu, Lei Zhang, Jinchang Fan, Xiaoqiang Cui, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 688(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407952643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lin Liu, Dongxu Jiao, Zhaoyong Jin, Wenting Lu, Yilong Dong, Shuai Ding, L.-M. Duan, Mingguang Yao, Shan Xu, Yanhua Liu, Lei Zhang, Jinchang Fan, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect-rich FeCoNiMnRu high-entropy alloys with activated interfacial water for boosting alkaline water/seawater hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161070</link>
      <description>Guangbo Liu, Chen Song, Xiaolei Li, Qisen Jia, Pengfei Wu, Zhihao Lou, Y. Ma, Xuejing Cui, Xin Zhou, Luhua Jiang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407961679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guangbo Liu, Chen Song, Xiaolei Li, Qisen Jia, Pengfei Wu, Zhihao Lou, Y. Ma, Xuejing Cui, Xin Zhou, Luhua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of metal-organic interphase in Cu-based electrochemical CO2-to-ethanol conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57221-x</link>
      <description>Yan Shen, Nan Fang, Xinru Liu, Ling Yu, Yu&#8208;Ming Su, Tian Tan, Feng Chen, He Lin, Boxuan Zhao, Jin Wang, Duan&#8208;Hui Si, Shunji Xie, Ye Wang, Da Zhou, Teng Zhang, Rong Cao, Cheng Wang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408055231

                Interphases are critical in electrochemical systems, influencing performance by controlling ion transport and stability. This study explores a metal-organic interphase in the electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) on Cu, extending the concept of interphases to CO2 conversion. Investigating organic modifications on CuOx, we discover metal-organic interphases over 10 nm thick in highly ethanol-selective systems, contrary to the expected monolayer adsorption. Using an automated platform, 1080 CO2RR experiments with 180 molecular modifiers identify functional groups affecting selectivity for ethanol and multi-carbon (C2+) products. We find that these modifiers consistently produce metal-organic interphases on the Cu or CuOx surface. These interphases modulate Cu coordination, CO2RR intermediates, and interfacial water configuration, significantly improving electrocatalytic performance. Testing across 11 CuOx-based catalysts validates this approach, culminating in the development of two electrocatalysts that achieve ~80% faradaic efficiency for C2+ products with ethanol partial current densities up to 328 and 507 mA cm&#8722;2. This study highlights the pivotal role of interphases in CO2RR, advancing CO2 conversion technologies. Interphases are crucial in electrochemical systems, but their role in CO2 electroreduction remains underexplored. Here, the authors report their importance in improving electrocatalytic performance by systematically investigating 180 molecular modifiers using an automatic electrocatalysis platform.</description>
      <author>Yan Shen, Nan Fang, Xinru Liu, Ling Yu, Yu&#8208;Ming Su, Tian Tan, Feng Chen, He Lin, Boxuan Zhao, Jin Wang, Duan&#8208;Hui Si, Shunji Xie, Ye Wang, Da Zhou, Teng Zhang, Rong Cao, Cheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57221-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bulkier anions versus hydrogen bonding in imidazolium ionic liquids: Stationary point analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115169</link>
      <description>Vitaly V. Chaban, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408082840

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vitaly V. Chaban</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standards for Meaningful Evaluations of Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials Software</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-80748-0_95</link>
      <description>Rika Kobayashi, Emily Kahl, Roger D. Amos, &#152;The &#156;minerals, metals &amp; materials series. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408085155

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rika Kobayashi, Emily Kahl, Roger D. Amos</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-80748-0_95</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for the Efficient Identification of High-Performance Metal-Doped Transition Metal Compounds for Hydrogen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-80748-0_62</link>
      <description>Xue Lu, Jie Dang, &#152;The &#156;minerals, metals &amp; materials series. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408085228

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Lu, Jie Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-80748-0_62</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of interface engineering and La doping to boost two-electron oxygen reduction to hydrogen peroxide over La2Sn2O7@La-doped ZnSnO3 heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03224-4</link>
      <description>Yanyan Sun, Kun Li, Muhammad Arif, Lei Han, Amjad Nisar, Ting Zhu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408087501

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanyan Sun, Kun Li, Muhammad Arif, Lei Han, Amjad Nisar, Ting Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03224-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver-Doped Porous Copper Catalysts for Efficient Resource Utilization of CO-Containing Flue Gases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenvironau.4c00121</link>
      <description>Zhengkai Zhuang, Guangtao Wang, Wen Zhao, Ruixin Yang, Yilin Zhou, Wenlei Zhu, ACS Environmental Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408092996

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhengkai Zhuang, Guangtao Wang, Wen Zhao, Ruixin Yang, Yilin Zhou, Wenlei Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenvironau.4c00121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N, S Coordination in Co Single Atom Catalyst Promoting Co2rr Towards Hcooh at Negative Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5163414</link>
      <description>H. L. Zhang, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Siyuan Liu, Hongyu Chen, Yi-tong Yin, Zhongyuan Yue, Shuxian Wei, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408093060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. L. Zhang, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Siyuan Liu, Hongyu Chen, Yi-tong Yin, Zhongyuan Yue, Shuxian Wei, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5163414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Catalysis for H2o2 Reduction Using Cu(Ii) Complexes with Nitrogen Donor Tetradentate Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5163265</link>
      <description>Janet Ocampo-Hern&#225;ndez, &#193;ngel Mendoza, Gilberto Rocha&#8208;Ortiz, Juan Pablo F. Rebolledo&#8208;Ch&#225;vez, Lillian G. Ram&#237;rez&#8208;Palma, Fernando Cort&#233;s&#8208;Guzm&#225;n, Marisela Cruz-Ram&#237;rez, Luis Ortiz&#8208;Frade, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408097789

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Janet Ocampo-Hern&#225;ndez, &#193;ngel Mendoza, Gilberto Rocha&#8208;Ortiz, Juan Pablo F. Rebolledo&#8208;Ch&#225;vez, Lillian G. Ram&#237;rez&#8208;Palma, Fernando Cort&#233;s&#8208;Guzm&#225;n, Marisela Cruz-Ram&#237;rez, Luis Ortiz&#8208;Frade</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5163265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Structure Prediction Meets Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03727</link>
      <description>Zian Chen, Zijun Meng, Tao He, Haichao Li, Jian Cao, Lina Xu, Hong&#8208;Ping Xiao, Yueyu Zhang, Xiao He, Guoyong Fang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408098824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zian Chen, Zijun Meng, Tao He, Haichao Li, Jian Cao, Lina Xu, Hong&#8208;Ping Xiao, Yueyu Zhang, Xiao He, Guoyong Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-to-Metal Charge Transfer Controls the Photophysical Properties and HER Activity of Ag&lt;sub&gt;13&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters Depends on the Hydrogen Adsorption Energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00101</link>
      <description>Aarti Devi, Harshita Seksaria, Rashi, Abir De Sarkar, Amitava Patra, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408099309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aarti Devi, Harshita Seksaria, Rashi, Abir De Sarkar, Amitava Patra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of water impurities on promoted and unpromoted cobalt-catalysts during the ammonia decomposition reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116054</link>
      <description>Zahra Almisbaa, Philippe Sautet, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408103035

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahra Almisbaa, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Outer- and Inner-Sphere Electrosynthesis from Biomass-Derived Furfural Using Single Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00468</link>
      <description>Sihang Liu, Zamaan Mukadam, Angus Pedersen, Jes&#250;s Barrio, J.V. Parker, Helen E.J. Tyrrell, Sarah J. Haigh, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Georg Kastlunger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408105894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sihang Liu, Zamaan Mukadam, Angus Pedersen, Jes&#250;s Barrio, J.V. Parker, Helen E.J. Tyrrell, Sarah J. Haigh, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Georg Kastlunger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel&#8211;Antimony Electrocatalyst for Durable Acidic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Proton Exchange Membrane Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00233</link>
      <description>Cheng Cai, Husileng Lee, Weili Shi, Y.H. Liu, Biaobiao Zhang, Licheng Sun, Tao Wang, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408106746

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Cai, Husileng Lee, Weili Shi, Y.H. Liu, Biaobiao Zhang, Licheng Sun, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Alkaline Water Electrolysis by the Rational Decoration of RuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; with the In Situ-Grown CoFe Nanolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c16691</link>
      <description>Sang&#8208;Woo Kim, Jeongah Lee, Yong Beom Kim, DongHwan Oh, Jun Kyu Kim, Bonjae Koo, Hyunseung Kim, Gi hong Jung, MinJoong Kim, Gisu Doo, Jongsu Seo, Tae Jin Lim, Kyeounghak Kim, Jeong Woo Han, WooChul Jung, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408113042

                Rational engineering of the surfaces of heterogeneous catalysts (especially the surfaces of supported metals) can endow intriguing catalytic functionalities for electrochemical reactions. However, it often requires complicated steps, and even if it does not, breaking the trade-off between activity and stability is quite challenging. Herein, we present a strategy for reconstructing supported catalysts via in situ growth of metallic nanolayers from the perovskite oxide support. When Ru-coated LaFe0.9Co0.1O3 is thermally reduced, the CoFe nanoalloy spontaneously migrates onto the Ru and greatly increases the physicochemical stability of Ru in alkaline water electrolysis. Benefiting from an 81% reduction in Ru dissolution after decoration, it operates for over 200 h without noticeable degradation. Furthermore, the underlying Ru modifies the electronic structure and surface adsorption properties of the CoFe overlayer toward reaction intermediates, synergistically catalyzing both the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction. Specifically, the mass activity of the oxygen evolution reaction is 64.1 times greater than that of commercial RuO2. Our work highlights a way to protect inherently unstable Ru from dissolution while allowing it to influence surface kinetics from the subsurface sites in heterogeneous catalysts.</description>
      <author>Sang&#8208;Woo Kim, Jeongah Lee, Yong Beom Kim, DongHwan Oh, Jun Kyu Kim, Bonjae Koo, Hyunseung Kim, Gi hong Jung, MinJoong Kim, Gisu Doo, Jongsu Seo, Tae Jin Lim, Kyeounghak Kim, Jeong Woo Han, WooChul Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c16691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrutinization of late first-row transition metals decorated octagonal boron (B8) ring complexes as single-atom catalysts for green hydrogen and oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra07274j</link>
      <description>Naveen Kosar, Tariq Mahmood, Muhammad Arshad, Muhammad Imran, Utkirjon Holikulov, RSC Advances. 15(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408117028

                DFT-driven design of late TM@B8 for enhanced SACs in HER.</description>
      <author>Naveen Kosar, Tariq Mahmood, Muhammad Arshad, Muhammad Imran, Utkirjon Holikulov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra07274j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced transition metal phosphide&#8211;based materials for hydrogen evolution reactions: a comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06166-8</link>
      <description>Bheema Divya, Manjunatha Kumara K S, Sunilkumar P Sunilkumar P, Srinivasa Budagumpi, Sumanjali Kota, M. B. Madhusudana Reddy, D. H. Nagaraju, Ionics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408118259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bheema Divya, Manjunatha Kumara K S, Sunilkumar P Sunilkumar P, Srinivasa Budagumpi, Sumanjali Kota, M. B. Madhusudana Reddy, D. H. Nagaraju</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06166-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom M/GDY catalysts for electrochemical ethylene conversion via tandem water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162865</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Sun, Wen Zhao, Wei Cai, Yuhua Chi, Hao Ren, Zhongtao Li, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408122811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Sun, Wen Zhao, Wei Cai, Yuhua Chi, Hao Ren, Zhongtao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P-NiMoN/NF Heterostructure Nanorod Arrays as Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Urea Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c22180</link>
      <description>Zixuan Zhang, Dongxing Tan, Jing Wang, Dan Zhang, Qingkun Kong, Weiqing Kong, Xiaowei Yin, Yuanyuan Feng, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408124543

                Electrolysis of water represents an effective method for the generation of high-purity hydrogen. Nevertheless, the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) exhibits slow kinetics, which leads to a high electrolytic potential and induces excessive energy consumption. In this work, nickel foam-supported 3D phosphide/bimetal nitride (Co2P-NiMoN/NF) nanorod array catalyst is prepared by calcination of NiMoO4, followed by phosphatization of Co(OH)2. The heterostructure catalyst exhibits excellent catalytic activity for cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER: &#951;100 = 98 mV, &#951;1000 = 297 mV) and anodic OER (&#951;100 = 277 mV, &#951;1000 = 382 mV) of water electrolysis in alkaline electrolyte, indicating its feasibility as a bifunctional catalyst for overall water splitting (OWS). Additionally, at a current density of 100 mA cm-2, the associated oxidation potential is decreased by roughly 160 mV when the anodic OER is replaced with the urea oxidation process (UOR), which has a far lower thermodynamic equilibrium potential. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the heterointerface between Co2P and NiMoN enriches the density of electronic states near the Fermi level, thereby enhancing electron transfer and promoting charge redistribution. This modulation precisely tunes the adsorption strengths of reactants during the reaction process, ultimately boosting the electrocatalytic performance. A current density of 100 mA cm-2 can be attained at a cell voltage of 1.51 V when Co2P-NiMoN/NF is used as the anode and cathode in the urea electrolysis cell. Notably, this cell potential is significantly lower compared to that of the water electrolysis cell (1.65 V), as well as the previously published values. The findings demonstrate that the Co2P-NiMoN/NF heterostructure can be used as a bifunctional catalyst for water and urea electrolysis and demonstrate an efficient strategy for the energy-efficient production of hydrogen through substituting UOR for OER at the anode of water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Zixuan Zhang, Dongxing Tan, Jing Wang, Dan Zhang, Qingkun Kong, Weiqing Kong, Xiaowei Yin, Yuanyuan Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c22180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Saturation: A Fundamental Principle for Single-Atom-Site Catalyst Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00643</link>
      <description>Chunjin Ren, Yu Cui, Qiang Li, Chongyi Ling, Jinlan Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408128326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunjin Ren, Yu Cui, Qiang Li, Chongyi Ling, Jinlan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced ORR and OER bifunctional performance of Co-N-C single atom catalyst by interlayer covalent interaction of graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162879</link>
      <description>Depeng Meng, Hongpeng Chen, Jinshuo Pang, Chunnian He, Chunsheng Shi, Naiqin Zhao, Enzuo Liu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408129206

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Depeng Meng, Hongpeng Chen, Jinshuo Pang, Chunnian He, Chunsheng Shi, Naiqin Zhao, Enzuo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design principles of non-noble metal catalysts for high-performance rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104155</link>
      <description>Pengxiang Liu, Yaqian Wang, Ruitao Lv, Guangying Zhang, Xu Liu, Lei Wang, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408129674

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengxiang Liu, Yaqian Wang, Ruitao Lv, Guangying Zhang, Xu Liu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient equivariant model for machine learning interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01535-3</link>
      <description>Ziduo Yang, Xian Wang, Yifan Li, Qiujie Lv, Calvin Yu&#8208;Chian Chen, Lei Shen, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407948128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziduo Yang, Xian Wang, Yifan Li, Qiujie Lv, Calvin Yu&#8208;Chian Chen, Lei Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01535-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favoring the Originally Unfavored Oxygen for Enhancing Nitrogen-to-Nitrate Electroconversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17380</link>
      <description>Xin Li, Guangtong Hai, Daniel Wan, Yiwen Liao, Zhangyi Yao, Fenglin Zhao, Lingzhi Huang, Jinsong Zhou, Gang Li, Gao&#8208;Feng Chen, Feng Ryan Wang, Michael K.H. Leung, Haihui Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408009662

                Current nitrate production involves a two-step thermochemical process that is energy-intensive and generates substantial CO2 emissions. Sustainable NO3&#8211; production via the nitrogen electrooxidation reaction powered by renewable electricity is highly desirable, but the Faradaic efficiency (FE) at high production rates is unsatisfactory due to competition from the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, we propose reengineering the catalyst's microstructure-to-macroenvironment interface by particularly utilizing the previously considered unfavored oxygen from the OER. We demonstrate that the re-engineered interface facilitates a record-breaking FE of 35.52% under 8 atm air, with an impressive increase in FE (41.56%) observed during a continuous electrochemical process lasting for 60 h due to the in situ formation of the O2-rich macro-interface environment. The revelation is anticipated to furnish groundbreaking perspectives for the reaction systems design in electrochemical nitrate production and other electrocatalytic fields.</description>
      <author>Xin Li, Guangtong Hai, Daniel Wan, Yiwen Liao, Zhangyi Yao, Fenglin Zhao, Lingzhi Huang, Jinsong Zhou, Gang Li, Gao&#8208;Feng Chen, Feng Ryan Wang, Michael K.H. Leung, Haihui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhibiting Overoxidation of Dynamically Evolved RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Achieve a Win&#8211;Win in Activity&#8211;Stability for Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18300</link>
      <description>Wenjing Li, Dingming Chen, Zhenxin Lou, Haiyang Yuan, Xiaopeng Fu, Hao Lin, Miaoyu Lin, Yu Hou, Haifeng Qi, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Haifeng Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408065754

                Proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis offers an efficient route to large-scale green hydrogen production, in which the RuO2 catalyst exhibits superior activity but limited stability. Unveiling the atomic-scale structural evolution during operando reaction conditions is critical but remains a grand challenge for enhancing the durability of the RuO2 catalyst in the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (a-OER). This study proposes an adaptive machine learning workflow to elucidate the potential-dependent state-to-state global evolution of the RuO2(110) surface within a complex composition and configuration space, revealing the correlation between structural patterns and stability. We identify the active state with distorted RuO5 units that self-evolve at low potential, which exhibits minor Ru dissolution and an activity self-promotion phenomenon. However, this state exhibits a low potential resistance capacity (PRC) and evolves into inert RuO4 units at elevated potential. To enhance PRC and mitigate the overevolution of the active state, we explore the metal doping engineering and uncover an inverse volcano-type doping rule: the doped metal-oxygen bond strength should significantly differ from the Ru-O bond. This rule provides a theoretical framework for designing stable RuO2-based catalysts and clarifies current discrepancies regarding the roles of different metals in stabilizing RuO2. Applying this rule, we predict and confirm experimentally that Na can effectively stabilize RuO2 in its active state. The synthesized Na-RuO2 operates in a-OER for over 1800 h without any degradation and enables long-term durability in PEM electrolysis. This work enhances our understanding of the operando structural evolution of RuO2 and aids in designing durable catalysts for a-OER.</description>
      <author>Wenjing Li, Dingming Chen, Zhenxin Lou, Haiyang Yuan, Xiaopeng Fu, Hao Lin, Miaoyu Lin, Yu Hou, Haifeng Qi, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Haifeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18300</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
