<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 01:11:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Modifying Parallel Excitations into One Framework for C(&lt;i&gt;sp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;)&#9472;H Bond Activation with Energy Combined More Than Two Photons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202404293</link>
      <description>Qingbo Shen, Jiali Chen, Xu Jing, Chunying Duan, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400973445

                Natural photosynthesis enzymes utilize energies of several photons for challenging oxidation of water, whereas artificial photo-catalysis typically involves only single-photon excitation. Herein, a multiphoton excitation strategy is reported that combines parallel photo-excitations with a photoinduced electron transfer process for the activation of C(sp</description>
      <author>Qingbo Shen, Jiali Chen, Xu Jing, Chunying Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202404293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theory of phonon-induced friction on molecular adsorbates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2400589121</link>
      <description>Ardavan Farahvash, Adam P. Willard, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 121(31)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400974197

                In this manuscript, we provide a general theory for how surface phonons couple to molecular adsorbates. Our theory maps the extended dynamics of a surface's atomic vibrational motions to a generalized Langevin equation, and by doing so captures these dynamics in a single quantity: the non-Markovian friction. The different frequency components of this friction are the phonon modes of the surface slab weighted by their coupling to the adsorbate degrees of freedom. Using this formalism, we demonstrate that physisorbed species couple primarily to acoustic phonons while chemisorbed species couple to dispersionless local vibrations. We subsequently derive equations for phonon-adjusted reaction rates using transition state theory and demonstrate that these corrections improve agreement with experimental results for CO desorption rates from Pt(111).</description>
      <author>Ardavan Farahvash, Adam P. Willard</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2400589121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Investigation into Modulating Surface&#8211;Adsorbate Interactions with Strain for Ammonia Synthesis on a Pd (111) Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01112</link>
      <description>Siddhesh S Borkar, Manish Shetty, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400976113

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siddhesh S Borkar, Manish Shetty</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Ultrathin CuAuAg Nanosheet-Assembled Three-Dimensional Nanoflowers for Photothermal Conversion and Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03360</link>
      <description>Haosheng Liang, Haixia Kong, Yuanyuan Min, Li Wang, Yanyun Ma, Haoyu Sun, Yi Wang, Yiqun Zheng, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400976355

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haosheng Liang, Haixia Kong, Yuanyuan Min, Li Wang, Yanyun Ma, Haoyu Sun, Yi Wang, Yiqun Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradient-concentration RuCo electrocatalyst for efficient and stable electroreduction of nitrate into ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50670-w</link>
      <description>Xinhong Chen, Yumeng Cheng, Bo Zhang, Jia Zhou, Sisi He, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400981079

                Electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia holds great promise for developing green technologies for electrochemical ammonia energy conversion and storage. Considering that real nitrate resources often exhibit low concentrations, it is challenging to achieve high activity in low-concentration nitrate solutions due to the competing reaction of the hydrogen evolution reaction, let alone considering the catalyst lifetime. Herein, we present a high nitrate reduction performance electrocatalyst based on a Co nanosheet structure with a gradient dispersion of Ru, which yields a high NH</description>
      <author>Xinhong Chen, Yumeng Cheng, Bo Zhang, Jia Zhou, Sisi He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50670-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study on NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Decomposition over Cu-Exchanged CHA Zeolites Using Automated Reaction Route Mapping Combined with Neural Network Potential and Density Functional Theory Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01831</link>
      <description>Shunsaku Yasumura, Taisetsu Kato, Yucheng Qian, Takashi Toyao, Ken&#8208;ichi Shimizu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400982626

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shunsaku Yasumura, Taisetsu Kato, Yucheng Qian, Takashi Toyao, Ken&#8208;ichi Shimizu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;tt&gt;cclib&lt;/tt&gt; 2.0: An updated architecture for interoperable computational chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0216778</link>
      <description>Eric Berquist, Amanda Dumi, Shiv Upadhyay, Omri Abarbanel, Minsik Cho, S.P. Gaur, Victor Hugo Cano Gil, Geoffrey Hutchison, Oliver S. Lee, Andrew Rosen, Sanjeed Schamnad, Felipe S. S. Schneider, Casper Steinmann, Maxim Stolyarchuk, Jonathon E. Vandezande, Weronika Zak, Karol M. Langner, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400983160

                Interoperability in computational chemistry is elusive, impeded by the independent development of software packages and idiosyncratic nature of their output files. The cclib library was introduced in 2006 as an attempt to improve this situation by providing a consistent interface to the results of various quantum chemistry programs. The shared API across programs enabled by cclib has allowed users to focus on results as opposed to output and to combine data from multiple programs or develop generic downstream tools. Initial development, however, did not anticipate the rapid progress of computational capabilities, novel methods, and new programs; nor did it foresee the growing need for customizability. Here, we recount this history and present cclib 2, focused on extensibility and modularity. We also introduce recent design pivots-the formalization of cclib's intermediate data representation as a tree-based structure, a new combinator-based parser organization, and parsed chemical properties as extensible objects.</description>
      <author>Eric Berquist, Amanda Dumi, Shiv Upadhyay, Omri Abarbanel, Minsik Cho, S.P. Gaur, Victor Hugo Cano Gil, Geoffrey Hutchison, Oliver S. Lee, Andrew Rosen, Sanjeed Schamnad, Felipe S. S. Schneider, Casper Steinmann, Maxim Stolyarchuk, Jonathon E. Vandezande, Weronika Zak, Karol M. Langner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0216778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeNNol: An efficient and flexible library for building force-field-enhanced neural network potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0217688</link>
      <description>Thomas Pl&#233;, Olivier Adjoua, Louis Lagard&#232;re, Jean&#8208;Philip Piquemal, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400983336

                Neural network interatomic potentials (NNPs) have recently proven to be powerful tools to accurately model complex molecular systems while bypassing the high numerical cost of ab initio molecular dynamics simulations. In recent years, numerous advances in model architectures as well as the development of hybrid models combining machine-learning (ML) with more traditional, physically motivated, force-field interactions have considerably increased the design space of ML potentials. In this paper, we present FeNNol, a new library for building, training, and running force-field-enhanced neural network potentials. It provides a flexible and modular system for building hybrid models, allowing us to easily combine state-of-the-art embeddings with ML-parameterized physical interaction terms without the need for explicit programming. Furthermore, FeNNol leverages the automatic differentiation and just-in-time compilation features of the Jax Python library to enable fast evaluation of NNPs, shrinking the performance gap between ML potentials and standard force-fields. This is demonstrated with the popular ANI-2x model reaching simulation speeds nearly on par with the AMOEBA polarizable force-field on commodity GPUs (graphics processing units). We hope that FeNNol will facilitate the development and application of new hybrid NNP architectures for a wide range of molecular simulation problems.</description>
      <author>Thomas Pl&#233;, Olivier Adjoua, Louis Lagard&#232;re, Jean&#8208;Philip Piquemal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0217688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Selectivity of CO2 Reduction Reaction on Elementary Metal Particles with DFT Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104866</link>
      <description>Qiang Wang, Jia Li, Yi Liu, Pi-Guey Su, Zhaohui Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401009030

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Wang, Jia Li, Yi Liu, Pi-Guey Su, Zhaohui Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104866</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of cations in hydrogen evolution reaction on a platinum electrode in mildly acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107784</link>
      <description>Chunmiao Ye, Xuan Liu, Marc T. M. Koper, Electrochemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401009209

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunmiao Ye, Xuan Liu, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI applications in energy transition and decarbonization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24010-2.00010-x</link>
      <description>Mohammad Ali Ahmadi, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401011533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammad Ali Ahmadi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24010-2.00010-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Higher-order equivariant neural networks for charge density prediction in materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01343-1</link>
      <description>Thomas Edward Koker, Keegan Quigley, Eric Taw, Kevin Tibbetts, Lin Li, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401011593

                Abstract The calculation of electron density distribution using density functional theory (DFT) in materials and molecules is central to the study of their quantum and macro-scale properties, yet accurate and efficient calculation remains a long-standing challenge. We introduce ChargE3Net, an E(3)-equivariant graph neural network for predicting electron density in atomic systems. ChargE3Net enables the learning of higher-order equivariant features to achieve high predictive accuracy and model expressivity. We show that ChargE3Net exceeds the performance of prior work on diverse sets of molecules and materials. When trained on the massive dataset of over 100K materials in the Materials Project database, our model is able to capture the complexity and variability in the data, leading to a significant 26.7% reduction in self-consistent iterations when used to initialize DFT calculations on unseen materials. Furthermore, we show that non-self-consistent DFT calculations using our predicted charge densities yield near-DFT performance on electronic and thermodynamic property prediction at a fraction of the computational cost. Further analysis attributes the greater predictive accuracy to improved modeling of systems with high angular variations. These results illuminate a pathway towards a machine learning-accelerated ab initio calculations for materials discovery.</description>
      <author>Thomas Edward Koker, Keegan Quigley, Eric Taw, Kevin Tibbetts, Lin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01343-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy alloys for catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-22142-2.00012-0</link>
      <description>Martin Lillebro Striib Nielsen, Jan Rossmeisl, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401012180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Martin Lillebro Striib Nielsen, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-22142-2.00012-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Ti active sites in Ziegler-Natta catalysts through realistic-scale computer simulations with universal neural network potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114414</link>
      <description>Masaki Fushimi, Devaiah Damma, Molecular Catalysis. 565(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401015645

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Masaki Fushimi, Devaiah Damma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A catalyst family of high-entropy alloy atomic layers with square atomic arrangements comprising iron- and platinum-group metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adl3693</link>
      <description>Cheng&#8208;Yu Wu, Yueh&#8208;Chun Hsiao, Ying Chen, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Tsung-Ju Lee, Chong&#8208;Chi Chi, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Liang&#8208;Ching Hsu, Hsin-Jung Tsai, Jiaqi Gao, Chun&#8208;Wei Chang, I&#8208;Ting Kao, Chia&#8208;Ying Wu, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ming&#8208;Yen Lu, Shan Zhou, Tung&#8208;Han Yang, Science Advances. 10(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401016416

                We report a catalyst family of high-entropy alloy (HEA) atomic layers having three elements from iron-group metals (IGMs) and two elements from platinum-group metals (PGMs). Ten distinct quinary compositions of IGM-PGM-HEA with precisely controlled square atomic arrangements are used to explore their impact on hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR). The PtRuFeCoNi atomic layers perform enhanced catalytic activity and durability toward HER and HOR when benchmarked against the other IGM-PGM-HEA and commercial Pt/C catalysts. Operando synchrotron x-ray absorption spectroscopy and density functional theory simulations confirm the cocktail effect arising from the multielement composition. This effect optimizes hydrogen-adsorption free energy and contributes to the remarkable catalytic activity observed in PtRuFeCoNi. In situ electron microscopy captures the phase transformation of metastable PtRuFeCoNi during the annealing process. They transform from random atomic mixing (25&#176;C), to ordered L1</description>
      <author>Cheng&#8208;Yu Wu, Yueh&#8208;Chun Hsiao, Ying Chen, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Tsung-Ju Lee, Chong&#8208;Chi Chi, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Liang&#8208;Ching Hsu, Hsin-Jung Tsai, Jiaqi Gao, Chun&#8208;Wei Chang, I&#8208;Ting Kao, Chia&#8208;Ying Wu, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ming&#8208;Yen Lu, Shan Zhou, Tung&#8208;Han Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adl3693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge transfer regulates electrocatalytic CO2 reduction on one-dimensional carbon nanotube/boron nitride nanotube heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128981</link>
      <description>Qigang Chen, Huohai Yang, Peng Wang, Qiang Ke, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401022912

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qigang Chen, Huohai Yang, Peng Wang, Qiang Ke, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Potential of Supported Superatoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403888</link>
      <description>Mehmet Emin K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, P. Jena, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401026613

                The importance of catalysts in industrial products is a driving factor in the search of efficient and cost-effective catalysts, creating considerable interest in the past decade in single-atom catalysis. One of the first requirements of a good catalyst is that it should bind to the molecules with energies intermediate between physisorption and chemisorption while simultaneously activating them. Herein, it is shown that superatoms, which are atomic clusters with fixed size and composition, can meet this challenge even better than the atoms whose chemistry they mimic. The reactions of molecules such as H</description>
      <author>Mehmet Emin K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, P. Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Doping Approach to Activate Lattice Oxygen Participation in K2WO4 Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124423</link>
      <description>Selvaraj Seenivasan, M. H. Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027067

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Selvaraj Seenivasan, M. H. Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrocatalytic Reduction of Nitric Oxide (No) to Ammonia (Nh3) on Metal-Free B4@G-C3n4 Nanosheet</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4906501</link>
      <description>Naga Venkateswara Rao Nulakani, Venkata Surya Kumar Choutipalli, Ahmad Azmin Mohamad, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027804

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naga Venkateswara Rao Nulakani, Venkata Surya Kumar Choutipalli, Ahmad Azmin Mohamad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4906501</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Past, Present and Future of UHV Surface Chemistry and the Birth of Single-Atom Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122566</link>
      <description>Audrey Dannar, E. Charles H. Sykes, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401031812

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Audrey Dannar, E. Charles H. Sykes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing highly efficient electrocatalyst for ORR and OER of transition metals doped g-C9N7: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112221</link>
      <description>Bo Zhang, Xianjun Chen, Tao Feng, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. 194(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401032730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Zhang, Xianjun Chen, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-deficient annealing boosts performance of CoNiFe oxide electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115675</link>
      <description>Thi-Thu-Hien Pham, Michaela Plevov&#225;, Stephan Bartling, Nils Rockstroh, Armin Springer, Adam Slabon, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401032956

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thi-Thu-Hien Pham, Michaela Plevov&#225;, Stephan Bartling, Nils Rockstroh, Armin Springer, Adam Slabon, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prospective techno-economic and life cycle assessment: a review across established and emerging carbon capture, storage and utilization (CCS/CCU) technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1412770</link>
      <description>Pingping Wang, Ada Josefina Robinson, Stavros Papadokonstantakis, Frontiers in Energy Research. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401038470

                Carbon Capture, Storage and Utilization (CCS/CCU) is critical for achieving net-zero emissions. Although the recent surge in CCS/CCU projects announcement, there is a clear gap between announced capacity (around 400 Mt CO&#8322; per year) and the Net Zero Emissions (NZE) scenario deployment target (around 1 Gt per year) by 2030. This review examines breakthroughs and advancements across both established and emerging CCS/CCU systems with different Technology Readiness Levels (TRLs) in various industrial sectors, emphasizing the necessity of prospective assessments for their acceleration and scalability. It examines the development and application of prospective Life Cycle Assessment (pLCA) and prospective Techno-Economic Assessment (pTEA), highlighting their limitations and importance of their outcomes in decision-making processes. Differences between the evolving dynamics of the technological systems (foreground) and the evolution of the overall socioeconomic system (background) are discussed. Incorporating scenario data from Integrated Assessment Models (IAMs) into pLCA and pTEA reveals an iterative relationship that significantly influences the outcome of both the environmental assessments and the economics of large-scale production of the CCS/CCU systems under study. This, in turn, could reshape investment strategies towards advanced technologies, necessitating their consideration within the evolving structure of IAMs. It is concluded that the inherent limitations of CCS/CCU technologies at an early stage of development require quantitative uncertainty analysis and demand robustness, interdisciplinary collaboration, policy intervention, and data transparency. The rigorous evaluative frameworks are key for developing economic, environmental and climate policies and enable well-informed decisions across rapidly evolving sectors. A framework is proposed in this review, outlining a multistep process that includes a series of databases and open-source tools to interface pTEA and pLCA with enhanced IAMs for CCS/CCU, demonstrating its potential to improve decision-making and policy development.</description>
      <author>Pingping Wang, Ada Josefina Robinson, Stavros Papadokonstantakis</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1412770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>150 years of oxygen chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00670-z</link>
      <description>, Nature Computational Science. 4(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401121830

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00670-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of Tm-Based Dual-Atom Catalysts Supported by B,N-Doped Biphenylene for Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4906500</link>
      <description>Maryam Fallahzadeh, Alireza Kokabi, Zahra Nasiri, Mina Fayazi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maryam Fallahzadeh, Alireza Kokabi, Zahra Nasiri, Mina Fayazi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4906500</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
