<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 01:46:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Resource Usage in Industrial Effluent: Synthesis of V/CrNC Oxygen Reduction Catalyst from Ammonium Polyvanadate (APV) Precipitation Wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40831-025-01085-4</link>
      <description>Han Yang, Yan Liu, Jibiao Han, Quan Yang, Yong Li, Ting&#8208;an Zhang, Journal of Sustainable Metallurgy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409697055

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Han Yang, Yan Liu, Jibiao Han, Quan Yang, Yong Li, Ting&#8208;an Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40831-025-01085-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Activity of an Ensemble of Sites for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol on a ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-on-Cu Inverse Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00848</link>
      <description>Zihan Yang, Simran Kumari, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Philippe Sautet, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409700371

                The significant increase in CO2 emissions from heavy fossil fuel utilization has raised serious concerns, highlighting the need for effective methods to convert CO2 into value-added chemicals. Here, we report a computational investigation on the catalytic activity of ZrO2-on-Cu inverse catalysts for CO2 hydrogenation to methanol, considering highly dispersed ZrO2 trimers on Cu (111). Such clusters present a large ensemble of formate-containing configurations, Zr3On(OH)m(OCHO)l, making the evaluation of the catalytic activity very challenging. We found that the sites on the various catalyst configurations exhibit markedly different activities for formate hydrogenation, despite their similar free energy and composition. To understand these differences in reactivity, we examined the structural and electronic nature of the low free-energy catalyst configurations and identified that the energy of the lowest unoccupied orbital of the reacting formate, modified by its binding with the catalytic site, is a descriptor for the reaction energy of the formate hydrogenation step. From there, we screened an ensemble of catalyst structures using this descriptor to predict highly active metastable catalyst configurations and computed the reaction pathways and transition states for formate hydrogenation. From this investigation, we distinguished reactive from nonreactive sites and formate species on the ZrO2/Cu inverse catalyst based on structural and electronic features. We showed that rare metastable configurations control the activity. Additionally, an efficient method for examining the reactivity of a large number of coexisting catalyst structures was developed.</description>
      <author>Zihan Yang, Simran Kumari, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine&#8208;Learning&#8208;Assisted Design and Optimization of Single&#8208;Atom Transition Metal&#8208;Incorporated Carbon Quantum Dot Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.70006</link>
      <description>Unbeom Baeck, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Duong Nguyen Nguyen, Jaekyum Kim, Jaehyoung Lim, Yujin Chae, Namsoo Shin, Heechae Choi, Joon Young Kim, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Woo&#8208;Seok Choe, Ho Seok Park, Uk Sim, Jung Kyu Kim, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409702011

                ABSTRACT Hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acidic media has been spotlighted for hydrogen production since it is a favourable kinetics with the supplied protons from a counterpart compared to that within alkaline environment. However, there is no choice but to use a platinum&#8208;based catalyst yet. As for a noble metal&#8208;free electrocatalyst, incorporation of earth&#8208;abundant transition metal (TM) atoms into nanocarbon platforms has been extensively adopted. Although a data&#8208;driven methodology facilitates the rational design of TM&#8208;anchored carbon catalysts, its practical application suffers from either a simplified theoretical model or the prohibitive cost and complexity of experimental data generation. Herein, an effective and facile catalyst design strategy is proposed based on machine learning (ML) and its model verification using electrochemical methods accompanied by density functional theory simulations. Based on a Bayesian genetic algorithm ML model, the Ni&#8208;incorporated carbon quantum dots (Ni@CQD) loaded on a three&#8208;dimensional reduced graphene oxide conductor are proposed as the best HER catalyst amongst the various TM&#8208;incorporated CQDs under the optimal conditions of catalyst loading, electrode type, and temperature and pH of electrolyte. The ML results are validated with electrochemical experiments, where the Ni@CQD catalyst exhibited superior HER activity, requiring an overpotential of 151 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a Tafel slope of 52 mV dec &#8722;1 and impressive durability in acidic media up to 100 h. This methodology can provide an effective route for the rational design of highly active electrocatalysts for commercial applications.</description>
      <author>Unbeom Baeck, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Duong Nguyen Nguyen, Jaekyum Kim, Jaehyoung Lim, Yujin Chae, Namsoo Shin, Heechae Choi, Joon Young Kim, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Woo&#8208;Seok Choe, Ho Seok Park, Uk Sim, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.70006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering materials science with VASPKIT: a toolkit for enhanced simulation and analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41596-025-01160-w</link>
      <description>W. T. Geng, Ya-Chao Liu, Nan Xu, Gang Tang, Yoshiyuki Kawazoe, Vei Wang, Nature Protocols. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409706620

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W. T. Geng, Ya-Chao Liu, Nan Xu, Gang Tang, Yoshiyuki Kawazoe, Vei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41596-025-01160-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectonics for Pentagon Defects in Carbon: Properties and Catalytic Role in Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500069</link>
      <description>Guoping Chen, Taro Koide, Junji Nakamura, Katsuhiko Ariga, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409710258

                Abstract The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is a crucial process in electrochemical energy technologies, featuring fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries in the coming carbon&#8208;neutral society. Carbon materials have garnered significant attention as economical, sustainable alternatives to precious metal catalysts. In particular, there have been increasing reports recently that pentagons introduced into graphitic carbons promote catalytic activity for ORR. In addition, interesting studies are reported on carbon materials&#8217; synthesis, characterization, and spin polarization properties with pentagonal defects. This review comprehensively summarizes the formation mechanism, characterization, spin, oxygen (O 2 ) adsorption, and ORR catalytic activity of carbon catalysts with pentagonal defects. By connecting the dots between theoretical insights and experimental results, this review elucidates the fundamental principles governing pentagon&#8208;related activity and offers perspectives on future directions for designing efficient ORR catalysts based on carbon materials.</description>
      <author>Guoping Chen, Taro Koide, Junji Nakamura, Katsuhiko Ariga</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction of Amorphous Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;S&#9472;O Material with a Functional Gradient Layer for Highly Efficient and Stable Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502293</link>
      <description>Lijuan Liu, Yingqiu Zheng, Wenshu Chen, Yongping Du, Linfeng Hu, Guoqiang Luo, Qiang Shen, Jian Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409710552

                Abstract Alkaline water electrolysis holds potential for large&#8208;scale, high&#8208;purity hydrogen production. However, the slow kinetics of water dissociation and challenging conditions in alkaline environments complicate the search for an electrocatalyst with both high activity and durability. In this study, a highly active and stable amorphous electrocatalyst is introduced, 3Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;S&#9472;O, developed via a straightforward electrodeposition method for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Notably, the surface of the 3Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;S&#9472;O catalyst undergoes a compositional reconstruction during alkaline HER, yet maintains its amorphous structure. This reconstruction spans roughly 6 &#181;m, leading to a gradual decrease in Ni and S content and a corresponding increase in O concentration toward the surface, thereby forming a stable, gradient active layer. Benefitting from this layer and its amorphous nature, the 3Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;S&#9472;O catalyst demonstrates superior alkaline HER activity&#8212;requiring only 170 mV to achieve an industrial HER current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 . It also showcases remarkable stability, with a mere 15 mV increase in overpotential during continuous HER at 300 mA cm &#8722;2 for 24 h, outperforming the commercial Pt/C catalyst. The research provides a novel approach to designing high&#8208;performance amorphous alkaline HER electrocatalysts cost&#8208;effectively and contributes insights for understanding and developing advanced amorphous catalysts across various applications.</description>
      <author>Lijuan Liu, Yingqiu Zheng, Wenshu Chen, Yongping Du, Linfeng Hu, Guoqiang Luo, Qiang Shen, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Na content and Mn defects in birnessite for high-voltage aqueous sodium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59223-1</link>
      <description>Xiaohui Zhu, Jing Xu, Qinghua Zhang, Tao Shen, Yuhang Zhuang, Tingting Chen, Shuang Li, Lin Gu, Hui Xia, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409712858

                Na-birnessite is a promising low-cost positive electrode material for aqueous sodium-ion batteries. However, its sodium storage capability is limited by narrow potential window and low redox activity in aqueous electrolytes. Herein, a Na-rich birnessite (NaMnO2&#8226;0.1H2O) with a highly ordered layered structure is reported as an advanced positive electrode for aqueous sodium-ion batteries, greatly suppressing Mn migration and its accompanying domino degradation effect, which enables a promoted upper charging cut-off potential up to 1.4 V (vs. Ag/AgCl), an enhanced specific capacity of 199.9 mAh g-1 at a specific current of 0.2 A g-1 based on the mass of active material for positive electrode, and greatly improved structural stability. In particular, a 3.0 V NaxH2-xTi2O5||NaMnO2&#8226;0.1H2O aqueous full cell prototype is validated, exhibiting a large specific energy of 117.1 Wh kg-1 based on the total mass of active materials in both positive and negative electrodes as well as a long cycle life. This work elucidates how interlayer chemistry and structural defects influence sodium ion storage in layered structures and provides opportunities for developing high-voltage aqueous batteries with large specific energy.</description>
      <author>Xiaohui Zhu, Jing Xu, Qinghua Zhang, Tao Shen, Yuhang Zhuang, Tingting Chen, Shuang Li, Lin Gu, Hui Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59223-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal Neural Network Potential Study of the Pt/CO Heterogeneous Catalytic System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106542</link>
      <description>Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Y&#363;suke Nanba, Michihisa Koyama, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409716699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Y&#363;suke Nanba, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Generative Model for the Inverse Design of Transition Metal Ligands and Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00242</link>
      <description>Magnus Strandgaard, Trond Linjordet, Hannes Kneiding, Arron L. Burnage, Ainara Nova, Jan H. Jensen, David Balcells, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409719662

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Magnus Strandgaard, Trond Linjordet, Hannes Kneiding, Arron L. Burnage, Ainara Nova, Jan H. Jensen, David Balcells</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Descriptors of Single-Atom Catalysts Supported on MXenes (Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C, Ti&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C) Determining CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07850</link>
      <description>Anna Vidal-L&#243;pez, Judith Mahringer, Aleix Comas&#8208;Vives, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409723086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna Vidal-L&#243;pez, Judith Mahringer, Aleix Comas&#8208;Vives</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EM-DAT: the Emergency Events Database</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2025.105509</link>
      <description>Damien Delforge, Valentin Wathelet, Regina Below, Cinzia Lanfredi Sofia, Margo Tonnelier, Joris Adriaan Frank van Loenhout, Niko Speybroeck, International Journal of Disaster Risk Reduction. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409724531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Damien Delforge, Valentin Wathelet, Regina Below, Cinzia Lanfredi Sofia, Margo Tonnelier, Joris Adriaan Frank van Loenhout, Niko Speybroeck</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2025.105509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D Novel o-B2N2 supported single-atom catalysts: Multifunctional activity in Hydrogen/Oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163335</link>
      <description>Chunling Zhang, Xunzhe Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409726015

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunling Zhang, Xunzhe Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the Repertoire of Photoswitchable Unnatural Amino Acids for Enzyme Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.04.17.649278</link>
      <description>Caroline Hiefinger, Michela Marcon, Verena Pape, Guillem Casadevall, Ranit Lahmy, Julian Nazet, Michael H. Bartl, Astrid Bruckmann, S&#237;lvia Osuna, Burkhard Koenig, Andrea C. Kneuttinger, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409728204

                Abstract Photoswitchable unnatural amino acids (psUAAs) play a crucial role in the engineering of light-sensitivity in enzymes, which holds significant promise for diverse applications such as biotherapy and biocatalysis. Besides near-quantitative photoconversion, the success and expediency of a psUAA for a certain application is defined by its interaction potential with the enzyme, its thermal stability and its effective wavelength of irradiation. To establish high versatility in the current repertoire, we have designed and synthesized six psUAAs based on azobenzene, arylazopyrazole, arylazothiazole, hemithioindigo and spiropyran photoswitches. The resulting psUAAs exhibit an enhanced interaction potential within an enzyme owing to their capacity for hydrogen bonding, ionic interactions, and metal ion coordination. Moreover, we observed diverse photochemical behaviors among the psUAAs, with four of them reversibly switching between the isomers with purely visible light. Notably, we identified orthogonal aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases that facilitate the incorporation of five of the six psUAAs co-translationally and computationally analyzed the synthetase-psUAA interactions. Finally, we evaluated the photochemical behavior of the five psUAAs within an enzymatic model and tested the photocontrol of catalysis confirming their diversity. Ultimately, our findings significantly expanded the repertoire of psUAAs and demonstrated their feasibility for enzyme engineering studies.</description>
      <author>Caroline Hiefinger, Michela Marcon, Verena Pape, Guillem Casadevall, Ranit Lahmy, Julian Nazet, Michael H. Bartl, Astrid Bruckmann, S&#237;lvia Osuna, Burkhard Koenig, Andrea C. Kneuttinger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.04.17.649278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Phosphorene: Theoretical Investigation of Its Promise as an Anode for High-Efficiency Lithium/Sodium-Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08089</link>
      <description>E. Granda-Rodriguez, J. W. Gonz&#225;lez, J.D. Correa, Elizabeth Fl&#243;rez, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409730397

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. Granda-Rodriguez, J. W. Gonz&#225;lez, J.D. Correa, Elizabeth Fl&#243;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Symmetry-oriented enumeration method for molecular crystal structure prediction and its application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.134112</link>
      <description>Xin Yu, Zengqi Xie, Yun-Ting Chen, Pengyue Gao, H. J. Zhao, Jian Lv, Yanchao Wang, Yanming Ma, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(13)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409731164

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Yu, Zengqi Xie, Yun-Ting Chen, Pengyue Gao, H. J. Zhao, Jian Lv, Yanchao Wang, Yanming Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.134112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detection and Measurement of Interfacial Charge Transfer Relaxation Time: FeNi/NF Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting to Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c02561</link>
      <description>Ahmed Halilu, Mahar Diana Hamid, Abubakar Abubakar Umar, Mohd Ali Hashim, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409732503

                A cost-effective nickel-iron (Ni-Fe) alloy with a predominant face-centered cubic(111) crystallographic orientation is demonstrated as a high-performance electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This alloy demonstrates mutual hybridization of Ni and Fe d-orbitals, bringing its valence energy level close to the Fermi level, comparable to that of the benchmark Pt/C catalyst. While water-splitting electrocatalysts typically undergo surface structural evolution after each reaction cycle, the time scale of surface reconstruction during HER remains uncharted. This study presents a NiFe/NF alloy with an enriched (111) orientation, an active surface area of 24,217 &#177; 0.1 cm2, an average crystallite size of 14.5 nm, and 0.634% lattice strain as an HER electrocatalyst. The electrocatalyst exhibits excellent performance towards HER, achieving a current density exceeding 800 mA/cm2, an overpotential of -133 mV, and a hydrogen turnover frequency of 2.8 &#215; 1012 s-1, and maintaining stable operation over 100 h. The distribution of relaxation time (DRT) analysis is introduced to deconvolute the HER process. A distinct high-frequency peak is attributed to interfacial charge transfer with a 2.38 &#215; 10-6 s relaxation time. Additionally, medium- and low-frequency peaks represent ion transport and hydrogen adsorption/desorption at 277.4 &#215; 10-6 and 905.1 &#215; 10-6 s relaxation times, respectively. The assignments can serve as a reference on the bulk and interfacial relaxation times critical for understanding electrocatalyst surface evolution using the DRT method, regardless of the material or type of electrochemical reaction. These findings are useful for advancing the design of low-cost, transition-metal-based alloys as catalysts for clean energy systems.</description>
      <author>Ahmed Halilu, Mahar Diana Hamid, Abubakar Abubakar Umar, Mohd Ali Hashim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c02561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in the measurement of thermochemical, electrochemical and photochemical efficiency of CO2 conversion to value-added products - its challenges and future directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meaene.2025.100049</link>
      <description>Subodh Chaudhari, Harish Pawar, Kajal Pawar, Pavan More, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409737971

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subodh Chaudhari, Harish Pawar, Kajal Pawar, Pavan More</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meaene.2025.100049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defective Carbon Catalysts with Graphitic N-Modified Adjacent Pentagons as Active Sites for Boosted Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c01475</link>
      <description>Lei Wang, Xuan Liu, Mengting Huang, Yun Han, Panjie Guo, Run Huang, Runsheng Chen, Helong Wu, Jinyan Zhang, Shuangming Chen, Aijun Du, Xin Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409738001

                Seawater electrocatalysis is highly desired for various energy storage and conversion systems, such as water splitting using seawater as an electrolyte and metal fuel cells. However, the adsorption of chloride ions (Cl-) on the active sites of cathodes would worsen the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity and stability, thus lowering the battery performance. Herein, the coupling active sites of graphitic N-regulated adjacent pentagon defects in carbon nanosheets (GAP/CN) were first synthesized by a low-boiling-point metal-mediated partial N-removal strategy. Experimental and theoretical results affirm the advantageous cooperative effect between adjacent pentagons and graphitic N toward the ORR in a harsh seawater environment, where adjacent pentagons act as the authentic highly effective ORR active sites and surrounding graphitic N site serves as the structural regulator to weaken the binding strength of harmful Cl- to prevent catalyst poisoning. As a result, GAP/CN delivers excellent ORR activities in diverse electrolytes, including 0.1 M KOH (half-wave potential of 0.87 V), alkaline artificial seawater (half-wave potential of 0.87 V), and natural seawater (half-wave potential of 0.71 V), and also good long-term stability, which can be comparable to commercial Pt/C. This study provides valuable guidance for the rational design of ORR electrocatalysts for seawater-related energy-conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Lei Wang, Xuan Liu, Mengting Huang, Yun Han, Panjie Guo, Run Huang, Runsheng Chen, Helong Wu, Jinyan Zhang, Shuangming Chen, Aijun Du, Xin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c01475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of NH3 from low-concentration NO on cascade dual-site catalysts in neutral media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6497629/v1</link>
      <description>Min Liu, Xiaoxi Guo, Tongwei Wu, Hengfeng Li, Yanning Zhang, Chao Ma, Hongmei Li, Liyuan Chai, Haitao Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409749339

                Abstract Electrosynthesis of NH3 from low-concentration NO (NORR) in neutral media offers a sustainable nitrogen fixation strategy but is hindered by weak NO adsorption, slow water dissociation, and sluggish hydrogenation kinetics. Herein, we propose a new strategy that successfully overcomes these limitations through using an electron-donating motif to modulate NO-affinitive catalysts, thereby creating dual active site with synergistic functionality. Specifically, we integrate electron-donating nanoparticles into a Fe single-atom catalyst (FeSAC), where Fe sites ensure strong NO adsorption, while electron-donating motifs promote water dissociation and NO hydrogenation. In situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS), in situ attenuated total reflection-infrared spectroscopy (ATR-IR), and theoretical calculations reveal that electron-donating motifs increase Fe site electron density, strengthening NO adsorption. Additionally, these motifs also promote water dissociation, supplying protons to lower the NO hydrogenation barrier. This synergistic interplay enables a cascade reaction mechanism, delivering a remarkable Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 90.3% and a NH3 yield rate of 709.7 &#181;g h&#8722; 1 mgcat.&#8722;1 under 1.0 vol% NO in neutral media, outperforming pure FeSAC (NH3 yield rate: 444.2 &#181;g h&#8722; 1 mgcat.&#8722;1, FE: 56.6%) and prior high-NO-concentration systems. Notably, a record NH3 yield of 3123.8 &#181;g h&#8722; 1 mgcat.&#8722;1 was achieved in a membrane electrode assembly (MEA) electrolyzer under a 1.0 vol% NO. This work establishes a new paradigm in NORR by simultaneously enhancing NO adsorption, water dissociation, and hydrogenation kinetics, providing a scalable route for efficient NH3 electrosynthesis from dilute NO sources.</description>
      <author>Min Liu, Xiaoxi Guo, Tongwei Wu, Hengfeng Li, Yanning Zhang, Chao Ma, Hongmei Li, Liyuan Chai, Haitao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6497629/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing hydrogen spillover in &#8220;double&#8221; transition metal dichalcogenide system for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237081</link>
      <description>Haoyu Yue, Bing Cong, Zhongnan Guo, Shuang Zhen, Pu Wang, Wenjing Guo, Wenxia Yuan, Journal of Power Sources. 644(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409754357

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoyu Yue, Bing Cong, Zhongnan Guo, Shuang Zhen, Pu Wang, Wenjing Guo, Wenxia Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A machine learning model with minimize feature parameters for multi-type hydrogen evolution catalyst prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01607-4</link>
      <description>Chao Wang, Bing Wang, Changhao Wang, A. Li, Zhipeng Chang, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409762158

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Wang, Bing Wang, Changhao Wang, A. Li, Zhipeng Chang, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01607-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Stm Study of Ni-Modified Pt(111) Electrodes: Structural Evolution and Hydrogen Evolution Activity in Koh</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5228962</link>
      <description>Shuehlin Yau, Chao&#8208;Lin Chung, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409766792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuehlin Yau, Chao&#8208;Lin Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5228962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in Self-citation Rates in High-impact Neurology, Neuroscience, and Psychiatry Journals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.88540.3</link>
      <description>Matthew Rosenblatt, Saloni Mehta, Hannah Peterson, Javid Dadashkarimi, Raimundo Rodriguez, Maya L. Foster, Brendan Adkinson, Qinghao Liang, Violet M Kimble, Jean Ye, Marie C McCusker, Michael C. Farruggia, Max Rolison, Margaret L. Westwater, Rongtao Jiang, Stephanie Noble, Dustin Scheinost, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409772274

                Citation metrics influence academic reputation and career trajectories. Recent works have highlighted flaws in citation practices in the Neurosciences, such as the under-citation of women. However, self-citation rates&#8212;or how much authors cite themselves&#8212;have not yet been comprehensively investigated in the Neurosciences. This work characterizes self-citation rates in basic, translational, and clinical Neuroscience literature by collating 100,347 articles from 63 journals between the years 2000-2020. In analyzing over five million citations, we demonstrate four key findings: 1) increasing self-citation rates of Last Authors relative to First Authors, 2) lower self-citation rates in low- and middle-income countries, 3) gender differences in self-citation stemming from differences in the number of previously published papers, and 4) variations in self-citation rates by field. Our characterization of self-citation provides insight into citation practices that shape the perceived influence of authors in the Neurosciences, which in turn may impact what type of scientific research is done and who gets the opportunity to do it.</description>
      <author>Matthew Rosenblatt, Saloni Mehta, Hannah Peterson, Javid Dadashkarimi, Raimundo Rodriguez, Maya L. Foster, Brendan Adkinson, Qinghao Liang, Violet M Kimble, Jean Ye, Marie C McCusker, Michael C. Farruggia, Max Rolison, Margaret L. Westwater, Rongtao Jiang, Stephanie Noble, Dustin Scheinost</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.88540.3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural&#8208;Insensitive Descriptors N&lt;sub&gt;s,p&lt;/sub&gt; Based on M&#8208;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;OH Active Entity for Predicting and Enhancing ORR Activity in 3&lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt; Transition Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500789</link>
      <description>Huan Li, Liyuan Yang, Weichao Wang, Jinchao Xu, Qi-Chao Shan, Gang Chen, Wen Wang, Ruiting Hao, Chunning Zhao, Xiang Wan, Weichao Wang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409773432

                Abstract The development of high&#8208;performance ORR catalysts is challenged by the understanding how the delocalized electrons in s &#8208; and p &#8208;orbitals influence oxygen intermediate adsorption and overall catalytic performance. To address these challenges, the from active unit to bulk catalyst (FAUC) design strategy is employed to investigate the roles of s&#8208; and p&#8208; orbitals in ORR activity. Specifically, six M&#8208;N 4 &#8208;OH (M = V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, and Ni) catalyst systems are constructed and analyzed using density functional theory (DFT), this study reveals that, compared to d &#8208;orbitals, the delocalized electrons in the s&#8208; and p&#8208; orbitals (N s,p ) exhibit a significant volcano relationship with ORR activity. This superior predictive capability arises from the weaker dependence of s&#8208; and p&#8208; orbitals on the local coordination environment. Additionally, a structure&#8208;activity relationship is established where shortening M&#9472;O and M&#9472;N bond lengths significantly increases N s,p . Through modification strategies such as doping and loading, the Co&#9472;N bond lengths are regulated in Co&#8208;N 4 &#8208;OH&#8208;C, resulting in shorter bonds and increased N s,p , which shifted ORR catalytic activity closer to the volcano peak. These findings validate the N s,p descriptor's rationality and universality across various 3 d transition metals, providing new insights for the design of high&#8208;performance ORR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Huan Li, Liyuan Yang, Weichao Wang, Jinchao Xu, Qi-Chao Shan, Gang Chen, Wen Wang, Ruiting Hao, Chunning Zhao, Xiang Wan, Weichao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Design of Mesoporous Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Films with Orthorhombic and Rhombohedral Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501534</link>
      <description>Minsu Han, Tomota Nagaura, Ho Ngoc Nam, Zihao Yang, Azhar Alowasheeir, Quan Manh Phung, Takeshi Yanai, Jeonghun Kim, Saad M. Alshehri, Tansir Ahamad, Yoshio Bando, Yusuke Yamauchi, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409773905

                Abstract Materials with the same chemical composition can exhibit distinct properties depending on their crystal phases. Here, the synthesis of two types of mesoporous Bi 2 Se 3 films at different reduction potentials is reported and their application in electrochemical glucose sensing. Mesoporous Bi 2 Se 3 is synthesized by incorporating block copolymer micelle assemblies into the deposition solution and applying a reduction potential. To characterize the crystal phases accurately, Bi 2 Se 3 films are heat&#8208;treated at 200 &#176;C for 1 h in a nitrogen atmosphere. The results reveal that the Bi 2 Se 3 films synthesized under different conditions exhibit clearly distinct phases: rhombohedral ( R &#8208;Bi 2 Se 3 ) and orthorhombic ( O &#8208;Bi 2 Se 3 ). The R &#8208;Bi 2 Se 3 &#8208;8 nm, featuring 8 nm pores and synthesized at a more negative reduction potential, outperforms its nonporous counterpart, achieving a glucose sensing sensitivity of 0.143 &#181;A cm &#8722;2 &#181;M &#8722;1 and a detection limit of 6.2 &#181;M at pH 7.4 in 0.1 M phosphate&#8208;buffered saline solution. In contrast, the O &#8208;Bi 2 Se 3 , prepared at a relatively positive potential, exhibits no glucose&#8208;sensing activity. The inactivity of O &#8208;Bi 2 Se 3 for glucose oxidation is likely due to the energetically unfavorable intermediates, as predicted by density functional theory calculations. These findings underscore the critical role of crystal phase control in porous nanomaterials and pave the way for developing innovative porous systems.</description>
      <author>Minsu Han, Tomota Nagaura, Ho Ngoc Nam, Zihao Yang, Azhar Alowasheeir, Quan Manh Phung, Takeshi Yanai, Jeonghun Kim, Saad M. Alshehri, Tansir Ahamad, Yoshio Bando, Yusuke Yamauchi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the new role of surface states in interfacial charge transfer at zinc ferrite photoanodes for efficient photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111066</link>
      <description>Guang-Ping Yi, Hong Liu, Yiping Zhao, Tiger H. Tao, Qiang Wang, Pengyi Tang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409776851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guang-Ping Yi, Hong Liu, Yiping Zhao, Tiger H. Tao, Qiang Wang, Pengyi Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal dichalcogenides-based electrocatalysts for green hydrogen production via water electrolysis: Design principles and modulation strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18686/cest294</link>
      <description>Dai Zhang, Ying Guo, Clean Energy Science and Technology. 3(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409780590

                The development of renewable energy-powered water electrolysis technology serves as a crucial prerequisite for realizing the large-scale application of hydrogen economy. Currently, commercial catalysts for water electrolysis predominantly rely on platinum-group noble metals, whose scarcity and exorbitant costs significantly hinder practical implementation of hydrogen production through water splitting. As promising alternatives to noble metal catalysts, transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) have attracted considerable research attention due to their high intrinsic catalytic activity and cost-effectiveness. Nevertheless, the catalytic performance of TMDs still lags behind that of noble metal benchmarks, prompting extensive and systematic investigations into performance enhancement and catalytic mechanisms. This review comprehensively summarizes strategic approaches for optimizing the electrocatalytic performance of TMDs in water electrolysis, integrating fundamental reaction principles, rational design philosophies for electrocatalysts, and the structure-property relationships of TMDs. Finally, we provide insightful perspectives on current challenges and future research directions in this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <author>Dai Zhang, Ying Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18686/cest294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Roles of Ions in Electrochemical Interface for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00700</link>
      <description>Jaegeun Noh, Han-Joo Kim, Hyein Park, Dong Young Chung, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409784084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaegeun Noh, Han-Joo Kim, Hyein Park, Dong Young Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic protonation of ligand sites in molecular catalysts enhances electrochemical CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adu6915</link>
      <description>Libo Sun, Tan Su, A.C. Fisher, Jieqiong Shan, Wei Chen, Hua Zhang, Xin Wang, Science Advances. 11(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409784277

                Molecular catalysts with functional group decorations are promising for electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction to produce valuable chemicals and fuels. Using nickel phthalocyanine derivatives with cyano, methoxy, and dimethylamino groups, this study unveils why decorating molecular catalysts with either electron-donating or electron-withdrawing groups can enhance their activity. Notably, the dimethylamino group&#8211;decorated catalyst demonstrated stable and nearly 100% CO 2 -to-CO reduction selectivity over a wide potential range and high CO partial current densities up to 300 milliamperes per square centimeter. Theoretical and in situ spectroscopic analyses revealed the critical role of dynamic protonation of ligand sites in activating the metal center, which can be facilitated by the decoration of electron-withdrawing groups. Conversely, electron-donating groups, although requiring higher energy for protonation, enhance the synergy between metal centers and protonated sites, favoring the formation of key *COOH intermediates and improving CO selectivity at higher bias. This study underscores the importance of dynamic protonation of ligand sites in optimizing functionalized molecular catalysts for enhanced CO 2 RR activity.</description>
      <author>Libo Sun, Tan Su, A.C. Fisher, Jieqiong Shan, Wei Chen, Hua Zhang, Xin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adu6915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and Theoretical Studies on Photocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to HCOOH by Biomass-Derived Carbon Dots Embedded Phytochemical-Based CdS Quantum Dots</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c01002</link>
      <description>Pramod Madhukar Gawal, Jumana Ishrat, Kalishankar Bhattacharyya, Animes Kumar Golder, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409784289

                Photocatalytic CO2 reduction provides a sustainable route to combat climate change by converting CO2 into valuable chemicals by using sunlight. This study presents both experimental and theoretical insights into the reduction of CO2 to HCOOH using biomass-derived carbon dots embedded onto phytochemical-based CdS quantum dots. The 0D CDs/CdS QDs(bio) composites exhibit rich sulfur vacancies and a more negative conduction band, effectively inhibiting CdS photocorrosion (SO42-) while enhancing the CO2 adsorption and photocurrent response. Additionally, it reduced PL intensity and increased decay time, suggesting the enhancement of charge separation and suppression of charge recombination. The optimal 0.4CDs/CdS QDs(bio) composite exhibited a remarkable CO2 reduction to HCOOH formation yield of 439.51 &#956;mol g-1 h-1 (apparent quantum yield of 3.81%) while retaining its structural and morphological stability. Density functional theory calculations reveal HCOO* as a key intermediate, confirming the thermodynamic preference for HCOOH formation over CO with a free energy change of -0.71 eV. This study introduces a novel bio-based CdS QDs composite modified with biomass-derived CDs, providing mechanistic insights into photocatalytic CO2 reduction for sustainable fuel production.</description>
      <author>Pramod Madhukar Gawal, Jumana Ishrat, Kalishankar Bhattacharyya, Animes Kumar Golder</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c01002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain and ligand effects in the 1-D limit: reactivity of steps</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01616-3</link>
      <description>Onyinyechukwu Goodness Njoku, Paige Fronczak, Kara Smeltz, Ian T. McCrum, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409786097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Onyinyechukwu Goodness Njoku, Paige Fronczak, Kara Smeltz, Ian T. McCrum</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01616-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Molecular Dynamics for a Charge-Potential Equilibration Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00286</link>
      <description>Robert V. Stanton, Mehmet Cagri Kaymak, Anders M. N. Niklasson, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409786188

                We introduce a shadow molecular dynamics (MD) approach based on the Atom-Condensed Kohn-Sham second-order (ACKS2) charge-potential equilibration model. In contrast to regular flexible charge models, the ACKS2 model includes both flexible atomic charges and potential fluctuation parameters that allow for physically correct charge fragmentation and improved scaling of the polarizability. Our shadow MD scheme is based on an approximation of the ACKS2's flexible charge-potential energy function, in combination with extended Lagrangian Born-Oppenheimer MD. Utilizing this shadow charge-potential equilibration approach mitigates the costly overhead and stability problems associated with finding well-converged iterative solutions to the charges and potential fluctuations of the ACKS2 model in an MD simulation. Our work provides a robust and versatile framework for efficient, high-fidelity MD simulations of diverse physical phenomena and applications.</description>
      <author>Robert V. Stanton, Mehmet Cagri Kaymak, Anders M. N. Niklasson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct seawater electrolysis: Breaking the dependency on noble metal-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.387</link>
      <description>Mi Gyoung Lee&#8236;, Seoungyeon Kim, Yong-Kul Lee, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409790242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mi Gyoung Lee&#8236;, Seoungyeon Kim, Yong-Kul Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourteen-Membered Macrocyclic Cobalt Complex Structure as a Potential Basis for Durable and Active Non-platinum Group Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c01306</link>
      <description>Zhiqing Feng, Junya Ohyama, Soutaro Honda, Yasushi Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Masato Machida, Masayuki Tsushida, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Makoto Moriya, Yuta Nabae, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409791038

                Non-platinum group metal catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under acidic conditions were developed using a CoN4 complex with a 14-membered-ring hexaazamacrocyclic ligand (Co-14MR). The carbon-supported Co-14MR catalyst (Co-14MR/C) showed higher ORR and HER activities than a conventional carbon-supported 16-membered-ring Co phthalocyanine (CoPc/C) catalyst. Heat treatment of Co-14MR/C at 600 &#176;C further enhanced its ORR and HER activity through structural modification of the Co active center via deprotonation of ligand amine groups. Density functional theory calculations indicated that the structural modifications of Co-14MR induced by heat treatment adjusted the adsorption energies of important intermediates in the ORR and HER toward optimal values, resulting in enhanced catalytic activity. The Co-14MR/C catalysts also exhibited higher durability in the ORR and HER than CoPc/C and Fe-14MR/C catalysts. Structural analysis suggested that the short Co-N bond lengths and small distortion of the CoN4 active site of the Co-14MR catalysts are the reasons for their high durability. These findings suggest that the Co-14MR structure is a promising design for non-platinum group metal catalysts for proton-exchange membrane fuel cells and water splitting.</description>
      <author>Zhiqing Feng, Junya Ohyama, Soutaro Honda, Yasushi Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Masato Machida, Masayuki Tsushida, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Makoto Moriya, Yuta Nabae</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c01306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating the screening of catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction in graphene materials based on DFT calculations and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115152</link>
      <description>Zikai Xiong, Shengjun Huo, Wanglai Cen, Jikun Feng, Jia&#8208;Hao Zeng, Meiling Hou, Yu Liu, Molecular Catalysis. 581(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409793550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zikai Xiong, Shengjun Huo, Wanglai Cen, Jikun Feng, Jia&#8208;Hao Zeng, Meiling Hou, Yu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser Irradiated Noble Metal&#8208;Free High Entropy Oxide 2&#8208;D Sheets for Highly Efficient Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202507930</link>
      <description>H. Denny Kamaruddin, Jianghong Zhang, Yu Lu, Mingzhen Xiu, Yuefan Wei, Yizhong Huang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409810275

                Abstract High entropy oxides (HEOs) have recently emerged as excellent alternative catalysts that can potentially replace noble metal catalysts such as RuO 2 and IrO 2 for water splitting applications. However, existing methods of synthesizing these catalysts are often tedious. In this work, a straightforward method is proposed using ultra&#8208;fast laser irradiation to synthesize heavily wrinkled noble metal&#8208;free (CoCuFeMnNi) 3 O 4 HEO 2&#8208;D sheets on nickel foam for excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. These sheets facilitate the OER at a low overpotential of only 245 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and is stable after 100 h of testing. This performance outmatches the majority of recently reported noble and noble metal&#8208;free HEA and HEO catalysts. As an anode in anion exchange water electrolyzer (AEMWE), a remarkably high current density of 1.722 A cm &#8722;2 is achieved at 2.0 V with negligible catalyst deterioration despite 70 h of testing. This result outranks the majority of other state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art AEMWE catalysts reported today. This work proves that laser irradiation synthesis enables the synthesis of efficient HEO catalysts, and is a pioneer synthesis of HEO 2&#8208;D interconnected sheets using laser irradiation. Crucially, this work proves that noble&#8208;metal free HEOs are highly efficient and durable catalysts in industrial AEMWE devices.</description>
      <author>H. Denny Kamaruddin, Jianghong Zhang, Yu Lu, Mingzhen Xiu, Yuefan Wei, Yizhong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202507930</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Single-Atom Catalysis for Hydrogen Evolution and Storage: A DFT Insight into First-Row Transition Metal-Porphyrin Complexes (Porph@TMs)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgsce.2025.205646</link>
      <description>Faheem Abbas, Saleem Nawaz Khan, Sadaf Bibi, Muhammad Yousaf, Francis M. Enujekwu, Muhammad Salman Khan, Sami Ullah, Mohammed A. Assiri, Gas Science and Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409828949

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faheem Abbas, Saleem Nawaz Khan, Sadaf Bibi, Muhammad Yousaf, Francis M. Enujekwu, Muhammad Salman Khan, Sami Ullah, Mohammed A. Assiri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgsce.2025.205646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Fe&#8208;Modulating Raney&#8208;Ni Electrodes toward High&#8208;Efficient and Durable AEM Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202501634</link>
      <description>Tao Jiang, Xinge Jiang, Chongyang Jiang, Jian Wang, Yoann Danlos, Taikai Liu, Chunming Deng, Chaoyue Chen, Hanlin Liao, Vasileios Kyriakou, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409832059

                Abstract Anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolysis holds promise for green hydrogen production. One of the main challenges is the preparation of highly efficient electrodes with scalable techniques. Herein, a novel Fe&#8208;modulating Raney&#8208;Ni electrode (NFA&#8208;CA) is developed through atmospheric plasma spraying and chemical etching techniques. The resulting electrode demonstrates high bifunctional catalytic activities with low overpotentials and Tafel slopes (HER: 27 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , 20 mV dec &#8722;1 ; OER: 169 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , 49 mV dec &#8722;1 ), competing for precious&#8208;metal catalysts and leading transition&#8208;metal&#8208;based compounds reported in the literature. Moreover, the corresponding AEM electrolyzer only requires 1.56 V to drive 1 A cm &#8722;2 and exceptional durability for 1000 h. Moreover, the AEM cell can reach 2 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.79 V, exceeding the United States Department of Energy target for AWE systems (2 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.80 V). The highly efficient and durable performance is attributed to the NiFe nanocrystals (core)&#8208;NiFe hydroxide (shell) nanostructures created by the treatment. This structure not only facilitates superior electrocatalytic properties but it is also maintained after 1000 h of continuous operation. It is consider that the present approach can offer an attractive route for scalable fabrication of NiFe&#8208;based electrodes for industrial AEM water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Tao Jiang, Xinge Jiang, Chongyang Jiang, Jian Wang, Yoann Danlos, Taikai Liu, Chunming Deng, Chaoyue Chen, Hanlin Liao, Vasileios Kyriakou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202501634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyoxometalated metal-organic framework superstructure for stable water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.ads1466</link>
      <description>Kaihang Yue, Ruihu Lu, Mingbin Gao, Fei Song, Yao Dai, Chenfeng Xia, Bingbao Mei, Hongliang Dong, Ruijuan Qi, Daliang Zhang, Jiangwei Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Fuqiang Huang, Bao Yu Xia, Ya Yan, Science. 388(6745)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409833855

                Stable, nonprecious catalysts are vital for large-scale alkaline water electrolysis. Here, we report a grafted superstructure, MOF@POM, formed by self-assembling a metal-organic framework (MOF) with polyoxometalate (POM). In situ electrochemical transformation converts MOF into active metal (oxy)hydroxides to produce a catalyst with a low overpotential of 178 millivolts at 10 milliamperes per square centimeter in alkaline electrolyte. An anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer incorporating this catalyst achieves 3 amperes per square centimeter at 1.78 volts at 80&#176;C and stable operation at 2 amperes per square centimeter for 5140 hours at room temperature. In situ electrochemical spectroscopy and theoretical studies reveal that the synergistic interactions between metal atoms create a fast electron-transfer channel from catalytic iron and cobalt sites, nickel, and tungsten in the polyoxometalate to the electrode, stabilizing the metal sites and preventing dissolution.</description>
      <author>Kaihang Yue, Ruihu Lu, Mingbin Gao, Fei Song, Yao Dai, Chenfeng Xia, Bingbao Mei, Hongliang Dong, Ruijuan Qi, Daliang Zhang, Jiangwei Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Fuqiang Huang, Bao Yu Xia, Ya Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.ads1466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomalous Diffusion of Metal Atoms on Oxide Surfaces: A Machine Learning Molecular Dynamics Study of Pt&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08512</link>
      <description>U. Saleem, Shaama Mallikarjun Sharada, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409835024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>U. Saleem, Shaama Mallikarjun Sharada</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering dynamic structural modulation of exogenous Fe3+ integrated into Ni-based anode toward oxygen electrocatalysis for rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111071</link>
      <description>Jingyi Han, Changmin Hou, Shihui Jiao, Xiaodi Niu, Lina Li, Jingqi Guan, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409841602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingyi Han, Changmin Hou, Shihui Jiao, Xiaodi Niu, Lina Li, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of Oxygen Evolution Performance of water splitting at High Current Density by Novel Electrodeposited NiFe-LDH Coatings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146332</link>
      <description>Sim&#243;n G. Quiroz, Santiago Cartagena, Jorge A. Calder&#243;n, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409846753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sim&#243;n G. Quiroz, Santiago Cartagena, Jorge A. Calder&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles investigation of grain boundary effects on fluorine-induced initial corrosion of NiCr alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113903</link>
      <description>Hamdy Arkoub, Miaomiao Jin, Computational Materials Science. 255(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409846985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hamdy Arkoub, Miaomiao Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single &#8211; atom Fe/N-embedded graphdiyne as catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction: A DFT approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.136</link>
      <description>Tung Pham, Minh T&#226;m L&#234;, Minh Thi Hong Le, Hoang Anh Nguyen, Hengquan Guo, Seung Geol Lee, Hsueh&#8208;Shih Chen, Nguyet N. T. Pham, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409850235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tung Pham, Minh T&#226;m L&#234;, Minh Thi Hong Le, Hoang Anh Nguyen, Hengquan Guo, Seung Geol Lee, Hsueh&#8208;Shih Chen, Nguyet N. T. Pham</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and performance evaluation of HfS2/AlSe heterostructure for enhanced photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.344</link>
      <description>Lijun He, Cheng Mi, Qijun Huang, Liyan Wang, Kang Ma, Liang She, Mi Yu, Yong Qin, Ping Yang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409850380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lijun He, Cheng Mi, Qijun Huang, Liyan Wang, Kang Ma, Liang She, Mi Yu, Yong Qin, Ping Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicted Cyclic Voltammetry Simulations on Iridium Oxide Surfaces with Comparisons To Experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02093-0</link>
      <description>Soonho Kwon, William A. Goddard, Topics in Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409856607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soonho Kwon, William A. Goddard</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02093-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant-Induced Hexagonal to Orthorhombic Phase Transition in Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;P Nanorods and Its Influence on the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03479</link>
      <description>Jordon Baker, Danyang Wang, Md. Kawsar Alam, Ka Un Lao, Indika U. Arachchige, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409867737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jordon Baker, Danyang Wang, Md. Kawsar Alam, Ka Un Lao, Indika U. Arachchige</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Penta-SiAsP Monolayer: A Highly Stable Pentagonal Ternary Material with Photocatalytic Potential for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-025-05015-7</link>
      <description>Chenghao Yang, Yanqing Shen, Kexin Wang, Xiangqian Jiang, Long Pang, E Peng, Zhongxiang Zhou, Catalysis Letters. 155(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409868693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenghao Yang, Yanqing Shen, Kexin Wang, Xiangqian Jiang, Long Pang, E Peng, Zhongxiang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-025-05015-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Defluorination Mechanism of Sodium Fluoro-Aluminates on Graphite: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c00956</link>
      <description>Min Tan, Jingjing Yan, Si Chung Chang, Hui He, Tao Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409870458

                The graphitized carbon blocks are used as cathode and anode materials on modern aluminum electrolyzers, which provide a reaction interface between molten salts and a graphitized cathode for the electrochemical reaction. The first-principle calculations were performed to clarify the defluorination mechanism of fluoro-aluminates on graphite cathodes in aluminum electrolysis for energy efficiency and carbon emission reduction. The adsorption behaviors of intermediates involved in defluorination reactions on graphite surfaces are analyzed, revealing their spontaneous adsorption based on their adsorption energies and charge density differences. Furthermore, the defluorination pathways of both single Na3AlF6 clusters and fluoride-aluminate polymers are elucidated. Notably, Na3AlF6, after undergoing the thermochemical defluorination process to obtain AlF3, preferentially undergoes electrochemical defluorination via Al-F-Al polymerization. The key findings indicate that the chemical defluorination of Na3AlF6 leading to NaAlF4 serves as a pivotal step, facilitating the overall defluorination process and enhancing the aluminum production efficiency. This work provides fundamental insights into optimizing aluminum electrolysis processes.</description>
      <author>Min Tan, Jingjing Yan, Si Chung Chang, Hui He, Tao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c00956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protons Accumulate at the Graphene&#8211;Water Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c02053</link>
      <description>Xavier R. Advincula, Kara D. Fong, Angelos Michaelides, Christoph Schran, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409871406

                Water's ability to autoionize into hydroxide and hydronium ions profoundly influences surface properties, rendering interfaces either basic or acidic. While it is well-established that protons show an affinity to the air-water interface, a critical knowledge gap exists in technologically relevant surfaces like the graphene-water interface. Here we use machine learning-based simulations with first-principles accuracy to unravel the behavior of hydroxide and hydronium ions at the graphene-water interface. Our findings reveal that protons accumulate at the graphene-water interface, with the hydronium ion predominantly residing in the first contact layer of water. In contrast, the hydroxide ion exhibits a bimodal distribution, found both near the surface and further away from it. Analysis of the underlying electronic structure reveals local polarization effects, resulting in counterintuitive charge rearrangement. Proton propensity to the graphene-water interface challenges the interpretation of surface experiments and is expected to have far-reaching consequences for ion conductivity, interfacial reactivity, and proton-mediated processes.</description>
      <author>Xavier R. Advincula, Kara D. Fong, Angelos Michaelides, Christoph Schran</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c02053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational High-Throughput Screening of High-Performance Transition Metal C8n8 Single-Atom Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5234301</link>
      <description>Keyuan Chen, X.L. Zhang, Li Ma, Yongzhi Wu, Haijin Li, Jueyi Ye, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Zhaohua Liu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409875350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Keyuan Chen, X.L. Zhang, Li Ma, Yongzhi Wu, Haijin Li, Jueyi Ye, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Zhaohua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5234301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation the Coordination of Fe-Co Diatomic Sites with Boron Atom for Fuel Cells and Zn-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5233860</link>
      <description>Dai Dang, Lin Zhang, Guifa Long, Chao Liu, Wenjun Fan, Jie Zheng, Tiejun Wang, Quanbing Liu, Xiaopeng Han, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409882712

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dai Dang, Lin Zhang, Guifa Long, Chao Liu, Wenjun Fan, Jie Zheng, Tiejun Wang, Quanbing Liu, Xiaopeng Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5233860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting electrocatalysts design combining general thermodynamic evaluation and specific kinetic study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116175</link>
      <description>Lu Han, Jun Long, Huan Li, Hao Li, Jianping Xiao, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409887124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Han, Jun Long, Huan Li, Hao Li, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Size Fits All? Development of the CPOSS209 Data Set of Experimental and Hypothetical Polymorphs for Testing Computational Modeling Methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00255</link>
      <description>Louise S. Price, Matteo Paloni, Matteo Salvalaglio, Sarah L. Price, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409887865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Louise S. Price, Matteo Paloni, Matteo Salvalaglio, Sarah L. Price</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A pH-dependent microkinetic modeling guided synthesis of porous dual-atom catalysts for efficient oxygen reduction in Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ee00215j</link>
      <description>Ting&#8208;Ting Li, Di Zhang, Yun Zhang, Dujuan Yang, Runxin Li, Fuyun Yu, Kengqiang Zhong, Xiaozhi Su, Tian&#8208;Wei Song, Long Jiao, Hai&#8208;Long Jiang, Guo&#8208;Ping Sheng, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Zhenyu Wu, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409889319

                Guided by the pH-field microkinetic model, we developed an porous Fe 1 Co 1 &#8211;N&#8211;C ORR catalyst, which exhibited excellent performance in zinc&#8211;air batteries and provided insights for advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ting&#8208;Ting Li, Di Zhang, Yun Zhang, Dujuan Yang, Runxin Li, Fuyun Yu, Kengqiang Zhong, Xiaozhi Su, Tian&#8208;Wei Song, Long Jiao, Hai&#8208;Long Jiang, Guo&#8208;Ping Sheng, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Zhenyu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ee00215j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dissolution: Paths in High-Entropy Alloy Composition Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00057-3</link>
      <description>Mads K. Plenge, Jack K. Pedersen, Luis A. Cipriano, Jan Rossmeisl, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409906731

                Abstract The stability of a nanoparticle catalyst during electrochemical reaction is crucial for its application. Despite increasing interest in multi-metallic alloy nanoparticles, such as high-entropy alloys (HEAs), for electrocatalysis and emerging models for their catalytic activity, there is limited work on frameworks that can predict the metastability of these alloys under reaction conditions, including stability against electrochemical surface dissolution. Incorporating electrochemical stability in multi-objective optimization would advance HEAs as a catalyst discovery platform. To address the knowledge gap on electrochemical stability, we propose a methodology for simulating the dissolution of n-element alloy nanoparticles comprised of density functional theory and machine-learning regression to calculate the dissolution potentials of the surface atoms. We demonstrate the methodology for the Ag&#8211;Au&#8211;Cu&#8211;Ir&#8211;Pd&#8211;Pt&#8211;Rh&#8211;Ru HEA system with the conditions of the oxygen reduction reaction. We investigated trends in stability against dissolution through a compositional grid search for the octo-metallic composition space, uncovering two alloying strategies to increase stability against electrochemical surface dissolution: Alloying with a noble metal or a metal with high relative surface energy. In the simulations, stabilization ensues from forming a protective surface layer, and consequently, the dissolution of persistent alloyed nanoparticles results in core&#8211;shell structures. The model enables tracing the evolution of the surface and dissolved composition during electrochemical dissolution, forming paths of dissolution and revealing unretainable surface compositions. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Mads K. Plenge, Jack K. Pedersen, Luis A. Cipriano, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00057-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing economic viability in carbon capture and storage with enhanced oil recovery projects: A dynamic stochastic approach to CO2 monitoring cost optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cie.2025.111187</link>
      <description>Peng Wu, Shansen Wei, Chengwei Lv, Qiangqiang Ren, Hong Wang, Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409907428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Wu, Shansen Wei, Chengwei Lv, Qiangqiang Ren, Hong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cie.2025.111187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty quantification for neural network potential foundation models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01572-y</link>
      <description>Jenna A. Bilbrey, Jesun Firoz, Michael Ka Ho Lee, Sutanay Choudhury, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409765509

                Abstract For neural network potentials (NNPs) to gain widespread use, researchers must be able to trust model outputs. However, the blackbox nature of neural networks and their inherent stochasticity are often deterrents, especially for foundation models trained over broad swaths of chemical space. Uncertainty information provided at the time of prediction can help reduce aversion to NNPs. In this work, we detail two uncertainty quantification (UQ) methods. Readout ensembling, by finetuning the readout layers of an ensemble of foundation models, provides information about model uncertainty, while quantile regression, by replacing point predictions with distributional predictions, provides information about uncertainty within the underlying training data. We demonstrate our approach with the MACE-MP-0 model, applying UQ to the foundation model and a series of finetuned models. The uncertainties produced by the readout ensemble and quantile methods are demonstrated to be distinct measures by which the quality of the NNP output can be judged.</description>
      <author>Jenna A. Bilbrey, Jesun Firoz, Michael Ka Ho Lee, Sutanay Choudhury</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01572-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science acceleration and accessibility with self-driving labs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59231-1</link>
      <description>Richard B. Canty, Jeffrey A. Bennett, Keith A. Brown, Tonio Buonassisi, Sergei V. Kalinin, John R. Kitchin, Benji Maruyama, R. G. Moore, Joshua Schrier, Martin Seifrid, Shijing Sun, Tejs Vegge, Milad Abolhasani, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409768533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Richard B. Canty, Jeffrey A. Bennett, Keith A. Brown, Tonio Buonassisi, Sergei V. Kalinin, John R. Kitchin, Benji Maruyama, R. G. Moore, Joshua Schrier, Martin Seifrid, Shijing Sun, Tejs Vegge, Milad Abolhasani</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59231-1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
