<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 01:26:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Role of Metastable Surfaces in Mechanochemical Reduction of Molybdenum Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00758</link>
      <description>Neung-Kyung Yu, Let&#237;cia F. Rasteiro, Van Son Nguyen, Kinga Go&#322;&#261;&#808;bek, Carsten Sievers, Andrew J. Medford, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404496465

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Neung-Kyung Yu, Let&#237;cia F. Rasteiro, Van Son Nguyen, Kinga Go&#322;&#261;&#808;bek, Carsten Sievers, Andrew J. Medford</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smallest [5,6]Fullerene as Building Blocks for 2D Networks with Superior Stability and Enhanced Photocatalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13167</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Wu, Bo Peng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404505778

                The assembly of molecules to form covalent networks can create varied lattice structures with physical and chemical properties distinct from those of conventional atomic lattices. Using the smallest stable [5,6]fullerene units as building blocks, various 2D C24 networks can be formed with superior stability and strength compared to the recently synthesized monolayer polymeric C60. Monolayer C24 harnesses the properties of both carbon crystals and fullerene molecules, such as stable chemical bonds, suitable band gaps, and large surface area, facilitating photocatalytic water splitting. The electronic band gaps of C24 are comparable to those of TiO2, providing appropriate band edges with sufficient external potential for overall water splitting over the acidic and neutral pH range. Upon photoexcitation, strong solar absorption enabled by strongly bound bright excitons can generate carriers effectively, while the type-II band alignment between C24 and other 2D monolayers can separate electrons and holes in individual layers simultaneously. Additionally, the number of surface-active sites of C24 monolayers are three times more than that of their C60 counterparts in a much wider pH range, providing spontaneous reaction pathways for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Our work provides insights into materials design using tunable building blocks of fullerene units with tailored functions for energy generation, conversion, and storage.</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Wu, Bo Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Performance and Kinetic Behavior of Anion&#8208;Intercalated Borate&#8208;Based NiFe LDH in Alkaline OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400457</link>
      <description>Maike Berger, Alexandra Markus, Stefan Palkovits, Regina Palkovits, ChemElectroChem. 11(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404505818

                Abstract The synthesis of hydrogen via water electrolysis is an important step towards resolving the energy crisis and impeding global warming, as hydrogen can be used as a green energy carrier. The oxygen evolution as one half&#8208;cell reaction (OER) is currently limiting efficient water splitting due to kinetic inhibition as well as a complex mechanism, causing a large overpotential. Nickel&#8208;iron layered double hydroxides (LDH) were found to be suitable OER catalysts, as they are cost effective, stable and highly active. This work focuses on the intercalation of different organic and inorganic borates into the LDH interlayers to study their influence on OER. Besides activity and stability measurements, three borate candidates were chosen for a kinetic study, including steady&#8208;state Tafel analysis and reaction order plots. It was found that the Bockris pathway with the second step as rate&#8208;determining step was predominant for all three catalysts. Of all candidates, the intercalation of borate resulted in the highest performance, which was associated with a high reducibility affecting the active metal sites.</description>
      <author>Maike Berger, Alexandra Markus, Stefan Palkovits, Regina Palkovits</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Mutual&#8208;Constraint of Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis via Direct O&lt;i&gt;&#9472;&lt;/i&gt;O Coupling on High&#8208;Valence Ir Single&#8208;Atom on MnO&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412950</link>
      <description>Ziyi Yang, Fayuan Lai, Qianjiang Mao, Chong Liu, Shengjie Peng, Xiangfeng Liu, Tianran Zhang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404506748

                Abstract Insufficient bifunctional activity of electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the major obstruction to the application of rechargeable metal&#8211;air batteries. The primary reason is the mutual constraint of ORR and OER mechanism, involving the same oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and demonstrating the scaling limitations of the adsorption energies. Herein, it is reported a high&#8208;valence Ir single atom anchored on manganese oxide (Ir SA &#8208;MnO x ) bifunctional catalyst showing independent pathways for ORR and OER, i.e., associated 4e &#8722; pathway on high&#8208;valence Ir site for ORR and a novel chemical&#8208;activated concerted mechanism for OER, where a distinct spontaneous chemical activation process triggers direct O &#9472; O coupling. The Ir SA &#8208;MnO x therefore delivers outstanding bifunctional activities with remarkably low potential difference (0.635 V) between OER potential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and ORR half&#8208;wave potential in alkaline solution. This work breaks the scaling limitations and provides a new avenue to design efficient and multifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Ziyi Yang, Fayuan Lai, Qianjiang Mao, Chong Liu, Shengjie Peng, Xiangfeng Liu, Tianran Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight Into Intermediate Behaviors and Design Strategies of Platinum Group Metal&#8208;Based Alkaline Hydrogen Oxidation Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414628</link>
      <description>Lixin Su, Hao Wu, Shaokun Zhang, Chenxi Cui, Shengnan Zhou, Huan Pang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404506934

                Abstract Hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) can effectively convert the hydrogen energy through the hydrogen fuel cells, which plays an increasingly important role in the renewable hydrogen cycle. Nevertheless, when the electrolyte pH changes from acid to base, even with platinum group metal (PGM) catalysts, the HOR kinetics declines with several orders of magnitude. More critically, the pivotal role of reaction intermediates and interfacial environment during intermediate behaviors on alkaline HOR remains controversial. Therefore, exploring the exceptional PGM&#8208;based alkaline HOR electrocatalysts and identifying the reaction mechanism are indispensable for promoting the commercial development of hydrogen fuel cells. Consequently, the fundamental understanding of the HOR mechanism is first introduced, with emphases on the adsorption/desorption process of distinct reactive intermediates and the interfacial structure during catalytic process. Subsequently, with the guidance of reaction mechanism, the latest advances in the rational design of advanced PGM&#8208;based (Pt, Pd, Ir, Ru, Rh&#8208;based) alkaline HOR catalysts are discussed, focusing on the correlation between the intermediate behaviors and the electrocatalytic performance. Finally, given that the challenges standing in the development of the alkaline HOR, the prospect for the rational catalysts design and thorough mechanism investigation towards alkaline HOR are emphatically proposed.</description>
      <author>Lixin Su, Hao Wu, Shaokun Zhang, Chenxi Cui, Shengnan Zhou, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Electrocatalysis of Dual-Metal Atoms Sandwiched by BN-doped Graphdiyne and Graphdiyne Sheets on Nitrogen Reduction: A First Principle Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105470</link>
      <description>Zhenhua Liu, Manqi Li, Tian Gao, Shiyao Liu, Hongmin Yu, Zhao Wang, Hao Sun, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404511796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenhua Liu, Manqi Li, Tian Gao, Shiyao Liu, Hongmin Yu, Zhao Wang, Hao Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicted Influence of Organic Structure Directing Agents on Al Distributions in CHA Zeolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02463</link>
      <description>Xuyao Gao, Sang&#8208;Do Yeo, Rajamani Gounder, Ahmad Moini, William F. Schneider, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404515134

                The distribution of Al on a zeolite framework can have a determining influence on chemical and catalytic properties. Those distributions are typically determined during synthesis as influenced by cationic organic structure directing agents (OSDAs). Here we use density functional theory (DFT) to compare the Al directing influence of N,N,N-trimethyl-1-adamantyl ammonium (TMAda+), an OSDA commonly used to crystallize CHA zeolite, with four isomers that retain the adamantyl structure but relocate the nitrogen center. Low energy configurations balance electrostatics-driven maximization of Al&#8211;Al and minimization of Al&#8211;N separations, the latter more important in OSDAs with more accessible charge centers. Statistical thermodynamics are used to predict thermal equilibrium Al distributions and corresponding Al pair features as a function of OSDA. All distributions differ from those predicted through naive application of L&#246;wenstein's rule, disfavor the placement of two Al second-nearest-neighbor or within a single six-ring, and introduce different biases toward eight-membered rings and more remote Al. Results illustrate the potential to influence Al location through OSDA selection.</description>
      <author>Xuyao Gao, Sang&#8208;Do Yeo, Rajamani Gounder, Ahmad Moini, William F. Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Oxygen-Induced Reactions and Their Impact on n-Type Polymeric Mixed Conductor-Based Devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c00654</link>
      <description>Prem D. Nayak, B&#252;&#351;ra Dereli, David Ohayon, Shofarul Wustoni, Tania C. Hidalgo, Victor Druet, Yazhou Wang, Adel Hama, Craig Combe, Sophie Griggs, Maryam Alsufyani, Rajendar Sheelamanthula, Iain McCulloch, Luigi Cavallo, Sahika Inal, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404518648

                Electron transporting (n-type) polymeric mixed conductors are an exciting class of materials for devices with aqueous electrolyte interfaces, such as bioelectronic sensors, actuators, and soft charge storage systems. However, their charge transport performance falls short of their p-type counterparts, primarily due to electrochemical side reactions such as the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). To mitigate ORR, a common strategy in n-type organic semiconductor design focuses on lowering the lowest unoccupied molecular orbital (LUMO) level. Despite empirical observations suggesting a correlation between deep LUMO levels, low ORR, and enhanced electrochemical cycling stability in water, this relationship lacks robust evidence. In this work, we delve into the electrochemical reactions of n-type polymeric mixed conductors with varying LUMO levels and assess the impact of ORR on charge storage performance and organic electrochemical transistor (OECT) operation. Our results reveal a limited correlation between LUMO levels and ORR currents, as well as the electrochemical operational stability of the films. While ORR currents minimally contribute to OECT channel currents under fixed biasing conditions, n-type films self-discharge rapidly at floating potentials in a capacitor-like configuration. The density functional theory analysis, complemented by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, underscores the critical role of backbone chemistry in controlling O2-related degradation pathways and device performance losses. These findings highlight the persistent challenge posed by ORR in n-type semiconductor design and advocate for shifting the focus toward exploring chemical moieties with limited O2 interactions to enhance operational stability and performance at n-type film/water interfaces.</description>
      <author>Prem D. Nayak, B&#252;&#351;ra Dereli, David Ohayon, Shofarul Wustoni, Tania C. Hidalgo, Victor Druet, Yazhou Wang, Adel Hama, Craig Combe, Sophie Griggs, Maryam Alsufyani, Rajendar Sheelamanthula, Iain McCulloch, Luigi Cavallo, Sahika Inal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c00654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt-xCe nanoparticles confined within HZSM-5 for increasing the selectivity of light olefins in iso-butane cracking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10934-024-01683-9</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Liu, Wei Ma, Hongdan Zhang, Ying Zhao, Peng Cheng, Zhen Zhao, Journal of Porous Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404519008

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Liu, Wei Ma, Hongdan Zhang, Ying Zhao, Peng Cheng, Zhen Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10934-024-01683-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteroatom Engineering in Earth-Abundant Cobalt Electrocatalyst for Energy-Saving Hydrogen Evolution Coupling with Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11228</link>
      <description>Siyuan Tang, Zhipeng Zhang, Quanjiang Lv, Xueqing Pan, Jianling Dong, Luyu Liu, Yangyang Wan, Jian Han, Fuzhan Song, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404522598

                The development of multifunctional electrocatalysts with high performance for electrocatalyzing urea oxidation-assisted water splitting is of great significance for energy-saving hydrogen production. In this work, we demonstrate a novel heteroatom engineering strategy for development of B-doped Co as a multifunctional electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and urea oxidation reaction (UOR). Density functional theory (DFT) results suggest that a B dopant can efficiently adjust the electron reconstruction of the exposure of Co sites nearby and facilitate electron transfer, resulting in an optimal d-band center along with a lower Gibbs free energy barrier. Ultimately, the obtained B&#8211;Co exhibits pH-universal HER properties in various electrolytes. A highly efficient HER performance with overpotentials as low as 27, 163, and 430 mV to &#8722;10, &#8722;100, and &#8722;500 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH, respectively, is observed for the B&#8211;Co electrode. More importantly, the UOR-assisted electrolyzer only requires a voltage input of 1.55 V to produce the current densities of 50 mA cm&#8211;2, resulting in a 200 mV saving-energy potential compared to water electrolysis, demonstrating its high efficiency of hydrogen production in industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Siyuan Tang, Zhipeng Zhang, Quanjiang Lv, Xueqing Pan, Jianling Dong, Luyu Liu, Yangyang Wan, Jian Han, Fuzhan Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of the oxygen reduction/evolution reactions catalyst supported on covalent organic framework doped by main group metal using a constant potential method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.210</link>
      <description>Yu Jin, Daoxiong Wu, Wenjun Xiao, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Jinshun Bi, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Yaqiong Su, Xuefei Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 94(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404524547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Jin, Daoxiong Wu, Wenjun Xiao, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Jinshun Bi, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Yaqiong Su, Xuefei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.210</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black phosphorene: A versatile allotrope revolutionizing environmental, energy, and biomedical applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216345</link>
      <description>Soumya Ranjan Mishra, Vishal Gadore, Vishwajit Chavda, Subhasree Panda, Saptarshi Roy, Pooja Sahoo, Lipi Pradhan, Harshita Rai, Shyam S. Pandey, Md. Ahmaruzzaman, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 524(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404530297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soumya Ranjan Mishra, Vishal Gadore, Vishwajit Chavda, Subhasree Panda, Saptarshi Roy, Pooja Sahoo, Lipi Pradhan, Harshita Rai, Shyam S. Pandey, Md. Ahmaruzzaman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Surface Strain in L1&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt;-Type Pt&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Ga&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;Co Intermetallic Catalyst for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction in Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01968</link>
      <description>Longhai Zhang, Yingjie Deng, Jiaxi Zhang, Weiquan Tan, Liming Wang, Li Du, Jiajun Huang, Shijun Liao, Dai Dang, Shuhui Sun, Zhiming Cui, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404540217

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Longhai Zhang, Yingjie Deng, Jiaxi Zhang, Weiquan Tan, Liming Wang, Li Du, Jiajun Huang, Shijun Liao, Dai Dang, Shuhui Sun, Zhiming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Local Atomic Environments of Te&#8208;Modulated Fe Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for High&#8208;Efficiency O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406659</link>
      <description>Zongge Li, Shuhua Liu, Wenjun Kang, Suyuan Zeng, Konggang Qu, Fanpeng Meng, Lei Wang, Rui Li, Yikai Yang, Kepeng Song, Shenglin Xiong, Bing Nan, Haibo Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404544525

                Atomically dispersed metal-nitrogen-carbon materials (AD-MNCs) are considered the most promising non-precious catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), but it remains a major challenge for simultaneously achieving high intrinsic activity, fast mass transport, and effective utilization of the active sites within a single catalyst. Here, an AD-MNCs consisting of defect-rich Fe-N</description>
      <author>Zongge Li, Shuhua Liu, Wenjun Kang, Suyuan Zeng, Konggang Qu, Fanpeng Meng, Lei Wang, Rui Li, Yikai Yang, Kepeng Song, Shenglin Xiong, Bing Nan, Haibo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel oxide enables high-temperature self-lubrication in superalloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54482-w</link>
      <description>Zhengyu Zhang, Eitan Hershkovitz, Qi An, Liping Liu, Xiaoqing Wang, Zhifei Deng, Garrett Baucom, Wenbo Wang, Jing Zhao, Zhi Jun Xin, L.J. Moore, Yi Yao, Md. Saidul Islam, Xin Chen, Bai Cui, Ling Li, Hongliang Xin, Lin Li, Honggyu Kim, Wenjun Cai, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404545133

                The ability to lubricate and resist wear at temperatures above 600 &#176;C in an oxidative environment remains a significant challenge for metals due to their high-temperature softening, oxidation, and rapid degradation of traditional solid lubricants. Herein, we demonstrate that high-temperature lubricity can be achieved with coefficients of friction (COF) as low as 0.10-0.32 at 600-900 &#176;C by tailoring surface oxidation in additively-manufactured Inconel superalloy. By integrating high-temperature tribological testing, advanced materials characterization, and computations, we show that the formation of spinel-based oxide layers on superalloy promotes sustained self-lubrication due to their lower shear strength and more negative formation and cohesive energy compared to other surface oxides. A reversible phase transformation between the cubic and tetragonal/monoclinic spinel was driven by stress and temperature during high temperature wear. To span Ni- and Cr-based ternary oxide compositional spaces for which little high-temperature COF data exist, we develop a computational design method to predict the lubricity of oxides, incorporating thermodynamics and density functional theory computations. Our finding demonstrates that spinel oxide can exhibit low COF values at temperatures much higher than conventional solid lubricants with 2D layered or Magn&#233;li structures, suggesting a promising design strategy for self-lubricating high-temperature alloys. The authors develop an approach for enhancing the wear resistance and lubricity of metals at elevated temperatures of in oxidative environments, where traditional solid lubricants fail. By engineering surface oxidation in additively manufactured Inconel, they achieve low friction coefficients, between 0.10 and 0.32 at 600-900 &#176;C, through the formation of a spinel-based oxide layer.</description>
      <author>Zhengyu Zhang, Eitan Hershkovitz, Qi An, Liping Liu, Xiaoqing Wang, Zhifei Deng, Garrett Baucom, Wenbo Wang, Jing Zhao, Zhi Jun Xin, L.J. Moore, Yi Yao, Md. Saidul Islam, Xin Chen, Bai Cui, Ling Li, Hongliang Xin, Lin Li, Honggyu Kim, Wenjun Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54482-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uniform anchoring of MoS2 nanosheets on MOFs-derived CoFe2O4 porous nanolayers to construct heterogeneous structural configurations for efficient and stable overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.136</link>
      <description>Yulin Duan, Zhengang Guo, Tingting Wang, Jifan Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 680(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404555318

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yulin Duan, Zhengang Guo, Tingting Wang, Jifan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of S-scheme heterojunction via coating ZIF-8-derived Zn0.7Cd0.3S on Ni2P hydrangea for efficient photocatalytic hydrogen evolution coupled with benzyl alcohol oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.095</link>
      <description>Xinggen Yuan, Yangkai Cheng, Churu Zhang, Guochao Shan, R. Z. Liu, Feiyang Luo, Yanyan Deng, Kaili Yao, Jing Xu, Shaoyun Shan, Wei Liu, Tianding Hu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 680(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404555365

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinggen Yuan, Yangkai Cheng, Churu Zhang, Guochao Shan, R. Z. Liu, Feiyang Luo, Yanyan Deng, Kaili Yao, Jing Xu, Shaoyun Shan, Wei Liu, Tianding Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the working principle of sustainable catalytic materials for selective hydrogenation of carbonyls bond in &#945;, &#946;-unsaturated aldehydes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216295</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zahid, Ahmed Ismail, Muhammad Farooq Khan, Nauman Ali, Syed ul Hasnain Bakhtiar, Atef El Jery, Basem Al Alwan, Rizwan Ullah, Fazal Raziq, Weidong He, Kai Zhang, Jiabao Yi, Xiaoqiang Wu, Sharafat Ali, Liang Qiao, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 525(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404556491

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zahid, Ahmed Ismail, Muhammad Farooq Khan, Nauman Ali, Syed ul Hasnain Bakhtiar, Atef El Jery, Basem Al Alwan, Rizwan Ullah, Fazal Raziq, Weidong He, Kai Zhang, Jiabao Yi, Xiaoqiang Wu, Sharafat Ali, Liang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Nitrogen Reduction Electrocatalyst with a Dual-Metal&#8211;Boron System: From High-Throughput Screening to Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15263</link>
      <description>Chen Chen, Yi Liu, Xue-fang Yu, Zhongwei Li, Wenzuo Li, Qingzhong Li, Xiaolong Zhang, Bo Xiao, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404556911

                Recently, dual-metal catalysts have attracted much attention due to their abundant active sites and tunable chemical properties. On the other hand, metal borides have been widely applied in splitting the inert chemical bonds in small molecules (such as N2) because of their excellent catalytic performances. As a combination of the above two systems, in this work, 11 kinds of transition metal atoms (TM = Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Mo, and W) were selected to embed in boron-doped graphene (BG) to construct 66 dual-metal&#8211;boron systems, and their performances toward the N2 reduction reaction (NRR) were examined using first-principles simulations. Our results revealed that such a dual-TM@BG system exhibits excellent thermodynamic and electrochemical stabilities, which facilitate the experimental synthesis. In particular, Fe&#8211;Fe- and Fe&#8211;Co-doped BG exhibit excellent performance for NRR, with the limiting potentials of &#8722;0.29 and &#8722;0.32 V, respectively, and both of them exhibit inhibitory effects on the H2 evolution reaction. Remarkably, the microkinetic modeling analysis revealed that the turnover frequency for the NH3 production on FeFe@BG reaches up to 7.27 &#215; 108 s&#8211;1 site&#8211;1 at 700 K and 100 bar, which further confirms its ultrafast reaction rate. In addition, the machine learning method was employed to further understand the catalytic mechanism, and it is found that the NRR performances of dual-TM@BG catalysts are closely related to the sum of radii of two TM atoms. Therefore, our work not only proposed two promising electrocatalysts for NRR but also verified the feasibility for the application of a dual-metal&#8211;boron system in NRR.</description>
      <author>Chen Chen, Yi Liu, Xue-fang Yu, Zhongwei Li, Wenzuo Li, Qingzhong Li, Xiaolong Zhang, Bo Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Exceptional Tandem Catalyst Pt&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;Pd&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; NPs Embedded on a Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Polypyrrole Composite Serving in Both the Ethanol Oxidation Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Direct Ethanol Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01819</link>
      <description>Rajib Adhikary, Jayati Datta, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404557878

                The present study explores the contributory benefits of PtPd catalyst nanoparticles supported on a mixed valence iron oxide (Fe3O4) and polypyrrole (PPy) composite for validation in both the ethanol oxidation reaction and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in alkaline medium for low temperature direct ethanol fuel cells (DEFCs). The high electrochemical surface area (ECSA) for PtPd/PPy-Fe3O4 with smart intervention of Fe3O4 directly/indirectly in the EOR and ORR sequences makes this distinct catalyst a highly preferred choice in direct ethanol fuel cells with respect to reduced polarization loss, substantial current density output, and greater stability compared to the usual Pt or Pd single nanocatalysts supported over carbon, while the conducting polymer present in the composite matrix enhances the charge transfer ability within the direct ethanol fuel cell framework. The catalyst nanoparticles are found to be in the size range 4&#8211;5 nm, as revealed from structure and morphology studies. Ion chromatographic analysis quantifies the reaction intermediates, acetate and carbonate, to the extent of 366 and 251 ppm using 1 M ethanol solution, while a low yield of H2O2 is a testament to the major utility of the combinatorial approach in the ORR. The studies involved morphology determined through electron microscopy and electrochemical characterization with the help of potentiodynamic polarization and RDE-RRDE techniques. The catalytic preeminence of the nanostructured PtPd/PPy-Fe3O4 was manifested by the facile electrode kinetics at the anode and cathode, the low yield of H2O2 in the ORR, and the appreciable power density output of 47.65 mW/cm2 of the complete cell bearing enormous mass activity for both the EOR and ORR. This novel attempt of introducing the single robust catalyst at both ends ensures better catalyst utilization, imparts affordability, and avoids carbon corrosion in the fuel cell environment.</description>
      <author>Rajib Adhikary, Jayati Datta</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the electronic, optical, and water-splitting properties of rare earth single-atom catalysts supported on graphitic carbon nitride monolayer: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.224</link>
      <description>Ranjini Sarkar, Tarun Kumar Kundu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 95(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404562895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ranjini Sarkar, Tarun Kumar Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoZn-based high entropy alloy catalysts enabled dual activation and stabilization in alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq6758</link>
      <description>Yunjie Mei, J. X. Chen, Qi Wang, Y.. Guo, Hanwen Liu, W. Shi, Lin Cheng, Yifei Yuan, Yuhua Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Yonggang Yao, Science Advances. 10(47)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404563910

                It remains a grand challenge to develop electrocatalysts with simultaneously high activity, long durability, and low cost for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), originating from two competing reaction pathways and often trade-off performances. The adsorbed evolution mechanism (AEM) suffers from sluggish kinetics due to a linear scaling relationship, while the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) causes unstable structures due to lattice oxygen escape. We propose a MoZnFeCoNi high-entropy alloy (HEA) incorporating AEM-promoter Mo and LOM-active Zn to achieve dual activation and stabilization for efficient and durable OER. Density functional theory and chemical probe experiments confirmed dual-mechanism activation, with representative Co-Co &#8224; -Mo sites facilitating AEM and Zn-O &#8224; -Ni sites enhancing LOM, resulting in an ultralow OER overpotential (&#951; 10 = 221 mV). The multielement interaction, high-entropy structure, and carbon network notably enhance structural stability for durable catalysis (&gt;1500 hours at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Our work offers a viable approach to concurrently enhance OER activity and stability by designing HEA catalysts to enable dual-mechanism synergy.</description>
      <author>Yunjie Mei, J. X. Chen, Qi Wang, Y.. Guo, Hanwen Liu, W. Shi, Lin Cheng, Yifei Yuan, Yuhua Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Yonggang Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq6758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the activity origin of Pd-anchored single-atom alloy catalysts for NO-to-NH3 conversion by DFT studies and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110656</link>
      <description>Jieyu Liu, Junze Zhang, Haigang Deng, Shuoao Wang, Xingxing Jiang, Li Wang, Changhong Wang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404564749

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jieyu Liu, Junze Zhang, Haigang Deng, Shuoao Wang, Xingxing Jiang, Li Wang, Changhong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screener and Enumerator with Force-Field Optimization (SEFFO): algorithm for searching adsorption sites and configurations on 2D materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109440</link>
      <description>Leran Lu, Wei Cao, Romain Botella, Computer Physics Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404565684

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leran Lu, Wei Cao, Romain Botella</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the spin configuration by topochemical transformation for optimized intermediates adsorption ability in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60140-3</link>
      <description>Jinchang Xu, Yongqi Jian, Guang-Qiang Yu, Wanli Liang, Xiashi Zhu, Muzi Yang, Jian Chen, Fangyan Xie, Yanshuo Jin, Nan Wang, Xi&#8208;Bo Li, Hui Meng, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404565943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinchang Xu, Yongqi Jian, Guang-Qiang Yu, Wanli Liang, Xiashi Zhu, Muzi Yang, Jian Chen, Fangyan Xie, Yanshuo Jin, Nan Wang, Xi&#8208;Bo Li, Hui Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60140-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nature of metal-support interaction for metal catalysts on oxide supports</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adp6034</link>
      <description>Tairan Wang, J. Junqing Hu, Runhai Ouyang, Y. Wang, Yi Huang, Sulei Hu, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Science. 386(6724)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404577752

                The metal-support interaction is one of the most important pillars in heterogeneous catalysis, but developing a fundamental theory has been challenging because of the intricate interfaces. Based on experimental &#8206;data, interpretable machine learning, theoretical derivation, and first-principles simulations, we established a &#8206;general theory of metal-oxide interactions grounded in &#8206;metal-metal and metal-oxygen interactions. The theory applies to metal nanoparticles and atoms on oxide supports and oxide films on metal supports. We found that for late-transition metal catalysts, metal-metal interactions dominated the oxide support effects and suboxide encapsulation over metal nanoparticles. A principle of strong metal-metal interactions for encapsulation occurrence is formulated and substantiated by extensive &#8206;experiments including 10 metals and 16 &#8206;oxides. The valuable insights revealed on (strong) metal-support interaction advance the interfacial design of supported metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tairan Wang, J. Junqing Hu, Runhai Ouyang, Y. Wang, Yi Huang, Sulei Hu, Wei&#8208;Xue Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adp6034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triggering the Dual-Metal-Site Lattice Oxygen Mechanism with In Situ-Generated Mn&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; Sites for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14338</link>
      <description>Jianyun Liu, Tanyuan Wang, Mingzi Sun, Mengyi Liao, Li Wang, Shuxia Liu, Hao Shi, Yang Liu, Yue Shen, Ruiguo Cao, Yunhui Huang, Bolong Huang, Qing Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404578003

                The development of high-performance non-Ir/Ru catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acid is critical for the applications of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). Here, we report a new kind of heterostructure catalyst by loading 5.8% Ag nanoparticles on MnO nanorods (Ag/MnO) for acidic OER. The as-prepared Ag/MnO requires only an overpotential of 196 mV for the OER at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and operates in a PEMWE for over 300 h at a current density of 200 mA cm&#8211;2, representing one of the best non-Ir/Ru OER catalysts. Operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy confirms that the introduction of trace Ag can promote the generation of highly active Mn3+&#8211;O sites with oxygen vacancies at a low voltage, leading to a dual-metal-site lattice oxygen-mediated pathway with faster kinetics than the adsorbate evolution mechanism. Theoretical calculations indicate that the trace Ag promotes the overlap between the d orbitals of Mn and the s, p orbitals of O, thereby activating the lattice oxygen and reducing the OER energy barrier. The dissolution of Mn is also suppressed by Ag due to the increased energy for vacancy formation of Mn, where the stability number reaches a high value of 3058, supporting improved structural stability.</description>
      <author>Jianyun Liu, Tanyuan Wang, Mingzi Sun, Mengyi Liao, Li Wang, Shuxia Liu, Hao Shi, Yang Liu, Yue Shen, Ruiguo Cao, Yunhui Huang, Bolong Huang, Qing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Engineering of NiCoP Sites via N, Ru Dual Doping for Bifunctional Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03879</link>
      <description>Meng Zhou, Wenzhi Jia, Tian Tian, Yuhan Ye, Jianping Zhou, Jian Tian, Guoxiang Pan, Bin He, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404578577

                Exploiting highly effective electrocatalysts is a challenge for boosting the overall efficiency of water splitting. Herein, we present a nitrogen and ruthenium dual-doping strategy to tailor the electronic structures of NiCoP(N, Ru&#8211;NiCoP), creating high-performance bifunctional electrodes for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The dual-doping approach is favorable for electronic interactions within the NiCoP and CoP, yielding a near-zero Gibbs free energy for H adsorption. Consequently, the optimized N, Ru&#8211;NiCoP electrodes exhibit exceptional bifunctional activities, with overpotentials of 53 and 405 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 for the HER and OER, respectively. Notably, their performance surpasses that of commercial Pt/C and RuO2 catalysts at large current densities, demonstrating their potential for industrial water splitting applications. Moreover, the overall water-splitting device achieves a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 with a driving voltage of only 1.54 V. This work provides an effective heteroatom doping strategy to develop low-cost and highly active electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Meng Zhou, Wenzhi Jia, Tian Tian, Yuhan Ye, Jianping Zhou, Jian Tian, Guoxiang Pan, Bin He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron group elements (Fe, Co, Ni) in Electrocatalytic applications: Evaluation, characterization and prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216343</link>
      <description>Jiwen Wu, Naiyan Liu, Fengshi Li, Binbin Jia, Jinlong Zheng, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 525(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404579172

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiwen Wu, Naiyan Liu, Fengshi Li, Binbin Jia, Jinlong Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An advanced bifunctional single-element-incorporated ternary perovskite cathode for next-generation fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235875</link>
      <description>Huaqing Ye, Yuhao Wang, Qirui Ye, Xueyang Li, Haoqing Lin, Bote Zhao, Feifei Dong, Meng Ni, Zhan Lin, Journal of Power Sources. 628(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404579368

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaqing Ye, Yuhao Wang, Qirui Ye, Xueyang Li, Haoqing Lin, Bote Zhao, Feifei Dong, Meng Ni, Zhan Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Generation for Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00572</link>
      <description>Maksim Kulichenko, Benjamin Nebgen, Nicholas Lubbers, Justin S. Smith, Kipton Barros, Alice Allen, Adela Habib, Emily Shinkle, Nikita Fedik, Ying Wai Li, Richard A. Messerly, Sergei Tretiak, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404580258

                The field of data-driven chemistry is undergoing an evolution, driven by innovations in machine learning models for predicting molecular properties and behavior. Recent strides in ML-based interatomic potentials have paved the way for accurate modeling of diverse chemical and structural properties at the atomic level. The key determinant defining MLIP reliability remains the quality of the training data. A paramount challenge lies in constructing training sets that capture specific domains in the vast chemical and structural space. This Review navigates the intricate landscape of essential components and integrity of training data that ensure the extensibility and transferability of the resulting models. We delve into the details of active learning, discussing its various facets and implementations. We outline different types of uncertainty quantification applied to atomistic data acquisition and the correlations between estimated uncertainty and true error. The role of atomistic data samplers in generating diverse and informative structures is highlighted. Furthermore, we discuss data acquisition via modified and surrogate potential energy surfaces as an innovative approach to diversify training data. The Review also provides a list of publicly available data sets that cover essential domains of chemical space.</description>
      <author>Maksim Kulichenko, Benjamin Nebgen, Nicholas Lubbers, Justin S. Smith, Kipton Barros, Alice Allen, Adela Habib, Emily Shinkle, Nikita Fedik, Ying Wai Li, Richard A. Messerly, Sergei Tretiak</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vesicle-Shaped Co-Ni-S designed by first principles screening and d-Band center control for active hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133743</link>
      <description>Youbin Zheng, Ze Li, Hao Guo, Cunyin Liu, Yuefeng Chen, Xiumei Han, Liang Dong, Jianbing Zang, Fuel. 382(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582457

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youbin Zheng, Ze Li, Hao Guo, Cunyin Liu, Yuefeng Chen, Xiumei Han, Liang Dong, Jianbing Zang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic modeling of bulk and grain boundary diffusion in solid electrolyte &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Li&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;6&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;PS&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;5&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Cl&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; using machine-learning interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.115407</link>
      <description>Yongliang Ou, Yuji Ikeda, Lena Scholz, Sergiy V. Divinski, Felix Fritzen, Blazej Grabowski, Physical Review Materials. 8(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404587883

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongliang Ou, Yuji Ikeda, Lena Scholz, Sergiy V. Divinski, Felix Fritzen, Blazej Grabowski</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.115407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of a transition metal single-atom electrocatalyst for the CH3NO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.217</link>
      <description>Kefeng Xie, Shengyuan Xu, Xiaohong Song, Mingqiang Liu, Kai Xu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 95(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404599942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kefeng Xie, Shengyuan Xu, Xiaohong Song, Mingqiang Liu, Kai Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.217</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain&#8208;Engineered Ir Shell Enhances Activity and Stability of Ir&#8208;Ru Catalysts for Water Electrolysis: An Operando Wide&#8208;Angle X&#8208;Ray Scattering Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403738</link>
      <description>Tom&#225;&#353; Hrbek, Peter K&#250;&#353;, Jakub Drnec, Marta Mirolo, Hridya Nedumkulam, Isaac Martens, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404602548

                Abstract Ir&#8208;Ru alloys with high Ru content serve as stable and highly active catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers (PEM&#8208;WEs), enabling efficient operation with low Ir loadings (150 &#181;g cm &#8722; 2 ). Despite this, the mechanisms behind their enhanced stability remain unclear. In this study, operando Wide&#8208;Angle X&#8208;ray Scattering (WAXS) and ex situ techniques are utilized to investigate the structural evolution of these magnetron&#8208;sputtered alloys during a PEM&#8208;WE operation. The findings reveal that Ru leaches from the surface upon potential application, forming a dynamic Ir&#8208;Ru@IrO x core&#8208;shell structure. The Ir shell, strained by the Ir&#8208;Ru core, maintains a lower oxidation state than pure Ir catalyst, leading to superior catalytic activity and stability. Remarkably, the Ir&#8208;Ru 25:75 catalyst demonstrates better stability over Ir&#8208;Ru 50:50, despite its higher Ru content, due to the better protection of the subsurface Ir and Ru from oxidation and dissolution. This study not only clarifies the performance&#8208;enhancing mechanisms of Ir&#8208;Ru catalysts but also suggests that other, more economical materials, such as Co or Ti, could serve as effective cores in Ir&#8208;M systems, offering a pathway to more cost&#8208;effective catalysts for PEM&#8208;WE applications.</description>
      <author>Tom&#225;&#353; Hrbek, Peter K&#250;&#353;, Jakub Drnec, Marta Mirolo, Hridya Nedumkulam, Isaac Martens, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Perovskite Oxides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Structures, Mechanisms, and Strategies for Performance Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416705</link>
      <description>Xiong Sun, Ying Yuan, Shuzhi Liu, Hongqing Zhao, Suqiang Yao, Sun Yuying, Shouxin Zhang, Yijiang Liu, Zhiqun Lin, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404618145

                Abstract Perovskite&#8208;type oxides are widely employed as oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts due to their tunable composition, diverse structure, abundant natural reserves, remarkable stability, and low cost. The intrinsic OER electrocatalytic activity of these perovskite oxides is generally enhanced by improving conductivity, increasing specific surface area, and optimizing the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates. This is achieved through rationally designed strategies, including compositional engineering, defect engineering, hybridization, and surface regulation. In this review, recent advances in perovskite oxides for OER are summarized, with a focus on exploring structure&#8208;performance relationships. This review provides a brief introduction to the application of perovskite oxides in OER, followed by the classification and characteristics of these perovskite oxides. The primary OER catalytic mechanisms, and well&#8208;established activity descriptors are discussed. The key strategies are concentrated for enhancing OER activity, including composition engineering, defect engineering, hybridization, and surface reconstruction. Finally, the challenges and opportunities in developing high&#8208;performance perovskite oxides as OER electrocatalysts are presented.</description>
      <author>Xiong Sun, Ying Yuan, Shuzhi Liu, Hongqing Zhao, Suqiang Yao, Sun Yuying, Shouxin Zhang, Yijiang Liu, Zhiqun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>: A Toolkit for Autonomous, User-Guided Construction of Machine-Learned Potential Energy Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109446</link>
      <description>Kai T&#246;pfer, Luis Itza Vazquez-Salazar, Markus Meuwly, Computer Physics Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404626715

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai T&#246;pfer, Luis Itza Vazquez-Salazar, Markus Meuwly</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Cationic Vacancy Defects to Switch Oxygen Evolution Mechanisms on Atomically Dispersed Ru for Enhanced Acidic Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124845</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Deshuai Yang, Zhen Yang, Lili Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404628614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Deshuai Yang, Zhen Yang, Lili Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Photocatalytic Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Ethanol via Unsaturated Cu&#8211;O Domains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11842</link>
      <description>Yan Wang, Mingqi He, Pengxin Yang, Yanan Zhou, Li Wang, Kaifu Zhang, Zhuo Jiang, Qiquan Luo, Shan Gao, Jinlong Yang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404629041

                Enhancing the selectivity of photocatalytic CO2 reduction to valuable multicarbon (C2+) products remains a significant challenge in green synthetic chemistry. Here, we present a dual-center strategy for metal oxides that boosts the photochemical conversion of CO2 to ethanol by regulating the coordination number of metal and oxygen sites. Notably, CuO catalysts rich in low-coordinated Cu&#8211;O domains have achieved nearly perfect ethanol selectivity (96.9%), extraordinary durability (60 h), and a superior yield rate of 30.5 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1, surpassing the performance of many existing photocatalysts in water vapor and CO2. Density functional theory calculations and operando spectroscopic results provide conclusive evidence that tricoordinated copper (Cu3c) increases the coverage of key *CO species, while bicoordinated oxygen (O2c) controls the migration of *CO species, thereby effectively reducing the energy requirement for *CO dimerization into *OC&#8211;CO intermediates (&#916;G*OC&#8211;CO = &#8722;0.56 eV) in the ethanol pathway. This work offers valuable insights for designing photocatalysts that exhibit improved selectivity for C2+ fuels.</description>
      <author>Yan Wang, Mingqi He, Pengxin Yang, Yanan Zhou, Li Wang, Kaifu Zhang, Zhuo Jiang, Qiquan Luo, Shan Gao, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving electrocatalytic OER activity of perovskites through insertion of ternary B-site metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102414</link>
      <description>M. Jones, Cheng Lyu, David P. Trudgeon, Jack Corbin, Ida Nawrocka, Zhenyu Zhang, Mikkel B. Lykkegaard, Shaoliang Guan, Tim Dodwell, Xiaohong Li, Materials Today Chemistry. 42(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404629505

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Jones, Cheng Lyu, David P. Trudgeon, Jack Corbin, Ida Nawrocka, Zhenyu Zhang, Mikkel B. Lykkegaard, Shaoliang Guan, Tim Dodwell, Xiaohong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in advanced design of iridium&#8208;based and ruthenium&#8208;based perovskite catalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.79</link>
      <description>Yuqing Cheng, Yibo Wang, Zhaoping Shi, Hongxiang Wu, Jiahao Yang, Jing Ni, Ming Yang, Ziang Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631203

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is of great importance for the production of green hydrogen. The large&#8208;scale implementation of PEMWE, however, is seriously impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode, which results in considerable overpotential and thus the decreased energy conversion efficiency. To overcome this problem, researchers have extensively explored efficient anode catalysts that possess high activity and prolonged stability. Up to now, Ir&#8208;based and Ru&#8208;based catalysts are considered to be the most efficient candidates. Especially perovskite&#8208;based catalysts have received intensive attention due to their distinctive structures and exceptional OER catalytic performance. To further promote their practical application, considerable research efforts are devoted to structural engineering toward enhanced activity and stability. In this paper, a review of the research progress on the advanced design of Ir&#8208; and Ru&#8208;based perovskite catalysts is presented, with a focus on phase engineering, doping/substitution, morphology control, and compositing with other materials for perovskite catalysts as well as some preparation methods commonly used. It also summarizes the challenges and opportunities concerning perovskite&#8208;based catalysts in current research, yielding further comprehension of the pertinent preparation and scrutiny of perovskite catalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Cheng, Yibo Wang, Zhaoping Shi, Hongxiang Wu, Jiahao Yang, Jing Ni, Ming Yang, Ziang Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.79</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe/Co bimetallic borides with modified electronic structure for Efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161893</link>
      <description>Shuai Wan, Lihong Bao, Yuyang Zong, Jiayu Xiao, Jiaru He, Xinyu Gao, Sheng Wang, Ruguang Ma, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631327

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Wan, Lihong Bao, Yuyang Zong, Jiayu Xiao, Jiaru He, Xinyu Gao, Sheng Wang, Ruguang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161893</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying stable Nb-O clusters using evolutionary algorithm and DFT: A foundation for machine learning potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112533</link>
      <description>I.S. Popov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1042;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, Andrey N. Enyashin, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631358

                No abstract</description>
      <author>I.S. Popov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1042;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, Andrey N. Enyashin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking performance: A round-robin testing for liquid alkaline electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.288</link>
      <description>Simon Appelhaus, L. Ritz, Sharon V. Pape, Felix Lohmann&#8208;Richters, Mikkel Ryk&#230;r Kraglund, Jens Oluf Jensen, Francesco Massari, Mehrdad Boroomandnia, Matteo C. Romano, Justin Albers, Clemens Kubeil, Christian Immanuel Bern&#228;cker, Michelle Sophie Lemcke, Nadine Menzel, Guido Bender, Binyu Chen, Steven Holdcroft, Renaud Delmelle, Joris Proost, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Pertti Kauranen, Vesa Ruuskanen, Toni Viinanen, Martin M&#252;ller, Thomas Turek, Meital Shviro, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 95(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404632463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simon Appelhaus, L. Ritz, Sharon V. Pape, Felix Lohmann&#8208;Richters, Mikkel Ryk&#230;r Kraglund, Jens Oluf Jensen, Francesco Massari, Mehrdad Boroomandnia, Matteo C. Romano, Justin Albers, Clemens Kubeil, Christian Immanuel Bern&#228;cker, Michelle Sophie Lemcke, Nadine Menzel, Guido Bender, Binyu Chen, Steven Holdcroft, Renaud Delmelle, Joris Proost, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Pertti Kauranen, Vesa Ruuskanen, Toni Viinanen, Martin M&#252;ller, Thomas Turek, Meital Shviro</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Electronic Correlations in Ruthenium Oxides for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00068</link>
      <description>Xianbing Miao, Jingda Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Shiming Zhou, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404632938

                Elucidating the electronic factors dominating the adsorption properties of transition-metal oxides is essential to construct highly efficient oxygen-evolving catalysts for hydrogen production by water splitting but remains a great challenge. Electron correlation from on-site Coulomb repulsion (U) among d-electrons is generally believed to significantly affect the electronic structure of these materials; however, it has long been neglected in studying their adsorption properties. Here, by choosing ruthenium oxide as a model system, we demonstrate the role of electron correlation on the electrocatalytic activity toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Our density functional theory plus U calculations on rutile RuO2 reveal that the electron correlation can tune the adsorption energies for oxygenated intermediate and optimize them after the metallic oxide being a Mott insulator upon increasing U. By regulating the RuO6 octahedral network, we constructed and synthesized a series of strongly correlated ruthenium oxides, where the Mott insulating ones indeed exhibit a superior OER performance to the metallic RuO2. Our work builds a bridge between the electrochemistry and Mott physics for transition-metal oxides, opening a new avenue for designing advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xianbing Miao, Jingda Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Shiming Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Offsetting Carbon Footprints: Exploring CCUS Challenges and Solutions Across Diverse Industries in India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-70262-4_10</link>
      <description>Bidisha Chakrabarti, Sadichha Jagadale, Hemant Bherwani, Rajesh B. Biniwale, Environmental footprints and eco-design of products and processes. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404633031

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bidisha Chakrabarti, Sadichha Jagadale, Hemant Bherwani, Rajesh B. Biniwale</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-70262-4_10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversion of Waste Tecoma Leaves into Heteroatom Doped Graphitic Carbon via a One-Step Chemical Activation Method for the Catalytic Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Supercapacitor Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.4c00329</link>
      <description>Avinash Sharma, Prakash Majee, Pooja Pooja, Ravinder Pawar, Yadagiri Naik Banothu, Mukul Pradhan, ACS Sustainable Resource Management. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404634956

                For solid waste management and sustainable development, the conversion of waste materials into valuable feedstocks is essential. Keeping in mind the concept of "waste-to-wealth," we have synthesized value-added microporous graphitic carbon from waste Tecoma leaves, referred to as TA, through a one-step chemical activation process and utilized it for oxygen reduction reactions (ORRs) and capacitive energy storage applications. The transformation of biomass into metal-free porous graphitic carbon having an ORR efficiency comparable to or even better than commercially available Pt/C is critical for renewable energy conversion technologies. The TA-900 sample, synthesized at 900 &#176;C having a high surface area of 1429 m2 g&#8211;1, containing 4.41 atom % nitrogen and 4.74 atom % oxygen, demonstrated excellent ORR performance among the synthesized graphitic carbon samples at different temperatures. It showed an onset potential (Eonset) of 1 V and a limiting current density (JL) of 6.21 mA cm&#8211;2, comparable to 10 wt % Pt/C. Both experimental and theoretical findings suggest that the TA-900 electrocatalyst exhibited a 4e&#8211; transfer mechanism in the electrocatalytic reduction of O2 to H2O. Regarding supercapacitor application, TA-900 achieved a high specific capacitance of 546 F g&#8211;1 in acidic and 327 F g&#8211;1 in neutral aqueous electrolyte at a current density of 1 A g&#8211;1 in a three-electrode setup. The TA-900-based symmetrical supercapacitor (SSC) device has remarkable durability, retaining its 84% capacitance retention even after 3000 cycles at 1 A g&#8211;1. It also achieved a notable energy density (33 Wh kg&#8211;1 and 6.60 mWh cm&#8211;3) and a power density (6.20 kW kg&#8211;1 and 1320 mW cm&#8211;3). The findings emphasize that heteroatom-doped TA-900 electrocatalysts synthesized from waste Tecoma leaves will be a promising, affordable alternative to the high-cost Pt/C catalyst used for clean energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Avinash Sharma, Prakash Majee, Pooja Pooja, Ravinder Pawar, Yadagiri Naik Banothu, Mukul Pradhan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.4c00329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights into the hydrogen evolution reaction catalyzed by Co MoP (n = 1 &#8764; 5) clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112527</link>
      <description>Tinghui Wu, Zhigang Zak Fang, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635623

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tinghui Wu, Zhigang Zak Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Donation from Carbon Support Enhances the Activity and Stability of Ultrasmall Ruo2 Nanoparticles in Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030506</link>
      <description>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the in-gap defect states in the photo-generated electrons&#8217; dynamics over two dimensional defective bismuth oxybromide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physleta.2024.130080</link>
      <description>Z. Fan, Mengshi Zhou, Jin Li, Chaoyu He, Tao Ouyang, Chunxiao Zhang, Chao Tang, Jianxin Zhong, Physics Letters A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Z. Fan, Mengshi Zhou, Jin Li, Chaoyu He, Tao Ouyang, Chunxiao Zhang, Chao Tang, Jianxin Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physleta.2024.130080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Pretrained Transformer for Heterogeneous Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11504</link>
      <description>Dong Hyeon Mok, Seoin Back, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404636284

                Discovery of novel and promising materials is a critical challenge in the field of chemistry and material science, traditionally approached through methodologies ranging from trial-and-error to machine-learning-driven inverse design. Recent studies suggest that transformer-based language models can be utilized as material generative models to expand the chemical space and explore materials with desired properties. In this work, we introduce the catalyst generative pretrained transformer (CatGPT), trained to generate string representations of inorganic catalyst structures from a vast chemical space. CatGPT not only demonstrates high performance in generating valid and accurate catalyst structures but also serves as a foundation model for generating the desired types of catalysts by text-conditioning and fine-tuning. As an example, we fine-tuned the pretrained CatGPT using a binary alloy catalyst data set designed for screening two-electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e-ORR) catalyst and generated catalyst structures specialized for 2e-ORR. Our work demonstrates the potential of generative language models as generative tools for catalyst discovery.</description>
      <author>Dong Hyeon Mok, Seoin Back</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of uncompensated resistance on Hads-terminated Pt electrodeposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-06130-y</link>
      <description>Yihua Liu, M. C. Lafouresse, Ugo Bertocci, John E. Bonevich, Joseph A. Dura, Lee J. Richter, Gery R. Stafford, Thomas P. Moffat, Journal of Solid State Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404636983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yihua Liu, M. C. Lafouresse, Ugo Bertocci, John E. Bonevich, Joseph A. Dura, Lee J. Richter, Gery R. Stafford, Thomas P. Moffat</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-06130-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prebiotic formation of enantiomeric excess D-amino acids on natural pyrite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54481-x</link>
      <description>Ruiqi Li, Quanzheng Deng, Lu Han, Tianwei Ouyang, Shunai Che, Yuxi Fang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404639395

                D-amino acids, found in excess in a minority of organisms and crucial for marine invertebrates, contrast with the more common L-amino acids in most life forms. The local prebiotic origin of D-amino acid enantiomeric excess in natural systems remains an unsolved conundrum. Herein, we demonstrate the formation of enantiomeric excess (ee) D-amino acids through photocatalytic reductive amination of &#945;-keto acids on natural pyrite. Various amino acids with ee values in the range of 14.5&#8211;42.4%, are formed. The wavy arrangement of atoms on the surface of pyrite is speculated to lead to the preferential formation of D-amino acids. This work reveals the intrinsic asymmetric photocatalytic activity of pyrite, which could expand understandings on mechanism of asymmetric catalysis and chirality of inorganic crystals. Furthermore, it provides a plausible pathway for the prebiotic formation of D-amino acids, adding further evidence to the origin of D-amino acids enantiomeric excess in natural systems. Enantiomeric excess D-amino acids form via photocatalytic reductive amination of &#945;-keto acids on natural pyrite. This provides a plausible pathway for the prebiotic formation of D-amino acids.</description>
      <author>Ruiqi Li, Quanzheng Deng, Lu Han, Tianwei Ouyang, Shunai Che, Yuxi Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54481-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical ozone production: from fundamental mechanisms to advanced applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00204k</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Xiaoge Peng, Xiaosa Wang, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang, EES Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404640974

                This work explores the mechanism of electrochemical ozone production (EOP), focusing on electrocatalyst development, standardized testing, EOP electrolyzer design and application. By addressing challenges and summarizing progress, it aims to promote practical EOP application in diverse fields.</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Xiaoge Peng, Xiaosa Wang, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00204k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and kinetic analysis of the oxygen evolution reaction on TiO2 (100) and (101) surfaces: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122654</link>
      <description>Felipe Marinho Fernandes, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, M&#225;rcio Soares Pereira, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404642081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Felipe Marinho Fernandes, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, M&#225;rcio Soares Pereira, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolating Cu-Zn active-sites in Ordered Intermetallics to Enhance Nitrite-to-Ammonia Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53897-9</link>
      <description>Jiao Lan, Sheng Wang, Cheng&#8208;Wei Kao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Feng Xie, Yongwen Tan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404643314

                Electrocatalytic nitrite reduction to the valuable ammonia is a green and sustainable alternative to the conventional Haber-Bosch method for ammonia synthesis, while the activity and selectivity for ammonia production remains poor at low nitrite concentrations. Herein, we report a nanoporous intermetallic single-atom alloy CuZn (np/ISAA-CuZn) catalyst with completely isolated Cu-Zn active-sites, which achieves neutral nitrite reduction reaction with a remarkable NH3 Faradaic efficiency over 95% and the highest energy efficiency of &#8776; 59.1% in wide potential range from &#8722;0.2 to &#8722;0.8 V vs. RHE. The np/ISAA-CuZn electrocatalyst was able to operate stably at 500 mA cm&#8722;2 for 220 h under membrane electrode assembly conditions with a stabilized NH3 Faraday efficiency of ~80% and high NO2&#8210; removal rate of ~100%. A series of in situ experimental studies combined with density functional theory calculations reveal that strong electronic interactions of isolated Cu-Zn active-sites altered the protonation adsorption species, effectively alleviating the protonation barrier of *NO2 and thus greatly facilitating the selective reduction of NO2&#8722; into NH3. Electrocatalytic nitrite reduction is a green alternative to the Haber-Bosch process, but its ammonia production remains inefficient at low nitrite levels. Here the authors report an intermetallic single atom alloy CuZn catalyst for nitrite reduction to ammonia with high efficiency and stability at low nitrite concentration of 1&#8722;10 mM.</description>
      <author>Jiao Lan, Sheng Wang, Cheng&#8208;Wei Kao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Feng Xie, Yongwen Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53897-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis beyond the Reversible Hydrogen Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101611</link>
      <description>Dipam Manish Patel, Anjana Tripathi, Vivianne K. Ocampo-Restrepo, Georg Kastlunger, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404651800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dipam Manish Patel, Anjana Tripathi, Vivianne K. Ocampo-Restrepo, Georg Kastlunger</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101611</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing effects of edge-N in Pt-based carbon support on hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105499</link>
      <description>Xianyou Luo, Bokai Cao, Muhammad Fayaz, Wende Lai, Baodong Du, Heng Zheng, Xunhui Xiong, Yong Chen, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404653390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianyou Luo, Bokai Cao, Muhammad Fayaz, Wende Lai, Baodong Du, Heng Zheng, Xunhui Xiong, Yong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using CrN4 Moiety to Weaken the Dissociation Barrier of Hydroxyl on Adjacent Single Iron Atom for Efficient Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103927</link>
      <description>Li-Lian Wang, Lei Zhu, Xinyu Zhao, Hang Ma, Bingjie Pang, Lingyan Duan, Kun Zeng, Lu Liu, Anran Chen, Hong Guo, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404655119

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li-Lian Wang, Lei Zhu, Xinyu Zhao, Hang Ma, Bingjie Pang, Lingyan Duan, Kun Zeng, Lu Liu, Anran Chen, Hong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Reconstructed Fe&#8208;CoOOH Semi&#8208;Crystalline Electrocatalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408854</link>
      <description>Abdul Qayum, Karim Harrath, Rui Li, Abebe Reda Woldu, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Fushen Lu, Xiangdong Yao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657010

                Abstract The development of robust and efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been the main focus of water electrolysis but remains a great challenge. Here, the synthesis of a highly active and ultra&#8208;stable Fe&#8208;CoOOH electrocatalyst is reported by steering raw cobalt foam via an in situ solution combustion method assisted by a galvanic replacement reaction and subsequent electrochemical reconstruction of the CoFeO x pre&#8208;catalyst. In/ ex situ electrochemical analysis and physicochemical characterizations show that the CoFeO x undergoes quick chemical and slow morphological reconstruction to Fe&#8208;CoOOH nanosheets. The Fe&#8208;CoOOH possesses a semi&#8208;crystalline nature with distinct short&#8208;range ordering and outstanding OER activity with overpotentials as low as 271 and 291 mV at current densities of 500 and 1,000 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The remarkable stability under 1,000 mA cm &#8722;2 for at least 700 h is achieved. Theoretical calculations confirm the crucial role of Fe doping in facilitating surface reconstruction, enhancing OER activity, and improving the stability of the Fe&#8208;CoOOH. Comparative analysis with other transition metals doping reveals the unique ability of Fe to adsorb onto the CoOOH surface, thereby modulating the electronic density and facilitating faster adsorption of reaction intermediates. This work represents valuable insights into the surface reconstruction and doping processes.</description>
      <author>Abdul Qayum, Karim Harrath, Rui Li, Abebe Reda Woldu, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Fushen Lu, Xiangdong Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of biaxial strain and sulfur/boron doping on the photocatalytic performance of the g-C3N5 system: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113560</link>
      <description>Yongde Yao, Fujian Tang, Shangtong Yang, Computational Materials Science. 247(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongde Yao, Fujian Tang, Shangtong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Ni-coordinated MOF on stainless steel via electrodeposition as efficient and stable oxygen evolution electrode for alkaline water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145416</link>
      <description>Valentina Maria Volanti, Andrea Zaffora, Leonardo Iannucci, Sabrina Grassini, Elisabetta Inico, Clara Saetta, Giovanni Di Liberto, Monica Santamaria, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657854

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Valentina Maria Volanti, Andrea Zaffora, Leonardo Iannucci, Sabrina Grassini, Elisabetta Inico, Clara Saetta, Giovanni Di Liberto, Monica Santamaria</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical behavior of LiNiCo oxide cathodes as catalyst for lithium-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-06149-1</link>
      <description>E. Meza, Francisco Herrera, Juan Luis Gautier, Journal of Solid State Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404662045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. Meza, Francisco Herrera, Juan Luis Gautier</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-06149-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing the carbon nano-belt (8-CNB) loaded late second-row transition metal (TM) single-atom catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution during water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109139</link>
      <description>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Shimna Biju, Remabai Balachandran, Khurshid Ayub, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 187(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404670172

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Shimna Biju, Remabai Balachandran, Khurshid Ayub, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo-assisted highly efficient electrocatalytic N2 fixation on nonmetal-metal dual atom catalysts through the reversable evolution of active center</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114712</link>
      <description>Zheng Xu, Yi Ding, Song Lu, Tiancun Liu, Hailing Liu, Yong Jun Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu, Molecular Catalysis. 571(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404676999

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheng Xu, Yi Ding, Song Lu, Tiancun Liu, Hailing Liu, Yong Jun Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the performance of g-C3N4 loaded silver nanoparticles (Ag4, Ag8, Ag13) catalysts and their electrocatalytic reduction mechanism of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114705</link>
      <description>Xin-Long Zhang, Ya-Yuan Shi, Xiao&#8208;Min Liang, Laicai Li, Molecular Catalysis. 571(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404678818

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Long Zhang, Ya-Yuan Shi, Xiao&#8208;Min Liang, Laicai Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Pt Active Sites on Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Nanocages for Industrial Hydrogen Evolution with Ultralow Pt Usage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11445</link>
      <description>Jingyi Tian, Minqi Xia, Xueyi Cheng, Chenghui Mao, Yiqun Chen, Yan Zhang, Changkai Zhou, Fengfei Xu, Lijun Yang, Xizhang Wang, Qiang Wu, Zheng Hu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404681858

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingyi Tian, Minqi Xia, Xueyi Cheng, Chenghui Mao, Yiqun Chen, Yan Zhang, Changkai Zhou, Fengfei Xu, Lijun Yang, Xizhang Wang, Qiang Wu, Zheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epoxidized Single-Atom Co&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalysts Promote the Oxygen Reduction Reaction via a Two-Electron Pathway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17354</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Jingyu Feng, Tao Yang, Yao Qin, Jiacheng Xie, Zengxi Wei, Shuangliang Zhao, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404686505

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Jingyu Feng, Tao Yang, Yao Qin, Jiacheng Xie, Zengxi Wei, Shuangliang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation effects on the alkaline oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101186</link>
      <description>Yifan Zeng, Dongbo Li, Pengtao Xu, Chem Catalysis. 4(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404580265

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Zeng, Dongbo Li, Pengtao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101186</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
