<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 01:37:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning electrical conductivity in lithium-doped sodium titanate via sonochemical synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118836</link>
      <description>J. Silva, Juliana Pereira da Silva, Rita Santos, Salom&#227;o dos Santos Costa, Francisco Xavier Nobre, M&#243;nica Tirado, Angsula Ghosh, Lianet Aguilera Dom&#237;nguez, Y. Leyet, Materials Science and Engineering B. 323(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414904817

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Silva, Juliana Pereira da Silva, Rita Santos, Salom&#227;o dos Santos Costa, Francisco Xavier Nobre, M&#243;nica Tirado, Angsula Ghosh, Lianet Aguilera Dom&#237;nguez, Y. Leyet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of surface phonons on the thermal conductivity of triply periodic minimal surface silicon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/ctfs-fx4m</link>
      <description>Peng Bi, Yakun Wan, Yong Yi, Songhu Bi, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 112(15)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414912749

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Bi, Yakun Wan, Yong Yi, Songhu Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/ctfs-fx4m</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Powering the Future: A Cobalt&#8208;Based Catalyst for Longer&#8208;Lasting Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519329</link>
      <description>Manami Banerjee, Peng Ren, Greesh Kumar, Lucie M. Lindenbeck, Byoung Joon Park, Anna Rokici&#324;ska, Piotr Ku&#347;trowski, Adam Slabon, Francesco Ciucci, Ramendra Sundar Dey, Shoubhik Das, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414914133

                Abstract The development of cost&#8208;effective catalysts for zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) remain challenging due to the sluggish kinetics of oxygen reduction (ORR) and evolution (OER) at the cathode. In this context, a novel N&#8208;doped graphitic shell&#8208;encapsulated cobalt catalyst is presented as an air electrode with exceptional bifunctional activity, achieving an ORR half&#8208;wave potential ( E 1/2 ) of 0.81 V and an OER overpotential of 349 mV in an alkaline medium. The catalyst demonstrated excellent cycling durability and delivered superior power density in both liquid and solid&#8208;state ZABs. Furthermore, a quasi&#8208;solid&#8208;state ZAB is assembled with the catalyst, and it maintained a stable open&#8208;circuit voltage (OCV) of 1.360 V for &gt;10 000 s. The catalyst achieved a peak power density of 127 mW cm &#8722;2 &#8212;significantly outperforming the benchmark Pt/C + RuO 2 system (74 mW cm &#8722;2 ). When two tandem&#8208;junction ZABs are connected in series, they achieved an OCV of 2.75 V and powering a &#8220;ZAB&#8221; LED strip and a mini fan. Furthermore, Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations revealed that the enhanced performance resulted from optimized binding energies between the Co@N(py) active sites and reaction intermediates. An in situ Raman study is carried out to understand the catalytic mechanism through transient intermediate detection.</description>
      <author>Manami Banerjee, Peng Ren, Greesh Kumar, Lucie M. Lindenbeck, Byoung Joon Park, Anna Rokici&#324;ska, Piotr Ku&#347;trowski, Adam Slabon, Francesco Ciucci, Ramendra Sundar Dey, Shoubhik Das</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Library for Monte Carlo Simulations with Ab Initio and Machine-Learned Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01148</link>
      <description>Woodrow N. Wilson, Vivek S. Bharadwaj, Neeraj Rai, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414914434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Woodrow N. Wilson, Vivek S. Bharadwaj, Neeraj Rai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Bifunctional Electrocatalysts Through p&#8208;Block Metal Incorporation in Transition Metal Doped N&#8208;Graphene for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507111</link>
      <description>Sougata Saha, K. Vipin Raj, Swapan K. Pati, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414917841

                Abstract Development of efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is essential for renewable energy storage and conversion technologies. While transition metal (TM) co&#8208;doped N&#8208;doped graphene systems (TM&#8208;N&#8208;G) are well&#8208;known for their electrocatalytic performance, their bifunctional activity for both OER and ORR remains limited and inefficient. In this work, bifunctional electrocatalytic performance of TM&#8208;N 6 &#8208;G systems (TM = Fe, Co, and Ni) is investigated by incorporating p&#8208;block metals (PM = Al, Ga, In, Sn, and Bi) into an N 4 cavity, resulting in TM&#8208;PM&#8208;N 6 &#8208;G structures. Systematic DFT calculations reveal that among all the system configurations, Co&#8208;Ga&#8208;N 6 &#8208;G and Co&#8208;Sn&#8208;N 6 &#8208;G emerge as highly efficient bifunctional catalysts. The enhanced catalytic activity of Co centres is attributed to optimal interactions with reaction intermediates, as elucidated by scaling relations, volcano plots, and contour maps. These optimal interactions are explained by changes in electronic structure of catalysts and charge redistribution at the TM sites, induced by incorporated PMs. A new descriptor &#978; is proposed to describe the catalytic activity, performing better than conventional d&#8208;band center. Additionally, several unifunctional catalysts are identified. This detailed analysis provides key insights and design strategies for developing high&#8208;performance bifunctional catalysts via PM doping in TM&#8208;N&#8208;G systems.</description>
      <author>Sougata Saha, K. Vipin Raj, Swapan K. Pati</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting paint resistance to pull-off by first principles calculations: The case of acrylic acid on (oxidised) metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2025.114898</link>
      <description>Manuel Montebelli, Paolo Restuccia, Maria Clelia Righi, Materials &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414926842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manuel Montebelli, Paolo Restuccia, Maria Clelia Righi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2025.114898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low&#8208;Voltage Driven Co&#8208;Production of Ammonia, Formate, and Hydrogen From Nitrite Reduction Coupled Formaldehyde Oxidation System on Ultra&#8208;Stable AuCuRh Nanowires under Illumination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202513320</link>
      <description>Ze&#8208;Nong Zhang, Xiaohui Wang, Wei Zhong, Xuan Ai, Xin Wang, Shu&#8208;Ni Li, Bao Yu Xia, Yu Chen, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414930241

                The nitrite electroreduction reaction (NO2RR) offers a green and sustainable pathway for environmental wastewater treatment and ammonia (NH3) generation. Herein, defect-rich trimetallic AuCuRh nanowires (AuCuRh NWs) with a large number of grain boundaries, twin boundaries, and atomic steps are successfully synthesized by galvanic replacement reaction. Due to its self-stability and high activity, AuCuRh NWs can efficiently drive the stable NO2RR at 0 V potential (Faradaic efficiency: 98.32%, NH3 yield rate: 20.49 mg h-1 mgcat -1). Moreover, AuCuRh NWs also reveal excellent electrocatalytic activity for the formaldehyde electrooxidation reaction (FOR), which can reach 10 mA cm-2 at only 0.35 V potential. The NO2RR||FOR electrolysis system assembled with AuCuRh NWs requires only the electrolysis voltage of 0.38 V to achieve the co-production of NH3, formate, and hydrogen and ultra-stable continuous electrolysis for 300 hours. The NO2RR||FOR electrolysis system can be further decreased to only 0.29 V under illumination due to plasmon-enhanced activity. This study provides an energy-efficient coupling strategy for the stable co-production of value-added chemicals.</description>
      <author>Ze&#8208;Nong Zhang, Xiaohui Wang, Wei Zhong, Xuan Ai, Xin Wang, Shu&#8208;Ni Li, Bao Yu Xia, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202513320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of the electrocatalytic activity of nonlinear optically active CuWO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanocomposites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5dt01694k</link>
      <description>Bankim J. Sanghavi, K. Aravinth, Manikandan Kandasamy, P. Balaji Bhargav, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414936464

                This research focused on successfully synthesizing CuWO4/g-C3N4 nanocomposites using microwave assistance, and their potential as electrochemical supercapacitors and electrocatalysts for the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions was thoroughly investigated. Structural studies demonstrated the anchoring of the spherical CuWO4 nanoparticles with a triclinic structure on the g-C3N4 surface. The CuWO4/g-C3N4 system showed an impressive specific capacitance of 111 F g-1 and excellent stability (85%) in supercapacitor applications. It also exhibited remarkable bifunctional electrocatalytic performance, efficiently facilitating both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in distinct electrolytes. Notably, it achieved a standard current density of 10 mA cm-2 with significantly lower Tafel slopes (46 mV dec-1 (HER) and 104 mV dec-1 (OER)) compared to pristine CuWO4. The nanocomposite's superior electrochemical performance was attributed to the synergistic effect of g-C3N4 and CuWO4, leading to high capacitance and excellent catalytic activity. Additionally, the nanocomposite exhibited enhanced nonlinear absorption and refraction upon He-Ne laser excitation, suggesting potential applications in optical devices. These findings highlight the promising prospects of CuWO4/g-C3N4 nanocomposites as multifunctional materials for energy storage and catalysis. DFT calculations further validate the experimental findings by providing insights into the electronic structures, quantum capacitance, adsorption geometries, and overpotentials of the hybrid systems. The calculated overpotential trend of CuW/gCN &lt; CuW agrees with the experimental data.</description>
      <author>Bankim J. Sanghavi, K. Aravinth, Manikandan Kandasamy, P. Balaji Bhargav, Brahmananda Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5dt01694k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning axial ligand coordination for enhanced activity and selectivity in metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon single-atom catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0288918</link>
      <description>H.T. Wang, Mingjie Liu, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414966260

                Axial ligand coordination plays a critical role in modulating the catalytic activity and selectivity of metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) single-atom catalysts (SACs) for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we systematically investigate FeN4, CoN4, and NiN4 active sites coordinated with a broad range of axial ligands to elucidate how ligand environments influence reaction energetics across different metal centers. Free energy analyses reveal that axial ligands can substantially modify key steps in the ORR pathway, including *OOH formation and *OH desorption, with distinct effects observed for each metal. FeN4 exhibits tunable activity and selectivity depending on the ligand, balancing between 4e&#8722; and 2e&#8722; pathways. CoN4 shows a pronounced preference toward the 2e&#8722; pathway under specific ligand environments, highlighting its potential for selective H2O2 production. In contrast, NiN4 displays generally high energy barriers and limited ORR activity across all axial ligands. These results establish a comparative framework for understanding how axial ligand coordination governs ORR performance and provide guidance for the rational design of M&#8211;N&#8211;C SACs with tailored activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>H.T. Wang, Mingjie Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0288918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the electrocatalytic activity of Fe/co-8-16-4 graphyne through sulfur or phosphorus doping for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238579</link>
      <description>Ghazaleh Jafari, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani, Journal of Power Sources. 660(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414967546

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ghazaleh Jafari, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partitioning adsorption energy: An electronegativity-based descriptor for hydrogen adsorption on group IV and III&#8211;V 2D honeycombs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0295089</link>
      <description>Yi Sheng Ng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414969325

                Understanding and predicting hydrogen adsorption energy is key to designing effective electrocatalysts. In this study, we develop a physically interpretable descriptor within a framework that decomposes atomic hydrogen adsorption energy into intuitive contributions, applied to 22 group IV and III&#8211;V 2D honeycomb materials. The density functional theory (DFT) calculated adsorption energy is decomposed into two components: bond energy, approximated by the integrated crystal orbital Hamilton population (ICOHP), and the energy cost of forming the additional bond, termed distortion energy Ed. This decomposition facilitates analysis of adsorption trends beyond treating adsorption energy as a single quantity. We find that ICOHP correlates strongly with the adsorption site electronegativity (R2 = 0.86), improving to R2 = 0.91 when electronegativity differences and structural parameters are included. Ed shows moderate correlation with the unrelaxed vacancy energy Evac (R2 = 0.60) and can be accurately modeled (R2 = 0.92) using similar dependences on electronegativity and structural parameters. Notably, Evac can be expressed in terms of the sum of electronegativities, enabling a DFT-free formulation. Combining both components into an Eads descriptor, we achieve an R2 score of 0.82 across both group IV and III&#8211;V systems. Further analysis reveals that increasing the adsorption site electronegativity weakens adsorption unless the lattice constant is sufficiently large. In addition, we identify a linear relationship between ICOHP and the zero-point energy change, allowing the descriptor to be extended to the free energy of hydrogen adsorption, a key indicator of hydrogen evolution reaction activity.</description>
      <author>Yi Sheng Ng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0295089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand-Canonical Equivariant Neural Potentials for Electrochemical Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01381</link>
      <description>Jia-Lan Chen, Xin&#8208;Rui Qi, Jinze Zhu, Jin Li, Xuechun Jiang, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Jin&#8208;Xun Liu, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414970226

                Electrochemical reactions under constant potential underpin critical processes in energy storage, catalysis, and corrosion but remain challenging to model owing to the voltage insensitivity of conventional machine learning potentials. The lack of a unified framework incorporating grand-canonical constraints into machine-learned models fundamentally limits accurate, scalable simulations of potential-dependent interfacial phenomena. Here, we present a constant-potential, E(3)-equivariant message-passing neural network (CPMPNN) that integrates grand-canonical electronic structure principles with a global excess-charge parameter that is dynamically redistributed via a multihead attention mechanism. The atomic geometry is encoded through a graph neural network that preserves the full symmetry of the Euclidean group in three dimensions (E(3))&#9472;including translations, rotations, and reflections. Benchmarking against the grand-canonical DFT confirms that the CPMPNN retains first-principles accuracy while achieving a three-orders-of-magnitude computational speedup. Applied to key electrocatalytic processes&#9472;CO dimerization in CO2 reduction and the Volmer step in hydrogen evolution on Cu(100)&#9472;CPMPNN captures how the applied potential modulates the reaction thermodynamics, charge distribution, and transition-state structures, providing mechanistic insight into potential-dependent kinetics. By bridging first-principle accuracy with molecular dynamics scalability, CPMPNN provides a transferable framework for operando modeling of electrified interfaces, enabling new mechanistic insights into potential-controlled electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Jia-Lan Chen, Xin&#8208;Rui Qi, Jinze Zhu, Jin Li, Xuechun Jiang, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Jin&#8208;Xun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Cr-Ru Oxide Catalysts on TiO2 Support for High-Efficiency Proton Exchange towards Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2025.107988</link>
      <description>Bohan Zhang, Chang Wen, Mingtao Xu, Zhilin Ye, Wenshang Chen, Ben Chen, Qingsong Hua, Ke Liu, Zhengkai Tu, Process Safety and Environmental Protection. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414974313

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bohan Zhang, Chang Wen, Mingtao Xu, Zhilin Ye, Wenshang Chen, Ben Chen, Qingsong Hua, Ke Liu, Zhengkai Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2025.107988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annihilation process of a diagonally arranged dislocation pair in graphene: density-functional tight-binding molecular dynamics and first-principles studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114301</link>
      <description>Yasuhito Ohta, Computational Materials Science. 261(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414974369

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yasuhito Ohta</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the efficiency and stability of cerium-doped trimetallic phosphides for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169404</link>
      <description>Mai Mai, Sampath Prabhakaran, Huyen Thi Dao, Lan Nguyen, Hyunseok Ko, Young Sun Mok, Van Hien Hoa, Do Hwan Kim, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414974776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mai Mai, Sampath Prabhakaran, Huyen Thi Dao, Lan Nguyen, Hyunseok Ko, Young Sun Mok, Van Hien Hoa, Do Hwan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the Code of RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Corrosion: A Theoretical Exploration of Potential&#8208;Driven Switches Between Oxidative and Reductive Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500341</link>
      <description>Badr Elkamash, Franziska He&#223;, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414979225

                Ruthenium dioxide (RuO 2 ) is a benchmark catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media but suffers from slow dissolution under operating conditions, limiting its long&#8208;term durability. Here, density functional theory combined with the computational hydrogen electrode model is employed to elucidate the atomistic mechanisms governing RuO 2 surface corrosion across a relevant potential window from 0 to 1.5 V standard hydrogen electrode (SHE) . The study reveals a potential&#8208;dependent switch in dissolution pathways: at anodic potentials above 1.21 V SHE , direct oxidative dissolution leads to soluble RuO 4 , whereas at lower potentials, coupled proton&#8211;electron transfer reactions drive the formation of soluble hydroxylated species, specifically Ru(OH) 4 and RuO 2 (OH) 2 . Key surface intermediates act as energetic basins, regulating transient dissolution during potential cycling and shutdown. Furthermore, it is shown that doping RuO 2 with W, Ti, or Ir shifts the onset potentials for these corrosion pathways, enhancing surface stability by widening the potential window where the materials are stable. These insights advance the mechanistic understanding of RuO 2 degradation and support rational strategies for designing durable OER catalysts in acidic water&#8208;splitting technologies.</description>
      <author>Badr Elkamash, Franziska He&#223;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tetragonal transition metal sulfides for hydrogen evolution: a density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107819</link>
      <description>Fei Yang, Yuan Yao, Chao Su, Beibei Xiao, Daifen Chen, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414979727

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Yang, Yuan Yao, Chao Su, Beibei Xiao, Daifen Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ParametrizANI: Fast and Accessible Dihedral Parametrization for Small Molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01957</link>
      <description>Pablo R. Arantes, Souvik Sinha, Giulia Palermo, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414982114

                In molecular studies, the accurate parametrization of small molecules stands as an essential yet growing demand. Addressing this, we introduce ParametrizANI, a tool crafted explicitly for establishing detailed protocols for dihedral parametrization using GAFF and OpenFF force fields. The robust PyTorch-based program, TorchANI, forms the backbone of ParametrizANI, functioning as a benchmark to uphold precision in parametrization tasks. TorchANI plays a pivotal role in enabling ANI (ANAKIN-ME) deep learning models, which are trained to predict potential energy surfaces and related molecular properties with high accuracy. Our work on ParametrizANI goes beyond just creating a tool; it is about building a research-friendly environment, free from the constraints of limited resources. We are committed to democratizing research, enabling teams of all sizes to perform dihedral parametrization with DFT-level accuracy. This tool opens up new possibilities in molecular dynamics and related fields. It marks a significant step forward in improving the scientific community's ability to parametrize small molecules. For a detailed look at its features, we invite you to check out ParametrizANI on GitHub (https://github.com/palermolab/ParametrizANI).</description>
      <author>Pablo R. Arantes, Souvik Sinha, Giulia Palermo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning oxygen evolution activity via transition metal doping in bimetallic nickel phosphates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164846</link>
      <description>Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Rizky Dio Idhola, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Hamad AlMohamadi, Shashikant P. Patole, Sasfan Arman Wella, Fiki T. Akbar, Jenny Rizkiana, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414991420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Rizky Dio Idhola, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Hamad AlMohamadi, Shashikant P. Patole, Sasfan Arman Wella, Fiki T. Akbar, Jenny Rizkiana, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Exploration of High-Dimensional Configuration Spaces for the Generation of Chemical Datasets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01286</link>
      <description>Xuewen Xiao, A. Allouche, E. Dartois, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Magoul&#232;s, Daniel Pel&#225;ez, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414992617

                In this work, we introduce an automated methodology for the efficient and relatively inexpensive exploration of large high-dimensional chemical spaces, with particular focus on number-of-atoms-conserving processes, such as in mechanochemical reactions. Our approach combines: (1) a physically motivated stochastic global-landscape exploration phase (mechanochemical distortion), which efficiently overcomes entropic barriers, and (2) a local exploration phase in which the previously determined local basins are sampled with molecular dynamics and graph theory. Specifically, this last phase makes use of the (vdW-) transition state search using a chemical dynamical simulations algorithm. Our methodology requires minimal input from the user. As a case study, we have explored the conformational landscape, including transition states and minimum energy paths, of the C60H10 hydrogen-carbon clusters owing to their astrochemical relevance as potential carriers of the aromatic infrared bands. From a single initial seed (geometry), we have obtained a series of 212 mechanochemically relevant conformers, and from just 3 of them, we have obtained a set of &gt;13 000 minima spanning the domain of our interest. The underlying chemical network has been fully characterized and rationalized using statistical analysis tools. Our case study perfectly illustrates the potential of our approach in the automatic generation of chemical databases, in other words, annotated data for the training of data-hungry deep learning models in chemistry.</description>
      <author>Xuewen Xiao, A. Allouche, E. Dartois, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Magoul&#232;s, Daniel Pel&#225;ez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prussian blue analogues and their derivatives for electrochemical energy conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.217215</link>
      <description>Jun Xiang, Shu Jiang, Guangxun Zhang, Shuaining Gao, Ke Wu, Mohsen Shakouri, Huan Pang, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 548(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414995718

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Xiang, Shu Jiang, Guangxun Zhang, Shuaining Gao, Ke Wu, Mohsen Shakouri, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.217215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Strain and Electronic Effects in AuCu@CuFePd Core&#8211;Shell Nanocatalysts for Acidic Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c03515</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Ma, Zhong Zheng, Hui Liu, Shaonan Tian, Dong Chen, Jun Yang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414998512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Ma, Zhong Zheng, Hui Liu, Shaonan Tian, Dong Chen, Jun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c03515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Mechanisms and Catalysis in Solar Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-5914-2_9</link>
      <description>Esdras J. Canto&#8208;Aguilar, Elena Puentes-Prado, Alice Kuzhikandathil, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino, Progress in optical science and photonics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415002587

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Esdras J. Canto&#8208;Aguilar, Elena Puentes-Prado, Alice Kuzhikandathil, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-5914-2_9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Analysis of the Energetic Stability of High-Entropy Structures of a Prototypical Lanthanide-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04892</link>
      <description>S. D. Madhu Kumar, Dorina F. Sava Gallis, David S. Sholl, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415008276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. D. Madhu Kumar, Dorina F. Sava Gallis, David S. Sholl</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles discovery of stable two-dimensional AlInX2 (X=N, P, As) with high carrier mobility for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417905</link>
      <description>Chunying Pu, Yuqing Kang, Xinfu Pan, Dawei Zhou, Physica B Condensed Matter. 718(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415011781

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunying Pu, Yuqing Kang, Xinfu Pan, Dawei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial assembly and electrolytic water mechanism of PW11M, PW11M@ZIF-67, and PW11M@FeCoNi-LDH: Insights from DFT and experimental characterizations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169358</link>
      <description>B. T. Dai, Liang Chen, Xiaolong Bao, Qin Zhong, Hongxia Qu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415013417

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. T. Dai, Liang Chen, Xiaolong Bao, Qin Zhong, Hongxia Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Scaling Relations with Inverse Catalysts: A Machine Learning Exploration of Trends in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-Formate Energy Barriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c05872</link>
      <description>L. Kempen, Marius Juul Nielsen, Mie Andersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415015901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. Kempen, Marius Juul Nielsen, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c05872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of C3N-based single-atom catalysts and calculation of the performance in electrocatalytic NO reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11164-025-05779-y</link>
      <description>Wei Song, Qingqing Guo, Pengfei Ma, Peng Wang, Xiao Liu, Chaozheng He, Jinlong Wang, Research on Chemical Intermediates. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415018593

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Song, Qingqing Guo, Pengfei Ma, Peng Wang, Xiao Liu, Chaozheng He, Jinlong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11164-025-05779-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Donor Gd&#8208;Evoked Pd&#9472;OH* Interaction Modulation via Alloying for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202514759</link>
      <description>Leilei Yin, Yuyan Liu, Shuai Zhang, Jincheng Liu, Yong Jiang, Yaping Du, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415018993

                Abstract Excessive adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates during oxygen reduction reactions (ORR) on palladium (Pd)&#8208;based materials is a critical factor limiting their catalytic activity. Alloying presents a powerful strategy to overcome this inherent challenge. In this study, the alloying of the low electronegativity lanthanide gadolinium (Gd) with Pd is explored. Pioneering theoretical calculations indicate that Gd, acting as an electron donor, induces charge redistribution between the metals. This process weakens the over&#8208;adsorption of OH* intermediates on the Pd surface and reduces the reaction overpotential. Subsequent experiments yield Pd 3 Gd solid&#8208;solution nano&#8208;alloys supported on conductive carbon black (Pd 3 Gd/C&#8208;600), resulting in a 30 mV enhancement in half&#8208;wave potential and a 4.5 fold increase in mass activity in an alkaline medium compared to Pd/C&#8208;600. Due to its superior performance in ORR, Zn&#8208;air batteries utilizing Pd 3 Gd/C&#8208;600 cathodes demonstrate remarkable peak power density and stability over 330 h. This study offers valuable insights into the rational design of rare earth alloys and their catalytic chemistry in ORR.</description>
      <author>Leilei Yin, Yuyan Liu, Shuai Zhang, Jincheng Liu, Yong Jiang, Yaping Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202514759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA methylation and machine learning: challenges and perspective toward enhanced clinical diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s13148-025-01967-0</link>
      <description>Erfan Aref-Eshghi, Alireza Abadi, Mohammad&#8208;Erfan Farhadieh, Amirreza Hooshmand, Fatemeh Ghasemi, Leila Youssefian, Hassan Vahidnezhad, Taylor Martin Kerrins, Xiaonan Zhao, Mahdi Akbarzadeh, Hakon Hakonarson, Amir Hossein Saeidian, Clinical Epigenetics. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415020889

                DNA methylation is an epigenetic modification that regulates gene expression by adding methyl groups to DNA, affecting cellular function and disease development. Machine learning, a subset of artificial intelligence, analyzes large datasets to identify patterns and make predictions. Over the past two decades, advances in bioinformatics technologies for arrays and sequencing have generated vast amounts of data, leading to the widespread adoption of machine learning methods for analyzing complex biological information for medical problems. This review explores recent advancements in DNA methylation studies that leverage emerging machine learning techniques for more precise, comprehensive, and rapid patient diagnostics based on DNA methylation markers. We present a general workflow for researchers, from clinical research questions to result interpretation and monitoring. Additionally, we showcase successful examples in diagnosing cancer, neurodevelopmental disorders, and multifactorial diseases. Some of these studies have led to the development of diagnostic platforms that have entered the global healthcare market, highlighting the promising future of this field.</description>
      <author>Erfan Aref-Eshghi, Alireza Abadi, Mohammad&#8208;Erfan Farhadieh, Amirreza Hooshmand, Fatemeh Ghasemi, Leila Youssefian, Hassan Vahidnezhad, Taylor Martin Kerrins, Xiaonan Zhao, Mahdi Akbarzadeh, Hakon Hakonarson, Amir Hossein Saeidian</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s13148-025-01967-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single&#8208;Atomic Ni&#8208;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Biofuel Cell for Mimicking Intramolecular Electron&#8208;Harnessing of Laccase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202511892</link>
      <description>Tapan Dey, Anubha Yadav, Nilanjan Seal, Babasaheb M. Matsagar, Norman C.&#8208;R. Chen, Praveen Kumar Yadav, Kevin C.&#8208;W. Wu, Amreen Bano, Saikat Dutta, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415023216

                Abstract Ni&#8211;N 4 &#8211;PAN&#8211;NC, consisting of an atomic Ni&#8211;N 4 site, mimics the intramolecular electron&#8208;harnessing of natural laccase (LAC) confined in a zeolitic imidazolate framework&#8208;8 (LAC@ZIF&#8208;8) for anodic electrooxidation of bisphenol&#8208;A (BPA). We have introduced a facile &#960;&#8208;conjugated unit of polyacrylonitrile (PAN)&#8208;resorcinol&#8208;derived N&#8208;doped conjugated &#8208;C&#8801;N. The atomically dispersed Ni&#8208;single&#8208;atom in Ni&#8211;N 4 &#8208; PAN&#8211;NC exhibits high activity for the paired electrolysis of ORR and the electrooxidation of BPA with an enhanced current density. The single Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC electrode effectively withdraws the electrons from electrooxidizing BPA due to a built&#8208;in electric field via incorporation of Ni&#8211;N 4 . The paired electrolysis of Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC biofuel cells is determined by LSV, EIS, and power&#8208;polarization curve for anodic electrooxidation of BPA. Machine learning molecular dynamics (ML&#8208;MD) simulation depicts non&#8208;covalent interaction (hydrogen bonding) between the O&#8208;hydroxyl of BPA and the N of the Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC, suggesting preferential adsorption on the Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC surface via weak van der Waals interactions and &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking between the aromatic rings of BPA and the conjugated PAN&#8208;NC. An increased power density with increased concentration of BPA in the absence of ABTS suggests a DET mechanism of BPA electrooxidation on Ni&#8211;N 4 , unlike a MET in the presence of ABTS when using LAC@ZIF&#8208;8. Thus, single atomic Ni &#8722; N 4 opens avenues with a DET mechanism.</description>
      <author>Tapan Dey, Anubha Yadav, Nilanjan Seal, Babasaheb M. Matsagar, Norman C.&#8208;R. Chen, Praveen Kumar Yadav, Kevin C.&#8208;W. Wu, Amreen Bano, Saikat Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202511892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin Matters: A Multidisciplinary Roadmap to Understanding Spin Effects in Oxygen Evolution Reaction During Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503556</link>
      <description>Emma van der Minne, Priscila Vensaus, Vadim Ratovskii, Seenivasan Hariharan, Jan Behrends, Cesare Franchini, Jonas Fransson, S. S. Dhesi, Felix Gunkel, Florian Gossing, Georgios Katsoukis, Ulrike I. Kramm, &#8234;Magal&#237; Lingenfelder, Qianqian Lan, Yury V. Kolen&#8217;ko, Yang Li, Ramsundar Rani Mohan, Jeffrey McCord, Lingmei Ni, Eva Pavarini, Rossitza Pentcheva, David H. Waldeck, Michael Verhage, Anke Yu, Zhichuan J. Xu, Piero Torelli, Silvia Mauri, Narcis Avarvari, Anja Bieberle&#8208;H&#252;tter, Christoph Baeumer, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415028808

                Abstract A central challenge in water electrolysis lies with the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) where the formation of molecular oxygen (O 2 ) is hindered by the constraint of angular momentum conservation. While the reactants OH &#8722; or H 2 O are diamagnetic (DM), the O 2 product has a paramagnetic (PM) triplet ground state, requiring a change in spin configuration when being formed. This constraint has prompted interest in spin&#8208;selective catalysts as a means to facilitate OER. In this context, the roles of magnetism and chirality&#8208;induced spin selectivity (CISS) in promoting the OER reaction have recently been investigated through both theoretical and experimental studies. However, pinpointing the key principles and their relative contribution in mediating spin&#8208;enhancement remains a significant challenge. This roadmap offers a forward&#8208;looking perspective on current experimental trends and theoretical developments in spin&#8208;enhanced OER electrocatalysis and outlines strategic directions for integrating incisive experiments and operando approaches with computational modeling to disentangle key mechanisms. By providing a conceptual framework and identifying critical knowledge gaps, this perspective aims to guide researchers toward dedicated experimental and computational studies that will deepen the understanding of spin&#8208;induced OER enhancement and accelerate the development of next&#8208;generation catalysts.</description>
      <author>Emma van der Minne, Priscila Vensaus, Vadim Ratovskii, Seenivasan Hariharan, Jan Behrends, Cesare Franchini, Jonas Fransson, S. S. Dhesi, Felix Gunkel, Florian Gossing, Georgios Katsoukis, Ulrike I. Kramm, &#8234;Magal&#237; Lingenfelder, Qianqian Lan, Yury V. Kolen&#8217;ko, Yang Li, Ramsundar Rani Mohan, Jeffrey McCord, Lingmei Ni, Eva Pavarini, Rossitza Pentcheva, David H. Waldeck, Michael Verhage, Anke Yu, Zhichuan J. Xu, Piero Torelli, Silvia Mauri, Narcis Avarvari, Anja Bieberle&#8208;H&#252;tter, Christoph Baeumer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic modelling of post-plasma catalysis to improve the conversion of dry reforming of methane in a gliding arc plasmatron</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116474</link>
      <description>Sara Ceulemans, Eduardo Morais, Bj&#246;rn Loenders, Annemie Bogaerts, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415029745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sara Ceulemans, Eduardo Morais, Bj&#246;rn Loenders, Annemie Bogaerts</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focused thermal energy at atomic microwave antenna sites for ecocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ady4043</link>
      <description>Ryo Ishibashi, Fuminao Kishimoto, Tatsushi Yoshioka, Hiroki Yamada, Koki Muraoka, Toshiaki Ina, Hiroki Taniguchi, Akira Nakayama, Toru Wakihara, Kazuhiro Takanabe, Science Advances. 11(41)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415035200

                Green transformation demands efficient protocols to convert renewable energy into usable forms. Microwave (MW)&#8211;driven catalytic systems offer a promising electrification strategy for chemical processes by enabling targeted, energy-efficient reactions. Unlike conventional heating, MW irradiation can localize energy at catalytic active sites. A major breakthrough is the selective MW heating of isolated metal ions or nanoparticles. This study presents a general catalyst design strategy to control MW-induced heating of single metal ions by tuning the zeolite framework and electrostatic interactions. Key structural and electronic factors governing atomic-scale energy localization are identified. Applying this approach to the reverse water-gas shift reaction results in energy efficiency improvements via targeted heating of single-ion sites. These findings mark a milestone in MW-assisted catalysis, establishing a framework for using MW energy in heterogeneous systems. The work introduces design principles for single-atom-antenna MW catalysts, advancing the development of next-generation catalytic reactors driven by electromagnetic energy.</description>
      <author>Ryo Ishibashi, Fuminao Kishimoto, Tatsushi Yoshioka, Hiroki Yamada, Koki Muraoka, Toshiaki Ina, Hiroki Taniguchi, Akira Nakayama, Toru Wakihara, Kazuhiro Takanabe</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ady4043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Total Galvanic Replacement Strategy for Synthesizing Hollow Multimetallic Nanocrystals Toward Enhanced Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519243</link>
      <description>Xiaoqian Lin, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, C. C. Tseng, Shang&#8208;Cheng Lin, Zuoli He, Yi Chen, C.Y. Lin, K. Y. Lee, Chueh&#8208;Cheng Yang, Chia&#8208;Hsin Wang, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Tung&#8208;Han Yang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415039331

                Abstract The synergistic effects in multimetallic nanocrystals make them attractive catalysts, but constructing hollow architectures with controlled features poses substantial challenges. Here, the galvanic replacement reaction between Ag nanocubes and three metal precursors (Pd 2+ , Pt 2+ , and Au 3+ ) is used to demonstrate that both atomic mixing and atomic arrangements of the resulting AgPdPtAu hollow nanocrystals can be tuned through four distinct precursor addition strategies. This study reveals that increasing the mixing entropy induces a transition from phase&#8208;separated domains to a homogeneous solid solution. Moreover, preferential bonding between deposited and template metals promotes the formation of nanocubes enclosed by {100} facets with square atomic arrangements. When dispersed on semiconductor supports, these facet&#8208;controlled AgPdPtAu hollow nanocrystals exhibit enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen production. Operando synchrotron X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and density functional theory calculations reveal that Pt&#8208;containing bridge sites act as primary hydrogen adsorption centers, exhibiting high local electron density and strong hydrogen binding. Additionally, bridge sites formed by mixed&#8208;affinity metal pairs (e.g., AuPt and AgPd), coupling strongly (Pt or Pd), and weakly (Au or Ag) hydrogen&#8208;adsorbing elements, exhibit near&#8208;optimal hydrogen adsorption and serve as key active sites for hydrogen evolution. This study establishes a versatile approach for engineering multimetallic hollow nanocrystals with tunable structures for catalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Xiaoqian Lin, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, C. C. Tseng, Shang&#8208;Cheng Lin, Zuoli He, Yi Chen, C.Y. Lin, K. Y. Lee, Chueh&#8208;Cheng Yang, Chia&#8208;Hsin Wang, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Tung&#8208;Han Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isopropanol Electro-Oxidation on PtCu Alloys for Aqueous Organic Redox Chemistry Toward Energy Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30194027</link>
      <description>Jinyao Tang, Xiaochen Shen, Laura Newsom, Rongxuan Xie, Parsa Pishva, Yanlin Zhu, Bin Liu, Zhenmeng Peng, Molecules. 30(19)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415040971

                Integration of renewable energy into modern power grids remains limited by intermittency and the need for reliable energy storage. Redox flow batteries (RFBs) are promising for large-scale energy storage, yet their widespread adoption is hindered by the high cost. In this study, we investigate isopropanol as a redox-active species with Pt-Cu alloy electrocatalysts for aqueous-organic RFBs. A series of PtxCu catalysts with varying Pt:Cu ratios were synthesized and studied for isopropanol electro-oxidation reaction (IPAOR) performance. Among them, PtCu demonstrated the best performance, achieving a low activation energy of 14.4 kJ/mol at 0.45 V vs. RHE and excellent stability at 1 M isopropanol (IPA) concentration. Kinetic analysis and in situ attenuated total reflectance-Fourier transform infrared (ATR-FTIR) spectroscopy revealed significantly reduced acetone accumulation on PtCu compared to pure Pt, indicating enhanced resistance to catalyst poisoning. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations further identified the first proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) as the rate-determining step (RDS) with C-H bond scission as the preferred pathway on PtCu. A proof-of-concept PtCu-catalyzed H-cell demonstrated stable cycling over 200 cycles, validating the feasibility of IPA as a low-cost, regenerable redox couple. These findings highlight PtCu-catalyzed IPA/acetone(ACE) chemistry as a promising platform for next-generation aqueous-organic RFBs.</description>
      <author>Jinyao Tang, Xiaochen Shen, Laura Newsom, Rongxuan Xie, Parsa Pishva, Yanlin Zhu, Bin Liu, Zhenmeng Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30194027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single&#8208;Atomic Ni&#8208;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Biofuel Cell for Mimicking Intramolecular Electron&#8208;Harnessing of Laccase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202511892</link>
      <description>Tapan Dey, Anubha Yadav, Nilanjan Seal, Babasaheb M. Matsagar, Norman C.&#8208;R. Chen, Praveen Kumar Yadav, Kevin C.&#8208;W. Wu, Amreen Bano, Saikat Dutta, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415041815

                Abstract Ni&#8211;N 4 &#8211;PAN&#8211;NC, consisting of an atomic Ni&#8211;N 4 site, mimics the intramolecular electron&#8208;harnessing of natural laccase (LAC) confined in a zeolitic imidazolate framework&#8208;8 (LAC@ZIF&#8208;8) for anodic electrooxidation of bisphenol&#8208;A (BPA). We have introduced a facile &#960;&#8208;conjugated unit of polyacrylonitrile (PAN)&#8208;resorcinol&#8208;derived N&#8208;doped conjugated &#8208;C&#8801;N. The atomically dispersed Ni&#8208;single&#8208;atom in Ni&#8211;N 4 &#8208; PAN&#8211;NC exhibits high activity for the paired electrolysis of ORR and the electrooxidation of BPA with an enhanced current density. The single Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC electrode effectively withdraws the electrons from electrooxidizing BPA due to a built&#8208;in electric field via incorporation of Ni&#8211;N 4 . The paired electrolysis of Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC biofuel cells is determined by LSV, EIS, and power&#8208;polarization curve for anodic electrooxidation of BPA. Machine learning molecular dynamics (ML&#8208;MD) simulation depicts non&#8208;covalent interaction (hydrogen bonding) between the O&#8208;hydroxyl of BPA and the N of the Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC, suggesting preferential adsorption on the Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC surface via weak van der Waals interactions and &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking between the aromatic rings of BPA and the conjugated PAN&#8208;NC. An increased power density with increased concentration of BPA in the absence of ABTS suggests a DET mechanism of BPA electrooxidation on Ni&#8211;N 4 , unlike a MET in the presence of ABTS when using LAC@ZIF&#8208;8. Thus, single atomic Ni &#8722; N 4 opens avenues with a DET mechanism.</description>
      <author>Tapan Dey, Anubha Yadav, Nilanjan Seal, Babasaheb M. Matsagar, Norman C.&#8208;R. Chen, Praveen Kumar Yadav, Kevin C.&#8208;W. Wu, Amreen Bano, Saikat Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202511892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable surface-plasma-exfoliated homogeneous ternary MoSe2/WSe2/Graphene nanosheets heterostructures as high-efficiency electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2025.100692</link>
      <description>Chang-Yu Hsiao, Phuoc&#8208;Anh Le, Ya-Wen Hsu, Jui&#8208;Cheng Kao, Chiang&#8208;Ju Chien, Jie Lin, Tzu&#8208;Ching Lu, Chun&#8208;Wei Pao, Yu-Chieh Lo, Kung&#8208;Hwa Wei, Materials Today Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415043207

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang-Yu Hsiao, Phuoc&#8208;Anh Le, Ya-Wen Hsu, Jui&#8208;Cheng Kao, Chiang&#8208;Ju Chien, Jie Lin, Tzu&#8208;Ching Lu, Chun&#8208;Wei Pao, Yu-Chieh Lo, Kung&#8208;Hwa Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2025.100692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radio Frequency-Induced Catalysis using Multi-Component Two-Dimensional Quasicrystals for Effective Sulfamethoxazole Removal from Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126062</link>
      <description>Zahoor Manzoor, R Karthik, M. Ferreira, Douglas S. Galv&#227;o, Nilay Krishna Mukhopadhyay, Thakur Prasad Yadav, Prikshat Dadhwal, Pranith Chander Saka, Cristiano F. Woellner, Shamik Chowdhury, Chandra Sekhar Tiwary, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415043622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahoor Manzoor, R Karthik, M. Ferreira, Douglas S. Galv&#227;o, Nilay Krishna Mukhopadhyay, Thakur Prasad Yadav, Prikshat Dadhwal, Pranith Chander Saka, Cristiano F. Woellner, Shamik Chowdhury, Chandra Sekhar Tiwary</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect on magnetic and electronic structure through hole substitution in pseudo-1-D spin chain compound NiTe2O5</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417854</link>
      <description>Avinash Chandra Maurya, D. Pal, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415043905

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Avinash Chandra Maurya, D. Pal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When wall slip wins over shear flow: A temperature-dependent Eyring slip law and a thermal multiscale model for diamond-like carbon lubricated by a polyalphaolefin oil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2025.111305</link>
      <description>Stefan Peeters, Edder J. Garc&#237;a, Franziska Stief, Thomas Reichenbach, Kerstin Falk, Gianpietro Moras, Michael Moseler, Tribology International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415045380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefan Peeters, Edder J. Garc&#237;a, Franziska Stief, Thomas Reichenbach, Kerstin Falk, Gianpietro Moras, Michael Moseler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2025.111305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroelectric phase transition in group-IV monochalcogenides from an equivariant machine learned force field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/t63g-4zp3</link>
      <description>Tina N. Mihm, Kasidet Jing Trerayapiwat, Pierre Darancet, Sahar Sharifzadeh, Physical Review Materials. 9(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415046901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tina N. Mihm, Kasidet Jing Trerayapiwat, Pierre Darancet, Sahar Sharifzadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/t63g-4zp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient local atomic cluster expansion for &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;BaTiO&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; close to equilibrium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/fnb6-vzyq</link>
      <description>Anna Gr&#252;nebohm, Matous Mrovec, Maxim N. Popov, L.&#8208;S. Hsu, Yury Lysogorskiy, Anton Bochkarev, Ralf Drautz, Physical Review Materials. 9(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415046938

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna Gr&#252;nebohm, Matous Mrovec, Maxim N. Popov, L.&#8208;S. Hsu, Yury Lysogorskiy, Anton Bochkarev, Ralf Drautz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/fnb6-vzyq</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron transfer and hydrogen spillover Co-driven to enhance hydrogen evolution reaction over oxygen-deficient tungsten oxide-supported iridium clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164792</link>
      <description>Zihao Fan, Chong Gao, Guangping Lei, Huiyuan Cheng, Bo Pang, Fujun Cui, Xuemei Wu, Wanting Chen, Xiangcun Li, Gaohong He, Applied Surface Science. 717(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415054003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihao Fan, Chong Gao, Guangping Lei, Huiyuan Cheng, Bo Pang, Fujun Cui, Xuemei Wu, Wanting Chen, Xiangcun Li, Gaohong He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Ni via heterostructure-induced electron deficiency and spatial intermediate coupling for enhanced alkaline HER/HOR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126069</link>
      <description>W. Liang, Zixuan Dan, Xiyu Gong, Jinchang Xu, Hongjuan Wang, Yonghai Cao, Hao Yu, Yanshuo Jin, Haofan Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415059325

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W. Liang, Zixuan Dan, Xiyu Gong, Jinchang Xu, Hongjuan Wang, Yonghai Cao, Hao Yu, Yanshuo Jin, Haofan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Center Inheritance: A Design Principle for Constructing Atomically Dispersed Bimetallic OER/ORR Catalysts Derived from Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04004</link>
      <description>Wenwen Li, Yiming Mo, Lingzhi Kang, Caixia Li, Jingnan Zheng, Chenglong Qiu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415068230

                Atomically dispersed bimetallic catalysts (ADCs), an emerging class of electrocatalysts, combine the synergistic advantages of dual-metal active sites with the atomic dispersion and high metal utilization efficiency characteristic of single-atom catalysts (SACs). Their unique structural features offer the potential to exceed the catalytic performance of conventional systems but simultaneously pose challenges due to the absence of well-established rational design principles. This paper proposes and validates a structural design strategy, "Active Center Inheritance," wherein high-performance SACs are transformed into ADCs by retaining the same active center (M&#8211;Nx). This approach not only preserves high catalytic activity but also significantly reduces the computational cost associated with density functional theory (DFT) calculations over 13,500 candidate systems, thereby accelerating the discovery of bifunctional electrocatalysts. A total of 17 high-performance oxygen evolution reaction (OER)/oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) bifunctional catalysts were identified through this strategy. This strategy was successfully generalized to three other ADC structural systems with different spatial arrangements. Moreover, a unified descriptor (&#966;), composed of four key electronic and atomic features, was constructed to effectively correlate the adsorption behaviors of critical reaction intermediates (*OH, *O, and *OOH) across diverse systems. The results reveal that SACs and ADCs can achieve comparable catalytic activity when constructed with the same M&#8211;Nx active center, thereby enabling the synergistic optimization of active sites. This work provides a theoretical basis and a rational design framework for the development of efficient multisite electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Wenwen Li, Yiming Mo, Lingzhi Kang, Caixia Li, Jingnan Zheng, Chenglong Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Electronic Descriptors for BaMO&#8323; (M=Sc to Zn) Perovskite ORR/OER Electrocatalysis: Decoding Bond Strength, Orbital Hybridization, and Electron Transfer Synergy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5589106</link>
      <description>Taoda Liu, Sheng Ma, Xiaohong Zhang, Jiaqi Wang, Zhong&#8208;Qun Tian, Yajie Dou, Zhiwei Peng, Tian Ouyang, Binbin Lin, Xiao-Ling He, Wenyan Tao, Yinghua Niu, Yinghua Niu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415069318

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Taoda Liu, Sheng Ma, Xiaohong Zhang, Jiaqi Wang, Zhong&#8208;Qun Tian, Yajie Dou, Zhiwei Peng, Tian Ouyang, Binbin Lin, Xiao-Ling He, Wenyan Tao, Yinghua Niu, Yinghua Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5589106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Text Mining and Quantum Simulations for the Design of 2D Monochalcogenide Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04625</link>
      <description>Mateus B. P. Querne, M. Machado, Ronaldo C. Prati, Natan M. Regis, Matheus P. Lima, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415077896

                The formulation of a structured framework dedicated to the systematic review of the literature, identification of potential compounds, theoretical quantum chemistry characterization, and assessment of the significance of stability descriptors is essential for accelerating the discovery of two-dimensional materials for technological applications. In this work, we selected the two-dimensional monochalcogenides (MQ), which have attracted increased interest due to their potential applications in future devices, as prototype materials for the present investigation. Our framework started with a natural language processing analysis of more than 5400 articles, revealing a growing research interest in the two-dimensional MQ compounds, especially in electronics, energy, and fundamental studies. This led to the selection of 27 diverse MQ compounds across 13 distinct two-dimensional structural phases for density functional theory calculations, resulting in an extensive database of physicochemical properties. We evaluated formation enthalpies, uncovering clear stability trends (e.g., stability declines with heavier chalcogens, dynamic robustness of GeSe), and evaluated equilibrium lattice parameters, noting predictable expansions and significant anisotropies. Bader charge analysis offered insights into charge-transfer and ionicity trends. Our electronic structure analysis identified band gaps (direct or indirect, depending on the M element group and the weight of the chalcogen) and optical absorption anisotropies significantly influenced by crystal symmetry and spin orbit coupling. Importantly, band alignment calculations classified all possible heterojunctions as type I, II, or III, underscoring their extensive potential for future optoelectronic device development. Additionally, we incorporated machine learning, using a random forest approach, along with our density functional theory calculations to accurately forecast trends in energetic properties. This analysis identified the electronic charge as a highly significant stability descriptor among the 34 descriptors, underscoring its importance for future machine learning endeavors. Hence, this study offers a streamlined framework for the characterization and discovery of promising two-dimensional materials, highlighting the synergy between data-driven analysis and quantum-based simulations.</description>
      <author>Mateus B. P. Querne, M. Machado, Ronaldo C. Prati, Natan M. Regis, Matheus P. Lima, Juarez L. F. Da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04625</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Oxidation in Medium-Entropy Spinel Oxides via Lattice Oxygen Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02570</link>
      <description>Mao Sun, Yu Tang, Jike Wang, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415094215

                The development of efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts requires advancements in both the mechanism understanding and material design. The lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) typically has a lower thermodynamic barrier than the absorbate evolution mechanism (AEM), yet controlling the OER pathway from the AEM to the LOM remains challenging. Here, we demonstrate efficient lattice oxygen activation in a spinel-structured CoFeMoRu medium-entropy oxide (CoFeMoRuMEO) catalyst through strategic octahedral engineering. The introduction of Mo increases the electron density at the Co sites, thereby weakening OH adsorption and suppressing CoOOH formation via the AEM pathway. Meanwhile, compressed RuO6 octahedra create shortened Ru&#8211;O bonds, enhancing Ru&#8211;O covalency and facilitating the critical O&#8211;O coupling step. As a result, the CoFeMoRuMEO catalyst achieves a remarkable overpotential of 168 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, setting a new benchmark for medium-to-high-entropy OER catalysts. Our work provides valuable insights into the transformation of the OER mechanism and performance optimization.</description>
      <author>Mao Sun, Yu Tang, Jike Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of Fe loss to promote reconstructed surface via black phosphorus over NiFeB nanosheets for efficient water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169571</link>
      <description>Zehao Wang, Huayu Chen, Yesheng Fu, Yin Hang, Dandan Yu, Junhui Liang, Yuexiang Huang, Liuqi Wang, Wei Gao, Da Chen, Yang Hou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415094324

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zehao Wang, Huayu Chen, Yesheng Fu, Yin Hang, Dandan Yu, Junhui Liang, Yuexiang Huang, Liuqi Wang, Wei Gao, Da Chen, Yang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are we there yet? Adventures on a road trip through machine learning as a computational chemist</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0297853</link>
      <description>Heather J. Kulik, No host. 1(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414936445

                Over the past two decades, the integration of machine learning (ML) into theoretical and computational chemistry has transformed the scale and scope of discovery that is possible on a computer. In this Perspective, I share my personal journey from early density functional theory method development for small transition metal complexes to the building of automated workflows and ML models for catalysis, redox chemistry, and materials design. I will describe my unlikely path toward machine learning starting from minimal models of catalysts and the use of structural databases to gain data-driven insights. I will then describe our experiences in training machine learning models for discovery, including active learning and descriptor-based approaches that enabled data-driven exploration despite limited experimental reference data for open-shell transition metal complexes. As an example of overcoming these limitations, I will describe our more recent efforts that culminated in experimental validation of our computational predictions. Along the way, challenges in data curation, DFT method sensitivity, and synthetic realism have shaped the trajectory of the field. I conclude with reflections on the rapid rise of generative AI, agentic workflows, and the enduring need to ask questions that truly advance molecular discovery.</description>
      <author>Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0297853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust catalyst assessment for the electrocatalytic nitrate reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-025-01691-z</link>
      <description>Devesh K. Pathak, Rajkumar Jana, Ruth Bello, Kelsey White, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger, Communications Chemistry. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415021585

                The electrocatalytic nitrate reduction reaction (NO3RR) can enable distributed conversion of waste to ammonia. Unlike the electrocatalytic dinitrogen reduction reaction, measurements of NO3RR often consider a fixed quantity of the nitrate anion in a batch system, presenting unique concerns for measurements of catalytic activity and selectivity. In addition, the sensitivity of kinetics and transport to electrolyte composition&#8212;where a diverse range of waste feedstocks are of interest&#8212;can have a notable impact on catalyst performance, hindering catalyst comparison. We highlight reaction complexities and advocate best practices for robust measurement of catalyst activity, selectivity, and Faradaic efficiency in this burgeoning field. Electrocatalytic nitrate reduction is widely studied, but under a range of conditions, with implications on catalyst performance. Here, the authors highlight potential pitfalls in comparing across (and within) existing literature and suggest approaches to assess electrocatalysts under common conditions.</description>
      <author>Devesh K. Pathak, Rajkumar Jana, Ruth Bello, Kelsey White, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-025-01691-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect compensation as a strategic approach to enhance photocatalytic water splitting performance of SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.70296</link>
      <description>Mingyi Zhang, A. Salvador, Gregory S. Rohrer, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415019979

                Abstract Determining suitable dopants with optimized doping concentration is critical to design efficient water splitting photocatalysts. However, there is currently a lack of fundamental knowledge to guide this process. Herein, we examine the impact of Al 3+ , Mg 2+ , and Ga 3+ on the photocatalytic performance of SrTiO 3 and propose a defect compensation model to understand the doping effect. Doped SrTiO 3 crystals were grown hydrothermally and treated in molten SrCl 2 . The hydrogen production rates from 50 catalysts produced in this way were measured with a high&#8208;throughput parallelized and automated photochemical reactor (PAPCR). The investigation revealed that all three dopants significantly enhance the photocatalytic reactivity. According to Brouwer diagrams computed using available reaction constants, the optimum reactivity is achieved when the concentration of acceptor dopants fully compensates the oxygen vacancy donors. The improved reactivity can be attributed to the reduction in free electron concentration, resulting in a space charge layer that is 1000 times longer. Consequently, this situation enhances the number of photogenerated charge carriers capable of being separated by the band bending and transported to the surface.</description>
      <author>Mingyi Zhang, A. Salvador, Gregory S. Rohrer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.70296</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
