<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 01:42:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic graphene vacancies: atomic-scale O2 scissors mediated by antiferromagnetic exchange interaction&#8211;spin-orbit selective coupling effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137998</link>
      <description>Gu Gaoyuan, Ge Ruijie, Yan Zhou, Jianing Zhang, Wenhui Li, Chong Peng, Bi Changlong, Shuyi Yang, E. Tao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 698(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410796023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gu Gaoyuan, Ge Ruijie, Yan Zhou, Jianing Zhang, Wenhui Li, Chong Peng, Bi Changlong, Shuyi Yang, E. Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137998</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering High-Entropy Oxides with a Machine-Learning Interatomic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.216101</link>
      <description>Jacob T. Sivak, Saeed S. I. Almishal, Mary Kathleen Caucci, Yueze Tan, Dhiya Srikanth, Joseph Petruska, Matthew Furst, Long&#8208;Qing Chen, Christina M. Rost, Jon&#8208;Paul Maria, Susan B. Sinnott, Physical Review Letters. 134(21)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410807714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jacob T. Sivak, Saeed S. I. Almishal, Mary Kathleen Caucci, Yueze Tan, Dhiya Srikanth, Joseph Petruska, Matthew Furst, Long&#8208;Qing Chen, Christina M. Rost, Jon&#8208;Paul Maria, Susan B. Sinnott</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.216101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable training of neural network potentials for complex interfaces through data augmentation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01651-0</link>
      <description>In Won Yeu, Annika Stuke, Jon L&#243;pez-Zorrilla, James Stevenson, David R. Reichman, Richard A. Friesner, Alexander Urban, Nongnuch Artrith, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410811203

                No abstract</description>
      <author>In Won Yeu, Annika Stuke, Jon L&#243;pez-Zorrilla, James Stevenson, David R. Reichman, Richard A. Friesner, Alexander Urban, Nongnuch Artrith</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01651-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium oxynitride-supported Ru nanoparticles as exceptional electrocatalysts for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.164204</link>
      <description>Milutin Smiljani&#263;, Marjan Bele, Luka Pavko, Armin Hrnji&#263;, Francisco Ruiz&#8208;Zepeda, Lazar Bijeli&#263;, Ana Rebeka Kam&#353;ek, Mejrema Nuhanovi&#263;, Ale&#353; Marsel, Lea Ga&#353;pari&#269;, Anton Kokalj, Nejc Hodnik, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410813354

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Milutin Smiljani&#263;, Marjan Bele, Luka Pavko, Armin Hrnji&#263;, Francisco Ruiz&#8208;Zepeda, Lazar Bijeli&#263;, Ana Rebeka Kam&#353;ek, Mejrema Nuhanovi&#263;, Ale&#353; Marsel, Lea Ga&#353;pari&#269;, Anton Kokalj, Nejc Hodnik</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.164204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating the dynamics of NV&#8722; formation in diamond in the presence of carbon self-interstitials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01605-6</link>
      <description>Guangzhao Chen, Joseph C. A. Prentice, Jason M. Smith, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410814582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guangzhao Chen, Joseph C. A. Prentice, Jason M. Smith</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01605-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructured Ni-Co Electrocatalyst with Enhanced Interfacial Charge Transfer for Efficient Biomass Upgrading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125539</link>
      <description>Dexin Chen, Yunxuan Ding, Xing Cao, Licheng Sun, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410814816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dexin Chen, Yunxuan Ding, Xing Cao, Licheng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density functional study on the oxygen evolution reaction mechanism of transition metal doped bimetallic NiCu phosphate surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115304</link>
      <description>Hamdi Ikhwan, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Sasfan Arman Wella, Fadjar Fathurrahman, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. 1250(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410816874

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hamdi Ikhwan, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Sasfan Arman Wella, Fadjar Fathurrahman, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrical switching of a p-wave magnet </title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-025-09034-7</link>
      <description>Song Qian, Srdjan Stavri&#263;, Paolo Barone, Andrea Droghetti, Daniil S. Antonenko, J&#246;rn W. F. Venderbos, Connor A. Occhialini, Batyr Ilyas, Emre Erge&#231;en, Nuh Gedik, Sang&#8208;Wook Cheong, Rafael M. Fernandes, Silvia Picozzi, Riccardo Comin, Nature. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410817098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Song Qian, Srdjan Stavri&#263;, Paolo Barone, Andrea Droghetti, Daniil S. Antonenko, J&#246;rn W. F. Venderbos, Connor A. Occhialini, Batyr Ilyas, Emre Erge&#231;en, Nuh Gedik, Sang&#8208;Wook Cheong, Rafael M. Fernandes, Silvia Picozzi, Riccardo Comin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-025-09034-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Iron-Based and Aluminum-Based Bimetals: A Systematic Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met15060603</link>
      <description>Jeffrey Ken B. Balangao, Carlito Baltazar Tabelin, Theerayut Phengsaart, Joshua B. Zoleta, Takahiko Arima, Ilhwan Park, Walubita Mufalo, Mayumi Ito, Richard Diaz Alorro, Aileen H. Orbecido, Arnel B. Beltran, Michael Angelo B. Promentilla, Sanghee Jeon, Kazutoshi Haga, Vannie Joy T. Resabal, Metals. 15(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410818058

                Bimetals&#8212;materials composed of two metal components with dissimilar standard reduction&#8211;oxidation (redox) potentials&#8212;offer unique electronic, optical, and catalytic properties, surpassing monometallic systems. These materials exhibit not only the combined attributes of their constituent metals but also new and novel properties arising from their synergy. Although many reviews have explored the synthesis, properties, and applications of bimetallic systems, none have focused exclusively on iron (Fe)- and aluminum (Al)-based bimetals. This systematic review addresses this gap by providing a comprehensive overview of conventional and emerging techniques for Fe-based and Al-based bimetal synthesis. Specifically, this work systematically reviewed recent studies from 2014 to 2023 using the Scopus, Web of Science (WoS), and Google Scholar databases, following the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines, and was registered under INPLASY with the registration number INPLASY202540026. Articles were excluded if they were inaccessible, non-English, review articles, conference papers, book chapters, or not directly related to the synthesis of Fe- or Al-based bimetals. Additionally, a bibliometric analysis was performed to evaluate the research trends on the synthesis of Fe-based and Al-based bimetals. Based on the 122 articles analyzed, Fe-based and Al-based bimetal synthesis methods were classified into three types: (i) physical, (ii) chemical, and (iii) biological techniques. Physical methods include mechanical alloying, radiolysis, sonochemical methods, the electrical explosion of metal wires, and magnetic field-assisted laser ablation in liquid (MF-LAL). In comparison, chemical protocols covered reduction, dealloying, supported particle methods, thermogravimetric methods, seed-mediated growth, galvanic replacement, and electrochemical synthesis. Meanwhile, biological techniques utilized plant extracts, chitosan, alginate, and cellulose-based materials as reducing agents and stabilizers during bimetal synthesis. Research works on the synthesis of Fe-based and Al-based bimetals initially declined but increased in 2018, followed by a stable trend, with 50% of the total studies conducted in the last five years. China led in the number of publications (62.3%), followed by Russia, Australia, and India, while Saudi Arabia had the highest number of citations per document (95). RSC Advances was the most active journal, publishing eight papers from 2014 to 2023, while Applied Catalysis B: Environmental had the highest number of citations per document at 203. Among the three synthesis methods, chemical techniques dominated, particularly supported particles, galvanic replacement, and chemical reduction, while biological and physical methods have started gaining interest. Iron&#8211;copper (Fe/Cu), iron&#8211;aluminum (Fe/Al), and iron&#8211;nickel (Fe/Ni) were the most commonly synthesized bimetals in the last 10 years. Finally, this work was funded by DOST-PCIEERD and DOST-ERDT.</description>
      <author>Jeffrey Ken B. Balangao, Carlito Baltazar Tabelin, Theerayut Phengsaart, Joshua B. Zoleta, Takahiko Arima, Ilhwan Park, Walubita Mufalo, Mayumi Ito, Richard Diaz Alorro, Aileen H. Orbecido, Arnel B. Beltran, Michael Angelo B. Promentilla, Sanghee Jeon, Kazutoshi Haga, Vannie Joy T. Resabal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met15060603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible H&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;&#8208;Lock/Unlock via Enol/Ketone Redox: Parasitic Reactions&#8208;Free Zn Anode and High&#8208;Performance Aqueous Zn&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202507684</link>
      <description>Yu Bai, Haiping Zhou, Jialin Yang, Qingqing Pan, Jiawei Wang, Yunpeng Wu, Xing&#8208;Long Wu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410822352

                Abstract Aqueous zinc&#8208;ion batteries (AZIBs) have great potential for large&#8208;scale energy storage applications. However, the parasitic reactions, such as continuous hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), seriously hamper the reversibility and cycling stability of the zinc metal anode (ZMA), limiting its practical application. In this paper, a pre&#8208;growth interfacial layer strategy is adopted to grow the enol/ketone conversion interfacial layer on the surface of ZMA (denoted as Zn@AA). H + can be reversible &#8220;lock/unlock&#8221; during reversible enol/ketone conversion reaction. It not only broadens the capacity of AZIBs (Zn 2+ /H + co&#8208;insertion), but also inhibits the HER reaction (the amounts of H 2 evolution decreased obviously in both Zn@AA||Zn@AA and Zn@AA||VO 2 &#183;H 2 O@Ppy (Ppy denote as polypyrrole) cells by on&#8208;line differential electrochemical mass spectrometry analysis), thereby improving its stability performance. The cycle life of the assembled Zn@AA||Zn@AA cell exceeded 3200 h at 1 mA cm &#8722;2 and 1 mA h cm &#8722;2 . Furtherly, the Zn@AA||VO 2 &#183;H 2 O@Ppy full cell also exhibited excellent cycling stability and capacity retention. This work provides new ideas for modifying the ZMA interfacial layer to inhibit the HER, which guides the development of AZIBs.</description>
      <author>Yu Bai, Haiping Zhou, Jialin Yang, Qingqing Pan, Jiawei Wang, Yunpeng Wu, Xing&#8208;Long Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202507684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 capture: a concise, comprehensive overview of recent research trends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20935/acadenvsci7739</link>
      <description>A K A Rathi, Jagdishchandra A. Rathi, No host. 2(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410824258

                Due to the growing threat of climate change, the pressing need for carbon dioxide capture has become a global priority in the development of innovative technologies. Multipronged approaches and multifarious research efforts are underway to efficiently capture carbon dioxide (CO2) from emission sources, ambient air, and indoor air. Currently, absorption is the dominant industrial-scale process, using different solvents and their blends to lower the energy intensity of solvent desorption and regeneration. However, adsorption is emerging as a promising alternative due to its energy efficiency, eco-friendliness, and potential for large-scale applications. High-performance sorbents with large surface areas and bio-based materials exhibit high CO2 loading and selectivity in fixed-bed and fluidized-bed systems. Cryogenic CO2 capture systems, which do not require solvents or membranes, are optimized for energy through process integration. Researchers are investigating different membrane materials in hollow fiber membrane contactors for enhanced CO2 capture efficiency. Membranes that can selectively filter CO2 from gas mixtures are also being explored. Furthermore, hybrid technologies integrating different CO2 capture approaches are being developed to reduce costs and boost overall performance to curb rising atmospheric CO2 levels.</description>
      <author>A K A Rathi, Jagdishchandra A. Rathi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20935/acadenvsci7739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrochemical capacitive performance of zinc and cobalt metal-organic frameworks derived electrodes in redox additive electrolyte and their application in electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237426</link>
      <description>Gowdhaman Arumugam, Stanleydhinakar Mathan, Vijayan Murugesan, Manickam Selvaraj, Omeer Albormani, R. Ramesh, Journal of Power Sources. 649(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410825282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gowdhaman Arumugam, Stanleydhinakar Mathan, Vijayan Murugesan, Manickam Selvaraj, Omeer Albormani, R. Ramesh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-density natural active sites for efficient nitrogen reduction on Kagome surfaces promoted by flat bands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01663-w</link>
      <description>Yuyuan Huang, Yanru Chen, Shunhong Zhang, Zhenyu Zhang, Ping Cui, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410825831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuyuan Huang, Yanru Chen, Shunhong Zhang, Zhenyu Zhang, Ping Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01663-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into the Intercorrelation between the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00591</link>
      <description>Tuo Zhang, Kaige Shi, Baodui Wang, Xiang-Yang Hou, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410826301

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tuo Zhang, Kaige Shi, Baodui Wang, Xiang-Yang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Single-Atom Catalysts Anchored on Defect-Engineered N-Doped Graphene Reveal an Interplay between CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c01417</link>
      <description>Dagmar Zaoralov&#225;, Robert Langer, Michal Otyepka, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410832396

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dagmar Zaoralov&#225;, Robert Langer, Michal Otyepka</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c01417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eccentric Corrosion-Induced Formation of &#947;-NiFeOOH and &#947;-NiCoOOH on NiFeCo Alloy for Enhanced OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c03007</link>
      <description>Sunil Mittal, Balakumaran Kamaraj, Sandeep Kumar Yadav, Pracheta Trivedi, Neha Clare Minj, Sengeni Anantharaj, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410833367

                An indirect, swift, and easy method of enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of an economically viable Fe-rich NiFeCo (NFC) alloy has been developed. This approach leverages the anodic potential sweeps applied indirectly to the counter electrode (CE) when one does cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) on by potential sweeping at the working electrode (WE). In this method, NFC was intentionally corroded indirectly by using it as a CE for the potential sweeping HER experiment done with a Pt WE. The indirectly corroded NFC (NFC_IC) featuring mostly &#947;-NiFeOOH and &#947;-NiCoOOH entities on the surface was able to begin the OER at an onset overpotential of 250 mV and reach the benchmark of 10 mA cm-2 at 290 mV, which is 60 and 55 mV lesser than that of the bare NFC and RuO2, respectively, all with exceptionally faster kinetics, as evidenced by a relatively smaller Tafel slope of 30 mV dec-1. These insights into designing a trimetallic alloy-based OER electrocatalyst have opened a previously unknown avenue in the development of advanced self-supported OER electrodes for better and efficient H2 production via water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Sunil Mittal, Balakumaran Kamaraj, Sandeep Kumar Yadav, Pracheta Trivedi, Neha Clare Minj, Sengeni Anantharaj</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c03007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of selective catalysts for ethylene hydroformylation via microkinetic modeling and universal neural network potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116253</link>
      <description>Kento Sakai, Ippei Furikado, Andrew J. Medford, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410842657

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kento Sakai, Ippei Furikado, Andrew J. Medford</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal-anchored biphenylene network for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction with highly selective CH4 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.247</link>
      <description>Xu Yang, Chong Wang, Song Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 140(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410842978

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu Yang, Chong Wang, Song Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom enhanced the catalytic activity of borophene catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.339</link>
      <description>Feihong Yang, Yong Pan, I.P. Jain, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 140(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410843038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feihong Yang, Yong Pan, I.P. Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economical Iron-nickel Bimetallic Electrocatalysis Enhanced Chlorine Evolution for Ammonia Removal in Wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146580</link>
      <description>Zhiyong Zhang, Aixing Chen, Ming&#8208;Lai Fu, Wenjie Sun, Huachun Lan, Baoling Yuan, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410851883

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyong Zhang, Aixing Chen, Ming&#8208;Lai Fu, Wenjie Sun, Huachun Lan, Baoling Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of noble metal nanoarrays via agglomeration and metallurgy for acidic water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60419-8</link>
      <description>Jiawei Tao, Ruiqin Gao, Geyu Lin, Chaoyang Chu, Yan Sun, Chunyang Yu, Yanhang Ma, Huibin Qiu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410855379

                Noble metal electrocatalysts remain the mainstay for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis, majorly due to their exceptional activity and durability in acidic media. However, conventional powder and particle catalysts intensively suffer from aggregation, shedding and poor electron conductivity in practical applications. Here, we develop a micellar brush-guided method to agglomerate and smelt metal nanoparticles into erect nanoarrays with designable constitutions on various substrates. While the nanoarrays of stacked nanoparticles show poor stability in the acidic media, the smelting treatment substantially enhances the electron conductivity by more than four order of magnitude and reinforces the nanoarray architectures. This allows the tailored fabrication of self-supported acid-durable metallic and alloy nanoarray catalysts with outstanding hydrogen evolution activity, and metal oxide nanoarray with extraordinary oxygen evolution activity. The integration of metallic Ru-nanoarray and RuOx-nanoarray in a proton exchange membrane electrolyzer further enables a long-term stable water electrolysis process for more than 500 h at 1 A cm-2.</description>
      <author>Jiawei Tao, Ruiqin Gao, Geyu Lin, Chaoyang Chu, Yan Sun, Chunyang Yu, Yanhang Ma, Huibin Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60419-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Electronic Properties of Nanoporous Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01115</link>
      <description>Bernhard Kretz, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410858752

                Different nanoporous graphene structures have shown great promise for a wide variety of applications. However, due to limitations in experimental or computational throughput, nanoporous graphenes have not been investigated systematically. In this work, we combine density functional theory and machine learning to study 460 structures of nanoporous graphene made from four different templates. We shed light on structure-band gap relations and perform molecular dynamics simulations and phonon calculations in order to determine the role of electron-phonon coupling on the renormalization of temperature-dependent band gaps. Our results uncover that certain subsets of nanoporous graphene exhibit a similar trend in the band gap as a function of a structural parameter as has been observed for armchair graphene nanoribbons. Furthermore, we find that electron-phonon coupling varies over a large range in the investigated nanoporous graphenes and that it drives the closing of the band gap with larger temperatures. Finally, we suggest nanoporous graphene structures for different applications, such as field-effect transistors. Thus, our work can help guide the development and improvement of nanoporous graphene-based devices.</description>
      <author>Bernhard Kretz, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchically porous carbon supports enable efficient syngas production in electrified reactive capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ee00094g</link>
      <description>Hengzhou Liu, Heejong Shin, Xiaoyan Li, Guangcan Su, Pengfei Ou, Yong Wang, Lihaokun Chen, Jiaqi Yu, Yuanjun Chen, Rong Xia, Geonhui Lee, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Christine Yu, Peiying Wang, Deokjae Choi, Daojin Zhou, Cong Tian, Issam Gereige, Ammar Alahmed, Aqil Jamal, Omar K. Farha, Shannon W. Boettcher, Jennifer B. Dunn, Ke Xie, Edward H. Sargent, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410859494

                Hierarchical carbon supports, internally coated with PDA and catalyst, enhance reactant mass transport, achieve molecular dispersion of the catalyst, and tune the electronic environment of the Co center.</description>
      <author>Hengzhou Liu, Heejong Shin, Xiaoyan Li, Guangcan Su, Pengfei Ou, Yong Wang, Lihaokun Chen, Jiaqi Yu, Yuanjun Chen, Rong Xia, Geonhui Lee, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Christine Yu, Peiying Wang, Deokjae Choi, Daojin Zhou, Cong Tian, Issam Gereige, Ammar Alahmed, Aqil Jamal, Omar K. Farha, Shannon W. Boettcher, Jennifer B. Dunn, Ke Xie, Edward H. Sargent</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ee00094g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Level Coupled-Cluster Description of Crystal Lattice Energies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00428</link>
      <description>Krystyna Syty, Grzegorz Czeka&#322;o, Pham Ngoc Khanh, Marcin Modrzejewski, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410860583

                The many-body expansion (MBE) of the lattice energy enables an ab initio description of molecular solids using correlated wave function approximations. However, the practical application of MBE requires computing the large number of n-body contributions efficiently. To this end, we employ a multi-level coupled-cluster approach which adapts the approximation level based on interaction type and intermolecular distance. The high-level method, including connected triple excitations, is applied only to monomer relaxation and dimer interactions roughly within the first and second coordination shells. Long-range dimers and trimers are treated using a simplified coupled-cluster description based on the random-phase approximation (RPA). A key feature is an energy correction which mitigates the underbinding error of the base RPA. Convergence to the bulk limit is accelerated by the addition of the periodic Hartree-Fock correction. The proposed approach is validated against recent diffusion Monte Carlo reference data for the X23 data set, achieving a mean absolute error of 3.1 kJ/mol, i.e., chemical accuracy for absolute lattice energies.</description>
      <author>Krystyna Syty, Grzegorz Czeka&#322;o, Pham Ngoc Khanh, Marcin Modrzejewski</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-scheme GeC/SnS2 heterojunction as an overall water splitting photocatalyst with ultra-high solar-to-hydrogen efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.299</link>
      <description>Chunju Hou, Qiang Ke, Xueling Lei, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 139(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410860694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunju Hou, Qiang Ke, Xueling Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced activity and chlorine protection in prolonged seawater electrolysis using MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/sulfonated reduced graphene oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5se00541h</link>
      <description>Prerna Tripathi, Renna Shakir, Amit Verma, J. Karthikeyan, Biswajit Ray, Amit Sinha, Shikha Singh, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410864297

                Sulfonated graphene's ability to repel chlorine has been demonstrated experimentally and through DFT investigations. Notably, the article presents the novel importance of sulfonic moieties as repelling agents for sea water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Prerna Tripathi, Renna Shakir, Amit Verma, J. Karthikeyan, Biswajit Ray, Amit Sinha, Shikha Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5se00541h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combined Experimental and DFT Study of Alumina (&#945;-Al2O3(0001))-Supported Fe Atoms in the Limit of a Single Atom</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15110804</link>
      <description>Ramazan T. Magkoev, Yong Men, Reza Behjatmanesh&#8211;Ardakani, Mohammadreza Elahifard, I. V. Silaev, &#1040;. &#1055;. &#1041;&#1083;&#1080;&#1077;&#1074;, N. Pukhaeva, Anatolij M. Turiev, &#1042;.&#1041;. &#1047;&#1072;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1096;&#1074;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080;, Aleksandr A. Takaev, &#1058;. &#1058;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1075;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077;&#1074;, Ramazan A. Khekilaev, &#1054;. &#1043;. &#1040;&#1096;&#1093;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Nanomaterials. 15(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410866195

                To probe the properties of single atoms is a challenging task, especially from the experimental standpoint, due to sensitivity limits. Nevertheless, it is sometimes possible to achieve this by making corresponding choices and adjustments to the experimental technique and sample under investigation. In the present case, the absolute value of the electronic charge the Fe atoms acquire when they are adsorbed on the surface of aluminum oxide &#945;-Al2O3(0001) was measured by a set of surface-sensitive techniques: low-energy ion scattering (LEIS), Auger electron spectroscopy (AES), low-energy electron diffraction (LEED), and work function (WF) measurements, in combination with density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The main focus was the submonolayer coverage of Fe atoms in situ deposited on the well-ordered stoichiometric &#945;-Al2O3(0001) 7 nm thick film formed on a Mo(110) crystal face. An analysis of the evolution of the Fe LVV Auger triplet upon variation of the Fe coverage shows that there is electronic charge transfer from Fe to alumina and that its value gradually decreases as the Fe coverage grows. The same trend is also predicted by the DFT results. Extrapolation of the experimental Fe charge value versus coverage plot yields an estimated value of a single Fe atom adsorbed on &#945;-Al2O3(0001) of 0.98e (electron charge units), which is in reasonable agreement with the calculated value (+1.15e). The knowledge of this value and the possibility of its adjustment may be important points for the development and tuning of modern sub-nanometer-scale technologies of diverse applied relevance and can contribute to a more complete justification and selection of the corresponding theoretical models.</description>
      <author>Ramazan T. Magkoev, Yong Men, Reza Behjatmanesh&#8211;Ardakani, Mohammadreza Elahifard, I. V. Silaev, &#1040;. &#1055;. &#1041;&#1083;&#1080;&#1077;&#1074;, N. Pukhaeva, Anatolij M. Turiev, &#1042;.&#1041;. &#1047;&#1072;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1096;&#1074;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080;, Aleksandr A. Takaev, &#1058;. &#1058;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1075;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077;&#1074;, Ramazan A. Khekilaev, &#1054;. &#1043;. &#1040;&#1096;&#1093;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15110804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating the Analysis of Substrate Reactivity through Environment Interaction Mapping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c00474</link>
      <description>Thiago H. da Silva, Jiang Lu, Zayah Cortright, Denis Mulumba, Md Sharif Khan, Oliviero Andreussi, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410868472

                Exploring the interaction configurations between substrates and atomic or molecular systems is crucial for various scientific and technological applications, such as characterizing catalytic reactions, solvation structures, and molecular interactions. Traditional approaches for generating substrate-reactant configurations often rely on chemical intuition, symmetry operations, or random initial states, which can be inefficient and challenging for systems with low symmetry or unknown interaction mechanisms. This work introduces a systematic and automated methodology to explore the configuration space between substrates and adsorbates using symmetry-invariant features that characterize the local atomistic topology of the substrate. The approach involves three key components: (1) defining and discretizing a contact space surrounding the substrate, (2) utilizing symmetry-invariant descriptors to capture local atomic environments, and (3) employing unsupervised machine-learning techniques for clustering and hierarchical analysis of interaction sites. The method ensures comprehensive yet nonredundant sampling of the configuration space, independent of the substrate dimensionality. Applications to simple ideal substrates show that symmetry intuition and high-symmetry sites are correctly recovered. Moreover, the method is shown to translate seamlessly to less symmetric substrates.</description>
      <author>Thiago H. da Silva, Jiang Lu, Zayah Cortright, Denis Mulumba, Md Sharif Khan, Oliviero Andreussi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c00474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlation of Structure and Electrocatalytic Performance of Bulk Oxides for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30112391</link>
      <description>Chuanhui Zhu, Changming Zhao, Hao Tian, S. Y. Tong, Molecules. 30(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410874996

                Hydrogen-centered electrochemical technologies play a vital role in sustainable energy conversion and storage. One of the challenges in achieving cheap hydrogen is to bridge the gap between advanced electrocatalysts and highly effective electrodes. The key lies in designing electrocatalysts with high intrinsic activity and understanding the structure&#8211;activity relationship in water electrolysis. Being proposed as promising electrocatalysts, bulk oxides, with their compositional and crystal structure flexibility, provide a good platform for studying the correlation between intrinsic activity and electronic structure and also for screening superior catalysts for water electrolysis. In this review, we discuss the recent developments of oxide electrocatalysts in understanding the structure&#8211;activity relationship. Firstly, we present a thorough overview of recent advances from both theoretical and experimental aspects. Subsequently, we highlight the design principles to provide guidance for promoting performance. Finally, the remaining challenges and perspectives about this field are presented. This review aims to provide guidance for the design of highly advanced oxide electrocatalysts for water electrolysis and large-scale green energy supply.</description>
      <author>Chuanhui Zhu, Changming Zhao, Hao Tian, S. Y. Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30112391</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do cyclic functional groups in the Cl-iron 3,5-diisopentoxyphenyl porphyrin complex influence the oxygen reduction reaction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2025.115401</link>
      <description>Phan Thi Hong Hoa, Viorel Chihaia, Do Ngoc Son, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410876593

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Phan Thi Hong Hoa, Viorel Chihaia, Do Ngoc Son</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2025.115401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT investigation on boron doped &#945;-graphyne and &#945;-graphdiyne as bifunctional catalysts toward HER and ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115306</link>
      <description>Chuanbo Wang, Baotao Kang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410882506

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuanbo Wang, Baotao Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-space investigations of on-surface intermolecular radical transfer reactions assisted by persistent radicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adu9436</link>
      <description>Huanjia Zhu, Junbo Wang, Kaifeng Niu, Yong Zhang, Yi Zhang, Chuan Deng, Peipei Huang, Deng&#8208;Yuan Li, Pei Nian Liu, Jianchen Lu, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Jinming Cai, Lifeng Chi, Qing Li, Science Advances. 11(22)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410886516

                Synthesizing radicals that have both long lifetimes and high chemical reactivity remains a long-term challenge. Here, persistent phenyl radicals are successfully synthesized on Ag(111) by protecting the carbon radical site by designing the precursor molecule with suitable steric hindrance. As carbon-carbon coupling is prohibited, such radicals remain intact for longer than 6 hours at room temperature on Ag(111). Taking advantage of the long lifetimes, the as-synthesized radicals are directly characterized in the real space at the single-chemical-bond scale by means of bond-resolving scanning tunneling microscopy imaging. Accompanied by the excellent stability, the radicals exhibit high chemical reactivities and facilitate the intermolecular radical transfer reactions at extreme low temperature. The preparation of persistent radicals not only favors the characterization of a surface-stabilized radical in the real space but also aids in illuminating the detailed reaction pathways of subsequent radical-assisted reactions directly.</description>
      <author>Huanjia Zhu, Junbo Wang, Kaifeng Niu, Yong Zhang, Yi Zhang, Chuan Deng, Peipei Huang, Deng&#8208;Yuan Li, Pei Nian Liu, Jianchen Lu, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Jinming Cai, Lifeng Chi, Qing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adu9436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous water dissociation on intermetallic electride LaCu0.67Si1.33 enhances electrochemical methanization of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60353-9</link>
      <description>Luming Zhang, Huan Ma, Yongfang Sun, Yilin Zhao, Huiying Deng, Yuhang Wang, Fei Wang, Xiaodong Wen, Mingchuan Luo, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410889205

                Renewable electricity driven CO2 electroreduction into methane offers a sustainable route to mitigate our dependence on natural gas. However, this route is now limited by the unsatisfied efficiency and short durability, which originates from a kinetic disparity between water dissociation (WD) and proton-coupled electron transfer on existing catalysts. Herein, we harness the exceptional WD capability of the intermetallic electride (IE) materials for the electrocatalytic methanization from CO2. Combinative experimental and theoretical approaches strongly evidence a spontaneous WD on an IE LaCu0.67Si1.33 catalyst due to its unique electronic structure (strongly modified charge states, reversible lattice hydride ions and anionic electrons). Consequently, this catalyst exhibits improved methanization performance in alkaline flow cells, achieving a methane Faraday efficiency of 72% at -1.21 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (vs. RHE) and peak partial current density of 476.7 mA cm-2 at -1.52 V vs. RHE. Energetic calculations further establish the mechanistic link between WD and methanization processes on our catalyst, on which a lowered free energy barrier for the key *CO to *CHO transformation step is observed. This work sheds light on the pivotal role of WD and expands the repertoire of materials for efficient electrocatalytic methanization from CO2.</description>
      <author>Luming Zhang, Huan Ma, Yongfang Sun, Yilin Zhao, Huiying Deng, Yuhang Wang, Fei Wang, Xiaodong Wen, Mingchuan Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60353-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-step preparation of star-shaped Fe5(PO4)4(OH)3-modified g-C3N4 for high-efficiency sacrificial-agent-free photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138031</link>
      <description>Yanan Di, Huaxin Li, Xianbo Yu, Chen Hu, Shuao Xie, Xiaoxue Xi, Wei Han, Zhongbo Hu, Xian Yue, Junhui Xiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410890418

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Di, Huaxin Li, Xianbo Yu, Chen Hu, Shuao Xie, Xiaoxue Xi, Wei Han, Zhongbo Hu, Xian Yue, Junhui Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient CO2 Electroreduction to Formate using Bismuth Nanodots within ZIF-8 Scaffold</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100450</link>
      <description>Muhammad Usman, Munzir H. Suliman, Maryam Abdinejad, Jesse Kok, Hussain Al Naji, Aasif Helal, Zain H. Yamani, Gabriele Centi, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410893603

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Usman, Munzir H. Suliman, Maryam Abdinejad, Jesse Kok, Hussain Al Naji, Aasif Helal, Zain H. Yamani, Gabriele Centi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Kinetic-Driven Oxygen Reduction Reaction Using Grand Canonical Ensemble Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01724</link>
      <description>Shibin Wang, Jin&#8208;Chang Guo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410893774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shibin Wang, Jin&#8208;Chang Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano high-entropy materials for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis: Rational design, structure-activity relationships, and applications in rechargeable metal-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104357</link>
      <description>Tarekegn Heliso Dolla, Siyabonga Patrick Mbokazi, Thabo Matthews, Rhiyaad Mohamed, Ludwe L. Sikeyi, Usman Muhammad Tukur, Jiexi Wang, Phumlani F. Msomi, Winny Kgabo Maboya, Peter R. Makgwane, Nithyadharseni Palaniyandy, Mkhulu Mathe, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410894056

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tarekegn Heliso Dolla, Siyabonga Patrick Mbokazi, Thabo Matthews, Rhiyaad Mohamed, Ludwe L. Sikeyi, Usman Muhammad Tukur, Jiexi Wang, Phumlani F. Msomi, Winny Kgabo Maboya, Peter R. Makgwane, Nithyadharseni Palaniyandy, Mkhulu Mathe</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Novel 2D Composite Nanomaterials by Coupling Graphene or Silicene with TM3N2 MXene (TM = Nb, Ta, Mo, and W) to Achieve Highly Efficient HER Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30112401</link>
      <description>Xiuyi Zhang, Guangtao Yu, Wei Zhang, E Yang, Wei Chen, Molecules. 30(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410894714

                MXenes have emerged as promising candidates for energy storage and catalyst design. Through detailed density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we designed a series of new 2D composite MXene-based nanomaterials by covering excellent TM3N2 MXenes (TM = Nb, Ta, Mo, and W) with graphene or buckled silicene. Our findings demonstrate that this coating can lead to high catalytic activity for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) in these composite MXene-based systems, with silicene exhibiting superior performance compared to graphene. The relevant carbon and silicon atoms in the coated materials serve as active sites for HER due to complex electron transfer processes. Additionally, doping N or P atoms into graphene/silicene, which have similar atomic radii, but larger electronegativity than C/Si atoms, can further enhance the HER activity of adjacent carbon or silicon atoms, thus endowing the composite systems with higher HER catalytic performance. Coupled with their high stability and metallic conductivity, all these composite systems show great potential as electrocatalysts for HER. These remarkable findings offer new strategies and valuable insights for designing non-precious and highly efficient MXene-based HER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiuyi Zhang, Guangtao Yu, Wei Zhang, E Yang, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30112401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of Oxygen Reduction Reaction Catalyzed by FePPc and Pz&#8208;FeTPr Conjugated Organic Polymer: Insights From Grand&#8208;Canonical Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202504887</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Ying Zhao, Xuebo Chen, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410898844

                Abstract This report examines the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalyzed by iron&#8208;polyphthalocyanine (FePPc) and pyrazine&#8208;linked iron&#8208;coordinated tetrapyrrole (Pz&#8208;FeTPr) conjugated organic polymer (COP) catalysts, utilizing grand&#8208;canonical density functional theory (GC&#8208;DFT) and microkinetic (MK) simulations. The computed half&#8208;wave potential for AA stacking FePPc under alkaline conditions is in strong agreement with experimental findings. The ORR mechanism for AA stacking FePPc is characterized by the * O 2 mechanism (), with the Fe site serving as the active site. In the case of Pz&#8208;FeTPr, the ORR mechanism is similarly governed by the * O 2 mechanism, with the Fe site remaining the active site at lower potentials (less than 0.5 V RHE , vs reversible hydrogen electrode). However, at higher potentials (greater than 0.5 V RHE ), the Fe site becomes obstructed by , resulting in a shift of the active site from the Fe site to a neighboring C site (designated as type A3). The corresponding ORR mechanism at the C site is denoted as mechanism (). This mechanism yields a calculated half&#8208;wave potential that aligns well with experimental observations. The mechanisms identified for FePPc and Pz&#8208;FeTPr can be substantiated by the Raman signals detected in experimental studies.</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Ying Zhao, Xuebo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202504887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#8217;s What You Value: A Theoretical Framework for Unveiling Archaeological Heritage Values Through Text Mining</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/13505033.2025.2505405</link>
      <description>H. Schwartz, Conservation and Management of Archaeological Sites. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410908330

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Schwartz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/13505033.2025.2505405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Layer Deposited Ir Nanostructures on Titania Nanotube Layers for Efficient Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146607</link>
      <description>Bilal Bawab, Jhonatan Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Pereira, Jan Michali&#269;ka, Miloslav Pouzar, Lud&#283;k Hrom&#225;dko, Ra&#250;l Zazpe, Jan M. Mac&#225;k, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410909176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bilal Bawab, Jhonatan Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Pereira, Jan Michali&#269;ka, Miloslav Pouzar, Lud&#283;k Hrom&#225;dko, Ra&#250;l Zazpe, Jan M. Mac&#225;k</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective proton-coupled electron transfer engineering between CuxIny alloy and polyoxometalate medium for efficient CO2 electroreduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116254</link>
      <description>Wencong Sun, Chunxiang Li, Yuehua Tai, Li Zhou, Wenxue Tian, Shumiao Li, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410910445

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wencong Sun, Chunxiang Li, Yuehua Tai, Li Zhou, Wenxue Tian, Shumiao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning strain of Platinum-Cobalt-Zinc trimetallic nanoparticles for efficient oxygen reduction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138046</link>
      <description>Weizhi Wang, Yingying Cai, Pengfei Tian, Jing Xu, Fu&#8208;Zhen Xuan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410928228

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weizhi Wang, Yingying Cai, Pengfei Tian, Jing Xu, Fu&#8208;Zhen Xuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Role of Hydroxyl Functionalization in Linear Poly(Ethylenimine) for Oxidation&#8208;Resistant Direct Air Capture of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400960</link>
      <description>Anthony J. Varni, L. Thigpen, Marcos F. Calegari Andrade, Maxwell A. T. Marple, Elwin Hunter&#8208;Sellars, Amitesh Maiti, Sichi Li, Simon H. Pang, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410930554

                Abstract Aminopolymer&#8208;based adsorbents are a prominent class of materials being used for direct air capture of CO 2 at the industrial scale. However, improving their working lifetime, specifically by increasing their resilience to oxidative degradation, remains an ongoing challenge. Toward this end, functionalization of aminopolymers with non&#8208;amine functionalities such as hydroxyls has emerged in recent years as a promising strategy toward improving adsorbent lifetime. Although there is a growing body of work demonstrating the effectiveness of this approach and investigating the origin of this improved stability, studies to date have primarily focused on branched aminopolymer systems such as branched poly(ethylenimine). In this work, hydroxyl&#8208;functionalized linear poly(ethylenimine) is used to continue to probe the underlying protective mechanism of this strategy. A combination of thermogravimetric analysis, NMR relaxometry, differential scanning calorimetry, and computational simulations is used to better understand the relationship between the extent of chemical functionalization, physical properties, and adsorbent performance.</description>
      <author>Anthony J. Varni, L. Thigpen, Marcos F. Calegari Andrade, Maxwell A. T. Marple, Elwin Hunter&#8208;Sellars, Amitesh Maiti, Sichi Li, Simon H. Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroelectrochemical Analysis of Oxygen Evolution by Nickel Hydroxide: Role of Oxygen Vacancies, Charge Transfer, and Silk Fibroin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500190</link>
      <description>Eduardo R. do Nascimento, Michele Lemos de Souza, Alexandre G. Brolo, Wendel A. Alves, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410930783

                Abstract This study investigates the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on nickel hydroxide (Ni(OH)&#8322;) catalysts, focusing on the roles of oxygen vacancies (O v ), charge transfer, and silk fibroin. Spectroelectrochemical techniques, including in situ surface&#8208;enhanced Raman (SERS) and UV&#8211;vis spectroscopy, revealed that O v formation and Ni&#8208;to&#8208;Au charge transfer facilitate the generation of high&#8208;valence Ni and superoxide species. A Mars&#8211;van Krevelen mechanism is proposed to describe the participation of lattice oxygen. Silk fibroin is found to enhance catalytic activity by lowering the activation energy of key intermediates, as indicated by higher transfer coefficients and Tafel slope analysis. At +300 mV overpotential, fibroin&#8208;modified samples exhibited intrinsic turnover frequencies (TOFs) of &#8776;0.7 s&#8315;&#185;, outperforming fibroin&#8208;free counterparts (&#8776;0.4 s&#8315;&#185;). These results highlight the synergy between structural defects and interfacial modifications in improving Ni(OH)&#8322;&#8208;based OER catalysts for sustainable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Eduardo R. do Nascimento, Michele Lemos de Souza, Alexandre G. Brolo, Wendel A. Alves</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect-Mediated Selectivity: Sulfur Vacancy Engineering in Tin Sulfide Boosts CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00438</link>
      <description>Linping Wu, Miaomiao Liu, Min Bu, Rui Tang, Ling Han, Xiaobin Fu, Yuxuan Zhang, Linjuan Zhang, Miao Shen, Qian Yuan, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410941018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linping Wu, Miaomiao Liu, Min Bu, Rui Tang, Ling Han, Xiaobin Fu, Yuxuan Zhang, Linjuan Zhang, Miao Shen, Qian Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled overall water splitting in two-dimensional Sr(BiO2)2: Spontaneous oxygen evolution and regulated hydrogen production via isoelectronic doping and strain engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180919</link>
      <description>Yuanfeng Xu, Hongjing Wang, Songsong Sun, Chang Liu, Yaning Song, Yanju Ji, Hao Zhang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410942700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanfeng Xu, Hongjing Wang, Songsong Sun, Chang Liu, Yaning Song, Yanju Ji, Hao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enriched asymmetric &#960; electrons confining single-site Pt for acidic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2025.101968</link>
      <description>Mingxia Xu, Yiran Kang, Leilei Wang, Yunlong Zhang, Guang Jiang, Yafeng Cai, Yunchuan Tu, Qiao Zhao, Jun Chi, Weiguo Song, Hongmei Yu, Jingting Hu, Wei Liu, Rui Huang, Liang Yu, Junling Lu, Xinhe Bao, Dehui Deng, Joule. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410816589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingxia Xu, Yiran Kang, Leilei Wang, Yunlong Zhang, Guang Jiang, Yafeng Cai, Yunchuan Tu, Qiao Zhao, Jun Chi, Weiguo Song, Hongmei Yu, Jingting Hu, Wei Liu, Rui Huang, Liang Yu, Junling Lu, Xinhe Bao, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2025.101968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A mini-review on performance metrics for electrochemically mediated ammonia recovery from wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ew01091d</link>
      <description>Weikun Chen, Taeyoung Kim, Environmental Science Water Research &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410865386

                This mini-review introduces a new plot comparing energy consumption and productivity as key performance metrics, providing valuable insights into the current status and future directions of electrochemically mediated ammonia recovery from wastewater.</description>
      <author>Weikun Chen, Taeyoung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ew01091d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovations in chemical process control: challenges and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101148</link>
      <description>Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian, Helen Durand, Joel A. Paulson, Lorenz T. Biegler, Current Opinion in Chemical Engineering. 48(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410907732

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian, Helen Durand, Joel A. Paulson, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Ru&#8211;O bond covalency via Ga-doping for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction in acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-025-2653-y</link>
      <description>Zhongliang Liu, Heng Liu, Kai Zhou, Miaomiao Liu, Tianrui Xue, Yongjun Shen, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Chunzhong Li, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410915316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongliang Liu, Heng Liu, Kai Zhou, Miaomiao Liu, Tianrui Xue, Yongjun Shen, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-025-2653-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of chemically modified higher tungsten boride by means of hybrid GNN/DFT approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01628-z</link>
      <description>Nikita A. Matsokin, Roman A. Eremin, Alena Kuznetsova, Innokentiy S. Humonen, A. Krautsou, Vladimir D. Lazarev, Yuliya Z. Vassilyeva, A. Ya. Pak, Semen Budennyy, Alexander G. Kvashnin, Andrei A. Osiptsov, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410940179

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nikita A. Matsokin, Roman A. Eremin, Alena Kuznetsova, Innokentiy S. Humonen, A. Krautsou, Vladimir D. Lazarev, Yuliya Z. Vassilyeva, A. Ya. Pak, Semen Budennyy, Alexander G. Kvashnin, Andrei A. Osiptsov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01628-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocluster Active Sites Formed on Heterogeneous Thermal Catalysts and Electrocatalysts by &lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; Reactive Environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01388</link>
      <description>Ahmed O. Elnabawy, Manos Mavrikakis, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410803138

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ahmed O. Elnabawy, Manos Mavrikakis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01388</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
