<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 01:36:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-Tuned Surface Reconstruction Promotes Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125356</link>
      <description>Guiling Wu, Qianlin Chen, Jinrong Min, Feng Wang, Yan Zhao, Zhaoyang Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409301686

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guiling Wu, Qianlin Chen, Jinrong Min, Feng Wang, Yan Zhao, Zhaoyang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking design strategies for oxygen evolution reaction catalysts: Insights from a kinetic perspective via constrained ab initio molecular dynamics simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162357</link>
      <description>Dongyup Shin, Sang Soo Han, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409307402

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongyup Shin, Sang Soo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D Package&#8208;Integrated Platinum Catalyst with Robust Interactions for Enhanced Cathodic Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503111</link>
      <description>Huiting Niu, Yan Liu, Lei Huang, Lebin Cai, Chenfeng Xia, Ruijuan Qi, Yu Mao, Wei Guo, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409308107

                Abstract Durable electrocatalysts and optimal ionomer distribution in cathode catalyst layer (CCL) are crucial for the efficiency and lifetime of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), especially at high currents. This work presents a 1D package&#8208;integrated platinum (Pt) catalyst designed to optimize mass exchange and boost cathodic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The package&#8208;integrated Pt catalyst not only enhances the active site utilization, activity, and stability of Pt alloys but also optimizes the ionomer coverage and oxygen transport within the CCL. It shows superior performance with a mass activity of 1.33 A mg Pt &#8722;1 and only a 12 mV decay in half&#8208;wave potential after 30 000 cycles. Additionally, it delivers impressive catalytic performance (320 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0.8 V), mass transport polarization (0.632 V at 2000 mA cm &#8722;2 ), and low oxygen transport resistance (0.03 s cm &#8722;1 ) in hydrogen&#8208;air fuel cells. This package&#8208;integrated catalyst with robust anti&#8208;ionomer interference and impressive transport capability is of great significance for designing efficient and long&#8208;lasting PEMFC cathodes.</description>
      <author>Huiting Niu, Yan Liu, Lei Huang, Lebin Cai, Chenfeng Xia, Ruijuan Qi, Yu Mao, Wei Guo, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on the recent mechanisms investigation of PFAS electrochemical oxidation degradation: mechanisms, DFT calculation, and pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenve.2025.1568542</link>
      <description>Gengyang Li, Mengyun Peng, Qingguo Huang, Ching&#8208;Hua Huang, Yongsheng Chen, Gary L. Hawkins, Ke Li, Frontiers in Environmental Engineering. 4(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409308265

                Per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) have drawn public concern recently due to their toxic properties and persistence in the environment, making it urgent to eliminate PFAS from contaminated water. Electrochemical oxidation (EO) has shown great promise for the destructive treatment of PFAS with direct electron transfer and hydroxyl radical (&#8901;OH)-mediated indirect reactions. One of the most popular electrodes is Magn&#233;li phase titanium suboxides. However, the degradation mechanisms of PFAS are still unsure and are under investigation now. The main methodology is the first-principal density functional theory (DFT) computation, which is recently used to explore the degradation mechanisms and interpret by-product formation during PFAS mineralization. From the literature review, the main applications of DFT computation for studying PFAS degradation mechanisms by EO include bond dissociation energy, absorption energy, activation energy, and overpotential &#951; for oxygen evolution reactions. The main degradation mechanisms and pathways of PFAS in the EO process include mass transfer, direct electron transfer, decarboxylation, peroxyl radical generation, hydroxylation, intramolecular rearrangement, and hydrolysis. In the recent 4 years, 11 papers performed DFT computation to explore the possible PFAS degradation mechanisms and pathways in the EO process. This paper&#8217;s objectives are to: 1) summarize the main degradation mechanisms of PFAS degradation in EO; 2) review the application of DFT computation for studying PFAS degradation mechanisms during EO; process; 3) review the possible degradation pathways of perfluorooctane sulfonoic acid (PFOS) and per-fluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) during EO process.</description>
      <author>Gengyang Li, Mengyun Peng, Qingguo Huang, Ching&#8208;Hua Huang, Yongsheng Chen, Gary L. Hawkins, Ke Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenve.2025.1568542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering 3d-Printed Molybdenum Carbide Catalysts for Selective Co2 Reduction to Co</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5211448</link>
      <description>Arturo Pajares, Mehmet Tanr&#305;verdi, Eduardo Couti&#241;o&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Jacob Andrade Arvizu, Maxim Guc, Pablo Guardia, H&#232;ctor Prats, Bart Michielsen, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409310095

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arturo Pajares, Mehmet Tanr&#305;verdi, Eduardo Couti&#241;o&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Jacob Andrade Arvizu, Maxim Guc, Pablo Guardia, H&#232;ctor Prats, Bart Michielsen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5211448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of bifunctional oxygen evolution/reduction electrocatalysts on g-C3N3 monolayer by a defect physics method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116135</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Liuming Yan, Chao Yang, Yanyan Qu, Aodi Zhang, Zhenzhen Feng, Wentao Wang, Pengfei Ou, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409315993

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Liuming Yan, Chao Yang, Yanyan Qu, Aodi Zhang, Zhenzhen Feng, Wentao Wang, Pengfei Ou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiSe synergistically enhancing FeNi bimetallic site catalysts for efficient bifunctional water electrolysis catalysts and mechanistic insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115108</link>
      <description>Zhiqiang Peng, H. Li, J. Jenny Li, Feng Ao, Yue Cheng, Kai Huang, Jun Yao, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao, Molecular Catalysis. 580(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409321916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiqiang Peng, H. Li, J. Jenny Li, Feng Ao, Yue Cheng, Kai Huang, Jun Yao, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media: from in situ characterization to rational design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.067</link>
      <description>Bo Sun, Haoyan Cheng, Kexing Song, Zhonghan Jiang, Changrui Shi, Hao Liang, Shuaiyu Ma, Hao Hu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409322908

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Sun, Haoyan Cheng, Kexing Song, Zhonghan Jiang, Changrui Shi, Hao Liang, Shuaiyu Ma, Hao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Oxides as Promising Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.116550</link>
      <description>Jie Zhang, Junhua You, Yao Zhao, Tong Liu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409327872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Zhang, Junhua You, Yao Zhao, Tong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.116550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogenation of Mixed Ir&#8211;Ti Oxide: A Powerful Concept to Promote the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00588</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Matej Zlatar, Yuejun Wang, Phillip Timmer, Alexander Spriewald-Luciano, Lorena Glatthaar, Serhiy Cherevko, Herbert Over, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409329062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Matej Zlatar, Yuejun Wang, Phillip Timmer, Alexander Spriewald-Luciano, Lorena Glatthaar, Serhiy Cherevko, Herbert Over</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Electrochemical Activity of Pt/C Catalysts through Mild Ultraviolet Pulsed Laser Post Irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00223</link>
      <description>Manuel Matten, Norbert Koch, Adib Caidi, Ivan Radev, Thomas de Lange, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409332699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manuel Matten, Norbert Koch, Adib Caidi, Ivan Radev, Thomas de Lange, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The NOMAD mini-apps: A suite of kernels from ab initio electronic structure codes enabling co-design in high-performance computing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.3</link>
      <description>Isidre Mas Magre, Rogeli Grima Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a, Jos&#233; Julio Guti&#233;rrez Moreno, Open Research Europe. 4(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409333649

                This article introduces a suite of mini-applications (mini-apps) designed to optimise computational kernels in ab initio electronic structure codes. The suite is developed from flagship applications participating in the NOMAD Center of Excellence, such as the ELPA eigensolver library and the GW implementations of the exciting, Abinit, and FHI-aims codes. The mini-apps were identified by targeting functions that significantly contribute to the total execution time in the parent applications. This strategic selection allows for concentrated optimisation efforts. The suite is designed for easy deployment on various High-Performance Computing (HPC) systems, supported by an integrated CMake build system for straightforward compilation and execution. The aim is to harness the capabilities of emerging (post)exascale systems, which necessitate concurrent hardware and software development &#8212; a concept known as co-design. The mini-app suite serves as a tool for profiling and benchmarking, providing insights that can guide both software optimisation and hardware design. Ultimately, these developments will enable more accurate and efficient simulations of novel materials, leveraging the full potential of exascale computing in material science research.</description>
      <author>Isidre Mas Magre, Rogeli Grima Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a, Jos&#233; Julio Guti&#233;rrez Moreno</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Screening of Molecule/Polymer Photocatalysts for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01785</link>
      <description>Lei Shi, Alessandro Troisi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409335152

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Shi, Alessandro Troisi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Metal Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C Sites with Improved Stability for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500116</link>
      <description>Shiyang Liu, Md Raziun Bin Mamtaz, Jia Chen, Haijiao Lu, Shuhao Wang, Quentin Meyer, Chuan Zhao, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409335837

                Abstract Low&#8208;cost and durable hydrogen fuel cells are crucial for the success of the hydrogen economy. While Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts are amongst the most promising low&#8208;cost alternative to platinum (Pt) for the oxygen reduction reaction, their unsatisfactory durability is the grand challenge faced by the field due to iron demetallation, carbon corrosion and electrode collapse. Herein, a dual&#8208;metal single&#8208;atom Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst with superior stability (49% loss in peak power density) than Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts (66% loss) over 96 h of continuous operations in H 2 &#8211;O 2 fuel cells is reported. Advanced operando electrochemical and post&#8208;mortem physical measurements shed light on the underlying mechanism. The iron&#8211;manganese bond anchors the iron strongly in the Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C centre, which lowers the hydrogen peroxide yield as a result. Operando electrochemical measurements reveal a more stable triple&#8208;phase boundary environment for the Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst than for Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C. Specifically, a combination of cyclic voltammetry and impedance spectroscopy with the distribution of relaxation times reveals that the iron demetallation and carbon corrosion are respectively 20% and 30% slower for the Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst than the Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst in hydrogen fuel cells. Altogether, this dual&#8208;metal site strategy paves the way for improving the stability of Pt&#8208;free catalysts for hydrogen fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Shiyang Liu, Md Raziun Bin Mamtaz, Jia Chen, Haijiao Lu, Shuhao Wang, Quentin Meyer, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Water in Green Carbon Science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00347</link>
      <description>Bo Peng, Kun Zhang, Yuhan Sun, Buxing Han, Mingyuan He, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409348887

                Within the context of green chemistry, the concept of green carbon science emphasizes carbon balance and recycling to address the challenge of achieving carbon neutrality. The fundamental processes in this field are oxidation and reduction, which often involve simple molecules such as CO2, CO, CH4, CHx, and H2O. Water plays a critical role in nearly all oxidation-reduction processes, and thus, it is a central focus of research in green carbon science. Water can act as a direct source of dihydrogen in reduction reactions or participate in oxidation reactions, frequently involving O-O coupling to produce hydrogen peroxide or dioxygen. At the atomic level, this coupling involves the statistically unfavorable proximity of two atoms, requiring optimization through a catalytic process influenced by two types of factors, as described by the authors. Extrinsic factors are related to geometrical and electronic criteria associated with the catalytic metal, involving its d-orbitals (or bands in the case of zerovalent metals and electrodes). Intrinsic factors are related to the coupling of oxygen atoms via their p-orbitals. At the mesoscopic or microscopic scale, the reaction medium typically consists of mixtures of lipophilic and hydrophilic phases with water, which may exist under supercritical conditions or as suspensions of microdroplets. These reactions predominantly occur at phase interfaces. A comprehensive understanding of the phenomena across these scales could facilitate improvements and even lead to the development of novel conversion processes.</description>
      <author>Bo Peng, Kun Zhang, Yuhan Sun, Buxing Han, Mingyuan He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monolayer Ytei for Photocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5213974</link>
      <description>Dan Mao, Rundong Wan, Shijie Wang, Ying Lei, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409349545

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Mao, Rundong Wan, Shijie Wang, Ying Lei, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5213974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Selectivity in Oxygen Electrocatalysis Using Chiral Nanoparticles as Electron-Spin Filters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03394</link>
      <description>Zixu Wang, Jinling Wan, Xuehao Sun, Lichao Sun, Shengli Chen, Qingfeng Zhang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409350393

                Controlling the electron spin of oxygen-containing intermediates is crucial for efficient oxygen electrocatalysis toward clean energy technologies such as fuel cells and water electrolysis. Current strategies for controlling the electron spins rely mainly on tuning the chemical structure of the oxygen electrocatalyst, which is often hardly achieved for metal and oxide electrocatalysts. The chiral-induced spin selectivity (CISS) effect, a significant discovery in chiral spintronics, represents an alternative approach for tuning the spin selectivity of oxygen electrocatalysts. Here we demonstrate the use of intrinsic chiral nanoparticles as electron-spin filters to tune the selectivity in oxygen electrocatalytic reactions. Chiral Au nanoparticles with a concave vortex cube structure were employed as the chiral substrate, exhibiting highly tunable optical chirality and intriguing CISS-like effect. As model systems, the catalytically active components such as Pt or Ni(OH)2 are overgrown onto chiral Au nanoparticles to construct the chiral hybrid electrocatalysts. Remarkably, both cases show chirality-dependent tunable activities over oxygen reduction/evolution reactions, respectively. The insights gained from this work not only shed light on the underlying mechanisms dictating the CISS-enhanced oxygen electrocatalysis by chiral nanoparticles but also provide an important knowledge framework that guides the rational design of chiral electrocatalysts toward oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Zixu Wang, Jinling Wan, Xuehao Sun, Lichao Sun, Shengli Chen, Qingfeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion power spectra as a window into dynamic materials architecture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adt6144</link>
      <description>S Fricke, Mia Salgado, Shira Haber, J&#233;r&#233;my Demarteau, Mutian Hua, Ah&#8208;Young Song, Brett A. Helms, Jeffrey A. Reimer, Science Advances. 11(15)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409357139

                Chemical recycling of commodity and specialty polymers presents a multifaceted challenge for industrial societies. On one hand, macromolecular architectures must be engineered to yield durable products that, on the other hand, rapidly deconstruct to recyclable monomers under pre-determined conditions. Polymer deconstruction is a chemical process that requires deep understanding of molecular reactivity in heterogeneous media, where porous material architectures evolve in both space and time. To build this understanding, we develop herein experimental and analytical methods describing sets of diffusive eigenmodes that exist within time-varying, non-Euclidean boundary conditions, a situation commonly encountered in the reactive deconstruction of polymers where chain fragments splay, alter their local dynamics, and evolve in their confinement of reacting media. Diffusion power spectra, discerned experimentally by NMR, yield polymer and solvent frequency-domain velocity autocorrelation functions that are analyzed in the context of physical models for chemical reactions parameterized with fractal mathematics. The results connect local motion in polymers to chemical reactivity during acidolysis of circular elastomers.</description>
      <author>S Fricke, Mia Salgado, Shira Haber, J&#233;r&#233;my Demarteau, Mutian Hua, Ah&#8208;Young Song, Brett A. Helms, Jeffrey A. Reimer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adt6144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Role of Bridge Adsorbed Hydrogen Intermediate on Pt&#8211;Ru Pair for Efficient Acidic Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202503221</link>
      <description>Hao Zhao, Baoxin Ni, Yongyu Pan, Yuze Li, Jun Li, Guo&#8208;Liang Wang, Zhiqing Zou, Kun Jiang, Qing&#8208;Qing Cheng, Lianhai Zu, Hui Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409361094

                Abstract Atop and multiple adsorbed hydrogen are considered as key intermediates on Pt&#8208;group metal for acidic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), yet the role of bridge hydrogen intermediate ( * H bridge ) is consistently overlooked experimentally. Herein, a Pt atomic chain modified fcc &#8208;Ru nanocrystal (Pt&#8211;Ru( fcc )) is developed with a co&#8208;crystalline structure, featuring * H bridge intermediate bonded on the Pt&#8211;Ru pair site. Electrons leap from the pair site to * H bridge facilitate hydrogen desorption, thus accelerating the Tafel kinetics and ensuring outstanding electrocatalytic performance, with a low overpotential (4.0 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and high turnover frequency (56.4 H 2 s &#8722;1 at 50 mV). Notably, the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer PEMWE with ultra&#8208;low loading of 10 ug Pt cm &#8722;2 shows excellent activity (1.61 V at 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 ) and low average degradation rate (4.0 &#181;V h &#8722;1 over 1000 h), significantly outperforming the benchmark Pt/C. Furthermore, the PEMWE&#8208;based 80 &#181;m Gore membrane under identical operating conditions requires only 1.54 and 1.58 V to achieve 1.0 and 1.5 A cm &#8722;2 . This finding highlights the key role of * H bridge at the Pt&#8211;Ru interface in obtaining high HER intrinsic activity and underscores the transformative potential in designing next&#8208;generation bimetallic catalysts for clean hydrogen energy.</description>
      <author>Hao Zhao, Baoxin Ni, Yongyu Pan, Yuze Li, Jun Li, Guo&#8208;Liang Wang, Zhiqing Zou, Kun Jiang, Qing&#8208;Qing Cheng, Lianhai Zu, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202503221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering innovative catalysts for efficient CO2 reduction toward carbon neutrality</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.116621</link>
      <description>Muhammad Awais, Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409371439

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Awais, Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.116621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new class of solid electrolytes with an ultra-low Na-ion migration barrier</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236979</link>
      <description>Artem D. Dembitskiy, Sergey N. Marshenya, Evgeny V. Antipov, Stanislav S. Fedotov, Dmitry A. Aksyonov, Journal of Power Sources. 642(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409371810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Artem D. Dembitskiy, Sergey N. Marshenya, Evgeny V. Antipov, Stanislav S. Fedotov, Dmitry A. Aksyonov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt 5d Density of States in Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalyst Governed by Ligand Effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00201</link>
      <description>Jiabin Xu, Jiatang Chen, Yun Mui Yiu, Jun Zhong, Yining Huang, Tsun&#8208;Kong Sham, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409372196

                In alloy systems, the strain and ligand effects are prevalent, but it is challenging to study the impact of either on the material structure independently. We conducted high-energy-resolution fluorescence detection (HERFD) X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and resonant X-ray emission spectroscopy (XES)/resonant inelastic X-ray scattering (RIXS) spectroscopy on a Pt3Mg alloy-based carbon material (Pt3Mg-N-C). By introducing a size-comparable atom, the strain effect is minimized, allowing the Pt d-density of states (d-DOS) to be primarily affected by the ligand effect. The experimental results reveal that Pt gains electrons in Pt3Mg-N-C, exhibiting a more symmetric d-band shape and a downshift of the d-band center compared to Pt metal, which is further confirmed by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The correlation between the Pt d-DOS and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity is also discussed.</description>
      <author>Jiabin Xu, Jiatang Chen, Yun Mui Yiu, Jun Zhong, Yining Huang, Tsun&#8208;Kong Sham</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiggle150: Benchmarking Density Functionals and Neural Network Potentials on Highly Strained Conformers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00015</link>
      <description>Rebecca Brew, Ian A. Nelson, Meruyert Binayeva, Amlan Nayak, W. Kyle Simmons, Joseph J. Gair, Corin Wagen, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409372236

                Accurate benchmarks are key to assessing the accuracy and robustness of computational methods, yet most available benchmark sets focus on equilibrium geometries, limiting their utility for applications involving nonequilibrium structures such as ab initio molecular dynamics and automated reaction-path exploration. To address this gap, we introduce Wiggle150, a benchmark comprising 150 highly strained conformations of adenosine, benzylpenicillin, and efavirenz. These geometries&#9472;generated via metadynamics and scored using DLPNO-CCSD(T)/CBS reference energies&#9472;exhibit substantially larger deviations in bond lengths, angles, dihedrals, and relative energies than other conformer benchmarks. We evaluate a diverse array of computational methods, including density-functional theory, composite quantum chemical methods, semiempirical models, neural network potentials, and force fields, on predicting relative energies for this challenging benchmark set. The results highlight multiple methods along the speed-accuracy Pareto frontier and identify AIMNet2 as particularly robust among the NNPs surveyed. We anticipate that Wiggle150 will be used to validate computational protocols involving nonequilibrium systems and guide the development of new density functionals and neural network potentials.</description>
      <author>Rebecca Brew, Ian A. Nelson, Meruyert Binayeva, Amlan Nayak, W. Kyle Simmons, Joseph J. Gair, Corin Wagen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Understanding of &lt;scp&gt;LaTaON&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; Decorated With Metal Cocatalysts for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70047</link>
      <description>Xiang Zhang, Yue Liu, Xin Zhou, International Journal of Quantum Chemistry. 125(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409372862

                ABSTRACT LaTaON 2 is a promising visible&#8208;light&#8208;responsive photocatalyst for water splitting because of its broad visible light absorption and suitable band edge positions. However, the high defect concentration hinders the charge transfer and results in the poor photocatalytic performance of LaTaON 2 . Loading proper cocatalysts is one of the most efficient strategies for promoting charge separation/transfer and achieving high reaction activity. In this work, we have used density functional theory calculations to study the depositions of Pt, Ru, and Ni single atom cocatalysts on LaTaON 2 (010) surface. The most stable adsorption configuration is the same site for all the elements, namely the top of the N atom on the La&#8208;terminated surface and the fourfold hollow site on the Ta&#8208;terminated surface. The adsorption of the metal single atom on Ta&#8208;termination is stronger than that on La&#8208;termination due to the formation of more bonds. Upon the deposition, no localized impurity states appear in the middle of the forbidden gap since the n d states of metal adatoms are located within the valence band and conduction band of LaTaON 2 . The efficiency of the photocatalysts is probed by investigating their ability to adsorb the H atom in a thermodynamically favorable manner. Our results reveal that the energetically favorable sites of HER are the N atom on the La&#8208;termination and the O and N atoms on the Ta&#8208;termination, respectively. Compared with the clean surface, the surfaces with Pt, Ru, and Ni single adatoms exhibit higher performance for HER because loading metal cocatalysts can further activate the surface nonmetal atoms and reduce the Gibbs free energy of hydrogen adsorption. The work gives an atom&#8208;level insight into the role of metal single atom cocatalysts in the LaTaON 2 photocatalyst for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Xiang Zhang, Yue Liu, Xin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The influence of core-shell chemical ordering on the generation and transfer of hot carriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102693</link>
      <description>Junais Habeeb Mokkath, Materials Today Chemistry. 45(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409377309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junais Habeeb Mokkath</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating d-p Band Center Distance at Metallene-Derived BOx-NiOOH to Unlock Lattice Oxygen for High-Efficient Glycerol Electrooxidation Coupled Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125368</link>
      <description>Zhenyu Li, Hao Sun, Qiaoyu Liu, Yijing Pian, Guang Yang, Jing Yu, Zexuan Zheng, Xiyang Wang, Subhajit Jana, Xinyu Bai, Zhuoyuan Ma, Xiaoxin Zou, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Haibin Chu, Yimin A. Wu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409378296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenyu Li, Hao Sun, Qiaoyu Liu, Yijing Pian, Guang Yang, Jing Yu, Zexuan Zheng, Xiyang Wang, Subhajit Jana, Xinyu Bai, Zhuoyuan Ma, Xiaoxin Zou, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Haibin Chu, Yimin A. Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the covalency of Ru-O bonds by dynamic reconstruction for efficient acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58654-0</link>
      <description>Luqi Wang, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Sheng Zhao, Yue Wang, Shengli Bi, Shaoxiong Li, Jianjie Ma, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Linlin Li, Tsung&#8208;Yi Chen, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Feng Hu, Yuping Wu, Shiling Peng, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409383439

                Developing ruthenium-based oxide catalysts capable of suppressing lattice oxygen participation in the catalytic reaction process is crucial for maintaining stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under acidic conditions. Herein, we delicately construct a RuO2 nanoparticle-anchored LiCoO2 nanosheet electrocatalyst (RuO2/LiCoO2), achieving dynamic optimization of RuO2 during the reaction process and improving catalytic stability. Benefiting from the unique electrochemical delithiation characteristics of the LiCoO2 support, the covalency of the Ru-O bond is effectively regulated during the OER process. The weakened Ru-O covalent bond inhibits the participation of lattice oxygen in the catalytic reaction and ensures the continuous operation of the Ru active sites. Moreover, the extended Ru-O bond in the optimized RuO2/LiCoO2 catalyst reduces the formation energy barrier of the *OOH intermediates, accelerating the progress of the OER. As a result, the RuO2/LiCoO2 catalyst requires only an overpotential of 150 &#177; 2 mV at 10 mA cm-2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and operates stably for 2000 h at 1 A cm-2 in a proton exchange membrane water electrolysis. This work opens new avenues for designing efficient ruthenium-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Luqi Wang, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Sheng Zhao, Yue Wang, Shengli Bi, Shaoxiong Li, Jianjie Ma, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Linlin Li, Tsung&#8208;Yi Chen, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Feng Hu, Yuping Wu, Shiling Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58654-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus-doped CuS@NF: A promising bifunctional electrocatalyst for enhanced water splitting efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163254</link>
      <description>Javid Barqi Mirzanlou, Moein Mehri, A.H. Salehi, Mohammad Zarei&#8208;Jelyani, Yalda Tarpoudi Baheri, Anisa Mutiara Badri, S. Morteza Mousavi&#8208;Khoshdel, Ximeng Liu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409383592

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Javid Barqi Mirzanlou, Moein Mehri, A.H. Salehi, Mohammad Zarei&#8208;Jelyani, Yalda Tarpoudi Baheri, Anisa Mutiara Badri, S. Morteza Mousavi&#8208;Khoshdel, Ximeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic performance of Ni-based high-entropy alloys with unique structural features in alkaline and seawater electrolysis under &#8722;10 &#176;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.071</link>
      <description>Yong Pan, Fachang Zhao, Guoning Ji, Songlin Xu, Ruiyu Li, Huiya Zhou, Rongda Zhao, Depeng Zhao, Fufa Wu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 127(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409384654

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Pan, Fachang Zhao, Guoning Ji, Songlin Xu, Ruiyu Li, Huiya Zhou, Rongda Zhao, Depeng Zhao, Fufa Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pristine metal-organic framework electrocatalysts for hydrogen production: Role of electrocatalyst properties in basic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clce.2025.100170</link>
      <description>Liberty L. Mguni, Olga K. Mmelesi, Emmanuel Kweinor Tetteh, Nombeko Graceful Sijadu, Yali Yao, Sudesh Rathilal, Cleaner Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409385084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liberty L. Mguni, Olga K. Mmelesi, Emmanuel Kweinor Tetteh, Nombeko Graceful Sijadu, Yali Yao, Sudesh Rathilal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clce.2025.100170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Pynta-Based Curriculum for ML-Accelerated Calculation of Transition States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00305</link>
      <description>Trevor Price, Saurabh Sivakumar, Matthew S. Johnson, Judit Z&#225;dor, Ambarish Kulkarni, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409396104

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Trevor Price, Saurabh Sivakumar, Matthew S. Johnson, Judit Z&#225;dor, Ambarish Kulkarni</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of CO2 Sequestration in a Stack Storage Complex in the San Juan Basin, NM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/224355-ms</link>
      <description>Vida Ama Bodi, William Ampomah, Dung Bui, Najmudeen Sibaweihi, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409400080

                ABSTRACT Effective CO2 sequestration requires not only minimizing carbon emissions but also optimizing storage efficiency while ensuring the integrity of storage sites. This research focuses on the assessment of CO2 injection in a stack storage system, specifically targeting the Entrada (high-permeability) and Bluff (low-permeability) formations within the San Juan Basin. By leveraging a single well to inject CO2 across multiple formations, the goal is to enhance storage efficiency, reduce the spatial extent of CO2 plumes, and minimize the area requiring long-term monitoring. A high-resolution hydrodynamic reservoir model was developed and validated using historical injection rates and pressure data from nearby saltwater disposal wells. This model was used to simulate 30 years of CO2 injection, aiming to store 50MtCO2f through a stacked storage configuration. Three well-completion strategies were explored: (1) a base case with injection into Entrada only, (2) a case with commingled injection into both formations through a single well, and (3) 6 scenarios using smart well-completion techniques to simultaneously inject CO2 into the Entrada and Bluff formations at controlled rates. Different injection rates were tested to identify the best scenario that minimizes CO2 plume size while meeting the storage target. Simulation results from the base case of injecting into Entrada only revealed that at an injection rate of 80MMSCFD, 50MtCO2 can be injected over 30 years. The commingled injection case showed that over 90% of injected CO2 entered the Entrada formation, leading to larger plume size (64.69 square miles after 100 years of post-injection monitoring) and an expanded area requiring monitoring. In contrast, the optimized injection strategy, with CO2 allocated at varying rates (25%, 31%, and 34% of the total injection rate of 80MMSCD) to the Bluff formation, resulted in the best scenario case significantly reducing the Entrada plume spatial extent by 22% while increasing the plume size in the Bluff formation by approximately 94%, accompanied by a 77% increment in the storage capacity. Ultimately, the best scenario reduced the total area requiring monitoring, demonstrating the effectiveness of a stack storage approach in controlling CO2 migration and pressure fronts. This study highlights the importance of optimizing CO2 in stacked storage systems to maximize sequestration efficiency. By carefully managing injection rates, the spread of CO2 plumes can be controlled, reducing monitoring costs and ensuring safe, long-term storage. The findings provide valuable insights for improving the practical implementation of CO2 capture and storage projects using stack storage systems.</description>
      <author>Vida Ama Bodi, William Ampomah, Dung Bui, Najmudeen Sibaweihi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/224355-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise modulation of nickel-molybdenum alloy (MoNi4)/molybdenum dioxide nanowires via a ternary nickel-cobalt-iron complex for enhanced electrochemical overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137560</link>
      <description>Peng Zuo, Fanfan Liu, Fuyan Zhao, Xiaofei Zhang, Yun Li, Kaiqin Xu, Fang Xiaowei, Zhi&#8208;wei Zhang, Yun Shen, Jinyun Liu, Yefeng Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409323446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Zuo, Fanfan Liu, Fuyan Zhao, Xiaofei Zhang, Yun Li, Kaiqin Xu, Fang Xiaowei, Zhi&#8208;wei Zhang, Yun Shen, Jinyun Liu, Yefeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of Ni- and Cu-Doped Molybdenum Ditelluride Electrocatalysts for Carbon Dioxide Reduction to Formic Acid and Carbon Monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040377</link>
      <description>Bin Zhao, Junyou Wang, Rui Wan, Zhongyao Li, Catalysts. 15(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409409343

                Under mild conditions, the effective conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into formic acid (HCOOH) and carbon monoxide (CO) represents a promising avenue for mitigating greenhouse gas emissions and addressing energy crises. In this work, we analyzed the electro-catalytic activities of six metals (Ti, Fe, Ni, Cu, Zn, and Cr) anchored on monolayer molybdenum telluride (TM@MoTe2) for the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) from CO2 to HCOOH and CO. Compared to the reversible hydrogen electrode, the limiting potential for HCOOH production on Ni@MoTe2 is only about &#8722;0.38 V, and it is only about &#8722;0.20 V for the CO production on Cu@MoTe2. The limiting potential is concerned with the free energies of *OCHO and *COOH. Both the CO2RRs suppress the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and exhibit good selectivity for the desired reaction products. These features enable the efficient conversion of CO2 into HCOOH on Ni@MoTe2 or CO on Cu@MoTe2. Our calculations could provide valuable insights for the design and synthesis of high-performance catalysts based on MoTe2.</description>
      <author>Bin Zhao, Junyou Wang, Rui Wan, Zhongyao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Adhesion Energies of Late Transition Metal Nanoparticles to Oxide Support Surfaces Using Oxide Reducibility and Metal Oxophilicity: Toward Predicting Catalyst Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06983</link>
      <description>Nida Janulaitis, Charles T. Campbell, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409410723

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nida Janulaitis, Charles T. Campbell</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Origin of Li Underpotential and Overpotential Deposition on Current Collectors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01078</link>
      <description>Jiankun Pu, Venkatasubramanian Viswanathan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409413029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiankun Pu, Venkatasubramanian Viswanathan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving MoS2 hydrogen evolution performance in anion exchange membrane water electrolysis by using LaNi5 alloy as a co-catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180420</link>
      <description>Hao Shang, Hang Shi, Haoliang Yu, Xiaohong Hu, Yan Xia, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1025(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409416058

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Shang, Hang Shi, Haoliang Yu, Xiaohong Hu, Yan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180420</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-type-II photocatalytic overall water splitting in a single covalent organic frameworks monolayer with polarized linkage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.141</link>
      <description>Chonggui Zhong, Liqun Song, Xiangqian Lu, Wei Qin, Yingcai Fan, Jingping Yu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 127(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409416234

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chonggui Zhong, Liqun Song, Xiangqian Lu, Wei Qin, Yingcai Fan, Jingping Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanadium-Modulated Molybdenum/Nickel-Based Multi-Heterostructures finely tailoring d-Band centers for electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137543</link>
      <description>Guimin Wang, Xueting Li, J J Wang, Haijing Yan, Dou Zhang, Chungui Tian, Zhang Hai-sheng, Yanqing Jiao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409417383

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guimin Wang, Xueting Li, J J Wang, Haijing Yan, Dou Zhang, Chungui Tian, Zhang Hai-sheng, Yanqing Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles insights into metallic doping effects on yttrium twin grain boundary</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112742</link>
      <description>Guanlin Lyu, Yuanxu Zhu, Yuguo Sun, Panpan Gao, Ping Qian, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409419596

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanlin Lyu, Yuanxu Zhu, Yuguo Sun, Panpan Gao, Ping Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Subspace Approximation for Random Phase Approximation Correlation Energies: Applications to Materials for Catalysis and Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01276</link>
      <description>Jacob M. Clary, Olivia Hull, Daniel Weinberg, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Mauro Del Ben, Derek Vigil&#8208;Fowler, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409424379

                Modeling complex materials using high-fidelity, ab initio methods at low cost is a fundamental goal for quantum chemical software packages. The GW approximation and random phase approximation (RPA) provide a unified description of both electronic structure and total energies using the same physics in a many-body perturbative approach that can be more accurate than generalized-gradient density functional theory (DFT) methods. However, GW/RPA implementations have historically been limited to either specific materials classes or application toward small chemical systems. The static subspace approximation allows for reduced cost full-frequency GW/RPA calculations and has previously been benchmarked thoroughly for GW calculations. Here, we describe our approach to including partial occupations of electronic orbitals in full-frequency GW and RPA calculations for the study of electrocatalysts. We benchmarked RPA total energy calculations using the subspace approximation across a diverse test suite of materials for a variety of computational parameters. The benchmarking quantifies the impact of different extrapolation procedures for representing the static polarizability at infinite screened cutoff, and shows that using screened cutoffs above 20-25 Ryd result in diminishing accuracy returns for predicting RPA total energies. Additionally, for moderately sized electrocatalytic models, 2-3 times fewer computational resources are used to compute RPA total energies by representing the static polarizability with 20-30% of the static subspace basis, with an error of approximately 0.01 eV or better in RPA adsorption energy calculations. Finally, we show that for these electrochemical models RPA can shift DFT adsorption energy shifts by up to 0.5 eV and that GW can frequently shift DFT eigenvalues of surface and adsorbate states by approximately 0.5-1 eV.</description>
      <author>Jacob M. Clary, Olivia Hull, Daniel Weinberg, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Mauro Del Ben, Derek Vigil&#8208;Fowler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Charge, Modulating the Catalytic Activity of Single-Atom Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17413</link>
      <description>Hansol Choi, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Geunsu Bae, Junsic Cho, Man Ho Han, Moulay Tahar Sougrati, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409425033

                Potential-induced electrode charging is a prerequisite to initiate electrochemical reactions at the electrode-electrolyte interface. The 'interface space charge' could dramatically alter the reaction environment and the charge density of the active site, both of which potentially affect the electrochemical activity. However, our understanding of the electrocatalytic role of space charge has been limited. Here, we separately modulate the amount of space charge (characterized by the areal density, &#963;) with maintaining the electrochemical potential for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at the same level, by exploiting the unique structural feature of MeNC. We reveal that changes in &#963; control the ORR activity, which is computationally explained by the inductive polarization of the charge density at the active sites, affecting their turnover rates. To guide catalyst design including the space charge effect, we develop a new descriptor, explaining the activity trend in various metal centers and pH conditions using a single volcano. These findings offer fresh insights into the role of space charge in electrocatalysis, providing a new framework for optimizing catalyst design and performance.</description>
      <author>Hansol Choi, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Geunsu Bae, Junsic Cho, Man Ho Han, Moulay Tahar Sougrati, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pt1Co1/CeO2 bimetallic single-atom catalyst with a strong Pt-Co synergistic effect for efficient oxidation of benzene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125369</link>
      <description>Siyi Ma, Chao Feng, Fang Dong, Shixing Wu, Weiliang Han, Weigao Han, Zhicheng Tang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409429227

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siyi Ma, Chao Feng, Fang Dong, Shixing Wu, Weiliang Han, Weigao Han, Zhicheng Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion with Cu&#8208;LDHs: A Review of Computational and Experimental Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202500014</link>
      <description>Fabio Loprete, Eleonora Tosi Brandi, Francesco Calcagno, Jacopo De Maron, Andrea Fasolini, Riccardo Tarroni, Francesco Basile, Ivan Rivalta, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409431547

                Abstract Layered Double Hydroxides (LDHs) are versatile materials with tuneable properties. They show promising electro&#8208; and photo&#8208;catalytic activity in the activation and conversion of CO 2 . Their unique properties make LDHs pivotal materials in emerging sustainable strategies for mitigating the effect of CO 2 emissions. However, the intricate structure&#8208;property relationship inherent to LDHs challenges their rational design. In this review, we provide a comprehensive overview of both experimental and computational studies about LDHs for photo&#8208; and electro&#8208;catalytic conversion of CO 2 , mainly focusing on Cu&#8208;based systems due to their superior performance in producing C 2 products. We present a background framework, describing the essentials computational and experimental tools, designed to support both experimentalists and theoreticians in the development of tailored LDH materials for efficient and sustainable CO 2 valorisation. Finally, we discuss future potential advancements, emphasizing the importance of new synergistic experimental&#8208;computational studies.</description>
      <author>Fabio Loprete, Eleonora Tosi Brandi, Francesco Calcagno, Jacopo De Maron, Andrea Fasolini, Riccardo Tarroni, Francesco Basile, Ivan Rivalta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202500014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the regulation strategy of active sites to explore the intrinsic mechanism over single&#8209;atom catalysts in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137595</link>
      <description>Wen Jiang, Qiang Xiao, Weidong Zhu, Fu&#8208;Min Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 693(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409434712

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Jiang, Qiang Xiao, Weidong Zhu, Fu&#8208;Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Pairwise Interaction for Extrapolative and Interpretable Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials with Physics-Informed Neural Network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00090</link>
      <description>Hoje Chun, Minjoon Hong, Seung Hyo Noh, Byungchan Han, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409438855

                Achieving both robust extrapolation and physical interpretability in machine learning interatomic potentials (ML-IPs) for atomistic simulation remains a significant challenge, particularly in data-scarce areas such as chemical reactions or complex, multicomponent materials at extreme conditions. Here, we present a pairwise-decomposed physics-informed neural network (P2Net) that parametrizes an analytical bond-order potential (BOP) layer to decouple the energy contributions of atomic pairs. By leveraging fundamental physical principles, P2Net demonstrates excellence at extrapolating beyond its training regime and accurately capturing molecular geometries far from equilibrium. The pairwise energy decomposition further empowers the bond analyses for deprotonation and SN2 reactions, which is not easy with most ML-IPs. The atomic pair energy offers how to elucidate the evolution of interatomic interactions as a reaction proceeds. Our methodology highlights enhanced data efficiency in building ML-IPs and facilitates more informative postsimulation analysis, thereby broadening the applicability of ML-IPs to complex and reactive systems.</description>
      <author>Hoje Chun, Minjoon Hong, Seung Hyo Noh, Byungchan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering bilayer GeSe/BiOI S-scheme heterojunction for solar-driven water-splitting hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.054</link>
      <description>Nianjun Luo, Wenyi Tang, Biao Wang, Hongkuan Yuan, Hong Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 127(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409441297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nianjun Luo, Wenyi Tang, Biao Wang, Hongkuan Yuan, Hong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold-modified nanoporous silicon for photoelectrochemical regulation of intracellular condensates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-025-01878-4</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Pengju Li, Jiping Yue, Lingyuan Meng, Wen Li, Chuan&#8208;Wang Yang, Saehyun Kim, Zhe Cheng, Asha Kamath, Samira Siahrostami, Bozhi Tian, Nature Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409443008

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Pengju Li, Jiping Yue, Lingyuan Meng, Wen Li, Chuan&#8208;Wang Yang, Saehyun Kim, Zhe Cheng, Asha Kamath, Samira Siahrostami, Bozhi Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-025-01878-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in green H2O2 production via metal-based functional materials: applications, strategies, and catalytic mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03285-z</link>
      <description>Danhua Jiao, Yongjun Li, Xiaodong Cai, Qizhao Wang, Yue Wang, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409448006

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Danhua Jiao, Yongjun Li, Xiaodong Cai, Qizhao Wang, Yue Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03285-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balsa Wood-Derived Carbon Enriched with Hydroxyl Functional Groups for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Sorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c00880</link>
      <description>Yuqing Meng, Manish Neupane, Drew M. Glenna, Asmita Jana, Wenhu Wang, Haiyan Zhao, Jin Qian, Yingchao Yang, Lu&#8208;Cun Wang, Seth W. Snyder, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409449693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuqing Meng, Manish Neupane, Drew M. Glenna, Asmita Jana, Wenhu Wang, Haiyan Zhao, Jin Qian, Yingchao Yang, Lu&#8208;Cun Wang, Seth W. Snyder</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c00880</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Time-Resolved X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy Unveils Partial Re-Oxidation of Tellurium Cluster for Prolonged Lifespan in Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00167</link>
      <description>Jiayin Yuan, Chang Long, Yu Zhang, Miao Zhang, Jian Chang, Yong&#8208;Lei Wang, Hao Zhang, Rongying Liu, Sadaf Saeedi Garakani, &#214;zlem U&#287;uz, Jiayin Yuan, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409449868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayin Yuan, Chang Long, Yu Zhang, Miao Zhang, Jian Chang, Yong&#8208;Lei Wang, Hao Zhang, Rongying Liu, Sadaf Saeedi Garakani, &#214;zlem U&#287;uz, Jiayin Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating hydrogen evolution catalyst discovery via data-driven strategy for high-performance single-atom catalysts embedded in h-BN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.04.002</link>
      <description>Hwanyeol Park, Dae&#8208;Myeong Geum, Ho Jun Kim, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409450188

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hwanyeol Park, Dae&#8208;Myeong Geum, Ho Jun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.04.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing nuclear quantum effects in electrocatalysis via a machine-learning enhanced grand canonical constant potential approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58871-7</link>
      <description>Menglin Sun, Bai-Qi Jin, Xiaolong Yang, Shenzhen Xu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409452381

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Menglin Sun, Bai-Qi Jin, Xiaolong Yang, Shenzhen Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58871-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction-driven formation of anisotropic strains in FeTeSe nanosheets boosts low-concentration nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58940-x</link>
      <description>Jiawei Liu, Yifan Xu, Ruihuan Duan, Mingsheng Zhang, Yue Hu, Mengxin Chen, Bo Han, Jinfeng Dong, Carmen Lee, L. S. R. Kumara, Okkyun Seo, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Takeshi Watanabe, Zheng Liu, Qiang Zhu, Jianwei Xu, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Dongshuang Wu, Qingyu Yan, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409453367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Liu, Yifan Xu, Ruihuan Duan, Mingsheng Zhang, Yue Hu, Mengxin Chen, Bo Han, Jinfeng Dong, Carmen Lee, L. S. R. Kumara, Okkyun Seo, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Takeshi Watanabe, Zheng Liu, Qiang Zhu, Jianwei Xu, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Dongshuang Wu, Qingyu Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58940-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Material Characteristics with System Properties for Membrane-Based Direct Air Capture (m-DAC) Using Process Operability and Inverse Design Approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04553</link>
      <description>Vitor Gama, Deepanjali Roy, Fernando V. Lima, Oishi Sanyal, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409324074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vitor Gama, Deepanjali Roy, Fernando V. Lima, Oishi Sanyal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of surface termination and tensile strain on the thermal conductivity of the Ti3C2Tx MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113890</link>
      <description>Jun Jiang, Hao Jin, Zhenzhen Xia, Yuting Zong, Jingwei Sun, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Computational Materials Science. 253(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409417078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Jiang, Hao Jin, Zhenzhen Xia, Yuting Zong, Jingwei Sun, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Investigation of the Influence of Rare Earth Element Doping on the Corrosion Characteristics of Mg (0001) surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417198</link>
      <description>Yuqi Gao, Guoning Bai, Hua Hou, Yuhong Zhao, Yongmei Zhang, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409424654

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuqi Gao, Guoning Bai, Hua Hou, Yuhong Zhao, Yongmei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417198</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
