<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 01:06:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrocatalytic hydrogen generation from water splitting with heterostructured MoS2/NiFe2O4 composite in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.042</link>
      <description>Noureen Amir Khan, Gul Rahman, Sang Youn Chae, Anwar ul Haq Ali Shah, Oh&#8208;Shim Joo, Shabeer Ahmad Mian, Akhtar Hussain, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396685920

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Noureen Amir Khan, Gul Rahman, Sang Youn Chae, Anwar ul Haq Ali Shah, Oh&#8208;Shim Joo, Shabeer Ahmad Mian, Akhtar Hussain</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant Induced Hollow Ni2P Nanocrystals Regulate Dehydrogenation Kinetics for Highly Efficient Solar-Driven Hydrazine Assisted H2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124165</link>
      <description>Umesh P. Suryawanshi, Uma V. Ghorpade, Priyank V. Kumar, Jun Sung Jang, Mingrui He, Hong Jae Shim, Hyo Rim Jung, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, Jihun Kim, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396690843

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Umesh P. Suryawanshi, Uma V. Ghorpade, Priyank V. Kumar, Jun Sung Jang, Mingrui He, Hong Jae Shim, Hyo Rim Jung, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, Jihun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moir&#233; fractional Chern insulators. I. First-principles calculations and continuum models of twisted bilayer &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;MoTe&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.205121</link>
      <description>Yujin Jia, Jong W. Yu, J. D. Liu, Jonah Herzog-Arbeitman, Ziyue Qi, Hanqi Pi, Nicolas Regnault, Hongming Weng, B. Andrei Bernevig, Quansheng Wu, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 109(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396692690

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujin Jia, Jong W. Yu, J. D. Liu, Jonah Herzog-Arbeitman, Ziyue Qi, Hanqi Pi, Nicolas Regnault, Hongming Weng, B. Andrei Bernevig, Quansheng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.205121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Stable Lithium Deposition Via Li3n-Enriched Inorganic Sei Induced by a Polycationic Polymer Layer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4819228</link>
      <description>Wenzhu Cao, Weimin Chen, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Tao Du, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396694075

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenzhu Cao, Weimin Chen, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Tao Du, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4819228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of transition metal-doped &#946;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; borophene as a new single-atom catalyst for carbon dioxide electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00601a</link>
      <description>Hongjie Huang, Ming&#8208;Yao Chen, Rongxin Zhang, Yuxuan Ding, Hong Huang, Zhangfeng Shen, Lingchang Jiang, Ge Zhang, Hongtao Jiang, Minhong Xu, Yangang Wang, Yongyong Cao, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396694578

                Among the 19 catalysts, Sc@&#946; 12 -BM and Y@&#946; 12 -BM were screened and easily reduced to C 1 products (CH 4 and CH 3 OH) and C 2 products (CH 3 CH 2 OH).</description>
      <author>Hongjie Huang, Ming&#8208;Yao Chen, Rongxin Zhang, Yuxuan Ding, Hong Huang, Zhangfeng Shen, Lingchang Jiang, Ge Zhang, Hongtao Jiang, Minhong Xu, Yangang Wang, Yongyong Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00601a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy Effects on Reactive Processes at Metal-Solvent Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06816</link>
      <description>Oskar Cheong, Fabian P. Tipp, Michael Eikerling, Piotr M. Kowalski, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396697785

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oskar Cheong, Fabian P. Tipp, Michael Eikerling, Piotr M. Kowalski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the heat treatment on structural and functional characteristics of the PtCu/C electrocatalysts on various carbon supports</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05920-8</link>
      <description>A. K. Nevelskaya, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Angelina Pavlets, V. S. Menshchikov, Ilya Pankov, A. V. Nikolskiy, A. T. Kozakov, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Journal of solid state electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396699496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. K. Nevelskaya, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Angelina Pavlets, V. S. Menshchikov, Ilya Pankov, A. V. Nikolskiy, A. T. Kozakov, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05920-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards non-blinking perovskite quantum dots</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4214840/v1</link>
      <description>Yitong Dong, Chenjia Mi, Gavin Gee, Chance Lander, Matthew Atteberry, Novruz G. Akhmedov, Lamia Hidayatova, Jesse DiCenso, Wai Tak Yip, Yihan Shao, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396699669

                Abstract Surface defect-induced photoluminescence blinking is ubiquitous in lead halide perovskite quantum dots (QDs). Despite efforts to passivate the defects on perovskite QDs by chemically engineering ligand binding moieties, blinking accompanied by photodegradation still poses barriers to studying and implementing quantum-confined perovskite QDs in quantum emitters. We posited that the intermolecular interaction between ligands can affect the QD surface passivation. In the solid state, steric repulsions among bulky ligand tails prevent adequate QD surface ligand coverage. Alternatively, attractive &#960;-&#960; stacking between low-steric phenethylammonium (PEA) ligands promotes the formation of a nearly epitaxial surface ligand layer. Here, we demonstrate that single CsPbBr3 QDs covered by these PEA ligands are nearly non-blinking, with single photon purity reaching 98%. Moreover, these QDs exhibited no spectral shifting and photodegradations, and they remained blinking-free after 12 hours of continuous operation. Free of interferences from blinking and photodegradation, we present size-dependent exciton radiative rates and emission line widths of single CsPbBr3 QDs ranging from strongly to weakly confined regimes.</description>
      <author>Yitong Dong, Chenjia Mi, Gavin Gee, Chance Lander, Matthew Atteberry, Novruz G. Akhmedov, Lamia Hidayatova, Jesse DiCenso, Wai Tak Yip, Yihan Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4214840/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-cluster anchored on PC6 monolayer as high-performance electrocatalyst for carbon dioxide reduction reaction: First principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.022</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Chenyin Li, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Journal of colloid and interface science. 669(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396702194

                Tremendous challenges remain to develop high-efficient catalysts for carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Chenyin Li, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the effect of solvent for hydrogen evolution in Pt-doped MXenes and corresponding high-entropy phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100808</link>
      <description>Zheng Shu, Zhangsheng Shi, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Teck Leong Tan, Yongqing Cai, Materials today sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396703787

                Effect of solvent at the water/solid interface plays a non-negligible role in chemical reactions. Explicit solvation has been proved for its important effect on thermodynamics and kinetics of catalytic reactions. However, systematic studies about this perspective are still absence. In this work, using the model of single platinum atom immobilized on the metal vacancies of a series of MXenes, we systematically investigate the implicit/explicit solvent effect on their catalytic performance of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). We find that the solvent effect plays a significant role in affecting the calculation results for some systems. For TiNbC-PtNb, the value of &#916;GH* decreases from -0.121 to -0.511 (-0.583) eV when considering implicit (explicit) correction, implying the decisive role of solvent effect for calculating HER in this system. Bader charge analysis and AIMD simulations reveal that TiNbC-PtNb surface is sensitive to H2O, thus causing this abnormal case. Surprisingly high-entropy phases of MXene overall are less sensitive to solvent compared to the pure phases, which could be due to their alloyed lattice with a strong ability against electronic and lattice fluctuations induced by solvent. Several systems like V2C-PtV, TiMoC-PtMo, and VNbC-PtV are predicted to be excellent electrocatalysts for alkaline HER with the appropriate Gibbs free energy of hydrogen adsorption and kinetic barrier of water. The perspective exemplified in this work highlights that more feasible operando should be considered, e.g., influence of water, to better simulate the reaction process. Our work suggests that Pt-doped MXenes are perfect systems for hosting atomic catalyst as well.</description>
      <author>Zheng Shu, Zhangsheng Shi, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Teck Leong Tan, Yongqing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100808</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascading symmetry constraint during machine learning-enabled structural search for sulfur-induced Cu(111)-(43&#215;43) surface reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0201421</link>
      <description>Florian Brix, Mads-Peter V. Christiansen, Bj&#248;rk Hammer, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396709157

                In this work, we investigate how exploiting symmetry when creating and modifying structural models may speed up global atomistic structure optimization. We propose a search strategy in which models start from high symmetry configurations and then gradually evolve into lower symmetry models. The algorithm is named cascading symmetry search and is shown to be highly efficient for a number of known surface reconstructions. We use our method for the sulfur-induced Cu (111) (43&#215;43) surface reconstruction for which we identify a new highly stable structure that conforms with the experimental evidence.</description>
      <author>Florian Brix, Mads-Peter V. Christiansen, Bj&#248;rk Hammer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0201421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolysis &#8211; Alkaline electrolyzer with anion-exchange membrane | Alkaline anion exchange membrane electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00241-3</link>
      <description>S. Ramakrishnan, Mohamed Mamlouk, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713567

                This chapter examines alkaline anion exchange membrane (AAEM) electrolysis, exploring both its advantages and challenges. A comprehensive overview of the fundamentals of water electrolyzers is provided. This is followed by a detailed discussion on the advantages and challenges faced by AEM electrolyzers in comparison to alkaline water electrolyzers (AWE) and proton exchange membrane electrolyzers (PEMWE). AEM chemistry and degradation mechanism was reviewed. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysis is discussed in terms of the activity descriptors, mechanism, and performance across a wide range of pH levels. Conclusion and recommendation were made on the advancement required in AEM water electrolyzers performance, durability and scale up challenges to enable rapid deployment and competitive green hydrogen production to meet global NetZero hydrogen ambitions.</description>
      <author>S. Ramakrishnan, Mohamed Mamlouk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00241-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Combined Density Functional Theory and Microkinetics Simulations Study of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction on Cu8/SnO2(110): The Crucial Role of Hydrogen Coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144409</link>
      <description>Zhaochun Liu, Roos Krosschell, Ivo A. W. Filot, Emiel J. M. Hensen, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396716198

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (eCO2R) is a promising approach for converting CO2 into valuable chemicals and fuels using renewable energy sources. We investigated the mechanism of eCO2R for a small Cu8 cluster placed on SnO2 containing O vacancies using density functional theory and predicted current density and selectivity by microkinetics simulations within the computational hydrogen electrode model. Low and high H coverages were modeled by Cu8/SnO2-x and Cu8H6/SnO2-x models, using statistical methods to identify their most stable structures. Different CO2 adsorption modes on Cu8/SnO2-x and Cu8H6/SnO2-x surface models, all containing an O vacancy, resulted in distinct reaction pathways, leading to either HCOOH or CO. The preferred formation of HCOOH occurred upon CO2 adsorption on an O vacancy on the Cu8H6/SnO2-x surface, followed by sequential hydrogenation to HCOO and HCOOH. Adsorption of CO2 on Cu8/SnO2-x opened a facile pathway to CO. Electronic structure analysis revealed that differences in charge donation of Cu to the antibonding orbitals of CO2 can explain the predicted selectivity differences. The preferred adsorption mode of CO2 is bidentate at the Cu-SnO2-x interface. Our findings emphasize the role of H coverage on Cu on the selectivity of eCO2R for Cu/SnOx catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhaochun Liu, Roos Krosschell, Ivo A. W. Filot, Emiel J. M. Hensen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derived Trends of the Oxygen Adsorption Energy Using the Simplistic Model of the Thermodynamic Potential for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821664</link>
      <description>Isabela C. Man, Ionut Tranc&#259;, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396718825

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Isabela C. Man, Ionut Tranc&#259;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Polar Bridging Molecules on the Photoelectrocatalytic Hydrogen Production from Perylene Diimide Network Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821599</link>
      <description>Weixing Nie, Mengnan Ruan, Ying Zhang, Yuxin Sun, Ke Ruan, Xiaowei Liu, Zhifeng Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396718887

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weixing Nie, Mengnan Ruan, Ying Zhang, Yuxin Sun, Ke Ruan, Xiaowei Liu, Zhifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured High Entropy Alloys as Structural and Functional Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03435</link>
      <description>Wenqing Zhu, Xiang Gao, Yiyu Yao, Shikai Hu, Zhixin Li, Yan Teng, Hang Wang, Hui Gong, Zhaoqi Chen, Yong Yang, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720590

                Since their introduction in 2004, high entropy alloys (HEAs) have attracted significant attention due to their exceptional mechanical and functional properties. Advances in our understanding of atomic-scale ordering and phase formation in HEAs have facilitated the development of fabrication techniques for synthesizing nanostructured HEAs. These materials hold immense potential for applications in various fields including automobile industries, aerospace engineering, microelectronics, and clean energy, where they serve as either structural or functional materials. In this comprehensive Review, we conduct an in-depth analysis of the mechanical and functional properties of nanostructured HEAs, with a particular emphasis on the roles of different nanostructures in modulating these properties. To begin, we explore the intrinsic and extrinsic factors that influence the formation and stability of nanostructures in HEAs. Subsequently, we delve into an examination of the mechanical and electrocatalytic properties exhibited by bulk or three-dimensional (3D) nanostructured HEAs, as well as nanosized HEAs in the form of zero-dimensional (0D) nanoparticles, one-dimensional (1D) nanowires, or two-dimensional (2D) nanosheets. Finally, we present an outlook on the current research landscape, highlighting the challenges and opportunities associated with nanostructure design and the understanding of structure-property relationships in nanostructured HEAs.</description>
      <author>Wenqing Zhu, Xiang Gao, Yiyu Yao, Shikai Hu, Zhixin Li, Yan Teng, Hang Wang, Hui Gong, Zhaoqi Chen, Yong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First-Principles and Machine Learning Study on Design of Graphitic Carbon Nitride-Based Single-Atom Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01412</link>
      <description>F.-Q. Chen, Yongan Yang, Xing Chen, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720626

                Photocatalytic nitrogen fixation offers an efficient, environmentally friendly, and energy-saving approach for ammonia synthesis. In this study, semiconductor materials, particularly graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) combined with single metal atoms, were theoretically investigated to identify promising candidates as nitrogen fixation photocatalysts. Initially, six different single 3d transition-metal atoms, i.e., V, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, and Cu, were loaded onto g-C3N4, and the optimal single-atom catalyst, Fe@g-C3N4, was selected through reaction energy calculations. This catalyst demonstrated excellent performance in terms of the electronic structure and light absorption properties. Furthermore, machine learning methods were applied to a limited sample set to predict a catalyst with a superior performance beyond the computational samples. Utilizing a backward elimination method and sure independence screening and sparsifying operator (SISSO) training, the key descriptors correlated with the target properties of the catalysts were identified. The SISSO descriptors, consisting of structural and electronic characteristic parameters, are interpretable and provide meaningful insights. Importantly, a catalyst, Ru@g-C3N4, with outstanding performance was predicted and verified by density functional theory calculations. This catalyst design strategy demonstrates promising results with limited computational data, highlighting the potential of combining theoretical simulations with machine learning methods for catalyst design.</description>
      <author>F.-Q. Chen, Yongan Yang, Xing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent developments of single atom alloy catalysts for electrocatalytic hydrogenation reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152072</link>
      <description>Zehua Jin, Yuting Xu, Manjeet Chhetri, Joseph Wood, Brian Torreon, Fanglin Che, Ming Yang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721231

                This review discusses the recent developments of single-atom alloy (SAA) catalysts toward CO2, CO, N2, and NO3&#8211; hydrogenation reactions in the electrocatalysis context, a natural expansion from the thermal catalysis origin where the concept of SAA was born and validated. Electrocatalytic hydrogenations of CO2, CO, NO3&#8211;, and N2 into value-added chemicals offer an attractive general route to mitigate greenhouse gas emissions using renewable energy without H2 feed stream. These reactions typically involve multiple electron-transfer-coupled elementary reaction steps that are of broad relevance to many electrocatalytic applications, making them well-positioned for translational fundamental studies relevant to other emerging electrochemical reactions. While there has been exciting progress in SAA research for various thermal catalytic reactions in the last decade, the design, application, and characterization of SAA catalysts in electrocatalysis remain nascent with intriguing uncertainties and ample opportunities. We highlight the recent research findings in this growing area, where the SAAs, owing to their unique doped metal properties and atomically precise bimetallic synergies, promote selective reaction pathways by tuning binding energies and distributions of adsorbates/intermediates. We also provide our perspective on this growing research area's potential challenges and opportunities.</description>
      <author>Zehua Jin, Yuting Xu, Manjeet Chhetri, Joseph Wood, Brian Torreon, Fanglin Che, Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Active Site and Predicting the Overall Activity of Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01542</link>
      <description>Quan Zhou, Hongwei Shou, Sicong Qiao, Yong Cao, Pengjun Zhang, Shiqiang Wei, Shuangming Chen, Xiaojun Wu, Song Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721746

                As one of the potential catalysts, disordered solid solution alloys can offer a wealth of catalytic sites. However, accurately evaluating their activity localization structure and overall activity from each individual site remains a formidable challenge. Herein, an approach based on density functional theory and machine learning was used to obtain a large number of sites of the Pt-Ru alloy as the model multisite catalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Subsequently, a series of statistical approaches were employed to unveil the relationship between the geometric structure and overall activity. Based on the radial frequency distribution of metal elements and the distribution of &#916;</description>
      <author>Quan Zhou, Hongwei Shou, Sicong Qiao, Yong Cao, Pengjun Zhang, Shiqiang Wei, Shuangming Chen, Xiaojun Wu, Song Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Type Active Sites Grown on Fe-Doped Ni Core Surfaces during the Initial Oxygen Evolution Reactions: Fe-Doping Effect?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08462</link>
      <description>Sung Soo Lim, Chang Weon Choi, Arumugam Sivanantham, Sangaraju Shanmugam, Yves Lansac, Yun Hee Jang, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sung Soo Lim, Chang Weon Choi, Arumugam Sivanantham, Sangaraju Shanmugam, Yves Lansac, Yun Hee Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron-incorporated IrO2-Ta2O5 coating as an efficient electrocatalyst for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152040</link>
      <description>Qikai Huang, Shaojie Zhuang, Yuexi Zheng, Xuerong Peng, Zhiguo Ye, Duosheng Li, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396722006

                The Ir-based electrocatalysts for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) have demonstrated remarkable durability. Enhancing the Ir-based electrocatalytic activity still remains crucial owing to the scarcity of iridium. Here, a high-temperature sintering technique is employed to fabricate a boron (B)-incorporated IrO2-Ta2O5 coating with an almost perfect rutile-type crystal structure on a corrosion-resistant titanium substrate, ensuring exceptional stability for the acidic OER. The B-incorporated IrO2-Ta2O5 electrode fabricated in a mixed solution of 0.6 M H3BO3, exhibits an overpotential of 210 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a lower Tafel slope of 34.2 mV dec&#8722;1 in a 0.5 M H2SO4 solution, which is far lower than the 272 mV overpotential and the 45.3 mV dec&#8722;1 of the IrO2-Ta2O5/Ti electrode. The electrode possesses a minimal potential increase even after undergoing continuous OER for 400 h at a high current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in a 0.5 M H2SO4 solution. The incorporation of B species into IrO2-Ta2O5 effectively fine-tunes the electronic structure of Ir active sites, leading to a substantial enhancement of the intrinsic electrocatalytic activity. This study provides promising prospects for reducing the energy consumption of noble IrO2-based electrocatalysts in the practical application of electrochemical industry for the acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Qikai Huang, Shaojie Zhuang, Yuexi Zheng, Xuerong Peng, Zhiguo Ye, Duosheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics for Catalysis Predictions: Are We Ready Yet?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05285</link>
      <description>Difan Zhang, Brett Smith, Haiyi Wu, Manh&#8208;Thuong Nguyen, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki Alexandra Glezakou, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396729186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Difan Zhang, Brett Smith, Haiyi Wu, Manh&#8208;Thuong Nguyen, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki Alexandra Glezakou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-field determination of NaSICON materials in the quaternary system Na2O-P2O5-SiO2-ZrO2: II. Glass-ceramics and the phantom of excessive vacancy formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxener.2024.100130</link>
      <description>Enkhtsetseg Dashjav, Marie-Theres Gerhards, F. Klein, Daniel Gr&#252;ner, Thomas C. Hansen, Jochen Rohrer, Karsten Albe, Dina Fattakhova&#8208;Rohlfing, Frank Tietz, Next energy. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396742744

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enkhtsetseg Dashjav, Marie-Theres Gerhards, F. Klein, Daniel Gr&#252;ner, Thomas C. Hansen, Jochen Rohrer, Karsten Albe, Dina Fattakhova&#8208;Rohlfing, Frank Tietz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxener.2024.100130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding the Kinetic Complexity of Pt-Catalyzed &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;-Butane Dehydrogenation by Machine Learning and Microkinetic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00864</link>
      <description>Hu Yong, Cheng Gong, Ming Lei, Meng-Su Yang, De Chen, Xinggui Zhou, Yi&#8208;An Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396746891

                n-Butane dehydrogenation to butene and butadiene has recently gained increasing attention owing to the exploitation and development of shale gas as well as the rapid growth in the demand for synthetic rubber worldwide. In this work, the full n-butane dehydrogenation reaction network involving 568 elementary steps on Pt is established by using a chemical informatics approach to loop over all of the atoms and chemical bonds in n-butane. By combining density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the Morgan molecular fingerprint method, and machine learning techniques, we have identified 208 elementary steps that contribute to the kinetically important reaction network, which presents some general guidelines for the formulation of mechanisms of great complexity. A detailed microkinetic analysis that ensures thermodynamic consistency is then performed, without and with the presence of H2 cofeeding, to assess the n-butane catalytic activity and butene selectivity. It turns out that in the absence of H2, the high coverages of the coke precursors give rise to a low catalytic activity due to the occupancy of a large number of active sites. The turnover frequencies for n-butane consumption and butene production rise rapidly as the H2/n-C4H10 ratio goes up from 0 to 1.33. Meanwhile, the selectivity toward 1-butene increases as well, whereas the selectivities toward 2-butene and 1,3-butadiene are not sensitive to the H2 partial pressure. The flux analysis reveals that the dominant reaction pathways for 1-butene and 2-butene follow the reverse Horiuti&#8211;Polanyi mechanism, and the byproducts are formed primarily by the C&#8211;C bond cleavage in CH3CCHC*. The C&#8211;H bond activation in n-butane is identified by the sensitivity analysis as the rate-limiting step for the overall reaction while the selectivities toward butenes are found to be controlled dominantly by the ease with which n-butane can be activated and how readily butenes can be deeply dehydrogenated.</description>
      <author>Hu Yong, Cheng Gong, Ming Lei, Meng-Su Yang, De Chen, Xinggui Zhou, Yi&#8208;An Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Assisted Study of REN&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;6&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-Doped Graphene as Potential Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Electrode Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00803</link>
      <description>Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Chao He, Daomiao Wang, Meiling Liu, Chao Liu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747083

                In the application of renewable energy, the oxidation&#8211;reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are two crucial reactions. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) based on metal-doped graphene have been widely employed due to their high activity and high atom utilization efficiency. However, the catalytic activity is significantly influenced by different metals and local coordination, making it challenging to efficiently screen through either experimental or density functional theory (DFT) calculations. To address this issue, this study employed a combination of DFT calculations and machine learning (DFT-ML) to investigate rare earth-modified carbon-based (RENxC6&#8211;x) electrocatalysts. Based on computational data from 75 catalysts, we trained two ML models to capture the underlying patterns of physical properties and overpotential. Subsequently, the candidate catalysts were screened, leading to the discovery of four ORR catalysts, nine OER catalysts, and five bifunctional electrocatalysts, all of which were thoroughly validated for their stability. Lastly, by integrating the ML models with the SHAP analysis framework, we revealed the influence of atomic radius, Pauling electronegativity, and other features on the catalytic activity. Additionally, we analyzed the physicochemical properties of potential catalysts through DFT calculations. The revolutionary DFT-ML approach provides a crucial driving force for the design and synthesis of potential catalysts in subsequent studies.</description>
      <author>Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Chao He, Daomiao Wang, Meiling Liu, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bell-Evans-Polanyi relation for hydrogen evolution reaction from first-principles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01244-3</link>
      <description>Timothy Yang, Wissam A. Saidi, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396748101

                Abstract The versatile Bell-Evans-Polanyi (BEP) relation stipulates the kinetics of a reaction in terms of thermodynamics. Herein, we establish the BEP relation for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) from fundamental electrochemical principles leveraging the Butler-Volmer relation for a one-step, one-electron process and the transition state theory. Based on first-principles investigations of HER mechanisms on fourteen metal electrodes, we firmly justify the BEP relation solely using an easy-to compute hydrogen adsorption free energy and universal electrochemical constants.</description>
      <author>Timothy Yang, Wissam A. Saidi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01244-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biologically templated formation of Cobalt-Phosphide-Graphene hybrids with charge redistribution for efficient hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.047</link>
      <description>Xingchen Zhou, Lanqian Gong, Chen Wu, Yanfang Peng, Bin Cao, Huan Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Xueliang Jiang, Bao Yu Xia, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760234

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingchen Zhou, Lanqian Gong, Chen Wu, Yanfang Peng, Bin Cao, Huan Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Xueliang Jiang, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical research on efficient electrocatalysis of CO2 reduction reaction by borophene loaded transition metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104454</link>
      <description>Meiling Liu, Rao Fu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meiling Liu, Rao Fu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Active Sites In Situ Formed in Metal Nanoparticle Reshaping under Reaction Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00088</link>
      <description>Xiao Yan Li, Pengfei Ou, Xinyi Duan, Ying Liu, Jun Meng, Beien Zhu, Yi Gao, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396764064

                Understanding the nonequilibrium transformation of nanocatalysts under reaction conditions is important because metastable atomic structures may be created during the process, which offers unique activities in reactions. Although reshaping of metal nanoparticles (NPs) under reaction conditions has been widely recognized, the dynamic reshaping process has been less studied at the atomic scale. Here, we develop an atomistic kinetic Monte Carlo model to simulate the complete reshaping process of Pt nanoparticles in a CO environment and reveal the in situ formation of atomic clusters on the NP surface, a new type of active site beyond conventional understanding, boosting the reactivities in the CO oxidation reaction. Interestingly, highly active peninsula and inactive island clusters both form on the (111) facets and interchange in varying states of dynamic equilibrium, which influences the catalytic activities significantly. This study provides new fundamental knowledge of nanocatalysis and new guidance for the rational design of nanocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiao Yan Li, Pengfei Ou, Xinyi Duan, Ying Liu, Jun Meng, Beien Zhu, Yi Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Co3O4-Based Hybrid Structures for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-024-00183-5</link>
      <description>Ha Huu, Quyet Van Le, Hai Bang Truong, Korean journal of chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396765408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ha Huu, Quyet Van Le, Hai Bang Truong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-024-00183-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Gold Precipitation by a Tertiary Diamide Driven by Thermodynamic Control</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01279</link>
      <description>Susanna S. M. Vance, Mateusz Mojsak, Luke M. M. Kinsman, Rebecca Rae, Caroline Kirk, Jason B. Love, Carole A. Morrison, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396767472

                The simple diamide ligand</description>
      <author>Susanna S. M. Vance, Mateusz Mojsak, Luke M. M. Kinsman, Rebecca Rae, Caroline Kirk, Jason B. Love, Carole A. Morrison</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming poisoning issues in hydrogen fuel cells with face-centered tetragonal FePt bimetallic catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.04.036</link>
      <description>Daeil Choi, Injoon Jang, Taekyung Lee, Yun Sik Kang, Sung Jong Yoo, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396767948

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daeil Choi, Injoon Jang, Taekyung Lee, Yun Sik Kang, Sung Jong Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.04.036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ion Exchange in Metal-Organic Frameworks and Their Derivatives: A Facile Strategy for Enhanced Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101595</link>
      <description>Haoran Li, Xin Li, Dai Jiayan, Shiyou Zheng, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396768176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoran Li, Xin Li, Dai Jiayan, Shiyou Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas-Phase Production of Hydroxylated Silicon Oxide Cluster Cations: Structure, Infrared Spectroscopy, and Astronomical Relevance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsearthspacechem.3c00346</link>
      <description>Andrea Donato, Bianca-Andreea Ghejan, Joost M. Bakker, Thorsten M. Bernhardt, Stefan T. Bromley, Sandra M. Lang, ACS earth and space chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396773745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrea Donato, Bianca-Andreea Ghejan, Joost M. Bakker, Thorsten M. Bernhardt, Stefan T. Bromley, Sandra M. Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsearthspacechem.3c00346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical Prior Mean Function-Driven Gaussian Processes Search for Minimum-Energy Reaction Paths with a Climbing-Image Nudged Elastic Band: A General Method for Gas-Phase, Interfacial, and Bulk-Phase Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00291</link>
      <description>Chong Teng, Yan Wang, Junwei Lucas Bao, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396773889

                The climbing-image nudged elastic band (CI-NEB) method serves as an indispensable tool for computational chemists, offering insight into minimum-energy reaction paths (MEPs) by delineating both transition states (TSs) and intermediate nonstationary structures along reaction coordinates. However, executing CI-NEB calculations for reactions with extensive reaction coordinate spans necessitates a large number of images to ensure a reliable convergence of the MEPs and TS structures, presenting a computationally demanding optimization challenge, even with mildly costly electronic-structure methods. In this study, we advocate for the utilization of physically inspired prior mean function-based Gaussian processes (GPs) to expedite MEP exploration and TS optimization via the CI-NEB method. By incorporating reliable prior physical approximations into potential energy surface (PES) modeling, we demonstrate enhanced efficiency in multidimensional CI-NEB optimization with surrogate-based optimizers. Our physically informed GP approach not only outperforms traditional nonsurrogate-based optimizers in optimization efficiency but also on-the-fly learns the reaction path valley during optimization, culminating in significant advancements. The surrogate PES derived from our optimization exhibits high accuracy compared to true PES references, aligning with our emphasis on leveraging reliable physical priors for robust and efficient posterior mean learning in GPs. Through a systematic benchmark study encompassing various reaction pathways, including gas-phase, bulk-phase, and interfacial/surface reactions, our physical GPs consistently demonstrate superior efficiency and reliability. For instance, they outperform the popular fast inertial relaxation engine optimizer by approximately a factor of 10, showcasing their versatility and efficacy in exploring reaction mechanisms and surface reaction PESs.</description>
      <author>Chong Teng, Yan Wang, Junwei Lucas Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Insights on Structural Sensitivity of Cobalt in NO Electroreduction to Ammonia and Hydroxylamine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01986</link>
      <description>Pengran Guo, Dong Luan, Huan Li, Lin Liu, Shaoxue Yang, Jianping Xiao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780897

                It has been reported that it was selective to produce ammonia on metallic cobalt in the electrocatalytic nitric oxide reduction reaction (eNORR), where hexagonal close-packed (hcp) cobalt outperforms face-centered cubic (fcc) cobalt. However, hydroxylamine is more selectively produced on a cobalt single-atom catalyst (Co-SAC). Herein, we uncover the structural sensitivity over hcp-Co, fcc-Co, and Co-SAC in eNORR by employing a recently developed constant potential simulation method and microkinetic modeling. It was found that the superior activity for ammonia production on hcp-Co can be attributed to its facile electron and proton transfer and a stronger lateral suppression effect from NO* over fcc-Co. The exceptional hydroxylamine selectivity on Co-SAC is due to the modified electronic structure, namely, a positively charged active center. It was found that it is more favorable to produce NOH* over hcp-Co and fcc-Co, while HNO* is more preferable on Co-SAC, which are firmly correlated with the vertical and strong NO adsorption on the former and the moderate adsorption on the latter. In other words, a key factor for selectivity control is the first step of NO* protonation. Therefore, the local structure and electronic structure of the catalysts can be critical in regulating the activity and selectivity in eNORR.</description>
      <author>Pengran Guo, Dong Luan, Huan Li, Lin Liu, Shaoxue Yang, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in tandem electrocatalysis of carbon dioxide: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114516</link>
      <description>Jiateng Chen, Liang Xu, Boxiong Shen, Renewable &amp; sustainable energy reviews. 199(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396785483

                The attainment of carbon neutrality has become a global consensus as a result of the increasing environmental problems caused by the consumption of fossil fuels. To achieve this objective, there has been widespread attention towards the electrocatalytic reduction reaction of carbon dioxide driven by renewable energy sources due to its mild reaction conditions. In recent years, generating high value-added multicarbon products has been the focus of considerable research efforts. However, the process of generating these products has been restricted by the complexity of the reaction path, the limitations of the scaling relationship, and the poor adaptability to the reaction environment, thereby impeding previous studies from achieving efficient conversion at high current densities. As a result, a more suitable catalyst design strategy is required to obtain high value-added products. This study proposes that the design approach of tandem catalysis will be effective in generating multicarbon products by exploring the mechanism of C&#8211;C bond coupling and the configuration of the reaction environment. This research summaries the mechanism and design requirements of tandem catalysis scaled by different intermediates transport distances and review strategies of tandem catalyst configurations, such as nanostructures, phase-mixed, phase-separated, and application of special supports, in facilitating the generation of multicarbon products. The study provides suggestions for the design of CO2 electrocatalytic tandem catalysts and conclude with a discussion of possible future directions.</description>
      <author>Jiateng Chen, Liang Xu, Boxiong Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of chalcogen doping in Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts for hydrogen-air polymer electrolyte fuel cells: Selenium doped Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234612</link>
      <description>S&#322;awomir Dyjak, Wojciech Tokarz, A. B&#322;achowski, Mateusz Gratzke, Barbara Szcz&#281;&#347;niak, Kamil Sobczak, Wojciech Kici&#324;ski, Journal of power sources. 609(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396791589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S&#322;awomir Dyjak, Wojciech Tokarz, A. B&#322;achowski, Mateusz Gratzke, Barbara Szcz&#281;&#347;niak, Kamil Sobczak, Wojciech Kici&#324;ski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ion solvation free energy calculations based on first-principles molecular dynamics thermodynamic integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0191068</link>
      <description>Chao Lin, Xiaojun He, Cong Xi, Qianfan Zhang, Lin&#8208;Wang Wang, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803459

                Numerous electrochemistry reactions require the precise calculation of the ion solvation energy. Despite the significant progress in the first-principles calculations for crystals and defect formation energies for solids, the liquid system free energy calculations still face many challenges. Ion solvation free energies can be calculated via different semiempirical ways, e.g., using implicit solvent models or cluster of explicit molecule models; however, systematically improving these models is difficult due to their lack of a solid theoretical base. A theoretically sound approach for calculating the free energy is to use thermodynamic integration. Nevertheless, owing to the difficulties of self-consistent convergence in first-principles calculations for unphysical atomic configurations, the computational alchemy approach has not been widely used for first-principles calculations. This study proposes a general approach to use first-principles computational alchemy for calculating the ion solvation energy. This approach is also applicable for other small molecules. The calculated ion solvation free energies for Li+, Na+, K+, Be2+, Mg2+, and Ca2+ are close to the experimental results, and the standard deviation due to molecular dynamics fluctuations is within 0.06 eV.</description>
      <author>Chao Lin, Xiaojun He, Cong Xi, Qianfan Zhang, Lin&#8208;Wang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0191068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe Based Mof Encapsulating [Co(En)3]3+ to Prepare Fen3-Con3 Dual-Atom Catalyst for Efficient Orr in Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823403</link>
      <description>Xiaopeng Zhang, Cheng Gao, Longzhu Li, Xiaoming Yan, Ning Zhang, Junjiang Bao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaopeng Zhang, Cheng Gao, Longzhu Li, Xiaoming Yan, Ning Zhang, Junjiang Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Via Partial Oxidation of Re Through Co Modification in Nanoalloy Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823406</link>
      <description>An Jiang, Chao Chen, Jiwen Feng, Qiang Li, Wei Liu, Mingdong Dong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396804020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>An Jiang, Chao Chen, Jiwen Feng, Qiang Li, Wei Liu, Mingdong Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic exploration of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</link>
      <description>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng, Computational and theoretical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396807019

                The reaction rate of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an important factor restricting its application. In this work, we have systematic explorated of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for ORR and OER. Firstly, a variety of stability analysis methods show that most of the catalysts have excellent stability. Secondly, a series of excellent bifunctional catalysts are screened by volcanic maps, ORR overpotential (&#951;ORR), OER overpotential (&#951;OER), and bifunctional index (BI), such as, RhN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.28 V, &#951;OER = 0.34 V, BI = 0.62 V) and CoN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.33 V, &#951;OER = 0.37 V, BI = 0.70 V). In particular, RhN3O1-1 has the smallest BI value, indicating that it has the best bifunctional catalytic activity. This study offers insights into how the coordination environment affects the activity of OER/ORR.</description>
      <author>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#28023;&#32966;&#29366;CoTe-CoP&#24322;&#36136;&#32467;&#26500;&#20652;&#21270;&#21058;&#22312;&#20840;pH&#33539;&#22260;&#20869;&#39640;&#25928;&#26512;&#27682;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2820-0</link>
      <description>Shengli Zhu, Minghui Xing, Zhe L&#252;, Zelong Qiao, Shitao Wang, Qianchuan Zhao, Yu Zhang, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao, Science China. Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834143

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengli Zhu, Minghui Xing, Zhe L&#252;, Zelong Qiao, Shitao Wang, Qianchuan Zhao, Yu Zhang, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2820-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of transition metal atom-doped NiSe2 electrocatalysts for efficient alkaline hydrogen precipitation using first principles screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141324</link>
      <description>Yangyang Xu, Yiwei Zhao, Yuanjiang Lv, Xinmeng Er, Mingxia Liu, Fei Ma, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834534

                Transition metal (TM) doping exhibits great potential in designing high-performance two-dimensional (2D) NiSe2-based catalysts for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). 22 TM atom-doped 2D-NiSe2 catalysts are screened, and the effects of TM doping on the thermal stability and HER catalytic activity are investigated by first-principles calculations. Among them, Cu doped 2D-NiSe2 might exhibit remarkable HER properties with the water dissociation energy of 1.03 eV and H adsorption Gibbs free energy of &#8722;0.05 eV. Furthermore, we elucidate the reasons behind the different HER activities. These findings suggest new possibilities for the application of Cu doped 2D-NiSe2 for alkaline HER, offering new perspectives for future research.</description>
      <author>Yangyang Xu, Yiwei Zhao, Yuanjiang Lv, Xinmeng Er, Mingxia Liu, Fei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretical Benchmark of the Geometric and Optical Properties for 3d Transition Metal Nanoclusters via Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00408</link>
      <description>Shana Havenridge, Cong Liu, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A/&#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835391

                Understanding structure&#8211;property relationships in atomically precise metal nanoclusters is vital in finding selective and tunable catalysts. In this study, density functional theory (DFT) was used to benchmark seven exchange correlation functionals at different basis sets for 17 atomically precise nanoclusters against experimentally determined geometries, band gaps, and optical gaps. The set contains both monometallic and bimetallic clusters that possess at least two types of 3d transition metals (specifically, Cu, Ni, Fe, or Co). The benchmark highlights that PBE0 is a good functional to use regardless of the basis set, and Minnesota functionals do well with respect to specific metals. Further, while long-range corrected functionals overestimate band and optical gaps, they model absorption features better than the other considered functionals. The study additionally looks at the photoinduced hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the CO2 reduction mechanism on nanoclusters reported from the literature.</description>
      <author>Shana Havenridge, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into effect of dopant site and dopant concentration on structural, electronic and optical properties of GaNbO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1237" altimg="si56.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; and its implications on visible light photocatalytic behavior: An ab-initio study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cocom.2024.e00916</link>
      <description>Bhakti Kshirsagar, Ankosh D. Deshmukh, David Mascarenhas, Vaishali Shah, Computational condensed matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bhakti Kshirsagar, Ankosh D. Deshmukh, David Mascarenhas, Vaishali Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cocom.2024.e00916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Simulation, and Membrane Wetting Estimation in Gas&#8211;Liquid Contacting Processes Including Shell-Side Reaction: Biogas Upgrading Using DEA Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00525</link>
      <description>G. Pantoleontos, Dimitrios Koutsonikolas, Akrivi Asimakopoulou, &#931;&#959;&#965;&#950;&#940;&#957;&#945; &#923;&#959;&#961;&#941;&#957;&#964;&#950;&#959;&#965;, George Karagiannakis, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396771432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. Pantoleontos, Dimitrios Koutsonikolas, Akrivi Asimakopoulou, &#931;&#959;&#965;&#950;&#940;&#957;&#945; &#923;&#959;&#961;&#941;&#957;&#964;&#950;&#959;&#965;, George Karagiannakis</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An overview of technologies for Capturing, Storing, and utilizing carbon Dioxide: Technology Readiness, large-scale Demonstration, and cost</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151998</link>
      <description>Divya Baskaran, P. Saravanan, Loganathan Nagarajan, Hun&#8208;Soo Byun, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396690643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Divya Baskaran, P. Saravanan, Loganathan Nagarajan, Hun&#8208;Soo Byun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151998</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering of polydisperse porous media for enhanced fluid flows through systematic topology tuning via differentiable direct numerical simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevfluids.9.054103</link>
      <description>Mohammed Alhashim, Michael P. Brenner, Physical review fluids. 9(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396813474

                Recent advancements in automatic differentiation, which played a pivotal role in deep learning, offer a promising approach to addressing challenges in controlling fluid flow behavior. We demonstrate the power of the method by optimizing the packing of a polydisperse system of periodically arranged circular rods to minimize the pressure drop across the media. We show how the optimum topology of the porous media changes with changing the packing fraction.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Alhashim, Michael P. Brenner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevfluids.9.054103</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
