<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 01:41:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Potency of Boron Doping on Graphene Nanoclusters as Catalysts for CO Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202500613</link>
      <description>Arikasuci Fitonna Ridassepri, Yutaro Umejima, Shota Sato, I Gusti Made Sanjaya, Nur Hayati, Samik Samik, Jun Nakamura, ChemistrySelect. 10(25)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411724277

                Abstract Graphene materials exhibit significant potential as electrocatalysts for the CO reduction reaction (CORR), a crucial process for mitigating greenhouse gas emissions. This study investigates the impact of boron (B) doping on the catalytic performance of graphene nanoclusters (GNCs) for CORR using density functional theory (DFT). Pristine GNC (C 54 H 18 ) and B&#8208;doped GNC (C 53 H 18 B) were examined through the computational hydrogen electrode (CHE) model. The results demonstrate that B doping slightly enhances adsorption energy, with C 53 H 18 B exhibiting higher adsorption energy (&#8722;2.40 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 eV) than C 54 H 18 (&#8722;0.79 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 eV), indicating a modest improvement in interaction strength, which is attributed to the electron&#8208;deficient sites introduced by the B atom, which strengthen CO&#8208;surface interactions, as evidenced by a shorter distance of 3.62 &#197; in C 53 H 18 B compared to 3.92 &#197; in C 54 H 18 . Free energy diagrams for both models reveal that methanol formation follows the same pathway: *CO &#8594; *CHO &#8594; *CH 2 O&#8594; *OCH 3 &#8594;CH 3 OH. Notably, the overpotential required for spontaneous reaction is significantly lower for B&#8208;GNC (0.89 V) than for the pristine GNC (1.50 V), indicating that B doping effectively enhances the electrocatalytic activity of GNCs for CORR. These findings highlight that B&#8208;GNC is a promising candidate for metal&#8208;free electrocatalysts with improved performance for sustainable COR applications.</description>
      <author>Arikasuci Fitonna Ridassepri, Yutaro Umejima, Shota Sato, I Gusti Made Sanjaya, Nur Hayati, Samik Samik, Jun Nakamura</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202500613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multivalence Driven High-Entropy Bimetallic Oxides for Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c05602</link>
      <description>Xianbing Miao, Liang Wu, Sheng Zhao, J.H. Zhang, Zi&#8208;Jiang Liu, Shiming Zhou, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411736224

                High-entropy materials have recently attracted much attention in diverse fields due to their tailorable compositions and unpredictable physicochemical properties. Generally, five or more metal elements occupying the same lattice sites in similar proportions are considered as a prerequisite for achieving high configuration entropy. Here we report an uncommon type of such material in V-doped RuO2, where the number of metal elements is reduced to only two. Both Ru and V ions are found in mixed oxidation states, which endow the bimetallic oxides with five different cations. Each of these cations behaves as an individual species to contribute to the configuration entropy, which is high enough to stabilize the single phase near the half-doping level. The large ionic disorder in this high-entropy oxide leads to lattice distortion, grain refining, and an evolution from metal to semiconductor, making it a superior electrochemical catalyst toward acidic water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Xianbing Miao, Liang Wu, Sheng Zhao, J.H. Zhang, Zi&#8208;Jiang Liu, Shiming Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c05602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Machine Learning-Assisted Evaluation of NHC-Functionalized C2N with Transition Metals for Efficient CO Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146778</link>
      <description>Jiasheng Peng, Daifei Ye, Yingying Fu, Dian Zheng, Xiaxia Gong, Wei Liu, Jing Xu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411736604

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiasheng Peng, Daifei Ye, Yingying Fu, Dian Zheng, Xiaxia Gong, Wei Liu, Jing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing photocatalytic H2O2 rate over 100 mM&#183;g-1&#183;h-1 under air atmosphere on C3N5-based isotype heterojunction surface via simply altering heating-rates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117791</link>
      <description>Wenwen Lv, Haining Cao, J. Zhuo, Yaodan Cao, Hongyan Liu, Maoquan Wu, Tongjie Yao, Sheng Li, Jie Wu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411766262

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenwen Lv, Haining Cao, J. Zhuo, Yaodan Cao, Hongyan Liu, Maoquan Wu, Tongjie Yao, Sheng Li, Jie Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117791</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen reduction reaction performance in boron carbon nitride through P doping for zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163913</link>
      <description>Fang Liu, Shiqing Zhang, Shaokai Ma, Zhaoyang Cao, Ying Li, Y.R. Ma, Xuewen Xu, Jun Zhang, Yanming Xue, Chengchun Tang, Applied Surface Science. 710(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411772312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fang Liu, Shiqing Zhang, Shaokai Ma, Zhaoyang Cao, Ying Li, Y.R. Ma, Xuewen Xu, Jun Zhang, Yanming Xue, Chengchun Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Formation Kinetics of the First Intermediate in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction on MnO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; with Different Electron Configurations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18273</link>
      <description>Ruifang Wei, Dongfeng Li, Panwang Zhou, Runze Liu, Chenwei Ni, Zeyu Cheng, Xiuli Wang, Can Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411779753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruifang Wei, Dongfeng Li, Panwang Zhou, Runze Liu, Chenwei Ni, Zeyu Cheng, Xiuli Wang, Can Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18273</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mussel&#8208;Inspired Self&#8208;Assembly of PtO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Atomic Catalysts for Interfacial Synergistic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202507807</link>
      <description>Yeo Hoon Yoon, Karthikeyan Jeyakumar, Gang San Lee, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Suchithra Padmajan Sasikala, Chan Woo Lee, Chuanwei Cheng, Jun Beom Kim, Haeshin Lee, Sang Ouk Kim, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411786099

                Abstract Molecular self&#8208;assembly strategy for Pt&#8208;O electrocatalysts is presented, achieved by facile solution processing of dopamine monomers. This mussel&#8208;inspired strategy ensures a highly defined PtO 4 atomic structure with uniform monolayer deposition across various 2D nanomaterials. By leveraging the intimate interplay between PtO 4 sites and 2D substrates, while maintaining a consistent coordination environment, underlying mechanism for enhanced kinetics in interfacial synergistic hydrogen evolution reaction is systematically elucidated. Notably, the self&#8208;assembled PtO 4 site exhibits up to a 30&#8208;fold enhancement of mass activity compared to commercial Pt/C catalysts, contingent upon the choice of substrate material. Theoretical investigation illustrates facilitated electron transfer, optimized energy barriers, and additional reaction pathways resulting from the synergistic interplay between PtO 4 and Ti 3 C 2 O 2 MXene. This straightforward, energy&#8208;efficient, and highly reliable scheme for atomic&#8208;level catalysts prospects a valuable platform toward sub&#8208;molecular level engineering of tailored electronic structures and properties.</description>
      <author>Yeo Hoon Yoon, Karthikeyan Jeyakumar, Gang San Lee, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Suchithra Padmajan Sasikala, Chan Woo Lee, Chuanwei Cheng, Jun Beom Kim, Haeshin Lee, Sang Ouk Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202507807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Catalysts Using Computational Chemistry, Machine Learning, and Cheminformatics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527847068.ch06</link>
      <description>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411788773

                No abstract</description>
      <author>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527847068.ch06</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark of Approximate Quantum Chemical and Machine Learning Potentials for Biochemical Proton Transfer Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00690</link>
      <description>Guilherme M. Arantes, Jan &#344;ez&#225;&#269;, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411792069

                Proton transfer reactions are among the most common chemical transformations and are central to enzymatic catalysis and bioenergetic processes. Their mechanisms are often investigated using DFT or approximate quantum chemical methods, whose accuracy directly impacts the reliability of the simulations. Here, a comprehensive set of semiempirical molecular orbital and tight-binding DFT approaches, along with recently developed machine learning (ML) potentials, are benchmarked against high-level MP2 reference data for a curated set of proton transfer reactions representative of biochemical systems. Relative energies, geometries, and dipole moments are evaluated for isolated reactions. Microsolvated reactions are also simulated using a hybrid QM/MM partition. Traditional DFT methods offer high accuracy in general but show markedly larger deviations for proton transfers involving nitrogen-containing groups. Among approximate models, RM1, PM6, PM7, DFTB2-NH, DFTB3, and GFN2-xTB show reasonable accuracy across properties, though their performance varies by chemical group. The ML-corrected (&#916;-learning) model PM6-ML improves accuracy for all properties and chemical groups and transfers well to QM/MM simulations. Conversely, standalone ML potentials perform poorly for most reactions. These results provide a basis for evaluating approximate methods and selecting potentials for proton transfer simulations in complex environments.</description>
      <author>Guilherme M. Arantes, Jan &#344;ez&#225;&#269;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fastatomstruct: A High-Performance Library for Structural and Dynamical Analysis of Atomic Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.08106</link>
      <description>Nils Holle, Sebastian Walfort, Riccardo Mazzarello, Martin Salinga, The Journal of Open Source Software. 10(110)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411801452

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nils Holle, Sebastian Walfort, Riccardo Mazzarello, Martin Salinga</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.08106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the oxygen evolution reaction mechanism catalyzed by phosphate-substituted FeCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanosheets: proton-coupled electron transfer assisted adsorbate evolution mechanism investigated by &lt;i&gt;in situ&lt;/i&gt; NAP-XPS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02093j</link>
      <description>Nut Thanasuwannakul, Chueh&#8208;Cheng Yang, Pantita Prapamonton, Chia-Hsin Wang, Nguyet N. T. Pham, Yu&#8208;Hsu Chang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411809016

                This study explores phosphate-substituted FeCo 2 O 4 as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction. In situ NAP-XPS analysis elucidates the reaction pathway, with proton-coupled electron transfer identified as a critical mechanistic step.</description>
      <author>Nut Thanasuwannakul, Chueh&#8208;Cheng Yang, Pantita Prapamonton, Chia-Hsin Wang, Nguyet N. T. Pham, Yu&#8208;Hsu Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02093j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the heterointerface of silver nanoparticles and cobalt oxide nanorings toward the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01457c</link>
      <description>Fatima Nasim, Hira Malik, Guobao Xu, Huilong Dong, Muhammad Arif Nadeem, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411813765

                A unique Ag/Co 3 O 4 interface anchored on nitrogen-doped carbon nanosheets was synthesized via a one-pot route. The heterostructure exhibits excellent ORR performance, outperforming Pt-based catalysts due to synergistic interfacial effects.</description>
      <author>Fatima Nasim, Hira Malik, Guobao Xu, Huilong Dong, Muhammad Arif Nadeem</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01457c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Engineering of Electronic Structure and Lattice Strain via Ce Doping in NiMn&#8208;LDH for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202502125</link>
      <description>Shashwat Bishwanathan, Nitash Kaushik, Simran Kaur Oberoi, Prashant Kumar Gupta, ChemistrySelect. 10(25)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411848913

                Abstract Water electrolysis is a more sustainable way to produce green hydrogen than steam methanol reforming or coal gasification. Its efficiency is limited by slow oxygen evolution processes at the anode. Highly effective anodic electrocatalysts are difficult to produce. Layered double hydroxide is a promising and thoroughly researched OER material, however, long&#8208;term stability issues arise. In this study, we examine the modification of the electronic structure of NiMn LDH through the introduction of Ce doping. The analysis of the material using XPS and XRD indicates that Ce is effectively integrated into the NiMn crystal structure, resulting in lattice distortion and alterations to the electronic structure when doped at concentrations of up to 5%. Furthermore, various electrochemical characterizations indicated that Ce doping increased the number of electrochemically active sites, improved electronic conductivity, and optimized the electrochemical kinetics. The 5% Ce&#8208;doped NiMn LDH demonstrated a current density of 30 mA/cm 2 at an overpotential of 561 mV, which is significantly lower than the 638 mV overpotential observed for NiMn LDH and considerably superior to that of commercial RuO 2 . The system exhibited complete stability throughout a 15&#8208;h operational duration at a consistent applied current density of 15 mA/cm 2 , with no indications of degradation observed.</description>
      <author>Shashwat Bishwanathan, Nitash Kaushik, Simran Kaur Oberoi, Prashant Kumar Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202502125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-Scale Insights into Electrochemical Hydrazine Oxidation on Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02636</link>
      <description>Diwakar Singh, Kai S. Exner, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411853221

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Diwakar Singh, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of Catalysts for Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries Based on Descriptors: Progress and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104429</link>
      <description>Kangdong Tian, Miaofa Yuan, Zhiwei Zhang, Chengxiang Wang, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411863236

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kangdong Tian, Miaofa Yuan, Zhiwei Zhang, Chengxiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional electrocatalysts for Zn&#8211;air batteries: A comprehensive review of design optimization and in-situ characterization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.101058</link>
      <description>Jagadis Gautam, Roop L. Mahajan, Seul&#8208;Yi Lee, Soo&#8208;Jin Park, Materials Science and Engineering R Reports. 166(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411866943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jagadis Gautam, Roop L. Mahajan, Seul&#8208;Yi Lee, Soo&#8208;Jin Park</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.101058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum-palladium catalysts of various composition in the oxygen electroreduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150166</link>
      <description>&#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Vladislav Menshikov, A. K. Nevelskaya, Angelina Pavlets, Kirill Paperzh, Ilya Pankov, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 150(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411868725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Vladislav Menshikov, A. K. Nevelskaya, Angelina Pavlets, Kirill Paperzh, Ilya Pankov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Silver-Chalcogenide Nanomaterial Enveloped with a Carborane-Thiolate Shell for the Electroreduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01918</link>
      <description>Arijit Jana, Zhengyuan Li, Amoghavarsha Ramachandra Kini, Vivek Yadav, Akhil S. Nair, M. Astrid Campos Mata, Jingjie Wu, Jan Mach&#225;&#269;ek, Tom&#225;&#353; Ba&#353;e, Biswarup Pathak, Soumyabrata Roy, Thalappil Pradeep, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411869333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arijit Jana, Zhengyuan Li, Amoghavarsha Ramachandra Kini, Vivek Yadav, Akhil S. Nair, M. Astrid Campos Mata, Jingjie Wu, Jan Mach&#225;&#269;ek, Tom&#225;&#353; Ba&#353;e, Biswarup Pathak, Soumyabrata Roy, Thalappil Pradeep</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Design and Simulation of High-Entropy Alloys via Machine Learning and Multiobjective Optimization Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00143</link>
      <description>Jian Cao, Zian Chen, Haichao Li, Chang Liu, Yutong He, Hongbin Zhang, Lina Xu, Hong&#8208;Ping Xiao, Xiao He, Guoyong Fang, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411871855

                High-entropy alloys (HEAs) are innovative metallic materials with unique properties and wide potential applications. However, the compositional complexity of HEAs poses a great challenge to investigate the physical mechanisms controlling their performance. Herein, we propose a novel framework composed of high-entropy alloys design and simulations (HEADS) that combines machine learning (ML), molecular dynamics (MD), and multiobjective optimization algorithm (MOOA). When considering the disordered characteristics of high-entropy alloys, this framework initially predicts the phase structure of high-entropy alloys with different compositions by using ML and subsequently performs theoretical modeling. Tensile simulations were conducted via MD to generate the mechanical property data, which served as the foundation for further optimization. Within this framework, deep neural network (DNN) models conduct multitask regression to fit the data obtained from the MD simulations, thereby developing an accurate performance prediction model. This model was employed as the fitness function in the multiobjective optimization algorithm to optimize the elastic modulus (EM) and ultimate tensile strength (UTS) of HEAs. The framework is validated using the FeNiCrCoCuAlMg alloy and supports flexible weight assignments for EM and UTS, allowing tailored optimization based on specific application requirements. HEADS framework can provide a robust strategy to accelerate the development of high-performance HEAs and offer new insights for engineering applications requiring advanced materials with optimized properties.</description>
      <author>Jian Cao, Zian Chen, Haichao Li, Chang Liu, Yutong He, Hongbin Zhang, Lina Xu, Hong&#8208;Ping Xiao, Xiao He, Guoyong Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00143</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new method based on a commercial molecular sieve for the determination of bioamines in fruit wines by dispersive solid phase microextraction coupled to LC-MS/MS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.microc.2025.114411</link>
      <description>Lingcan Kong, Hao Chen, Qing Liu, Microchemical Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411872715

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingcan Kong, Hao Chen, Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.microc.2025.114411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-energy argon implantation in carbon nanowalls as a way to produce electrodes for supercapacitor applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-03770-6</link>
      <description>Julia Bondareva, Sergei A. Smirnov, &#1044;. &#1054;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074;, D. A. Chernodubov, Oleg N. Dubinin, &#1050;. &#1048;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1089;&#1083;&#1072;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, Tolganay B. Egorova, A. A. Shibalova, M. A. Tarkhov, R. A. Khmelnitsky, V. A. Dravin, Nikita Orekhov, Xiaoyang Shi, Fedor S. Fedorov, Stanislav A. Evlashin, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411873678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Julia Bondareva, Sergei A. Smirnov, &#1044;. &#1054;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074;, D. A. Chernodubov, Oleg N. Dubinin, &#1050;. &#1048;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1089;&#1083;&#1072;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, Tolganay B. Egorova, A. A. Shibalova, M. A. Tarkhov, R. A. Khmelnitsky, V. A. Dravin, Nikita Orekhov, Xiaoyang Shi, Fedor S. Fedorov, Stanislav A. Evlashin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-03770-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero shot molecular generation via similarity kernels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60963-3</link>
      <description>Rokas Elijo&#353;ius, Fabian Zills, Ilyes Batatia, Sam Walton Norwood, D&#225;vid P&#233;ter Kov&#225;cs, Christian Holm, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411879488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rokas Elijo&#353;ius, Fabian Zills, Ilyes Batatia, Sam Walton Norwood, D&#225;vid P&#233;ter Kov&#225;cs, Christian Holm, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60963-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating water dissociation to achieve ampere-level hydrogen peroxide electrosynthesis in brine and seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60950-8</link>
      <description>Jiahuan Nie, Qiao Jiang, Zhiyuan Sang, Min Zheng, Zhenxin Li, Yunguo Liu, De&#8217;an Yang, Yao Zheng, Lichang Yin, Feng Hou, Xiao Yan, Ji Liang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411882047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahuan Nie, Qiao Jiang, Zhiyuan Sang, Min Zheng, Zhenxin Li, Yunguo Liu, De&#8217;an Yang, Yao Zheng, Lichang Yin, Feng Hou, Xiao Yan, Ji Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60950-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preferable single-atom catalysts enabled by natural language processing for high energy density Na-S batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60931-x</link>
      <description>Ruilin Bai, Yu Yao, Qiaosong Lin, Ling Juan Wu, Zhen Li, Huijuan Wang, Mingze Ma, Di Mu, Lingxiang Hu, Haiqing Yang, W.S. Li, Shaolong Zhu, Xiaojun Wu, Xianhong Rui, Yan Yu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411882184

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruilin Bai, Yu Yao, Qiaosong Lin, Ling Juan Wu, Zhen Li, Huijuan Wang, Mingze Ma, Di Mu, Lingxiang Hu, Haiqing Yang, W.S. Li, Shaolong Zhu, Xiaojun Wu, Xianhong Rui, Yan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60931-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning and data-driven methods in computational surface and interface science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01691-6</link>
      <description>Lukas H&#246;rmann, Wojciech G. Stark, Reinhard J. Maurer, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411886920

                Abstract Machine learning and data-driven methods have started to transform the study of surfaces and interfaces. Here, we review how data-driven methods and machine learning approaches complement simulation workflows and contribute towards tackling grand challenges in computational surface science from 2D materials to interface engineering and electrocatalysis. Challenges remain, including the scarcity of large datasets and the need for more electronic structure methods for interfaces.</description>
      <author>Lukas H&#246;rmann, Wojciech G. Stark, Reinhard J. Maurer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01691-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Iron dynamics of NiFe (oxy)hydroxides toward robust active sites in water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60728-y</link>
      <description>Zhao Jian-xiong, Yuwei Zhang, Yike Ye, Qiucheng Xu, Songzhu Luo, Fanxu Meng, Siyuan Zhu, Xiaoning Li, Xinlong Lin, Anke Yu, Xiao Ren, Tianze Wu, Zhichuan J. Xu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411887044

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhao Jian-xiong, Yuwei Zhang, Yike Ye, Qiucheng Xu, Songzhu Luo, Fanxu Meng, Siyuan Zhu, Xiaoning Li, Xinlong Lin, Anke Yu, Xiao Ren, Tianze Wu, Zhichuan J. Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-60728-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Potential-Dependent Selectivity of Propylene Electrooxidation: The Role of Electrochemistry-Induced Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07246</link>
      <description>Danyang Li, Panpan Sun, Di Zhang, Hao Li, Haoxiang Xu, Dapeng Cao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411887668

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Danyang Li, Panpan Sun, Di Zhang, Hao Li, Haoxiang Xu, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Interface Engineering of the Water Oxidation Electrocatalyst and One-to-One Advantages: High Intrinsic Activity and Solar to Hydrogen Conversion Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02164</link>
      <description>Dhanasingh Thiruvengadam, Ravichandran Nithiasri, Arokiadoss Davidrichetson, M.R. Suresh Kumar, Jayaraman Jayabharathi, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411900185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dhanasingh Thiruvengadam, Ravichandran Nithiasri, Arokiadoss Davidrichetson, M.R. Suresh Kumar, Jayaraman Jayabharathi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel van der Waals heterostructure g-C3N4/XP3 for photocatalytic hydrogen production: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150135</link>
      <description>Xiaoqing Liu, Jinghong Zhao, Wei Kang, Xue Du, Faling Ling, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 151(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411922312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoqing Liu, Jinghong Zhao, Wei Kang, Xue Du, Faling Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination and organometallic compounds of graphyne and graphdiyne: Synthesis, properties and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216890</link>
      <description>M. Aslam, Anirudh Pratap Singh Raman, Ishika Rana, Madhur Babu Singh, Kumar Rakesh Ranjan, Chandrabhan Verma, Akram Alfantazi, Prashant Singh, Kamlesh Kumari, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 543(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411925938

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Aslam, Anirudh Pratap Singh Raman, Ishika Rana, Madhur Babu Singh, Kumar Rakesh Ranjan, Chandrabhan Verma, Akram Alfantazi, Prashant Singh, Kamlesh Kumari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in computational approaches for bridging theory and experiments in electrocatalyst design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5nh00216h</link>
      <description>Yaqin Zhang, Yu Xiong, Yuhang Wang, Qianqian Wang, Jun Fan, Nanoscale Horizons. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411926485

                Cutting-edge computational strategies that bridge theoretical principles and experimental insights to enable the rational design and dynamic understanding of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yaqin Zhang, Yu Xiong, Yuhang Wang, Qianqian Wang, Jun Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5nh00216h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ stabilization of Cu+ for CO2 Electroreduction via Environmental-molecules-induced ZnO1-x shield</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61189-z</link>
      <description>Fanxing Zhang, Ning Cao, C. Y. Wang, Shengxiang Wang, Yi He, Yao Shi, Mi Yan, Ying Bao, Zhenglong Li, Pengfei Xie, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411932409

                Electrochemical CO2-to-ethanol conversion is challenged by sluggish C-C coupling kinetics and wide products distribution. Although Cu+ has been demonstrated to enhance multi-carbon (C2+) formation, the stabilization of Cu+ under reduction conditions is difficult. Here, we report a hydrogen-ethanol pretreatment strategy to obtain Cu nanoparticles covered by highly dispersed and disordered ZnO1-x clusters. Ethanol-induced ZnO1-x redispersion gives rise to abundant Cu+ on the subsurface. The optimal catalyst delivers a 73.0% ethanol Faradaic efficiency (FE) and 86.0% total C2+ FE at -0.9 V, with a 2.3 mmol cm-2 h-1 ethanol formation rate and single-pass ethanol yield of 18.0%. The catalyst also exhibits stability beyond 500 h, attributed to the stabilization of Cu+ by the ZnO1-x shield that requires a high energy barrier for lattice oxygen removal. In situ X-ray spectroscopy and calculations reveal a volcano relationship between Cu+ ratio in Cu species and ethanol FE. Optimal Cu+ density not only facilitates *OC-COH coupling but also optimizes the adsorption energy of *CH2CH2O on catalyst for ethanol electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Fanxing Zhang, Ning Cao, C. Y. Wang, Shengxiang Wang, Yi He, Yao Shi, Mi Yan, Ying Bao, Zhenglong Li, Pengfei Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61189-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Does Carbon-Based Pt&#8211;Fe Catalyst Enhance Electrochemical Hydrogen Transfer Efficiency by Correlated Water Dynamics?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04006</link>
      <description>Pratik N. Kalode, Bhabani S. Mallik, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411932707

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pratik N. Kalode, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Hessian Data Improve the Performance of Machine Learning Potentials?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00402</link>
      <description>Austin Rodriguez, Justin S. Smith, Jose L. Mendoza&#8208;Cortes, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411932806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Austin Rodriguez, Justin S. Smith, Jose L. Mendoza&#8208;Cortes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials design with target-oriented Bayesian optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01704-4</link>
      <description>Yuan Tian, Tongtong Li, Jianbo Pang, Yumei Zhou, Dezhen Xue, Xiangdong Ding, Turab Lookman, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411937000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan Tian, Tongtong Li, Jianbo Pang, Yumei Zhou, Dezhen Xue, Xiangdong Ding, Turab Lookman</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01704-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How far are volcanologists from volcanoes?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00445-025-01849-6</link>
      <description>Gilles Seropian, Thomas J. Aubry, Jamie Farquharson, James Hickey, Bulletin of Volcanology. 87(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411951833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gilles Seropian, Thomas J. Aubry, Jamie Farquharson, James Hickey</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00445-025-01849-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abridging the modelling of CO oxidation on single atom catalysts: From microkinetics to descriptor-based analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116308</link>
      <description>Hai&#8208;Yan Su, Keju Sun, Xiufang Ma, Xiangxuan Huang, Jie Feng, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411958542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hai&#8208;Yan Su, Keju Sun, Xiufang Ma, Xiangxuan Huang, Jie Feng, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Data Set Population for Training Machine Learning Potentials with Automated System Generation and Strategic Sampling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00616</link>
      <description>Alberto Pacini, Mauro Ferrario, Maria Clelia Righi, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411958907

                Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials (MLIPs) offer a powerful way to overcome the limitations of ab initio and classical molecular dynamics simulations. However, a major challenge is the generation of high-quality training data sets, which typically require extensive ab initio calculations and intensive user intervention. Here, we introduce Strategic Configuration Sampling (SCS), an active learning framework to construct compact and comprehensive data sets for MLIP training. SCS introduces the usage of workflows for the automated generation and exploration of systems, collections of MD simulations where geometries and run conditions are set up automatically based on high-level, user defined inputs. To explore nontrivial atomic environments, initial geometries can be assembled dynamically via collaging of structures harvested from preceding runs. Multiple automated exploration workflows can be run in parallel, each with its own resource budget according to the computational complexity of each system. Besides leveraging the MLIP models trained iteratively, SCS also incorporates pretrained models to steer the exploration MD, thereby eliminating the need for an initial data set. By integrating widely used software, SCS provides a fully open-source, automatic, active learning framework for the generation of data sets in a high-throughput fashion. Case studies demonstrate its versatility and effectiveness to accelerate the deployment of MLIP in diverse materials science applications.</description>
      <author>Alberto Pacini, Mauro Ferrario, Maria Clelia Righi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-selective reactivity modulation with intact reaction dynamics in H2 dissociation on single-atom alloy Au1/Ag(111) surface: Six dimensional quantum insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0278056</link>
      <description>Kaixin Meng, Haiming Huang, Tianhui Liu, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411961076

                The dissociative dynamics of molecular H2 on the Au1/Ag(111) single-atom alloy (SAA) surface was systematically investigated through full-dimensional quantum dynamical calculations. A neural network-derived potential energy surface with a 4.2 meV root-mean-square error was employed to ensure high-fidelity simulations. Density functional theory calculations identified a reduced static dissociation barrier of 1.08 eV for the SAA system, compared to the 1.22 and 1.25 eV values for pristine Ag(111) and Au(111) surfaces, respectively. Despite this energetic advantage, the six-dimensional quantum dynamical analysis revealed that the dissociation probabilities for H2 in the vibrational ground (v = 0) state exceeded those on Ag(111) only at kinetic energies below 1.33 eV. This reactivity suppression at elevated energies was attributed to the site-specific modulation induced by the Au dopant, which selectively enhanced reactivities at the top-Au, hcp, and fcc sites while inhibiting those at bridge and top-Ag sites. Furthermore, the vibrational excitation, rotational alignment, and rotational excitation effects were found to closely resemble those observed for H2 dissociation on pristine Ag(111), demonstrating that the fundamental dynamical characteristics of the reaction remain qualitatively preserved despite SAA modification. These findings provide critical insights into the interplay between local electronic structure modification and global reaction dynamics in SAA systems.</description>
      <author>Kaixin Meng, Haiming Huang, Tianhui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0278056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Charge Transfer and Delayed Recombination in a Type-II Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;TeO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;/MoSi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure: A Time-Domain Ab Initio Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01469</link>
      <description>Arooba Kanwal, Yixue Duan, Zhen&#8208;Chao Dong, Zirui Jiang, Hao Fan, Abdul Jalil, Syed Raza Ali Raza, M. Varma, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411965669

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arooba Kanwal, Yixue Duan, Zhen&#8208;Chao Dong, Zirui Jiang, Hao Fan, Abdul Jalil, Syed Raza Ali Raza, M. Varma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling electron storage at the interface between Au and anatase-TiO2 under ambient conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101430</link>
      <description>Yichen Li, Dongfang Cheng, Giyeong Son, Anna V. Shneidman, Kang Rui Garrick Lim, Joanna Aizenberg, Philippe Sautet, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411965739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yichen Li, Dongfang Cheng, Giyeong Son, Anna V. Shneidman, Kang Rui Garrick Lim, Joanna Aizenberg, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101430</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of H2 donation in heterogeneous Mo-based olefin metathesis site creation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2025.102670</link>
      <description>Dimitri Gatzios, Stephen Stockton, Avery F. Hill, Hannah Frankovic, M. M. Montemore, Lucas D. Ellis, Cell Reports Physical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411965856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dimitri Gatzios, Stephen Stockton, Avery F. Hill, Hannah Frankovic, M. M. Montemore, Lucas D. Ellis</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2025.102670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First principles investigation of zb-TiSn: A promising narrow bandgap semiconductor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417512</link>
      <description>R. Sudeep, M Sarojini, Uma Mahendra Kumar Koppolu, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411968216

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Sudeep, M Sarojini, Uma Mahendra Kumar Koppolu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Hybrid&#8208;phase IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts with Ti for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503601</link>
      <description>Young Hwa Yun, Jungwoo Choi, Young&#8208;Tae Park, Ho Bum Park, Gisu Doo, MinJoong Kim, Sang Soo Han, Jong Hyeok Park, Sechan Lee, Changsoo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411970770

                Abstract To realize a sustainable energy transition, water electrolysis&#8212;particularly proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE)&#8212;holds significant promise. However, practical deployment is hindered by the cost and instability of the anode catalyst, IrO 2 . Recent studies indicate that tuning the Ir&#9472;O bond distance, via doping or composite formation, is key to enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of IrO 2 &#8208;based electrocatalysts. Herein, a hybrid&#8208;phase Ti&#8208;incorporated IrO 2 electrocatalyst is developed, exhibiting outstanding OER activity (298.8 mV at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and stability over 25 h. This improvement originates from asymmetric interatomic interactions introduced by Ti, as revealed by combined experimental X&#8208;ray analyses and theoretical modeling. Ti incorporation induces tensile strain along the z&#8208;axis in IrO 2 motifs, effectively reducing the average Ir&#9472;O bond distance and thereby enhancing OER activity. In situ X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy further confirms that at 1.5 V (vs. RHE), the elongated Ir&#9472;O bond facilitates &#9472;OOH* intermediate formation while suppressing Ir dissolution, contributing to superior stability. These findings underscore the critical role of Ir&#9472;O bond engineering in balancing activity and durability, offering strategic insights for the rational design of high&#8208;performance OER catalysts for renewable energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Young Hwa Yun, Jungwoo Choi, Young&#8208;Tae Park, Ho Bum Park, Gisu Doo, MinJoong Kim, Sang Soo Han, Jong Hyeok Park, Sechan Lee, Changsoo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of graphdiyne-supported single- and dual-atom electrocatalysts for highly efficient hydrogen evolution reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150144</link>
      <description>Wangdi Zhang, Xiaojun Li, Junwei Lu, Shuna Li, Yunguang Zhang, Zhongkui Zhang, Mengqi Zhang, Wenyu Xi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 153(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411978826

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangdi Zhang, Xiaojun Li, Junwei Lu, Shuna Li, Yunguang Zhang, Zhongkui Zhang, Mengqi Zhang, Wenyu Xi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; Hydroxylation of the Sn&#8211;Co Diatomic Catalyst Boosting Ultrastable Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c02744</link>
      <description>Lulu Lyu, Hu Xu, Wenqi Fan, Bing Shao, Qichen Wang, Gilseob Kim, Jai Won Chung, Zhen Zhou, Yong&#8208;Mook Kang, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411980110

                Diatomic catalysts (DAs) exhibit superior catalytic activity for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) due to the synergistic interplay between dual metals. However, their dynamic evolution remains unexplored under the working conditions. Herein, Sn-Co diatomic pairs on N-doped carbon with an asymmetric N3Sn-CoN3 structure (SnCoN6 DA) are rationally designed for promoting ORR activity and durability. The operando hydroxylation of SnCoN6 DA regulates O2 adsorption on Co, allowing more d orbitals to hybridize with O2 s/p orbitals. Furthermore, the *OH-Sn moiety serves as an electron modulator that upshifts the d-band center of Co, enabling stronger binding with *OOH and expediting subsequent O-O cleavage. Accordingly, the operando hydroxylation of SnCoN6 DA positively shifts the half-wave potential by 54 mV and enhances the kinetic current density by 16.1 times compared to those of the Co single-atom catalyst. The constructed Zn-air battery shows an ultralong cycling life span (more than 3650 h at 5 and 10 mA cm-2).</description>
      <author>Lulu Lyu, Hu Xu, Wenqi Fan, Bing Shao, Qichen Wang, Gilseob Kim, Jai Won Chung, Zhen Zhou, Yong&#8208;Mook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c02744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction on IrO2(110) is governed by Walden-type mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61367-z</link>
      <description>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig, Stephan N. Steinmann, Kai S. Exner, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411983783

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig, Stephan N. Steinmann, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61367-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical computational study of the effect of point defects and equivalent elemental doping on the photoelectrocatalytic properties of ZnO monolayers (0 0 1)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114061</link>
      <description>Hailan Li, Qingyu Hou, Yulan Gu, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma, Computational Materials Science. 258(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411983856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hailan Li, Qingyu Hou, Yulan Gu, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable synthesis of NiFe-layered double hydroxide for efficient anion exchange membrane electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61356-2</link>
      <description>&#193;lvaro Seijas&#8208;Da Silva, Adrian Hartert, V&#237;ctor Oestreicher, Jorge Romero, Camilo Jaramillo&#8208;Hern&#225;ndez, Luuk J. J. Muris, Gr&#233;goire Thorez, Bruno J. C. Vieira, Guillaume Ducourthial, Alice Fiocco, S&#233;bastien Legendre, Cristi&#225;n Huck&#8208;Iriart, Mart&#237;n Mizrahi, Diego L&#243;pez-Alcal&#225;, Anna T.S. Freiberg, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Jo&#227;o C. Waerenborgh, Jos&#233; J. Baldov&#237;, Serhiy Cherevko, M. Varela, Simon Thiele, Vicent Lloret, Gonzalo Abell&#225;n, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411983897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#193;lvaro Seijas&#8208;Da Silva, Adrian Hartert, V&#237;ctor Oestreicher, Jorge Romero, Camilo Jaramillo&#8208;Hern&#225;ndez, Luuk J. J. Muris, Gr&#233;goire Thorez, Bruno J. C. Vieira, Guillaume Ducourthial, Alice Fiocco, S&#233;bastien Legendre, Cristi&#225;n Huck&#8208;Iriart, Mart&#237;n Mizrahi, Diego L&#243;pez-Alcal&#225;, Anna T.S. Freiberg, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Jo&#227;o C. Waerenborgh, Jos&#233; J. Baldov&#237;, Serhiy Cherevko, M. Varela, Simon Thiele, Vicent Lloret, Gonzalo Abell&#225;n</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61356-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model-based Operability and Safety Optimization for PEM Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.132227</link>
      <description>Beatriz Dantas, Sahithi Srijana Akundi, Yuanxing Liu, Austin Braniff, Shayan S. Niknezhad, Systems and Control Transactions. 4(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411815687

                In this paper, we present a systematic approach to quantify the safe operating window of a proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) system considering energy intermittency and varying hydrogen demand. The PEMWE model has been developed based on first principles, with the polarization curve validated against a lab-scale experimental setup. The impact of key operational variables is investigated which include voltage, inlet temperature, and water flowrate (utilized for both feed and system cooling). Emphasis is given on operating temperature, a safety-critical variable, as its elevation can pose significant hydrogen safety risks within both the electrolyzer cells and the storage system. The impact of temperature on process safety is quantified via a risk index considering the fault probability and consequence severity. Process operability analysis is employed to assess the achievability of a safe and feasible region for design and operations. This analysis provides a comprehensive framework to optimize PEMWE systems for enhanced operational flexibility and robust performance with application to modular hydrogen production using renewable energy sources.</description>
      <author>Beatriz Dantas, Sahithi Srijana Akundi, Yuanxing Liu, Austin Braniff, Shayan S. Niknezhad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.132227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface oxidation mechanism and mechanical properties of lightweight high-entropy alloys AlCrMoTi and AlCrMoTiV based on site preference</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107071</link>
      <description>Cheng Qian, Xiaoqiong Zhang, Xingyu Chen, Longju Su, Rong Chen, Jiansen Wen, Bo Wu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411839657

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Qian, Xiaoqiong Zhang, Xingyu Chen, Longju Su, Rong Chen, Jiansen Wen, Bo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Principles Evaluation of Platinum Cluster Metal&#8211;Support Interactions on Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Supports</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15070635</link>
      <description>Vu Nguyen, Shubham Vyas, Catalysts. 15(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411889978

                The fundamental chemistries and electronic structures of platinum catalysts over nitrogen-doped carbon supports were examined to determine the subtle yet important roles graphitic defect-based and pyridinic defect-based nitrogen defects have in stabilizing platinum. These roles address and extend previously gathered incomplete knowledge of how combinations of graphitic defect and pyridinic defect affect the local electronic structure, leading to a greater unified understanding of platinum stability. A theoretical study was designed where different atomically sized platinum clusters were investigated over seven different nitrogen defect combinations on graphene carbon support. Differently sized platinum clusters offered parametric insights into the differences in metal&#8211;support interactions.</description>
      <author>Vu Nguyen, Shubham Vyas</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15070635</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lowering the barrier to access information-rich transient kinetic data for machine learning methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116306</link>
      <description>Brooklyne Ariana Thompson, Shengguang Wang, Konstantinos A. Goulas, M. Ross Kunz, Rebecca Fushimi, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411919099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brooklyne Ariana Thompson, Shengguang Wang, Konstantinos A. Goulas, M. Ross Kunz, Rebecca Fushimi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>El Agente: An autonomous agent for quantum chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2025.102263</link>
      <description>Yushi Zou, Austin H. Cheng, Abdulrahman Aldossary, Jie Bai, Shi Xuan Leong, Jorge A. Campos-Gonzalez-Angulo, Changhyeok Choi, Cher Tian Ser, Gary Tom, Andrew Wang, Zijian Zhang, Ilya Yakavets, Hao Han, Chris Crebolder, Varinia Bernales, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik, Matter. 8(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411932316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yushi Zou, Austin H. Cheng, Abdulrahman Aldossary, Jie Bai, Shi Xuan Leong, Jorge A. Campos-Gonzalez-Angulo, Changhyeok Choi, Cher Tian Ser, Gary Tom, Andrew Wang, Zijian Zhang, Ilya Yakavets, Hao Han, Chris Crebolder, Varinia Bernales, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2025.102263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of flow chemistry in self-driving labs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2025.102205</link>
      <description>Nikolai Mukhin, Pragyan Jha, Milad Abolhasani, Matter. 8(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411957801

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nikolai Mukhin, Pragyan Jha, Milad Abolhasani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2025.102205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Computational Framework for Cyclic Steady-State Simulation of Dynamic Catalysis Systems: Application to Ammonia Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.105384</link>
      <description>Carolina Colombo Tedesco, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird, Systems and Control Transactions. 4(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411816096

                Dynamic or Programmable Catalysis is an innovative strategy to improve heterogeneous catalysis processes by modulating the binding energies (BE) of adsorbates on a catalytic surface. The technique enables the periodic favoring of different reaction steps, overcoming limitations imposed by the Sabatier Principle and allowing for higher overall reaction rates, otherwise unattainable. Previously, we implemented a simultaneous simulation approach using the algebraic modeling language Pyomo and the solver IPOPT to obtain cyclic steady state results for a unimolecular reactive system with up to four-order of magnitude increases in computational performance compared to the previously reported sequential approach. The flexibility of the method allowed for the investigation of the influence of forcing signal parameters on system behavior and provided a framework for waveform design. In this study, we use a hybrid framework that combines the sequential and the simultaneous simulation approaches to find the cyclic steady state of a more complex system, of ammonia synthesis, comprising 19 reversible elementary reaction steps. The framework allowed us to investigate sine wave parameters with approximately 220 times less computational effort compared to the sequential approach alone. With the parameters studied, our findings indicate that frequencies exceeding 1000 Hz and compressive strains greater than 2% can negatively impact the system performance. Future work will focus on expanding the model to include lateral interactions between molecules, using other waveform as forcing signals, and integrating systematic mathematical optimization approaches. These advancements pave the way to establishing a general framework for identifying optimal waveforms across diverse dynamic catalysis systems.</description>
      <author>Carolina Colombo Tedesco, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69997/sct.105384</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
