<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 01:11:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Activation of Methane on Hydroxyapatite Surfaces: Insights from Machine Learning and Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109762</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Xiaoyu Yan, Xin Wang, Mingli Yang, Dingguo Xu, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397031046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Xiaoyu Yan, Xin Wang, Mingli Yang, Dingguo Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109762</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Single-Atom Supported on W2n3 as Efficient Electrocatalysts for the Nitrogen Reduction Reaction: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4832791</link>
      <description>Shengjie Xia, Jiyi Yang, Yue Meng, Zhiling Huang, Bo Xie, Ni Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397031139

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengjie Xia, Jiyi Yang, Yue Meng, Zhiling Huang, Bo Xie, Ni Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4832791</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed Iridium on Mo2C as an efficient and stable alkaline hydrogen oxidation reaction catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48672-9</link>
      <description>Jinjie Fang, Haiyong Wang, Dianwei Qian, Hao Wang, Xingdong Wang, Jiajing Pei, Zhiyuan Xu, Chengjin Chen, Wei Zhu, Hui Li, Yushan Yan, Zhongbin Zhuang, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397033739

                Abstract Hydroxide exchange membrane fuel cells (HEMFCs) have the advantages of using cost-effective materials, but hindered by the sluggish anodic hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) kinetics. Here, we report an atomically dispersed Ir on Mo 2 C nanoparticles supported on carbon (Ir SA -Mo 2 C/C) as highly active and stable HOR catalysts. The specific exchange current density of Ir SA -Mo 2 C/C is 4.1 mA cm &#8722;2 ECSA , which is 10 times that of Ir/C. Negligible decay is observed after 30,000-cycle accelerated stability test. Theoretical calculations suggest the high HOR activity is attributed to the unique Mo 2 C substrate, which makes the Ir sites with optimized H binding and also provides enhanced OH binding sites. By using a low loading (0.05 mg Ir cm &#8722;2 ) of Ir SA -Mo 2 C/C as anode, the fabricated HEMFC can deliver a high peak power density of 1.64 W cm &#8722;2 . This work illustrates that atomically dispersed precious metal on carbides may be a promising strategy for high performance HEMFCs.</description>
      <author>Jinjie Fang, Haiyong Wang, Dianwei Qian, Hao Wang, Xingdong Wang, Jiajing Pei, Zhiyuan Xu, Chengjin Chen, Wei Zhu, Hui Li, Yushan Yan, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48672-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported tetra-atom clusters on g-CN as catalysts for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide to formate: A computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160299</link>
      <description>Wenjing Zhou, Xuxin Kang, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397289374

                Single-cluster catalysts (SCCs) have emerged as highly efficient catalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR), providing a promising avenue to solve the carbon dilemma. Based on density functional theory calculations, we systematically investigated the capability of 12 tetra-atom transitional-metal clusters anchored on g-CN (TM4@g-CN) for CO2RR and found that all clusters have good stability on the substrate. Notably, the charge variation of the top metal atom (TM4) of six SCCs is close to zero which makes them readily donate electrons to the adsorbate CO2 and subsequent reaction intermediates. Our results demonstrate that CO2 can be efficiently reduced to HCOOH on Ni4, Cu4, and Au4@g-CN with low limiting potentials of &#8722;0.21, &#8722;0.22, and &#8722;0.19 V, respectively, outperforming the corresponding single-atom counterparts. Both &#916;G(&#8727;CO2) and &#916;G(&#8727;OCHO/&#8727;COOH) exhibit a volcano relationship with the reaction activity, and the TM4 serves as electron reservoirs throughout the entire reaction process. This work offers valuable insights for the advancement of cost-effective supported single cluster catalysts.</description>
      <author>Wenjing Zhou, Xuxin Kang, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom catalysts with anion center toward oxygen electrocatalysis based on the conductive 1T-HfTe2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115548</link>
      <description>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397292015

                Advancing efficient catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) or oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is imperative for commercializing emerging energy devices. Using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we propose doping different transition metal (TM) atoms to regulate the electronic structures of the two-dimensional 1T-HfTe2 monolayer to achieve bifunctional catalysis for the ORR/OER. Due to the small electronegativity of the Hf atom, we found the doped TMs can generally form anion centers by accepting abundant charges from the Hf interlayer. At the same time, the highly conductive 1T-HfTe2 contributes to the charge transfer between the active center and the reaction intermediates, rendering the designed SACs the tunable activity for the reactions. By comparing the theoretical overpotentials of ORR and OER on 15 single-atom catalysts (SACs), Pt-doped system exhibits excellent catalytic activity for both ORR and OER, outperforming the traditional Pt(1 1 1) and RuO2(1 1 0) catalysts. Based on the charge transfer mechanism, we clarified that the doped TM atoms act as a 'bridge' to transfer the electrons from the substrate to the reaction intermediates, thereby effectively contributing to the improvement of catalytic activity. In summary, our study shows that, by doping appropriate TM atoms, the intrinsic inert HfTe2 can be activated toward efficient ORR/OER. This could provide some guidance for the design of new two-dimensional ORR/OER bifunctional catalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton relay in hydrogen-bond networks promotes alkaline hydrogen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4375967/v1</link>
      <description>Jiayuan Li, Yuefei Li, Shishi Zhang, Boyang Li, Yaqiong Su, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398132625

                Abstract Common O-/H-down orientation of H2O molecules on electrocatalysts brings favorable OH/H delivery however adverse H/OH delivery in their dissociation process, hampering H2O dissociation kinetics of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). To overcome this challenge, we raised a synergetic H2O dissociation concept of metal-supported electrocatalysts involving efficient OH delivery from O-down H2O to the metal, timely proton relay from O-down H2O on the metal to H-down H2O on the support through the hydrogen-bond network, and prompt H delivery from H-down H2O to the support. After theoretically profiling that a high work function difference between metal and support (&#916;&#934;) induces a strong electric field at the metal-support interface that increases hydrogen-bond connectivity to promote proton relay, we examined this concept over cobalt phosphide-supported ruthenium (Ru/CoP) catalysts with a high &#916;&#934; = 0.4 eV, reaching record high HER performance with a Ru utilization activity of 66.1 A mgRu-1 at a 100 mV overpotential.</description>
      <author>Jiayuan Li, Yuefei Li, Shishi Zhang, Boyang Li, Yaqiong Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4375967/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database mining and first-principles assessment of organic proton-transfer ferroelectrics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.054413</link>
      <description>Seyedmojtaba Seyedraoufi, Elin Dypvik S&#248;dahl, Carl Henrik G&#246;rbitz, Kristian Berland, Physical review materials. 8(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398142116

                In organic proton-transfer ferroelectrics (OPTFe), molecules are linked to form hydrogen-bonded networks, and proton transfer (PT) between molecules is the dominant mechanism of ferroelectric switching. The fast-switching frequencies of OPTFes make them attractive alternatives to conventional ceramic ferroelectrics, which contain rare and/or toxic elements and require high processing temperatures. In this study, we mined the Cambridge Structural Database (CSD) for potential OPTFes, uncovering most of the previously reported ones, both tautomeric compounds and acid-base salts, in addition to 12 new compounds, nine of which were tautomeric salts. The identification of PT tautomeric salts highlights a potential new avenue for engineering novel OPTFes. The CSD mining was based on identifying polar crystal structures with pseudoinversion symmetry and viable PT paths. The spontaneous polarization ${\mathbit{P}}_{\mathrm{s}}$ and the PT barriers ${U}_{\mathrm{PT}}$ were calculated for a selection of the compounds using density-functional theory.</description>
      <author>Seyedmojtaba Seyedraoufi, Elin Dypvik S&#248;dahl, Carl Henrik G&#246;rbitz, Kristian Berland</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.054413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Variable Multi-Metric Optimization of Self-Assembled Photocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Performance Using Machine Learning Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01305</link>
      <description>Shannon A. Bonke, Giovanni Trezza, Luca Bergamasco, Hongwei Song, Santiago Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Jim&#233;nez, Leif Hammarstr&#246;m, Eliodoro Chiavazzo, Erwin Reisner, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398142708

                The sunlight-driven reduction of CO2 into fuels and platform chemicals is a promising approach to enable a circular economy. However, established optimization approaches are poorly suited to multivariable multimetric photocatalytic systems because they aim to optimize one performance metric while sacrificing the others and thereby limit overall system performance. Herein, we address this multimetric challenge by defining a metric for holistic system performance that takes multiple figures of merit into account, and employ a machine learning algorithm to efficiently guide our experiments through the large parameter matrix to make holistic optimization accessible for human experimentalists. As a test platform, we employ a five-component system that self-assembles into photocatalytic micelles for CO2-to-CO reduction, which we experimentally optimized to simultaneously improve yield, quantum yield, turnover number, and frequency while maintaining high selectivity. Leveraging the data set with machine learning algorithms allows quantification of each parameter's effect on overall system performance. The buffer concentration is unexpectedly revealed as the dominating parameter for optimal photocatalytic activity, and is nearly four times more important than the catalyst concentration. The expanded use and standardization of this methodology to define and optimize holistic performance will accelerate progress in different areas of catalysis by providing unprecedented insights into performance bottlenecks, enhancing comparability, and taking results beyond comparison of subjective figures of merit.</description>
      <author>Shannon A. Bonke, Giovanni Trezza, Luca Bergamasco, Hongwei Song, Santiago Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Jim&#233;nez, Leif Hammarstr&#246;m, Eliodoro Chiavazzo, Erwin Reisner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-aided first-principles calculations of redox potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01295-6</link>
      <description>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Ferenc Karsai, Georg Kresse, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398143044

                Abstract We present a method combining first-principles calculations and machine learning to predict the redox potentials of half-cell reactions on the absolute scale. By applying machine learning force fields for thermodynamic integration from the oxidized to the reduced state, we achieve efficient statistical sampling over a broad phase space. Furthermore, through thermodynamic integration from machine learning force fields to potentials of semi-local functionals, and from semi-local functionals to hybrid functionals using &#916;-machine learning, we refine the free energy with high precision step-by-step. Utilizing a hybrid functional that includes 25% exact exchange (PBE0), this method predicts the redox potentials of the three redox couples, Fe 3+ /Fe 2+ , Cu 2+ /Cu + , and Ag 2+ /Ag + , to be 0.92, 0.26, and 1.99 V, respectively. These predictions are in good agreement with the best experimental estimates (0.77, 0.15, 1.98 V). This work demonstrates that machine-learned surrogate models provide a flexible framework for refining the accuracy of free energy from coarse approximation methods to precise electronic structure calculations, while also facilitating sufficient statistical sampling.</description>
      <author>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Ferenc Karsai, Georg Kresse</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01295-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Operando X-ray Spectroscopic and DFT Studies Revealing Improved H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Evolution by the Synergistic Ni&#8211;Co Electron Effect in the Alkaline Condition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02613</link>
      <description>Lian&#8208;Ming Lyu, Han-Jung Li, R. Tsai, Ching-Feng Chen, Ya&#8208;Hsuan Chang, Y.C. Chuang, Cheng-Shiuan Li, Jeng-Lung Chen, Te&#8208;Wei Chiu, Chun Hong Kuo, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398145067

                The different electrolyte conditions, e.g., pH value, for driving efficient HER and OER are one of the major issues hindering the aim for electrocatalytic water splitting in a high efficiency. In this regard, seeking durable and active HER electrocatalysts to align the alkaline conditions of the OER is a promising solution. However, the success in this strategy will depend on a fundamental understanding about the HER mechanism at the atomic scale. In this work, we have provided thorough understanding for the electrochemical HER mechanisms in KOH over Ni- and Co-based hollow pyrite microspheres by in operando X-ray spectroscopies and DFT calculations, including NiS</description>
      <author>Lian&#8208;Ming Lyu, Han-Jung Li, R. Tsai, Ching-Feng Chen, Ya&#8208;Hsuan Chang, Y.C. Chuang, Cheng-Shiuan Li, Jeng-Lung Chen, Te&#8208;Wei Chiu, Chun Hong Kuo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and ionic conduction enhancement mechanisms at CeO2/SrTiO3 heterointerfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0185746</link>
      <description>Bonan Zhu, Georg Schusteritsch, Weiwei Li, Wandong Xing, Rong Yu, Chris J. Pickard, Judith L. MacManus&#8208;Driscoll, Applied physics reviews. 11(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398146412

                Fluorite-perovskite heterointerfaces garner great interest for enhanced ionic conductivity for application in electronic and energy devices. However, the origin of observed enhanced ionic conductivity as well as the details of the atomic structure at these interfaces remain elusive. Here, systematic, multi-stoichiometry computational searches and experimental investigations are performed to obtain stable and exact atomic structures of interfaces between CeO2 and SrTiO3&#8212;two archetypes of the corresponding structural families. Local reconstructions take place at the interface because of mismatched lattices. TiO2 terminated SrTiO3 causes a buckled rock salt CeO interface layer to emerge. In contrast, SrO terminated SrTiO3 maintains the fluorite structure at the interface compensated by a partially occupied anion lattice. Moderate enhancement in oxygen diffusion is found along the interface by simulations, yet evidence to support further significant enhancement is lacking. Our findings demonstrate the control of interface termination as an effective pathway to achieve desired device performance.</description>
      <author>Bonan Zhu, Georg Schusteritsch, Weiwei Li, Wandong Xing, Rong Yu, Chris J. Pickard, Judith L. MacManus&#8208;Driscoll</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0185746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1339-4_12</link>
      <description>Umesh P. Suryawanshi, Mayur A. Gaikwad, Uma V. Ghorpade, Jihun Kim, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, Energy, environment, and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398151349

                Water electrolysis or electrochemical water splitting is considered a promising technology for delivering a portable and sustainable energy source through hydrogen fuel. The crucial aspect for advancing toward industrial implementation rests in the utilization of cost-effective electrocatalysts with high efficiency. This book chapter provides a comprehensive overview of catalysts for electrochemical water splitting, emphasizing their importance, state-of-the-art advancements, challenges, and opportunities. Since catalysts play a critical role in facilitating efficient hydrogen production by improving reaction kinetics and selectivity, various catalyst types and their performance and stability evaluation are also explored. It highlights recent advancements in catalyst design, including nanostructuring and surface engineering. Challenges such as degradation, cost, and material availability are discussed, along with opportunities for innovation in earth-abundant catalysts and improved durability. This chapter aims to foster progress in catalyst design and development and inspire future research in electrolysis and electrochemical water splitting for sustainable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Umesh P. Suryawanshi, Mayur A. Gaikwad, Uma V. Ghorpade, Jihun Kim, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1339-4_12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals and Roles of Nanoelectrocatalysis for Sustainable Energy and Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-55329-5_1</link>
      <description>Juhan Lee, Rafael L. Zornitta, Katlego Makgopa, J.G. Gamaethiralalage, Modibane Desmond Kwena, Kumar Raju, Environmental chemistry for a sustainable world. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398151733

                Electrocatalysis is a pivotal scientific discipline and a crucial part of industrial processes for the sustainable future for mankind. It is closely related to energy efficiency and the general processing rate of various electrochemical applications. Thus, a sound understanding of electrocatalysis provides versatile new functions and innovative solutions to numerous challenges we face in conventional and advanced technologies. Particularly, the challenges regarding the need for sustainable energy and water use arise with growing demands for more environmentally friendly, safer, and energy-efficient materials, which are less dependent on limited resources. In terms of resolving these challenging demands, the emergence of nanomaterials has brought a significant advance in technologies and enabled an in-depth and comprehensive understanding of electrocatalysis. In this book chapter, we explore various electrochemical applications of both conventional and advanced technologies by categorizing them into five functioning groups: harvest, removal, consumption, storage, and analytics. For these applications with a particular aspect of sustainable energy and water, we discuss the roles and fundamentals of electrocatalysis, including technical parts such as cell configuration and its core elements, as well as the theories of thermodynamics and kinetics. Furthermore, we discuss how nanomaterials development and research activities have contributed to the deep understanding of nanoelectrocatalysis by reviewing some of the recent progress of various technologies. Finally, we explore the roles and the trend of these advanced nanomaterials in electrocatalysis with a focus on the properties and the design of materials.</description>
      <author>Juhan Lee, Rafael L. Zornitta, Katlego Makgopa, J.G. Gamaethiralalage, Modibane Desmond Kwena, Kumar Raju</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-55329-5_1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous TiN-based ceramic electrode with N-modified Co-based Nanorods/TiN heterointerfaces for efficient overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234722</link>
      <description>Chuntian Tan, Haisen Huang, Feihong Wang, Nianwang Ke, Anding Huang, Wangzhong Tang, Luyuan Hao, Liangjun Yin, Xin Xu, Yuxi Xian, Simeon Agathopoulos, Journal of power sources. 610(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398154955

                The development of high-performance electrocatalytic electrodes for overall water splitting is a crucial issue to realize renewable hydrogen production. This paper presents the in situ growth of N-modified Co-based nanorods on porous TiN ceramic membranes using the hydrothermal method and thermal NH3 treatment, resulting in a novel self-supported electrocatalytic electrode with abundant heterointerfaces, denoted as NCTN-x-y (x: nitridation temperature; y: nitridation time). In the alkaline medium (1 M KOH), the NCTN-350-2 electrode displays the best hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity (&#414;10 = 66 mV), and the NCTN-250-3 electrode manifests the best oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance (&#414;10 = 270 mV). Accordingly, these two electrodes comprise an electrolyzer, which features a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at a low cell voltage of 1.63 V. The good electrocatalytic performance can be attributed to the abundant heterointerfaces formed between the porous TiN ceramic membrane and the N-modified Co-based nanorods, in conjunction with the hierarchical pore structure of the TiN ceramic membrane. Theoretical calculations identify that the construction of heterointerfaces modulates the electronic structure of active sites, thereby promoting the dissociation of H2O, optimizing the H* adsorption energy (&#916;GH*), and accelerating the reaction kinetics, which ultimately improve the electrocatalytic activity of electrode.</description>
      <author>Chuntian Tan, Haisen Huang, Feihong Wang, Nianwang Ke, Anding Huang, Wangzhong Tang, Luyuan Hao, Liangjun Yin, Xin Xu, Yuxi Xian, Simeon Agathopoulos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co2 Electroreduction on Single Atom Catalysts: Role of the Local Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4836660</link>
      <description>Simon Emken, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398159410

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simon Emken, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4836660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclic Steady-State Simulation and Waveform Design for Dynamic/Programmable Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01543</link>
      <description>Consiglia Tedesco, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398161548

                Dynamic catalysis is a novel and promising approach that aims to improve the catalyst performance by modulating the binding energies of adsorbates to favor different reaction steps periodically. In this work, we investigate a unimolecular dynamic catalytic system, with a focus on methods for simulating the transient behavior and identifying the optimal wave parameters for the modulations. Employing the modeling language Pyomo and the solver IPOPT, we formulate a Boundary Value Problem with limit cycle conditions to obtain results with orders-of-magnitude improvements in computational efficiency when compared to forward integration methods. Leveraging this flexible approach, mathematical optimization was applied to the parameters of piecewise and continuous forcing functions to identify the maximum time-averaged turnover frequency (avTOF). We relate the results to the Extended Sabatier Volcano graphical representation, which provides insight into the behavior and optimal parameters of the target systems. Our results further support the notion that periodic shifts in rate-controlling elementary steps lead to a rate of reaction enhancement beyond the Sabatier limit.</description>
      <author>Consiglia Tedesco, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic modulation of the d-band center in Ni3S2 by selenium and iron for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.155</link>
      <description>Xu Song, Dongxu Jiao, Xiaowen Ruan, Zhaoyong Jin, Yu Qiu, Jinchang Fan, Lei Zhang, Weitao Zheng, Xiaoqiang Cui, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398164983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu Song, Dongxu Jiao, Xiaowen Ruan, Zhaoyong Jin, Yu Qiu, Jinchang Fan, Lei Zhang, Weitao Zheng, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate and Efficient Computation of the Fundamental Bandgap of the Vacancy-Ordered Double Perovskite Cs&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;TiBr&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07957</link>
      <description>J. E. Ingall, Edward Linscott, Nicola Colonna, Alister J. Page, V. J. Keast, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398165608

                Metal halide perovskites (MHPs) demonstrate an exceptional combination of properties. Rapid progress has extended their application beyond solar cells, light-emitting diodes, photodetectors, and lasers to include memristors, artificial synapse devices, and pressure induced emission. In particular, the vacancy-ordered double perovskite Cs2TiBr6 has been identified as a promising material. The effective characterization of MHPs requires accurate and efficient methods for the calculation of electronic structure. Koopmans compliant (KC) functionals are an accurate and computationally efficient alternative to many-body perturbation theory using the GW approximation but have yet only been validated on a small number of simple materials. In this work, KC functionals were applied to the more complex case of Cs2TiBr6 and gave a zero-temperature fundamental gap of 4.28 eV, in close agreement with the value of 4.44 eV obtained using the accurate, but more computationally expensive, evGW0 approach. The temperature-dependent renormalization of the bandgap has also been investigated and found to be significant. Agreement with the experimental optical bandgaps of 1.76&#8211;2.0 eV would also require the inclusion of exciton binding energy.</description>
      <author>J. E. Ingall, Edward Linscott, Nicola Colonna, Alister J. Page, V. J. Keast</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-type atomic Ru promoted bifunctional catalytic process realizing ultralow overpotential for Li-O2 batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124203</link>
      <description>Ya&#8208;Mei Guo, Peng Wang, Yunjie Liu, Shaojun Guo, Lei Shi, Jingrui Sun, Yu Tian, Xiaojun Wang, Shenlong Zhao, Zhiming Liu, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398165652

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya&#8208;Mei Guo, Peng Wang, Yunjie Liu, Shaojun Guo, Lei Shi, Jingrui Sun, Yu Tian, Xiaojun Wang, Shenlong Zhao, Zhiming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput investigation of stability and Li diffusion of doped solid electrolytes via neural network potential without configurational knowledge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62054-7</link>
      <description>Ryohto Sawada, Kosuke Nakago, Chikashi Shinagawa, So Takamoto, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398168460

                Solid electrolytes hold substantial promise as vital components of all-solid-state batteries. Enhancing their performance necessitates simultaneous improvements in their stability and lithium conductivity. These properties can be calculated using first-principles simulations, provided that the crystal structure of the material and the diffusion pathway through the material are known. However, solid electrolytes typically incorporate dopants to enhance their properties, necessitating the optimization of the dopant configuration for the simulations. Yet, performing such calculations via the first-principles approach is so costly that existing approaches usually rely on predetermined dopant configurations informed by existing knowledge or are limited to systems doped with only a few atoms. The proposed method enables the optimization of the dopant configuration with the support of neural network potential (NNP). Our approach entails the use of molecular dynamics to analyze the diffusion after the optimization of the dopant configuration. The application of our approach to Li</description>
      <author>Ryohto Sawada, Kosuke Nakago, Chikashi Shinagawa, So Takamoto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62054-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium&#8211;Nickel Nanoparticles with Unconventional Face&#8208;Centered Cubic Crystal Phase for Highly Active Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406259</link>
      <description>Kang Chen, Ziyang Liu, Shiyu Zhu, Yuan Liu, Yun Liu, Lingrui Wang, Tianyu Xia, Zhonglong Zhao, Gaorong Han, Shaobo Cheng, Haizhong Guo, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398168963

                Abstract Ru&#8208;based nanomaterials are promising alternatives to Pt electrocatalysts for green hydrogen energy generation, and crystal phase engineering holds the key to unlocking their catalytic potential to new heights. However, controllable phase regulation on Ru&#8208;alloys remains a formidable challenge, and unraveling the crystal phase&#8208;related electrocatalytic performance is of great significance. Herein, RuNi nanoparticles are successfully synthesized with an unconventional face&#8208;centered cubic ( fcc ) phase via a facile route. Comprehensive transmission electron microscopy confirmed the structural characteristics of the fcc &#8208;RuNi and electrochemical analyses indicate the impressive electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction of fcc &#8208;RuNi. Notably, the anomalous fcc &#8208;RuNi nanoparticles possess an extraordinarily low overpotential of 16 mV in hydrogen evolution. Density functional theory calculations indicate that these nanoparticles are energetically conducive to intermediate desorption and H 2 O dissociation. This study enhances comprehension of phase regulation in Ru&#8208;based nanostructures and will propel phase engineering in diverse catalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Kang Chen, Ziyang Liu, Shiyu Zhu, Yuan Liu, Yun Liu, Lingrui Wang, Tianyu Xia, Zhonglong Zhao, Gaorong Han, Shaobo Cheng, Haizhong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Main Group SnN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;O Single Sites with Optimized Charge Distribution for Boosting the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04112</link>
      <description>Xinyue Shao, Ruihui Gan, Yuan Rao, Ta Thi Thuy Nga, Mengfang Liang, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Chang Ma, Jin Yong Lee, Hao Li, Hyoyoung Lee, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398169098

                Transition metal single-atom catalysts (SACs) have been regarded as possible alternatives to platinum-based materials due to their satisfactory performance of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). By contrast, main-group metal elements are rarely studied due to their unfavorable surface and electronic states. Herein, a main-group Sn-based SAC with penta-coordinated and asymmetric first-shell ligands is reported as an efficient and robust ORR catalyst. The introduction of the vertical oxygen atom breaks the symmetric charge balance, modulating the binding strength to oxygen intermediates and decreasing the energy barrier for the ORR process. As expected, the prepared Sn SAC exhibits outstanding ORR activity with a high half-wave potential of 0.912 V (vs RHE) and an excellent mass activity of 13.1 A mg</description>
      <author>Xinyue Shao, Ruihui Gan, Yuan Rao, Ta Thi Thuy Nga, Mengfang Liang, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Chang Ma, Jin Yong Lee, Hao Li, Hyoyoung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V activated Ag-O catalytic sites for direct electro-epoxidation to successive producing propylene oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4390560/v1</link>
      <description>Zhongtao Li, Yan Lin, Xinyang Miao, Yi Sun, Hui Li, Hao Ren, Wenhao Cui, Mingbo Wu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398169124

                Abstract As one environmentally friendly and sustainable method, direct electrooxidation of propylene (D-EOPO) can successively produce propylene oxide, but the poor selectivity and activity of the catalyst hinder the application. To overcome the issues, a D-EOPO device based on a membrane electrode reactor (MEA) has been developed with optimized Ag-V-O/GDL catalyst to active oxygen formation for propylene epoxidation. In-situ spectroscopy and theoretical calculations have revealed the critical role of introduced V, which can accelerate the formation of Ag-O to decrease the generation energy barriers of O* from absorbed water on the catalyst surface. Moreover, the V doping also can attribute to a positive shift of the d-band center of Ag, and facilitate the adsorption of propylene on the active center. Thus, the formation of the key intermediate (OC3H6*) by coupling O* with adsorbed propylene is synergistic promoted, thereby enabling the efficiency of D-EOPO. Finally, the MEA reactor with the developed Ag/V bimetallic catalyst have been developed for continuous D-EOPO, which can steadily electrooxidize propylene to PO with a yield of 64.48 &#181;mol/h over 72 hours (almost the highest among currently reports).</description>
      <author>Zhongtao Li, Yan Lin, Xinyang Miao, Yi Sun, Hui Li, Hao Ren, Wenhao Cui, Mingbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4390560/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvothermal Fabrication of Mesoporous Pd Nano-Corals at Mild Temperature for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14100876</link>
      <description>Ming Zhao, K. Maruyama, Satoshi Tanaka, Nanomaterials. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398172348

                Porous metallic nanomaterials exhibit interesting physical and chemical properties, and are widely used in various fields. Traditional fabrication techniques are limited to metallurgy, sintering, electrodeposition, etc., which limit the control of pore size and distribution, and make it difficult to achieve materials with high surface areas. On the other hand, the chemical preparation of metallic nanoparticles is usually carried out with strong reducing agents or at high temperature, resulting in the formation of dispersed particles which cannot evolve into porous metal. In this study, we reported the simple fabrication of coral-like mesoporous Pd nanomaterial (Pd NC) with a ligament size of 4.1 nm. The fabrication was carried out by simple solvothermal reduction at a mild temperature of 135 &#176;C, without using any templates. The control experiments suggested that tetrabutylammonium bromide (TBAB) played a critical role in the Pd(II) reduction into Pd nanoclusters and their subsequent aggregation to form Pd NC, and another key point for the formation of Pd NC is not to use a strong reducing agent. In alkaline water electrolysis, the Pd NC outperforms the monodisperse Pd NPs and the state-of-the-art Pt (under large potentials) for H2 evolution reaction, probably due to its mesoporous structure and large surface area. This work reports a simple and novel method for producing porous metallic nanomaterials with a high utilization efficiency of metal atoms, and it is expected to contribute to the practical preparation of porous metallic nanomaterials by solvothermal reductions.</description>
      <author>Ming Zhao, K. Maruyama, Satoshi Tanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14100876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Electrocatalysis of Dual-Metal Atoms Sandwiched by Bn-Doped Graphdiyne and Graphdiyne Sheets on Nitrogen Reduction: A First Principle Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4835416</link>
      <description>Hao Sun, Zhenhua Liu, Manqi Li, Tian Gao, Shiyao Liu, Hui Yu, Zhao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398174889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Sun, Zhenhua Liu, Manqi Li, Tian Gao, Shiyao Liu, Hui Yu, Zhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4835416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Electron Donating and Withdrawing Groups on Electrochemical Hydrogenolysis and Hydrogenation of Carbonyl Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03032</link>
      <description>Jonah B. Eisenberg, Kwanpyung Lee, Xin Yuan, J. R. Schmidt, Kyoung&#8208;Shin Choi, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398175169

                The hydrogenolysis or hydrodeoxygenation of a carbonyl group, where the C&#9552;O group is converted to a CH</description>
      <author>Jonah B. Eisenberg, Kwanpyung Lee, Xin Yuan, J. R. Schmidt, Kyoung&#8208;Shin Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Phase Transition and Electrochemical Application of Mose2 Material for Energy Conversion and Storage Devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4835108</link>
      <description>Suddhasatwa Basu, Muthuraja Velpandian, Priyanka Gupta, Anshid Kuttasseri, Arup Mahata, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398176601

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suddhasatwa Basu, Muthuraja Velpandian, Priyanka Gupta, Anshid Kuttasseri, Arup Mahata</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4835108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving asymmetric redox chemistry for oxygen evolution reaction through strong metal-support interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.019</link>
      <description>Shihao Wang, Meiling Fan, Hongfei Pan, Jiahui Lyu, Jinsong Wu, Haolin Tang, Haining Zhang, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398177664

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shihao Wang, Meiling Fan, Hongfei Pan, Jiahui Lyu, Jinsong Wu, Haolin Tang, Haining Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Construction of Pt Incorporated Co3O4 as High-Performance Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110898</link>
      <description>Peijia Wang, Yaotian Yan, Bin Qin, Xiaohang Zheng, Wei Cai, Junlei Qi, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398178062

                Electrocatalysts in alkaline electrocatalytic water splitting are required to efficiently produce hydrogen while posing a challenge to show excellent performances. Herein, we have successfully synthesized platinum nanoparticles incorporated in a Co3O4 nanostructure (denoted as Pt-Co3O4) that show superior HER activity and stability in alkaline solutions (the overpotentials of 37 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2). The outstanding electrocatalytic activity originates from synergistic effects between Pt and Co3O4 and increased electron conduction. Theoretical calculations show a significant decrease in the &#916;GH* of Co active sites and a remarkable increase in electron transport. Our work puts forward a special and simple synthesized way of adjusting the H* adsorption energy of an inert site for application in HER.</description>
      <author>Peijia Wang, Yaotian Yan, Bin Qin, Xiaohang Zheng, Wei Cai, Junlei Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast Water Desalination with a Graphene&#8211;MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoporous Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01960</link>
      <description>Omid Barati Farimani, Zhonglin Cao, Amir Barati Farimani, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398179706

                Energy-efficient water desalination is the key to tackle the challenges with drought and water scarcity that affect 1.2 billion people. The material and type of membrane in reverse osmosis water desalination are the key factors in their efficiency. In this work, we explored the potential of a graphene-MoS</description>
      <author>Omid Barati Farimani, Zhonglin Cao, Amir Barati Farimani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Host-Guest-Induced Electronic State Triggers Two-Electron Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4393432/v1</link>
      <description>Xinggui Long, Hongni Chen, Chao Wang, Wei Han, Lili Li, Yali Xing, Chuanhui Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398182676

                Abstract Supramolecular polymers hold promising application prospects in catalysis due to their distinctive molecular recognition and dynamic crosslinking features. However, investigating supramolecular organic electrocatalysts with high efficiency in oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) to hydrogen peroxide (ORHP) remains an unexplored frontier. Herein, we present organic polymers for ORHP by introducing cyclodextrin-containing noncovalent building blocks, and the skeleton electronic environment is further regulated via a host-guest chemistry strategy, affording HG-CD-Ph and HG-CD-TPB with abundant dynamic bonds. The oxygen intermediate desorption and electronic states are well-modulated through the host-guest decoration, resulting in appropriate regional electron binding force and controllable chemical activity. Notably, the introduction of supramolecular host-guest units into the polymer model P-CN-Ph achieves an ultra-high production rate of 9.14 mol g&#8722;1 cat h&#8722;1, and demonstrates an excellent Faraday efficiency of 98.01%, surpassing most reported metal-free electrocatalysts. Supported by theory calculation and in situ FT-IR experiment, it is revealed that C atoms (site&#8211;1) adjacent to &#8211;C=N (N) group are potential active sites. Moreover, the dynamic bonds in supramolecular catalysts can effectively regulate the binding ability of oxygen and its intermediates, leading to high reactivity and selectivity for the 2e&#8722; ORR. This work pioneers host-guest strategy and provides inspiring ideas for the ORHP process.</description>
      <author>Xinggui Long, Hongni Chen, Chao Wang, Wei Han, Lili Li, Yali Xing, Chuanhui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4393432/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-performance RuO2/CNT paper electrode as cathode for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124220</link>
      <description>Jae&#8208;Yeop Jeong, Jong Min Lee, Yoo Sei Park, Song Jin, Seungjun Myeong, Sungjun Heo, Hoseok Lee, Justin Georg Albers, Young Woo Choi, Min Ho Seo, Sung Mook Choi, Jooyoung Lee, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398185320

                This study reports on the synthesis and characterization of an effective cathode paper electrode comprising comparatively inexpensive hydrous RuO2 (h-RuO2) nanoparticles on carbon nanotubes (CNT) for anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolysis. The concentration of hydrous RuO2 nanoparticles on the CNT was varied to assess their impact on the electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The electrocatalytic performance of h-RuO2/CNT comprising 22.0 wt% of Ru was evaluated. Promising results were obtained, with a current density of -10 mA/cm2 at only 36 mV of overpotential and a mass activity of -2.41 A/gRu at 100 mV. Additionally, we conducted first-principles calculations to compare the HER catalytic activities of crystalline RuO2 and hydrous RuO2 with varying vacancies and to determine the H2O concentration in the structural lattice using free-energy diagrams. The study findings demonstrate that the h-RuO2/CNT paper can be used as an efficient electrocatalyst for AEM water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Jae&#8208;Yeop Jeong, Jong Min Lee, Yoo Sei Park, Song Jin, Seungjun Myeong, Sungjun Heo, Hoseok Lee, Justin Georg Albers, Young Woo Choi, Min Ho Seo, Sung Mook Choi, Jooyoung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial heteroatom (P, S and Cl)-decorated Fe single-atom catalyst for the oxygen reduction reaction: a DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra01754d</link>
      <description>Qunji Xue, Xuede Qi, Kun Li, Yi Zeng, Xu Feng, Kai Zhang, Xueqiang Qi, Li Li, Andreu Cabot, RSC advances. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398187877

                Overpotential and &#916; G (*OH) have a volcanic relationship, the catalytic process is hindered by too strong or too weak interaction between catalyst and adsorbate. ORR is constrained in strong binding region by the reduction of *OH to H 2 O.</description>
      <author>Qunji Xue, Xuede Qi, Kun Li, Yi Zeng, Xu Feng, Kai Zhang, Xueqiang Qi, Li Li, Andreu Cabot</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra01754d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering atomically dispersed dual Pt&#8211;Ni sites on nitrogen-doped carbon with spherical core-shell structure for enhanced oxygen reduction activity towards microbial fuel cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234747</link>
      <description>Wenyi Wang, Long Tang, Cheng Chen, Yuanyuan Wang, Wencong Sun, Xueqin Wang, Yijian Jiang, Haiyan Liu, Journal of power sources. 610(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398190594

                Inspired by the development of efficient, durable electrocatalytic functional materials to address the issues of kinetic retardation and mass transport to enhance oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), one strategy is proposed for core-shell structural nitrogen-doped carbon with atomically dispersed binary platinum-nickel (Pt&#8211;Ni) atoms (N&#8211;C@Pt&#8211;Ni/N&#8211;C) with controlled bimetallic sites and adjusted electronic coordination environment. Practical application of experimental and simulated theoretical calculation results show the coordination microenvironment optimization for active site can promote the charge rearrangement of Pt&#8211;Ni sites, thus regulating the free energy of the reaction intermediates of oxygen-containing species. The N&#8211;C@Pt&#8211;Ni/N&#8211;C reveals astounding catalytic capacity during ORR, leading to a large power density (1472.6 &#177; 50.6 mW m&#8722;2) and long-term reliability (OCP by the current loss with 0.1 mA) in the actual microbial fuel cells. This work not only reveals controllable preparation of functional materials with binary isolated atomic dispersion, but also presents more perspective of electronic structure optimal performance enhancement relationship at the atomic-sized active sites.</description>
      <author>Wenyi Wang, Long Tang, Cheng Chen, Yuanyuan Wang, Wencong Sun, Xueqin Wang, Yijian Jiang, Haiyan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow-Nanostructured Ptco Alloy Advances Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysis in Polymer Electrolyte Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4837701</link>
      <description>Muhammad Iqbal Maulana, Ha-Young Lee, Caleb Gyan-Barimah, Jong Hun Sung, Jong&#8208;Sung Yu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398193456

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Iqbal Maulana, Ha-Young Lee, Caleb Gyan-Barimah, Jong Hun Sung, Jong&#8208;Sung Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4837701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclo[16]carbon through the lens of density functional theory: Role of impurity decoration in hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.236</link>
      <description>Ashvin Kanzariya, Shardul Vadalkar, L. K. Saini, Prafulla K. Jha, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398196581

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashvin Kanzariya, Shardul Vadalkar, L. K. Saini, Prafulla K. Jha</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D carbon nanotubene and its hetero-bimetal-contain derivatives: A new family of carbon allotropes for promoting CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120279</link>
      <description>Yuhan Mei, Hui Huang, Youshen Xia, Yihui Bao, Houyang Chen, Chemical engineering science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398198996

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhan Mei, Hui Huang, Youshen Xia, Yihui Bao, Houyang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refining the Active Phases of Silver/Nickle-based Catalysts Achieves a Highly-Selective Reduction of Nitrate to Ammonium at Low Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124224</link>
      <description>Yingyang Jiang, Degui Kong, Liangbin Huang, Shilu Wu, Peng Xu, Ling Ye, Xuemei Zhou, Jinjie Qian, Hao Tang, Yifei Ge, Jia Guan, Zhi Yang, Huagui Nie, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398200903

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingyang Jiang, Degui Kong, Liangbin Huang, Shilu Wu, Peng Xu, Ling Ye, Xuemei Zhou, Jinjie Qian, Hao Tang, Yifei Ge, Jia Guan, Zhi Yang, Huagui Nie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarifying sequential electron-transfer steps in single-nanoparticle electrochemical process for identifying the intrinsic activity of electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60015-x</link>
      <description>Zixiong Sun, Zhuangzhuang Lai, Yingying Zhao, Jianfu Chen, Wei Ma, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398201156

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zixiong Sun, Zhuangzhuang Lai, Yingying Zhao, Jianfu Chen, Wei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60015-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the electronic state of ruthenium to boost highly selective electrooxidation of ethylene to ethylene glycol in acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60024-0</link>
      <description>Jie Wang, Y. L. Chen, Yuda Wang, Hong Zhao, Jinyu Ye, Qian Cheng, Hui Yang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398201266

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Wang, Y. L. Chen, Yuda Wang, Hong Zhao, Jinyu Ye, Qian Cheng, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60024-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering oxygen-evolving catalysts for acidic water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0200438</link>
      <description>Xuan Minh Chau Ta, Th&#224;nh Tr&#7847;n&#8208;Ph&#250;, Thi Kim Anh Nguyen, Manjunath Chatti, Rahman Daiyan, Applied physics reviews. 11(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398206370

                The utilization of water electrolysis for green hydrogen (H2) production, powered by renewable energy, is a promising avenue for sustainable development. Proton-exchange-membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) stands out as one of the most efficient H2 production technologies. However, implementing it on an industrial scale faces substantial challenges, particularly regarding the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The OER, a critical process with inherently slow kinetics requiring additional potential, significantly influences overall water-splitting efficiency. Most OER electrocatalysts in PEMWE struggle with poor stability in harsh acidic environments at high oxidative potentials. While rare-earth metal oxides, such as iridium or ruthenium oxides, offer stability in commercial oxygen-evolving electrocatalysts (OECs), their use depends on achieving economically and sustainably viable operations. An alternative approach involves developing low- or non-noble metal-based OECs with sustaining high activity and long-term durability. Although such materials currently exhibit lower activity and stability than noble-based OECs, notable progress has been made in enhancing their performance. This review provides an overview of recent advancements in designing acidic-stable OECs based on low or without noble metal contents. It delves into the thermodynamics and degradation mechanisms of OECs in acidic media, evaluation parameters for activity and stability, strategies for developing active and acid-stable OECs, and the challenges and opportunities of acid water electrolysis. Through a detailed analysis of these aspects, the review aims to identify opportunities for engineering actively durable OECs.</description>
      <author>Xuan Minh Chau Ta, Th&#224;nh Tr&#7847;n&#8208;Ph&#250;, Thi Kim Anh Nguyen, Manjunath Chatti, Rahman Daiyan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0200438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Ordered C-Rich Carbon Nitride Nanomaterials with Pyrrole and Imidazole Moieties for Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting through Built-In Electric Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01127</link>
      <description>Dong&#8208;Chun Yang, Ran Jia, Xin Wang, Shuming Bai, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398207920

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dong&#8208;Chun Yang, Ran Jia, Xin Wang, Shuming Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge sites dominate the hydrogen evolution reaction on platinum nanocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01156-x</link>
      <description>Zhihong Huang, Tao Cheng, Aamir Hassan Shah, Guangyan Zhong, Chunru Wan, Peiqi Wang, Mengning Ding, Jin Huang, Weide Zhong, Sibo Wang, Jing Cai, Bosi Peng, Haotian Liu, Yu Huang, William A. Goddard, Xiangfeng Duan, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398209411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhihong Huang, Tao Cheng, Aamir Hassan Shah, Guangyan Zhong, Chunru Wan, Peiqi Wang, Mengning Ding, Jin Huang, Weide Zhong, Sibo Wang, Jing Cai, Bosi Peng, Haotian Liu, Yu Huang, William A. Goddard, Xiangfeng Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01156-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-enabled fast exploration of stable and active single-atom catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59717/j.xinn-mater.2024.100072</link>
      <description>Woonghyeon Park, Juhwan Noh, Geun Ho Gu, Ga Eun Nam, Sang&#8208;Mun Jung, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Yousung Jung, &#152;The &#156;Innovation materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398211163

                &lt;p&gt;Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can convert renewable energy into hydrogen through water electrolysis. Identifying stable and active single-atom catalysts (SACs) for OER under acidic conditions holds great promise for developing cost-effective and efficient energy storage solutions, but challenging due to the vast number of potential material compositions and diverse surface morphologies. Here, to accelerate new discoveries, we present a high-throughput screening (HTS) framework that leverages the power of machine learning (ML) and density functional theory (DFT). The proposed framework includes an assessment of both the thermodynamic and electrochemical stability of support surfaces. In addition, the integration of ML and uncertainty quantification for predicting the binding energies dramatically reduces the computational cost (by over a factor of 10), facilitating the identification of catalytically active SACs. Following the proposed scheme, we suggest 14 new promising SACs for OER across the 795 binary oxide supports and 21 transition metal atom combinations. These catalysts are found to break the scaling relation due to the enhanced *OOH binding with the support, which arises from favorable hydrogen bonding interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Woonghyeon Park, Juhwan Noh, Geun Ho Gu, Ga Eun Nam, Sang&#8208;Mun Jung, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Yousung Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59717/j.xinn-mater.2024.100072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on fundamentals for designing stable ruthenium-based catalysts for the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60013-6</link>
      <description>Wangyan Gou, Yichen Wang, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398224626

                Clean and renewable energy is generally localized and intermittent. Thus, energy conversion and storage technologies are necessary to compensate for these shortcomings. Electrolytic water splitting presents a reliable and promising energy technology for producing high purity hydrogen (H2). Among the platinum metals, ruthenium (Ru) has gained significant attentions as it generally outperforms commercial catalysts in terms of activity at a more affordable price. Although great progress has been made in improving the catalytic activity of Ru-based catalysts, stability remains a major challenge hindering their practical applications. To this end, this review introduces the fundamentals of the stability over Ru-based catalysts for water splitting, including the reaction mechanisms of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), measurement methods and evaluation criteria, as well as deactivation mechanisms. Moreover, the up-to-date advances of representative strategies for improving HER and OER stability of Ru-based catalysts are further discussed with respect to specific design principles and underlying mechanisms. Ultimately, insights into the challenges and opportunities for Ru-based electrocatalysts are provided to promote the development of next-generation Ru-based catalysts with exceptional stability. This review aims at guiding the design and synthesis of superior catalysts, generating increased interest among researchers, and stimulating further advanced research.</description>
      <author>Wangyan Gou, Yichen Wang, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60013-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CALPHAD-based modeling of pressure-dependent Al, Cu and Li unary systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.calphad.2024.102692</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Mathew, Rupesh Chafle, Benjamin Klusemann, Calphad. 85(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398231459

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Mathew, Rupesh Chafle, Benjamin Klusemann</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.calphad.2024.102692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal polyoxometalates with reduced graphene oxide for high-performance air-electrode of metal-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.229</link>
      <description>Filipe M. B. Gusm&#227;o, Teodora &#272;uri&#263;, Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Kristina Radinovi&#263;, Diogo M.F. Santos, Dalibor M. Stankovi&#263;, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398231572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Filipe M. B. Gusm&#227;o, Teodora &#272;uri&#263;, Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Kristina Radinovi&#263;, Diogo M.F. Santos, Dalibor M. Stankovi&#263;, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Platinum Bimetallic Surfaces, M/Pt(111) and Pt/M/Pt(111) (M = Mo, Zn, and Co), for Furfural Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00467</link>
      <description>Fahime Khouini, Morteza Vahedpour, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398234785

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fahime Khouini, Morteza Vahedpour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation Effects on the Adsorbed Intermediates of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Are Systematic and Predictable</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00727</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Sargeant, Paramaconi Rodr&#237;guez, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398251204

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Sargeant, Paramaconi Rodr&#237;guez, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Negatively Charged Pt Single Atoms on Amorphous Ni(OH)2 Nanosheets with Promoted Hydrogen Absorption in Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01420-6</link>
      <description>Y. Liu, Gui Liu, Xiangyu Chen, Cun Xue, Mingxuan Sun, Yifei Liu, Jian Kang, Xiujuan Sun, Xiaotian Wang, Nano-micro letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398251721

                Abstract Single-atom (SA) catalysts with nearly 100% atom utilization have been widely employed in electrolysis for decades, due to the outperforming catalytic activity and selectivity. However, most of the reported SA catalysts are fixed through the strong bonding between the dispersed single metallic atoms with nonmetallic atoms of the substrates, which greatly limits the controllable regulation of electrocatalytic activity of SA catalysts. In this work, Pt&#8211;Ni bonded Pt SA catalyst with adjustable electronic states was successfully constructed through a controllable electrochemical reduction on the coordination unsaturated amorphous Ni(OH) 2 nanosheet arrays. Based on the X-ray absorption fine structure analysis and first-principles calculations, Pt SA was bonded with Ni sites of amorphous Ni(OH) 2 , rather than conventional O sites, resulting in negatively charged Pt &#948; &#8722; . In situ Raman spectroscopy revealed that the changed configuration and electronic states greatly enhanced absorbability for activated hydrogen atoms, which were the essential intermediate for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction. The hydrogen spillover process was revealed from amorphous Ni(OH) 2 that effectively cleave the H&#8211;O&#8211;H bond of H 2 O and produce H atom to the Pt SA sites, leading to a low overpotential of 48 mV in alkaline electrolyte at &#8722;1000 mA cm &#8722;2 mg &#8722;1 Pt , evidently better than commercial Pt/C catalysts. This work provided new strategy for the controllable modulation of the local structure of SA catalysts and the systematic regulation of the electronic states.</description>
      <author>Y. Liu, Gui Liu, Xiangyu Chen, Cun Xue, Mingxuan Sun, Yifei Liu, Jian Kang, Xiujuan Sun, Xiaotian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01420-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress and perspective on electrocatalysis in neutral media: Mechanisms, materials, and advanced characterizations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/idm2.12172</link>
      <description>Fu-Shun Lai, Haochuan Shang, Yuechao Jiao, Xinyi Chen, Tianran Zhang, Xiangfeng Liu, Interdisciplinary materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398252762

                Abstract Electrocatalysis, which involves oxidation and reduction reactions with direct electron transfer, is essential for a variety of clean energy conversion devices. Currently, the vast majority of studies regarding electrocatalysis reactions focus on strong acidic or alkaline media because of the higher catalytic activity. Nevertheless, some inherent drawbacks, including the corrosive environment, expensive proton exchange membranes, and side effects, are still hard to break through. A sustainably promising way to overcome these shortcomings is to deploy neutral/near&#8208;neutral electrolytes for electrocatalysis reactions. Unfortunately, insufficient research in this area due to the lack of attention to related issues has slowed down the development process. In this review, we systematically review the catalytic reaction mechanisms, neutral electrolytes, electrocatalysts, and modification strategies carried out in neutral media on the three most common electrocatalytic reactions, that is, hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, and oxygen evolution reaction. Furthermore, the advanced characterization tools for guiding catalyst synthesis and mechanistic studies are also summarized. Eventually, we propose some challenges and perspectives on electrocatalysis reactions in neutral media and hope it will attract more research interest and provide guidance in neutral electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Fu-Shun Lai, Haochuan Shang, Yuechao Jiao, Xinyi Chen, Tianran Zhang, Xiangfeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/idm2.12172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy nanostructured electrocatalysts for water and carbon dioxide electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2967-2</link>
      <description>Genxiang Wang, Junxiang Chen, Zhenhai Wen, Shanpeng Li, Science China. Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398253444

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Genxiang Wang, Junxiang Chen, Zhenhai Wen, Shanpeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2967-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Analysis of Chemical Descriptors by Machine Learning Reveals Atomistic Insights into Solute&#8211;Lipid Interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.4c00080</link>
      <description>Johan F. Lange, Andrea Anelli, Jochem Alsenz, Martin Kuentz, P. J. O&#8217;Dwyer, Wiebke Saal, Nicole Wyttenbach, Brendan T. Griffin, Molecular pharmaceutics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398465851

                This study explores the research area of drug solubility in lipid excipients, an area persistently complex despite recent advancements in understanding and predicting solubility based on molecular structure. To this end, this research investigated novel descriptor sets, employing machine learning techniques to understand the determinants governing interactions between solutes and medium-chain triglycerides (MCTs). Quantitative structure-property relationships (QSPR) were constructed on an extended solubility data set comprising 182 experimental values of structurally diverse drug molecules, including both development and marketed drugs to extract meaningful property relationships. Four classes of molecular descriptors, ranging from traditional representations to complex geometrical descriptions, were assessed and compared in terms of their predictive accuracy and interpretability. These include two-dimensional (2D) and three-dimensional (3D) descriptors, Abraham solvation parameters, extended connectivity fingerprints (ECFPs), and the smooth overlap of atomic position (SOAP) descriptor. Through testing three distinct regularized regression algorithms alongside various preprocessing schemes, the SOAP descriptor enabled the construction of a superior performing model in terms of interpretability and accuracy. Its atom-centered characteristics allowed contributions to be estimated at the atomic level, thereby enabling the ranking of prevalent molecular motifs and their influence on drug solubility in MCTs. The performance on a separate test set demonstrated high predictive accuracy (RMSE = 0.50) for 2D and 3D, SOAP, and Abraham Solvation descriptors. The model trained on ECFP4 descriptors resulted in inferior predictive accuracy. Lastly, uncertainty estimations for each model were introduced to assess their applicability domains and provide information on where the models may extrapolate in chemical space and, thus, where more data may be necessary to refine a data-driven approach to predict solubility in MCTs. Overall, the presented approaches further enable computationally informed formulation development by introducing a novel in silico approach for rational drug development and prediction of dose loading in lipids.</description>
      <author>Johan F. Lange, Andrea Anelli, Jochem Alsenz, Martin Kuentz, P. J. O&#8217;Dwyer, Wiebke Saal, Nicole Wyttenbach, Brendan T. Griffin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.4c00080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monolayer Ta2Se: A low-cost catalyst with enhanced stability and high basal plane activity for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100851</link>
      <description>Hongbo Wu, Weizhen Meng, Fengxian Ma, Yalong Jiao, Materials today sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398762454

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongbo Wu, Weizhen Meng, Fengxian Ma, Yalong Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Localization of Hot Carriers in Au144(SCH3)60 Clusters Doped with Copper</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109348</link>
      <description>Junais Habeeb Mokkath, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398765585

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junais Habeeb Mokkath</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-level precision engineering: Single-atom catalysts with controlled loading density for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160384</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Li, Jingcheng Xu, Daming Liu, Jiyuan Yang, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Z.S Wang, Xinyang Liu, L.-L. Jia, Yazi Liu, Congfei Yao, Yuhao Li, Zichao Lian, Weiwei Yang, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398765970

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Li, Jingcheng Xu, Daming Liu, Jiyuan Yang, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Z.S Wang, Xinyang Liu, L.-L. Jia, Yazi Liu, Congfei Yao, Yuhao Li, Zichao Lian, Weiwei Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Investigation of LiF Formation at Graphite&#8211;Electrolyte Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01719</link>
      <description>Xueping Qin, Arghya Bhowmik, Tejs Vegge, Ivano E. Castelli, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398771699

                The performance of rechargeable batteries is strongly influenced by the solid&#8211;electrolyte interphase (SEI), and a comprehensive understanding of SEI formation from the atomic level is crucial for effective battery design. The dynamics of the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface is important and needs to be considered when evaluating the mechanism of the SEI formation. Here, we employed ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) and density functional theory (DFT) calculations to examine interfacial behaviors and LiF formation. Through molecular dynamics and structure sampling, we successfully constructed an electrochemical stability diagram correlating the thermodynamic free energy with the potential, which is determined by the work function of electrode surfaces. DFT calculations revealed that LiF formation at the graphite&#8211;electrolyte interfaces occurs easily via the intermediate LiHF complex. Interestingly, LiF tends to be solvated by solvents rather than directly deposited onto electrode surfaces (e.g., the Au electrode), a phenomenon we identify as a critical determinant of the porous and uneven nature of the LiF layer observed on graphite electrodes. Our finding offers new mechanistic insights into LiF formation at graphite&#8211;electrolyte interfaces.</description>
      <author>Xueping Qin, Arghya Bhowmik, Tejs Vegge, Ivano E. Castelli</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01719</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Approach toward Predicting Coverage-Dependent Surface Free Energies on Transition-Metal Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08106</link>
      <description>Asmee M. Prabhu, Tej S. Choksi, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398776985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asmee M. Prabhu, Tej S. Choksi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the surface Pt coordination environment in the PtN overlayers on PtCuN hollow nanospheres for efficient oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119817</link>
      <description>Xiashuang Luo, Cehuang Fu, Zulipiya Shadike, Liang Ma, Lu An, Liuxuan Luo, Yi Guo, Jiewei Yin, Xiaohui Yan, Meng He, Shuiyun Shen, Junliang Zhang, Applied catalysis. A, General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398780525

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiashuang Luo, Cehuang Fu, Zulipiya Shadike, Liang Ma, Lu An, Liuxuan Luo, Yi Guo, Jiewei Yin, Xiaohui Yan, Meng He, Shuiyun Shen, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Oxygen Vacancies with Different Valence States on the Photo(electro)catalytic Performance of a 2D TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;:N (001) System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c01809</link>
      <description>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Shaoqiang Guo, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398781021

                The effect of different valence states Vo on the photo(electro)catalytic performance of the 2D TiO2:N system was investigated using the GGA+U method with first principles. In the poor oxygen conditions, the Ef values of 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0/Vo1+/Vo2+) systems are all less than zero, and all of them are exothermic. Photocatalytic investigations revealed that among the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo1+), 2D Ti24O46N (Vo2+), and 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) systems, the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system has the best carrier activity, the longest electron&#8211;hole lifetime, prominent visible light, infrared light redshift, and outstanding oxidation ability. The photocatalytic decomposition of water and oxygen evolution is highly advantageous. Electrocatalytic studies showed that compared with the free energy of 2D Ti24O46N (Vo1+) and 2D Ti24O46N (Vo2+) systems the free energy &#916;GH* of the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system is &#8722;0.156 eV and the smallest, which is conducive to hydrogen evolution. The overpotential of the oxygen evolution reaction is 0.360 V, which is close to zero, and the four reaction processes are all downward, indicating that the OER reaction can be driven independently by the photogenerated holes, which is conducive to the electrocatalytic reaction. Moreover, the ability of decomposing water is relatively good. The 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system is a candidate nanomaterial and can be applied as a novel photoelectric catalyst.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Shaoqiang Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c01809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-the-fly kinetic Monte Carlo simulations with neural network potentials for surface diffusion and reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0199240</link>
      <description>Tomoko Yokaichiya, Takao Ikeda, Koki Muraoka, Akira Nakayama, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398781168

                We develop an adaptive scheme in the kinetic Monte Carlo simulations, where the adsorption and activation energies of all elementary steps, including the effects of other adsorbates, are evaluated &#8220;on-the-fly&#8221; by employing the neural network potentials. The configurations and energies evaluated during the simulations are stored for reuse when the same configurations are sampled in a later step. The present scheme is applied to hydrogen adsorption and diffusion on the Pd(111) and Pt(111) surfaces and the CO oxidation reaction on the Pt(111) surface. The effects of interactions between adsorbates, i.e., adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate lateral interactions, are examined in detail by comparing the simulations without considering lateral interactions. This study demonstrates the importance of lateral interactions in surface diffusion and reactions and the potential of our scheme for applications in a wide variety of heterogeneous catalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Tomoko Yokaichiya, Takao Ikeda, Koki Muraoka, Akira Nakayama</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0199240</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Analysis of R-X Oxidative Addition to Pd Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc00628c</link>
      <description>Mikhail V. Polynski, Yulia S. Vlasova, Yaroslav V. Solovev, Sergey M. Kozlov, Valentine P. Ananikov, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398787658

                Oxidative addition (OA) is a necessary step in mechanisms of widely used synthetic methodologies such as the Heck reaction, cross-coupling reactions, and the Buchwald-Hartwig amination. This study pioneers the exploration...</description>
      <author>Mikhail V. Polynski, Yulia S. Vlasova, Yaroslav V. Solovev, Sergey M. Kozlov, Valentine P. Ananikov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc00628c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amine-functionalized macroporous resin for direct air capture with high CO2 capacity in real atmospheric conditions: Effects of moisture and oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127999</link>
      <description>Zhao Shu, Yiran Zhang, Linjia Li, Jiaqi Feng, Qiuping Wei, Yijun Wang, Zhen Huang, Hong Lin, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397043380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhao Shu, Yiran Zhang, Linjia Li, Jiaqi Feng, Qiuping Wei, Yijun Wang, Zhen Huang, Hong Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Correlation between the Interface Structures and Tunable Magnetic Properties of La&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;CoO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;/La&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;MnO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; Bilayers Using Deep Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c18773</link>
      <description>Hong Sun, Vincenzo Lordi, Yayoi Takamura, Amit Samanta, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398395216

                Perovskite oxides are gaining significant attention for use in next-generation magnetic and ferroelectric devices due to their exceptional charge transport properties and the opportunity to tune the charge, spin, lattice, and orbital degrees of freedom. Interfaces between perovskite oxides, exemplified by La1&#8211;xSrxCoO3&#8722;&#948;/La1&#8211;xSrxMnO3&#8722;&#948; (LSCO/LSMO) bilayers, exhibit unconventional magnetic exchange switching behavior, offering a pathway for innovative designs in perovskite oxide-based devices. However, the precise atomic-level stoichiometric compositions and chemophysical properties of these interfaces remain elusive, hindering the establishment of surrogate design principles. We leverage first-principles simulations, evolutionary algorithms, and neural network searches with on-the-fly uncertainty quantification to design deep learning model ensembles to investigate over 50,000 LSCO/LSMO bilayer structures as a function of oxygen deficiency (&#948;) and strontium concentration (x). Structural analysis of the low-energy interface structures reveals that preferential segregation of oxygen vacancies toward the interfacial La0.7Sr0.3CoO3&#8722;&#948; layers causes distortion of the CoOx polyhedra and the emergence of magnetically active Co2+ ions. At the same time, an increase in the Sr concentration and a decrease in oxygen vacancies in the La0.7Sr0.3MnO3&#8722;&#948; layers tend to retain MnO6 octahedra and promote the formation of Mn4+ ions. Electronic structure analysis reveals that the nonuniform distributions of Sr ions and oxygen vacancies on both sides of the interface can alter the local magnetization at the interface, showing a transition from ferromagnetic (FM) to local antiferromagnetic (AFM) or ferrimagnetic regions. Therefore, the exotic properties of La1&#8211;xSrxCoO3&#8722;&#948;/La1&#8211;xSrxMnO3&#8722;&#948; are strongly coupled to the presence of hard/soft magnetic layers, as well as the FM to AFM transition at the interface, and can be tuned by changing the Sr concentration and oxygen partial pressure during growth. These insights provide valuable guidance for the precise design of perovskite oxide multilayers, enabling tailoring of their functional properties to meet specific requirements for various device applications.</description>
      <author>Hong Sun, Vincenzo Lordi, Yayoi Takamura, Amit Samanta</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c18773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An overview about neural networks potentials in molecular dynamics simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.27389</link>
      <description>Raidel Martin&#8208;Barrios, Edisel Navas&#8208;Conyedo, Xuyi Zhang, Yunwei Chen, Jorge Gul&#237;n&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, International journal of quantum chemistry. 124(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398217329

                Abstract Ab&#8208;initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) is a key method for realistic simulation of complex atomistic systems and processes in nanoscale. In AIMD, finite&#8208;temperature dynamical trajectories are generated by using forces computed from electronic structure calculations. In systems with high numbers of components a typical AIMD run is computationally demanding. On the other hand, machine learning (ML) is a subfield of the artificial intelligence that consist in a set of algorithms that show learning by experience with the use of input and output data where algorithms are capable of analysing and predicting the future. At present, the main application of ML techniques in atomic simulations is the development of new interatomic potentials to correctly describe the potential energy surfaces (PES). This technique is in constant progress since its inception around 30 years ago. The ML potentials combine the advantages of classical and Ab&#8208;initio methods, that is, the efficiency of a simple functional form and the accuracy of first principles calculations. In this article we review the evolution of four generations of machine learning potentials and some of their most notable applications. This review focuses on MLPs based on neural networks. Also, we present a state of art of this topic and future trends. Finally, we report the results of a scientometric study (covering the period 1995&#8211;2023) about the impact of ML techniques applied to atomistic simulations, distribution of publications by geographical regions and hot topics investigated in the literature.</description>
      <author>Raidel Martin&#8208;Barrios, Edisel Navas&#8208;Conyedo, Xuyi Zhang, Yunwei Chen, Jorge Gul&#237;n&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.27389</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A systematic &lt;scp&gt;DFT&lt;/scp&gt; study of structure and electronic properties of titanium dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27376</link>
      <description>Asma Marzouk, Konstantinos D. Papavasileiou, Loukas D. Peristeras, G. Leendert Bezemer, Alexander P. van Bavel, Prathamesh M. Shenai, Ioannis G. Economou, Journal of computational chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398768314

                Abstract DFT functionals are of paramount importance for an accurate electronic and structural description of transition metal systems. In this work, a systematic analysis using some well&#8208;known and commonly used DFT functionals is performed. A comparison of the structural and energetic parameters calculated with the available experimental data is made in order to find the adequate functional for an accurate description of the TiO 2 bulk and surface of both anatase and rutile structures. In the absence of experimental data on the surface energy, the theoretical predictions obtained using the high&#8208;accuracy HSE06 functional were used as a reference to compare against the surface energy values calculated with the other DFT functionals. A clear improvement in the electronic description of both anatase and rutile was observed by introducing the Hubbard U correction term to PBE, PW91, and OptPBE functionals. The OptPBE&#8208; U 4 functional was found to offer a good compromise between accurately describing the structural and electronic properties of titania.</description>
      <author>Asma Marzouk, Konstantinos D. Papavasileiou, Loukas D. Peristeras, G. Leendert Bezemer, Alexander P. van Bavel, Prathamesh M. Shenai, Ioannis G. Economou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27376</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
