<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 01:27:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Liquid Crystalline Materials Based on Interfacial Photocatalytic Processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03397</link>
      <description>Ayushi Tripathi, Trenton J. Wolter, Robert J. Twieg, Manos Mavrikakis, Nicholas L. Abbott, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409577870

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ayushi Tripathi, Trenton J. Wolter, Robert J. Twieg, Manos Mavrikakis, Nicholas L. Abbott</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Layer Deposition of PdRu&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Alloy Nanoparticles for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00794</link>
      <description>Yu Liu, Tao&#8208;Qing Zi, Yue Huang, Shuai Zhang, Jawad Ali Shah Syed, Li Gao, Wei-Min Li, Aidong Li, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409579688

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Liu, Tao&#8208;Qing Zi, Yue Huang, Shuai Zhang, Jawad Ali Shah Syed, Li Gao, Wei-Min Li, Aidong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00794</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pulsed Tandem Electrocatalysis Strategy for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00633</link>
      <description>Hao Sun, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409582450

                Electroreduction of CO2 to value-added C2 products remains hindered by sluggish C-C coupling kinetics and competing side reactions. Inspired by the tandem catalytic mechanisms of multienzyme systems, we designed a dual-site single-atom nanozyme (DSAN) comprising FeN4 and FeO4 sites (FeN4-FeO4). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations under constant potential reveal that the FeN4 site functions as a CO generator, while the FeO4 site facilitates CO migration, C-C coupling, and subsequent C2 product formation. To further optimize the catalytic efficiency, we introduced a pulsed electrocatalysis strategy by alternating between zero potential and -0.7 V. This approach dynamically modulates active-site functions: at -0.70 V, CO2 adsorption and *CH3CH2OH formation are facilitated, while at 0 V, CO migration and C-C coupling are enhanced due to the spin-state transitions during potential switching. Additionally, the zero potential suppresses excessive hydrogenation of key intermediates, thereby improving CH3CH2OH selectivity. These findings highlight the synergistic strategy integrating tandem catalysis and pulsed potential control, offering a novel and effective approach for CO2-to-C2 conversion using SAN catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hao Sun, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00633</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic electroreduction of nitrate to ammonia via bimetallic Fe-Cu sites supported on hierarchical porous carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tramat.2025.100030</link>
      <description>Yu Li, Pengpeng Qiu, Chunhong Qi, Minghao Li, Meng Xie, Guihua Zhu, Wei Luo, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409583434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Li, Pengpeng Qiu, Chunhong Qi, Minghao Li, Meng Xie, Guihua Zhu, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tramat.2025.100030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ formation of SrCO3 microcrystals-decorated Fe3O4 nanosheets as an efficient and long-lasting catalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162842</link>
      <description>Amina Lahrichi, Youness El Issmaeli, Bruno G. Pollet, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409590121

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amina Lahrichi, Youness El Issmaeli, Bruno G. Pollet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational insights into the photocatalytic conversion of CO2 to C2H4 on synergistic dual sites in tandem rhenium-bipyridine/copper-porphyrinic system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116144</link>
      <description>Debo Ding, Xiahe Chen, Hongli Wu, Hai&#8208;Min Shen, Teng&#8208;Shuo Zhang, Keke Wang, Yun&#8208;Fang Yang, Yuanbin She, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409605256

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Debo Ding, Xiahe Chen, Hongli Wu, Hai&#8208;Min Shen, Teng&#8208;Shuo Zhang, Keke Wang, Yun&#8208;Fang Yang, Yuanbin She</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Study on the CO2 Reduction Reaction (CO2RR) Performance of h-BN-Based Single-Atom Catalysts Modified with Transition Metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15080628</link>
      <description>Xiansheng Yu, Can Zhao, Qiaoyue Chen, Wei Lai, Xucai Zhao, Lili Zhang, Liqian Wu, Yineng Huang, Nanomaterials. 15(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409607392

                The reasonable design of low-cost, high-activity single-atom catalysts (SACs) is crucial for achieving highly efficient electrochemical CO2RR. In this study, we systematically explore, using density functional theory (DFT), the performance of transition metal (TM = Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn)-doped defect-type hexagonal boron nitride (h-BN) SACs TM@B&#8722;1N (B vacancy) and TM@BN&#8722;1 (N vacancy) in both CO2RR and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Integrated crystal orbital Hamiltonian population (ICOHP) analysis reveals that these catalysts weaken the sp orbital hybridization of CO2, which promotes the formation of radical-state intermediates and significantly reduces the energy barrier for the hydrogenation reaction. Therefore, these theoretical calculations indicate that the Mn, Fe, Co@B&#8722;1N, and Co@BN&#8722;1 systems demonstrate excellent CO2 chemical adsorption properties. In the CO2RR pathway, Mn@B&#8722;1N exhibits the lowest limiting potential (UL = &#8722;0.524 V), and its higher d-band center (&#8722;0.334 eV), which aligns optimally with the adsorbate orbitals, highlights its excellent catalytic activity. Notably, Co@BN&#8722;1 exhibits the highest activity in HER, while UL is &#8722;0.217 V. Furthermore, comparative analysis reveals that Mn@B&#8722;1N shows 16.4 times higher selectivity for CO2RR than for HER. This study provides a theoretical framework for designing bifunctional SACs with selective reaction pathways. Mn@B&#8722;1N shows considerable potential for selective CO2 conversion, while Co@BN&#8722;1 demonstrates promising prospects for efficient hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Xiansheng Yu, Can Zhao, Qiaoyue Chen, Wei Lai, Xucai Zhao, Lili Zhang, Liqian Wu, Yineng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15080628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The use of an Rh-intercalated SiC/graphene interface for CO2 electrochemical reduction: A theoretical investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122760</link>
      <description>Munusamy Rajendran Ashwin Kishore, Karin Larsson, Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409619063

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munusamy Rajendran Ashwin Kishore, Karin Larsson</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of the Key Proton Activities in Hydrogen Evolution Reaction by Electrochromic Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500631</link>
      <description>Yaping Jiang, Jun Hu, Hang Cai, Hongxiang Zeng, Hongyu Wang, Jiangbei Wan, Zhen Wang, Zhigang Chen, Zhigang Zhao, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409620546

                Abstract The electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is a promising route to produce sustainable hydrogen energy carrier for global carbon neutrality. The HER performance is largely determined by the overall proton activities, but the identification of such key proton activities in microscopic HER process is rather difficult. Herein, the study demonstrates a visualized HER concept by integrating the fundamental HER process with electrochromic technology on a well&#8208;designed Pt@WO 3 platform in acidic electrolyte, where the overall proton activities in HER process can be rapidly discriminated by the color changes of Pt@WO 3 electrochromic electrode. In contrast to bare WO 3 counterpart, the Pt@WO 3 electrochromic electrode displays a rather more positive potential of initial&#8208;coloration state and faster decoloration rate associated with significantly improved reaction kinetics of hydrogen intercalation and deintercalation within WO 3 component. Correspondingly, the as&#8208;prepared Pt@WO 3 catalyst electrode exhibits a remarkable HER activity with a lower onset&#8208;potential (45 mV, proton adsorption and accumulation) and smaller Tafel slope (50 mV dec &#8722;1 , proton desorption), nearly 11.1&#8208; and 3.5&#8208;fold enhancement than those of bare WO 3 counterpart. It is believed that the work in integrating the interesting visualization functionality into fundamental HER process may improve the readability of such microscopic electrocatalytic reaction and advance the exploration of more intelligent electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yaping Jiang, Jun Hu, Hang Cai, Hongxiang Zeng, Hongyu Wang, Jiangbei Wan, Zhen Wang, Zhigang Chen, Zhigang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrooxidation of Thymol or Carvacrol to Obtain Thymoquinone on Defective Pt/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424617</link>
      <description>Liang Zhang, Wei Chen, Yuxuan Lu, Yimin Jiang, Liguang Lin, Shengkai Li, Fang Wang, Jianfeng Jia, Zhengjun Wang, Jun Li, Huile Jin, Jingjing Lv, Yuqin Zou, Shuangyin Wang, Shun Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409621900

                Abstract Thymoquinone (TQ), a compound with diverse pharmacological benefits, faces limited availability from natural sources. In this study, the design of a highly efficient electrocatalyst, Pt clusters loaded on CeO 2 with rich oxygen vacancies (Vo&#8208;Pt/CeO 2 ), for the electrocatalytic oxidation of thymol (TY) or carvacrol to produce TQ is reported. The introduction of oxygen vacancies to the surface of Vo&#8208;Pt/CeO 2 significantly reduces the adsorption energy of TQ, facilitating its desorption and preventing product accumulation and catalyst poisoning. As a result, Vo&#8208;Pt/CeO 2 demonstrates exceptional electrocatalytic performance, achieving &#8776;100% selectivity and up to 98% yield of TQ under 1.2 V RHE . In situ, Raman spectroscopy indicates that the electrocatalytic oxidation mechanism of TY involves water attacking the TY intermediate to form thymohydroquinone, which is subsequently oxidized to TQ. Overall, this work provides novel insights into the catalyst design and presents a new strategy for sustainable TQ synthesis.</description>
      <author>Liang Zhang, Wei Chen, Yuxuan Lu, Yimin Jiang, Liguang Lin, Shengkai Li, Fang Wang, Jianfeng Jia, Zhengjun Wang, Jun Li, Huile Jin, Jingjing Lv, Yuqin Zou, Shuangyin Wang, Shun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N, S coordination in Co single atom catalyst promoting CO2RR towards HCOOH at negative potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115137</link>
      <description>H. L. Zhang, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Siyuan Liu, Hongyu Chen, Yiqun Lisa Yin, Zhongyuan Yue, Shuxian Wei, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing L&#252;, Molecular Catalysis. 581(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409624180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. L. Zhang, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Siyuan Liu, Hongyu Chen, Yiqun Lisa Yin, Zhongyuan Yue, Shuxian Wei, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Perspective on Multiscale Modeling of Explicit Solvation-Enabled Simulations of Catalysis at Liquid&#8211;Solid Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01563</link>
      <description>Ricardo A. Garc&#237;a C&#225;rcamo, Jiexin Shi, Ali Estejab, Tianjun Xie, Sanchari Bhattacharjee, Sayani Biswas, Cameron J. Bodenschatz, Xiuting Chen, Manish Maurya, Xiaohong Zhang, Rachel B. Getman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409625181

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ricardo A. Garc&#237;a C&#225;rcamo, Jiexin Shi, Ali Estejab, Tianjun Xie, Sanchari Bhattacharjee, Sayani Biswas, Cameron J. Bodenschatz, Xiuting Chen, Manish Maurya, Xiaohong Zhang, Rachel B. Getman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances of HKUST-1 metal&#8211;organic frameworks in the biomedical applications: A comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162753</link>
      <description>Mohashin Kabir, Mahbubur Rahman, Tarikul Islam, Qi Meng, Hailei Liu, Minghua Li, Shaohua Wu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409626122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohashin Kabir, Mahbubur Rahman, Tarikul Islam, Qi Meng, Hailei Liu, Minghua Li, Shaohua Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Recent Progress of High-Entropy Layered Double Hydroxides and High-Entropy Amorphous Materials for Water Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.decarb.2025.100110</link>
      <description>Tadele Hunde Wondimu, Yong Zuo, A.A. Shah, Puiki Leung, Yilkal Dessie, Filimon Hadish, Cristina Flox, Qiang Liao, DeCarbon. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409638521

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tadele Hunde Wondimu, Yong Zuo, A.A. Shah, Puiki Leung, Yilkal Dessie, Filimon Hadish, Cristina Flox, Qiang Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.decarb.2025.100110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Coupling of Ni-Oxalate Prism and Layered FeOOH for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125393</link>
      <description>Sukhwa Hong, Jiseon Kim, Soonho Kwon, Kahyun Ham, Haowei Long, William A. Goddard, Kangwoo Cho, Paul J. A. Kenis, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409644052

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sukhwa Hong, Jiseon Kim, Soonho Kwon, Kahyun Ham, Haowei Long, William A. Goddard, Kangwoo Cho, Paul J. A. Kenis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One dimensional AWO4 and A2O3 structured high entropy oxide nanowires and their superior oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180556</link>
      <description>Lei Yang, Yiting Dong, Xiaoxian Tian, Jun Yin, Qingwan Wang, Wanxin Wu, Yingguo Yang, Lulu Tang, Xueqin Yuan, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409644800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Yang, Yiting Dong, Xiaoxian Tian, Jun Yin, Qingwan Wang, Wanxin Wu, Yingguo Yang, Lulu Tang, Xueqin Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of NiW@Pd nanocrystals for the electro-catalytic application in the fuel cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6317277/v1</link>
      <description>Ahmed B.M. Ibrahim, Mohamed A. Habib, Sidra Munir, Fawad Ahmad, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409648191

                Abstract The effective inter-conversion of electricity and chemicals via an electrochemical reaction, is significant for energy storage devices such as batteries and fuel cells. These fuel cells are regarded as promising solution to energy crisis in 21st century. The slow kinetics of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is one of the topmost barriers in this discipline and Pt-based catalysts are needed to boost the durability and activity of ORR. To cope with high cost and less accessibility of Pt/C catalyst, Pd based alloys are being expressed as potential replacements for Pt-based electro catalysts in fuel cells as cathodes for oxygen reduction reactions (ORR). But its performance and stability are less than those of Pt. The morphology and composition can be altered by alloying process to enhance their catalytic properties towards ORR. In this study, alloys of Pd with tungsten(W) and nickel(Ni) were synthesized and deposited the prepared material (NiWPd) onto the glassy carbon. Electrochemical investigations confirmed that NiWPd catalysts have improved electro catalytic activities towards oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) with higher specific and mass activities in comparison to Pd/C and Pt/C catalysts. 1.5% NiWPd showed highest ORR performance. Its mass activity came out to be 2.2mA/cm2 that was superior to Pd/C and Pt/C electro catalyst, due to dopants and geometrical impact.</description>
      <author>Ahmed B.M. Ibrahim, Mohamed A. Habib, Sidra Munir, Fawad Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6317277/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nucleation in Confinement: A Pathway to Size-Controlled Ultrasmall Icosahedral Silver Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00288</link>
      <description>Rohan Parmar, Raj Kumar Ramamoorthy, Pierre Roblin, Nicolas Ratel&#8208;Ramond, Lise&#8208;Marie Lacroix, Isaac Rodr&#237;guez-Ruiz, S&#233;bastien Teychen&#233;, Guillaume Viau, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409655754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rohan Parmar, Raj Kumar Ramamoorthy, Pierre Roblin, Nicolas Ratel&#8208;Ramond, Lise&#8208;Marie Lacroix, Isaac Rodr&#237;guez-Ruiz, S&#233;bastien Teychen&#233;, Guillaume Viau</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening and mechanism exploration of excellent OER/HER catalysts for Janus 2H-WSSe monolayer adsorbed transition metal single atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109598</link>
      <description>Zefang Li, Gangbing Song, Yukai An, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 194(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409657957

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zefang Li, Gangbing Song, Yukai An</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically precise Ni clusters inducing active NiN2 sites with uniform-large vacancies towards efficient CO2-to-CO conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59079-5</link>
      <description>Guangyuan Xu, Xingjie Peng, Chuanqiang Wu, Shibo Xi, Huixin Xiang, Lei Feng, Zhendong Liu, Yi Duan, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Si Chen, Yuan Kong, Yanzhe Ma, F.L. Nie, Jie Zhao, Xiao Hai, Su&#8208;Huai Wei, Meng Zhou, Tianfu Wang, Chuanhao Yao, Wu Zhou, Huan Yan, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409661358

                CO2 electroreduction to CO promises to give an efficient strategy for CO2 fixation and transformation. However, current reported active sites fail to deliver sufficient activity with high CO Faradic efficiency (FEco) over a wide range of potential. Here, we show a general synthetic protocol to fabricate a batch of highly pure and active NiN2 catalysts with precise engineering of the uniform-large (UL) vacancy around the active sites, which is accomplished through the 'pre-deposition + pyrolysis' of various atomically precise Ni clusters (Nin) and in-situ etching of the support by the 'nano bomb' (sulfur-ligand in the clusters). The NiN2 sites with UL vacancies could achieve a high turnover frequency (TOF) of 350000 h-1 with ~100% FEco in a wide potential range of 1500 mV. In-situ infrared spectra and theoretical calculations reveal that a highly pure NiN2 site with UL vacancy contributes to this remarkable catalytic performance compared to the counterparts. This general synthetic strategy enables us to simultaneously engineer active sites and surrounding vacancies with the employment of atomically precise metal clusters, thereby enhancing catalytic performance for other specific reactions.</description>
      <author>Guangyuan Xu, Xingjie Peng, Chuanqiang Wu, Shibo Xi, Huixin Xiang, Lei Feng, Zhendong Liu, Yi Duan, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Si Chen, Yuan Kong, Yanzhe Ma, F.L. Nie, Jie Zhao, Xiao Hai, Su&#8208;Huai Wei, Meng Zhou, Tianfu Wang, Chuanhao Yao, Wu Zhou, Huan Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59079-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hexaminobenzene in conductive metal-organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for overall water splitting and metal-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237126</link>
      <description>Anyang Wang, Xiting Wang, Xuhao Wan, Jun Jia, Zeyuan Li, Ke Xue, Rong Han, Zhaofu Zhang, Jun Wang, Yuzheng Guo, Journal of Power Sources. 644(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409661938

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anyang Wang, Xiting Wang, Xuhao Wan, Jun Jia, Zeyuan Li, Ke Xue, Rong Han, Zhaofu Zhang, Jun Wang, Yuzheng Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph neural network-driven prediction of high-performance CO2 reduction catalysts based on Cu-based high-entropy alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60264-0</link>
      <description>Zihao Jiao, C. Zhang, Ya Liu, Liejin Guo, Ziyun Wang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 71(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409665084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihao Jiao, C. Zhang, Ya Liu, Liejin Guo, Ziyun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60264-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning d-band electronic structure of Ni-Fe oxyhydroxides via doping engineering boosts seawater oxidation performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60255-x</link>
      <description>Liyuan Xiao, Xue Bai, Jingyi Han, Zhenl&#252; Wang, Jingqi Guan, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 71(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409665270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liyuan Xiao, Xue Bai, Jingyi Han, Zhenl&#252; Wang, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60255-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into Structure-Activity Relationships between Y Zeolites and their n-C10 Hydrocracking Performances via Machine Learning Approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60259-7</link>
      <description>Qianyi Ma, Hong Nie, Ping Yang, Jianqiang Liu, Hongyi Gao, Wei David Wang, Shihao Dong, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 71(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409665333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianyi Ma, Hong Nie, Ping Yang, Jianqiang Liu, Hongyi Gao, Wei David Wang, Shihao Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60259-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combining reinforcement learning with graph convolutional neural networks for efficient design of TiAl/TiAlN interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20590</link>
      <description>Xinyu Jiang, Haofan Sun, Qiong Nian, Houlong Zhuang, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409668079

                Abstract Ti/TiN coatings are used in a wide range of engineering applications due to their superior properties such as high hardness and toughness. Doping Al into Ti/TiN can further enhance properties and lead to even higher performance. Therefore, studying the atomic&#8208;level behavior of the TiAl/TiAlN interface is important. However, due to the large number of possible combinations for the 50 mol% Al&#8208;doped Ti/TiN system, it is time&#8208;consuming to use the DFT&#8208;based Monte Carlo methods to find the optimal TiAl/TiAlN system with a high work of adhesion. In this study, we use a graph convolutional neural network as an interatomic potential, combined with reinforcement learning, to improve the efficiency of finding optimal structures with a high work of adhesion. By inspecting the features of structures in neural networks, we found that the optimal structures follow a certain pattern of doping Al near the interface. The electronic structure and bonding analysis indicate that the optimal TiAl/TiAlN structures have higher bonding strength. We expect our approach to significantly accelerate the design of advanced ceramic coatings, which can lead to more durable and efficient materials for engineering applications.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Jiang, Haofan Sun, Qiong Nian, Houlong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-metal synergistic integration for electronic structure regulation in schreibersite-type Mo2Fe0.8Ru0.2P electrocatalysts: exceptional enhancement of activity and stability for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.04.020</link>
      <description>Peng Zhang, Shiyu Xu, Hao Li, Chenglin Cui, Sheng-Yang Huang, Zhengyang Li, Hyun Jun Song, Lirui Mao, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Ho Seok Park, Jin Yong Lee, Ji Man Kim, Pil J. Yoo, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409670884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Zhang, Shiyu Xu, Hao Li, Chenglin Cui, Sheng-Yang Huang, Zhengyang Li, Hyun Jun Song, Lirui Mao, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Ho Seok Park, Jin Yong Lee, Ji Man Kim, Pil J. Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.04.020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Amsterdam Modeling Suite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0258496</link>
      <description>Evert Jan Baerends, N&#233;stor F. Aguirre, N. Austin, Jochen Autschbach, F. Matthias Bickelhaupt, Rosa E. Bulo, Chiara Cappelli, Adri C. T. van Duin, Franco Egidi, C&#233;lia Fonseca Guerra, A. F&#246;rster, Mirko Franchini, T. P. M. Goumans, Thomas Heine, Matti Hellstr&#246;m, Christoph R. Jacob, Lasse Jensen, Mykhaylo Krykunov, Erik van Lenthe, Artur Michalak, Mariusz P. Mitoraj, Johannes Neugebauer, Valentin Paul Nicu, Pier Philipsen, Harry Ramanantoanina, Robert R&#252;ger, Georg Schreckenbach, Mauro Stener, Marcel Swart, J. M. Thijssen, Tom&#225;&#353; Trnka, Lucas Visscher, Alexei Yakovlev, Stan van Gisbergen, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(16)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409679285

                In this paper, we present the Amsterdam Modeling Suite (AMS), a comprehensive software platform designed to support advanced molecular and materials simulations across a wide range of chemical and physical systems. AMS integrates cutting-edge quantum chemical methods, including Density Functional Theory (DFT) and time-dependent DFT, with molecular mechanics, fluid thermodynamics, machine learning techniques, and more, to enable multi-scale modeling of complex chemical systems. Its design philosophy allows for seamless coupling between components, facilitating simulations that range from small molecules to complex biomolecular and solid-state systems, making it a versatile tool for tackling interdisciplinary challenges, both in industry and in academia. The suite also emphasizes user accessibility, with an intuitive graphical interface, extensive scripting capabilities, and compatibility with high-performance computing environments.</description>
      <author>Evert Jan Baerends, N&#233;stor F. Aguirre, N. Austin, Jochen Autschbach, F. Matthias Bickelhaupt, Rosa E. Bulo, Chiara Cappelli, Adri C. T. van Duin, Franco Egidi, C&#233;lia Fonseca Guerra, A. F&#246;rster, Mirko Franchini, T. P. M. Goumans, Thomas Heine, Matti Hellstr&#246;m, Christoph R. Jacob, Lasse Jensen, Mykhaylo Krykunov, Erik van Lenthe, Artur Michalak, Mariusz P. Mitoraj, Johannes Neugebauer, Valentin Paul Nicu, Pier Philipsen, Harry Ramanantoanina, Robert R&#252;ger, Georg Schreckenbach, Mauro Stener, Marcel Swart, J. M. Thijssen, Tom&#225;&#353; Trnka, Lucas Visscher, Alexei Yakovlev, Stan van Gisbergen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0258496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Transition-Metal-Anchored Indium Nitride Single-Atom Catalysts for Enhanced Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00569</link>
      <description>Muhammad Tariq, K. Raghu Raja Pandiyan, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409684380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Tariq, K. Raghu Raja Pandiyan, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Resource Usage in Industrial Effluent: Synthesis of V/CrNC Oxygen Reduction Catalyst from Ammonium Polyvanadate (APV) Precipitation Wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40831-025-01085-4</link>
      <description>Han Yang, Yan Liu, Jibiao Han, Quan Yang, Yong Li, Ting&#8208;an Zhang, Journal of Sustainable Metallurgy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409697055

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Han Yang, Yan Liu, Jibiao Han, Quan Yang, Yong Li, Ting&#8208;an Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40831-025-01085-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Activity of an Ensemble of Sites for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol on a ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-on-Cu Inverse Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00848</link>
      <description>Zihan Yang, Simran Kumari, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Philippe Sautet, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409700371

                The significant increase in CO2 emissions from heavy fossil fuel utilization has raised serious concerns, highlighting the need for effective methods to convert CO2 into value-added chemicals. Here, we report a computational investigation on the catalytic activity of ZrO2-on-Cu inverse catalysts for CO2 hydrogenation to methanol, considering highly dispersed ZrO2 trimers on Cu (111). Such clusters present a large ensemble of formate-containing configurations, Zr3On(OH)m(OCHO)l, making the evaluation of the catalytic activity very challenging. We found that the sites on the various catalyst configurations exhibit markedly different activities for formate hydrogenation, despite their similar free energy and composition. To understand these differences in reactivity, we examined the structural and electronic nature of the low free-energy catalyst configurations and identified that the energy of the lowest unoccupied orbital of the reacting formate, modified by its binding with the catalytic site, is a descriptor for the reaction energy of the formate hydrogenation step. From there, we screened an ensemble of catalyst structures using this descriptor to predict highly active metastable catalyst configurations and computed the reaction pathways and transition states for formate hydrogenation. From this investigation, we distinguished reactive from nonreactive sites and formate species on the ZrO2/Cu inverse catalyst based on structural and electronic features. We showed that rare metastable configurations control the activity. Additionally, an efficient method for examining the reactivity of a large number of coexisting catalyst structures was developed.</description>
      <author>Zihan Yang, Simran Kumari, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine&#8208;Learning&#8208;Assisted Design and Optimization of Single&#8208;Atom Transition Metal&#8208;Incorporated Carbon Quantum Dot Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.70006</link>
      <description>Unbeom Baeck, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Duong Nguyen Nguyen, Jaekyum Kim, Jaehyoung Lim, Yujin Chae, Namsoo Shin, Heechae Choi, Joon Young Kim, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Woo&#8208;Seok Choe, Ho Seok Park, Uk Sim, Jung Kyu Kim, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409702011

                ABSTRACT Hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acidic media has been spotlighted for hydrogen production since it is a favourable kinetics with the supplied protons from a counterpart compared to that within alkaline environment. However, there is no choice but to use a platinum&#8208;based catalyst yet. As for a noble metal&#8208;free electrocatalyst, incorporation of earth&#8208;abundant transition metal (TM) atoms into nanocarbon platforms has been extensively adopted. Although a data&#8208;driven methodology facilitates the rational design of TM&#8208;anchored carbon catalysts, its practical application suffers from either a simplified theoretical model or the prohibitive cost and complexity of experimental data generation. Herein, an effective and facile catalyst design strategy is proposed based on machine learning (ML) and its model verification using electrochemical methods accompanied by density functional theory simulations. Based on a Bayesian genetic algorithm ML model, the Ni&#8208;incorporated carbon quantum dots (Ni@CQD) loaded on a three&#8208;dimensional reduced graphene oxide conductor are proposed as the best HER catalyst amongst the various TM&#8208;incorporated CQDs under the optimal conditions of catalyst loading, electrode type, and temperature and pH of electrolyte. The ML results are validated with electrochemical experiments, where the Ni@CQD catalyst exhibited superior HER activity, requiring an overpotential of 151 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a Tafel slope of 52 mV dec &#8722;1 and impressive durability in acidic media up to 100 h. This methodology can provide an effective route for the rational design of highly active electrocatalysts for commercial applications.</description>
      <author>Unbeom Baeck, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Duong Nguyen Nguyen, Jaekyum Kim, Jaehyoung Lim, Yujin Chae, Namsoo Shin, Heechae Choi, Joon Young Kim, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Woo&#8208;Seok Choe, Ho Seok Park, Uk Sim, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.70006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering materials science with VASPKIT: a toolkit for enhanced simulation and analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41596-025-01160-w</link>
      <description>W. T. Geng, Ya-Chao Liu, Nan Xu, Gang Tang, Yoshiyuki Kawazoe, Vei Wang, Nature Protocols. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409706620

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W. T. Geng, Ya-Chao Liu, Nan Xu, Gang Tang, Yoshiyuki Kawazoe, Vei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41596-025-01160-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectonics for Pentagon Defects in Carbon: Properties and Catalytic Role in Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500069</link>
      <description>Guoping Chen, Taro Koide, Junji Nakamura, Katsuhiko Ariga, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409710258

                Abstract The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is a crucial process in electrochemical energy technologies, featuring fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries in the coming carbon&#8208;neutral society. Carbon materials have garnered significant attention as economical, sustainable alternatives to precious metal catalysts. In particular, there have been increasing reports recently that pentagons introduced into graphitic carbons promote catalytic activity for ORR. In addition, interesting studies are reported on carbon materials&#8217; synthesis, characterization, and spin polarization properties with pentagonal defects. This review comprehensively summarizes the formation mechanism, characterization, spin, oxygen (O 2 ) adsorption, and ORR catalytic activity of carbon catalysts with pentagonal defects. By connecting the dots between theoretical insights and experimental results, this review elucidates the fundamental principles governing pentagon&#8208;related activity and offers perspectives on future directions for designing efficient ORR catalysts based on carbon materials.</description>
      <author>Guoping Chen, Taro Koide, Junji Nakamura, Katsuhiko Ariga</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction of Amorphous Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;S&#9472;O Material with a Functional Gradient Layer for Highly Efficient and Stable Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502293</link>
      <description>Lijuan Liu, Yingqiu Zheng, Wenshu Chen, Yongping Du, Linfeng Hu, Guoqiang Luo, Qiang Shen, Jian Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409710552

                Abstract Alkaline water electrolysis holds potential for large&#8208;scale, high&#8208;purity hydrogen production. However, the slow kinetics of water dissociation and challenging conditions in alkaline environments complicate the search for an electrocatalyst with both high activity and durability. In this study, a highly active and stable amorphous electrocatalyst is introduced, 3Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;S&#9472;O, developed via a straightforward electrodeposition method for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Notably, the surface of the 3Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;S&#9472;O catalyst undergoes a compositional reconstruction during alkaline HER, yet maintains its amorphous structure. This reconstruction spans roughly 6 &#181;m, leading to a gradual decrease in Ni and S content and a corresponding increase in O concentration toward the surface, thereby forming a stable, gradient active layer. Benefitting from this layer and its amorphous nature, the 3Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;S&#9472;O catalyst demonstrates superior alkaline HER activity&#8212;requiring only 170 mV to achieve an industrial HER current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 . It also showcases remarkable stability, with a mere 15 mV increase in overpotential during continuous HER at 300 mA cm &#8722;2 for 24 h, outperforming the commercial Pt/C catalyst. The research provides a novel approach to designing high&#8208;performance amorphous alkaline HER electrocatalysts cost&#8208;effectively and contributes insights for understanding and developing advanced amorphous catalysts across various applications.</description>
      <author>Lijuan Liu, Yingqiu Zheng, Wenshu Chen, Yongping Du, Linfeng Hu, Guoqiang Luo, Qiang Shen, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Na content and Mn defects in birnessite for high-voltage aqueous sodium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59223-1</link>
      <description>Xiaohui Zhu, Jing Xu, Qinghua Zhang, Tao Shen, Yuhang Zhuang, Tingting Chen, Shuang Li, Lin Gu, Hui Xia, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409712858

                Na-birnessite is a promising low-cost positive electrode material for aqueous sodium-ion batteries. However, its sodium storage capability is limited by narrow potential window and low redox activity in aqueous electrolytes. Herein, a Na-rich birnessite (NaMnO2&#8226;0.1H2O) with a highly ordered layered structure is reported as an advanced positive electrode for aqueous sodium-ion batteries, greatly suppressing Mn migration and its accompanying domino degradation effect, which enables a promoted upper charging cut-off potential up to 1.4 V (vs. Ag/AgCl), an enhanced specific capacity of 199.9 mAh g-1 at a specific current of 0.2 A g-1 based on the mass of active material for positive electrode, and greatly improved structural stability. In particular, a 3.0 V NaxH2-xTi2O5||NaMnO2&#8226;0.1H2O aqueous full cell prototype is validated, exhibiting a large specific energy of 117.1 Wh kg-1 based on the total mass of active materials in both positive and negative electrodes as well as a long cycle life. This work elucidates how interlayer chemistry and structural defects influence sodium ion storage in layered structures and provides opportunities for developing high-voltage aqueous batteries with large specific energy.</description>
      <author>Xiaohui Zhu, Jing Xu, Qinghua Zhang, Tao Shen, Yuhang Zhuang, Tingting Chen, Shuang Li, Lin Gu, Hui Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59223-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal Neural Network Potential Study of the Pt/CO Heterogeneous Catalytic System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106542</link>
      <description>Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Y&#363;suke Nanba, Michihisa Koyama, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409716699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Y&#363;suke Nanba, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Generative Model for the Inverse Design of Transition Metal Ligands and Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00242</link>
      <description>Magnus Strandgaard, Trond Linjordet, Hannes Kneiding, Arron L. Burnage, Ainara Nova, Jan H. Jensen, David Balcells, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409719662

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Magnus Strandgaard, Trond Linjordet, Hannes Kneiding, Arron L. Burnage, Ainara Nova, Jan H. Jensen, David Balcells</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Descriptors of Single-Atom Catalysts Supported on MXenes (Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C, Ti&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C) Determining CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07850</link>
      <description>Anna Vidal-L&#243;pez, Judith Mahringer, Aleix Comas&#8208;Vives, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409723086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna Vidal-L&#243;pez, Judith Mahringer, Aleix Comas&#8208;Vives</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EM-DAT: the Emergency Events Database</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2025.105509</link>
      <description>Damien Delforge, Valentin Wathelet, Regina Below, Cinzia Lanfredi Sofia, Margo Tonnelier, Joris Adriaan Frank van Loenhout, Niko Speybroeck, International Journal of Disaster Risk Reduction. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409724531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Damien Delforge, Valentin Wathelet, Regina Below, Cinzia Lanfredi Sofia, Margo Tonnelier, Joris Adriaan Frank van Loenhout, Niko Speybroeck</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2025.105509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D Novel o-B2N2 supported single-atom catalysts: Multifunctional activity in Hydrogen/Oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163335</link>
      <description>Chunling Zhang, Xunzhe Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409726015

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunling Zhang, Xunzhe Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Ge Wu, Jinbo Hao, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the Repertoire of Photoswitchable Unnatural Amino Acids for Enzyme Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.04.17.649278</link>
      <description>Caroline Hiefinger, Michela Marcon, Verena Pape, Guillem Casadevall, Ranit Lahmy, Julian Nazet, Michael H. Bartl, Astrid Bruckmann, S&#237;lvia Osuna, Burkhard Koenig, Andrea C. Kneuttinger, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409728204

                Abstract Photoswitchable unnatural amino acids (psUAAs) play a crucial role in the engineering of light-sensitivity in enzymes, which holds significant promise for diverse applications such as biotherapy and biocatalysis. Besides near-quantitative photoconversion, the success and expediency of a psUAA for a certain application is defined by its interaction potential with the enzyme, its thermal stability and its effective wavelength of irradiation. To establish high versatility in the current repertoire, we have designed and synthesized six psUAAs based on azobenzene, arylazopyrazole, arylazothiazole, hemithioindigo and spiropyran photoswitches. The resulting psUAAs exhibit an enhanced interaction potential within an enzyme owing to their capacity for hydrogen bonding, ionic interactions, and metal ion coordination. Moreover, we observed diverse photochemical behaviors among the psUAAs, with four of them reversibly switching between the isomers with purely visible light. Notably, we identified orthogonal aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases that facilitate the incorporation of five of the six psUAAs co-translationally and computationally analyzed the synthetase-psUAA interactions. Finally, we evaluated the photochemical behavior of the five psUAAs within an enzymatic model and tested the photocontrol of catalysis confirming their diversity. Ultimately, our findings significantly expanded the repertoire of psUAAs and demonstrated their feasibility for enzyme engineering studies.</description>
      <author>Caroline Hiefinger, Michela Marcon, Verena Pape, Guillem Casadevall, Ranit Lahmy, Julian Nazet, Michael H. Bartl, Astrid Bruckmann, S&#237;lvia Osuna, Burkhard Koenig, Andrea C. Kneuttinger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.04.17.649278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Phosphorene: Theoretical Investigation of Its Promise as an Anode for High-Efficiency Lithium/Sodium-Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08089</link>
      <description>E. Granda-Rodriguez, J. W. Gonz&#225;lez, J.D. Correa, Elizabeth Fl&#243;rez, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409730397

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. Granda-Rodriguez, J. W. Gonz&#225;lez, J.D. Correa, Elizabeth Fl&#243;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Symmetry-oriented enumeration method for molecular crystal structure prediction and its application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.134112</link>
      <description>Xin Yu, Zengqi Xie, Yun-Ting Chen, Pengyue Gao, H. J. Zhao, Jian Lv, Yanchao Wang, Yanming Ma, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(13)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409731164

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Yu, Zengqi Xie, Yun-Ting Chen, Pengyue Gao, H. J. Zhao, Jian Lv, Yanchao Wang, Yanming Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.134112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detection and Measurement of Interfacial Charge Transfer Relaxation Time: FeNi/NF Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting to Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c02561</link>
      <description>Ahmed Halilu, Mahar Diana Hamid, Abubakar Abubakar Umar, Mohd Ali Hashim, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409732503

                A cost-effective nickel-iron (Ni-Fe) alloy with a predominant face-centered cubic(111) crystallographic orientation is demonstrated as a high-performance electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This alloy demonstrates mutual hybridization of Ni and Fe d-orbitals, bringing its valence energy level close to the Fermi level, comparable to that of the benchmark Pt/C catalyst. While water-splitting electrocatalysts typically undergo surface structural evolution after each reaction cycle, the time scale of surface reconstruction during HER remains uncharted. This study presents a NiFe/NF alloy with an enriched (111) orientation, an active surface area of 24,217 &#177; 0.1 cm2, an average crystallite size of 14.5 nm, and 0.634% lattice strain as an HER electrocatalyst. The electrocatalyst exhibits excellent performance towards HER, achieving a current density exceeding 800 mA/cm2, an overpotential of -133 mV, and a hydrogen turnover frequency of 2.8 &#215; 1012 s-1, and maintaining stable operation over 100 h. The distribution of relaxation time (DRT) analysis is introduced to deconvolute the HER process. A distinct high-frequency peak is attributed to interfacial charge transfer with a 2.38 &#215; 10-6 s relaxation time. Additionally, medium- and low-frequency peaks represent ion transport and hydrogen adsorption/desorption at 277.4 &#215; 10-6 and 905.1 &#215; 10-6 s relaxation times, respectively. The assignments can serve as a reference on the bulk and interfacial relaxation times critical for understanding electrocatalyst surface evolution using the DRT method, regardless of the material or type of electrochemical reaction. These findings are useful for advancing the design of low-cost, transition-metal-based alloys as catalysts for clean energy systems.</description>
      <author>Ahmed Halilu, Mahar Diana Hamid, Abubakar Abubakar Umar, Mohd Ali Hashim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c02561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in the measurement of thermochemical, electrochemical and photochemical efficiency of CO2 conversion to value-added products - its challenges and future directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meaene.2025.100049</link>
      <description>Subodh Chaudhari, Harish Pawar, Kajal Pawar, Pavan More, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409737971

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subodh Chaudhari, Harish Pawar, Kajal Pawar, Pavan More</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meaene.2025.100049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defective Carbon Catalysts with Graphitic N-Modified Adjacent Pentagons as Active Sites for Boosted Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c01475</link>
      <description>Lei Wang, Xuan Liu, Mengting Huang, Yun Han, Panjie Guo, Run Huang, Runsheng Chen, Helong Wu, Jinyan Zhang, Shuangming Chen, Aijun Du, Xin Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409738001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Wang, Xuan Liu, Mengting Huang, Yun Han, Panjie Guo, Run Huang, Runsheng Chen, Helong Wu, Jinyan Zhang, Shuangming Chen, Aijun Du, Xin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c01475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regressing the self-consistent Hamiltonian and density from the non-self-consistent Hamiltonian</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6347952/v1</link>
      <description>S. Richter, Thomas D. K&#252;hne, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409637053

                Abstract We show that the non-self-consistent electronic Hamiltonian can be used as a chemical descriptor with all common invariances (i.e. translation, rotation, reflection, and permutation) via simple orthonormal matrix transformations. We used a linear regression on a labeled dataset of water dimer clusters with the aforementioned non-self-consistent Hamiltonian matrices as inputs to evaluate their potential as descriptors for predicting the self-consistent Hamiltonian and the corresponding ground-state electron density. Our regression tests were performed as a single layer ANN with a linear activation function to facilitate a relevance analysis. We further mapped our feature space data for non-linear regression up to third order polynomial multivariate regression. To further investigate the influence of the invariances a simplified relevance analysis on the input matrices was done using the trained weights of the input layer. This analysis revealed a shift in relevance from the intra-molecular part (without invariances) to the inter-molecular part of the input matrices when our invariances were applied.</description>
      <author>S. Richter, Thomas D. K&#252;hne</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6347952/v1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
