<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 01:16:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>General applications of density functional theory in photocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60006-9</link>
      <description>Shiwen Du, Fuxiang Zhang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 61(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400603432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiwen Du, Fuxiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60006-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlating Nitrate Adsorption with the Local Environments of FeCoNiCuZn High-Entropy Alloy Catalysts Using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01071</link>
      <description>Xiang He, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400603905

                The electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia holds significant values for water remediations and energy applications, which quests for the development of highly effective catalysts with considerable stability and selectivity. Recently, high-entropy alloys (HEAs) are attracting growing attention for electrocatalytic processes. Nonetheless, studies of HEA-based nitrate reduction to ammonia are still at the early stage, and it remains unclear how the HEA compositions affect the adsorption and activation of the reaction intermediates. Herein, high-throughput density functional theory (DFT) calculations were integrated with machine learning to investigate the dependence of nitrate adsorption on the FeCoNiCuZn HEA structures. In particular, a total of 1268 different structures were sampled and constructed from the multidimensional configuration space, followed by the DFT calculations to investigate the Gibbs free energy of nitrate adsorption (i.e., &#916;</description>
      <author>Xiang He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the multiple effects of MOF-derived TiO2 on Ti-Fe2O3 photoanodes for efficient and stable photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60005-7</link>
      <description>Kaikai Ba, Yunan Liu, Kai Zhang, Ping Wang, Yanhong Lin, Sheng Wang, Ziheng Li, Tengfeng Xie, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 61(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400603959

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaikai Ba, Yunan Liu, Kai Zhang, Ping Wang, Yanhong Lin, Sheng Wang, Ziheng Li, Tengfeng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60005-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Mechanistic Landscape and Advantages of Two-Dimensional Phthalocyanine in Sustainable Urea Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4893780</link>
      <description>Xiaorong Zhu, Ming Ge, Xiaolei Yuan, Yijin Wang, Yanfeng Tang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400604092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaorong Zhu, Ming Ge, Xiaolei Yuan, Yijin Wang, Yanfeng Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4893780</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferromagnetic-Interaction-Induced Spin Symmetry Broken in Ruthenium Oxide for Enhanced Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02736</link>
      <description>Lei Tan, Xiaotong Wu, Haifeng Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Bingbao Mei, Xiangxiang Pan, Weibo Hu, Faiza Meharban, Qi Xiao, Yonghui Zhao, Chao Fu, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Wei Luo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400604797

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Tan, Xiaotong Wu, Haifeng Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Bingbao Mei, Xiangxiang Pan, Weibo Hu, Faiza Meharban, Qi Xiao, Yonghui Zhao, Chao Fu, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Ag12m Icosahedrons: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4893394</link>
      <description>Pilar Rodriguez Rodr&#237;&#173;guez, Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400611077

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pilar Rodriguez Rodr&#237;&#173;guez, Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4893394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and robust single-layer IrO cluster electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120508</link>
      <description>Wenbo Liu, Zhicheng Hu, Tong Ren, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang, Chemical engineering science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400614572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenbo Liu, Zhicheng Hu, Tong Ren, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120508</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relaxor Unveils Geometrical Frustration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120172</link>
      <description>&#1052;. &#1042;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, L. A. Avakyan, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1079;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1057;. &#1040;. &#1048;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, A.I. Stash, &#1045;. &#1057;. &#1046;&#1091;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, B. P. Gorshunov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1096;, Acta materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400615552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1052;. &#1042;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, L. A. Avakyan, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1079;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1057;. &#1040;. &#1048;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, A.I. Stash, &#1045;. &#1057;. &#1046;&#1091;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, B. P. Gorshunov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1096;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined Cu&#8544; sites in partially electro-reduced 2D conductive Cu-MOF film for boosting CO2 electrocatalysis to C2 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153993</link>
      <description>Bing Chang, Fengtao Zhang, Zhaojun Min, Sheng Wang, Qingchun Xia, Jing Fan, Maohong Fan, Jianji Wang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400618342

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Chang, Fengtao Zhang, Zhaojun Min, Sheng Wang, Qingchun Xia, Jing Fan, Maohong Fan, Jianji Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum-level machine learning calculations of Levodopa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compbiolchem.2024.108146</link>
      <description>Hossein Shirani, Seyed Majid Hashemianzadeh, Computational biology and chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400618468

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hossein Shirani, Seyed Majid Hashemianzadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compbiolchem.2024.108146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of the catalytic mechanism of hydrogen evolution reaction enhanced by surface oxidation on FCC_CoCrFeNi and Co0.35Cr0.15Fe0.2Mo0.1Ni0.2 multi-principal element alloys based on site preference</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160730</link>
      <description>Liangji Weng, Xiaoqiong Zhang, Longju Su, Cheng Qian, Qi Cai, Tianliang Xie, Rong Chen, Hui Guo, Bo Wu, Baisheng Sa, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400618572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liangji Weng, Xiaoqiong Zhang, Longju Su, Cheng Qian, Qi Cai, Tianliang Xie, Rong Chen, Hui Guo, Bo Wu, Baisheng Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of noble metal-free electrocatalysts towards acidic water oxidation: From fundamental understanding to state-of-the-art catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100295</link>
      <description>Jing Ni, Zhaoping Shi, Yibo Wang, Jiahao Yang, Hongxiang Wu, Pengbo Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400618967

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Ni, Zhaoping Shi, Yibo Wang, Jiahao Yang, Hongxiang Wu, Pengbo Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative neural networks-accelerated prediction of transition state energy barriers for CO catalytic oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175546</link>
      <description>Tian Tang, Jingyu Xue, Xiaoqiang Shen, Jinfei Chen, Vladislav Rac, Vesna Raki&#263;, Xinbao Li, Bo Zhou, Yanrong Chen, Hao Song, Xuesen Du, Journal of alloys and compounds. 1002(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400621470

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tian Tang, Jingyu Xue, Xiaoqiang Shen, Jinfei Chen, Vladislav Rac, Vesna Raki&#263;, Xinbao Li, Bo Zhou, Yanrong Chen, Hao Song, Xuesen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D materials for enabling hydrogen as an energy vector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109997</link>
      <description>Johnson Kehinde Abifarin, Juan F. Torres, Yuerui Lu, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400623392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Johnson Kehinde Abifarin, Juan F. Torres, Yuerui Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109997</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering electronic structures and oxygen vacancies of manganese-doped nickel molybdate porous nanosheets for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.118</link>
      <description>Fang Miao, Peng Cui, Tiantian Gu, Bo Sun, Zhijie Yan, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400648309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fang Miao, Peng Cui, Tiantian Gu, Bo Sun, Zhijie Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Electroreduction on Single Atom Catalysts: Role of the Local Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144714</link>
      <description>Gianfranco Pacchioni, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400650185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gianfranco Pacchioni, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Modified Nickel Phosphides Electrocatalyst for Stable Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Neutral Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409365</link>
      <description>P. Zhang, Han Man, Yao Huo, Fei Zhang, Yang Liu, Renbing Wu, Fei Wang, Dalin Sun, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400658006

                Abstract The development of efficient and long&#8208;term stable electrodes for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in seawater is highly desirable for hydrogen generation but remains challenging. In this work, a highly active CrO x @Ni 2 P&#8208;Ni 5 P 4 /NF electrode is developed and investigated its dynamic reconstruction for HER in neutral electrolytes. The combination of in situ Raman spectra and electrochemical measurements revealed the dynamic surface reconstruction of the catalyst during HER. The CrO x modification not only effectively facilitates water dissociation but also stabilizes the structure post&#8208;reconstruction, enabling rapid and stable hydrogen generation in neutral media. Remarkably, CrO x @Ni 2 P&#8208;Ni 5 P 4 /NF exhibits overpotentials of 109 and 263 mV at current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m PBS, respectively. Concurrently, it exhibits stable operation for 500 h in 1 m PBS and 140 h in natural seawater at current densities of 50 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The proposed catalytic electrode and the mechanistic insights present a significant stride toward the realization of metal phosphides for direct seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>P. Zhang, Han Man, Yao Huo, Fei Zhang, Yang Liu, Renbing Wu, Fei Wang, Dalin Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening of single transition-metal atoms anchored Janus MoSSe monolayers as efficient electrocatalysts for nitrogen fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132474</link>
      <description>Jia-Xing Guo, Shao-Yi Wu, Chunyu Yao, Rong-Gang Tian, Shunping Shi, Fuel. 374(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400601712

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia-Xing Guo, Shao-Yi Wu, Chunyu Yao, Rong-Gang Tian, Shunping Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Post-combustion Capture: A Critical Review of Current Technologies and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02513</link>
      <description>Federica Raganati, Paola Ammendola, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400646404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Federica Raganati, Paola Ammendola</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Cu-Based Monatomic Alloys: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01246</link>
      <description>Xiaojiao Li, Liyun Jiang, Yong Zhou, Qi Yu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400651340

                In recent years, single-atom alloy catalysts (SAAs) have received much attention due to the combination of structural features of both single-atom and alloy catalysts, as well as their efficient catalytic activity, high selectivity, and high stability in various chemical reactions. In this work, we designed a series of Cu-based SAAs by doping isolated 3d transition metal (TM1) atoms on the surface of Cu(111) (TM1 = Fe, Co, Ru, Rh, Os and Ir), in which Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs are considered to be the most stable among 3d-series SAAs due to their optimal binding energy (Eb). The density of states of SAAs have been systematically investigated to further discuss structural properties. Based on density functional theory calculations, the activity and selectivity of Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs are investigated for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). The initial hydrogenation of CO2 on Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs can form *CO intermediates, which will be further to CH4 production by the pathway of *CO &#8594; *CHO &#8594; *CHOH &#8594; *CH2OH &#8594; *CH2 &#8594; *CH3 &#8594; CH4. This study provides theoretical insights for the rational design of selective Cu-based monatomic alloy catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaojiao Li, Liyun Jiang, Yong Zhou, Qi Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure to Property: Chemical Element Embeddings for Predicting Electronic Properties of Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01990</link>
      <description>Shokirbek Shermukhamedov, Dilorom Mamurjonova, Thana Maihom, Michael Probst, Journal of chemical information and modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400653212

                We present a new general-purpose machine learning model that is able to predict a variety of crystal properties, including Fermi level energy and band gap, as well as spectral ones such as electronic densities of states. The model is based on atomic representations that enable it to effectively capture complex information about each atom and its surrounding environment in a crystal. The accuracy achieved for band gaps exceeds results previously published. By design, our model is not restricted to the electronic properties discussed here but can be extended to fit diverse chemical descriptors. Its advantages are (a) its low computational requirements, making it an efficient tool for high-throughput screening of materials; and (b) the simplicity and flexibility of its architecture, facilitating implementation and interpretation, especially for researchers in the field of computational chemistry.</description>
      <author>Shokirbek Shermukhamedov, Dilorom Mamurjonova, Thana Maihom, Michael Probst</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene-supported MN4 single-atom catalysts for multifunctional electrocatalysis enabled by axial Fe tetramer coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.132</link>
      <description>Lulu Gao, Donghai Wu, Silu Li, Haobo Li, Dongwei Ma, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400672156

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lulu Gao, Donghai Wu, Silu Li, Haobo Li, Dongwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin occupancy regulation of the Pt d-orbital for a robust low-Pt catalyst towards oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50332-x</link>
      <description>Dongping Xue, Yifang Yuan, Yue Yu, Siran Xu, Yifan Wei, Jiaqi Zhang, Haizhong Guo, Minhua Shao, Jianan Zhang, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400672738

                Disentangling the limitations of O-O bond activation and OH* site-blocking effects on Pt sites is key to improving the intrinsic activity and stability of low-Pt catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Herein, we integrate of PtFe alloy nanocrystals on a single-atom Fe-N-C substrate (PtFe@Fe</description>
      <author>Dongping Xue, Yifang Yuan, Yue Yu, Siran Xu, Yifan Wei, Jiaqi Zhang, Haizhong Guo, Minhua Shao, Jianan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50332-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the oxygen evolution reaction activity of lanthanide-doped NiFe-LDHs through lanthanide contraction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154059</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Kai-Sheng Chen, ZihaoYan, Yongjun Chen, Hongtao Liu, Pengfei Yin, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400673171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Kai-Sheng Chen, ZihaoYan, Yongjun Chen, Hongtao Liu, Pengfei Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-plane heterostructures of transition metal dichalcogenide monolayers with enhanced charge separation and effective overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.171</link>
      <description>Ling Zhu, Qihui Sun, Junwei Wang, Weiqiang Lv, Azim Khan, Yifan Liu, Nasir Mahmood, Xian Jian, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400677098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Zhu, Qihui Sun, Junwei Wang, Weiqiang Lv, Azim Khan, Yifan Liu, Nasir Mahmood, Xian Jian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of electronic and optical properties of g-CN/XTe2(X=W, Mo) heterojunctions by biaxial strain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.148</link>
      <description>Yang Shen, Pei Yuan, Zhihao Yuan, Zhen Cui, Deming Ma, Fengjiao Cheng, Ke Qin, Hanxiao Wang, Enling Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400677137

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Shen, Pei Yuan, Zhihao Yuan, Zhen Cui, Deming Ma, Fengjiao Cheng, Ke Qin, Hanxiao Wang, Enling Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Electrochemical Activity of 2D Materials Edges through Oriented Electric Fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06341</link>
      <description>Hao Chen, Ding&#8208;Rui Chen, You-Chen Lin, Po-Hsieh Lin, Jeng&#8208;Shian Chang, Jeyavelan Muthu, Mario Hofmann, Ya&#8208;Ping Hsieh, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400678584

                The edges of 2D materials have emerged as promising electrochemical catalyst systems, yet their performance still lags behind that of noble metals. Here, we demonstrate the potential of oriented electric fields (OEFs) to enhance the electrochemical activity of 2D materials edges. By atomically engineering the edge of a fluorographene/graphene/MoS</description>
      <author>Hao Chen, Ding&#8208;Rui Chen, You-Chen Lin, Po-Hsieh Lin, Jeng&#8208;Shian Chang, Jeyavelan Muthu, Mario Hofmann, Ya&#8208;Ping Hsieh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Dynamics of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation on Iron Catalysts Using ReaxFF Molecular Dynamics Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01212</link>
      <description>Quang K. Loi, Debra J. Searles, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400686575

                The conversion of CO</description>
      <author>Quang K. Loi, Debra J. Searles</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Heteroatom Doping in Enhancing the Catalytic Activities and Stability of Atomically Dispersed Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02747</link>
      <description>Xueqi Cheng, Dengfeng Wu, Hui Xu, Wei Zhang, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400692872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xueqi Cheng, Dengfeng Wu, Hui Xu, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic&#8208;Level Observation of Potential&#8208;Dependent Variations at the Surface of an Oxide Catalyst during Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403392</link>
      <description>Chang Hyun Park, Hyungdoh Lee, Jin&#8208;Seok Choi, Tae Gyu Yun, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400699451

                Understanding the intricate details of the surface atomic structure and composition of catalysts during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for developing catalysts with high stability in water electrolyzers. While many notable studies highlight surface amorphization and reconstruction, systematic analytical tracing of the catalyst surface as a function of overpotential remains elusive. Heteroepitaxial (001) films of chemically stable and lattice-oxygen-inactive LaCoO</description>
      <author>Chang Hyun Park, Hyungdoh Lee, Jin&#8208;Seok Choi, Tae Gyu Yun, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the crystallographic orientation dependent electrochemical corrosion rates of aluminum and its binary alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41529-024-00490-6</link>
      <description>Haini Jin, Yudong Sui, Xiaohua Yu, Hao Zhou, Jing Feng, Yehua Jiang, npj materials degradation. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400701152

                Abstract This paper provides a study for crystallographic orientation-dependent corrosion rate of aluminum employing an ab initio model with inputs from first-principles calculations. Results showed that the sequence of corrosion rate is in the order of (111) &lt; (410) &lt; (331) &lt; (221) &lt; (321) &lt; (211) &lt; (110) &lt; (100) &lt; (210) &lt; (320) &lt; (310) &lt; (311) for aluminum. The predicted corrosion current densities for (111), (110), and (100) surfaces are in general agreement with the experimental results. The alloying effects were further investigated employing this model with results validated via the polarization curves of alloyed aluminum.</description>
      <author>Haini Jin, Yudong Sui, Xiaohua Yu, Hao Zhou, Jing Feng, Yehua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41529-024-00490-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Atom Doping with GeC: Tuning Electronic, Magnetic and Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416320</link>
      <description>Shaoqiang Wang, Zhihao Yuan, Zhen Cui, Physica. B, Condensed matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400720298

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaoqiang Wang, Zhihao Yuan, Zhen Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Score-based denoising for atomic structure identification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01337-z</link>
      <description>Tim Hsu, Babak Sadigh, Nicolas Bertin, Cheol Woo Park, James Chapman, Vasily V. Bulatov, Fei Zhou, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400720724

                Abstract We propose an effective method for removing thermal vibrations that complicate the task of analyzing complex dynamics in atomistic simulation of condensed matter. Our method iteratively subtracts thermal noises or perturbations in atomic positions using a denoising score function trained on synthetically noised but otherwise perfect crystal lattices. The resulting denoised structures clearly reveal underlying crystal order while retaining disorder associated with crystal defects. Purely geometric, agnostic to interatomic potentials, and trained without inputs from explicit simulations, our denoiser can be applied to simulation data generated from vastly different interatomic interactions. The denoiser is shown to improve existing classification methods, such as common neighbor analysis and polyhedral template matching, reaching perfect classification accuracy on a recent benchmark dataset of thermally perturbed structures up to the melting point. Demonstrated here in a wide variety of atomistic simulation contexts, the denoiser is general, robust, and readily extendable to delineate order from disorder in structurally and chemically complex materials.</description>
      <author>Tim Hsu, Babak Sadigh, Nicolas Bertin, Cheol Woo Park, James Chapman, Vasily V. Bulatov, Fei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01337-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus and nitrogen co-doped-graphene: Stability and catalytic activity in oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2024.100379</link>
      <description>Jinmin Guo, Weiwei Shao, Hongfeng Yan, Min Zhao, Yang&#8208;Yi Liu, Qiufeng Fang, T.X. Xia, Jinlong Wang, Xiao-Chun Li, Carbon trends. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400722108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinmin Guo, Weiwei Shao, Hongfeng Yan, Min Zhao, Yang&#8208;Yi Liu, Qiufeng Fang, T.X. Xia, Jinlong Wang, Xiao-Chun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2024.100379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Evaluation of Adiabatic Proton Tunneling across the Electrified Double Layer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01336</link>
      <description>M. Askari, Reagan Huckabee, Joseph A. Gauthier, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400725059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Askari, Reagan Huckabee, Joseph A. Gauthier</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts based on two-dimensional metalloporphyrin monolayers for electrochemical nitrate reduction to ammonia by first-principles calculations and interpretable machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.200</link>
      <description>Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Aling Ma, Zhiyi Liu, Zhenzhen Wang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400728644

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Aling Ma, Zhiyi Liu, Zhenzhen Wang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Entity Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00723</link>
      <description>Thomas B. Clarke, Lynn E. Krushinski, Kathryn J. Vannoy, Guillermo S. Col&#243;n-Quintana, Kingshuk Roy, Jeffrey E. Dick, Christophe Renault, Myrtle Hill, Jeffrey E. Dick, Chemical reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400729701

                Making a measurement over millions of nanoparticles or exposed crystal facets seldom reports on reactivity of a single nanoparticle or facet, which may depart drastically from ensemble measurements. Within the past 30 years, science has moved toward studying the reactivity of single atoms, molecules, and nanoparticles, one at a time. This shift has been fueled by the realization that everything changes at the nanoscale, especially important industrially relevant properties like those important to electrocatalysis. Studying single nanoscale entities, however, is not trivial and has required the development of new measurement tools. This review explores a tale of the clever use of old and new measurement tools to study electrocatalysis at the single entity level. We explore in detail the complex interrelationship between measurement method, electrocatalytic material, and reaction of interest (e.g., carbon dioxide reduction, oxygen reduction, hydrazine oxidation, etc.). We end with our perspective on the future of single entity electrocatalysis with a key focus on what types of measurements present the greatest opportunity for fundamental discovery.</description>
      <author>Thomas B. Clarke, Lynn E. Krushinski, Kathryn J. Vannoy, Guillermo S. Col&#243;n-Quintana, Kingshuk Roy, Jeffrey E. Dick, Christophe Renault, Myrtle Hill, Jeffrey E. Dick</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the carbon nanomaterial&#8208;supported Pt complex electrocatalysts for efficient and selective chlorine evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27466</link>
      <description>Jewel Hossen, Naoki Nakatani, Journal of computational chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400735545

                Chlorine is an important chemical which has long been produced in chlor-alkali process using dimensionally stable anodes (DSA). However, some serious drawbacks of DSA inspire the development of alternative anodes for chlorine evolution reaction (CER). In this study, we focused on the graphene- and carbon nanotube-supported platinum tetra-phenyl porphyrins as electrocatalysts for CER, which have been theoretically investigated based on density functional theory. Our results reveal that the supported substrates possess potential CER electrocatalytic activity with very low thermodynamic overpotentials (0.012-0.028 V) via Cl* pathway instead of ClO*. The electronic structures analyses showed that electron transfer from the support to the adsorbed chlorine via the Pt center leads to strong Pt-Cl interactions. Furthermore, the supported electrocatalysts exhibited excellent selectivity toward CER because of high overpotentials and reaction barriers of oxygen evolution process. Therefore, our results may pave the way for designing CER electrocatalyst utilizing emerging carbon nanomaterials.</description>
      <author>Jewel Hossen, Naoki Nakatani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional platinum borides: A Dirac nodal line quantum electrocatalyst for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.202</link>
      <description>Zi Gao, Fengxian Ma, Weizhen Meng, Yalong Jiao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400735606

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zi Gao, Fengxian Ma, Weizhen Meng, Yalong Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detrimental Increase of Spin-Phonon Coupling in Molecular Qubits on Substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05728</link>
      <description>Kathleen R. Mullin, R Greer, Michael J. Waters, M. Jeremy Amdur, Lei Sun, Danna E. Freedman, James M. Rondinelli, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400736052

                Molecular qubits are a promising platform for quantum information systems. Although single molecule and ensemble studies have assessed the performance of</description>
      <author>Kathleen R. Mullin, R Greer, Michael J. Waters, M. Jeremy Amdur, Lei Sun, Danna E. Freedman, James M. Rondinelli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-level tailoring of single-atom tungsten catalysts for optimized electrochemical nitrate-to-ammonia conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.134</link>
      <description>Yujie Sun, Guoning Feng, Zhiwei Wang, Jing Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjian Sa, Qiaohong Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Zuju Ma, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400737656

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Sun, Guoning Feng, Zhiwei Wang, Jing Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjian Sa, Qiaohong Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Zuju Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning copper into an efficient and stable CO evolution catalyst beyond noble metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50436-4</link>
      <description>Jing Xue, Xue Dong, Chunxiao Liu, Jiawei Li, Yizhou Dai, Weiqing Xue, Laihao Luo, Yuan Ji, Xiao Zhang, Li Xu, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Jianping Xiao, Chuan Xia, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400746760

                Using renewable electricity to convert CO</description>
      <author>Jing Xue, Xue Dong, Chunxiao Liu, Jiawei Li, Yizhou Dai, Weiqing Xue, Laihao Luo, Yuan Ji, Xiao Zhang, Li Xu, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Jianping Xiao, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50436-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Organic Spacers and Dimensionality on Templating of Halide Perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01283</link>
      <description>Erik Fransson, Julia Wiktor, Paul Erhart, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400774317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Erik Fransson, Julia Wiktor, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-scale computational screening of all-silica zeolites for adsorptive separation of ternary (H2S/CO2/CH4) mixtures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154116</link>
      <description>S.&#8208;J. YOON, Muhammad Hassan, Yongchul G. Chung, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400798317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S.&#8208;J. YOON, Muhammad Hassan, Yongchul G. Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Property Prediction of Functional Organic Molecular Crystals with Graph Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3626203.3670584</link>
      <description>Dana O&#8217;Connor, Paola A. Buitrago, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400799096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dana O&#8217;Connor, Paola A. Buitrago</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1145/3626203.3670584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating digital chemistry within the broader chemistry community</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trechm.2024.06.008</link>
      <description>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena, Trends in chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400642443

                No abstract</description>
      <author>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trechm.2024.06.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sampling rare events using nanostructures for universal Pt neural network potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cap.2024.07.005</link>
      <description>Joonhee Kang, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Min Ho Seo, Jehyun Lee, Current applied physics. 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400621569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joonhee Kang, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Min Ho Seo, Jehyun Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cap.2024.07.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strained heterojunction enables high-performance, fully textured perovskite/silicon tandem solar cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.015</link>
      <description>Zhiliang Liu, Zhijun Xiong, Shaofei Yang, Ke Fan, Jiang Long, Yuliang Mao, Chaochao Qin, Sibo Li, Longbin Qiu, Jie Zhang, Francis Lin, Linfeng Fei, Yong Hua, Jia Yao, Yu Cao, Jian Zhou, Yimu Chen, Hong Zhang, Haitao Huang, Alex K.&#8208;Y. Jen, Kai Yao, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400651877

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiliang Liu, Zhijun Xiong, Shaofei Yang, Ke Fan, Jiang Long, Yuliang Mao, Chaochao Qin, Sibo Li, Longbin Qiu, Jie Zhang, Francis Lin, Linfeng Fei, Yong Hua, Jia Yao, Yu Cao, Jian Zhou, Yimu Chen, Hong Zhang, Haitao Huang, Alex K.&#8208;Y. Jen, Kai Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.015</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
