<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 01:20:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Holey Graphyne-Supported Single Atom Catalyst for Nitrogen Reduction Reaction by Interpretable Machine Learning and First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105401</link>
      <description>Dian Zheng, Fei Deng, Jing Xu, Wei Liu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404060333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dian Zheng, Fei Deng, Jing Xu, Wei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic catalysis meets heterostructure synergy: Unveiling the trifunctional efficacy of transition Metal@WS2/ReSe2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.377</link>
      <description>Xudong Hu, Jingyi Shang, Shuang Li, Jun Long, Shi&#8208;Bo Cheng, Saad Ahmed, Sheng Wang, Usman Farooq, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404060959

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xudong Hu, Jingyi Shang, Shuang Li, Jun Long, Shi&#8208;Bo Cheng, Saad Ahmed, Sheng Wang, Usman Farooq</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-valence Co deposition based on selfcatalysis of lattice Mn doping for robust acid water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.043</link>
      <description>Ning Yu, Fuli Wang, Xinying Jiang, Jin&#8208;Long Tan, Mirabbos Hojamberdiev, Han Hu, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061006

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Yu, Fuli Wang, Xinying Jiang, Jin&#8208;Long Tan, Mirabbos Hojamberdiev, Han Hu, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-doped porous graphite with multilevel pore defects and ultra-high conductivity anchoring Pt nanoparticles for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.041</link>
      <description>Yu Hao, Dongfang Chen, Guangxin Yang, Song Hu, Shunyu Wang, Pucheng Pei, Jinkai Hao, Xiaoming Xu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Hao, Dongfang Chen, Guangxin Yang, Song Hu, Shunyu Wang, Pucheng Pei, Jinkai Hao, Xiaoming Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bond-Based Machine Learning Model for Molecular Polarizabilities and A Priori Raman Spectra</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01086</link>
      <description>Jakub K. Sowa, Peter J. Rossky, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061157

                The use of machine learning (ML) algorithms in molecular simulations has become commonplace in recent years. There now exists, for instance, a multitude of ML force field algorithms that have enabled simulations approaching ab initio level accuracy at time scales and system sizes that significantly exceed what is otherwise possible with traditional methods. Far fewer algorithms exist for predicting rotationally equivariant, tensorial properties such as the electric polarizability. Here, we introduce a kernel ridge regression algorithm for machine learning of the polarizability tensor. This algorithm is based on the bond polarizability model and allows prediction of the tensor components at the cost similar to that of scalar quantities. We subsequently show the utility of this algorithm by simulating gas phase Raman spectra of biphenyl and malonaldehyde using classical molecular dynamics simulations of these systems performed with the recently developed MACE-OFF23 potential. The calculated spectra are shown to agree very well with the experiments and thus confirm the expediency of our algorithm as well as the accuracy of the used force field. More generally, this work demonstrates the potential of physics-informed approaches to yield simple yet effective machine learning algorithms for molecular properties.</description>
      <author>Jakub K. Sowa, Peter J. Rossky</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covariant Jacobi-Legendre expansion for total energy calculations within the projector augmented wave formalism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.184106</link>
      <description>Bruno Focassio, Michelangelo Domina, Urvesh Patil, A. Fazzio, Stefano Sanvito, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061393

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bruno Focassio, Michelangelo Domina, Urvesh Patil, A. Fazzio, Stefano Sanvito</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.184106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Potential of Machine Learning to Optimize the Activity of Cu-Based Dual Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01208</link>
      <description>A. Das, Diptendu Roy, Souvik Manna, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Das, Diptendu Roy, Souvik Manna, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Guideline for Cross-Sector Coupling of Carbon Capture Technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/gases4040021</link>
      <description>Hossein Asgharian, Ali Yahyaee, Chungen Yin, Vincenzo Liso, Mads Pagh Nielsen, Florin Iov, Gases. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404062213

                Many governments around the world have taken action to utilise carbon capture (CC) technologies to reduce CO2 emissions. This technology is particularly important to reduce unavoidable emissions from industries like cement plants, oil refineries, etc. The available literature in the public domain explores this theme from two distinct perspectives. The first category of papers focuses only on modelling the CC plants by investigating the details of the processes to separate CO2 from other gas components without considering the industrial applications and synergies between sectors. On the other hand, the second category investigates the required infrastructure that must be put in place to allow a suitable integration without considering the specific particularities of each carbon capture technology. This review gives a comprehensive guideline for the implementation of CC technologies for any given application while also considering the coupling between different energy sectors such as heating, power generation, etc. It also identifies the research gaps within this field, based on the existing literature. Moreover, it delves into various aspects and characteristics of these technologies, while comparing their energy penalties with the minimum work required for CO2 separation. Additionally, this review investigates the main industrial sectors with CC potential, the necessary transportation infrastructure from the point sources to the end users, and the needs and characteristics of storage facilities, as well as the utilisation of CO2 as a feedstock. Finally, an overview of the computation tools for CC processes and guidelines for their utilisation is given. The guidelines presented in this paper are the first attempt to provide a comprehensive overview of the technologies, and their requirements, needed to achieve the cross-sector coupling of CC plants for a wide range of applications. It is strongly believed that these guidelines will benefit all stakeholders in the value chain while enabling an accelerated deployment of these technologies.</description>
      <author>Hossein Asgharian, Ali Yahyaee, Chungen Yin, Vincenzo Liso, Mads Pagh Nielsen, Florin Iov</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/gases4040021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface&#8208;Interface Engineering of Electrocatalysts for Two&#8208;Electron Water Oxidation Reaction to Produce H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413243</link>
      <description>Zhen Chen, Xi Liu, Sheng Wang, Lin Yang, Sheng Wang, Wei Wang, Shuqin Song, Zhongwei Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404068129

                Abstract Electrochemical two&#8208;electron water oxidation reaction (2e &#8722; WOR) driven by renewable energy offers an attractive route to produce H 2 O 2 , while the corresponding electrocatalyst still requires further improvement for the activity, selectivity, and the resulting H 2 O 2 yield. Surface&#8208;interface engineering of electrocatalysts has great potential to advance 2e &#8722; WOR performance. This review provides a succinct yet comprehensive insight into the functional mechanisms of surface&#8208;interfacial properties affecting 2e &#8722; WOR performance on electrocatalyst. The Gibbs free energy theoretical framework related to surface electronic structure and interfacial reactive kinetics mechanism related to electrolyte, electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface structure, and interfacial microenvironment properties are firstly discussed. Afterward, various surface&#8208;interface engineering strategies toward high performance electrocatalysts including the regulation of surface electronic structure, the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface structure, and the interfacial microenvironment have been overviewed. Rational manipulations of the above surface&#8208;interfacial engineering strategies are critical to design highly efficient 2e &#8722; WOR electrocatalysts, leading to the development of the green H 2 O 2 production.</description>
      <author>Zhen Chen, Xi Liu, Sheng Wang, Lin Yang, Sheng Wang, Wei Wang, Shuqin Song, Zhongwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction of Single-Twinned AgPdIr Nanoalloy during the Formate Oxidation and Dehydrogenation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03637</link>
      <description>Quan Tang, Longfei Guo, Tao Jin, Shuang Shan, Qiao Wang, Junpeng Wang, Bowei Pan, Zhen Li, Fuyi Chen, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404071955

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Quan Tang, Longfei Guo, Tao Jin, Shuang Shan, Qiao Wang, Junpeng Wang, Bowei Pan, Zhen Li, Fuyi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodegradation of nitrogenous pollutants in sewage: from reaction fundamentals to energy valorization applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00517a</link>
      <description>Minglei Sun, Li Wang, Yi Feng, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Sheng Wang, Zhong&#8208;Yong Yuan, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404078300

                This review provides a comprehensive insight into the electrodegradation processes of nitrogenous pollutants in sewage, highlighting the reaction mechanisms, theoretical descriptors, catalyst design, and energy valorization strategies.</description>
      <author>Minglei Sun, Li Wang, Yi Feng, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Sheng Wang, Zhong&#8208;Yong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00517a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Atomic Ordering Uniformity Enables Selectively Leached Nanoporous Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P Metallic Glass for Enhanced Glucose Sensing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408816</link>
      <description>Yu Lou, J. B. Li, Zhongzheng Yao, Zhenduo Wu, Huiqiang Ying, Lan Tan, Liu Si-nan, Jianrong Zeng, Ruohan Yu, Hong Liu, Xun&#8208;Li Wang, He Zhu, Si Lan, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404078877

                Abstract Constructing nanostructures, such as nanopores, within metallic glasses (MGs) holds great promise for further unlocking their electrochemical capabilities. However, the MGs typically exhibit intrinsic atomic&#8208;scale isotropy, posing a significant challenge in directly fabricating anisotropic nanostructures using conventional chemical synthesis. Herein a selective leaching approach, which focuses on tailoring the uniformity of atomic ordering, is introduced to achieve pore&#8208;engineered Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P MG. This innovative approach significantly boosts the number of exposed active sites, thereby enhancing the electrochemical sensitivity for glucose detection. Electrochemical tests reveal that the nanoporous Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P MG exhibits high sensitivity (3.19 mA m m &#8315;&#185; cm&#8315; 2 ) and remarkable stability (97.7% current retention after 1000 cycles). During electrochemical cycling, synchrotron X&#8208;ray pair distribution function and X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure analyses reveal that the distance between active sites decreases, enhancing electron transport efficiency, while the medium&#8208;range ordered structure of the Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P MG remains stable, contributing to its exceptional glucose sensing capabilities. A microglucose sensor is successfully developed by integrating the nanoporous Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P MG with a screen&#8208;printed electrode, demonstrating the practical applicability. This study not only offers a new avenue for the design of highly active nanoporous MGs but also sheds light on the mechanisms behind the high electrochemistry performance of MGs.</description>
      <author>Yu Lou, J. B. Li, Zhongzheng Yao, Zhenduo Wu, Huiqiang Ying, Lan Tan, Liu Si-nan, Jianrong Zeng, Ruohan Yu, Hong Liu, Xun&#8208;Li Wang, He Zhu, Si Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the Pt/ionomer/water interface on the oxygen reduction reaction: insights into the micro-three-phase interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06600f</link>
      <description>Shangkun Jiang, Qiong Xiang, Zhi-Yan Xie, Na Yang, Jiawei Liu, Li Li, Zidong Wei, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404079241

                Understanding the Pt/ionomer/water interface structure and its impact on the oxygen reduction reaction activity is essential for enhancing catalyst utilization and performance of fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Shangkun Jiang, Qiong Xiang, Zhi-Yan Xie, Na Yang, Jiawei Liu, Li Li, Zidong Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06600f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Establishment and Screening of Double-Atom Catalysts Supported on Biphenylene for an Efficient Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02582</link>
      <description>K. Raghu Raja Pandiyan, Dinesh Kumar Dhanthala Chittibabu, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404080387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Raghu Raja Pandiyan, Dinesh Kumar Dhanthala Chittibabu, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Efficient Oxygen Evolution via Anchoring Carbon-Layer-Confined RuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; on a Well-Matched Substrate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03507</link>
      <description>Liming Zeng, Biao Yuan, Qing Zhou, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404099969

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a multistep proton-coupled four-electron process with sluggish kinetics, which seriously limits the hydrogen production efficiency, thus it is of great importance to develop an efficient and stable OER catalyst. In this study, a two-step differential pyrolysis strategy is employed to design a three-dimensional porous microstructured material consisting of RuOx nanoparticles coated by a thin-layer carbon, where the active particles were isolated in separate chambers and the RuOx nanoparticles mainly existed in the form of a heterogeneous interface between RuO2 and partial metallic Ru. The preparation parameters of the catalysts are optimized via combining transient and steady-state polarization properties, and the target catalyst Cat-500&#8211;1.5t shows the best OER catalytic performance after ca. 60 h of a chronopotentiometry test in an acidic medium with a much smaller performance change than other samples. The unique design of adopting a carbon layer to form separate reaction chambers largely mitigates the excessive oxidation loss of the active components under strong oxidation potential. The suitability of the catalyst with the loaded substrate and test media is explored, and in an acidic medium, the carbon paper is much better than the titanium fiber, while in an alkaline medium, the titanium fiber is obviously superior to the carbon paper. On both carbon paper and titanium fiber, the performance in an alkaline medium outperforms that in an acidic medium, and the possible reasons for the performance difference are analyzed. Herein, to obtain the actual electrocatalytic performance, the optimal design of the catalyst structure and matching suitable conductive substrate in a specific medium are quite necessary, which provides a feasible strategy for the acquisition of efficient and stable electrocatalysts and the desirable presentation of performance.</description>
      <author>Liming Zeng, Biao Yuan, Qing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03507</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab initio characterization of protein molecular dynamics with AI2BMD</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-08127-z</link>
      <description>Tong Wang, Xinheng He, Mingyu Li, Yatao Li, Ran Bi, Yusong Wang, Chaoran Cheng, Xiangzhen Shen, Jiawei Meng, He Zhang, Haiguang Liu, Zun Wang, Shaoning Li, Bin Shao, Tie&#8208;Yan Liu, Nature. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404105372

                Biomolecular dynamics simulation is a fundamental technology for life sciences research, and its usefulness depends on its accuracy and efficiency1&#8211;3. Classical molecular dynamics simulation is fast but lacks chemical accuracy4,5. Quantum chemistry methods such as density functional theory can reach chemical accuracy but cannot scale to support large biomolecules6. Here we introduce an artificial intelligence-based ab initio biomolecular dynamics system (AI2BMD) that can efficiently simulate full-atom large biomolecules with ab initio accuracy. AI2BMD uses a protein fragmentation scheme and a machine learning force field7 to achieve generalizable ab initio accuracy for energy and force calculations for various proteins comprising more than 10,000 atoms. Compared to density functional theory, it reduces the computational time by several orders of magnitude. With several hundred nanoseconds of dynamics simulations, AI2BMD demonstrated its ability to efficiently explore the conformational space of peptides and proteins, deriving accurate 3J couplings that match nuclear magnetic resonance experiments, and showing protein folding and unfolding processes. Furthermore, AI2BMD enables precise free-energy calculations for protein folding, and the estimated thermodynamic properties are well aligned with experiments. AI2BMD could potentially complement wet-lab experiments, detect the dynamic processes of bioactivities and enable biomedical research that is impossible to conduct at present. A study introduces AI2BMD, an artificial intelligence-based dynamics simulation program that uses protein fragmentation with a machine learning force field to accurately and efficiently model the folding and unfolding of large proteins.</description>
      <author>Tong Wang, Xinheng He, Mingyu Li, Yatao Li, Ran Bi, Yusong Wang, Chaoran Cheng, Xiangzhen Shen, Jiawei Meng, He Zhang, Haiguang Liu, Zun Wang, Shaoning Li, Bin Shao, Tie&#8208;Yan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-08127-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Spectroscopy Advances in Energy Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05853</link>
      <description>Qimei Yang, Xiaoyun Song, Ting Zheng, Jian Yang, Wei Ding, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404109663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qimei Yang, Xiaoyun Song, Ting Zheng, Jian Yang, Wei Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Carbon Dioxide Capture by Amines and Conversion to Methane on Single-Atom Nickel Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09744</link>
      <description>Tomaz Neves&#8208;Garcia, Mahmudul Hasan, Quansong Zhu, Jing Li, Zhan Jiang, Yongye Liang, Hailiang Wang, Liane M. Rossi, Robert E. Warburton, L. Robert Baker, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404112538

                Direct electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2) capture species, i.e., carbamate and (bi)carbonate, can be promising for CO2 capture and conversion from point-source, where the energetically demanding stripping step is bypassed. Here, we describe a class of atomically dispersed nickel (Ni) catalysts electrodeposited on various electrode surfaces that are shown to directly convert captured CO2 to methane (CH4). A detailed study employing X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and electron microscopy (EM) indicate that highly dispersed Ni atoms are uniquely active for converting capture species to CH4, and the activity of single-atom Ni is confirmed using control experiments with a molecularly defined Ni phthalocyanine catalyst supported on carbon nanotubes. Comparing the kinetics of various capture solutions obtained from hydroxide, ammonia, primary, secondary, and tertiary amines provide evidence that carbamate, rather than (bi)carbonate and/or dissolved CO2, is primarily responsible for CH4 production. This conclusion is supported by 13C nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy of capture solutions as well as control experiments comparing reaction selectivity with and without CO2 purging. These findings are understood with the help of density functional theory (DFT) calculations showing that single-atom nickel (Ni) dispersed on gold (Au) is active for the direct reduction of carbamate, producing CH4 as the primary product. This is the first example of direct electrochemical conversion of carbamate to CH4, and the mechanism of this process provides new insight on the potential for integrated capture and conversion of CO2 directly to hydrocarbons.</description>
      <author>Tomaz Neves&#8208;Garcia, Mahmudul Hasan, Quansong Zhu, Jing Li, Zhan Jiang, Yongye Liang, Hailiang Wang, Liane M. Rossi, Robert E. Warburton, L. Robert Baker</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated image acquisition and analysis of graphene and hexagonal boron nitride from pristine to highly defective and amorphous structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-77740-9</link>
      <description>Diana Propst, Wael Joudi, Manuel L&#228;ngle, Jacob Madsen, Clara Kofler, Barbara Maria Mayer, David Lamprecht, Clemens Mangler, Lado Filipovic, Toma Susi, Jani Kotakoski, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404112546

                Abstract Defect-engineered and even amorphous two-dimensional (2D) materials have recently gained interest due to properties that differ from their pristine counterparts. Since these properties are highly sensitive to the exact atomic structure, it is crucial to be able to characterize them at atomic resolution over large areas. This is only possible when the imaging process is automated to reduce the time spent on manual imaging, which at the same time reduces the observer bias in selecting the imaged areas. Since the necessary datasets include at least hundreds if not thousands of images, the analysis process similarly needs to be automated. Here, we introduce disorder into graphene and monolayer hexagonal boron nitride (hBN) using low-energy argon ion irradiation, and characterize the resulting disordered structures using automated scanning transmission electron microscopy annular dark field imaging combined with convolutional neural network-based analysis techniques. We show that disorder manifests in these materials in a markedly different way, where graphene accommodates vacancy-type defects by transforming hexagonal carbon rings into other polygonal shapes, whereas in hBN the disorder is observed simply as vacant lattice sites with very little rearrangement of the remaining atoms. Correspondingly, in the case of graphene, the highest introduced disorder leads to an amorphous membrane, whereas in hBN, the highly defective lattice contains a large number of vacancies and small pores with no indication of amorphisation. Overall, our study demonstrates that combining automated imaging and image analysis is a powerful way to characterize the structure of disordered and amorphous 2D materials, while also illustrating some of the remaining shortcomings with this methodology.</description>
      <author>Diana Propst, Wael Joudi, Manuel L&#228;ngle, Jacob Madsen, Clara Kofler, Barbara Maria Mayer, David Lamprecht, Clemens Mangler, Lado Filipovic, Toma Susi, Jani Kotakoski</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-77740-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo2B2O2-supported Cu and Ni heterogeneous dual atom catalysts for oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113505</link>
      <description>Erpeng Wang, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun, Computational Materials Science. 247(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404129222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Erpeng Wang, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shear Deformation of Non-modulated Ni2MnGa Martensite: An Ab Initio Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40830-024-00510-z</link>
      <description>Martin Heczko, Petr &#352;est&#225;k, Hanu&#353; Seiner, M Zelen&#253;, Shape Memory and Superelasticity. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404132613

                Abstract The impact of shear deformation in $$(101)[10\overline{1}]$$    ( 101 )   [ 10  1 &#175;  ]    system of non-modulated (NM) martensite in Ni 2 MnGa ferromagnetic shape memory alloy is investigated by means of ab initio atomistic simulations. The shear system is associated with twinning of NM lattice and intermatensitic transformation to modulated structures. The stability of the NM lattice increases with increasing content of Mn. The most realistic shear mechanism for twin reorientation can be approximated by the simple shear mechanism, although the lowest barriers were calculated for pure shear mechanism. The energy barrier between twin variants further reduces due to spontaneous appearance of lattice modulation or, in other words, the nanotwins with thickness of two atomic planes. Such nanotwins appear also on the generalized planar fault energy (GPFE) curve calculated using a newly developed advanced procedure and exhibits even lower energy than the defect free NM structure. These nanotwin doublelayers are also basic building blocks of modulated structures and play an important role in intermartensitic transformation.</description>
      <author>Martin Heczko, Petr &#352;est&#225;k, Hanu&#353; Seiner, M Zelen&#253;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40830-024-00510-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation of Single-, Double-, and Triple- &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-block Metals Anchored on g-CN Monolayer for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02399</link>
      <description>Yanan Zhou, Li Sheng, Lanlan Chen, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404133632

                The design and development of highly active non-noble metal electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are crucial for metal-air batteries. In this work, the electrocatalytic performance of different p-block metal (PM = Sn, Sb, Pb and Bi) atoms embedded in the g-CN monolayer (PMx@g-CN, x = 1&#8211;3) for the OER and ORR was systematically investigated by density functional theory (DFT). The strong interaction between PMx atoms and g-CN substrates indicates the good stability of PMx@g-CN catalysts. Among all the designed catalysts, Bi3@g-CN is found to be a promising bifunctional electrocatalyst for both the OER and ORR with the calculated overpotential &#951;OER and &#951;ORR of 0.23 and 0.25 V, respectively. With the atomic active sites of PMx increasing from x = 1 to 3, the OER and ORR catalytic activity is enhanced. The correlations between the overpotentials of the OER/ORR and Bader charge values of the anchored PMx atoms of the catalysts were established. Our findings contribute to searching for noble metal-free bifunctional electrocatalysts and shed light on the rational design of atomic active sites on electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yanan Zhou, Li Sheng, Lanlan Chen, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02399</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning assisted screening of nitrogen-doped graphene-based dual-atom hydrogen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114649</link>
      <description>Huijie Zhang, Qiang Wei, Shuaichong Wei, Yuhong Luo, Wei Zhang, Guihua Liu, Molecular Catalysis. 570(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404141047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huijie Zhang, Qiang Wei, Shuaichong Wei, Yuhong Luo, Wei Zhang, Guihua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in X-ray absorption near edge structure (XANES) simulations for catalysis: Theories and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.arcc.2024.10.006</link>
      <description>Jiayi Xu, Yu Lim Kim, Rishu Khurana, Shana Havenridge, Prajay Patel, Cong Liu, Annual reports in computational chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404141332

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayi Xu, Yu Lim Kim, Rishu Khurana, Shana Havenridge, Prajay Patel, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.arcc.2024.10.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the synergistic mechanisms of dual-atom catalysts on BeN substrates for enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction: A machine learning-assisted first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161745</link>
      <description>Wentao Liang, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Rong Xiao-feng, Degui Wang, Wei Deng, Wenjun Xiao, Gang Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Changsong Gao, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhen Wang, Liang Zhang, Jinshun Bi, X J Liu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404161075

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wentao Liang, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Rong Xiao-feng, Degui Wang, Wei Deng, Wenjun Xiao, Gang Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Changsong Gao, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhen Wang, Liang Zhang, Jinshun Bi, X J Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in CO2 Splitting Processes with Non-Thermal Plasma-Assisted</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114692</link>
      <description>Baiqiang Zhang, Hengfei Zuo, Bo Wu, Kenji Kamiya, Wei Ma, Nobusuke Kobayashi, Y. Ma, Tingxiang Jin, Yuhui Chen, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404171277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baiqiang Zhang, Hengfei Zuo, Bo Wu, Kenji Kamiya, Wei Ma, Nobusuke Kobayashi, Y. Ma, Tingxiang Jin, Yuhui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening and investigation of ligand effect on TM single atom catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114981</link>
      <description>N.J. Hemavathi, Chiranjib Majumder, Suman Kalyan Sahoo, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404171634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N.J. Hemavathi, Chiranjib Majumder, Suman Kalyan Sahoo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Pathway on RuP&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; through Ab Initio Grand Canonical Monte Carlo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04913</link>
      <description>Shihan Qin, Sayan Banerjee, Mehmet G&#246;khan &#350;ensoy, Andrew M. Rappe, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404185926

                In this study, the high catalytic reactivity of ruthenium phosphide (RuP2) has been identified by first-principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations for the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Complex surface reconstructions are considered by applying the ab initio grand canonical Monte Carlo (ai-GCMC) algorithm, efficiently providing a sufficient phase-space exploration of possible surfaces. Combined with surface-phase Pourbaix diagrams, we are able to identify the actual surfaces that obtained under specific experimental environments, thus leading to a more accurate understanding of the nature of the active sites and the binding strength of adsorbates. Specifically, through hundreds of surface reconstructions and hydrogenation states generated with ai-GCMC, we identify the most favorable surface phases of RuP2 under aqueous acidic conditions. We discover that the HER activity is determined by multiple surfaces with different stoichiometries within a narrow electrode potential window. Low HER overpotential (&#951;) has been found for each of the identified surfaces, as low as 0.04 V. High H-coverage reconstructed surfaces have been discovered under acidic conditions, and the surface Ru sites introduced by additional Ru adatoms or exposed by P-vacancies serve as the active sites for HER based on their nearly reversible H binding. This work provides atomistic insights into the origin of high HER activity on RuP2 by exploring the dynamic surface phases of electrocatalysts and features a generalizable method to explore the reconstructed/hydrogenated surface space as a function of experimental conditions.</description>
      <author>Shihan Qin, Sayan Banerjee, Mehmet G&#246;khan &#350;ensoy, Andrew M. Rappe</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in development of characterization capabilities to evaluate candidate materials for direct air capture applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102975</link>
      <description>Marcus Carter, Huong Giang T. Nguyen, Andrew P. Allen, Feng Yi, Wei&#8208;Chang Yang, Avery E. Baumann, W. Sean McGivern, Jeffrey A. Manion, Ivan Kuzmenko, Zois Tsinas, Charlotte M. Wentz, Malia B. Wenny, Daniel W. Siderius, Roger D. van Zee, Christopher M. Stafford, Craig M. Brown, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 89(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404199074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marcus Carter, Huong Giang T. Nguyen, Andrew P. Allen, Feng Yi, Wei&#8208;Chang Yang, Avery E. Baumann, W. Sean McGivern, Jeffrey A. Manion, Ivan Kuzmenko, Zois Tsinas, Charlotte M. Wentz, Malia B. Wenny, Daniel W. Siderius, Roger D. van Zee, Christopher M. Stafford, Craig M. Brown</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the Origin of Enhanced C2+ Selectivity on Oxide-Derived Copper toward CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124805</link>
      <description>Hui Yu, Wenru Zhao, Xiangzun Dong, J. Wang, Wei Wang, Liu-Liu Shen, Guirong Zhang, Donghai Mei, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404202096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Yu, Wenru Zhao, Xiangzun Dong, J. Wang, Wei Wang, Liu-Liu Shen, Guirong Zhang, Donghai Mei</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Au decorated Ni(OH)2 nanostructures: the role of alkaline cations solvation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124804</link>
      <description>Lucas D. Germano, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Antonio G. S. de Oliveira&#8208;Filho, Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404205963

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lucas D. Germano, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Antonio G. S. de Oliveira&#8208;Filho, Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalytic Performance of Nickel&#8208;Nitrogen&#8208;Carbon Catalysts through Coordination Environment Engineering&lt;sup&gt;&#8224;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400769</link>
      <description>Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404209081

                Comprehensive Summary Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted significant attention due to their high atomic utilization and tunable coordination environment. However, the catalytic mechanisms related to the active center and coordination environment remain unclear. In this study, we systematically investigated the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalytic activities of NiN 4 , NiN 3 , NiN 3 H 2 , NiN 4 X, NiN 3 X, and NiN 3 H 2 X (X denotes axial ligand) through density functional theory (DFT) calculations. This study unveils two distinct reaction pathways for ORR and OER, involving proton&#8208;electron pairs adsorbed from both the solution and the catalyst surface. The overpotential is the key parameter to evaluate the catalytic performance when proton&#8208;electron pairs are adsorbed from the solution. NiN 3 and NiN 3 H 2 show promise as pH&#8208;universal bifunctional electrocatalysts for both ORR and OER. On the other hand, when proton&#8208;electron pairs are adsorbed from the catalyst surface, the reaction energy barrier becomes the crucial metric for assessing catalytic activity. Our investigation reveals that NiN 3 H 2 consistently exhibits optimal ORR activity across a wide pH range, regardless of the source of proton&#8208;electron pair (solvent or catalyst surface).</description>
      <author>Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational descriptor for electrochemical currents of carbon dioxide reduction on Cu facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115836</link>
      <description>Timothy T. Yang, Wissam A. Saidi, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404211724

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timothy T. Yang, Wissam A. Saidi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of Hydrogen Evolution over Oxidized Cu&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;Y&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; in an Ionic Liquid Electrolyte for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrochemical Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01802</link>
      <description>Xiaofan Hou, Feifei You, Ming&#8208;Hui Zhao, Meng Shen, L.T. Fan, Mingming Peng, Kenji Kamiya, Eika W. Qian, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404220319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaofan Hou, Feifei You, Ming&#8208;Hui Zhao, Meng Shen, L.T. Fan, Mingming Peng, Kenji Kamiya, Eika W. Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Accelerated Surface Reconstruction of CoSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoneedle Forms Active CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@CoOOH Interface to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403744</link>
      <description>Quanxin Guo, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhengrong Xu, Rui Liu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404222203

                Abstract Interface engineering is an efficient strategy to create high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for water splitting. In the present work, CeO 2 @CoSe 2 nanoneedle on carbon cloth (CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC) demonstrates high efficiency for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and water splitting. CeO 2 with abundant O vacancies facilitates the adsorption of OH &#8722; and boosts the reconstruction of CoSe 2 into CoOOH at lower potentials. The in situ generated active CeO 2 @CoOOH heterointerface upshifts the d&#8208;band center of Co site, thereby decreasing the free energy of rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) ( * O to * OOH) during the OER process. It delivers a low OER overpotential of 245 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC is also found to be active for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER, 138 mV overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), profiting from CeO 2 &#8208;facilitated * H 2 O dissociation and * H adsorption on CoSe 2 . The overall water splitting is achieved over the CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC bifunctional electrode with a low electrolysis voltage of 1.54 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work offers valuable insights into CeO 2 &#8208;assisted surface reconstruction as well as provides water electrolysis catalysts through interface engineering.</description>
      <author>Quanxin Guo, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhengrong Xu, Rui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Electronic Properties of CumAgn Bimetallic Clusters for Enhanced CO2 Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252212053</link>
      <description>Turki Alotaibi, Moteb Alotaibi, Fatimah Alhawiti, Norah Aldosari, Majd Alsunaid, Lama Aldawas, Talal F. Qahtan, Ali K. Ismael, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 25(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404224096

                The urgent demand for efficient CO2 reduction technologies has driven enormous studies into the enhancement of advanced catalysts. Here, we investigate the electronic properties and CO2 adsorption properties of CumAgn bimetallic clusters, particularly Cu4Ag1, Cu1Ag4, Cu3Ag2, and Cu2Ag3, using generalized gradient approximation (GGA)/density functional theory (DFT). Our results show that the atomic arrangement within these clusters drastically affects their stability, charge transfer, and catalytic performance. The Cu4Ag1 bimetallic cluster emerges as the most stable structure, revealing superior charge transfer and effective chemisorption of CO2, which promotes effective activation of the CO2 molecule. In contrast, the Cu1Ag4 bimetallic cluster, in spite of comparable adsorption energy, indicates insignificant charge transfer, resulting in less pronounced CO2 activation. The Cu3Ag2 and Cu2Ag3 bimetallic clusters also display high adsorption energies with remarkable charge transfer mechanisms, emphasizing the crucial role of metal composition in tuning catalytic characteristics. This thorough examination provides constructive insights into the design of bimetallic clusters for boosted CO2 reduction. These findings could pave the way for the development of cost-effective and efficient catalysts for industrial CO2 reduction, contributing to global efforts in carbon management and climate change mitigation.</description>
      <author>Turki Alotaibi, Moteb Alotaibi, Fatimah Alhawiti, Norah Aldosari, Majd Alsunaid, Lama Aldawas, Talal F. Qahtan, Ali K. Ismael</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252212053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver Electrodes Are Highly Selective for CO in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction due to Interplay between Voltage Dependent Kinetics and Thermodynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02869</link>
      <description>Michele Re Fiorentin, Francesca Risplendi, Clara Salvini, Juqin Zeng, Giancarlo Cicero, Hannes J&#243;nsson, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404227466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Michele Re Fiorentin, Francesca Risplendi, Clara Salvini, Juqin Zeng, Giancarlo Cicero, Hannes J&#243;nsson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dependence of Oxygen Diffusion on the La and Sr Configuration in Melilite-Type La&lt;sub&gt;1+&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ga&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7+&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;/2&lt;/sub&gt; by Neural Network Potential Molecular Dynamics Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03617</link>
      <description>T KOYAMA, Masanobu Nakayama, Judith Schuett, Steffen Grieshammer, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404230693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>T KOYAMA, Masanobu Nakayama, Judith Schuett, Steffen Grieshammer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Assess and Predict Electrical Double Layer Properties. Implications for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00806</link>
      <description>Christian M. Schott, Peter M. Schneider, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Haiting Yu, Rainer G&#246;tz, Felix Haimerl, Elena L. Gubanova, Jian Zhou, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Qi&#8208;Wei Zhang, Vitaly Alexandrov, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404238022

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Christian M. Schott, Peter M. Schneider, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Haiting Yu, Rainer G&#246;tz, Felix Haimerl, Elena L. Gubanova, Jian Zhou, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Qi&#8208;Wei Zhang, Vitaly Alexandrov, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Co Doping on Copper Nanoclusters for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07514</link>
      <description>Guilherme Rodrigues do Nascimento, Marionir M. C. B. Neto, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404238489

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guilherme Rodrigues do Nascimento, Marionir M. C. B. Neto, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-Learning-Assisted Screening of Nanocluster Electrocatalysts: Mapping and Reshaping the Activity Volcano for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14076</link>
      <description>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Milan Kumar Jena, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404241066

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Milan Kumar Jena, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedding material graphs using the electron-ion potential: application to material fracture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00246f</link>
      <description>Sherif Abdulkader Tawfik, Tri Minh Nguyen, Salvy P. Russo, Truyen Tran, Sunil Gupta, Svetha Venkatesh, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404194542

                Improving the physics of physics-informed machine learning.</description>
      <author>Sherif Abdulkader Tawfik, Tri Minh Nguyen, Salvy P. Russo, Truyen Tran, Sunil Gupta, Svetha Venkatesh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00246f</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
