<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:45:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>SMATool: Strength of Materials Analysis Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109189</link>
      <description>Chinedu Ekuma, Computer physics communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393254202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chinedu Ekuma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances on Computational Modeling of Supported Single-Atom and Cluster Catalysts: Characterization, Catalyst&#8211;Support Interaction, and Active Site Heterogeneity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14040224</link>
      <description>Jiayi Xu, Colton J. Lund, Prajay Patel, Yu Lim Kim, Cong Liu, Catalysts. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393254287

                To satisfy the need for catalyst materials with high activity, selectivity, and stability for energy conversion, material design and discovery guided by theoretical insights are a necessity. In the past decades, the rise in theoretical investigations into the properties of catalyst materials, reaction mechanisms, and catalyst design principles has shed light on the catalysis field. Quantitative structure&#8211;activity relationships have been developed through incorporating spectroscopic simulations, electronic structure calculations, and reaction mechanistic studies. In this review, we report the state-of-the-art computational approaches to catalyst materials characterization for supported single-atom and cluster catalysts utilizing spectroscopic simulations, i.e., XANES simulation, and material properties investigation via electronic-structure calculations. Furthermore, approaches regarding reaction mechanisms, focusing on active site heterogeneity, are also discussed.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Xu, Colton J. Lund, Prajay Patel, Yu Lim Kim, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14040224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Electrocatalytic Activity in HMF Oxidation to FDCA by Fine&#8208;Tuning the Degree of NiOOH Phase Over Ni Nanoparticles Supported on Graphene Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400779</link>
      <description>Sorasak Klinyod, Nuttapon Yodsin, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Zikkawas Pasom, Sunpet Assavapanumat, Marisa Ketkaew, Pinit Kidkhunthod, Tetsu Yonezawa, Supawadee Namuangruk, Chularat Wattanakit, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393259803

                Abstract The development of an efficient electrocatalyst for HMF oxidation to FDCA has been in the early stages. Herein, the NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam is fabricated as an electrocatalyst for FDCA production. However, the electrocatalytic performance of the untreated NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam is observed with moderate Faradaic efficiency (FE) (73.0%) and FDCA yield (80.2%). By electrochemically treating the NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam in an alkaline solution with positive potential at different treatment durations, the degree of NiOOH on metal surfaces is changed. The distinctive electrocatalytic activity obtained when using the different NiOOH degrees allows to understand the crucial impact of NiOOH species in HMF electrooxidation. Enhancing the portion of the NiOOH phase on the electrocatalyst surface improves electrocatalytic activity in terms of FE and FDCA yield up to 94.8&#177;4.8% and 86.9&#177;4.1%, respectively. Interestingly, as long as the NiOOH portion on the electrocatalyst surface is preserved or regenerated, the electrocatalyst performance can be intact even after several catalytic cycles. The theoretical study via density functional theory (DFT) also agrees with the experimental observations and confirms that the NiOOH phase facilitates the electrochemical transformation of HMF to FDCA through the HMFCA pathway, and the potential limiting step of the overall reaction is the oxidation of FFCA to FDCA.</description>
      <author>Sorasak Klinyod, Nuttapon Yodsin, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Zikkawas Pasom, Sunpet Assavapanumat, Marisa Ketkaew, Pinit Kidkhunthod, Tetsu Yonezawa, Supawadee Namuangruk, Chularat Wattanakit</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultralow charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap of 0.05 V in sunlight&#8208;responsive neutral aqueous Zn&#8211;air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.535</link>
      <description>Zhimin Niu, Yan Gao, Tianhui Wu, Fei Zhang, Ran Zhao, Zijia Chen, Yiming Yuan, Tifeng Jiao, Jianmin Gu, L&#252; Li, Desong Wang, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393260047

                Abstract Rechargeable neutral aqueous zinc&#8722;air batteries (ZABs) are a promising type of energy storage device with longer operating life and less corrosiveness compared with conventional alkaline ZABs. However, the neutral ZABs normally possess poor oxygen evolution reactions (OERs) and oxygen reduction reactions performance, resulting in a large charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap and low round&#8208;trip efficiency. Herein, we demonstrate a sunlight&#8208;assisted strategy for achieving an ultralow voltage gap of 0.05 V in neutral ZABs by using the FeOOH&#8208;decorated BiVO 4 (Fe&#8208;BiVO 4 ) as an oxygen catalyst. Under sunlight, the electrons move from the valence band (VB) of Fe&#8208;BiVO 4 to the conduction band producing holes in VB to promote the OER process and hence reduce the overpotential. Meanwhile, the photopotential generated by the Fe&#8208;BiVO 4 compensates a part of the charging potential of neutral ZABs. Accordingly, the energy loss of the battery could be compensated via solar energy, leading to a record&#8208;low gap of 0.05 V between the charge and discharge voltage with a high round&#8208;trip efficiency of 94%. This work offers a simple but efficient pathway for solar&#8208;energy utilization in storage devices, further guiding the design of high energy efficiency of neutral aqueous ZABs.</description>
      <author>Zhimin Niu, Yan Gao, Tianhui Wu, Fei Zhang, Ran Zhao, Zijia Chen, Yiming Yuan, Tifeng Jiao, Jianmin Gu, L&#252; Li, Desong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Valence W&lt;sup&gt;6+&lt;/sup&gt; Ions Boost Cr&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; Activity in CrWO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Ideal Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400114</link>
      <description>C. Kim, Dasom Jeon, Nayeong Kim, Jungki Ryu, JunHee Lee, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393261486

                Abstract Electrocatalytic activity of multi&#8208;valence metal oxides for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) arises from various interactions among the constituent metal elements. Although the high&#8208;valence metal ions attract recent attentions due to the interactions with their neighboring 3 d transition metal catalytic center, atomic&#8208;scale explanations for the catalytic efficiencies are still lacking. Here, by employing density functional theory predictions and experimental verifications, unprecedented electronic isolation of the catalytic 3 d center ( M 2+ ) induced by the surrounding high&#8208;valence ions such as W 6+ is discovered in multivalent oxides M WO 4 ( M = Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, and Zn). Due to W 6+ &#8217;s extremely high oxidation state with the minimum electron occupations (d 0 ), the surrounding W 6+ blocks electron transfer toward the catalytic M 2+ ions and completely isolates the ions electronically. Now, the isolated M 2+ ions solely perform OER without any assistant electron flow from the adjacent metal ions, and thus the original strong binding energies of Cr with OER intermediates are effectively moderated. Through exploiting &#8220;electron isolators&#8221; such as W 6+ surrounding the catalytic ion, exploring can be done beyond the conventional materials such as Ni&#8208; or Co&#8208;oxides into new candidate groups such as Cr and Mn on the left side of the periodic table for ideal OER.</description>
      <author>C. Kim, Dasom Jeon, Nayeong Kim, Jungki Ryu, JunHee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Design of Transition Metal-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01456</link>
      <description>Liang Guo, Jingwen Zhou, Fu Liu, Xiangchuan Meng, Yangbo Ma, Fengkun Hao, Yi Xiong, Zhanxi Fan, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Guo, Jingwen Zhou, Fu Liu, Xiangchuan Meng, Yangbo Ma, Fengkun Hao, Yi Xiong, Zhanxi Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Interlayer Bonding on Superlubric Sliding of Graphene Contacts: A Machine-Learning Potential Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c13099</link>
      <description>Penghua Ying, Amir Natan, Oded Hod, Michael Urbakh, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277820

                Surface defects and their mutual interactions are anticipated to affect the superlubric sliding of incommensurate layered material interfaces. Atomistic understanding of this phenomenon is limited due to the high computational cost of ab initio simulations and the absence of reliable classical force-fields for molecular dynamics simulations of defected systems. To address this, we present a machine-learning potential (MLP) for bilayer defected graphene, utilizing state-of-the-art graph neural networks trained against many-body dispersion corrected density functional theory calculations under iterative configuration space exploration. The developed MLP is utilized to study the impact of interlayer bonding on the friction of bilayer defected graphene interfaces. While a mild effect on the sliding dynamics of aligned graphene interfaces is observed, the friction coefficients of incommensurate graphene interfaces are found to significantly increase due to interlayer bonding, nearly pushing the system out of the superlubric regime. The methodology utilized herein is of general nature and can be adapted to describe other homogeneous and heterogeneous defected layered material interfaces.</description>
      <author>Penghua Ying, Amir Natan, Oded Hod, Michael Urbakh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c13099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transferable Water Potentials Using Equivariant Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00605</link>
      <description>Tristan Maxson, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393280718

                Machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) have emerged as a technique that promises quantum theory accuracy for reduced cost. It has been proposed [J. Chem. Phys. 2023, 158, 084111] that MLIPs trained on solely liquid water data cannot accurately transfer to the vapor&#8211;liquid equilibrium while recovering the many-body decomposition (MBD) analysis of gas-phase water clusters. This suggests that MLIPs do not directly learn the physically correct interactions of water molecules, limiting transferability. In this work, we show that MLIPs using equivariant architecture and trained on 3200 liquid water structures reproduces liquid-phase water properties (e.g., density within 0.003 g/cm3 between 230 and 365 K), vapor&#8211;liquid equilibrium properties up to 550 K, the MBD analysis of gas-phase water cluster up to six-body interactions, and the relative energy and the vibrational density of states of ice phases. We show that potentials developed using equivariant MLIPs allow transferability for arbitrary phases of water that remain stable in nanosecond long simulations.</description>
      <author>Tristan Maxson, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvement of manganese electrolytic process and secondary resources recovery of manganese&#65306;a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2024.03.097</link>
      <description>Tianyi Wu, Baozhong Ma, Yarui An, Yongqiang Chen, Chengyan Wang, Process Safety and Environmental Protection. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393282254

                The mainstream process for the production of electrolytic manganese metal is hydrometallurgy, which includes leaching, purification and electrolysis. The electrolytic process consumes the most energy in the whole production. With the development of manganese mineral resources, the recovery of manganese from secondary sources plays an important role. Therefore, the majorization of the manganese electrolytic process and the recovery of manganese from secondary resources are very important. This article introduces the process flow of manganese metallurgy and provides a systematic overview of the optimisation of various aspects of the manganese electrolytic process, including the improvement of the electrolytic cell, the development of the electrodes, the innovation of current applying methods and the exploration of additives. At the same time, this review also summarizes the recovery methods of valuable elements from secondary resources in recent years. Finally, the challenges and future prospects of electrolytic manganese metal are discussed.</description>
      <author>Tianyi Wu, Baozhong Ma, Yarui An, Yongqiang Chen, Chengyan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2024.03.097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical fundamentals | Mixed potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00187-0</link>
      <description>&#193;ngel Cuesta, Alan J. Gibson, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393286278

                In this chapter we first explain the concept of mixed potentials by comparison with equilibrium potentials and then expand briefly on the relevance of mixed potentials in corrosion, where the concept was used first. The relevance of mixed potentials to understanding electrocatalytic reactions follows then, using the peroxide oxidation and reduction reactions and their connection with the oxygen reduction reaction as an example. This then allows us to explain the effect of mixed potentials on the performance of electrochemical energy conversion and storage. The chapter also includes some practical applications of the measurement of mixed potentials, such as the detection of modern forgeries of archeological objects or the determination of kinetic parameters of electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>&#193;ngel Cuesta, Alan J. Gibson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00187-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical fundamentals | Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00188-2</link>
      <description>Enrique Herrero, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393286318

                In this chapter, the basic principles of electrocatalysis will be presented. A general description of the electrocatalytic phenomena will be given, emphasizing the necessity of a specific interaction between the electrode surface, which acts as the electrocatalyst, and some of the species (reactants or intermediates) participating in the electrochemical reaction. A model that justifies the appearance of volcano curves when the electrochemical reaction rates are plotted vs. the electrode adsorption properties will be described. The implications of this model for some of the most important electrochemical reactions will be discussed as well as the limits in its application. Finally, the effects of the interfacial properties in the electrocatalysis, such as surface charge, pH, and electrolyte composition (anions and cations) will be described providing examples of their effects.</description>
      <author>Enrique Herrero, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00188-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water-regulated 2D Ni-MOF-derived heat-sheared Nano-Ni@TC for efficient hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.312</link>
      <description>Qianwei Chen, Lianghuo Fan, Wenqian Liu, Ruilin He, Jieyu Zhang, Yangyang Tan, Wei Sun, Shu&#8208;Juan Bao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393295238

                Hydrogen energy has garnered significant attention due to its high calorific value and minimal environmental impact. However, the high-current electrolysis of water encounters challenges such as insufficient active sites and the disruptive effects from rapidly generated bubbles. In this paper, a small amount of water was introduced to modify the strong coordination ability of metal ions with organic ligands, and prepared 2D Ni MOFs. Subsequently, thin carbon-armed Ni-based catalysts (Ni@TC NPs) were prepared through nickel-assisted low-temperature pyrolysis. Unlike other 3D MOFs, the 2D MOF thin sheets prepared in this work can decompose at low temperatures due to its thin thickness, and the exposed Ni will accelerate the carbonization of surrounding organic groups, resulting in the formation of smaller and uniformly distributed thin carbon-armored Ni@TC NPs at lower temperature. Serving as a Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) electrocatalyst, Ni@TC NPs demonstrate exceptional electrocatalytic performance (low overpotential of 36.6 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and low Tafel slope of 91.06 mV dec&#8722;1), and long-term stability (over 50 h at 440 mA cm&#8722;2). The electronic modulation between the thin carbon armor and the metal center endows Ni@TC NPs with excellent kinetic performance, while the carbon armor provides protection in alkaline environments. In addition, the small and dense bubbles that quickly escape greatly reduce the bubble shielding and oscillation effects on the electrode surface, enabling Ni@TC NPs to work stably under high currents.</description>
      <author>Qianwei Chen, Lianghuo Fan, Wenqian Liu, Ruilin He, Jieyu Zhang, Yangyang Tan, Wei Sun, Shu&#8208;Juan Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal single-atoms supported on hexagonal ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; monolayers for the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00107a</link>
      <description>Xinlu Cheng, Kui Cheng, Xiaowang Zhou, Mingyang Shi, Gang Jiang, Jiguang Du, PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393299658

                The 2D h-ZnIn 2 S 4 monolayers are used as substrate materials to investigate the HER catalytic activity of single TM atoms supported on the surface, and the mechanism of the high catalytic activity of SAC is also discussed.</description>
      <author>Xinlu Cheng, Kui Cheng, Xiaowang Zhou, Mingyang Shi, Gang Jiang, Jiguang Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00107a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible Hydrogen Electrode (RHE) Scale Dependent Surface Pourbaix Diagram at Different pH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00298</link>
      <description>Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Wang Yuan, Hao Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393301713

                In the analysis of electrocatalysis mechanisms and the design of catalysts, the effect of electrochemistry-induced surface coverage is a critical consideration that should not be overlooked. The surface Pourbaix diagram emerges as a fundamental tool in this context, providing essential insights into the surface coverage of adsorbates generated via electrochemical potential-driven water activation. A classic surface Pourbaix diagram considers the pH effects by correcting the free energy of H+ ions by the concentration-dependent term: &#8722;kBT ln(10) &#215; pH, which is independent of the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) scale. However, this is sometimes inconsistent with the experimentally observed potential-dependent surface coverage at an RHE scale, especially under high-pH conditions. Here, we derived the pH-dependent surface Pourbaix diagram at an RHE scale by considering the energetics computed by density functional theory with the Bayesian Error Estimation Functional with van der Waals corrections (BEEF-vdW), the electric field effects, the derived adsorption-induced dipole moment and polarizability, and the potential of zero-charge. Using Pt(111) as the typical example, we found that the surface coverage predicted by the proposed RHE-dependent surface Pourbaix diagram can significantly minimize the discrepancy between theory and experimental observations, especially under neutral-alkaline, moderate-potential conditions. This work provides a new methodology and establishes guidelines for the precise analysis of the surface coverage prior to the evaluation of the activity of an electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Wang Yuan, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid Electrolyte Anions Adsorption Effects on IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08103</link>
      <description>S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393302584

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis is a promising technology merging the usage of intermittent renewable energy sources with the production of green hydrogen. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction remains the bottleneck of the efficiency of these devices due to sluggish reaction kinetics, high cost, and the scarcity of state-of-the-art catalytic materials. Though most research is focused on the discovery of new catalytic materials, understanding the effects of acid electrolyte anions is crucial to designing and optimizing existing electrocatalysts in diverse electrochemical microenvironments. Herein, we systematically study the effects of acid electrolytes on the IrO2(110) surface under OER reaction conditions using density functional theory. The potential-dependent anion adsorption results show that HPO42&#8211; adsorbs the strongest, followed by SO42&#8211;, NO3&#8211;, and ClO4&#8211; respectively at 1.6 V (vs RHE). HPO42&#8211; and SO42&#8211; block the Ir-active sites by competitively adsorbing with the OER intermediates while ClO4&#8211; does not interfere with OER performance. By evaluating dipole-field interactions, surface work function changes, Bader charges of adsorbed anions, and the effects of adsorbed electrolyte anions on the adsorption of the OER intermediates, we provide further insights into acid anion electrolyte effects under the OER conditions. This expansion of fundamental understanding of the effects of acid electrolyte anion adsorption on IrO2 assists in engineering better-performing catalysts with integrated electrolyte microenvironment for OER.</description>
      <author>S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The reduction mechanism of C1 product from carbon dioxide catalyzed by Ni-doped g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Molecular catalysis (Online). 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393305887

                This work employs density functional theory (DFT) to scrutinize the catalytic efficacy of nano nickel (Ni) clusters supported by graphitic carbon nitride (Nin@g-C3N4, where n ranges from 1 to 6) in the context of the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Structural examination revealed that Nin@g-C3N4 possesses a substantial binding energy (-1.63 eV to -7.72 eV), confirming the structural stability of the catalyst in the CO2RR. Electronic structure analysis revealed a pronounced orbital overlap near the Fermi level between the 3d orbital of Ni atoms and the 2p orbital of adjacent cavity nitrogen atoms in Nin@g-C3N4. Further insights are gleaned from the calculations of the Bader charge and energy band, indicating significant charge transfer and band gap alteration, suggesting enhanced conductivity due to Ni doping on g-C3N4. The catalytic performance in the CO2RR is predominantly influenced by the size of the doped Ni clusters. The Ni4@g-C3N4 cluster demonstrated optimal efficiency in producing formic acid (HCOOH) with a limiting potential of -0.12 V. In contrast, the Ni5@g-C3N4 cluster excels in methane (CH4) formation, with a limiting potential of -0.35 V. Additionally, these catalysts exhibit marked inhibition of the hydrogen evolution reaction, further underscoring their potential in CO2RR applications.</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous confined Pt-based intermetallic compound with wrinkled carbon to enhance the performance towards oxygen reduction reaction for proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234357</link>
      <description>Ferng Chun Ke, Qian Cheng, Dong Ge Tong, Deyou Liu, Xu Xiang, Yubin Chen, Hui Yang, Hui Yang, Journal of power sources (Print). 603(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393307875

                The formation of small-sized (&lt;5 nm) and high-loading (&gt;50 wt%) Pt-based intermetallic compound structures commonly requires thermal treatment to conquer the atom-ordering barrier, which inevitably causes severe nanoparticle agglomeration and hence reduces oxygen reduction reaction activity. Herein, we provided a synthetic wrinkled carbon support by vapor deposition from methane (CH4), and then we utilized the carbon to synthesize sub-5 nm high-loading (50.6 wt%) Pt3Co1 intermetallic compound by mesoporous confinement effect. Structural characterizations reveal that the nanoparticles are mainly located in the pores of the mesoporous carbon with an average size of ca. 4.1 nm, corroborating the confinement effect of the mesoporous structure. As a consequence, the Pt3Co1 intermetallic compound catalyst exhibits superior oxygen reduction reaction activity with a mass activity (@0.9V) of 0.35 A/mgPt and satisfactory durability with a mass activity decline by 22% after 40k-cycles accelerated durability test. Membrane electrode assembly with the resultant catalyst delivers the desirable performance with the peak power density of ca. 1.0 W/cm2 while lowering the Pt loading to 0.1 mg/cm2, suggesting the practical application potential in low-Pt proton exchange membrane fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Ferng Chun Ke, Qian Cheng, Dong Ge Tong, Deyou Liu, Xu Xiang, Yubin Chen, Hui Yang, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directional multiobjective optimization of metal complexes at the billion-system scale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00616-5</link>
      <description>Hannes Kneiding, Ainara Nova, David Balcells, Nature computational science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393309150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hannes Kneiding, Ainara Nova, David Balcells</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00616-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Mechanism on Typical MXenes under Realistic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00072</link>
      <description>Xueli Liu, Libo Yao, Sijia Zhang, Chuanqi Huang, Wenshao Yang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393316898

                MXenes are a revolutionary class of two-dimensional materials that have been recently demonstrated to exhibit promising capability of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) in theory and experiment. In electrocatalytic reactions, the active phases, the mechanism, and the performance can be greatly influenced by electrochemical conditions such as applied electrode potential, pH, and electrolyte. Therefore, in this first-principles study, the stable surface structures of three typical MXenes (V2C, Mo2C, and Ti3C2) with variation of electrocatalytic conditions were determined by the Pourbaix phase diagrams. Additionally, the reaction mechanism for CO2RR toward C1 products was investigated based on the thermal dynamically stable phases. The computation revealed that surfaces of all three MXenes are dominated by H* termination throughout the practical CO2RR electrochemical condition ranges. Meanwhile, the bicarbonate ions, which serve as the major electrolyte in CO2RR, show thermal dynamic unfavorability to adsorb on the surfaces. Among the three types of MXenes, V2CH exhibits higher activity in generating CO and HCOOH through the CO2RR, while Mo2CH exhibits higher activity in producing HCHO, CH3OH, and CH4. This comprehensive study provides crucial insights into the mechanism of electrocatalytic CO2RR on MXenes under realistic electrochemical conditions.</description>
      <author>Xueli Liu, Libo Yao, Sijia Zhang, Chuanqi Huang, Wenshao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Review of Bimetallic Nanoparticle&#8211;Graphene Oxide and Bimetallic Nanoparticle&#8211;Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Nanocomposites as Photo-, Electro-, and Photoelectrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071646</link>
      <description>Mogwasha D. Makhafola, Sheriff A. Balogun, Kwena D. Modibane, Energies (Basel). 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317710

                This review extensively discusses current developments in bimetallic nanoparticle&#8211;GO and bimetallic nanoparticle&#8211;MOF nanocomposites as potential catalysts for HER, along with their different synthesis methodologies, structural characteristics, and catalytic mechanisms. The photoelectrocatalytic performance of these catalysts was also compared based on parameters such as Tafel slope, current density, onset potential, turnover frequency, hydrogen yield, activation energy, stability, and durability. The review shows that the commonly used metal alloys in the bimetallic nanoparticle&#8211;GO-based catalysts for HERs include Pt-based alloys (e.g., PtNi, PtCo, PtCu, PtAu, PtSn), Pd-based alloys (e.g., PdAu, PdAg, PdPt) or other combinations, such as AuNi, AuRu, etc., while the most used electrolyte sources are H2SO4 and KOH. For the bimetallic nanoparticle MOF-based catalysts, Pt-based alloys (e.g., PtNi, PtCu), Pd-based alloys (e.g., PdAg, PdCu, PdCr), and Ni-based alloys (e.g., NiMo, NiTi, NiAg, NiCo) took the lead, with KOH being the most frequently used electrolyte source. Lastly, the review addresses challenges and prospects, highlighting opportunities for further optimization and technological integration of the catalysts as promising alternative photo/electrocatalysts for future hydrogen production and storage.</description>
      <author>Mogwasha D. Makhafola, Sheriff A. Balogun, Kwena D. Modibane</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Double Perovskites in the Dion&#8211;Jacobson Phase Alleviate Parity Forbidden Transitions for Photovoltaic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03276</link>
      <description>Robert V. Stanton, Dhara Trivedi, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317812

                Two-dimensional double perovskites have recently been identified as a potential class of materials for the improvement of halide-perovskite-based solar cell technology. The expanded set of utilizable B- and B&#8242;-site cations afforded to double perovskites, combined with tunable structural and electronic properties in two-dimensional perovskites, leads to a highly modifiable set of materials, which have yet to be explored. In this study, we investigate the structural, electronic, and thermoelectric properties of these materials and identify a number of key structure&#8211;property relationships governing their performance. In the process, we demonstrate a link between the relative electronegativities of the building components and the resultant geometric structures. Furthermore, we provide insights aimed toward alleviating concerns associated with parity forbidden transitions which plague many double perovskite systems. In addition, we identify a number of two-dimensional double perovskites including the mixed-oxidation state In25Tl75Cl-based system which displays optically active transitions as low as 1.41 eV across the Brillouin zone and indicators pointing toward stable experimental synthesis.</description>
      <author>Robert V. Stanton, Dhara Trivedi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects of Carbon Vacancies in Conjunction with Phosphorus Dopant across Bilayer Graphene for the Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c00495</link>
      <description>Huimin Hu, Jin Ho Choi, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393318016

                Bilayer graphene (BLG) exhibits distinct physical properties under external influences, such as torsion and structural defects, setting it apart from monolayer graphene. In this study, we explore the synergistic effects of carbon vacancies, in conjunction with phosphorus dopants, across BLG, focusing on their impact on structural, magnetic, electrical, and hydrogen adsorption properties. Our findings reveal that the substitutional doping of a phosphorus atom into a single carbon vacancy in a graphene layer induces substantial structural distortion in BLG. In contrast, doping phosphorus into a double vacancy maintains the flat structure of graphene layers. These distinct layer structures affect the electron distribution and spin arrangement, leading to varied electronic configurations and intriguing magnetic behaviors. Furthermore, the presence of abundant unsaturated electrons around the vacancy promotes the capture and bonding of hydrogen atoms. Hydrogen adsorption on BLG results in substantial orbital hybridization, accompanied by significant charge transfer. The calculated Gibbs free energies for hydrogen adsorption on BLG range from &#8722;0.08 to 0.09 eV, indicating exceptional catalytic activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction. These findings carry implications for optimizing the properties of graphene layers, making them highly desirable for applications such as catalysis.</description>
      <author>Huimin Hu, Jin Ho Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c00495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effects of Fe and P doping in WS2 monolayers for enhanced bifunctional electrocatalysis in water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.261</link>
      <description>Sampath Prabhakaran, Getasew Mulualem Zewdie, Hong Seok Kang, Do Hwan Kim, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393332697

                The quest for efficient dual-purpose electrocatalysts to facilitate water splitting is an ongoing challenge in materials science. In this study, we introduce a novel approach involving the incorporation of Fe and P atoms into WS2 monolayers (MLs) through rigorous first-principle calculations. The introduction of Fe and P atoms brings about remarkable enhancements in the electronic properties of the WS2 MLs, significantly boosting the catalytic performance of the 1T' phase. The doping-induced changes in energy levels lead to the formation of a spin-polarized density of states, which exhibits superior conductivity in the vicinity of the d-band center and Fermi level. These electronic alterations are intricately governed by the valence and conduction bands. In addition to this, the introduced dopants elevate the charge transfer rate while simultaneously reducing interfacial resistance. Furthermore, the strong bonding of the dopants plays a pivotal role in reducing the energy barrier during adsorption. This, in turn, leads to a substantial decrease in the Gibbs free energy (0.101 eV) for the hydrogen evolution reaction and a lowered overpotential (0.36 V) for the oxygen evolution reaction. These findings collectively offer a promising avenue for the development of advanced bifunctional catalysts in the context of water splitting, suggesting that substitutional heteroatom doping of 1T&#8242;-WS2 MLs holds substantial potential in this field.</description>
      <author>Sampath Prabhakaran, Getasew Mulualem Zewdie, Hong Seok Kang, Do Hwan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pivotal role of Ce3+ polarons on promoting oxygen reduction reaction activity of Pt1/CeO2 catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234393</link>
      <description>Yan Jiang, Wei Xiao, Rong Zeng, Qi&#8208;Jun Hong, Xiaowu Li, Ligen Wang, Journal of power sources (Print). 603(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393337631

                The Pt1/CeO2 single-atom catalyst excels across catalytic fields, promising applications in the oxygen reduction reactions (ORRs). Here, we employ first-principles calculations to systematically investigate the ORR mechanism catalyzed by Pt1/CeO2 systems and the activity regulated by Ce3+ polarons. We determine the reaction pathways of different Pt1/CeO2 systems by evaluating four critical factors: O2 adsorption energy, O2 dissociation Gibbs barrier, Gibbs free energy change for O2&#8594;OOH*, and H2O2 adsorption structure. Notably, most Pt1/CeO2 systems tend to react through the 4e&#8722; associative path. Theoretical activity calculations reveal that PtOH/CeO2(110) system show low overpotential of 0.47 V comparable to pure Pt. The excellent ORR activity is attributed to the synergistic mechanism of Pt and surrounding Ce3+ polarons, where the polaron regulation mechanism dominates the reaction. The quantity of Ce3+ polarons not only affects the reaction active sites but also regulates the radical adsorption state. With an elevated Ce3+ polarons concentration, the ORR overpotential in Pt1/CeO2 system can decrease from 0.47 to 0.16 V, leading to a substantial enhancement in activity. This work first underscores the crucial involvement of Ce3+ polarons in catalyzing the ORR, reducing the significance of Pt in catalysis, inspiring a new way to design active non-platinum electrocatalysts for ORR in experiments.</description>
      <author>Yan Jiang, Wei Xiao, Rong Zeng, Qi&#8208;Jun Hong, Xiaowu Li, Ligen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photochemical reduction of ultrasmall Pt nanoparticles on single-layer transition-metal dichalcogenides for hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2023.101487</link>
      <description>Liang Mei, Yuefeng Zhang, Ting Ying, W. Zheng, Honglu Hu, Ruijie Yang, Ruixin Yan, Yue Zhang, Chong Cheng, Bilu Liu, Shuang Li, Zhiyuan Zeng, Materials today energy. 42(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393337653

                Single-layer TaS2 and TiS2 nanosheets were meticulously synthesized through an electrochemical lithium-intercalation-based exfoliation method. Subsequently, ultrasmall Pt nanoparticles, finely sized between 1.2 and 1.6 nm, were expertly deposited onto these monolayer nanosheets via an environmentally friendly photochemical reduction process. The resulted Pt-TaS2 and Pt-TiS2 composites exhibit hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity comparable with commercial Pt/C. Density functional theory calculations reveal that the introduced Pt (111) plane energetically promotes the adsorption of &#8727;H with an optimal &#916;G value of 0.09 eV. Furthermore, these composite materials demonstrate outstanding cycle stability, far exceeding that of Pt/C. This compelling performance underscores the potential of Pt-TaS2 and Pt-TiS2 hybrids as promising alternatives for HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Liang Mei, Yuefeng Zhang, Ting Ying, W. Zheng, Honglu Hu, Ruijie Yang, Ruixin Yan, Yue Zhang, Chong Cheng, Bilu Liu, Shuang Li, Zhiyuan Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2023.101487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validation workflow for machine learning interatomic potentials for complex ceramics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</link>
      <description>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash, Computational materials science. 239(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393373529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process Operability Analysis of Membrane-Based Direct Air Capture for Low-Purity CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsengineeringau.3c00069</link>
      <description>Vitor V. Gama, Beatriz Dantas, Oishi Sanyal, Fernando V. Lima, ACS Engineering Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277124

                Addressing climate change constitutes one of the major scientific challenges of this century, and it is widely acknowledged that anthropogenic CO2 emissions largely contribute to this issue. To achieve the "net-zero" target and keep the rise in global average temperature below 1.5 &#176;C, negative emission technologies must be developed and deployed at a large scale. This study investigates the feasibility of using membranes as direct air capture (DAC) technology to extract CO2 from atmospheric air to produce low-purity CO2. In this work, a two-stage hollow fiber membrane module process is designed and modeled using the AVEVA Process Simulation platform to produce a low-purity (&#8776;5%) CO2 permeate stream. Such low-purity CO2 streams could have several possible applications such as algae growth, catalytic oxidation, and enhanced oil recovery. An operability analysis is performed by mapping a feasible range of input parameters, which include membrane surface area and membrane performance metrics, to an output set, which consists of CO2 purity, recovery, and net energy consumption. The base case for this simulation study is generated considering a facilitated transport membrane with high CO2/N2 separation performance (CO2 permeance = 2100 GPU and CO2/N2 selectivity = 1100), when tested under DAC conditions. With a constant membrane area, both membranes' intrinsic performances are found to have a considerable impact on the purity, recovery, and energy consumption. The area of the first module plays a dominant role in determining the recovery, purity, and energy demands, and in fact, increasing the area of the second membrane has a negative impact on the overall energy consumption, without improving the overall purities. The CO2 capture capacity of DAC units is important for implementation and scale-up. In this context, the performed analysis showed that the m-DAC process could be appropriate as a small-capacity system (0.1&#8211;1 Mt/year of air), with reasonable recoveries and overall purity. Finally, a preliminary CO2 emissions analysis is carried out for the membrane-based DAC process, which leads to the conclusion that the overall energy grid must be powered by renewable sources for the technology to qualify within the negative emissions category.</description>
      <author>Vitor V. Gama, Beatriz Dantas, Oishi Sanyal, Fernando V. Lima</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsengineeringau.3c00069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolytic Regeneration of Spent Caustic Soda from CO2 Capture Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</link>
      <description>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho, Processes. 12(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393866132

                The traditional electrochemical caustic soda recovery system uses the generated pH gradient across the ion exchange membrane for the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent from CO2 capture. This electrochemical CO2 capture system releases the by-products H2 and O2 at the cathode and anode, respectively. Although effective for capturing CO2, the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limit the energy efficiency of this technique. Hence, this study proposed and validated a hybrid electrochemical cell based on the H2-cycling from the cathode to the anode to eliminate the reliance on anodic oxygen generation. The results show that our lab-scale prototype enabled effective spent caustic soda recovery with an electron utilisation efficiency of 90%, and a relative carbonate/bicarbonate diffusional flux of approximately 40%. The system also enabled the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent with a minimum electrochemical energy input of 0.19 kWh/kg CO2 at a CO2 recovery rate of 0.7 mol/m2/h, accounting for 30% lower energy demand than a control system without H2-recycling, making this technique a promising alternative to the conventional thermal regeneration technology.</description>
      <author>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenges of hydrogen production from biomass gasification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13613-9.00005-2</link>
      <description>Jingwei Chen, Yilin Guo, Xiaomin Wu, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393323912

                With the development of alternative energy sources, biomass gasification for hydrogen production technology has attracted high attentions from researchers. This chapter introduces three main aspects: biomass gasification for hydrogen production technology, enhancement strategies for hydrogen production from biomass gasification, and hydrogen purification technology. The physical and chemical processes of hydrogen production from traditional biomass gasification, the effects of various key parameters on the performance of hydrogen production from biomass gasification, and the advantages and disadvantages of existing hydrogen purification technologies are introduced in details. Although the technology of hydrogen production from biomass gasification has been studied for many years, there are still challenges that hinder the commercialization and industrialization of hydrogen production technology from biomass gasification. The challenges including the detailed gasification evolution mechanisms of biomass, the gasification interactions between biomass components, the development of new catalysts and purification technologies, and the antiaging of catalytic and purification materials have been proposed in this chapter. In particular, there is a lack of precise and detailed descriptions of the gasification evolution mechanism of biomass macromolecules, catalytic and deactivation mechanisms of catalysts, which provide a theoretical basis for precise manipulation of the direction of hydrogen production reactions from biomass gasification. Finally, it is hoped that by overcoming the challenges presented, the technical barriers of hydrogen production from biomass gasification can be broken through, and the hydrogen production technology from biomass gasification can be commercialized and industrialized.</description>
      <author>Jingwei Chen, Yilin Guo, Xiaomin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13613-9.00005-2</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
