<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 01:24:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Water Adsorption on Pt(211): Insights from Heterodyne-Detected Vibrational Sum-Frequency Generation Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04469</link>
      <description>Naoki Nagatsuka, Takumi Otsuki, Takanori Koitaya, K. Watanabe, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413753398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naoki Nagatsuka, Takumi Otsuki, Takanori Koitaya, K. Watanabe</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic Stability Tests of Machine Learning Potentials for Molecular Simulations in Computational Drug Discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01150</link>
      <description>Kavindri Ranasinghe, Adam L. Baskerville, Geoffrey P. F. Wood, Gerhard K&#246;nig, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413755146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kavindri Ranasinghe, Adam L. Baskerville, Geoffrey P. F. Wood, Gerhard K&#246;nig</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the curse of dimensionality: Solving configurational integrals for crystalline solids by tensor networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/xrbw-xr49</link>
      <description>Duc P. Truong, Benjamin Nebgen, Derek DeSantis, Dimiter N. Petsev, K. &#216;. Rasmussen, Boian S. Alexandrov, Physical Review Materials. 9(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413756492

                Accurately evaluating configurational integrals for dense solids remains a central and difficult challenge in the statistical mechanics of condensed systems. Here, we present a tensor network approach that reformulates the high-dimensional configurational integral for identical-particle crystals into a sequence of computationally efficient summations. We represent the integrand as a high-dimensional tensor and apply tensor-train (TT) decomposition together with a custom TT-cross interpolation. This approach circumvents the need to explicitly construct the full tensor. We introduce tailored rank-1 and rank-2 schemes optimized for sharply peaked Boltzmann probability densities, typical for identical-particle crystals. When applied to the calculation of internal energy and pressure-temperature curves for crystalline Cu and Ar at high (GPa) pressures, as well as the alpha-to-beta phase transition diagram of Sn, our method accurately reproduces molecular dynamics simulation results using tight-binding, machine learning, hierarchical interacting particle&#8211;neural network, and modified embedded atom method potentials,all within seconds of computation time.</description>
      <author>Duc P. Truong, Benjamin Nebgen, Derek DeSantis, Dimiter N. Petsev, K. &#216;. Rasmussen, Boian S. Alexandrov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/xrbw-xr49</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CaTS: Toward Scalable and Efficient Transition State Screening for Catalyst Discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03945</link>
      <description>Jun Yin, Wentao Li, Honghao Chen, Ju Qiu, Huasheng Feng, Xiangya Xu, Qiuyan Jin, Xiaonan Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413758911

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Yin, Wentao Li, Honghao Chen, Ju Qiu, Huasheng Feng, Xiangya Xu, Qiuyan Jin, Xiaonan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts based on one-dimensional metal porphyrin chains toward oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0280114</link>
      <description>Liang Chen, Haiyang Gao, Chuncai Kong, Zhimao Yang, Tao Yang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413763347

                Single-atom catalysts has emerged as a groundbreaking concept in catalysis, where individual metal atoms are anchored on supports such as carbon-based materials, oxides, or nitrides, serving as isolated active sites for catalytic reactions. In the present study, we theoretically explore the geometries, bonding properties, electronic structures, and potential catalytic performances of the recently synthesized one-dimensional (1D) M-porphyrin chains, in which the M&#8211;N4&#8211;C motif acts as the active site for oxygen reduction reactions (ORRs). Three configurations of 1D M-porphyrin chains (M = Ni, Zn) were investigated, including (a) M-porphyrin ribbon, (b) butadiyne-linked M-porphyrin, and (c) M-porphyrin-fused graphene nanoribbons. The calculation results reveal that all those 1D M-porphyrin chains are semiconductors. Energy decomposition analysis combined with natural orbital for chemical valence (EDA-NOCV) shows that the metal&#8211;ligand interaction in Ni-porphyrin is stronger than that in Zn-porphyrin. Compared to Zn-porphyrin chains, Ni-porphyrin chains exhibit stronger adsorption and superior electron transfer capabilities, which is attributed to enhanced orbital hybridization between the Ni 3d atomic orbitals and adsorbed oxygen 2p orbitals. The catalytic reaction pathways of these chains are similar for all those SACs and depend slightly on linker types, highlighting the importance of the local environment of the M&#8211;N4&#8211;C coordination framework. These findings provide valuable insights into the design of SACs with tailored properties, offering significant potential for applications in energy conversion and environmental catalysis.</description>
      <author>Liang Chen, Haiyang Gao, Chuncai Kong, Zhimao Yang, Tao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0280114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Origin of Activity-Stability Trade-Off in Strain-Engineered Pt-Based Oxygen Reduction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03738</link>
      <description>Luyao Li, Liheng Wang, Zhiyao Duan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413768837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luyao Li, Liheng Wang, Zhiyao Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-scale 3D structural dynamics and functional degradation of Pt alloy nanocatalysts during the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63448-5</link>
      <description>Chaehwa Jeong, Juhyeok Lee, Hyesung Jo, KwangHo Lee, SangJae Lee, Colin Ophus, Peter Ercius, EunAe Cho, Yongsoo Yang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413770504

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaehwa Jeong, Juhyeok Lee, Hyesung Jo, KwangHo Lee, SangJae Lee, Colin Ophus, Peter Ercius, EunAe Cho, Yongsoo Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63448-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing machine learning interatomic potentials for hydroxide transport: Surprising efficiency of single-concentration training</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0284063</link>
      <description>Jonas H&#228;nseroth, Christian Dre&#223;ler, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413772894

                We investigate the transferability of machine learning interatomic potentials across concentration variations in chemically similar systems, using aqueous potassium hydroxide solutions as a case study. Despite containing identical chemical species (K+, OH&#8722;, and H2O) across all concentrations, models fine-tuned on specific KOH concentrations exhibit surprisingly poor transferability to others, with force prediction errors increasing dramatically from 30 meV &#197;&#8722;1 (at training concentration) to 90 meV &#197;&#8722;1 (at very different concentrations). This reveals a critical limitation when applying such models beyond their training domain, even within chemically homogeneous systems. We demonstrate that strategic selection of training data can substantially overcome these limitations without requiring extensive computational resources. Models fine-tuned on intermediate concentrations (6.26 mol l&#8722;1) exhibit remarkable transferability across the entire concentration spectrum (0.56&#8211;17.89 mol l&#8722;1), often outperforming more computationally expensive models trained on multiple concentration datasets. This approach enables accurate simulation of hydroxide transport dynamics across varying electrolyte conditions while maintaining near-quantum accuracy. Our simulations further reveal the emergence of hydroxide&#8211;hydroxide hydrogen bonding at high concentrations&#8212;a phenomenon not explicitly represented in dilute training data but successfully captured by our intermediate-concentration model. This work establishes practical guidelines for developing broadly applicable machine learning force fields with optimal transferability, challenging the assumption that diverse training datasets are always necessary for robust performance in similar chemical environments.</description>
      <author>Jonas H&#228;nseroth, Christian Dre&#223;ler</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0284063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping modulation effect on the electronic structure and catalytic activities of strontium titanate from first-principles investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151156</link>
      <description>Mingzhen Zhu, Shuhui Lv, Bin Xiao, Meijia Gao, Qiang Yang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 169(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413774790

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingzhen Zhu, Shuhui Lv, Bin Xiao, Meijia Gao, Qiang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjusting the Criteria for Hydrogen Evolution by Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12309</link>
      <description>Mansu Kim, Sohui Kim, Xijun Wang, Randall Q. Snurr, Joseph T. Hupp, Hyeon-Sik Jang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413775161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mansu Kim, Sohui Kim, Xijun Wang, Randall Q. Snurr, Joseph T. Hupp, Hyeon-Sik Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Sol&#8211;Gel NiFe (Oxy)hydroxide Coatings on Ni Foam Yield Unified Anodes for Robust AEM Water Electrolyzer Modules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c03052</link>
      <description>Sun Young Kang, Ok&#8208;Hee Kim, Hee Ji Choi, Hyunjoo Choi, Hosung Choi, Ilchai La, Gyoo&#8208;Soo Chae, Yong&#8208;Hun Cho, Gilho Kim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413787705

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sun Young Kang, Ok&#8208;Hee Kim, Hee Ji Choi, Hyunjoo Choi, Hosung Choi, Ilchai La, Gyoo&#8208;Soo Chae, Yong&#8208;Hun Cho, Gilho Kim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c03052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Conversion of Seawater Vapor to Hydrogen Using Cu&#8211;Fe/Al2O3 Catalysts Assisted by Non-thermal Plasma</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-025-05152-z</link>
      <description>Yuhang Zhong, Hui Xu, Zhiguo Li, Yuqi Zhang, Jianyuan Hou, Yuan Yuan, Xingang Liu, Renxi Zhang, Catalysis Letters. 155(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413788794

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhang Zhong, Hui Xu, Zhiguo Li, Yuqi Zhang, Jianyuan Hou, Yuan Yuan, Xingang Liu, Renxi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-025-05152-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the thermal transport properties of Biphenylene nanotubes: A molecular dynamics study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2025.127729</link>
      <description>Jhionathan de Lima, Cristiano F. Woellner, International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 255(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413789149

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jhionathan de Lima, Cristiano F. Woellner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2025.127729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fining Crystal Facet and Oxygen Vacancy Engineering of Bifunctional BiOBr Facilitates Excellent Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution and Phenol Hydroxylation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c03072</link>
      <description>Xue Li, Guangri Chen, Guoliang Zhu, Lianwei Shan, Jagadeesh Suriyaprakash, Haitao Wu, Xuejiao Li, Xiulan He, Limin Dong, Ziqi Shi, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413792927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Li, Guangri Chen, Guoliang Zhu, Lianwei Shan, Jagadeesh Suriyaprakash, Haitao Wu, Xuejiao Li, Xiulan He, Limin Dong, Ziqi Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c03072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence in Geomorphology: A Bibliometric Analysis of Trends, Techniques, and Global Research Patterns</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences15090331</link>
      <description>Marco Luppichini, Domenico Capolongo, Giovanni Scardino, Giovanni Scicchitano, M&#243;nica Bini, Geosciences. 15(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413796749

                In recent years, artificial intelligence has gained significant traction in Earth sciences, driving a shift from qualitative approaches to quantitative, data-driven methodologies. In geomorphology, artificial intelligence techniques are now applied at multiple scales and for diverse purposes, leveraging a wide spectrum of methods including supervised and unsupervised machine learning, regression algorithms, classification models, clustering techniques, neural networks, and dimensionality reduction. This study presents a structured bibliometric analysis of the scientific literature indexed in Scopus, analyzing over 2000 articles published between 1990 and 2024. Through a bibliometric approach, we explore temporal trends, the most commonly used artificial intelligence techniques, thematic domains, geographic patterns, and associated keywords. Results reveal the pervasive use of artificial intelligence in key geomorphological areas, particularly in fluvial, coastal, and erosional contexts, alongside the adoption of a rich variety of algorithms. The study also highlights the wide range of AI techniques applied in geomorphological research, spanning from traditional machine learning models to advanced neural architectures. This review provides a critical overview of the current landscape and outlines future directions to support more transparent, equitable, and integrated adoption of artificial intelligence in geomorphological research. The findings of this study are relevant to a wide range of stakeholders. Researchers and Ph.D. candidates can use the results to identify dominant thematic and methodological trajectories and detect underexplored areas. Data scientists and AI specialists may benefit from the mapped applications to implement advanced techniques in geomorphological contexts. The analysis also offers useful insights for funding agencies aiming to support strategic and equitable research development, particularly in underrepresented regions. Finally, journal editors and publishers may use emerging trends to inform the design of thematic issues and research priorities.</description>
      <author>Marco Luppichini, Domenico Capolongo, Giovanni Scardino, Giovanni Scicchitano, M&#243;nica Bini</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences15090331</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Catalyst&#8208;Support Interaction Stabilizes IrO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters for Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202515920</link>
      <description>Y. Liu, Haeseong Jang, Xiaoke Xi, Ying Zhong, Ruiguo Cao, Shuhong Jiao, Xiyu Li, Zhanwu Lei, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413796815

                Abstract Low&#8208;loading iridium (Ir) catalysts hold great promise for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their typically high Ir utilization and reduced cost. However, their practical application is limited by poor stability under the harsh acidic oxidative conditions of proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis. Here, a controlled structural transformation strategy is presented that converts an unstable LiCoO 2 &#8208;supported Ir single&#8208;atom catalyst (Ir&#8208;LiCoO 2 ) into a corrosion&#8208;resistant Co 3 O 4 &#8208;supported IrO x nanocluster catalyst (IrO x /Co 3 O 4 ), significantly enhancing catalyst durability. Strong catalyst&#8208;support interactions between IrO x and Co 3 O 4 facilitate charge transfer, thereby stabilizing the IrO x nanoclusters against leaching and optimizing the electronic structure of the Ir active sites. As a result, IrO x /Co 3 O 4 exhibits substantially enhanced OER performance compared to Ir&#8208;LiCoO 2 , achieving excellent operational stability over 1200 h and a low overpotential of &#8776;233 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 . This superior performance is further validated in PEM electrolyzers, confirming its practical applicability. Furthermore, theoretical calculations reveal that Ir sites in IrO x /Co 3 O 4 exhibit higher dissolution potentials and improve charge transfer capabilities with OER intermediates compare to those in Ir&#8208;LiCoO 2 and IrO 2 , which effectively suppresses Ir leaching and lowers the energy barrier of the potential&#8208;determining step.</description>
      <author>Y. Liu, Haeseong Jang, Xiaoke Xi, Ying Zhong, Ruiguo Cao, Shuhong Jiao, Xiyu Li, Zhanwu Lei, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202515920</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights into CO2 reduction on C3N3 supported single atom catalysts: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115439</link>
      <description>Sajjad Ali, Pir Muhammad Ismail, Muhammad Humayun, Hazem Abu&#8208;Farsakh, M. Bououdina, Faheem Jan, Molecular Catalysis. 586(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413801420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajjad Ali, Pir Muhammad Ismail, Muhammad Humayun, Hazem Abu&#8208;Farsakh, M. Bououdina, Faheem Jan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Adaptive Sn&#8211;Fe Electron Pair Centers in Pt/SnFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Anti-Tumor Synergistic Therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c11501</link>
      <description>Meichun Fu, Zhiyu Shao, Yuan Zhang, Qian Zhu, Kuo He, Mengzhu Zhang, Yuzhu Hou, Laiping Fang, Fei Yan, Shuang Zhang, Jianshi Du, Ping&#8217;an Ma, Keke Huang, Shouhua Feng, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413802585

                Despite the multiple advantages of high tissue penetration depth, selectivity, and noninvasiveness of photothermal-assisted antitumor synergistic therapy, developing photothermal agents with multifunctional characteristics, desirable tumor therapeutic effects, and biological stability remains a key challenge. Herein, an electronic structure-regulated strategy is proposed to activate self-adaptive Sn&#8211;Fe electron pair centers (Sn2+/Sn4+ and Fe2+/Fe3+) through loading the electron donor Pt (Pt/SFO-1, -2, -3, -4). Experimental and theoretical calculations indicate that abundant dynamic active centers can facilitate the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS), which enables Pt/SFO samples to possess catalase (CAT), peroxidase (POD), and oxidase (OXD) enzyme-like activities. Upon near-infrared (NIR) laser irradiation, Pt/SFO-2 with a Pt load of 0.9% achieves the highest ROS production, showing a 9-fold compared with SnFe2O4 and implements the synergistic therapy of photothermal therapy (PTT), photodynamic therapy (PDT), and chemodynamic therapy (CDT). The electronic state regulation of inorganic photothermal agents not only improves tumor therapeutic effects but also offers a novel strategy to regulate the electron structure of active centers.</description>
      <author>Meichun Fu, Zhiyu Shao, Yuan Zhang, Qian Zhu, Kuo He, Mengzhu Zhang, Yuzhu Hou, Laiping Fang, Fei Yan, Shuang Zhang, Jianshi Du, Ping&#8217;an Ma, Keke Huang, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c11501</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI, agentic models and lab automation for scientific discovery &#8212; the beginning of scAInce</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/frai.2025.1649155</link>
      <description>Thomas Hartung, Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence. 8(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413803484

                Until recently, the conversation about generative artificial intelligence in science revolved around the textual prowess of large language models such as GPT-3.5 and the promise that they might one day draft a decent literature review. Since then, progress has been nothing short of breathtaking. We now find ourselves in the era of multimodal, agentic systems that listen, see, speak and act, orchestrating cloud software and physical laboratory hardware with a fluency that would have sounded speculative in early 2023. In this review, I merge the substance of our 2024 white paper for the World Economic Forum Top-10-Technologies Report with the latest advances through mid-2025, charting a course from automated literature synthesis and hypothesis generation to self-driving laboratories, organoid intelligence and climate-scale forecasting. The discussion is grounded in emerging governance regimes&#8212;notably the European Union Artificial Intelligence Act and ISO 42001&#8212;and is written from the dual vantage-point of a toxicologist who has spent a career championing robust, humane science and of a field chief editor charged with safeguarding scholarly standards in Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence . I argue that research is entering a &#8220;co-pilot to lab-pilot&#8221; transition in which AI no longer merely interprets knowledge but increasingly acts upon it . This shift promises dramatic efficiency gains yet simultaneously amplifies concerns about reproducibility, auditability, safety and equitable access.</description>
      <author>Thomas Hartung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/frai.2025.1649155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Chemistry in Zeolite Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837676859-00312</link>
      <description>Alexander A. Kolganov, Evgeny A. Pidko, Zeolites. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413806482

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alexander A. Kolganov, Evgeny A. Pidko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837676859-00312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards selective Ir/IrO2 electrochemical dissolution of Ir-based electrocatalysts for enhanced proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238224</link>
      <description>Jia Du, Matej Zlatar, Damin Zhang, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Jonathan Quinson, Serhiy Cherevko, Matthias Arenz, Journal of Power Sources. 657(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413818446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Du, Matej Zlatar, Damin Zhang, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Jonathan Quinson, Serhiy Cherevko, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of machine learning in high-throughput screening of binary alloys for the hydrogenation of benzene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7387859/v1</link>
      <description>Zhili Chang, Guangquan Li, Wei&#8208;Jun Cai, Haolan Liu, Guangcheng Zhang, Wei&#8208;Tao Ou, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413819549

                Abstract The hydrogenation of benzene is a key reaction in industry, and binary alloys are promising candidates for improving the catalytic efficiency of this process. In this study, the adsorption energies of benzene and hydrogen over random 150 alloys are determined using density functional theory (DFT) calculation, and varied physical properties of alloys are used as descriptors. Four machine learning (ML) models, light gradient boosting machine (LGBM), extreme gradient boosting (XGBT), multilayer perceptron (MLP) and support vector machine (SVM) are employed to predict the adsorption energies. After feature selection and parameter optimization, LGBM model shows the highest prediction accuracy, with correlation coefficient (R2) and root mean square error (RMSE) of 0.813 and 0.415 eV for benzene, as well as 0.874 and 0.176 eV for hydrogen. Therefore, LGBM model is selected to predict the adsorption energies of benzene and hydrogen (&#916;EB and &#916;EH), and Cu2Ni2 has excellent &#916;EB and &#916;EH of -4.97 and &#8722; 1.81 eV.</description>
      <author>Zhili Chang, Guangquan Li, Wei&#8208;Jun Cai, Haolan Liu, Guangcheng Zhang, Wei&#8208;Tao Ou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7387859/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligned d-orbital energy level of dual-atom sites catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction in anion exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63322-4</link>
      <description>Youze Zeng, Xue Wang, Qi Wei, Changpeng Liu, Lanlu Lu, Meiling Xiao, Kai Li, Fei Xiao, Minhua Shao, Wei Xing, Jianbing Zhu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413819938

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youze Zeng, Xue Wang, Qi Wei, Changpeng Liu, Lanlu Lu, Meiling Xiao, Kai Li, Fei Xiao, Minhua Shao, Wei Xing, Jianbing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63322-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Janus XGa&#8211;PbP (X = S, Se) monolayers: excellent photocatalysts for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra04300j</link>
      <description>Khawla Chaoui, Warda Elaggoune, Luc Henrard, Kamel Zanat, Mohamed Achehboune, RSC Advances. 15(38)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413830424

                Janus V&#8211;IV&#8211;III&#8211;VI monolayers ( SGa&#8211;PbP, SeGa&#8211;PbP) show structural stability, tunable optoelectronics, and excellent photocatalytic activity, making them strong candidates for solar-driven hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Khawla Chaoui, Warda Elaggoune, Luc Henrard, Kamel Zanat, Mohamed Achehboune</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra04300j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect&#8208;Engineered ReS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles on NiS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheet Heterostructures as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500910</link>
      <description>Anki Reddy Mule, Chandan Chandru Gudal, Jun Ho Seok, Jeong Hwan Byun, Pil J. Yoo, Jung Kyu Kim, Sang Uck Lee, Jae Su Yu, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413831679

                Abstract Design and preparation of freestanding bifunctional ordered structural catalysts with superior activity, low cost, and good reversibility, are crucial for commercial water&#8208;splitting applications. In this study, a durable and effective NiS 2 /ReS 2 (NRS) electrocatalyst is successfully fabricated using various quantities of Re source on carbon cloth (CC) by a facile solvothermal method. Upon changing the quantities of the Re source, the catalyst dimensions and shape undergo substantial changes, enabling the control of the catalytic activity of NRS. In particular, the optimal NRS&#8208;50@CC displays remarkable catalytic performance for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions, revealing small overpotentials of 244 mV at 20 mA cm &#8722;2 and 108 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively, as well as notable stability. Moreover, the NRS&#8208;50@CC (+, &#8722;) cell device requires a voltage of &#8776;1.56 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . This paper proposes a novel approach for the construction of durable bifunctional electrocatalysts using exceptionally active layered metal chalcogenide materials.</description>
      <author>Anki Reddy Mule, Chandan Chandru Gudal, Jun Ho Seok, Jeong Hwan Byun, Pil J. Yoo, Jung Kyu Kim, Sang Uck Lee, Jae Su Yu, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precisely Bonded Fe&#9472;Cu Diatomic Sites with Nitrogen&#8208;Bridged Coordination on Hollow C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Spheres for Efficient C&#9472;N Coupling and Selective Photocatalytic Urea Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202512234</link>
      <description>Muhammad Irfan Ahmad, Xie Quan, Haokun Bai, Yanming Liu, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413839734

                Abstract The photocatalytic synthesis of urea from CO 2 and N 2 co&#8208;reduction presents a promising alternative to the conventional energy&#8208;intensive Haber&#8211;Bosch process. However, competitive adsorption on the catalyst surface often limits selectivity and yield. Here, we designed hollow graphitic carbon nitride (g&#8208;C 3 N 4 ) spheres, which serve as a high surface area scaffold for precise anchoring of Fe&#9472;Cu diatomic sites. Hollow architecture enhances light harvesting via inner&#8208;scattering effects and charge separation. Each Fe&#9472;Cu site is coordinated with two nitrogen atoms, forming N 2 &#9472;Fe 1 &#9472;Cu 1 &#9472;N 2 /C 3 N 4 DAC (hereafter referred to as FeCu/CN), which enables cooperative activation of CO 2 and N 2 , in contrast to monodispersed diatomic (Fe+Cu/CN), and single&#8208;atom catalysts (Fe/CN, Cu/CN). The FeCu/CN bonded pairs serve as highly efficient active centers, facilitating the synergistic adsorption and activation of multiple reactants. Specifically, during the co&#8208;reduction of CO 2 and N 2 , the Fe 1 site preferentially adsorbs and activates CO 2 , while bonded Cu 1 sites stabilize N 2 on FeCu/CN and enable synergistic C&#9472;N coupling through the formation of *NCON intermediates. As a result, the FeCu/CN achieves an exceptional urea yield of 7.40 mg&#183;g cat &#8722;1 &#183;h &#8722;1 with a 38.58% selectivity under visible light irradiation. Our findings highlight the crucial role of atomic&#8208;level coordination in multireactants and offer insights into the C&#9472;N coupling for value&#8208;added products using CO 2 and N 2 as feedstock.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Irfan Ahmad, Xie Quan, Haokun Bai, Yanming Liu, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202512234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study on single metal anchored CrSe2 for efficient electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1003-6326(25)66841-5</link>
      <description>Yadan Sun, Kun Xie, Pei Shi, Zhiyan Feng, Long LIN, Transactions of Nonferrous Metals Society of China. 35(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413844713

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yadan Sun, Kun Xie, Pei Shi, Zhiyan Feng, Long LIN</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1003-6326(25)66841-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT Study of Lattice Dynamics and Phase Transitions of Mg2NA (A = F, Cl, Br, I) Compounds in Antichalcopyrite and Anti-LiFeO2 Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s0022476625080116</link>
      <description>V. S. Timofeev, A. B. Gordienko, Journal of Structural Chemistry. 66(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413845007

                No abstract</description>
      <author>V. S. Timofeev, A. B. Gordienko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s0022476625080116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction on Silver and Silver&#8208;Based Nanostructured Cathodes: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/er/2481690</link>
      <description>&#1054;. &#1030;. &#1050;untyi, Vasyl Skrypnychuk, Galyna Zozulya, International Journal of Energy Research. 2025(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413847492

                During the recent decade, the search for catalytically active cathodes of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) for fuel cells and secondary metal&#8211;air batteries has been one of the priority directions of electrochemical energy applications. Existing highly efficient electrocatalysts based on very expensive and rare platinum (Pt) and Pt group elements need replacement with affordable and scalable electrode materials. In this article, we review the recent trends and progress in the research of ORR catalysts alternative to Pt group elements, namely, silver (Ag)&#8208;based nanostructured cathodes. The following main research directions are presented: (1) the O 2 electroreduction mechanism; (2) nanostructured and nanoporous Ag surfaces; (3) Ag nanoparticles (AgNPs) anchored to a carbon substrate; (4) Ag nanostructures deposited onto M x O y &#8722; carbon nanocomposites; (5) bimetallic Ag&#8211;M nanostructures. The first direction encompasses the analysis of literature data on ORR on Ag surface, which is stable in alkaline electrolytes and provides a four&#8208;electron (4e) pathway for the ORR. In the second direction, we demonstrate the dependence of electroreduction efficiency on the size and shape of AgNPs and their nanoscale porosity. The third direction is based on the enhancement of catalytic activity via designing of fine and ultrafine AgNPs attached to highly porous carbon support nanomaterials such as carbon black, mesoporous carbon (MC), reduced graphene oxide, nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene, multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) and nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes (NCNTs). The fourth direction, hybrid AgNPs&#8211;M x O y /carbon nanocomposites, is one of the most promising for ORR applications. The catalytic activity of these nanocomposites is based on the synergy of the AgNPs&#8211;M x O y couple, and the nanoscale porosity of carbon materials ensures mass transport of dissolved oxygen to the electrode surface. We describe the characteristic features of electrochemical oxygen reduction for the systems of AgNPs with nanoparticles of MnO 2 , ZrO 2 , WO 3 , Fe 3 O 4 and Co 3 O 4 , which can tune Ag surface states. The fifth separate research direction is the use of bimetallic Ag&#8211;M nanostructures for electrocatalytic ORR. The most studied systems are binary, including Ag&#8211;Pd, Ag&#8211;Cu, Ag&#8211;Co and Ag&#8211;Ni. This review outlines the trends and prospects of future development of the Ag&#8208;based nanostructured catalytically active cathodes for oxygen reduction.</description>
      <author>&#1054;. &#1030;. &#1050;untyi, Vasyl Skrypnychuk, Galyna Zozulya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/er/2481690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Materials in Electrocatalysis for Fuel Cell-Based Transportation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-6624-9_14</link>
      <description>Jennifer Laverde, Nataly Carolina Rosero&#8208;Navarro, Energy, environment, and sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413860894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jennifer Laverde, Nataly Carolina Rosero&#8208;Navarro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-6624-9_14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation Mechanisms of Single-Atom Doped Ti2CO2 MXene for CO2 Reduction: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147290</link>
      <description>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413864072

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Coordination Engineering of Fe&#8211;Co Dual-Atom Catalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction Reaction via Synergistic Electronic Modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02229</link>
      <description>H.P. Wang, Ming-Yuan Yu, Huilong Dong, Erjun Kan, Cheng Zhan, Youyong Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413873160

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H.P. Wang, Ming-Yuan Yu, Huilong Dong, Erjun Kan, Cheng Zhan, Youyong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Metal&#8211;Metal Distance on the Performance of Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction: A Density Functional Theory and Micro&#8208;kinetics Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507733</link>
      <description>Yu Mao, Yongfang Zhou, Mengjiao Li, Ziyun Wang, Run Shi, Lu Shang, Tierui Zhang, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413875741

                Abstract Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) display excellent activity for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The dual&#8208;metal configuration allows for synergistic interactions and tailored adsorption of key intermediates, thereby breaking traditional * OH&#8211; * OOH scaling relations and enabling dissociative O 2 activation pathways. Recent studies suggest that the metal&#8211;metal (M&#8211;M) distance within DACs critically influences their electronic structure and catalytic behavior; however, a deep understanding of M&#8211;M distance effects on ORR thermodynamics and kinetics is presently lacking. Herein, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and microkinetic modeling are performed on 108 DACs with varied M&#8211;M distances (2.2&#8211;3.5 &#197;). Moderate M&#8211;M distances (&#8776;3 &#197;) are found to weaken * OH binding, lower the * OH&#8211; * OOH scaling slope, and promote bridging O 2 adsorption for facile dissociation. The dissociative pathway lowered the effective scaling relation from &#8776;3.2 to 2.72 eV, approaching the theoretical value of 2.46 eV. Micro&#8208;kinetic simulations identified O 2 activation as the rate&#8208;determining step during ORR, with DACs possessing a M&#8211;M distance &#8776;3 &#197; exhibiting the highest turnover frequencies, due the effective balancing of active&#8208;site availability and O 2 activation efficiency. These findings highlight the key role of M&#8211;M distance in controlling ORR activity, guiding the design of next&#8208;generation DACs with improved efficiency.</description>
      <author>Yu Mao, Yongfang Zhou, Mengjiao Li, Ziyun Wang, Run Shi, Lu Shang, Tierui Zhang, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Phosphorus Nanosheets as Efficient Ion Navigators at Room Temperature in Polyacrylonitrile&#8208;Based Composite Solid Polymer Electrolyte for Li&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202504995</link>
      <description>Swati Jadhav, Laxman Kaulage, Suparna Saha, Amreen Bano, Satishchandra Ogale, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413877507

                Abstract Solid polymer electrolytes (SPEs) have garnered significant interest lately for all&#8208;solid&#8208;state batteries (ASSBs) because of their easy processability and flexibility; however, their low ionic conductivity has to be enhanced by forming composite polymer electrolyte (CPE). Herein, a polyacrylonitrile (PAN)&#8208;based triple&#8208;composite solid polymer electrolyte with black phosphorus nanosheets (BPN) and SiO 2 nanoparticles (SO) is reported, which synergistically utilizes the efficient directed Li+ pathways (via BP) while reducing PAN crystallization (by SiO 2 ) and enhancing the dissociation of Li salts. Thus, an impressive ionic conductivity of 4.41 &#215; 10 &#8722;4 S cm &#8722;1 is realised in PAN&#8208;BPN&#8208;SO&#8208;LiClO4 CPE, which is 65 times higher than that of PAN&#8208;LiClO 4 (6.8 &#215; 10 &#8722;6 S cm &#8722;1 ). A wider electrochemical stability window (up to 4.68 V vs Li/Li + ) is also realized, enabling compatibility with high&#8208;voltage cathodes. The BPN&#8208;SO CPE exhibited good discharge capacities 146 mAh g &#8722;1 at 0.1C and 108 mAh g &#8722;1 at 1C rate, with 75% capacity retention after 100 cycles. The graphite/LiFePO 4 full&#8208;cell with PAN&#8208;BPN&#8208;SO&#8208;LIClO4 CPE showed a room&#8208;temperature discharge capacity of 87 mAh g &#8722;1 at 0.1 C, which is significantly enhanced to 152 mAh g &#8722;1 at 40 &#176;C. A CPE&#8208;based pouch cell (12 cm 2 , 111.29 mAh g &#8722;1 at 0.1 C) performed well in folding, puncturing, and cutting performance tests. A computational modelling study is performed to elucidate the mechanism.</description>
      <author>Swati Jadhav, Laxman Kaulage, Suparna Saha, Amreen Bano, Satishchandra Ogale</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202504995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support-tuned iridium reconstruction with crystalline phase dominating acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63541-9</link>
      <description>Kexin Zhang, Xiao Liang, Yucheng Wang, Yongcun Zou, Xiao Zhao, Hui Chen, Xiaoxin Zou, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413878568

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kexin Zhang, Xiao Liang, Yucheng Wang, Yongcun Zou, Xiao Zhao, Hui Chen, Xiaoxin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63541-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precisely Bonded Fe&#9472;Cu Diatomic Sites with Nitrogen&#8208;Bridged Coordination on Hollow C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Spheres for Efficient C&#9472;N Coupling and Selective Photocatalytic Urea Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202512234</link>
      <description>Muhammad Irfan Ahmad, Xie Quan, Haokun Bai, Yanming Liu, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413886946

                Abstract The photocatalytic synthesis of urea from CO 2 and N 2 co&#8208;reduction presents a promising alternative to the conventional energy&#8208;intensive Haber&#8211;Bosch process. However, competitive adsorption on the catalyst surface often limits selectivity and yield. Here, we designed hollow graphitic carbon nitride (g&#8208;C 3 N 4 ) spheres, which serve as a high surface area scaffold for precise anchoring of Fe&#9472;Cu diatomic sites. Hollow architecture enhances light harvesting via inner&#8208;scattering effects and charge separation. Each Fe&#9472;Cu site is coordinated with two nitrogen atoms, forming N 2 &#9472;Fe 1 &#9472;Cu 1 &#9472;N 2 /C 3 N 4 DAC (hereafter referred to as FeCu/CN), which enables cooperative activation of CO 2 and N 2 , in contrast to monodispersed diatomic (Fe+Cu/CN), and single&#8208;atom catalysts (Fe/CN, Cu/CN). The FeCu/CN bonded pairs serve as highly efficient active centers, facilitating the synergistic adsorption and activation of multiple reactants. Specifically, during the co&#8208;reduction of CO 2 and N 2 , the Fe 1 site preferentially adsorbs and activates CO 2 , while bonded Cu 1 sites stabilize N 2 on FeCu/CN and enable synergistic C&#9472;N coupling through the formation of *NCON intermediates. As a result, the FeCu/CN achieves an exceptional urea yield of 7.40 mg&#183;g cat &#8722;1 &#183;h &#8722;1 with a 38.58% selectivity under visible light irradiation. Our findings highlight the crucial role of atomic&#8208;level coordination in multireactants and offer insights into the C&#9472;N coupling for value&#8208;added products using CO 2 and N 2 as feedstock.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Irfan Ahmad, Xie Quan, Haokun Bai, Yanming Liu, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202512234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoporous Ti layer encapsulating stainless steel for alkaline water electrolysis: superior electrocatalytic and structural stability under industrially relevant conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5gc02936h</link>
      <description>P. F. Duan, Kai Zhao, Xiaoyi Jiang, Yu&#8208;Chen Liu, Le Ke, Xiude Wang, Longqiao Ran, Xian-Zong Wang, Ning Yan, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413892285

                Nanoporous Ti coating enables high activity and structural stability of 316L stainless steel in the OER under industrially relevant conditions.</description>
      <author>P. F. Duan, Kai Zhao, Xiaoyi Jiang, Yu&#8208;Chen Liu, Le Ke, Xiude Wang, Longqiao Ran, Xian-Zong Wang, Ning Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5gc02936h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of bimetallic single-atom catalysts and theoretical study of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5nj02459e</link>
      <description>Yang Liu, Zhao&#8208;Di Yang, Guiling Zhang, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413894406

                Co x Fe 3&#8722; x SACs efficiently produce HCOOH. DFT shows Co 1 Fe 2 has optimal activity/selectivity at Fe sites, with the lowest *CO 2 &#8594; *OCOH barrier (0.51 eV). Fe incorporation tunes electronic structure, suppresses HER, and enhances intermediate adsorption.</description>
      <author>Yang Liu, Zhao&#8208;Di Yang, Guiling Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5nj02459e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Approach to Carbon Capture Value Chain Development Challenges and Cost-Effective Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/226810-ms</link>
      <description>Lu&#237;s Ferreira Pires, Satyajeet Kawathekar, Peter Dewar, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413897401

                Abstract This paper provides a comprehensive analysis of the carbon capture and storage value chain, focusing on cost optimization strategies and frameworks for successful development. Through systematic evaluation of capture-transport-storage components, we identify critical cost drivers and demonstrate methodologies for economic optimization in early-stage project development. Carbon capture technologies constitute the primary cost component, accounting for 60-80% of total chain (IEA 2024), with post-combustion systems exhibiting energy penalties of 25-35% compared to 15-20% for advanced solvents (Environmental Science &amp; Technology 2024). Transportation costs range from 0.25-55.82 euros per tonne depending on distance and flowrate, while storage costs demonstrate significant variability based on geological conditions and monitoring requirements (MDPI 2024). Cost optimization analysis confirms that cluster and hub models achieve 30-40% cost reductions compared to standalone facilities when maintaining utilization rates above 80% (World Economic Forum 2025). The Northern Lights and Porthos projects early implementation results provide encouraging indicators of successful multi-stakeholder collaboration approaches (Equinor. 2024; Port of Rotterdam. 2024). Digital cost estimation methodologies enable progressive accuracy improvement until final investment decision, supporting systematic project optimization throughout development phases.</description>
      <author>Lu&#237;s Ferreira Pires, Satyajeet Kawathekar, Peter Dewar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/226810-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocluster catalyst driving ampere-level current density in direct seawater electrolysis quantum leap towards sustainable energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.101092</link>
      <description>Vempuluru Navakoteswara Rao, Yeongjun Yoon, Jyoti Prakash Das, Vijayakumar Elumalai, Anandhan Ayyappan Saj, Hanna Lee, Tae Kyu Kim, Kyeounghak Kim, Arunprasath Sathyaseelan, P. Muthukumar, Sang&#8208;Jae Kim, Materials Science and Engineering R Reports. 167(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413898788

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vempuluru Navakoteswara Rao, Yeongjun Yoon, Jyoti Prakash Das, Vijayakumar Elumalai, Anandhan Ayyappan Saj, Hanna Lee, Tae Kyu Kim, Kyeounghak Kim, Arunprasath Sathyaseelan, P. Muthukumar, Sang&#8208;Jae Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.101092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive theoretical study on CuOx/Cu(110) catalyzed water&#8211;gas shift reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116404</link>
      <description>Yu-Bi Huang, Yingqi Wang, Gui&#8208;Chang Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413890083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Bi Huang, Yingqi Wang, Gui&#8208;Chang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of surface point defects on the electronic and optical properties of GeSi bulk materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp02567b</link>
      <description>Hai Wan, Haijuan Zhang, Hsiaotao T. Bi, Li Liu, Wanyu Zhao, Shuqi Wang, Qiang L&#252;, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413884569

                First-principles calculations reveal how surface vacancies, interstitials, and antisite defects reshape the electronic structure and optical response of Ge 0.8 Si 0.2 .</description>
      <author>Hai Wan, Haijuan Zhang, Hsiaotao T. Bi, Li Liu, Wanyu Zhao, Shuqi Wang, Qiang L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp02567b</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
