<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 01:19:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Exact average many-body interatomic interaction model for random alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commt.2024.100018</link>
      <description>Max Hodapp, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403930872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Max Hodapp</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commt.2024.100018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of a CuCo dual-atom catalyst for nitrogen fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra06077f</link>
      <description>Miaomiao Han, Shouxin Zhang, Chenyu Zhang, RSC Advances. 14(47)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403940197

                The potential for N 2 fixation of the heteronuclear CuCo dual-atom catalyst (DAC) was investigated by DFT calculations.</description>
      <author>Miaomiao Han, Shouxin Zhang, Chenyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra06077f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling activity of transition metal single-atom sites on the graphene-like BC2P monolayer for oxygen evolution reaction: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114648</link>
      <description>Xi Fu, Jian Lin, Guangyao Liang, Wenhu Liao, Haixia Gao, Xiaowu Li, Liming Li, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403943389

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xi Fu, Jian Lin, Guangyao Liang, Wenhu Liao, Haixia Gao, Xiaowu Li, Liming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption of Imidazolium&#8208;Based Ionic Liquid On Pt(111) Surface Studied Using Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400458</link>
      <description>Arka Prava Sarkar, Sandeep K. Reddy, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403952421

                Abstract The strength and nature of adsorption of imidazolium&#8208;based tetraflouroborate ionic liquid (IL) on platinum surface has been investigated via first principle&#8208;based density functional theory method. Adsorption of both IL cation and IL ion&#8208;pair as a function of increasing alkyl chain length is taken into consideration. Three different orientations of ionic liquid cations are found to be stable with higher adsorption energy noticed for the alkyl chain parallel to the platinum surface. The anions are found to stabilize the IL cation orientation where the alkyl chain is oriented perpendicular the platinum surface. These results are further corroborated by the charge transfer analysis and electron density difference maps. The significant charge transfer between the ionic liquid pair and the surface indicates electrochemical applications for systems involving electrolytes and metal surface, where electrostatic interactions play a major role. The results of this investigation can be helpful for further analysis of electrode&#8211;electrolyte systems as well as the development of force field parameters for these systems.</description>
      <author>Arka Prava Sarkar, Sandeep K. Reddy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study on two-dimensional direct Z-scheme g-GeC/MoSe2 heterostructure for overall photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113496</link>
      <description>Yuxi Zhang, Peng Wang, Fangfang Li, Yiliang Cai, Computational Materials Science. 246(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403966198

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxi Zhang, Peng Wang, Fangfang Li, Yiliang Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous NiO nanopyramids with superior electrochromic energ-y storage properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.10.460</link>
      <description>Yingdi Shi, Yong Zhang, Yulei Zheng, Kai Tang, Xiang Ke, Zirong Li, Jing Tang, Zhenzhen Hui, Longqiang Ye, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403968719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingdi Shi, Yong Zhang, Yulei Zheng, Kai Tang, Xiang Ke, Zirong Li, Jing Tang, Zhenzhen Hui, Longqiang Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.10.460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-anchoring synthesis of Pt1Ni1@Pt/C core-shell catalysts for stable oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53808-y</link>
      <description>Jialin Cui, Di Zhang, Zhongliang Liu, Congcong Li, Tingting Zhang, Shixin Yin, Yiting Song, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Chunzhong Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403969270

                Proton-exchange-membrane fuel cells demand highly efficient catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction, and core-shell structures are known for maximizing precious metal utilization. Here, we reported a controllable "carbon defect anchoring" strategy to prepare Pt</description>
      <author>Jialin Cui, Di Zhang, Zhongliang Liu, Congcong Li, Tingting Zhang, Shixin Yin, Yiting Song, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53808-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambient-condition acetylene hydrogenation to ethylene over WS2-confined atomic Pd sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53481-1</link>
      <description>Wangwang Zhang, Kelechi Uwakwe, Jingting Hu, Wei Yan, Juntong Zhu, Wu Zhou, Chao Ma, Liang Yu, Rui Huang, Dehui Deng, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403969537

                Ambient-condition acetylene hydrogenation to ethylene (AC-AHE) is a promising process for ethylene production with minimal additional energy input, yet remains a great challenge due to the difficulty in the coactivation of acetylene and H</description>
      <author>Wangwang Zhang, Kelechi Uwakwe, Jingting Hu, Wei Yan, Juntong Zhu, Wu Zhou, Chao Ma, Liang Yu, Rui Huang, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53481-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of strain, pH and oxygen-deficient on catalytic performance of Ruddlesden-Popper oxide Srn+1RunO3n+1 (n=1, 2) for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.405</link>
      <description>Jiahao Zhang, Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403971281

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahao Zhang, Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution enabled by porous Eu-Ni(PO3)2 nanosheet arrays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.11.001</link>
      <description>Pu Wang, Xiangrui Wu, Meng Li, Xuan Wang, Huiyu Wang, Qiuzi Huang, Hao Li, Yawen Tang, Gengtao Fu, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403978086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pu Wang, Xiangrui Wu, Meng Li, Xuan Wang, Huiyu Wang, Qiuzi Huang, Hao Li, Yawen Tang, Gengtao Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.11.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution in proton exchange membrane electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24062-1.00002-4</link>
      <description>Williane da Silva Freitas, Barbara Mecheri, Alessandra D&#8217;Epifanio, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403978627

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Williane da Silva Freitas, Barbara Mecheri, Alessandra D&#8217;Epifanio</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24062-1.00002-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pH-Mediated Solution-Phase Proton Transfer Drives Enhanced Electrochemical Hydrogenation of Phenol in Alkaline Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04874</link>
      <description>Brianna Markunas, Taber Yim, Joshua Snyder, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403979659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brianna Markunas, Taber Yim, Joshua Snyder</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overlooked Role of Electrostatic Interactions in HER Kinetics on MXenes: Beyond the Conventional Descriptor &#916;&lt;i&gt;G&lt;/i&gt; &#8764; 0 to Identify the Real Active Site</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02588</link>
      <description>Xiang Huang, Xiangting Hu, Jiong Wang, Hu Xu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403980675

                Understanding the atomic-level mechanism of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) on MXene materials is crucial for developing affordable HER catalysts, while their complex surface terminations present a substantial challenge. Herein, employing constant-potential grand canonical density functional theory calculations, we elucidate the reaction kinetics of the HER on MXenes with various surface terminations by taking experimentally reported Mo</description>
      <author>Xiang Huang, Xiangting Hu, Jiong Wang, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating nonmetal atom doping in two-dimensional VSe2 monolayers for hydrogen and oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232667</link>
      <description>Rabia Hassan, Fei Ma, Yan Li, Rehan Hassan, Muhammad Farhan Qadir, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403981233

                The electrocatalytic performance of VSe2 doped with nonmetals (NMs) was studied using density functional theory, in which NM atoms (C, N, O, P, S, F, Cl, Br, and I) replaced Se or V (denoted as NM@Se or NM@V). Notably, P@V and Br@V monolayers exhibit high catalytic hydrogen evolution reaction activity with the lowest &#916;GH* = 0.08 eV and &#8722;0.03 eV, respectively, surpassing Pt (&#916;GH* = &#8722;0.1 eV). By applying the scaling relationship of &#916;GH* of H*, which is an intermediate for each volcano, the exchange current density diagrams are established. Based on thermodynamic analysis, P@V and Br@V monolayers produce exchange currents of about &#8722;1.42 and &#8722;0.70i0/(A cm&#8722;2), respectively. The oxygen evolution reaction activity of the I@Se monolayer (&#951;OER = 0.95 V) is the best among all the monolayers. Among the oxygen reduction reaction catalysts, the O@Se monolayer displays high activity with a low &#951;ORR (0.82 V), which is even better than that of binary Pt and Pd alloys (0.9&#8211;0.87 V).</description>
      <author>Rabia Hassan, Fei Ma, Yan Li, Rehan Hassan, Muhammad Farhan Qadir</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced N-doping nickel-cobalt phosphides for boosting hydrogen evolution in acid and alkali media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.364</link>
      <description>Kai Liu, Zizai Ma, Zihao Wan, Xiaoguang Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Liu, Zizai Ma, Zihao Wan, Xiaoguang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combining graph deep learning and London dispersion interatomic potentials: A case study on pnictogen chalcohalides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237101</link>
      <description>&#199;etin K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, S&#252;meyra G&#252;ler-K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984284

                Machine-learning interatomic potential models based on graph neural network architectures have the potential to make atomistic materials modeling widely accessible due to their computational efficiency, scalability, and broad applicability. The training datasets for many such models are derived from density-functional theory calculations, typically using a semilocal exchange-correlation functional. As a result, long-range interactions such as London dispersion are often missing in these models. We investigate whether this missing component can be addressed by combining a graph deep learning potential with semiempirical dispersion models. We assess this combination by deriving the equations of state for layered pnictogen chalcohalides BiTeBr and BiTeI and performing crystal structure optimizations for a broader set of V&#8211;VI&#8211;VII compounds with various stoichiometries, many of which possess van der Waals gaps. We characterize the optimized crystal structures by calculating their x-ray diffraction patterns and radial distribution function histograms, which are also used to compute Earth mover&#8217;s distances to quantify the dissimilarity between the optimized and corresponding experimental structures. We find that dispersion-corrected graph deep learning potentials generally (though not universally) provide a more realistic description of these compounds due to the inclusion of van der Waals attractions. In particular, their use results in systematic improvements in predicting not only the van der Waals gap but also the layer thickness in layered V&#8211;VI&#8211;VII compounds. Our results demonstrate that the combined potentials studied here, derived from a straightforward approach that neither requires fine-tuning the training nor refitting the potential parameters, can significantly improve the description of layered polar crystals.</description>
      <author>&#199;etin K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, S&#252;meyra G&#252;ler-K&#305;l&#305;&#231;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-driven sewage sludge electroreforming coupled with biological funnelling to cogenerate green food and hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44221-024-00329-z</link>
      <description>Hu Zhao, Ziying Sun, Chenchen Li, Dan Wu, Li Quan Lee, Dan Lu, Yuanda Lv, Xi Jie Chu, Ying Li, Wenguang Tu, Ovi Lian Ding, Jin Zhou, Zhigang Zou, Yan Zhou, Hong Li, Nature Water. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hu Zhao, Ziying Sun, Chenchen Li, Dan Wu, Li Quan Lee, Dan Lu, Yuanda Lv, Xi Jie Chu, Ying Li, Wenguang Tu, Ovi Lian Ding, Jin Zhou, Zhigang Zou, Yan Zhou, Hong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44221-024-00329-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Activity Trends in Electrochemical Dinitrogen Oxidation over Transition Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05036</link>
      <description>Samuel Olusegun, Yancun Qi, Nishithan C. Kani, Meenesh R. Singh, Joseph A. Gauthier, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403985663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samuel Olusegun, Yancun Qi, Nishithan C. Kani, Meenesh R. Singh, Joseph A. Gauthier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Active Sites on Pd/Pt Alloy Nanoparticles by CO Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c08291</link>
      <description>Daniel Silvan Dolling, Jiachen Chen, Jan&#8208;Christian Schober, Marcus Creutzburg, Arno Jeromin, Vedran Vonk, Dmitry Sharapa, Thomas F. Keller, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Heshmat Noei, Andreas Stierle, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403996395

                We studied the adsorption of CO on Pd/Pt nanoparticles (NPs) with varying compositions using polarization-dependent Fourier transform infrared reflection absorption spectroscopy (FT-IRRAS) and theoretical calculations (DFT). We prepared PtPd alloy NPs via physical vapor codeposition on &#945;-Al</description>
      <author>Daniel Silvan Dolling, Jiachen Chen, Jan&#8208;Christian Schober, Marcus Creutzburg, Arno Jeromin, Vedran Vonk, Dmitry Sharapa, Thomas F. Keller, Philipp N. Ple&#223;ow, Heshmat Noei, Andreas Stierle</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c08291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised representation learning of Kohn&#8211;Sham states and consequences for downstream predictions of many-body effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53748-7</link>
      <description>Bowen Hou, Jinyuan Wu, Diana Y. Qiu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403996728

                Representation learning for the electronic structure problem is a major challenge of machine learning in computational condensed matter and materials physics. Within quantum mechanical first principles approaches, density functional theory (DFT) is the preeminent tool for understanding electronic structure, and the high-dimensional DFT wavefunctions serve as building blocks for downstream calculations of correlated many-body excitations and related physical observables. Here, we use variational autoencoders (VAE) for the unsupervised learning of DFT wavefunctions and show that these wavefunctions lie in a low-dimensional manifold within latent space. Our model autonomously determines the optimal representation of the electronic structure, avoiding limitations due to manual feature engineering. To demonstrate the utility of the latent space representation of the DFT wavefunction, we use it for the supervised training of neural networks (NN) for downstream prediction of quasiparticle bandstructures within the GW formalism. The GW prediction achieves a low error of 0.11 eV for a combined test set of two-dimensional metals and semiconductors, suggesting that the latent space representation captures key physical information from the original data. Finally, we explore the generative ability and interpretability of the VAE representation.</description>
      <author>Bowen Hou, Jinyuan Wu, Diana Y. Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53748-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable photocatalytic hydrogen peroxide production over octonary high-entropy oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53896-w</link>
      <description>Hao Ling, Huacong Sun, Lisha Lu, Jingkun Zhang, Lei Liao, Jianlin Wang, Xiaowei Zhang, Yingying Lan, Renjie Li, Wengang Lu, Lejuan Cai, Xuedong Bai, Wenlong Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404010700

                The direct utilization of solar energy for the artificial photosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) provides a reliable approach for producing this high-value green oxidant. Here we report on the utility of high-entropy oxide (HEO) semiconductor as an all-in-one photocatalyst for visible light-driven H2O2 production directly from H2O and atmospheric O2 without the need of any additional cocatalysts or sacrificial agents. This high-entropy photocatalyst contains eight earth-abundant metal elements (Ti/V/Cr/Nb/Mo/W/Al/Cu) homogeneously arranged within a single rutile phase, and the intrinsic chemical complexity along with the presence of a high density of oxygen vacancies endow high-entropy photocatalyst with distinct broadband light harvesting capability. An efficient H2O2 production rate with an apparent quantum yield of 38.8% at 550 nm can be achieved. The high-entropy photocatalyst can be readily assembled into floating artificial leaves for sustained on-site production of H2O2 from open water resources under natural sunlight irradiation. An "all-in-one" high-entropy semiconductor photocatalyst enables the photocatalytic production of H2O2 from H2O and O2 under visible light without any external cocatalysts or sacrificial agents</description>
      <author>Hao Ling, Huacong Sun, Lisha Lu, Jingkun Zhang, Lei Liao, Jianlin Wang, Xiaowei Zhang, Yingying Lan, Renjie Li, Wengang Lu, Lejuan Cai, Xuedong Bai, Wenlong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53896-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Study of Cl Adsorption on Pt(111) and Pt(100) using Ab Initio Grand-Canonical Monte Carlo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122647</link>
      <description>Eun Mi Kim, Junseok Kim, Kristen A. Fichthorn, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404011693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eun Mi Kim, Junseok Kim, Kristen A. Fichthorn</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122647</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing Key Process Design Considerations for Carbon Capture, Utilization and Storage (CCUS) Towards Decarbonization of Existing Assets Operations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/221884-ms</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zakwan Mohd Sahak, Masniroszaime Md Zain, Azila Alias, Muhammad Yazid Bin Zulkifli, Sohrab Rohani, Khairul Rostani, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404014042

                Abstract With the net zero emission (NZE) commitment by 2050 following COP26 being pledged by country and industrial leaders, the technology focus for CCUS has shifted from high-CO2 gas field development to also include capturing CO2 from other industrial emission sources e.g. flaring and gas turbines. With the expanding scopes, careful consideration especially from process design perspective needs to be taken to ensure the overall CCUS conceptual design is techno-commercially feasible and viable to meet the CCUS end target and NZE aspiration in the long term. Process design intent shall start with the input-output specifications, where main input specifications would be looking at source or CCUS fluid (e.g. gas field/flare stack etc.) which will determine the type of CO2 capture technology required. Target output usage (storage/ utilization) will affect the tail-end process design, since both require different process setup. Other considerations would also be: (1) location (onshore vs offshore) which will affect the facilities network and logistics, (2) contaminants such as SOx and NOx which will determine other treatment requirements and affect the final use of the separated CO2-rich stream (utilization, storage strategy), and (3) material selection for the mixed contaminants stream. Depending on the concentration of CO2 in the source, a series of treatment steps may be required to get the optimum recovery for further utilization and storage. The presence of other contaminants is also discussed, which may affect the overall CCUS processes. Method to either utilize the separated CO2 stream or injection to reservoir for storage is also explored. An integrated approach is required to ensure a successful CCUS process design from start to end. Challenges and lesson-learnt from a conceptual CCUS system are analyzed including technology maturation, presence of other contaminants and final use of CO2-based products/storage. The technical and commercial aspects associated with each technology are also addressed. Key design elements are proposed with aspiration of a successful CCUS implementation in reducing future carbon footprint and realizing NZE aspiration and decarbonization goal, requiring planning for end-to-end solutions.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zakwan Mohd Sahak, Masniroszaime Md Zain, Azila Alias, Muhammad Yazid Bin Zulkifli, Sohrab Rohani, Khairul Rostani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/221884-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Margaret: Streamlining Research Productivity Analysis in Colombia with an R Package for GrupLAC Integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29173/istl2777</link>
      <description>Sebasti&#225;n Robledo, Bryan Arias, C Garc&#237;a, Ingrid Durley Torres, Martha Zuluaga, Issues in Science and Technology Librarianship. None(108)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404027754

                Margaret is an advanced R package designed to systematically extract and consolidate data pertaining to research outputs (such as publications, books, book chapters, and conference presentations) of scientific groups from the GrupLAC platform, an online application managed by Minciencias in Colombia for the registration and updating of researcher and research group information in the fields of science, technology, and innovation. The challenge of monitoring and evaluating scientific production across various web platforms presents a substantial barrier to universities in tracking their contributions effectively. To address this challenge, Margaret accepts a designated list of links corresponding to university-affiliated research groups within GrupLAC. Utilizing web-scraping techniques, the package retrieves and compiles this data into a comprehensive XLSX file. This file encompasses information across 51 distinct categories of research products, enabling research directors to meticulously assess, monitor, and enhance various strategies that aim to augment the production, quality, and impact of scientific outputs. The Shiny application is publicly accessible and can be accessed via the following link: https://ucatolicaluisamigo-investigaciones.shinyapps.io/margaret/</description>
      <author>Sebasti&#225;n Robledo, Bryan Arias, C Garc&#237;a, Ingrid Durley Torres, Martha Zuluaga</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29173/istl2777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nucleotide coordinated polymers, a ROS-based immunomodulatory antimicrobial, doubly kill Pseudomonas aeruginosa biofilms of implant infections</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioactmat.2024.10.026</link>
      <description>Jinghuang Chen, XiaoChen Tang, Qihan Sun, Xin Ji, Xingbo Wang, Zhendong Liu, Xu Dong Zhang, Hai-Jiao Xu, Fan Yang, Jian Sun, Xiurong Yang, Bioactive Materials. 44(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404028972

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinghuang Chen, XiaoChen Tang, Qihan Sun, Xin Ji, Xingbo Wang, Zhendong Liu, Xu Dong Zhang, Hai-Jiao Xu, Fan Yang, Jian Sun, Xiurong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioactmat.2024.10.026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Point-defect-induced electronic polarization to enhance H* generation for removal of bisphenol A</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.121814</link>
      <description>Huajing Zhou, T.J. Li, F M Zhang, Faze Chen, Zilian Liu, Rongrong Miao, Qingqing Guan, Lingxiang Zhao, Liang He, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404029498

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huajing Zhou, T.J. Li, F M Zhang, Faze Chen, Zilian Liu, Rongrong Miao, Qingqing Guan, Lingxiang Zhao, Liang He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.121814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment regulation to synthesize sub-3 nm Pt-based high-entropy alloy nanoparticles enabling compressed lattice to boost electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124775</link>
      <description>Zhiyin Huang, Yuqin Peng, Lixin Xing, M. Xu, Meng Fang, Huiqi Xie, Jiamin Li, Yangdong Zhou, Puwei Wu, Ning Wang, Chunmei Tang, Mingjie Wu, Liguang Wang, Siyu Ye, Lei Du, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404032861

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyin Huang, Yuqin Peng, Lixin Xing, M. Xu, Meng Fang, Huiqi Xie, Jiamin Li, Yangdong Zhou, Puwei Wu, Ning Wang, Chunmei Tang, Mingjie Wu, Liguang Wang, Siyu Ye, Lei Du</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Accurate and Robust Constraint-Based Orbital-Optimized Core Excitations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c04139</link>
      <description>Yannick Lemke, J&#246;rg Ku&#223;mann, Christian Ochsenfeld, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404033915

                We adapt our recently developed constraint-based orbital-optimized excited-state method (COOX) for the computation of core excitations. COOX is a constrained density functional theory (cDFT) approach based on excitation amplitudes from linear-response time-dependent DFT (LR-TDDFT), and has been shown to provide accurate excitation energies and excited-state properties for valence excitations within a spin-restricted formalism. To extend COOX to core-excited states, we introduce a spin-unrestricted variant which allows us to obtain orbital-optimized core excitations with a single constraint. Using a triplet purification scheme in combination with the constrained unrestricted Hartree&#8211;Fock formalism, scalar-relativistic zero-order regular approximation corrections, and a semiempirical treatment of spin&#8211;orbit coupling, COOX is shown to produce highly accurate results for K- and L-edge excitations of second- and third-period atoms with subelectronvolt errors despite being based on LR-TDDFT, for which core excitations pose a well-known challenge. L- and M-edge excitations of heavier atoms up to uranium are also computationally feasible and numerically stable, but may require more advanced treatment of relativistic effects. Furthermore, COOX is shown to perform on par with or better than the popular &#916;SCF approach while exhibiting more robust convergence, highlighting it as a promising tool for inexpensive and accurate simulations of X-ray absorption spectra.</description>
      <author>Yannick Lemke, J&#246;rg Ku&#223;mann, Christian Ochsenfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c04139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment Control over Electrocatalytic Activity of g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/2H-MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Superlattice-like Heterostructures for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03492</link>
      <description>Xiaorong Gan, Liqun Ye, Huimin Zhao, Dangyuan Lei, Yanhui Ao, Dan Zhao, Peifang Wang, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404043326

                Microenvironments in heterogeneous catalysis have been recognized as equally important as the types and amounts of active sites for regulating catalytic activity. Two-dimensional (2D) nanospaces between van der Waals (vdW) gaps of layered materials provide an ideal microenvironment to create novel functionalities. Here, we explore a facile method for fabricating g-C3N4/2H-MoS2 superlattice-like heterostructures based on thermochemical intercalation and polymerization reactions of formamide within enlarged vdW gaps of 2H-MoS2 nanosheets without any transfer process. DFT calculations demonstrate that the interlayer electron&#8211;electron correlations due to the intercalation effect of g-C3N4, rather than high-&#954; dielectric environments, lead to the improvement of intrinsic conductivity of 2H-MoS2 nanosheets. As the proof of concept in applications for the electrocatalysis field, the heterostructure for hydrogen electrochemical reaction (HER) exhibits high stability and catalytic activity in both acid and alkaline media, such as a quite low onset overpotential of 98 mV, a high exchange current density of 77.6 &#956;A cm&#8211;2, and a small Tafel slope (52.9 mV dec&#8211;1) in an acid medium. The enhanced HER activity is attributed to the improved conductivity and nanoconfinement effect of 2D nanospaces that decrease the reaction activation energy and activate the inert basal planes.</description>
      <author>Xiaorong Gan, Liqun Ye, Huimin Zhao, Dangyuan Lei, Yanhui Ao, Dan Zhao, Peifang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Storage in Different Geological Conditions Based on Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04274</link>
      <description>Ming Liu, Zhen Li, Qi Jing, Ying Meng, Jixian Zhou, Mingcheng Ni, Xianmin Zhou, Hao Chen, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404048617

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming Liu, Zhen Li, Qi Jing, Ying Meng, Jixian Zhou, Mingcheng Ni, Xianmin Zhou, Hao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Holey Graphyne-Supported Single Atom Catalyst for Nitrogen Reduction Reaction by Interpretable Machine Learning and First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105401</link>
      <description>Dian Zheng, Fei Deng, Jing Xu, Wei Liu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404060333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dian Zheng, Fei Deng, Jing Xu, Wei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic catalysis meets heterostructure synergy: Unveiling the trifunctional efficacy of transition Metal@WS2/ReSe2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.377</link>
      <description>Xudong Hu, Jingyi Shang, Shuang Li, Jun Long, Shi&#8208;Bo Cheng, Saad Ahmed, Sheng Wang, Usman Farooq, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404060959

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xudong Hu, Jingyi Shang, Shuang Li, Jun Long, Shi&#8208;Bo Cheng, Saad Ahmed, Sheng Wang, Usman Farooq</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-valence Co deposition based on selfcatalysis of lattice Mn doping for robust acid water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.043</link>
      <description>Ning Yu, Fuli Wang, Xinying Jiang, Jin&#8208;Long Tan, Mirabbos Hojamberdiev, Han Hu, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061006

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Yu, Fuli Wang, Xinying Jiang, Jin&#8208;Long Tan, Mirabbos Hojamberdiev, Han Hu, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-doped porous graphite with multilevel pore defects and ultra-high conductivity anchoring Pt nanoparticles for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.041</link>
      <description>Yu Hao, Dongfang Chen, Guangxin Yang, Song Hu, Shunyu Wang, Pucheng Pei, Jinkai Hao, Xiaoming Xu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Hao, Dongfang Chen, Guangxin Yang, Song Hu, Shunyu Wang, Pucheng Pei, Jinkai Hao, Xiaoming Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bond-Based Machine Learning Model for Molecular Polarizabilities and A Priori Raman Spectra</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01086</link>
      <description>Jakub K. Sowa, Peter J. Rossky, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061157

                The use of machine learning (ML) algorithms in molecular simulations has become commonplace in recent years. There now exists, for instance, a multitude of ML force field algorithms that have enabled simulations approaching ab initio level accuracy at time scales and system sizes that significantly exceed what is otherwise possible with traditional methods. Far fewer algorithms exist for predicting rotationally equivariant, tensorial properties such as the electric polarizability. Here, we introduce a kernel ridge regression algorithm for machine learning of the polarizability tensor. This algorithm is based on the bond polarizability model and allows prediction of the tensor components at the cost similar to that of scalar quantities. We subsequently show the utility of this algorithm by simulating gas phase Raman spectra of biphenyl and malonaldehyde using classical molecular dynamics simulations of these systems performed with the recently developed MACE-OFF23 potential. The calculated spectra are shown to agree very well with the experiments and thus confirm the expediency of our algorithm as well as the accuracy of the used force field. More generally, this work demonstrates the potential of physics-informed approaches to yield simple yet effective machine learning algorithms for molecular properties.</description>
      <author>Jakub K. Sowa, Peter J. Rossky</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covariant Jacobi-Legendre expansion for total energy calculations within the projector augmented wave formalism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.184106</link>
      <description>Bruno Focassio, Michelangelo Domina, Urvesh Patil, A. Fazzio, Stefano Sanvito, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061393

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bruno Focassio, Michelangelo Domina, Urvesh Patil, A. Fazzio, Stefano Sanvito</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.184106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Potential of Machine Learning to Optimize the Activity of Cu-Based Dual Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01208</link>
      <description>A. Das, Diptendu Roy, Souvik Manna, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Das, Diptendu Roy, Souvik Manna, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Guideline for Cross-Sector Coupling of Carbon Capture Technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/gases4040021</link>
      <description>Hossein Asgharian, Ali Yahyaee, Chungen Yin, Vincenzo Liso, Mads Pagh Nielsen, Florin Iov, Gases. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404062213

                Many governments around the world have taken action to utilise carbon capture (CC) technologies to reduce CO2 emissions. This technology is particularly important to reduce unavoidable emissions from industries like cement plants, oil refineries, etc. The available literature in the public domain explores this theme from two distinct perspectives. The first category of papers focuses only on modelling the CC plants by investigating the details of the processes to separate CO2 from other gas components without considering the industrial applications and synergies between sectors. On the other hand, the second category investigates the required infrastructure that must be put in place to allow a suitable integration without considering the specific particularities of each carbon capture technology. This review gives a comprehensive guideline for the implementation of CC technologies for any given application while also considering the coupling between different energy sectors such as heating, power generation, etc. It also identifies the research gaps within this field, based on the existing literature. Moreover, it delves into various aspects and characteristics of these technologies, while comparing their energy penalties with the minimum work required for CO2 separation. Additionally, this review investigates the main industrial sectors with CC potential, the necessary transportation infrastructure from the point sources to the end users, and the needs and characteristics of storage facilities, as well as the utilisation of CO2 as a feedstock. Finally, an overview of the computation tools for CC processes and guidelines for their utilisation is given. The guidelines presented in this paper are the first attempt to provide a comprehensive overview of the technologies, and their requirements, needed to achieve the cross-sector coupling of CC plants for a wide range of applications. It is strongly believed that these guidelines will benefit all stakeholders in the value chain while enabling an accelerated deployment of these technologies.</description>
      <author>Hossein Asgharian, Ali Yahyaee, Chungen Yin, Vincenzo Liso, Mads Pagh Nielsen, Florin Iov</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/gases4040021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface&#8208;Interface Engineering of Electrocatalysts for Two&#8208;Electron Water Oxidation Reaction to Produce H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413243</link>
      <description>Zhen Chen, Xi Liu, Sheng Wang, Lin Yang, Sheng Wang, Wei Wang, Shuqin Song, Zhongwei Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404068129

                Abstract Electrochemical two&#8208;electron water oxidation reaction (2e &#8722; WOR) driven by renewable energy offers an attractive route to produce H 2 O 2 , while the corresponding electrocatalyst still requires further improvement for the activity, selectivity, and the resulting H 2 O 2 yield. Surface&#8208;interface engineering of electrocatalysts has great potential to advance 2e &#8722; WOR performance. This review provides a succinct yet comprehensive insight into the functional mechanisms of surface&#8208;interfacial properties affecting 2e &#8722; WOR performance on electrocatalyst. The Gibbs free energy theoretical framework related to surface electronic structure and interfacial reactive kinetics mechanism related to electrolyte, electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface structure, and interfacial microenvironment properties are firstly discussed. Afterward, various surface&#8208;interface engineering strategies toward high performance electrocatalysts including the regulation of surface electronic structure, the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface structure, and the interfacial microenvironment have been overviewed. Rational manipulations of the above surface&#8208;interfacial engineering strategies are critical to design highly efficient 2e &#8722; WOR electrocatalysts, leading to the development of the green H 2 O 2 production.</description>
      <author>Zhen Chen, Xi Liu, Sheng Wang, Lin Yang, Sheng Wang, Wei Wang, Shuqin Song, Zhongwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction of Single-Twinned AgPdIr Nanoalloy during the Formate Oxidation and Dehydrogenation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03637</link>
      <description>Quan Tang, Longfei Guo, Tao Jin, Shuang Shan, Qiao Wang, Junpeng Wang, Bowei Pan, Zhen Li, Fuyi Chen, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404071955

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Quan Tang, Longfei Guo, Tao Jin, Shuang Shan, Qiao Wang, Junpeng Wang, Bowei Pan, Zhen Li, Fuyi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodegradation of nitrogenous pollutants in sewage: from reaction fundamentals to energy valorization applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00517a</link>
      <description>Minglei Sun, Li Wang, Yi Feng, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Sheng Wang, Zhong&#8208;Yong Yuan, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404078300

                This review provides a comprehensive insight into the electrodegradation processes of nitrogenous pollutants in sewage, highlighting the reaction mechanisms, theoretical descriptors, catalyst design, and energy valorization strategies.</description>
      <author>Minglei Sun, Li Wang, Yi Feng, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Sheng Wang, Zhong&#8208;Yong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00517a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Atomic Ordering Uniformity Enables Selectively Leached Nanoporous Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P Metallic Glass for Enhanced Glucose Sensing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408816</link>
      <description>Yu Lou, J. B. Li, Zhongzheng Yao, Zhenduo Wu, Huiqiang Ying, Lan Tan, Liu Si-nan, Jianrong Zeng, Ruohan Yu, Hong Liu, Xun&#8208;Li Wang, He Zhu, Si Lan, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404078877

                Abstract Constructing nanostructures, such as nanopores, within metallic glasses (MGs) holds great promise for further unlocking their electrochemical capabilities. However, the MGs typically exhibit intrinsic atomic&#8208;scale isotropy, posing a significant challenge in directly fabricating anisotropic nanostructures using conventional chemical synthesis. Herein a selective leaching approach, which focuses on tailoring the uniformity of atomic ordering, is introduced to achieve pore&#8208;engineered Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P MG. This innovative approach significantly boosts the number of exposed active sites, thereby enhancing the electrochemical sensitivity for glucose detection. Electrochemical tests reveal that the nanoporous Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P MG exhibits high sensitivity (3.19 mA m m &#8315;&#185; cm&#8315; 2 ) and remarkable stability (97.7% current retention after 1000 cycles). During electrochemical cycling, synchrotron X&#8208;ray pair distribution function and X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure analyses reveal that the distance between active sites decreases, enhancing electron transport efficiency, while the medium&#8208;range ordered structure of the Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P MG remains stable, contributing to its exceptional glucose sensing capabilities. A microglucose sensor is successfully developed by integrating the nanoporous Pd&#8208;Ni&#8208;P MG with a screen&#8208;printed electrode, demonstrating the practical applicability. This study not only offers a new avenue for the design of highly active nanoporous MGs but also sheds light on the mechanisms behind the high electrochemistry performance of MGs.</description>
      <author>Yu Lou, J. B. Li, Zhongzheng Yao, Zhenduo Wu, Huiqiang Ying, Lan Tan, Liu Si-nan, Jianrong Zeng, Ruohan Yu, Hong Liu, Xun&#8208;Li Wang, He Zhu, Si Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the Pt/ionomer/water interface on the oxygen reduction reaction: insights into the micro-three-phase interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06600f</link>
      <description>Shangkun Jiang, Qiong Xiang, Zhi-Yan Xie, Na Yang, Jiawei Liu, Li Li, Zidong Wei, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404079241

                Understanding the Pt/ionomer/water interface structure and its impact on the oxygen reduction reaction activity is essential for enhancing catalyst utilization and performance of fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Shangkun Jiang, Qiong Xiang, Zhi-Yan Xie, Na Yang, Jiawei Liu, Li Li, Zidong Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06600f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Establishment and Screening of Double-Atom Catalysts Supported on Biphenylene for an Efficient Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02582</link>
      <description>K. Raghu Raja Pandiyan, Dinesh Kumar Dhanthala Chittibabu, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404080387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Raghu Raja Pandiyan, Dinesh Kumar Dhanthala Chittibabu, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of graph neural network in computational heterogeneous catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0227821</link>
      <description>Zihao Jiao, Ya Liu, Ziyun Wang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984381

                Heterogeneous catalysis, as a key technology in modern chemical industries, plays a vital role in social progress and economic development. However, its complex reaction process poses challenges to theoretical research. Graph neural networks (GNNs) are gradually becoming a key tool in this field as they can intrinsically learn atomic representation and consider connection relationship, making them naturally applicable to atomic and molecular systems. This article introduces the basic principles, current network architectures, and datasets of GNNs and reviews the application of GNN in heterogeneous catalysis from accelerating the materials screening and exploring the potential energy surface. In the end, we summarize the main challenges and potential application prospects of GNNs in future research endeavors.</description>
      <author>Zihao Jiao, Ya Liu, Ziyun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0227821</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
