<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 01:11:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effect Enables the Dual-Metal Doped Cobalt Telluride Particles as Potential Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution in Alkaline Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00921</link>
      <description>Xuyang Jing, Jinyuan Dong, Yi Mao, Lingyan Zhou, Jiabao Ding, Huilong Dong, Linjuan Zhang, Y. Zhang, Weifeng Zhang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400182573

                Cobalt (Co)-based materials have been widely investigated as hopeful noble-metal-free alternatives for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline electrolytes, which is crucial for generating hydrogen by water electrolysis. Herein, cobalt-based telluride particles with good electronic conductivity as anodic electrocatalysts were prepared under vacuum by the solid-state strategy, which display remarkable activities toward the OER. Nickel (Ni) and iron (Fe) codoped cobalt telluride (NiFe-CoTe) exhibits an overpotential of 321 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Xuyang Jing, Jinyuan Dong, Yi Mao, Lingyan Zhou, Jiabao Ding, Huilong Dong, Linjuan Zhang, Y. Zhang, Weifeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00921</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the role of electrode potential micro-environments in single Mn atoms for carbon dioxide and oxygen electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6799-7</link>
      <description>Pengcheng Liu, Yanyi Liu, Kaili Wang, Shuai Shi, Mengmeng Jin, Jingxiu Liu, Tina Qin, Qian Liu, Xijun Liu, Jia He, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400187321

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengcheng Liu, Yanyi Liu, Kaili Wang, Shuai Shi, Mengmeng Jin, Jingxiu Liu, Tina Qin, Qian Liu, Xijun Liu, Jia He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6799-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the Second-Shell Coordination Environment on the Performance of P-Block Metal Single-Atom Catalysts for the Electrosynthesis of Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070421</link>
      <description>Yidi Wu, Yuxiang Zhang, Sen Lin, Catalysts. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400197520

                Hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) is an important chemical with a diverse range of industrial applications in chemical synthesis and medical disinfection. The traditional anthraquinone oxidation process, with high energy consumption and complexity, is being replaced by cost-effective and environmentally friendly alternatives. In order to explore suitable catalysts for the electrocatalytic synthesis of H2O2, the stability of B,N-doped graphene loaded with various p-block metal (PM) single atoms (i.e., PM-NxBy: x and y represent the number of atoms of N and B, respectively) and the effects of different numbers and positions of B dopants in the second coordination shell on the catalytic performance were studied by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The results show that Ga-N4B6 and Sb-N4B6 exhibit enhanced stability and 2e&#8722; oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity and selectivity. Their thermodynamic overpotential &#951; values are 0.01 V, 0.03 V for Ga-N4B6&#8217;s two configurations and 0.02 V, 0 V for Sb-N4B6&#8217;s two configurations. Electronic structure calculations indicate that the PM single atom adsorbs OOH* intermediates and transfers electrons into them, resulting in the activation of the O-O bond, which facilitates the subsequent hydrogenation reaction. In summary, Sb-N4B6 and Ga-N4B6 exhibit extraordinary 2e&#8722; ORR performance, and their predicted activities are comparable to those of known outstanding catalysts (such as PtHg4 alloy). We propose effective strategies on how to enhance the 2e&#8722; ORR activities of carbon materials, elucidate the origin of the activity of potential catalysts, and provide insights for the design and development of electrocatalysts that can be used for H2O2 production.</description>
      <author>Yidi Wu, Yuxiang Zhang, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the &#8727;O vs. &#8727;OH scaling relation intercept more relevant than the &#8727;OOH vs. &#8727;OH intercept to capture trends in the oxygen evolution reaction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101039</link>
      <description>Maksim Sokolov, Kai S. Exner, Chem catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400198183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maksim Sokolov, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetal Oxides Anchored on Carbon Nanotubes/Nanosheets as High&#8208;Efficiency and Durable Bifunctional Oxygen Catalyst for Advanced Zn&#8211;Air Battery: Experiments and DFT Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402104</link>
      <description>Qi&#8208;Dong Ruan, Yuehong Zhao, Rui Feng, Muhammad Zia Ul Haq, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400201233

                To meet increasing requirement for innovative energy storage and conversion technology, it is urgent to prepare effective, affordable, and long-term stable oxygen electrocatalysts to replace precious metal-based counterparts. Herein, a two-step pyrolysis strategy is developed for controlled synthesis of Fe</description>
      <author>Qi&#8208;Dong Ruan, Yuehong Zhao, Rui Feng, Muhammad Zia Ul Haq, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compressively Strained Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; in Core&#8212;Shell Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalyst Boosts Zinc&#8212;Air Battery Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404065</link>
      <description>Hongpeng Wu, Yudan Li, Haobo Li, Feng Wu, Lihong Li, Xin Xu, Yunfang Gao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400201497

                Abstract Fe 3 O 4 is barely taken into account as an electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), an important reaction for metal&#8212;air batteries and fuel cells, due to its sluggish catalytic kinetics and poor electron conductivity. Herein, how strain engineering can be employed to regulate the local electronic structure of Fe 3 O 4 for high ORR activity is reported. Compressively strained Fe 3 O 4 shells with 2.0% shortened Fe&#9472;O bond are gained on the Fe/Fe 4 N cores as a result of lattice mismatch at the interface. A downshift of the d&#8208;band center occurs for compressed Fe 3 O 4 , leading to weakened chemisorption energy of oxygenated intermediates, and lower reaction overpotential. The compressed Fe 3 O 4 exhibits greatly enhanced electrocatalytic ORR activity with a kinetic current density of 27 times higher than that of pristine one at 0.80 V (vs reversible hydrogen electrode), as well as potential application in zinc&#8208;air batteries. The findings provide a new strategy for tuning electronic structures and improving the catalytic activity of other metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongpeng Wu, Yudan Li, Haobo Li, Feng Wu, Lihong Li, Xin Xu, Yunfang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Understanding of the Electrocatalytic Mechanism for Co/Fe/Cu Doped Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on Urea Oxidation Reactions: Theory and Experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c02596</link>
      <description>Lu Chen, Wenjie Jiang, Jing Tao, Bingxian Chu, Zhixiang Zhai, Tianqi Yu, He Huang, Shibin Yin, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400205094

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Chen, Wenjie Jiang, Jing Tao, Bingxian Chu, Zhixiang Zhai, Tianqi Yu, He Huang, Shibin Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c02596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atom Ag Bonding Between PF3T Nanocluster and TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Leads the Ultra&#8208;Stable Visible&#8208;Light&#8208;Driven Photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403176</link>
      <description>Jui&#8208;Cheng Kao, Tsung-Hsien Teng, Huey-Wen Lin, Fan&#8208;Gang Tseng, Li&#8208;Yu Ting, Dinesh Bhalothia, Ho&#8208;Hsiu Chou, Yu&#8208;Chieh Lo, Jyh&#8208;Pin Chou, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400208247

                Abstract Atomic Ag cluster bonding is employed to reinforce the interface between PF3T nano&#8208;cluster and TiO 2 nanoparticle. With an optimized Ag loading (Ag/TiO 2 = 0.5 wt%), the Ag atoms will uniformly disperse on TiO 2 thus generating a high density of intermediate states in the band gap to form the electron channel between the terthiophene group of PF3T and the TiO 2 in the hybrid composite (denoted as T@Ag05&#8208;P). The former expands the photon absorption band width and the latter facilitates the core&#8208;hole splitting by injecting the photon excited electron (from the excitons in PF3T) into the conduction band (CB) of TiO 2 . These characteristics enable the high efficiency of H 2 production to 16 580 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 g &#8722;1 and photocatalysis stability without degradation under visible light exposure for 96 h. Compared to that of hybrid material without Ag bonding (TiO 2 @PF3T), the H 2 production yield and stability are improved by 4.1 and 18.2&#8208;fold which shows the best performance among existing materials in similar component combination and interfacial reinforcement. The unique bonding method offers a new prospect to accelerate the development of photocatalytic hydrogen production technologies.</description>
      <author>Jui&#8208;Cheng Kao, Tsung-Hsien Teng, Huey-Wen Lin, Fan&#8208;Gang Tseng, Li&#8208;Yu Ting, Dinesh Bhalothia, Ho&#8208;Hsiu Chou, Yu&#8208;Chieh Lo, Jyh&#8208;Pin Chou, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Layer Deposition of Molybdenum Carbide Thin Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400270</link>
      <description>Paloma Ruiz K&#228;rkk&#228;inen, Georgi Popov, Timo Hatanp&#228;&#228;, A. Kemppinen, K. Kohop&#228;&#228;, Mohammad Bagheri, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Mikko Heikkil&#228;, Kenichiro Mizohata, Mykhailo Chundak, Petro Deminskyi, Anton Vihervaara, M&#225;rio Luiz Ribeiro, Joel H&#228;tinen, Joonas Govenius, Matti Putkonen, Mikko Ritala, Advanced materials interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400209069

                Abstract The development of deposition processes for metal carbide thin films is rapidly advancing, driven by their potential for applications including catalysis, batteries, and semiconductor devices. Within this landscape, atomic layer deposition (ALD) offers exceptional conformality, uniformity, and thickness control on spatially complex structures. This paper presents a comprehensive study on the thermal ALD of MoC x with MoCl 5 and 1,4&#8208;bis(trimethylgermyl)&#8208;1,4&#8208;dihydropyrazine [(Me 3 Ge) 2 DHP] as precursors, focusing on the functional properties and characterization of the films. The depositions are conducted at 200&#8211;300 &#176;C and very smooth films with RMS Rq &#8776;0.3&#8211;0.6 nm on Si, TiN, and HfO 2 substrates are obtained. The process has a high growth rate of 1.5 &#197; cycle &#8722;1 and the films appear to be continuous already after 5 cycles. The films are conductive even at thicknesses below 5 nm, and films above 18 nm exhibit superconductivity up to 4.4 K. In lieu of suitable references, Raman modes for molybdenum carbides and nitrides are calculated and X&#8208;ray diffraction and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy are used for phase analysis.</description>
      <author>Paloma Ruiz K&#228;rkk&#228;inen, Georgi Popov, Timo Hatanp&#228;&#228;, A. Kemppinen, K. Kohop&#228;&#228;, Mohammad Bagheri, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Mikko Heikkil&#228;, Kenichiro Mizohata, Mykhailo Chundak, Petro Deminskyi, Anton Vihervaara, M&#225;rio Luiz Ribeiro, Joel H&#228;tinen, Joonas Govenius, Matti Putkonen, Mikko Ritala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the impact of oxygen vacancies in engineered bimetallic oxides for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction: insights from experimental and theoretical approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01180e</link>
      <description>Pratheep Panneerselvam, Chob Singh, J. Santhosh Kumar, Thamarainathan Doulassiramane, R. Padmanaban, Akshaya K. Samal, M. Sakar, Arvind H. Jadhav, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400210206

                In this study, we presented hollow bimetallic mixed oxides of molybdenum and nickel, prepared through a facile polymer-assisted solution process.</description>
      <author>Pratheep Panneerselvam, Chob Singh, J. Santhosh Kumar, Thamarainathan Doulassiramane, R. Padmanaban, Akshaya K. Samal, M. Sakar, Arvind H. Jadhav</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01180e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction Reaction from Ab Initio Thermodynamics: Single versus Dual Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400536</link>
      <description>Ilaria Barlocco, Mar&#237;a Julia Spotti, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Advanced theory and simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400210353

                Abstract The electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) is a key process for the energy transition. Transition metal atoms atomically dispersed on a solid support represent a promising approach to the design of new catalytic materials. The interest for single&#8208; (SACs) and dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) is steadily growing. In general, DACs are considered more active than SACs for NRR. In this work, the complex chemistry behind NRR is investigated on a set of SACs and DACs by means of density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The results indicate that self&#8208;interaction corrected exchange&#8208;correlation functionals must be adopted, at variance with several studies in the literature. Furthermore, it is not possible to extrapolate results obtained on conventional extended catalytic surfaces to SACs and DACs, due to a richer scenario of possible reaction paths. In general, the results show a positive effect on the catalytic activity moving from 3d to 5d metals, and from SACs and DACs. However, if the two effects work together, that is, 5d metals in DACs, the reaction intermediates may be too strongly bound, thus resulting in reduced catalytic activity. In this respect, the fact that DACs are expected to be superior to SACs in NRR is not always verified.</description>
      <author>Ilaria Barlocco, Mar&#237;a Julia Spotti, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating coordination environment of main-group elements co-doped graphene: Boost CO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si3.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;RR activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114316</link>
      <description>Yiqun Guo, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan, Molecular catalysis. 564(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400211940

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiqun Guo, Shan Gao, Xiangmei Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Collective Potential of Lanthanide Single-Atom Catalysts for Efficient CO2-to-CO Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4614446/v1</link>
      <description>Min Liu, Qiyou Wang, Tao Luo, Xueying Cao, Yu Gong, Yuxiang Liu, Hongmei Li, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chao Ma, Kang Liu, Junwei Fu, Shiguo Zhang, Changxu Liu, Zhang Lin, Liyuan Chai, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400213375

                Abstract Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have received increasing attention due to their 100% atomic utilization efficiency. The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) to CO using SAC offers a promising approach for CO2 utilization, but achieving facile CO2 adsorption and CO desorption remains challenging for traditional SACs. Instead of singling out specific atoms, we propose a novel strategy utilizing atoms from the entire lanthanide (Ln) group to facilitate the CO2RR. Density functional theory calculations, operando spectroscopy, and X-ray absorption spectroscopy elucidate the bridging adsorption mechanism for a representative erbium (Er) single-atom catalyst. Remarkably, we realize a series of Ln SACs spanning 14 elements that exhibit CO Faradaic efficiencies exceeding 90%. The Er catalyst achieves an ultrahigh turnover frequency of ~ 130,000 h&#8210;1, accompanying with a remarkable 42.6% full-cell energy efficiency and record-high 94% single-pass CO2 conversion efficiency. This unparalleled catalytic platform leverages the collective potential of the lanthanide group, introducing new possibilities for efficient CO2-to-CO conversion and beyond through the exploration of unique bonding motifs in single-atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>Min Liu, Qiyou Wang, Tao Luo, Xueying Cao, Yu Gong, Yuxiang Liu, Hongmei Li, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chao Ma, Kang Liu, Junwei Fu, Shiguo Zhang, Changxu Liu, Zhang Lin, Liyuan Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4614446/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulsed Laser&#8208;Initiated Dual&#8208;Catalytic Interfaces for Directed Electroreduction of Nitrite to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400187</link>
      <description>Talshyn Begildayeva, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Thuy Ngoc Nguyen, Ahreum Min, Hyeyoung Shin, Myong Yong Choi, Small structures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400218580

                Green and highly selective synthesis of ammonia (NH 3 ) via electrochemical reduction reaction of toxic nitrite (NO 2 &#8722; RR) in a neutral electrolyte is a feasible solution for energy and environmental issues. Dual&#8208;nature electrocatalysts combining metal and metal&#8208;derived materials are crucial for enhancing the selectivity parameter and efficacy of this reaction. Here, Pd&#8208;, Pt&#8208;, Ru&#8208;, and Ir&#8208;decorated Co 3 (PO 4 ) 2 (CoPi) composites with a robust metal&#8211;support interaction are obtained via the one&#8208;pot pulsed laser ablation in liquid method. Among the designed composites, Ir&#8211;CoPi affords &#8776;100% Faradaic efficiency, mass balance, and selectivity toward NH 3 product at sufficiently low potentials. Further, it affords the highest NH 3 yield rate of 19.13 mg h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 with 78.1% removal of toxic NO 2 &#8722; with a rate constant k app = 0.31 m m min &#8722;1 under &#8722;1.6 V versus Ag/AgCl. In situ experiments and theoretical investigations reveal the underlying mechanisms responsible for this outstanding performance of Ir&#8211;CoPi, which can be accredited to the generation of specific active sites on the Ir component. Insights derived from the evolving intermediate reactive species provide new opportunities for large&#8208;scale NH 3 production through electrochemical techniques, density functional theory calculations, and the improvement of the corresponding industrial processes.</description>
      <author>Talshyn Begildayeva, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Thuy Ngoc Nguyen, Ahreum Min, Hyeyoung Shin, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Exchange-Correlation Functionals for Heterogeneous Catalysis of Nitrogen Species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01497</link>
      <description>Honghui Kim, Neung-Kyung Yu, Nianhan Tian, Andrew J. Medford, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400222504

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Honghui Kim, Neung-Kyung Yu, Nianhan Tian, Andrew J. Medford</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic Model Fitted with a Genetic Algorithm to Experimental XPS Coverages at High Pressure&#8211;CO Hydrogenation on Rh(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02020</link>
      <description>Mikael Valter-Lithander, Minttu M. Kauppinen, David Degerman, Gabriel L. S. Rodrigues, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, Lars G. M. Pettersson, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400228976

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mikael Valter-Lithander, Minttu M. Kauppinen, David Degerman, Gabriel L. S. Rodrigues, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, Lars G. M. Pettersson</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Ionic Interferents on Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction: Mechanistic Insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03949</link>
      <description>Jie Fan, Leslie K. Arrazolo, Jiaxin Du, Huimin Xu, Siyu Fang, Yue Liu, Zhongbiao Wu, Jae&#8208;Hong Kim, Xuanhao Wu, Environmental science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400228979

                Nitrate, a prevalent water pollutant, poses substantial public health concerns and environmental risks. Electrochemical reduction of nitrate (eNO</description>
      <author>Jie Fan, Leslie K. Arrazolo, Jiaxin Du, Huimin Xu, Siyu Fang, Yue Liu, Zhongbiao Wu, Jae&#8208;Hong Kim, Xuanhao Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03949</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting oxygen reduction in acidic media through integration of Pt-Co alloy effect and strong interaction with carbon defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6774-3</link>
      <description>Nannan Ji, Hong Sheng, Shilong Liu, Yangyuan Zhang, Hongfei Sun, Lingzhi Wei, Ziqi Tian, Peng Jiang, Qianwang Chen, Jianwei Su, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400229661

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nannan Ji, Hong Sheng, Shilong Liu, Yangyuan Zhang, Hongfei Sun, Lingzhi Wei, Ziqi Tian, Peng Jiang, Qianwang Chen, Jianwei Su</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6774-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Ni on Nitrogen&#8208;Doped Carbon Substrate Enhances Basic HER Performance of Ru Clusters**</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202400490</link>
      <description>Penggang Jiao, Shuang Chen, Weitai Wu, Zhiwei Li, Ping Xu, Hassanien Gomaa, Cuihua An, Chunling Qin, Qibo Deng, Ning Hu, ChemistrySelect. 9(25)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400231590

                Abstract Hydrogen production through water electrolysis is a viable method to reduce reliance on conventional energy sources. Nonetheless, water electrolysis necessitates using effective electrocatalysts to enhance the efficiency of converting electrical energy into chemical energy. Compared with the high cost of platinum (Pt), ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;based materials show significant promise as electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Here, a Ru cluster supported on a nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon substrate containing an atomically dispersed nickel electrocatalyst is synthesized (NiRu&#8208;NC). In NiRu&#8208;NC electrocatalyst, Ru clusters act as primary active sites, while atomically dispersed Ni atoms act as auxiliary sites. The HER activity of Ru clusters is enhanced by modifying the electronic structure of Ru sites. This unique structure enhances the interaction between the Ru cluster and the substrate, showing excellent HER performance in an alkaline environment. The overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 is only 25 mV, and the Tafel slope is 29 mV dec &#8722;1 . In continuous operation for 24 h, the overpotential value hardly rose, indicating exemplary stability behavior of the applied NiRu&#8208;NC electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Penggang Jiao, Shuang Chen, Weitai Wu, Zhiwei Li, Ping Xu, Hassanien Gomaa, Cuihua An, Chunling Qin, Qibo Deng, Ning Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202400490</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvent-free synthesis of nickel doped ruthenium for efficient hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.380</link>
      <description>Jinxiang Chai, Ying-Song Yu, Guang Han, Hugh C. De Long, Qifu Zheng, Jianliang Xie, Mingfei Shao, Minghui Yang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 78(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400241716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinxiang Chai, Ying-Song Yu, Guang Han, Hugh C. De Long, Qifu Zheng, Jianliang Xie, Mingfei Shao, Minghui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membraneless Electrochemical Synthesis Strategy toward Nitrate-to-Ammonia Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c02445</link>
      <description>Yongguang Bu, Wenjing Yu, Qiang Yang, Wenkai Zhang, Qiang Sun, Weiwen Wu, Peixin Cui, Chao Wang, Guandao Gao, Environmental science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400242054

                Electroreduction of nitrate (NO</description>
      <author>Yongguang Bu, Wenjing Yu, Qiang Yang, Wenkai Zhang, Qiang Sun, Weiwen Wu, Peixin Cui, Chao Wang, Guandao Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c02445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Evaluation of Penta&#8208;Coordinated Fe Phthalocyanine During the Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Various Acidic Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400186</link>
      <description>C&#233;sar Z&#250;&#241;iga Loyola, Nicol&#225;s Troncoso, Ang&#233;lica Gatica, Federico Tasca, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400242233

                Abstract Iron phthalocyanine (FePc) was penta&#8208;coordinated with pyridine ligand (Py) grafted on carbon nanotube (CNT), to form (FePc&#8208;Py&#8208;CNT). The complex was studied as a catalyst for the oxygen reduction reaction ORR in seven different supporting electrolytes: OH &#8722; (0.1 M), OH &#8722; (1 M), NO 3 &#8722; (1 M), HSO 4 &#8722; (1 M), ClO 4 &#8722; (1 M), Br &#8722; (1 M), Cl &#8722; (1 M), to unveil anion&#8208;poisoning effects and mechanism. Through cyclic voltammetry and polarization curves in N 2 and O 2 saturated atmospheres, thermodynamic and kinetic data were acquired. In acid media, the formal potential Fe(III)/(II) ( E 0&#8217; Fe(III)/(II) ) of the complex is biased to more negative potentials by the anion presence. Similar effects were observed for the onset potential ( E onset ) during polarization curves for the ORR. When the ORR was performed in the presence of either ClO 4 &#8722; , or HSO 4 &#8722; , anions, Tafel analysis showed different values depending if were derived from the low or from the high overpotential regions, revealing an inner&#8208;sphere electron transfer mechanism (ISET). The Tafel values derived from measurements in the presence of Cl &#8722; and Br &#8722; anions do not change when extracted at low or at high overpotentials evidencing an outer&#8208;sphere reaction mechanism (OSET). Gibbs free energies were derived from poisoning tests confirming the ISET and OSET mechanisms. The poisoning effect is responsible for the immediate loss of performance for these catalysts during the ORR in acidic media.</description>
      <author>C&#233;sar Z&#250;&#241;iga Loyola, Nicol&#225;s Troncoso, Ang&#233;lica Gatica, Federico Tasca</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yb-Modified Carbon-Based Bifunctional Oxygen Electrode Catalyst: A Density Functional Theory Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03420</link>
      <description>Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Daomiao Wang, Chao Liu, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400242664

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Daomiao Wang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03420</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance study of activated multi-walled carbon nanotubes on catalyzing amine-based carbon capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132371</link>
      <description>Lingling Li, Xin He, Pan Li, Si Chen, Tongtong Wang, Chunxi Hai, Yong Sun, Qian Xu, Shengde Dong, Luxiang Ma, Yuan Zhou, Fuel. 373(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400248041

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingling Li, Xin He, Pan Li, Si Chen, Tongtong Wang, Chunxi Hai, Yong Sun, Qian Xu, Shengde Dong, Luxiang Ma, Yuan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Intermediates Using Ethylene Diamine Tetraacetate for Boosting Electrochemical Ch4 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4882231</link>
      <description>Seokwoo Choe, Yu Jin Kim, Kyeounghak Kim, Youn Jeong Jang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400264723

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seokwoo Choe, Yu Jin Kim, Kyeounghak Kim, Youn Jeong Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4882231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel-Type Zn2-2xnbxfexti1-2xo4-2x (0&amp;lt;X&#8804;0.15) Solid Solution: A Novel Photocatalyst for Overall Conversion Co2 and H2o</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4882234</link>
      <description>Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Jiwu Zhao, Yanmei Chen, Li Li, Jinni Shen, Xuxu Wang, Jun Liang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400264860

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Jiwu Zhao, Yanmei Chen, Li Li, Jinni Shen, Xuxu Wang, Jun Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4882234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adapting OC20-Trained EquiformerV2 Models for High-Entropy Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01704</link>
      <description>Christian M. Clausen, Jan Rossmeisl, Zachary W. Ulissi, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400266871

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Christian M. Clausen, Jan Rossmeisl, Zachary W. Ulissi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photothermal RuNiFeOx/FeNi3 heterostructured arrays with Janus wettability for highly enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132368</link>
      <description>Lunhong Ai, Yao Tian, Tiancun Xiao, Jiayi Zhang, Chenghui Zhang, Jing Jiang, Fuel. 373(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400267754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lunhong Ai, Yao Tian, Tiancun Xiao, Jiayi Zhang, Chenghui Zhang, Jing Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances, mechanisms and applications in oxygen evolution electrocatalysis of gold-driven</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153719</link>
      <description>Tong Liu, Jiangbo Lu, Zhihao Chen, Luo Zhang, Yurong Ren, Xiangqun Zhuge, Zhihong Luo, Guogang Ren, Lei Wei-Wei, Dan Li&#365;, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400269040

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role in electrochemical energy storage and conversion. Among different metal elements, gold (Au) stands out due to its high electronegativity and remarkable catalytic properties, especially when it is in nanoscale size. In this review, we aim to comprehensively analyze the oxygen electrocatalytic performance of nanosized Au, including the influence of the crystal surface, morphology, substrate materials of Au nanoparticles, size and ligands of Au nanoclusters, and Au single atoms on oxygen electrocatalysis. By exploring the catalytic performance of noble metals, non-noble metals, oxides, hydroxides/oxyhydroxides/layered double hydroxides, sulfides, phosphides, nitrides, and selenides through the integration of nanosized Au, which offers valuable insights for enhancing the OER efficiency. These effects can be attributed to two mechanisms: i) adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) and ii) lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM), where the nanosized Au changed the electronic structure of the catalysts and improved the adsorption of reaction intermediates to accelerate electron transfer process or exerts the synergistic effect between metallic Au and oxygen vacancies. For instance, Gold-driven OER catalysts can be widely used in zinc-air batteries and water splitting in the future.</description>
      <author>Tong Liu, Jiangbo Lu, Zhihao Chen, Luo Zhang, Yurong Ren, Xiangqun Zhuge, Zhihong Luo, Guogang Ren, Lei Wei-Wei, Dan Li&#365;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153719</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in selenide-based electrocatalysts for hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction: From mechanism and synthesis to application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101641</link>
      <description>Yunlong Zhang, Ying&#8208;Bing Jiang, Abdukader Abdukayum, Xusheng Xie, Sanshuang Gao, Xijun Liu, L. Zhang, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400269924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunlong Zhang, Ying&#8208;Bing Jiang, Abdukader Abdukayum, Xusheng Xie, Sanshuang Gao, Xijun Liu, L. Zhang, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering both intrinsic characteristic and local microenvironment of platinum sites toward highly efficient oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.012</link>
      <description>Haibin Wang, Chunlei Li, Mengling Liu, Di Dou, L. Chen, Limin Zhang, Qiuping Zhao, Cong Ye, Yi Wang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400271700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Wang, Chunlei Li, Mengling Liu, Di Dou, L. Chen, Limin Zhang, Qiuping Zhao, Cong Ye, Yi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948; and its catalytic oxidation of NO and its reaction path</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e33580</link>
      <description>Yige Guo, Xiaoxue Niu, Huaiyu Yang, Liwen Chen, Yi Ren, Hao Guo, Bo Wu, Heliyon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400278855

                The oxidation rate of NO to NO2 is a critical parameter in the removal of NOx within selective catalytic reduction (SCR) systems. LaCoO3-&#948; is a kind of potential catalyst to enhance the oxidation of NO to NO2, it may offers an economic and stable alternative to noble metal catalysts, particularly at elevated temperatures. This study aimed to enhance the catalytic efficiency of LaCoO3-&#948; through strontium (Sr) doping. La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948; (with varying x values of 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4) was synthesized using a sol-gel method. La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948; exhibited superior NO oxidation catalytic activity compared to LaCoO3-&#948;, with the most notable enhancement observed at x = 0.3 (84% conversion). This improvement can be attributed to the substitution of La3+ with Sr2+, which induces lattice distortion and charge imbalance, thereby creating more oxygen vacancies that enhance the catalytic oxidation capability of La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948;. However, it's important to note that an excessive amount of Sr can result in the formation of SrCO3 deposits on the surface of La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948;, thereby diminishing its catalytic oxidation performance. The catalytic oxidation reaction behavior adhered most closely to the O2-adsorbed E-R model, the surface defects in La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948; playing a pivotal role in the catalytic reaction.</description>
      <author>Yige Guo, Xiaoxue Niu, Huaiyu Yang, Liwen Chen, Yi Ren, Hao Guo, Bo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e33580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic enhancement of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction by role of Ni-Fe LDH introducing frustrated Lewis pairs via vacancy-engineered</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110199</link>
      <description>M. Li, Haozhi Wang, Zijun Yang, Zhiping Yin, Yuan Liu, Yingmei Bian, Yang Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400279219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Li, Haozhi Wang, Zijun Yang, Zhiping Yin, Yuan Liu, Yingmei Bian, Yang Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some remaining puzzles in hydrogen electrocatalysis mechanisms on platinum surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.002</link>
      <description>Shangqian Zhu, X.M. Liu, Xuesi Wang, Qinglan Zhao, Minhua Shao, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400281751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shangqian Zhu, X.M. Liu, Xuesi Wang, Qinglan Zhao, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cobalt&#8211;Platinum&#8211;Ruthenium System for Acidic Methanol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01008</link>
      <description>Hai Tao Xu, Daoyuan Zheng, Haldrian Iriawan, Jen-Hung Fang, Junghwa Kim, Xiao Wang, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Ju Li, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Chemistry of materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400283865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hai Tao Xu, Daoyuan Zheng, Haldrian Iriawan, Jen-Hung Fang, Junghwa Kim, Xiao Wang, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Ju Li, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coverage-dependent activation of CO over Ni/Cu(100) single atom alloys (SAAs)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213809</link>
      <description>Wu Meng, Ling Zhao Li, Ruijiao Zhao, Yu Liu, X.D. Wang, Han&#8208;Yue Qiu, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 161(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400294030

                Single atom alloys (SAAs) often bring new chemistry in heterogeneous catalysis and well-defined structure for the study of structure&#8211;activity relationship (SAR). However, the existing pressure gap causes the reported SARs quite divergent. Herein, we have studied CO activation over Ni/Cu(100) SAAs in ultrahigh vacuum (UHV) and millibar range. While the Ni SAAs formed on Cu(100) significantly enhance the CO adsorption strength under UHV conditions, the CO treatment at elevated pressure leads to notable surface carbon and oxygen deposition through surface reaction. Density functional theory calculations revealed that either dissociation or disproportionation is thermodynamically forbidden for the coverage of CO less than 5/16 ML. However, these two reaction pathways can be opened at higher CO coverages due to the elevated energy state involving repulsion between adsorbed CO. This work uncovers the initial activation process of CO and demonstrates one typical cause for the pressure gap in surface science study as well.</description>
      <author>Wu Meng, Ling Zhao Li, Ruijiao Zhao, Yu Liu, X.D. Wang, Han&#8208;Yue Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated workflows and interfaces for data-driven semi-empirical electronic structure calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0209742</link>
      <description>P. V. Stishenko, Adam McSloy, Berk Onat, B. Hourahine, Reinhard J. Maurer, James R. Kermode, Andrew J. Logsdail, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 161(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400294489

                Modern software engineering of electronic structure codes has seen a paradigm shift from monolithic workflows toward object-based modularity. Software objectivity allows for greater flexibility in the application of electronic structure calculations, with particular benefits when integrated with approaches for data-driven analysis. Here, we discuss different approaches to create deep modular interfaces that connect big-data workflows and electronic structure codes and explore the diversity of use cases that they can enable. We present two such interface approaches for the semi-empirical electronic structure package, DFTB+. In one case, DFTB+ is applied as a library and provides data to an external workflow; in another, DFTB+receives data via external bindings and processes the information subsequently within an internal workflow. We provide a general framework to enable data exchange workflows for embedding new machine-learning-based Hamiltonians within DFTB+ or enabling deep integration of DFTB+ in multiscale embedding workflows. These modular interfaces demonstrate opportunities in emergent software and workflows to accelerate scientific discovery by harnessing existing software capabilities.</description>
      <author>P. V. Stishenko, Adam McSloy, Berk Onat, B. Hourahine, Reinhard J. Maurer, James R. Kermode, Andrew J. Logsdail</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0209742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity-Selectivity Trade-off in Propane Dehydrogenation: Pt&#8211;C Repulsion is the Essence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01253</link>
      <description>Xin Chang, Lyudmila V. Moskaleva, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400294516

                While linear scaling relationships have made enormous progress in the computational design of new catalysts, the simultaneous enhancement or weakening of adsorbates for a specific reaction leads to an activity-selectivity trade-off. Focusing on the important industrial reaction, propane dehydrogenation, strategies to break linear scaling relationships have been established to maintain activity with increased selectivity. Nonetheless, elucidating the essential reason for generating the trade-off in propane dehydrogenation from electronic and geometric aspects is still elusive. Moreover, it remains uncertain whether the modified catalyst is restricted by another trade-off. This work begins by examining the effect of electronic regulation on the activity-selectivity trade-off and reveals that either too weak or too strong Pt&#8211;C repulsion is the essence of this trade-off. When geometric modulation is introduced, the alloy exhibiting similar Pt&#8211;C repulsion to Pt maintains catalytic activity with remarkably improved selectivity. However, despite establishing a better scaling relationship through geometric modulation, the activity-selectivity trade-off still exists with Pt&#8211;C repulsion as its essence.</description>
      <author>Xin Chang, Lyudmila V. Moskaleva, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in Ni-based catalysts for the electrochemical oxidation of ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.06.045</link>
      <description>Xin Tan, Shiming Chen, Dafeng Yan, Ruixing Du, Qitong Zhong, Longfei Liao, Zhenchen Tang, Feng Zeng, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400299514

                The electrochemical ethanol oxidation reaction (EOR) plays a crucial role in electrochemical hydrogen production and direct ethanol fuel cells, both vital for utilizing renewable energies. Ni-based catalysts are pivotal in enabling efficient EOR, leading to the formation of acetic acid/acetaldehyde or CO2. These can serve as alternative anodic oxidation reactions for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water electrolysis or the anodic reaction for direct ethanol fuel cells, respectively. This review explores recent advancements in EOR over Ni-based catalysts. It begins with an overview of EOR performance across various Ni-based catalysts, followed by an examination of the reaction chemistry, mechanism, and active sites. The review then delves into strategies for designing highly active Ni-based EOR catalysts. These strategies include promotion with transition metals, noble metals, nonmetals, and carbon materials, as well as creating amorphous structures, special morphologies, and single-atom catalysts. Additionally, it discusses the concept of self-supporting catalysts using three-dimensional porous substrates. Finally, the review highlights emerging methodologies that warrant further exploration, along with future directions for designing highly active and stable EOR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xin Tan, Shiming Chen, Dafeng Yan, Ruixing Du, Qitong Zhong, Longfei Liao, Zhenchen Tang, Feng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.06.045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxyl Group Modification Improves the Selectivity of Metal Single Atom on Poly(Heptazine Imide) for Electrocatalytic Acetylene Semi-Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4885298</link>
      <description>Xiaoxiao Chen, Yang Li, Yaofeng Yuan, Wei Lin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400315165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxiao Chen, Yang Li, Yaofeng Yuan, Wei Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4885298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing the relationship between the activity and stability of anode oxide-based electrocatalysts in acid for PEMWE electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02869d</link>
      <description>Yingying Xu, Yingxia Zhao, Zihui Yuan, Yue Sun, Shaomin Peng, Yuanhong Zhong, Ming Sun, Lin Yu, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400320837

                This review covers advancements in noble and non-noble metal oxides for acidic OER, emphasizing the evaluation of catalyst instability, and strategies to enhance IrO 2 , RuO 2 , and TM oxides.</description>
      <author>Yingying Xu, Yingxia Zhao, Zihui Yuan, Yue Sun, Shaomin Peng, Yuanhong Zhong, Ming Sun, Lin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02869d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Ammonia Yield Rate from Dilute Nitrate Solutions Using a Cu(100)-Rich Foil: A Step Closer to Large-Scale Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05818</link>
      <description>Abhishek Garg, Arunava Saha, Supriti Dutta, Swapan K. Pati, M. Eswaramoorthy, C. N. R. Rao, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400321361

                The electrochemical reduction of nitrate (NO3&#8211;) ions to ammonia (NH3) provides an alternative method to eliminate harmful NO3&#8211; pollutants in water as well as to produce highly valuable NH3 chemicals. The NH3 yield rate however is still limited to the &#956;mol h&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 range when dealing with dilute NO3&#8211; concentrations found in waste streams. Copper (Cu) has attracted much attention because of its unique ability to effectively convert NO3&#8211; to NH3. We have reported a simple and scalable electrochemical method to produce a Cu foil having its surface covered with a porous Cu nanostructure enriched with (100) facets, which efficiently catalyzes NO3&#8211; to NH3. The Cu(100)-rich electrocatalyst showed a very high NH3 production rate of 1.1 mmol h&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 in NO3&#8211; concentration as low as 14 mM NO3&#8211;, which is 4&#8211;5 times higher than the best-reported values. Increasing the NO3&#8211; concentration (140 mM) resulted in an NH3 production yield rate of 3.34 mmol h&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2. The durability test conducted for this catalyst foil in a flow cell system showed greater than 100 h stability with a Faradaic efficiency greater than 98%, demonstrating its potential to be used on an industrially relevant scale. Further, density functional theory (DFT) calculations have been performed to understand the better catalytic activity of Cu(100) compared to Cu(111) facets toward NO3&#8211;RR.</description>
      <author>Abhishek Garg, Arunava Saha, Supriti Dutta, Swapan K. Pati, M. Eswaramoorthy, C. N. R. Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulated Reaction Route for Oxyhydroxides toward Top&#8208;Performing Water Oxidation via &lt;i&gt;e&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;g&lt;/sub&gt; Electron Filling State</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405474</link>
      <description>Na Yao, Na Luo, Shan Jiang, Aofei Cai, Wei Pi, Xing Wang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400323980

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity on transition metal (TM) catalysts is governed by OER mechanism, yet discovering a controllable parameter to custom&#8208;tailor OER mechanism remains a challenge. Here, the study highlights an e g electron&#8208;filling state in octahedral TM&#8208;catalysts, achieved by the modulation of splitting energy (&#916;) via different anions (R) (Cl &#8722; , PO 4 3&#8722; , NO 3 &#8722; , F &#8722; , SO 4 2&#8722; , CO 3 2&#8722; ). The e g &#8208; electron filling state customization predominantly arises from the adjustment of Co&#8208; d z 2 orbital energy, which can tailor the bandgap between Co&#8208; d z 2 and O&#8208; p orbits (&#916;&#949; d&#8208;p ), thus customizing lattice&#8208;oxygen (O L ) activities and the OER mechanism. Combining the experimental measurements with DFT calculations, it is concluded that increased e g electron in TM&#8208;catalysts brings decreased &#916;&#949; d&#8208;p , which can manageably strengthen lattice&#8208;oxygen reactivity. Consequently, the OER mechanism on TM catalyst is transformed from adsorbate precipitation mechanism (AEM) to lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) and customized OER pathways with different lattice&#8208;oxygen activities. The screened PO 4 3&#8208;_ TM, with the optimal O L activity in LOM path, possesses excellent activity and stability, achieving a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at 236 mV overpotential and maintaining stable operation for 300 h with inapparent degradation at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Na Yao, Na Luo, Shan Jiang, Aofei Cai, Wei Pi, Xing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Structure Prediction for Battery Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-47303-6_7</link>
      <description>Ziheng Lu, Bonan Zhu, Topics in applied physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400330694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziheng Lu, Bonan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-47303-6_7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Investigation on the Nitrogen Reduction Mechanism in Two-Dimensional Transition-Metal Boride with Ordered Metal Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00951</link>
      <description>L.-C. Ma, Xianfei Chen, Yi Huang, Peicong Zhang, Beibei Xiao, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400330812

                The creation of ordered collective vacancies in experiment proves challenging within a two-dimensional lattice, resulting in a limited understanding of their impact on catalyst performance. Motivated by the successful experimental synthesis of monolayer molybdenum borides with precisely ordered metal vacancies [Zhou et al. Science 2021, 373, 801&#8211;805] through dealloying, the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) in monolayer borides was systematically investigated to elucidate the influence of such ordered metal vacancies on catalytic reactions and the underlying mechanisms. The results reveal that the N-containing intermediates tend to dissociate, facilitating the NRR process with reduced UL. The emergence of ordered metal vacancies modulates the electronic properties of the catalyst and partially facilitates the decomposition of N-containing intermediates. However, the UL for NRR in Mo4/3B2 and W4/3B2 exhibits a significant increase. The compromised electrochemical performance is explained through the development of a simple electronic descriptor of the d&#8211;p band center (&#916;dM&#8211;pB). Among these materials, Mo4/3Sc2/3B2 exhibits the most superior catalytic activity with a UL of &#8722;0.5 V and favorable NRR selectivity over the HER. Our results provide mechanistic insights into the role of ordered metal vacancies in transition-metal boride for the NRR and highlight a novel avenue toward the rational design of superior NRR catalysts.</description>
      <author>L.-C. Ma, Xianfei Chen, Yi Huang, Peicong Zhang, Beibei Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00951</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab Initio Interfacial Electrochemistry Applied to Understanding, Tuning and Designing Battery Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-47303-6_3</link>
      <description>Arthur Hagopian, Anja Kopa&#269; Lautar, Jean&#8208;S&#233;bastien Filhol, Topics in applied physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400331032

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arthur Hagopian, Anja Kopa&#269; Lautar, Jean&#8208;S&#233;bastien Filhol</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-47303-6_3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic stability of Pt-based alloys for fuel-cell catalysts calculated from atomistics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00463a</link>
      <description>Shubham Sharma, Cheng Zeng, Andrew A. Peterson, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400332737

                New atomistic models dissect dissolution, near-surface, and bulk diffusion, elevating Pt-alloy catalyst's stability analysis.</description>
      <author>Shubham Sharma, Cheng Zeng, Andrew A. Peterson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00463a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Strain&#8208;Induced Noble Metal Nanohybrids for Electro&#8208;catalysis: From Theoretical Mechanisms to Practical Use</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400154</link>
      <description>Zhao&#8208;Yang Chen, Lingtong Li, Fujun Zhao, Yinghong Zhu, Youqun Chu, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400336100

                Abstract In response to the climate goal of achieving carbon neutrality by 2050, efficient electrochemical energy conversion devices are garnering increasing attention. However, the enhancement of electrochemical performance using noble metal electrocatalysts, along with cost reduction and electrode fabrication, remain significant challenges. Noble metal hybrid nanostructures, possessing multiple surface functionalities, lead to outstanding electrocatalytic performances and low&#8208;cost potential. Strain effects can bolster the bonding strength between the noble metal layers and the substrate or core layers, while simultaneously affecting electrocatalytic performance through tuning the binding strength between catalytically active sites and reactants, including intermediates. This review encapsulates the research efforts directed towards improving the performance of noble metal electrocatalysts and provides an overview of the latest advancements in controlling the surface state of noble metals by incorporating a secondary component. We discuss systematic approaches to adjusting surface strain effects on noble metals, characterization techniques, and application case studies, while extracting key design indicators for readers to consider from a macroscopic perspective. Further, we outline the challenges encountered and current solutions when advancing noble metal catalysts from theoretical mechanisms to practical use. Finally, the perspectives on the future research of noble metal surface layer control techniques were also provided.</description>
      <author>Zhao&#8208;Yang Chen, Lingtong Li, Fujun Zhao, Yinghong Zhu, Youqun Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Intrinsic Mechanism of High-Performance Two-Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for ORR/OER through Theoretical Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00961</link>
      <description>Xiaofei Wei, Shoufu Cao, Shan Cheng, Chunyu Lu, Xinhui Chen, Xiaoqing Lu, Xiaobo Chen, Fangna Dai, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400346361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaofei Wei, Shoufu Cao, Shan Cheng, Chunyu Lu, Xinhui Chen, Xiaoqing Lu, Xiaobo Chen, Fangna Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure- and Morphology-Controlled Synthesis of Hexagonal Ni&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Zn&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;P Nanocrystals and Their Composition-Dependent Electrocatalytic Activity for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00539</link>
      <description>Lisa S. Graves, Rajib Sarkar, J. E. Baker, Ka Un Lao, Indika U. Arachchige, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400346688

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lisa S. Graves, Rajib Sarkar, J. E. Baker, Ka Un Lao, Indika U. Arachchige</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile and Scalable Colloidal Synthesis of Transition Metal Dichalcogenide Nanoparticles with High-Performance Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04968</link>
      <description>Jing Li, Angelika Wrzesi&#324;ska&#8208;Lashkova, Marielle Deconinck, M.W. Gobel, Yana Vaynzof, Vladimir Lesnyak, Alexander Eychm&#252;ller, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400350027

                Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) have garnered significant attention as efficient electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to their high activity, stability, and cost-effectiveness. However, the development of a convenient and economical approach for large-scale HER applications remains a persistent challenge. In this study, we present the successful synthesis of TMD nanoparticles (including MoS</description>
      <author>Jing Li, Angelika Wrzesi&#324;ska&#8208;Lashkova, Marielle Deconinck, M.W. Gobel, Yana Vaynzof, Vladimir Lesnyak, Alexander Eychm&#252;ller</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arc plasma&#8208;deposited Co single&#8208;atom catalysts supported on an aligned carbon nanofiber for hydrogen peroxide electrosynthesis and an electro&#8208;Fenton process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.582</link>
      <description>Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Sooyeon Kim, Ki Ro Yoon, Thao Thi Le, Chinh V. Hoang, Jae Won Choi, Wenjun Zhang, Sae Yane Paek, Chung Hyeon Lee, Ji Hyun Lee, Keun Hwa Chae, Sohee Jeong, Seung&#8208;Yong Lee, Byeong&#8208;Kwon Ju, Sang&#8208;Hoon Kim, Sang Soo Han, Jong Min Kim, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400359072

                Abstract Atomically dispersed single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) on carbon supports show great promise for H 2 O 2 electrosynthesis, but conventional wet chemistry methods using particulate carbon blacks in powder form have limited their potential as two&#8208;electron (2e &#8722; ) oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts. Here, we demonstrate high&#8208;performance Co SACs supported on a free&#8208;standing aligned carbon nanofiber (CNF) using electrospinning and arc plasma deposition (APD). Based on the surface oxidation treatment of aligned CNF and precise control of the deposition amount in a dry&#8208;based APD process, we successfully form densely populated Co SACs on aligned CNF. Through experimental analyses and density functional theory calculations, we reveal that Co SAC has a Co&#8211;N 2 &#8211;O 2 moiety with one epoxy group, leading to excellent 2e &#8722; ORR activity. Furthermore, the aligned CNF significantly improves mass transfer in flow cells compared to randomly oriented CNF, showing an overpotential reduction of 30 mV and a 1.3&#8208;fold improvement (84.5%) in Faradaic efficiency, and finally achieves an outstanding production rate of 15.75 mol g cat &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 at 300 mA cm &#8722;2 . The high&#8208;performance Co SAC supported on well&#8208;aligned CNF is also applied in an electro&#8208;Fenton process, demonstrating rapid removal of methylene blue and bisphenol F due to its exceptional 2e &#8722; ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Sooyeon Kim, Ki Ro Yoon, Thao Thi Le, Chinh V. Hoang, Jae Won Choi, Wenjun Zhang, Sae Yane Paek, Chung Hyeon Lee, Ji Hyun Lee, Keun Hwa Chae, Sohee Jeong, Seung&#8208;Yong Lee, Byeong&#8208;Kwon Ju, Sang&#8208;Hoon Kim, Sang Soo Han, Jong Min Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curvature-Dependent Electrochemical Hydrogen Peroxide Synthesis Performance of Oxidized Carbon Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01637</link>
      <description>Fangxin She, Zhongyuan Guo, Fangzhou Liu, Zixun Yu, Jiaxiang Chen, Yuhang Fan, Yaojie Lei, Yuan Chen, Hao Li, Wei Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400360164

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangxin She, Zhongyuan Guo, Fangzhou Liu, Zixun Yu, Jiaxiang Chen, Yuhang Fan, Yaojie Lei, Yuan Chen, Hao Li, Wei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing Mo&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Clusters and Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C Nanoparticles on Oxidized Carbon Nanotubes Boosting the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02069</link>
      <description>Shuo Cao, Zun Guan, Ying Ma, Bing Xu, Jinghong Ma, Wei Chu, Riguang Zhang, Giuliano Giambastiani, Yuefeng Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400360420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuo Cao, Zun Guan, Ying Ma, Bing Xu, Jinghong Ma, Wei Chu, Riguang Zhang, Giuliano Giambastiani, Yuefeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Hydroxide Growth over Nickel&#8211;Iron Phosphide with Enhanced Overall Water Splitting Performances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402881</link>
      <description>Jian Hu, Jinwei Yin, Aoyuan Peng, Dishu Zeng, Jia-Hong Ke, Jilei Liu, Kaifeng Guo, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400361332

                Abstract In this work, three dimensional (3D) self&#8208;supported Ni&#8208;FeOH@Ni&#8208;FeP needle arrays with core&#8208;shell heterojunction structure are fabricated via in situ hydroxide growth over Ni&#8208;FeP surface. The as&#8208;prepared electrodes show an outstanding oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, only requiring the low overpotential of 232 mV to reach 200 mA cm &#8722;2 with the Tafel slop of 40 mV dec &#8722;1 . For overall water splitting, an alkaline electrolyzer with these electrodes only requires a cell voltage of 2.14 V to reach 1 A cm &#8722;2 . Mechanistic investigations for such excellent electrocatalytic performances are utilized by in situ Raman spectroscopy in conjunction with density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The computation results present that Ni&#8208;FeOH@Ni&#8208;FeP attains better intrinsic conductivity and the D&#8208;band center (close to that of the ideal catalyst), thus giving superior excellent catalytic performances. Likewise, the surface Ni&#8208;FeOH layer can improve the structural stability of Ni&#8208;FeP cores and attenuate the eventual formation of irreversible FeOOH products. More importantly, the appearance of FeOOH intermediates can effectively decrease the energy barrier of NiOOH intermediates, and then rapidly accelerate the sluggish reaction dynamics, as well as further enhance the electrocatalytic activities, reversibility and cycling stability.</description>
      <author>Jian Hu, Jinwei Yin, Aoyuan Peng, Dishu Zeng, Jia-Hong Ke, Jilei Liu, Kaifeng Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pserformance Enhancement of Rechargeable Zinc-Air Battery through Synergistic Ex-solution of Multi-component Pt/CoWO4-x Nanofiber in Hybrid Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124371</link>
      <description>Chang&#8208;Ho Lee, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Jaewook An, Ji&#8208;Soo Jang, Bonjae Koo, Jong Min Kim, Kihyun Shin, Lee C, Ki Ro Yoon, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400363166

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang&#8208;Ho Lee, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Jaewook An, Ji&#8208;Soo Jang, Bonjae Koo, Jong Min Kim, Kihyun Shin, Lee C, Ki Ro Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Construction of Interfacial Akagan&#233;ite FeOOH Phase to Enable the Long&#8208;Term Stability of Nickel&#8208;Iron Hydroxides for Seawater Splitting at Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407781</link>
      <description>Z.X. Liu, Yuanyuan Li, Libin Zeng, Xiaofeng Peng, Dashuai Wang, Zhongjian Li, Boguang Yang, Yuanyuan Li, Lecheng Lei, Yang Hou, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400365766

                Abstract NiFe&#8208;based hydroxides are well&#8208;established as efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline purified water. However, they usually degrade rapidly in seawater electrolysis because of concentrated Cl &#8722; anions in seawater. In this work, a facile approach utilizing an ultrafast dipping method is presented to fabricate durable and scalable NiFe hydroxides, enhanced by interfacial akagan&#233;ite FeOOH for seawater splitting. This study reveals significantly improved electrocatalytic stability of NiFe hydroxides at an ampere&#8208;level current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for 100 h in alkaline seawater. It is realized by the formed FeOOH in a specific akagan&#233;ite phase whose lattice tunnels are well filled by intrinsic Cl &#8722; anions, that serve to electrostatically repel corrosive chlorides in electrolyte. This anionic design also provides superior corrosion protection for other active metal&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts when deployed in alkaline purified water and allows for facile scaling up of the anode, facilitating the practical utilization for seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Z.X. Liu, Yuanyuan Li, Libin Zeng, Xiaofeng Peng, Dashuai Wang, Zhongjian Li, Boguang Yang, Yuanyuan Li, Lecheng Lei, Yang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reconstruction of Pt(001) Surface and the Shell&#8208;Like Reconstruction of the Vicinal Pt(001) Surfaces Revealed by Neural Network Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404274</link>
      <description>Cheng Qian, Daniel Hedman, Pai Li, Sung Youb Kim, Feng Ding, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400366058

                Abstract In this work, a highly accurate neural network potential (NNP) is presented, named Pt NNP , and the exploration of the reconstruction of the Pt(001) surface and its vicinal surfaces with it. Contrary to the most accepted understanding of the Pt(001) surface reconstruction, the study reveals that the main driving force behind Pt(001) quasi&#8208;hexagonal reconstruction is not the surface stress relaxation but the increased coordination number of the surface atoms resulting in stronger intralayer binding in the reconstructed surface layer. In agreement with experimental observations, the optimized supercell size of the reconstructed Pt(001) surface contains (5 &#215; 20) unit cells. Surprisingly, the reconstruction of the vicinal Pt(001) surfaces leads to a smooth shell&#8208;like surface layer covering the whole surface and diminishing sharp step edges.</description>
      <author>Cheng Qian, Daniel Hedman, Pai Li, Sung Youb Kim, Feng Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing photoelectrocatalytic water splitting performance through PdCoP co-modification of Ti:Fe2O3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.336</link>
      <description>Penghui Bai, Juan Xie, Hu Wang, Xiaolan Kang, Ke Jiang, Chen Yang, Xia Wang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 79(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400366739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Penghui Bai, Juan Xie, Hu Wang, Xiaolan Kang, Ke Jiang, Chen Yang, Xia Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-engineered ruthenium oxide on titanium oxide oxygen evolution electrocatalysts for proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124382</link>
      <description>Hyung&#8208;Koo Yoon, Hee Jo Song, Ji Seong Hyoung, Sang Won Jung, Andi Haryanto, Chan Woo Lee, Dong&#8208;Wan Kim, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400381918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyung&#8208;Koo Yoon, Hee Jo Song, Ji Seong Hyoung, Sang Won Jung, Andi Haryanto, Chan Woo Lee, Dong&#8208;Wan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First and Second Reductions in an Aprotic Solvent: Comparing Computational and Experimental One-Electron Reduction Potentials for 345 Quinones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00602</link>
      <description>Sarah Elhajj, Samer Gozem, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400382975

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarah Elhajj, Samer Gozem</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using ethanol and isopropanol as biomass model compounds for understanding bond scission mechanisms over Cu/Mo2N catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124362</link>
      <description>William N. Porter, Wenjie Liao, Marcus Yu, Yong Yuan, Zhexi Lin, Ping Liu, Kuan Chang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400388059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>William N. Porter, Wenjie Liao, Marcus Yu, Yong Yuan, Zhexi Lin, Ping Liu, Kuan Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XtalOpt Version 13: Multi-Objective Evolutionary Search for Novel Functional Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109306</link>
      <description>Samad Hajinazar, Eva Zurek, Computer physics communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400392210

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samad Hajinazar, Eva Zurek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset for quantum-mechanical exploration of conformers and solvent effects in large drug-like molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03521-8</link>
      <description>Leonardo Medrano Sandonas, Dries Van Rompaey, Alessio Fallani, Mathias Hilfiker, David F. Hahn, Laura P&#233;rez&#8208;Benito, Jonas Verhoeven, Gary Tresadern, J&#246;rg K. Wegner, Hugo Ceulemans, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Scientific data. 11(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400396982

                Abstract We here introduce the Aquamarine (AQM) dataset, an extensive quantum-mechanical (QM) dataset that contains the structural and electronic information of 59,783 low-and high-energy conformers of 1,653 molecules with a total number of atoms ranging from 2 to 92 (mean: 50.9), and containing up to 54 (mean: 28.2) non-hydrogen atoms. To gain insights into the solvent effects as well as collective dispersion interactions for drug-like molecules, we have performed QM calculations supplemented with a treatment of many-body dispersion (MBD) interactions of structures and properties in the gas phase and implicit water. Thus, AQM contains over 40 global and local physicochemical properties (including ground-state and response properties) per conformer computed at the tightly converged PBE0+MBD level of theory for gas-phase molecules, whereas PBE0+MBD with the modified Poisson-Boltzmann (MPB) model of water was used for solvated molecules. By addressing both molecule-solvent and dispersion interactions, AQM dataset can serve as a challenging benchmark for state-of-the-art machine learning methods for property modeling and de novo generation of large (solvated) molecules with pharmaceutical and biological relevance.</description>
      <author>Leonardo Medrano Sandonas, Dries Van Rompaey, Alessio Fallani, Mathias Hilfiker, David F. Hahn, Laura P&#233;rez&#8208;Benito, Jonas Verhoeven, Gary Tresadern, J&#246;rg K. Wegner, Hugo Ceulemans, Alexandre Tkatchenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03521-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrocatalytic nitrate-to-ammonia of single Fe active sites via coordination engineering: From theory to experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.055</link>
      <description>Heying Li, Xinyang Liu, Ziwang Kan, Song Liu, Jingxiang Zhao, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400398824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Heying Li, Xinyang Liu, Ziwang Kan, Song Liu, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron distribution regulating of nonmetal doped monolayer g-GaN for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160683</link>
      <description>Yafei Zhao, Liang He, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400398871

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yafei Zhao, Liang He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the Performance and Modification Mechanism of Gutta-Percha-Modified Asphalt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16131860</link>
      <description>Simeng Yan, Shichao Cui, Ning Guo, Zhaoyang Chu, Jun Zhang, Sitong Yan, Xin Jin, Polymers. 16(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400211097

                Presently, there is a significant focus on the investigation and advancement of polymer-modified asphalt that is both high-performing and environmentally sustainable. This study thoroughly examined the performance and modification mechanism of gutta-percha (GP) as a novel asphalt modifier. The investigation was conducted using a combination of macro- and microscopic testing, as well as molecular dynamics simulations. This work primarily examined the compatibility of GP with asphalt molecular modeling. This paper used molecular dynamics to identify the most suitable mixing temperature. Next, the gray correlation theory was used to discuss the most effective method for preparing gutta-percha-modified asphalt (GPMA). The macro-rheological tests and microscopic performance analysis provided a full understanding of the impact of GP on asphalt properties and the process of alteration. The findings indicate that eucommia ulmoides gum (EUG) exhibits good compatibility with asphalt, while sulfur-vulcanized eucommia ulmoides gum (SEUG) does not demonstrate compatibility with asphalt. Both EUG and SEUG enhance the thermal stability and resistance to deformation of asphalt at high temperatures, with SEUG having a particularly notable effect. However, both additives do not improve the resistance of asphalt to cracking at low temperatures. The manufacturing method for EUG-modified asphalt (EUGMA) involves physical mixing, whereas sulfur-vulcanized eucommia ulmoides gum-modified asphalt (SEUGMA) involves physical mixing together with certain chemical processes. This research establishes a theoretical foundation for the advancement of GP as a novel environmentally friendly and highly effective asphalt modification.</description>
      <author>Simeng Yan, Shichao Cui, Ning Guo, Zhaoyang Chu, Jun Zhang, Sitong Yan, Xin Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16131860</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
