<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 01:25:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped Ni-Based Catalysts Surpass Ir-Baselines for Oxygen Evolution Due to Optimal Charge-Transfer Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</link>
      <description>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Assess and Predict Electrical Double Layer Properties. Implications for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00806</link>
      <description>Christian M. Schott, Peter M. Schneider, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Haiting Yu, Rainer G&#246;tz, Felix Haimerl, Elena L. Gubanova, Jian Zhou, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Qi&#8208;Wei Zhang, Vitaly Alexandrov, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404238022

                The electrical double layer (EDL) plays a central role in electrochemical energy systems, impacting charge transfer mechanisms and reaction rates. The fundamental importance of the EDL in interfacial electrochemistry has motivated researchers to develop theoretical and experimental approaches to assess EDL properties. In this contribution, we review recent progress in evaluating EDL characteristics such as the double-layer capacitance, highlighting some discrepancies between theory and experiment and discussing strategies for their reconciliation. We further discuss the merits and challenges of various experimental techniques and theoretical approaches having important implications for aqueous electrocatalysis. A strong emphasis is placed on the substantial impact of the electrode composition and structure and the electrolyte chemistry on the double-layer properties. In addition, we review the effects of temperature and pressure and compare solid-liquid interfaces to solid-solid interfaces.</description>
      <author>Christian M. Schott, Peter M. Schneider, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Haiting Yu, Rainer G&#246;tz, Felix Haimerl, Elena L. Gubanova, Jian Zhou, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Qi&#8208;Wei Zhang, Vitaly Alexandrov, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Co Doping on Copper Nanoclusters for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07514</link>
      <description>Guilherme Rodrigues do Nascimento, Marionir M. C. B. Neto, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404238489

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guilherme Rodrigues do Nascimento, Marionir M. C. B. Neto, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-Learning-Assisted Screening of Nanocluster Electrocatalysts: Mapping and Reshaping the Activity Volcano for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14076</link>
      <description>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Milan Kumar Jena, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404241066

                In computational heterogeneous catalysis, Sabatier's principle-based activity volcano plots provide an intuitive guide to catalyst design but impose a fundamental constraint on the maximum achievable catalytic performance. Recently, subnano clusters have emerged as an exciting platform, offering high noble metal utilization and superior performance for various reactions compared to extended surfaces, reflecting a complex structure-activity relationship in the non-scalable regime. However, understanding their non-monotonic catalytic activity, attributed to the large configurational space and their fluxional identity, poses a formidable challenge. Here, we present a machine learning (ML) framework that captures the non-monotonic trends in oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity at the subnanometer scale, attributed to their dynamic fluxional characteristics. We demonstrate a size-dependent shifting and reshaping of the ORR activity volcano, with Au replacing Pt at the peak. Leveraging only upon the non-</description>
      <author>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Milan Kumar Jena, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplification of solvation shell with water clusters in the simulation of electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0230137</link>
      <description>Hanxuan Liu, Zheng&#8208;Qing Huang, Xin Gao, Guidong Yang, Chun&#8208;Ran Chang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404244919

                Electrochemical methods for nitrogen reduction have received extensive attention due to the mild reaction conditions. In order to gain an insight into the mechanism of the electrochemical nitrogen reduction process, theoretical simulations are necessary. However, current simulation studies contain many imprecise approximations that may hinder the real recognition of the reaction process. Although solvation methods have recently been developed to provide efficient descriptions, their further applications are hindered by controversy over modeling of solvents and the enormous computational effort required. In this work, we simplify the solvation conditions by using water clusters and compare them with an accurate water layer model. The results demonstrate that the simplified water clusters can effectively capture protons, simulate the surface electric environment, and enable the calculation of the activation energy of the reaction. This method offers an affordable approach for simulating the surface potentials and solvents and provides a new reference for the theoretical study of the electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction.</description>
      <author>Hanxuan Liu, Zheng&#8208;Qing Huang, Xin Gao, Guidong Yang, Chun&#8208;Ran Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0230137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular level insights on the pulsed electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54122-3</link>
      <description>Ke Ye, Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Hyun Dong Jung, Peng Shen, So Min Jang, Zhe Weng, Seoin Back, Wen&#8208;Bin Cai, Kun Jiang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404252638

                Electrochemical CO</description>
      <author>Ke Ye, Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Hyun Dong Jung, Peng Shen, So Min Jang, Zhe Weng, Seoin Back, Wen&#8208;Bin Cai, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54122-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Hidden Catalytic Sites in 2D Basal Plane via p&#8211;n Heterojunction Interface Engineering Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403722</link>
      <description>Eugene Kim, Sungsoon Kim, Yong&#8208;Chul Kim, Kiran Hamkins, Jihyun Baek, MinJoong Kim, Tae&#8208;Kyung Liu, Young Moon Choi, Jung Hwan Lee, Gyu Yong Jang, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Geunsik Lee, Xiaolin Zheng, Jong Hyeok Park, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404255224

                Abstract Nonprecious metal&#8208;based 2D materials have shown promising electrocatalytic activity toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the catalytically active sites of 2D materials are mainly presented at the edge, and most of their basal planes are still catalytically inactive, which turns into a significant drawback on the catalytic efficiency. Here, a novel p&#8211;n heterojunction strategy is suggested that generates active sites on the basal plane of 2D NiFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH). The n&#8208;type NiFe&#8208;LDH is first grown on a nickel foam (NF) substrate, and p&#8208;type Co 3 O 4 nanocubes are deposited through a simple dip&#8208;coating method to fabricate a Co 3 O 4 /NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF p&#8211;n heterojunction electrode. As a result, electron transfer is induced at the interface of p&#8208;type Co 3 O 4 and n&#8208;type NiFe&#8208;LDH, which consequently promotes oxidation of the inert Ni 2+ state to a more catalytically active Ni 3+ state on the inert basal plane of NiFe&#8208;LDH. As&#8208;prepared Co 3 O 4 /NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF electrodes obtained enhanced OER performance showing a high current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.48 V (vs RHE) which outperforms that of pristine NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF. The utilization of the p&#8211;n junction concept will disclose a new strategy for modifying the electronic structure of the catalytically inactive basal plane and stimulating its electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Eugene Kim, Sungsoon Kim, Yong&#8208;Chul Kim, Kiran Hamkins, Jihyun Baek, MinJoong Kim, Tae&#8208;Kyung Liu, Young Moon Choi, Jung Hwan Lee, Gyu Yong Jang, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Geunsik Lee, Xiaolin Zheng, Jong Hyeok Park</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A general machine-learning framework for high-throughput screening for stable and efficient RuO2-based acidic oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5347326/v1</link>
      <description>Zhe Shang, Qian Dang, Sheng Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404257326

                Abstract Doping guest elements is an effective way to increase activity and stability of RuO2 catalysts in acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, due to the vastness of doping space, it is challenging for either high-cost experiments or density functional theory (DFT) calculations to screen out the doped structures with the optimized catalytic performance. Herein, we reported a machine-learning (ML) framework that aims to realize high-throughput screening for both stability and activity of doped-RuO2 acidic OER catalysts from mono-doping to triple-doping at a low level of computational cost. Compared to the d-band theory and some other previous models, our ML model was constructed based on more general input features and realized higher prediction accuracy with mean absolute errors (MAEs) of 0.074, 0.142 and 0.082 eV for *OH, *O and *OOH adsorption, respectively. Through the ML models, three doping structures, Ru41Zn7O96, Ru41Zn4Fe3O96, and Ru39Zn4Cu4Co1O96 were found to possess the extraordinarily high stability and comparable or higher activity than the previously reported OER catalysts. This work provided an efficient study paradigm in fields of material screening and a useful guide for experimental synthesis.</description>
      <author>Zhe Shang, Qian Dang, Sheng Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5347326/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Synergistic Multifunctional Electrocatalysis of N-Doped Graphene/WS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure with Single-Atom Catalysts for Water Splitting and Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16119</link>
      <description>Deepak Arumugam, Divyakaaviri Subramani, Akilesh Muralidharan, R. Shankar, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404257452

                As the demand for sustainable energy continues to rise, electrocatalysis has become increasingly prominent in the advancement of clean energy technologies. By scrutinizing the material to function as a multifunctional catalyst, the effectiveness of energy conversion processes is significantly enhanced. This study focuses on harnessing graphene/WS</description>
      <author>Deepak Arumugam, Divyakaaviri Subramani, Akilesh Muralidharan, R. Shankar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution activity by two-dimensional van der Waals AlSb/ZnO heterostructure: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105397</link>
      <description>Aroni Ghosh, Ahmed Zubair, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404258858

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aroni Ghosh, Ahmed Zubair</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wear Resistance of N-Doped CoCrFeNiMn High Entropy Alloy Coating on the Ti-6Al-4V Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11666-024-01864-7</link>
      <description>Minhui Yang, J.L. Xu, J.C. Huang, L. W. Zhang, Jiawei Luo, Journal of Thermal Spray Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404259216

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minhui Yang, J.L. Xu, J.C. Huang, L. W. Zhang, Jiawei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11666-024-01864-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty Based Machine Learning-DFT Hybrid Framework for Accelerating Geometry Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00953</link>
      <description>Akksay Singh, Jiaqi Wang, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404259391

                Geometry optimization is an important tool used for computational simulations in the fields of chemistry, physics, and material science. Developing more efficient and reliable algorithms to reduce the number of force evaluations would lead to accelerated computational modeling and materials discovery. Here, we present a delta method-based neural network-density functional theory (DFT) hybrid optimizer to improve the computational efficiency of geometry optimization. Compared to previous active learning approaches, our algorithm adds two key features: a modified delta method incorporating force information to enhance efficiency in uncertainty estimation, and a quasi-Newton approach based upon a Hessian matrix calculated from the neural network; the later improving stability of optimization near critical points. We benchmarked our optimizer against commonly used optimization algorithms using systems including bulk metal, metal surface, metal hydride, and an oxide cluster. The results demonstrate that our optimizer effectively reduces the number of DFT force calls by 2-3 times in all test systems.</description>
      <author>Akksay Singh, Jiaqi Wang, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-Driven Coordinated Oxygen Migration in an Electrocatalyst for Sustainable H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11307</link>
      <description>Zhiping Deng, Song Jin, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Min Ho Seo, Xiaolei Wang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404276344

                Local coordination environment (LCE) manipulation has emerged as a significant approach for modulating the electrocatalytic behavior of low-dimensional nanomaterials. However, challenges persist in accurately identifying active sites and understanding dynamic changes during operation. Here, we underscore the influence of LCE on the electrochemical production of H</description>
      <author>Zhiping Deng, Song Jin, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Min Ho Seo, Xiaolei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Ferroelectricity and Photocatalytic Performance in Wurtzite Zn2VN3: A Novel Approach for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110972</link>
      <description>Liting Niu, Huakai Xu, Guo-Xia Lai, Zi-Xuan Chen, Ya-Yi Tian, Xiang-Fu Xu, Xiaodong Yang, Weiling Zhu, Xing-Yuan Chen, Lijuan Chen, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404277101

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liting Niu, Huakai Xu, Guo-Xia Lai, Zi-Xuan Chen, Ya-Yi Tian, Xiang-Fu Xu, Xiaodong Yang, Weiling Zhu, Xing-Yuan Chen, Lijuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron energy loss spectra and exciton band structure of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;WSe&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; monolayers studied by &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; Bethe-Salpeter equation calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.205417</link>
      <description>Y. C. Shih, Fredrik Nilsson, Guang&#8208;Yu Guo, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404280760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y. C. Shih, Fredrik Nilsson, Guang&#8208;Yu Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.205417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the mysteries of hydrogen spillover phenomenon in hydrogen evolution reaction: Fundamentals, evidence and enhancement strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216321</link>
      <description>Shan Zhao, Zhenhong Wang, Jingyu Wang, Pengfei Wang, Zonglin Liu, Jie Shu, Ting&#8208;Feng Yi, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 524(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404281882

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Zhao, Zhenhong Wang, Jingyu Wang, Pengfei Wang, Zonglin Liu, Jie Shu, Ting&#8208;Feng Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopically Elucidating the Local Proton-Coupled Electron Transfer Loop from Amino to Nitro Groups via the Au Surface in a N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c04579</link>
      <description>Yang Lu, Yifan Huang, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404282266

                Proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) has been significant in understanding the reactions in solution. In a solid-gas interface, it remains a challenge to identify electron transfer or proton transfer intermediates. Here, in a Au/N</description>
      <author>Yang Lu, Yifan Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c04579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning aided design of high performance copper-based sulfide photocathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06128d</link>
      <description>Yuxi Cao, Keng Shen, Yuanfei Li, F. Lan, Zeyu Guo, K. H. Zhang, Kang Wang, Feng Jiang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404282816

                With the help of machine learning algorithms, we developed software that can predict the performance of copper-based sulfide photocathodes and this system shows excellent accuracy of up to 96%.</description>
      <author>Yuxi Cao, Keng Shen, Yuanfei Li, F. Lan, Zeyu Guo, K. H. Zhang, Kang Wang, Feng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06128d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the catalytic performance of carbon nitrides for overall water splitting by tuning the C/N ratio: A theoretical investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141750</link>
      <description>Afshan Mohajeri, Fatemeh Ansari, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404291995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Afshan Mohajeri, Fatemeh Ansari</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into the essential role of weak interactions in the electrocatalytic reduction of nitrobenzene: Ag-anchored graphene electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112513</link>
      <description>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Lixin Ye, Weihua Zhu, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404293862

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Lixin Ye, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Topological Platinum Telluride Superstructures with Periodic Tellurium Vacancies for Efficient and Robust Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c10085</link>
      <description>Xin Xu, Sheng Wang, Shuming Yu, Chenhui Wang, Guowei Liu, Hao Li, Jiangang Yang, Jing Li, Tao Sun, Xiao Hai, Lei Li, Xue Liu, Ying Zhang, Weifeng Zhang, Quan Zhang, Kedong Wang, Nan Xu, Yaping Ma, Fangfei Ming, Ping Cui, Jiong Lu, Zhenyu Zhang, Xudong Xiao, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404297417

                Defect engineering in the inherently inert basal planes of transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs), involving the introduction of chalcogen vacancies, represents a pivotal approach to enhance catalytic activity by exposing high-density catalytic metal single-atom sites. However, achieving a single-atom limit spacing between chalcogen vacancies to form ordered superstructures remains challenging for creating uniformly distributed high-density metal single-atom sites on TMDs comparable to carbon-supported single-atom catalysts (SACs). Here we unveil an efficient TMD-based topological catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), featuring high-density single-atom reactive centers on a few-layer (7 &#215; 7)-PtTe</description>
      <author>Xin Xu, Sheng Wang, Shuming Yu, Chenhui Wang, Guowei Liu, Hao Li, Jiangang Yang, Jing Li, Tao Sun, Xiao Hai, Lei Li, Xue Liu, Ying Zhang, Weifeng Zhang, Quan Zhang, Kedong Wang, Nan Xu, Yaping Ma, Fangfei Ming, Ping Cui, Jiong Lu, Zhenyu Zhang, Xudong Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c10085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparison of Modern Solvation Models for Oxygen Reduction at the Pt(111) Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04924</link>
      <description>Tom Demeyere, Chris&#8208;Kriton Skylaris, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404299800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tom Demeyere, Chris&#8208;Kriton Skylaris</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Ultrafast Energy Transfer Pathways in Energetic Materials: Time-Dependent and Quantum State-Resolved</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00775</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Jitai Yang, Gangbei Zhu, Jiarui Li, You Li, Yu Zhai, Hua-Jie Song, Yanqiang Yang, Hui Li, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404302254

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Jitai Yang, Gangbei Zhu, Jiarui Li, You Li, Yu Zhai, Hua-Jie Song, Yanqiang Yang, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward first principles-based simulations of dense hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219405</link>
      <description>M. B&#246;nitz, Jan Vorberger, Mandy Bethkenhagen, Maximilian B&#246;hme, David M. Ceperley, A. Filinov, Thomas Gawne, Frank Graziani, G. Gregori, Paul Hamann, Stephanie B. Hansen, Markus Holzmann, S. X. Hu, H. K&#228;hlert, Valentin V. Karasiev, Uwe Kleinschmidt, Linda Kordts, Christopher Makait, Burkhard Militzer, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Carlo Pierleoni, Martin Preising, Kushal Ramakrishna, R. Redmer, Sebastian Schwalbe, Pontus Svensson, Tobias Dornheim, Physics of Plasmas. 31(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404306208

                Accurate knowledge of the properties of hydrogen at high compression is crucial for astrophysics (e.g., planetary and stellar interiors, brown dwarfs, atmosphere of compact stars) and laboratory experiments, including inertial confinement fusion. There exists experimental data for the equation of state, conductivity, and Thomson scattering spectra. However, the analysis of the measurements at extreme pressures and temperatures typically involves additional model assumptions, which makes it difficult to assess the accuracy of the experimental data rigorously. On the other hand, theory and modeling have produced extensive collections of data. They originate from a very large variety of models and simulations including path integral Monte Carlo (PIMC) simulations, density functional theory (DFT), chemical models, machine-learned models, and combinations thereof. At the same time, each of these methods has fundamental limitations (fermion sign problem in PIMC, approximate exchange&#8211;correlation functionals of DFT, inconsistent interaction energy contributions in chemical models, etc.), so for some parameter ranges accurate predictions are difficult. Recently, a number of breakthroughs in first principles PIMC as well as in DFT simulations were achieved which are discussed in this review. Here we use these results to benchmark different simulation methods. We present an update of the hydrogen phase diagram at high pressures, the expected phase transitions, and thermodynamic properties including the equation of state and momentum distribution. Furthermore, we discuss available dynamic results for warm dense hydrogen, including the conductivity, dynamic structure factor, plasmon dispersion, imaginary-time structure, and density response functions. We conclude by outlining strategies to combine different simulations to achieve accurate theoretical predictions that are based on first principles.</description>
      <author>M. B&#246;nitz, Jan Vorberger, Mandy Bethkenhagen, Maximilian B&#246;hme, David M. Ceperley, A. Filinov, Thomas Gawne, Frank Graziani, G. Gregori, Paul Hamann, Stephanie B. Hansen, Markus Holzmann, S. X. Hu, H. K&#228;hlert, Valentin V. Karasiev, Uwe Kleinschmidt, Linda Kordts, Christopher Makait, Burkhard Militzer, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Carlo Pierleoni, Martin Preising, Kushal Ramakrishna, R. Redmer, Sebastian Schwalbe, Pontus Svensson, Tobias Dornheim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Surface Functionalization of Exfoliated MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets for Improved Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05965</link>
      <description>Leandro Hostert, Matheus Santos Dias, Caroline B. de Aquino, F. Santos, Val&#233;ria S. Marangoni, Cec&#237;lia de Carvalho Castro Silva, Leandro Seixas, Camila M. Maroneze, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404308961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leandro Hostert, Matheus Santos Dias, Caroline B. de Aquino, F. Santos, Val&#233;ria S. Marangoni, Cec&#237;lia de Carvalho Castro Silva, Leandro Seixas, Camila M. Maroneze</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Potential-Dependent Kinetics for the Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CO over Ti@4N-Gr</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00073</link>
      <description>Yousef A. Alsunni, Abdulaziz Alherz, Charles B. Musgrave, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404317122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yousef A. Alsunni, Abdulaziz Alherz, Charles B. Musgrave</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Catalytic Activity of MXene Nanosheet Supported on CuFeO2 Nanoparticles Applied on Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.11.181</link>
      <description>Zhen-Yuan Lan, Dhanapal Vasu, Yung&#8208;Chieh Liu, Chung&#8208;Lun Yu, Te&#8208;Wei Chiu, Tetsu Yonezawa, Hongbing Jia, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404318336

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhen-Yuan Lan, Dhanapal Vasu, Yung&#8208;Chieh Liu, Chung&#8208;Lun Yu, Te&#8208;Wei Chiu, Tetsu Yonezawa, Hongbing Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.11.181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards superior CO2RR catalysts: Deciphering the selectivity puzzle over dual-atom catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.080</link>
      <description>Jia Zhao, Sen Lin, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404319061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Zhao, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Based Layered Perovskite Oxyfluoride Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution: Insights from Crystal Facets with Heteroanionic Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05740</link>
      <description>Ryusuke Mizuochi, Yuuki Sugawara, Kengo Oka, Yoshiyuki Inaguma, Shunsuke Nozawa, Toshiyuki Yokoi, Takeo Yamaguchi, Kazuhiko Maeda, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404320100

                Mixed-anion compounds have recently attracted attention as solid-state materials that exhibit properties unattainable with those of their single-anion counterparts. However, the use of mixed-anion compounds to control the morphology and engineer the crystal facets of electrocatalysts has been limited because their synthesis method is still immature. This study explored the electrocatalytic properties of a Pb-Fe oxyfluoride, Pb</description>
      <author>Ryusuke Mizuochi, Yuuki Sugawara, Kengo Oka, Yoshiyuki Inaguma, Shunsuke Nozawa, Toshiyuki Yokoi, Takeo Yamaguchi, Kazuhiko Maeda</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafine Ruthenium Nanoparticles Anchored on S,N-Codoped Carbon Nanofibers for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Electricity Coproduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07973</link>
      <description>Yaxin Lai, Lvlv Ji, Jianying Wang, Jiangnan Shen, Junbin Liao, Xiaoyang He, Li Wang, Zuofeng Chen, Li Wang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404320510

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaxin Lai, Lvlv Ji, Jianying Wang, Jiangnan Shen, Junbin Liao, Xiaoyang He, Li Wang, Zuofeng Chen, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual active site pathways in cobalt-based bimetallic catalysts enhance oxygen evolution reaction activity: Density functional theory studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105428</link>
      <description>Zeliang Ju, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Chengfeng Yin, Qingxin Kang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404321196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeliang Ju, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Chengfeng Yin, Qingxin Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of the Conceptual and Functional Factors Affecting the Effectiveness of Proton-Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering8060116</link>
      <description>Gaydaa Al Zohbi, ChemEngineering. 8(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404322371

                Hydrogen has the potential to decarbonize the energy and industrial sectors in the future, mainly if it is generated by water electrolysis. The proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) system is regarded as a propitious technology to produce green hydrogen from water using power supplied by renewable energy sources. It offers many benefits, such as high performance, high proton conductibility, quick response, compact size, and low working temperature. Many conceptual and functional parameters influence the effectiveness of PEM, including temperature, pressure of anode and cathode regions, water content and wideness of the layer, and cathode and anode exchange current density. In addition, the anodic half-reaction (known as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER)) and cathodic half-reaction (known as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)) perform an important function in the development of PEMWE. The current study aims to present these parameters and discuss their impacts on the performance of PEM. Also, the PEM efficiency is presented. The different methods used to enhance the scattering of OER electrocatalysts and minimize catalyst loading to minimize the price of PEMWE are also highlighted. Moreover, the alternative noble metals that could be used as electrocatalysts in HER and OER to minimize the cost of PEM are reviewed and presented.</description>
      <author>Gaydaa Al Zohbi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering8060116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potassium and Boron Co-Doping of g-C3N4 Tuned CO2 Reduction Mechanism for Enhanced Photocatalytic Performance: A First-Principles Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225339</link>
      <description>Gang Fu, Wenqing Zhen, Hongyi Wang, Xin Zhou, Li Yang, Jiaxu Zhang, Molecules. 29(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404331595

                Graphitic phase carbon nitride (g-C3N4, abbreviated as CN) can be used as a photocatalyst to reduce the concentration of atmospheric carbon dioxide. However, there is still potential for improvement in the small band gap and carrier migration properties of intrinsic materials. K-B co-doped CN (KBCN) was investigated as a promising photocatalyst for carbon dioxide reduction via the Density Functional Theory (DFT) method. The electronic and optical properties of CN and KBCN indicate that doping K and B can improve the catalytic performance of CN by promoting charge migration and separation. In terms of the Gibbs free energy change, the CO2 reduction reaction catalysed by KBCN results in CH3OH, and its optimal pathway is CO2 &#8594; *CO2 &#8594; *COOH &#8594; CO &#8594; *OCH &#8594; HCHO &#8594; *OCH3 &#8594; CH3OH. Compared with CN, the doping elements K and B shift the rate-determining step from CO2 &#8594; *CO2 to *CO2 &#8594; *COOH. The K and B elements co-doping tuned the charge distribution between the catalyst and the adsorbate and reduced the Gibbs free energy of the rate-determining step from 1.571 to 0.861 eV, suggesting that the CO2 reduction activity of KBCN is superior to that of CN. Our work provides useful insights for the design of metallic&#8211;nonmetallic co-doped CN for photocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2PR) reactions.</description>
      <author>Gang Fu, Wenqing Zhen, Hongyi Wang, Xin Zhou, Li Yang, Jiaxu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT modeling of the oxygen electroreduction reaction on SiN3-doped carbon nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044460x24050123</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1079;&#1100;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1046;&#1091;&#1088;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083; &#1054;&#1073;&#1097;&#1077;&#1081; &#1061;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1080;. 94(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404337748

                The thermodynamic features and mechanism of the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction were studied using the revPBE0-D3(BJ)/Def2-TZVP method on the example of (6,6)-armchair carbon nanotube doped with a tricoordinated silicon atom and nitrogen atoms of pyridinic and graphitic nature. Irreversible oxidation of the silicon center as a result of the formation of stable oxygen-containing adsorbates was shown. It was found that Si-poisoned structures are capable of participating in the catalysis of the target reaction along two- and four-electron routes at high overpotentials. For a nanotube doped simultaneously with pyridinic and graphitic nitrogens the potential possibility of eliminating the silicon atom from the catalyst composition in the form of orthosilicic acid and the participation of a silicon-free nitrogen-doped framework in the oxygen electroreduction reaction, for which the stage of tautomerization of pyridin-2(1H)-one to pyridin-2-ol is the limiting step was shown.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1079;&#1100;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044460x24050123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen radical-boosted electrocatalytic CO2 reduction using Ni-partnered heteroatomic pairs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53529-2</link>
      <description>Zhibo Yao, Hao Cheng, Yifei Xu, Xinyu Zhan, Song Hong, Xinyi Tan, Tai&#8208;Sing Wu, Pei Xiong, Y. L. Soo, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Leiduan Hao, Liang Xu, Alex W. Robertson, Bingjun Xu, Ming Yang, Zhenyu Sun, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404348913

                The electrocatalytic reduction of CO</description>
      <author>Zhibo Yao, Hao Cheng, Yifei Xu, Xinyu Zhan, Song Hong, Xinyi Tan, Tai&#8208;Sing Wu, Pei Xiong, Y. L. Soo, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Leiduan Hao, Liang Xu, Alex W. Robertson, Bingjun Xu, Ming Yang, Zhenyu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53529-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput framework for lattice dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01437-w</link>
      <description>Zhuoying Zhu, Junsoo Park, Hrushikesh Sahasrabuddhe, Alex M. Ganose, Rees Chang, John W. Lawson, Anubhav Jain, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404351163

                Abstract We develop an automated high-throughput workflow for calculating lattice dynamical properties from first principles including those dictated by anharmonicity. The pipeline automatically computes interatomic force constants (IFCs) up to 4th order from perturbed training supercells, and uses the IFCs to calculate lattice thermal conductivity, coefficient of thermal expansion, and vibrational free energy and entropy. It performs phonon renormalization for dynamically unstable compounds to obtain real effective phonon spectra at finite temperatures and calculates the associated free energy corrections. The methods and parameters are chosen to balance computational efficiency and result accuracy, assessed through convergence testing and comparisons with experimental measurements. Deployment of this workflow at a large scale would facilitate materials discovery efforts toward functionalities including thermoelectrics, contact materials, ferroelectrics, aerospace components, as well as general phase diagram construction.</description>
      <author>Zhuoying Zhu, Junsoo Park, Hrushikesh Sahasrabuddhe, Alex M. Ganose, Rees Chang, John W. Lawson, Anubhav Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01437-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable production of high-performance electrocatalysts for electrochemical water splitting at large current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100334</link>
      <description>Zichen Xu, Zhong&#8208;Shuai Wu, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404353371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zichen Xu, Zhong&#8208;Shuai Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage (CCUS) projects on environmental protection, economic development, and social equity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144218</link>
      <description>Xiaoning Su, Pengfe&#239; Liu, Yingdan Mei, Jixiang Qiu, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404353449

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoning Su, Pengfe&#239; Liu, Yingdan Mei, Jixiang Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of Transition Metal-Nitrogen-Carbon Materials as Electrocatalysts for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145357</link>
      <description>Megan C. Davis, Wilton J. M. Kort-Kamp, Edward F. Holby, Piotr Zelenay, Ivana Matanovi&#263;, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404357011

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Megan C. Davis, Wilton J. M. Kort-Kamp, Edward F. Holby, Piotr Zelenay, Ivana Matanovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential dependence in electrocatalysis: a theoretical perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2402-2</link>
      <description>Leyu Liu, Zhaoming Xia, Zeyu Wang, Yinjuan Chen, Hai Xiao, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404373403

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leyu Liu, Zhaoming Xia, Zeyu Wang, Yinjuan Chen, Hai Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2402-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metals Doped into g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; via N,O Coordination as Efficient Electrocatalysts for the Carbon Dioxide Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03938</link>
      <description>Haoyang Qiu, Huohai Yang, Li Wang, Manxi Leng, Xingbo Ge, Yang Xu, Xin Chen, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404376052

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO</description>
      <author>Haoyang Qiu, Huohai Yang, Li Wang, Manxi Leng, Xingbo Ge, Yang Xu, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03938</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy Engineering Strategies for Optimizing Solid Oxide Cell Air Electrode Performance: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177585</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Chen, Ben Ma, Chen Dang, Yingke Zhou, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404387765

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Chen, Ben Ma, Chen Dang, Yingke Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Throughput UV&#8208;Induced Synthesis and Screening of Alloy Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406848</link>
      <description>Xu Li, Jianyun Cao, Jiexin Chen, Jiyang Xie, Chengding Gu, Xiaohong Li, Nigel Brandon, Wanbiao Hu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404390051

                Abstract The combination of different elements in alloy catalysts can lead to improved activity as it provides opportunities to tune the electronic structures of surface atoms. However, the synthesis and performance screening of alloy catalysts through a vast chemical space are cost&#8208; and labor&#8208;intensive. Herein, a UV&#8208;induced, high&#8208;throughput method is reported for the synthesis and screening of alloy electrocatalysts in a fast and low&#8208;cost manner. A platform that integrates 37 mini&#8208;reaction&#8208;cells enables simultaneous UV&#8208;induced photodeposition of alloy nanoparticles with up to 37 compositions. These mini&#8208;reaction&#8208;cells further allow a transfer&#8208;free, high&#8208;throughput electrochemical performance screening. Binary (PtPd, PtIr, PdIr), ternary (PtPdIr, PtRuIr) and quaternary (PtPdRuIr) alloys have been synthesized with the activity of the binary alloys (57 compositions) for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) being screened. The predicted high performance of identified alloy compositions are subsequently validated by standard measurements using a rotating disk electrode configuration. It is found that the as&#8208;synthesized alloy nanoparticles are rich in twin boundaries and thus possess lattice strain. Density functional theory calculation implies that the high ORR activity of the screened Pt 0.75 Pd 0.25 alloy originates from the interplay between the differentiated adsorption sites because of alloying and the strain&#8208;induced modulation of the d&#8208;band center.</description>
      <author>Xu Li, Jianyun Cao, Jiexin Chen, Jiyang Xie, Chengding Gu, Xiaohong Li, Nigel Brandon, Wanbiao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Coordination&#8208;Driven Metal&#8208;Oxygen Interaction Triggers Oxygen Evolution in Polymorphic and High&#8208;Entropy Phosphate Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416834</link>
      <description>Sampath Gayathri, Paulraj Arunkumar, Dipankar Saha, Durga P. Acharya, J. Karthikeyan, Jong Hun Han, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404390058

                Abstract Engineering metal&#8208;oxygen (M&#8210;O) interactions for catalyzing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by tuning the coordination geometry of metal sites is crucial for improving catalytic performance, which remains unexplored, especially in structurally diverse phosphate&#8208;based catalysts. Herein, two NaCoPO 4 (NCP) polymorphs with distinct metal coordinations: orthorhombic&#8208; Pnma (CoO 6 ) and hexagonal&#8208;P 6 5 (CoO 4 ) denoted as O&#8208;NCP and H&#8208;NCP, respectively are synthesized through unique quenching&#8208;based synthesis, to investigate the impact of coordination geometry on M&#8210;O covalency and OER performance. The CoO 4 (H&#8208;NCP) polymorph delivered superior OER activity with low overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 (&#951; 10 = 303 mV) and long&#8208;term stability than CoO 6 &#8208;based O&#8208;NCP. Spectroscopic and computational studies linked the superior activity of CoO 4 to higher Co&#8210;O covalency, enhanced metal electronic states near the Fermi level, and improved electrochemical reconstruction. Further, M&#8210;O covalency regulated OER mechanism, where high&#8208;covalent CoO 4 follows conventional concerted proton&#8208;electron transfer pathway, while CoO 6 entails a non&#8208;concerted pathway, where the lattice oxygen participation remains unfavorable due to downshifted O 2p band center. Further, OER&#8208;active tetrahedral metal is demonstrated in a high&#8208;entropy catalyst requiring lower &#951; 10 of &#8776;284 mV. This study unlocks a unique strategy for designing next&#8208;generation OER catalysts with superior activity and durability, harnessing the interplay between metal coordination and metal&#8208;oxygen covalency.</description>
      <author>Sampath Gayathri, Paulraj Arunkumar, Dipankar Saha, Durga P. Acharya, J. Karthikeyan, Jong Hun Han</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalyst Design for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-73442-7_3</link>
      <description>Zafar Khan Ghouri, SpringerBriefs in energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404391126

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zafar Khan Ghouri</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-73442-7_3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective electroreduction of acetylene to 1,3-butadiene on iodide-induced Cu&#948;+&#8211;Cu0 sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01250-0</link>
      <description>Wei Jie Teh, Eleonora Romeo, Shibo Xi, Ben C. Rowley, Francesc Illas, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Boon Siang Yeo, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404391693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Jie Teh, Eleonora Romeo, Shibo Xi, Ben C. Rowley, Francesc Illas, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Boon Siang Yeo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01250-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT and AIMD studies on the conversion and decomposition of Li2S2 to Li2S on 2D-FeS2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113531</link>
      <description>Fenning Zhao, Hongtao Xue, Yi Dong, Fuling Tang, Computational Materials Science. 247(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404396316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fenning Zhao, Hongtao Xue, Yi Dong, Fuling Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roles of copper(I) in water-promoted CO2 electrolysis to multi-carbon compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54282-2</link>
      <description>Xiaoyang He, Lin Li, Xiang-Ying Li, Minzhi Zhu, Qinghong Zhang, Shunji Xie, Bingbao Mei, Fanfei Sun, Zheng Jiang, Jun Cheng, Ye Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404397577

                The membrane electrode assembly (MEA) is promising for practical applications of the electrocatalytic CO</description>
      <author>Xiaoyang He, Lin Li, Xiang-Ying Li, Minzhi Zhu, Qinghong Zhang, Shunji Xie, Bingbao Mei, Fanfei Sun, Zheng Jiang, Jun Cheng, Ye Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54282-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effects of metal single atoms and clusters on graphene-supported electrocatalysts: insights into the mechanism of oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119830</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Jianguang Feng, Zhongxia Shang, Beili Pang, Shuo Zhang, Hongzhou Dong, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404397644

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Jianguang Feng, Zhongxia Shang, Beili Pang, Shuo Zhang, Hongzhou Dong, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The critical effect of different additive interlayer anions on NiFe-LDH for direct seawater splitting: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.069</link>
      <description>Lu Wang, Ying Wang, Liang Zhou, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Zhijian Wu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404398431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Wang, Ying Wang, Liang Zhou, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Zhijian Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cifkit: A Python package for coordination geometry and atomic site analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07205</link>
      <description>Sangjoon Lee, Anton O. Oliynyk, The Journal of Open Source Software. 9(103)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404401482

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sangjoon Lee, Anton O. Oliynyk</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-199-Based Nitrogen-Doped Bimetal Cathode Catalyst for Anion Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01926</link>
      <description>Afandi Yusuf, Yusuf Pradesar, Guan-Cheng Chen, Hsin&#8208;Chih Huang, Chen&#8208;Hao Wang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404408856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Afandi Yusuf, Yusuf Pradesar, Guan-Cheng Chen, Hsin&#8208;Chih Huang, Chen&#8208;Hao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity&#8211;Stability Relationships in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.4c00086</link>
      <description>Wonchul Park, Dong Young Chung, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404410584

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wonchul Park, Dong Young Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.4c00086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Machine Learning in Industry 4.0: Benchmark Framework for Rare-event Prediction in Chemical Processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108929</link>
      <description>Vikram Sudarshan, Warren D. Seider, Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404413260

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vikram Sudarshan, Warren D. Seider</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variants of Surface Charges and Capacitances in Electrocatalysis: Insights from Density-Potential Functional Theory Embedded with an Implicit Chemisorption Model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/prxenergy.3.043008</link>
      <description>Jun Huang, Fabiola Dom&#237;nguez-Flores, Marko Melander, PRX Energy. 3(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404414084

                Prevalent electrolyte effects across a wide range of electrocatalytic reactions underscore the general importance of the local reaction conditions in the electrical double layer (EDL). Compared to traditional EDLs, the electrocatalytic siblings feature partially charged chemisorbates that could blur our long-held views of surface charge densities and differential capacitances&#8212;two interrelated quantities shaping the crucial local reaction conditions. Herein, five variants of surface charge density and three variants of differential capacitance in the presence of chemisorbates are defined and compared. A semiclassical model of electrocatalytic EDLs is developed for a quantitative analysis of the differences and interrelationships between these variants of surface charge densities and differential capacitances. It is revealed that the potential- and concentration-dependent net charge on these chemisorbates dramatically changes the surface charge densities and differential capacitances. Specifically, the free surface charge density could decrease as the electrode potential becomes more positive, implying that the . The relationship between the free and total surface charge densities is analyzed with aid of the concept of electrosorption valency. By linking the electrosorption valency with the differential capacitance in the absence of chemisorbates, we explain the potential and concentration dependence of the former. The conceptual analysis presented in this work has important implications for experimental characterization and first-principles-based atomistic simulations of electrocatalysis and EDL effects. Particularly, we disclose a hidden yet potentially crucial disadvantage of widely employed atomistic simulation models that fix the coverage of chemisorbates. Proposing the self-consistent implicit model as an expedient remedy for this disadvantage, this work contributes to more realistic modeling of electrocatalytic EDLs. Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Jun Huang, Fabiola Dom&#237;nguez-Flores, Marko Melander</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/prxenergy.3.043008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;supported thin&#8208;film electrode consisting of transition metal borides for highly efficient hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.656</link>
      <description>Qi Miao, Lihong Bao, Yuxin Gao, Hao Wang, Yongjun Cao, Wei Ma, Lei Li, Xiaowei Yang, Jijun Zhao, Ruguang Ma, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404415452

                Abstract Transition metal borides (TMBs) are a new class of promising electrocatalysts for hydrogen generation by water splitting. However, the synthesis of robust all&#8208;in&#8208;one electrodes is challenging for practical applications. Herein, a facile solid&#8208;state boronization strategy is reported to synthesize a series of self&#8208;supported TMBs thin films (TMB&#8208;TFs) with large area and high catalytic activity. Among them, MoB thin film (MoB&#8208;TF) exhibits the highest activity toward electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), displaying a low overpotential ( &#951; 10 = 191 and 219 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and a small Tafel slope (60.25 and 61.91 mV dec &#8722;1 ) in 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 and 1.0 M KOH, respectively. Moreover, it outperforms the commercial Pt/C at the high current density region, demonstrating potential applications in industrially electrochemical water splitting. Theoretical study reveals that both surfaces terminated by TM and B atoms can serve as the active sites and the H* binding strength of TMBs is correlated with the p band center of B atoms. This work provides a new pathway for the potential application of TMBs in large&#8208;scale hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Qi Miao, Lihong Bao, Yuxin Gao, Hao Wang, Yongjun Cao, Wei Ma, Lei Li, Xiaowei Yang, Jijun Zhao, Ruguang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Raman Study of Layered Double Hydroxide Catalysts for Water Oxidation to Hydrogen Evolution: Recent Progress and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17225712</link>
      <description>Jing Wen, Siyuan Tang, Xiang Ding, Yin Yin, Fuzhan Song, Xinchun Yang, Energies. 17(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404417724

                With the increasing global emphasis on green energy and sustainable development goals, the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is gradually becoming a crucial focus in research on water oxidation for hydrogen generation. However, its complicated reaction processes associated with its high energy barrier severely limit the efficiency of energy conversion. Recently, layered double hydroxide (LDH) has been considered as one of the most promising catalysts in alkaline media. Nonetheless, lacking a deep insight into the kinetic process of the electrocatalytic OER process is detrimental to the further optimization of LDH catalysts. Therefore, monitoring the catalytic reaction kinetic process via surface-sensitive in situ spectroscopy is especially important. In particular, the in situ Raman technique is capable of providing fingerprint information for surface species and intermediates in the operating environment. From the perspective of Raman spectroscopy, this paper provides an exhaustive overview of research progress in in situ Raman for the characterization of the catalytic mechanism of LDH catalysts, providing theoretical guidance for designing LDH materials. Finally, we present an incisive discussion on the challenges of the electrocatalytic in situ Raman technique and its future development trend.</description>
      <author>Jing Wen, Siyuan Tang, Xiang Ding, Yin Yin, Fuzhan Song, Xinchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17225712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00005-8</link>
      <description>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404418612

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00005-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging materials for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00007-1</link>
      <description>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404418616

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00007-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction and alcohol oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00012-5</link>
      <description>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404418624

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00012-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging materials for hydrogen oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00009-5</link>
      <description>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404419142

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00009-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic hydrogen oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00008-3</link>
      <description>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404419295

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24038-6.00008-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-Supported ZnO under Conditions of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Methanol: Why 0.2 ML Coverage?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02908</link>
      <description>Robert H. Lavroff, Edison Cummings, Kaustubh J. Sawant, Zisheng Zhang, Philippe Sautet, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404420877

                By hydrogenating carbon dioxide to value-added products such as methanol, heterogeneous catalysts can lower greenhouse gas emissions and generate alternative liquid fuels. The most common commercial catalyst for the reduction of CO2 to methanol is Cu/ZnO/Al2O3, where ZnO improves conversion and selectivity toward methanol. The structure of this catalyst is thought to be Zn oxy(hydroxyl) overlayers on the nanometer scale on Cu. In the presence of CO2 and H2 under reaction conditions, the Cu substrate itself can be restructured and/or partially oxidized at its interface with ZnO, or the Zn might be reduced, possibly completely to a CuZn alloy, making the exact structure and stoichiometry of the active site a topic of active debate. In this study, we examine Zn3 clusters on Cu(100) and Cu(111), as a subnano model of the catalyst. We use a grand canonical genetic algorithm to sample the system structure and stoichiometry under catalytic conditions: T of 550 K, initial partial pressures of H2 of 4.5 atm and CO2 of 0.5 atm, and 1% conversion. We uncover a strong dependence of the catalyst stoichiometry on the surface coverage. At the optimal 0.2 ML surface coverage, chains of Zn(OH) form on both Cu surfaces. On Cu(100), the catalyst has many thermally accessible metastable minima, whereas on Cu(111), it does not. No oxidation or reconstruction of the Cu is found. However, at a lower coverage of Zn, Zn3 clusters take on a metallic form on Cu(100), and slightly oxidized Zn3O on Cu(111), while the surface uptakes H to form a variety of low hydrides of Cu. We thus hypothesize that the 0.2 ML Zn coverage is optimal, as found experimentally, because of the stronger yet incomplete oxidation afforded by Zn at this coverage.</description>
      <author>Robert H. Lavroff, Edison Cummings, Kaustubh J. Sawant, Zisheng Zhang, Philippe Sautet, Anastassia N. Alexandrova</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances and future prospects of MXene-based photocatalysts in environmental remediations.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114812</link>
      <description>Basiru O. Yusuf, Mustapha Umar, Mansur Aliyu, Aliyu Musa Alhassan, Mohammed Mosaad Awad, Omer Ahmed Taialla, AbdulHakam Shafiu Abdullahi, Jamilu Nura Musa, Khalid Alhooshani, Saheed A. Ganiyu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404432102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Basiru O. Yusuf, Mustapha Umar, Mansur Aliyu, Aliyu Musa Alhassan, Mohammed Mosaad Awad, Omer Ahmed Taialla, AbdulHakam Shafiu Abdullahi, Jamilu Nura Musa, Khalid Alhooshani, Saheed A. Ganiyu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Hydrogen Interaction with Transition Metal Surfaces: A High-Throughput Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06194</link>
      <description>Miquel All&#233;s, Ling Meng, Ismael Beltr&#225;n, Francisco M. Fern&#225;ndez, Francesc Vi&#241;es, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404436423

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miquel All&#233;s, Ling Meng, Ismael Beltr&#225;n, Francisco M. Fern&#225;ndez, Francesc Vi&#241;es</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in electrochemical synthesis: expanding from water electrolysis to dual-value-added products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100333</link>
      <description>Genxiang Wang, Ao Chen, Yao Chen, Fen Qiao, Junfeng Wang, Nianjun Yang, Shouxin Zhang, Zhenhai Wen, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404436613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Genxiang Wang, Ao Chen, Yao Chen, Fen Qiao, Junfeng Wang, Nianjun Yang, Shouxin Zhang, Zhenhai Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge-substituents and center metal optimization boosting oxygen electrocatalysis in porphyrin-based covalent organic polymers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.109</link>
      <description>Hongyan Zhuo, Qiming Ye, Shaoze Wang, Yu Han, Tianle Yang, Binghan Jiang, Chuangyu Wei, Linlin Feng, Tenglong Jin, Xue Liu, Zhuang Shi, Hao Song, Zhen Fu, Wenmiao Chen, Yuexing Zhang, Fuling Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404437595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongyan Zhuo, Qiming Ye, Shaoze Wang, Yu Han, Tianle Yang, Binghan Jiang, Chuangyu Wei, Linlin Feng, Tenglong Jin, Xue Liu, Zhuang Shi, Hao Song, Zhen Fu, Wenmiao Chen, Yuexing Zhang, Fuling Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering for improving photoelectrocatalytic performance of 2D/2D MXene@MoS2 for N2 reduction reaction: A theoretical insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133704</link>
      <description>Fengjuan Guo, Jun&#8208;Wei Ma, Xiaoyan Deng, Hongtao Gao, Fuel. 382(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404438403

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengjuan Guo, Jun&#8208;Wei Ma, Xiaoyan Deng, Hongtao Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degree of Span Control to Determine the Impact of Different Mechanisms and Limiting Steps: Oxygen Evolution Reaction Over Co3o4(001) as a Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5023098</link>
      <description>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404443680

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5023098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Loaded Catalyst Layers For Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell Dynamic Operation Part 1: Experimental Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145364</link>
      <description>Florent Vandenberghe, Fabrice Micoud, Pascal Schott, Arnaud Morin, Cl&#233;mence Lafforgue, Marian Chatenet, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404444429

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Florent Vandenberghe, Fabrice Micoud, Pascal Schott, Arnaud Morin, Cl&#233;mence Lafforgue, Marian Chatenet</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From electrons to phase diagrams with machine learning potentials using pyiron based automated workflows</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01441-0</link>
      <description>Sarath Menon, Yury Lysogorskiy, A. Knoll, Niklas Leimeroth, Marvin Poul, Minaam Qamar, Jan Jan&#223;en, Matous Mrovec, Jochen Rohrer, Karsten Albe, J&#246;rg Behler, Ralf Drautz, J&#246;rg Neugebauer, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404447799

                Abstract We present a comprehensive and user-friendly framework built upon the integrated development environment (IDE), enabling researchers to perform the entire Machine Learning Potential (MLP) development cycle consisting of (i) creating systematic DFT databases, (ii) fitting the Density Functional Theory (DFT) data to empirical potentials or MLPs, and (iii) validating the potentials in a largely automatic approach. The power and performance of this framework are demonstrated for three conceptually very different classes of interatomic potentials: an empirical potential (embedded atom method - EAM), neural networks (high-dimensional neural network potentials - HDNNP) and expansions in basis sets (atomic cluster expansion - ACE). As an advanced example for validation and application, we show the computation of a binary composition-temperature phase diagram for Al-Li, a technologically important lightweight alloy system with applications in the aerospace industry.</description>
      <author>Sarath Menon, Yury Lysogorskiy, A. Knoll, Niklas Leimeroth, Marvin Poul, Minaam Qamar, Jan Jan&#223;en, Matous Mrovec, Jochen Rohrer, Karsten Albe, J&#246;rg Behler, Ralf Drautz, J&#246;rg Neugebauer</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01441-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Oxide Pathway Mechanism for Sustainable Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12942</link>
      <description>Xuejie Cao, Hongye Qin, Jinyang Zhang, Xiaojie Chen, Lifang Jiao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404283747

                The advancement of acid-stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is crucial for efficient hydrogen production through proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis. Unfortunately, the activity of electrocatalysts is constrained by a linear scaling relationship in the adsorbed evolution mechanism, while the lattice-oxygen-mediated mechanism undermines stability. Here, we propose a heterogeneous dual-site oxide pathway mechanism (OPM) that avoids these limitations through direct dioxygen radical coupling. A combination of Lewis acid (Cr) and Ru to form solid solution oxides (Cr</description>
      <author>Xuejie Cao, Hongye Qin, Jinyang Zhang, Xiaojie Chen, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12942</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
