<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 01:16:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven Designed Low Pt Loading PtFeCoNiMnGa Nano High Entropy Alloy with High Catalytic Activity for Zn-air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103773</link>
      <description>Liuxiong Luo, Rui Tang, Linfen Su, Jiayi Kou, Ting Liu, Yuke Li, Xinhui Cao, Jing Wang, Shen Gong, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402290264

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liuxiong Luo, Rui Tang, Linfen Su, Jiayi Kou, Ting Liu, Yuke Li, Xinhui Cao, Jing Wang, Shen Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conjugated microporous polymer derived hierarchically porous N-rich nanocarbon as a durable electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction reaction in Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155560</link>
      <description>Lunjie Liu, Zian Xu, Yu Xia, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Qin Jin, Baobing Zheng, Chongxuan Liu, Shaoqing Chen, Zhe Zhang, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402290836

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lunjie Liu, Zian Xu, Yu Xia, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Qin Jin, Baobing Zheng, Chongxuan Liu, Shaoqing Chen, Zhe Zhang, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the effects of Cu doping on the H2 activation by CeO2 surface frustrated Lewis pairs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114518</link>
      <description>&#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Xiaolan Wu, Kaisi Liu, Lei Liu, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402298072

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Xiaolan Wu, Kaisi Liu, Lei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of promising bifunctional catalysts for OER/ORR in disulfides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105069</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Wang, Zhiyan Feng, Peili Shi, Yong Zhang, Pengtao Wang, Lixin Li, Ye Shen, Long Lin, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402298823

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Wang, Zhiyan Feng, Peili Shi, Yong Zhang, Pengtao Wang, Lixin Li, Ye Shen, Long Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand Canonical Ensemble Approaches in CP2K for Modeling Electrochemistry at Constant Electrode Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00671</link>
      <description>Ziwei Chai, Sandra Luber, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402305073

                In electrochemical experiments, the number of electrons of the electrode immersed in the electrolyte is usually variable. Additionally, the numbers of adsorbed substances on the surface of the electrode, the solvent molecules, and counter charge ions in the near-surface region can also vary. Treating electrochemical solid-liquid interfaces with the typical fixed electron number density functional theory (DFT) approach tends to be a challenge. This can be addressed by using grand canonical ensemble approaches. We present the implementation of two grand canonical ensemble approaches in the open-source computational chemistry software CP2K that go beyond the existing canonical ensemble paradigm. The first approach is based on implicit solvent models and explicit atomistic solute (electrode with/without adsorbed species) models, and includes two recent developments: (a) grand canonical self-consistent field (GC-SCF) method (</description>
      <author>Ziwei Chai, Sandra Luber</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00671</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Reconstruction of Nickel Iron Hydrogen Cyanamide with in-situ Produced Proton Acceptor for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124561</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ajmal, Shishi Zhang, Xiaolei Guo, Xiaokang Liu, Chengxiang Shi, Ruijie Gao, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Lun Pan, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402308153

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ajmal, Shishi Zhang, Xiaolei Guo, Xiaokang Liu, Chengxiang Shi, Ruijie Gao, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Lun Pan, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of structural, electronic, and magnetic properties at the &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;0001&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mspace width="0.16em"/&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Cr&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;O&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&#8722;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;111&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Pt&lt;/&#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevresearch.6.033263</link>
      <description>M. Reher, Nicola A. Spaldin, Sophie F. Weber, Physical Review Research. 6(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402309429

                We perform first-principles density functional calculations to elucidate structural, electronic, and magnetic properties at the interface of (0001)Cr2O3&#8722;(111)Pt bilayers. This investigation is motivated by the fact that, despite the promise of Cr2O3&#8722;Pt heterostructures in a variety of antiferromagnetic spintronic applications, many key structural, electronic, and magnetic properties at the Cr2O3&#8722;Pt interface are poorly understood. We first analyze all inequivalent lateral interface alignments to determine the lowest energy interfacial structure. For all lateral alignments including the lowest energy one, we observe an accumulation of electrons at the interface between Cr2O3 and Pt. We find an unexpected reversal of the magnetic moments of the interface Cr ions in the presence of Pt compared to surface Cr moments in vacuum-terminated (0001)Cr2O3. We also find that the heterostructure exhibits a magnetic proximity effect in the first three Pt layers at the interface with Cr2O3, providing a mechanism by which the anomalous Hall effect can occur in (0001)Cr2O3&#8722;(111)Pt bilayers. Our results provide the basis for a more nuanced interpretation of magnetotransport experiments on (0001)Cr2O3&#8722;(111)Pt bilayers and should inform future development of improved antiferromagnetic spintronic devices based on the Cr2O3&#8722;Pt material system. Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>M. Reher, Nicola A. Spaldin, Sophie F. Weber</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevresearch.6.033263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Nanocrystalline/Amorphous Interfaces to Enhance Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance for FeNi&#8208;Based Alloy Fibers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413088</link>
      <description>B. Li, Sida Jiang, Qiang Fu, Ran Wang, Weizhi Xu, Junxiang Chen, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Ping Xu, Xianjie Wang, Jianhua Li, Hongbo Fan, Juntao Huo, Jianfei Sun, Zhiliang Ning, Bo Song, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402309728

                Abstract Efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts play a pivotal role in water electrolysis, notably for industrial high current densities (&gt;1000 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Crystalline/amorphous heterostructure interfaces have proven to be advantageous for enhancing the OER activities of electrocatalytic materials. However, the constructing and tailoring for crystalline/amorphous interfaces still remain a great challenge due to the destruction of active substrates by intricate post&#8208;treatment. Here, a strategy to tailor nanocrystalline/amorphous (N/A) interface and optimize the electrocatalytic performance of as&#8208;cast N/A alloys by adjusting the size of nanocrystals is proposed. The N/A alloy fibers obtained based on this strategy exhibit superior OER performance with an overpotential of 227 mV (@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), maintaining stability for over 1000, 600, and 240 h under high current densities of 500, 1000, and 1800 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. Theoretical calculations and material characterizations reveal that N/A interfaces, facilitated by appropriately sized nanocrystals possessing a loose atomic arrangement, favorable surface electronic structure, advantageous local coordination, and optimal O&#8208;contained intermediate adsorption, can yield abundant active sites without compromising stability. This study not only provides a deeper understanding of the tailoring mechanism of N/A interfaces but also offers a new design perspective for the development of cost&#8208;effective, industrial&#8208;grade electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>B. Li, Sida Jiang, Qiang Fu, Ran Wang, Weizhi Xu, Junxiang Chen, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Ping Xu, Xianjie Wang, Jianhua Li, Hongbo Fan, Juntao Huo, Jianfei Sun, Zhiliang Ning, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction mechanism in pristine TPO-graphene and its boron doped derivative in acidic medium: A density-functional theory forecast</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.493</link>
      <description>Debaprem Bhattacharya, Debnarayan Jana, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402310813

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Debaprem Bhattacharya, Debnarayan Jana</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Force training neural network potential energy surface models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/kin.21759</link>
      <description>Christian Devereux, Yoona Yang, Carles Mart&#237;, Judit Z&#225;dor, Michael Eldred, Habib N. Najm, International Journal of Chemical Kinetics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402311068

                Abstract Machine learned chemical potentials have shown great promise as alternatives to conventional computational chemistry methods to represent the potential energy of a given atomic or molecular system as a function of its geometry. However, such potentials are only as good as the data they are trained on, and building a comprehensive training set can be a costly process. Therefore, it is important to extract as much information from training data as possible without further increasing the computational cost. One way to accomplish this is by training on molecular forces in addition to energies. This allows for three additional labels per atom within the molecule. Here we develop a neural network potential energy surface for studying a hydrogen transfer reaction between two isomers of . We show that, for a much smaller training set, force training not only improves the accuracy of the model compared to only training on energies, but also provides more accurate and smoother first and second derivatives that are crucial to run dynamics and extract vibrational frequencies in the context of transition&#8208;state theory. We also demonstrate the importance of choosing the proper force to energy weight ratio for the loss function to minimize the model test error.</description>
      <author>Christian Devereux, Yoona Yang, Carles Mart&#237;, Judit Z&#225;dor, Michael Eldred, Habib N. Najm</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/kin.21759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modified Activation-Relaxation Technique (ARTn) Method Tuned for Efficient Identification of Transition States in Surface Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00767</link>
      <description>Jisu Jung, Hyungmin An, Jinhee Lee, Seungwu Han, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402312089

                Exploring potential energy surfaces (PES) is essential for unraveling the underlying mechanisms of chemical reactions and material properties. While the activation-relaxation technique (ARTn) is a state-of-the-art method for identifying saddle points on PES, it often faces challenges in complex energy landscapes, especially on surfaces. In this study, we introduce iso-ARTn, an enhanced ARTn method that incorporates constraints on an orthogonal hyperplane and employs an adaptive active volume. By leveraging a neural network potential (NNP) to conduct an exhaustive saddle point search on the Pt(111) surface with 0.3 monolayers of surface oxygen coverage, iso-ARTn achieves a success rate that is 8.2% higher than the original ARTn, with 40% fewer force calls. Moreover, this method effectively finds various saddle points without compromising the success rate. Combined with kinetic Monte Carlo simulations for event table construction, iso-ARTn with NNP demonstrates the capability to reveal structures consistent with experimental observations. This work signifies a substantial advancement in the investigation of PES, enhancing both the efficiency and breadth of saddle point searches.</description>
      <author>Jisu Jung, Hyungmin An, Jinhee Lee, Seungwu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00767</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An automatic variable laser power attenuator for continuous-wave quantum cascade lasers in cryogenic ion vibrational predissociation spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0189140</link>
      <description>Vladimir Gorbachev, Larisa Miloglyadova, Peter Chen, Review of Scientific Instruments. 95(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402313807

                Cryogenic ion vibrational predissociation (CIVP) spectroscopy is an established and valuable technique for molecular elucidation in the gas phase. CIVP relies on tunable lasers, wherein among typical laser schemes, the application of mid-infrared continuous-wave quantum cascade laser (cw-QCL) is the most robust and elegant solution, as we have recently demonstrated. However, potential challenges arise from an inhomogeneous character across laser power tuning curves. A large laser power output could have undesired consequences, such as multiphoton absorption or saturation effects. Significant variations in laser power tuning curves could potentially alter the shape of the investigated band, particularly for diffuse bands. In this study, we have developed and introduced an automatic variable laser power attenuator designed to keep the laser power output uniform at a user-defined value across the entire available spectral range. We demonstrated the application of this attenuator in obtaining CIVP spectra of a model compound with a diffuse N&#8211;H&#8211;N band. This approach enhances the reliability of measuring diffuse bands and overall applicability of cw-QCL.</description>
      <author>Vladimir Gorbachev, Larisa Miloglyadova, Peter Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0189140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the pH effect on hydrogen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00370e</link>
      <description>Wenhong Li, Fan Gao, Guoquan Na, Xingqiang Wang, Zhenglong Li, Yaxiong Yang, Zhiqiang Niu, Yongquan Qu, Dingsheng Wang, Hongge Pan, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402315199

                This review systematically provides various insights into the pH effect on hydrogen electrocatalysis, and thus providing a reference for future development of hydrogen electrocatalysis based on these insights.</description>
      <author>Wenhong Li, Fan Gao, Guoquan Na, Xingqiang Wang, Zhenglong Li, Yaxiong Yang, Zhiqiang Niu, Yongquan Qu, Dingsheng Wang, Hongge Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00370e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modifying the Reactivity of Single Pd Sites in a Trimetallic Sn&#8208;Pd&#8208;Ag Surface Alloy: Tuning CO Binding Strength</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405715</link>
      <description>Lars Mohrhusen, Shengjie Zhang, M. M. Montemore, R. J. Madix, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402315393

                Abstract Improving control over active&#8208;site reactivity is a grand challenge in catalysis. Single&#8208;atom alloys (SAAs) consisting of a reactive component doped as single atoms into a more inert host metal feature localized and well&#8208;defined active sites, but fine tuning their properties is challenging. Here, a framework is developed for tuning single&#8208;atom site reactivity by alloying in an additional inert metal, which this work terms an alloy&#8208;host SAA. Specifically, this work creates about 5% Pd single&#8208;atom sites in a Pd 33 Ag 67 (111) single crystal surface, and then identifies Sn based on computational screening as a suitable third metal to introduce. Subsequent experimental studies show that introducing Sn indeed modifies the electronic structure and chemical reactivity (measured by CO desorption energies) of the Pd sites. The modifications to both the electronic structure and the CO adsorption energies are in close agreement with the calculations. These results indicate that the use of an alloy host environment to modify the reactivity of single&#8208;atom sites can allow fine&#8208;tuning of catalytic performance and boost resistance against strong&#8208;binding adsorbates such as CO.</description>
      <author>Lars Mohrhusen, Shengjie Zhang, M. M. Montemore, R. J. Madix</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Atomic Ordering on Phase Stability and Elastic Properties of Pd-Ag Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14091017</link>
      <description>Xiaoli Chen, G.-N. Luo, Yuxuan Cao, Chaoping Liang, Metals. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402319242

                Palladium (Pd) and its alloys, renowned for their good corrosion resistance, catalytic efficiency, and hydrogen affinity, find extensive use in various industrial applications. However, the susceptibility of pure Pd to hydrogen embrittlement necessitates alloying strategies such as Pd-Ag systems. This study investigates the impact of the ordering on the phase stability and elastic properties of Pd-Ag alloys through first-principles calculations. We explore a series of ordered phase structures alongside random solid solutions using Special Quasirandom Structures (SQSs), evaluating their thermodynamic stability and elastic properties. Our findings indicate the possible existence of stable ordered L12 Pd3Ag and PdAg3 and L11 PdAg phases, which are thought to exist only in Cu-Pt alloys. An analysis of the elastic constants and anisotropy indices underscores some pronounced directional dependencies in the mechanical responses between the random solid-solution and ordered phases. This suggests that the ordered phases not only are thermodynamically and mechanically more stable than solid-solution phases, but also display a decrease in anisotropy indices. The results provide a deeper understanding of the atomic behavior of Pd-Ag alloys, and shed light on the design of multiphase Pd-Ag alloys to improve their mechanical properties.</description>
      <author>Xiaoli Chen, G.-N. Luo, Yuxuan Cao, Chaoping Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14091017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B-Site and Oxygen Vacancy Tuning of Free-Standing La&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Cu&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/Multiwalled Carbon Nanotube Paper for Low Overpotential Long-Cycling Li-CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03735</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Yating Shi, Liying Ma, Biao Chen, Jianli Kang, Chunsheng Shi, Chunnian He, Naiqin Zhao, Ming He, Junwei Sha, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402319378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Yating Shi, Liying Ma, Biao Chen, Jianli Kang, Chunsheng Shi, Chunnian He, Naiqin Zhao, Ming He, Junwei Sha</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merging semi-crystallization and multispecies iodine intercalation at photo-redox interfaces for dual high-value synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52158-z</link>
      <description>Fei Chen, Chang-Wei Bai, Pijun Duan, Zhiquan Zhang, Yi-Jiao Sun, Xin&#8208;Jia Chen, Han&#8208;Qing Yu, Han&#8208;Qing Yu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402325043

                The artificial photocatalytic synthesis based on graphitic carbon nitride (g-C</description>
      <author>Fei Chen, Chang-Wei Bai, Pijun Duan, Zhiquan Zhang, Yi-Jiao Sun, Xin&#8208;Jia Chen, Han&#8208;Qing Yu, Han&#8208;Qing Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52158-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin ternary PtNiRu nanowires for enhanced oxygen reduction and methanol oxidation catalysis via d-band center regulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.054</link>
      <description>Guopu Cai, Chun Hua, Hongji Ren, Renqin Yu, Deying Xu, Muhammad Arif Khan, Jian Guo, Yu Sun, Ya Tang, Huidong Qian, Zhonghong Xia, Daixin Ye, Jiujun Zhang, Hongbin Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402327197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guopu Cai, Chun Hua, Hongji Ren, Renqin Yu, Deying Xu, Muhammad Arif Khan, Jian Guo, Yu Sun, Ya Tang, Huidong Qian, Zhonghong Xia, Daixin Ye, Jiujun Zhang, Hongbin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the electric field on the electronic structure of flat hexagonal two-dimensional GaN bilayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110356</link>
      <description>R.A. Reyna-Lara, J.D. Correa, K.A. Rodr&#237;guez-Magdaleno, F.M. Nava-Maldonado, M.E. Mora&#8208;Ramos, J.C. Mart&#305;&#769;nez-Orozco, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402332529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R.A. Reyna-Lara, J.D. Correa, K.A. Rodr&#237;guez-Magdaleno, F.M. Nava-Maldonado, M.E. Mora&#8208;Ramos, J.C. Mart&#305;&#769;nez-Orozco</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the catalytic performance of RuO2(1 1 0) for highly-selective ethylene production from methane at low temperature: Insights from first-principles and microkinetic simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.059</link>
      <description>Santhanamoorthi Nachimuthu, Guan-Cheng Xie, Jyh&#8208;Chiang Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402339158

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Santhanamoorthi Nachimuthu, Guan-Cheng Xie, Jyh&#8208;Chiang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali Metals Activated High Entropy Double Perovskites for Boosted Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202406453</link>
      <description>Nian X. Sun, Zhuangzhuang Lai, Zihan Wang, Nader Sheibani, Tianyi Wang, Zhichuan Zheng, Bowen Zhang, Xin Dong, Wei Peng, Peng Du, Zhiwei Hu, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Haifeng Wang, Ming Lei, Kai Huang, Runze Yu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402354851

                Abstract An efficient and facile water dissociation process plays a crucial role in enhancing the activity of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Considering the intricate influence between interfacial water and intermediates in typical catalytic systems, meticulously engineered catalysts should be developed by modulating electron configurations and optimizing surface chemical bonds. Here, a high&#8208;entropy double perovskite (HEDP) electrocatalyst La 2 (Co 1/6 Ni 1/6 Mg 1/6 Zn 1/6 Na 1/6 Li 1/6 )RuO 6 , achieving a reduced overpotential of 40.7 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and maintaining exemplary stability over 82 h in a 1 m KOH electrolyte is reported. Advanced spectral characterization and first&#8208;principles calculations elucidate the electron transfer from Ru to Co and Ni positions, facilitated by alkali metal&#8208;induced super&#8208;exchange interaction in high&#8208;entropy crystals. This significantly optimizes hydrogen adsorption energy and lowers the water decomposition barrier. Concurrently, the super&#8208;exchange interaction enhances orbital hybridization and narrows the bandgap, thus improving catalytic efficiency and adsorption capacity while mitigating hysteresis&#8208;driven proton transfer. The high&#8208;entropy framework also ensures structural stability and longevity in alkaline environments. The work provides further insights into the formation mechanisms of HEDP and offers guidelines for discovering advanced, efficient hydrogen evolution catalysts through super&#8208;exchange interaction.</description>
      <author>Nian X. Sun, Zhuangzhuang Lai, Zihan Wang, Nader Sheibani, Tianyi Wang, Zhichuan Zheng, Bowen Zhang, Xin Dong, Wei Peng, Peng Du, Zhiwei Hu, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Haifeng Wang, Ming Lei, Kai Huang, Runze Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202406453</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissolution Manufacturing Strategy for the Facile Synthesis of Nanoporous Metallic Glass Multifunctional Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401109</link>
      <description>Shenghao Zeng, Wenqing Ruan, Zhe Chen, Shuai Ren, J.Z. Jiang, Jiajia Lin, Heting Zhang, Zhenxuan Zhang, Jianan Fu, Qing Chen, Xiong Liang, Jiang Ma, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402362637

                Abstract The quest for heightened energy efficiency is inextricably linked to advancements in energy storage and conversion technologies, wherein multifunctional catalysts play a pivotal role by mitigating the slow kinetics endemic to many catalytic reactions. The intricate synthesis and bespoke design of such catalysts, however, present notable challenges. Addressing this, the present study capitalizes on a novel dissolution manufacturing strategy to engineer self&#8208;supporting, nanoporous multifunctional electrocatalysts, circumventing the prevalent issue of customizing catalytic functionalities upon demand. This innovative approach grants the flexibility to finely tune the incorporation of active species and metalloid binders, culminating in the creation of a self&#8208;supporting nanoporous metal glass electrocatalyst doped with RuO 2 (NPMG@RuO 2 ) with outstanding performance in alkaline media. The catalyst showcases superior electrocatalytic activity, achieving low overpotentials of 41.50 mV for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and 226.0 mV for Oxygen Evolution Reaction alongside sustained stability over 620 hours.These achievements are attributed to the distinct nanoporous architecture that ensures a high density of catalytic sites and mechanical strength, bolstered by the synergistic interplay between RuO 2 and Pt&#8208;based metallic glass. The findings provide a versatile template for the development of nanoporous multifunctional catalysts, signifying a leap forward in the realm of energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Shenghao Zeng, Wenqing Ruan, Zhe Chen, Shuai Ren, J.Z. Jiang, Jiajia Lin, Heting Zhang, Zhenxuan Zhang, Jianan Fu, Qing Chen, Xiong Liang, Jiang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially Confined Alloying of Pt Accelerates Mass Transport for Fuel Cell Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405748</link>
      <description>Yuxin Gao, Huan Liu, Xintian Wang, Xiao Liu, Bin Shan, Rong Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402362698

                Abstract Pt&#8208;based alloy with high mass activity and durability is highly desired for proton exchange membrane fuel cells, yet a great challenge remains due to the high mass transport resistance near catalysts with lowering Pt loading. Herein, an extensible approach employing atomic layer deposition to accurately introduce a gas&#8208;phase metal precursor into platinum nanoparticles (NPs) pre&#8208;filled mesoporous channels is reported, achieved by controlling both the deposition site and quantity. Following the spatially confined alloying treatment, the prepared PtSn alloy catalyst within mesopores demonstrates a small size and homogeneous distribution (2.10 &#177; 0.53 nm). The membrane electrode assembly with mesoporous carbon&#8208;supported PtSn alloy catalyst achieves a high initial mass activity of 0.85 A at 0.9 V, which is attributed to the smallest local oxygen transport resistance (3.68 S m &#8722;1 ) ever reported. The mass activity of the catalyst only decreases by 11% after 30000 cycles of accelerated durability test, representing superior full&#8208;cell durability among the reported Pt&#8208;based alloy catalysts. The enhanced activity and durability are attributed to the decreased adsorption energy of oxygen intermediates on Pt surface and the strong electronic interaction between Pt and Sn inhibiting Pt dissolution.</description>
      <author>Yuxin Gao, Huan Liu, Xintian Wang, Xiao Liu, Bin Shan, Rong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen adsorption on fcc metal surfaces towards the rational design of electrode materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-71703-w</link>
      <description>Cl&#225;udio M. Lousada, Atharva M Kotasthane, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402369593

                Abstract The successful large-scale implementation of hydrogen as an energy vector requires high performance electrodes and catalysts made of abundant materials. Rational materials design strategies are the most efficient means of reaching this goal. Here we present a study on the adsorption of H-atoms onto fcc transition metal surfaces and propose descriptors for the rational design of electrodes and catalysts by means of correlations between fundamental properties of the materials and among other properties, their experimentally measured performance as hydrogen evolution electrodes (HEE). A large set of quantum mechanical modelling data at the DFT level was produced, covering the adsorption of H-atoms onto the most stable surfaces (100), (110) and (111) of: Ag, Au, Co, Cu, Ir, Ni, Pd, Pt and Rh. For each material and surface, a coverage dependent set of minimum energy structures was produced and chemical potentials for adsorption of H-atoms were obtained. Averaging procedures are here proposed to approach modelling to the experiments. Several correlations between the computed data and experimentally measured quantities are done to validate our methodology: surface plane dependent adsorption energies, chemical potentials and experimentally determined surface energies and work functions. We search for descriptors of catalytic activity by testing correlations between the DFT data obtained from our averaging procedures and experimental data on HEE performance. Our methodology allows us to obtain linear correlations between the adsorption energy of H-atoms and the exchange current density ( i 0 ) in a HEE, avoiding the volcano-like plots. We show that the chemical potential has limitations as a descriptor of i 0 because it reaches an early plateau in terms of i 0 . Simple quantities obtained from database data such as the first stage electronegativity (&#967;) as devised by Mulliken has a strong linear correlation i 0 . With a quantity we denominate modified second-stage electronegativity (&#967; 2m ) we can reproduce the typical volcano plot in a correlation with i 0 . A theoretical and conceptual framework is presented. It shows that both &#967; and &#967; 2m , that depend on the first ionization potential, second ionization potential and electron affinity of the elements can be used as descriptors in rational design of electrodes or of catalysts for hydrogen systems.</description>
      <author>Cl&#225;udio M. Lousada, Atharva M Kotasthane</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-71703-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Release via Internal Polarization Fields for Optimal S&#8208;H Bonding States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411211</link>
      <description>Hyunho Seok, Minjun Kim, Jinill Cho, Sihoon Son, Yonas Tsegaye Megra, Jin-Hyoung Lee, Myeong Gyun Nam, Keon&#8208;Woo Kim, K&#252;bra Ayd&#305;n, Seong Soo Yoo, Hyeonjeong Lee, Vinit Kanade, Muyoung Kim, Jihun Mun, Jin Kon Kim, Ji Won Suk, Hyeong&#8208;U Kim, Pil J. Yoo, Taesung Kim, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402376928

                Abstract Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) have received considerable attention as promising electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), yet their potential is often constrained by the inertness of the basal planes arising from their poor hydrogen adsorption ability. Here, the relationship between the electronic structure of the WS 2 basal plane and HER activity is systemically analyzed to establish a clear insight. The valance state of the sulfur atoms on the basal plane has been tuned to enhance hydrogen adsorption through sequential engineering processes, including direct phase transition and heterostructure that induces work function&#8208;difference&#8208;induced unidirectional electron transfer. Additionally, an innovative synthetic approach, harnessing the built&#8208;in internal polarization field at the W&#8208;graphene heterointerface, triggers the in&#8208;situ formation of sulfur vacancies in the bottom WS x (x &lt; 2) layers. The resultant modulation of the valance state of the sulfur atom stabilizes the W&#8208;S bond, while destabilizing the S&#8208;H bond. The electronic structural changes are further amplified by the release and transfer of surplus electrons via sulfur vacancies, filling the valance state of W and S atoms. Consequently, this work provides a comprehensive understanding of the interplay between the electronic structure of the WS 2 basal plane and the HER activity, focusing on optimizing S&#8208;H bonding state.</description>
      <author>Hyunho Seok, Minjun Kim, Jinill Cho, Sihoon Son, Yonas Tsegaye Megra, Jin-Hyoung Lee, Myeong Gyun Nam, Keon&#8208;Woo Kim, K&#252;bra Ayd&#305;n, Seong Soo Yoo, Hyeonjeong Lee, Vinit Kanade, Muyoung Kim, Jihun Mun, Jin Kon Kim, Ji Won Suk, Hyeong&#8208;U Kim, Pil J. Yoo, Taesung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Morphology Modifier Enables the Preparation of Ultra&#8208;Long Platinum Nanowires Excluding Mo Component for Efficient Oxygen Reduction Reaction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401138</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Hu, Jiajia Yang, Lei Tang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Yihua Zhu, R. Li, Cui Liu, Jianhua Shen, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402376933

                Abstract The structural tailoring of Pt&#8208;based catalysts into 1D nanowires for oxygen reduction reactions (ORR) has been a focus of research. Mo(CO) 6 is commonly used as a morphological modifier to form nanowires, but it is found that it inevitably leads to Mo doping. This doping introduces unique electrochemical signals not seen in other Pt&#8208;based catalysts, which can directly reflect the stability of the catalyst. Through experiments, it is demonstrated that Mo doping is detrimental to ORR performance, and theoretical calculations have shown that Mo sites that are inherently inactive also poison the ORR activity of the surrounding Pt. Therefore, a novel gas&#8208;assisted technique is proposed to replace Mo(CO) 6 with CO, which forms ultrafine nanowires with an order of magnitude increase in length, ruling out the effect of Mo. The catalyst performs at 1.24 A mg Pt &#8722;1 , 7.45 times greater than Pt/C, demonstrating significant ORR mass activity, and a substantial improvement in stability. The proton exchange membrane fuel cell using this catalyst provides a higher power density (0.7 W cm &#8722;2 ). This study presents a new method for the preparation of ultra&#8208;long nanowires, which opens up new avenues for future practical applications of low&#8208;Pt catalysts in PEMFC.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Hu, Jiajia Yang, Lei Tang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Yihua Zhu, R. Li, Cui Liu, Jianhua Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation Characteristics of Pt&#8208;Ni Alloy Nanoparticles Fabricated by Nanolamination of Atomic Layer Deposition in Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404943</link>
      <description>Mei-Hsiu Liao, T.S. Chin, Xu&#8208;Feng Luo, Yu&#8208;Chun Chuang, Tsong&#8208;Pyng Perng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377237

                Abstract Forced&#8208;flow atomic layer deposition nanolamination is employed to fabricate Pt&#8208;Ni nanoparticles on XC&#8208;72, with the compositions ranging from Pt 94 Ni 6 to Pt 67 Ni 33 . Hydrogen is used as a co&#8208;reactant for depositing Pt and Ni. The growth rate of Pt is slower than that using oxygen reactant, and the growth exhibits preferred orientation along the (111) plane. Ni shows much slower growth rate than Pt, and it is only selectively deposited on Pt, not on the substrate. Higher ratios of Ni would hinder subsequent stacking of Pt atoms, resulting in lower overall growth rate and smaller particles (1.3&#8211;2.1 nm). Alloying of Pt with Ni causes shifted lattice that leads to larger lattice parameter and d&#8208;spacing as Ni fraction increases. From the electronic state analysis, Pt 4f peaks are shifted to lower binding energies with increasing the Ni content, suggesting charge transfer from Ni to Pt. Schematic of the growth behavior is proposed. Most of the alloy nanoparticles exhibit higher electrochemical surface area and oxygen reduction reaction activity than those of commercial Pt. Especially, Pt 83 Ni 17 and Pt 87 Ni 13 show excellent mass activities of 0.76 and 0.59 A mg Pt &#8722;1 , respectively, higher than the DOE target of 2025, 0.44 A mg Pt &#8722;1 .</description>
      <author>Mei-Hsiu Liao, T.S. Chin, Xu&#8208;Feng Luo, Yu&#8208;Chun Chuang, Tsong&#8208;Pyng Perng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404943</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Modification Effect of Se&#8208;doped Porous Carbon for Hydrogen Evolution Coupled Selective Electrooxidation of Ethylene Glycol to Value&#8208;added Glycolic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404540</link>
      <description>Daehee Jang, Minseon Park, Junbeom Maeng, Jungseub Ha, Si&#8208;Young Choi, Nayeon Kim, Min Ho Seo, Won Bae Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377581

                Abstract The ethylene glycol oxidation reaction (EGOR) has attracted attention because ethylene glycol (EG), which exhibits large&#8208;scale production and a low market price, can be reformed into valuable glycolic acid (GCA) with the cogeneration of high&#8208;purity hydrogen gas during the reaction. In this study, a noble catalyst material of Pt nanoparticles supported on Se&#8208;doped porous carbon (Pt/SePC) is prepared and investigated for the selective electrochemical oxidation of EG to GCA. Pt/SePC achieved a maximum EG conversion of 94.6% and GCA selectivity of 84.4% and maintained this high performance with negligible degradation during durability tests. Furthermore, the EGOR required lower overpotential rather than the oxygen evolution reaction, thus the EGOR coupled with the hydrogen evolution reaction can reduce the cell overpotential to 0.60 V, which is much lower than that of water electrolysis (1.58 V). The effect of Se doping is investigated through experimental analyses and density functional theory (DFT) calculations, and they shows that Se modified the binding energy of Pt nanoparticles and the adsorption energy of reactants by lattice deformation and charge density modification. This study provides scientific insights and strategies for electrocatalyst design for the selective oxidation of polyols to value&#8208;added chemicals via the cogeneration of hydrogen gas.</description>
      <author>Daehee Jang, Minseon Park, Junbeom Maeng, Jungseub Ha, Si&#8208;Young Choi, Nayeon Kim, Min Ho Seo, Won Bae Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetically Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Mild Alkaline Electrolytes by Building Catalysts on Magnetic Frame</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405946</link>
      <description>Ming Xie, Haotian Wang, Xianjun Li, Guojun Han, Yongqiang Yang, Xinyue Shi, Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Guo&#8208;Xing Miao, Meng&#8208;Hao Yang, Jing Fu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377734

                Abstract Under large current densities, the excessive hydroxide ion (OH) consumption hampers alkaline water splitting involving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). High OH concentration (&#8776;30 wt.%) is often used to enhance the catalytic activity of OER, but it also leads to higher corrosion in practical systems. To achieve higher catalytic activity in low OH concentration, catalysts on magnetic frame (CMF) are built to utilize the local magnetic convection induced from the host frame's magnetic field distributions. This way, a higher reaction rate can be achieved in relatively lower OH concentrations. A CMF model system with catalytically active CoFeO x nanograins grown on the magnetic Ni foam is demonstrated. The OER current of CoFeO x @NF receives &#8776;90% enhancement under 400 mT (900 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.65 V) compared to that in zero field, and exhibits remarkable durability over 120 h. As a demonstration, the water&#8208;splitting performance sees a maximum 45% magnetic enhancement under 400 mT in 1 m KOH (700 mA cm &#8722;2 at 2.4 V), equivalent to the concentration enhancement of the same electrode in a more corrosive 2 m KOH electrolyte. Therefore, the catalyst&#8208;on&#8208;magnetic&#8208;frame strategy can make efficient use of the catalysts and achieve higher catalytic activity in low OH concentration by harvesting local magnetic convection.</description>
      <author>Ming Xie, Haotian Wang, Xianjun Li, Guojun Han, Yongqiang Yang, Xinyue Shi, Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Guo&#8208;Xing Miao, Meng&#8208;Hao Yang, Jing Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arsenene/Ti&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction as a Promising Z&#8208;Scheme Photocatalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408353</link>
      <description>Ling Hua, Youxi Wang, Zhenyu Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377844

                Abstract In order to address imminent energy and environmental challenges, photocatalytic water splitting emerges as a promising way for harnessing solar radiation to generate clean chemical energy. 2D arsenene (&#946;&#8208;As) has notable catalytic activity in hydrogen production. Based on first principles calculations and non&#8208;adiabatic molecular dynamics (NAMD) simulations, the &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 heterojunction is predicted to be a promising Z&#8208;scheme photocatalyst for overall solar water splitting. It has a desirable energy band structure with the valence band maximum of Ti 2 CO 2 and the conduction band minimum of &#946;&#8208;As well below and above the redox potentials of H 2 O. Both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can proceed spontaneously under light irradiation. NAMD simulations confirm that it is a Z&#8208;scheme photocatalyst with fast electron&#8211;hole combination dynamics. Instead of by intrinsic electric field, such a fast electron&#8211;hole combination is driven by a large nonadiabatic coupling. The heterojunction exhibits strong optical absorption in the visible and ultraviolet regions. The estimated solar&#8208;to&#8208;hydrogen (STH) efficiency limit of &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 reaches 32%, which is the highest among all &#946;&#8208;As based junctions reported in the literature. These results suggest that &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 is a promising photocatalyst for achieving overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Ling Hua, Youxi Wang, Zhenyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing hydrogen evolution reaction performance through defect engineering in WTeX (X= S, Se) monolayers: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.069</link>
      <description>Wenhua Lou, Jingming Gao, Gang Liu, Asad Ali, Baonan Jia, Xiaoning Guan, Xiao&#8208;Guang Ma, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 87(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402395244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenhua Lou, Jingming Gao, Gang Liu, Asad Ali, Baonan Jia, Xiaoning Guan, Xiao&#8208;Guang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Adsorption on Solid and Liquid Surfaces of Ga&#8211;Sn and Ga&#8211;In</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400456</link>
      <description>Charlie Ruffman, Samuel R. B. Case, Timothy P. Grayson, Nicola Gaston, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402396019

                Abstract Dynamic liquid metal catalysts have remarkable activity and selectivity toward certain reactions, such as carbon dioxide reduction. The surface hydrogen coverage may play a role in this, including controlling competing reactions such as hydrogen evolution. Using a novel method of statistically selecting relevant snapshots from a dynamic liquid metal trajectory, the hydrogen adsorption energy is reported across liquid surfaces of Ga&#8211;Sn and Ga&#8211;In via density functional theory. A fully dynamic sampling of hydrogen adsorption to the liquid metal is also conducted with ab initio molecular dynamics at temperature. The results indicate that hydrogen only associates weakly with Ga&#8211;Sn and Ga&#8211;In surfaces, with minimal difference between the two materials. Hydrogen adsorbs only slightly more stably (&#8776;0.1 eV) to the liquid surfaces compared to the solid. A low hydrogen coverage is predicted on the liquid metal of &#8776;0.03 H &#197; &#8722;2 at potentials of around &#8211;1.15 V (vs RHE). However, the mobility of hydrogen on the liquid surface is much greater due to a novel mechanism whereby the dynamic surface rearranges, opening pathways for diffusion. The results suggest that the unique catalytic behavior of these liquid metal materials may be due to changes in adsorbate diffusivity when the metals are melted.</description>
      <author>Charlie Ruffman, Samuel R. B. Case, Timothy P. Grayson, Nicola Gaston</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Determining the Architecture of Ensembles of Bimetallic PtCu Nanoparticles Based on Atomic Radial Distribution Functions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s2635167623601304</link>
      <description>Ya. N. Gladchenko-Djevelekis, Darya Tolchina, V. V. Srabionyan, &#1042;. &#1040;. &#1044;&#1091;&#1088;&#1099;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, L. A. Avakyan, &#1051;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1075;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, Nanobiotechnology Reports. 19(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402398758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya. N. Gladchenko-Djevelekis, Darya Tolchina, V. V. Srabionyan, &#1042;. &#1040;. &#1044;&#1091;&#1088;&#1099;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, L. A. Avakyan, &#1051;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1075;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s2635167623601304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Structure Sensitivity of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation over Cu/ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Insights into the Role of the Support and the Active Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03803</link>
      <description>Tom&#225;s Vergara, Daviel G&#243;mez, Lucas Warmuth, Annika E. Enss, Martin Peterlechner, Rodrigo Pallac&#225;n, Vlad Martin&#8208;Diaconescu, Laura Simonelli, Felix Studt, Patricia Concepci&#243;n, Romel Jim&#233;nez, Alejandro Karelovic, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402402343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tom&#225;s Vergara, Daviel G&#243;mez, Lucas Warmuth, Annika E. Enss, Martin Peterlechner, Rodrigo Pallac&#225;n, Vlad Martin&#8208;Diaconescu, Laura Simonelli, Felix Studt, Patricia Concepci&#243;n, Romel Jim&#233;nez, Alejandro Karelovic</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysis of oxygen reduction reaction by iron porphyrin and its sensing application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118647</link>
      <description>Tidapa Rattanaumpa, Pakuna Panbo, Suwit Suthirakun, Keerakit Kaewket, Jinnapat Wijitsak, Piyanut Pinyou, Kamonwad Ngamchuea, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402404651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tidapa Rattanaumpa, Pakuna Panbo, Suwit Suthirakun, Keerakit Kaewket, Jinnapat Wijitsak, Piyanut Pinyou, Kamonwad Ngamchuea</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118647</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Activity of Bimetallic Transition Metal Oxides for O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01417</link>
      <description>Shagun Singh, Naiwrit Karmodak, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402404992

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shagun Singh, Naiwrit Karmodak</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Descriptors for Electrocatalyst Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14090608</link>
      <description>Samuel Akinlolu Ogunkunle, Fabien Mortier, Assil Bouzid, Jack Jon Hinsch, Lei Zhang, Zhenzhen Wu, Samuel Bernard, Yong Zhu, Yun Wang, Catalysts. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402411006

                The quest for efficient green hydrogen production through Alkaline Water Electrolysis (AWE) is a critical aspect of the clean energy transition. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline media is central to this process, with the performance of electrocatalysts being a determining factor for overall efficiency. Theoretical studies using energy-based descriptors are essential for designing high-performance alkaline HER electrocatalysts. This review summarizes various descriptors, including water adsorption energy, water dissociation barrier, and Gibbs free energy changes of hydrogen and hydroxyl adsorption. Examples of how to apply these descriptors to identify the active site of materials and better design high-performance alkaline HER electrocatalysts are provided, highlighting the previously underappreciated role of hydroxyl adsorption-free energy changes. As research progresses, integrating these descriptors with experimental data will be paramount in advancing AWE technology for sustainable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Samuel Akinlolu Ogunkunle, Fabien Mortier, Assil Bouzid, Jack Jon Hinsch, Lei Zhang, Zhenzhen Wu, Samuel Bernard, Yong Zhu, Yun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14090608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysing (organo-)catalysis: Trends in the application of machine learning to enantioselective organocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3762/bjoc.20.196</link>
      <description>Stefan P. Schmid, Leon Schlosser, Frank Glorius, Kjell Jorner, Beilstein Journal of Organic Chemistry. 20(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402411271

                Organocatalysis has established itself as a third pillar of homogeneous catalysis, besides transition metal catalysis and biocatalysis, as its use for enantioselective reactions has gathered significant interest over the last decades. Concurrent to this development, machine learning (ML) has been increasingly applied in the chemical domain to efficiently uncover hidden patterns in data and accelerate scientific discovery. While the uptake of ML in organocatalysis has been comparably slow, the last two decades have showed an increased interest from the community. This review gives an overview of the work in the field of ML in organocatalysis. The review starts by giving a short primer on ML for experimental chemists, before discussing its application for predicting the selectivity of organocatalytic transformations. Subsequently, we review ML employed for privileged catalysts, before focusing on its application for catalyst and reaction design. Concluding, we give our view on current challenges and future directions for this field, drawing inspiration from the application of ML to other scientific domains.</description>
      <author>Stefan P. Schmid, Leon Schlosser, Frank Glorius, Kjell Jorner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3762/bjoc.20.196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Nitrogen Activation in Electrochemical Reduction: The Role of Rare Earth Oxide Surface Configurations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02531</link>
      <description>Sharmistha Karmakar, Meng Li, Abderrahman Atifi, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402413266

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sharmistha Karmakar, Meng Li, Abderrahman Atifi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Peroxide Generation and Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction on Pt/Co/Pt(111) and Pt/Co/Pt(100) Single-Crystal Model Catalyst Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03106</link>
      <description>Kenta Hayashi, Takeru Tomimori, Yoshihiro Chida, Naoto Todoroki, Toshimasa Wadayama, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402413399

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kenta Hayashi, Takeru Tomimori, Yoshihiro Chida, Naoto Todoroki, Toshimasa Wadayama</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Reliable Conformational Energies of Amino Acids and Dipeptides&#9472;The DipCONFS Benchmark and DipCONL Datasets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00801</link>
      <description>Christoph Plett, Stefan Grimme, Andreas Hansen, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402435288

                Simulating peptides and proteins is becoming increasingly important, leading to a growing need for efficient computational methods. These are typically semiempirical quantum mechanical (SQM) methods, force fields (FFs), or machine-learned interatomic potentials (MLIPs), all of which require a large amount of accurate data for robust training and evaluation. To assess potential reference methods and complement the available data, we introduce two sets, DipCONFL and DipCONFS, which cover large parts of the conformational space of 17 amino acids and their 289 possible dipeptides in aqueous solution. The conformers were selected from the exhaustive PeptideCS dataset by Andris et al. [</description>
      <author>Christoph Plett, Stefan Grimme, Andreas Hansen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Machine Learning Potentials for In-Situ Searching of Active sites in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00051</link>
      <description>Xiran Cheng, Cheng-Yen Wu, Jiayan Xu, Yulan Han, Wenping Xie, P. Hu, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402438846

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiran Cheng, Cheng-Yen Wu, Jiayan Xu, Yulan Han, Wenping Xie, P. Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable long-lived exciton lifetime and high carrier mobilities in Group III A elements doped two-dimensional blue phosphorene: A time domain &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219326</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, Yulong Qiu, Caifeng Zhou, Hao Dong, Applied Physics Letters. 125(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402443529

                In this Letter, we combine first-principles calculations with the non-adiabatic molecular dynamics (NAMD) method to investigate the photocatalytic and excited-state properties of blue phosphorene (BlueP). Doping with Group III A elements not only maintains an appropriate bandgap and band edge positions for photocatalytic water splitting but also converts the indirect bandgap of BlueP to a direct bandgap, significantly enhancing photon absorption efficiency. The dopants effectively improve optical absorption in the visible and ultraviolet light regions, potentially enabling a solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency of 22.3% in the photocatalytic water splitting process. In NAMD calculations, we consider the dynamics of the electron&#8211;hole pair recombination process between the valence band maximum and conduction band minimum. We demonstrate the regulatory impact of dopant elements, temperature, and non-adiabatic coupling strength on the exciton lifetime of doped BlueP through ab initio molecular dynamics and NAMD methods. This study reveals the relationship between the charge transfer mechanism and non-adiabatic coupling in low-dimensional materials, offering valuable insights into the excited-state properties of optoelectronic materials. Ultimately, our findings contribute to the development of tunable, long-lived exciton lifetimes and high carrier mobilities in doped BlueP, which hold significant potential for photocatalytic water splitting to generate hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, Yulong Qiu, Caifeng Zhou, Hao Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles investigation of H2O2 electrosynthesis on Cu-C24N24 single-atom catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114520</link>
      <description>Junkai Wang, Yifei Wang, Zhenxia Huang, Qianku Hu, Aiguo Zhou, Shaowei Zhang, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402467532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junkai Wang, Yifei Wang, Zhenxia Huang, Qianku Hu, Aiguo Zhou, Shaowei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114520</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Composition-Dependent Catalytic Mechanism of Pt&#8211;Ni Alloys for Oxygen Reduction: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02164</link>
      <description>Zhiyuan Xia, Xiangyu Zhu, Xing Chen, Yanan Zhou, Qiquan Luo, Jinlong Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402469323

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyuan Xia, Xiangyu Zhu, Xing Chen, Yanan Zhou, Qiquan Luo, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure, Bonding, and Vibrational Dynamics of a Triamine High Energy Density Material under Pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03637</link>
      <description>Zachary L. Whipple, Roma R. Ripani, Janki Brahmbhatt, Muhtar Ahart, Nilesh P. Salke, Yue Meng, Zhenxian Liu, Stella Chariton, Stephen A. Gramsch, Santanu Chaudhuri, Emmanuele Parisi, Roberto Centore, Russell J. Hemley, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402477400

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zachary L. Whipple, Roma R. Ripani, Janki Brahmbhatt, Muhtar Ahart, Nilesh P. Salke, Yue Meng, Zhenxian Liu, Stella Chariton, Stephen A. Gramsch, Santanu Chaudhuri, Emmanuele Parisi, Roberto Centore, Russell J. Hemley</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Polymer End Groups on the Formation of Solid Electrolyte Interphase at the Lithium Metal Interface: A First-Principles Calculations Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03261</link>
      <description>Kazem Zhour, Andreas Heuer, Diddo Diddens, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402480543

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kazem Zhour, Andreas Heuer, Diddo Diddens</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneity in Point Defect Distribution and Mobility in Solid Ion Conductors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12128</link>
      <description>Md Salman Rabbi Limon, Zeeshan Ahmad, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402482224

                Alkali metal anodes paired with solid ion conductors offer promising avenues for enhancing battery energy density and safety. To facilitate rapid ion transport crucial for fast charging and discharging of batteries, it is essential to understand the behavior of point defects in these conductors. In this study, we investigate the heterogeneity of defect distribution in two prototypical solid ion conductors, Li</description>
      <author>Md Salman Rabbi Limon, Zeeshan Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen evolution reaction on Ag12M icosahedrons: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141588</link>
      <description>Peter L. Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Kessler, Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402488700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peter L. Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Kessler, Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening of transition metal atom doped ZnS and ZnSe nanostructures as promising bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04011b</link>
      <description>Feifei Xia, Shu Li, Fengli Yang, Yingpin Wen, Chunzhi Zheng, RSC Advances. 14(40)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402491900

                The computed OER and ORR overpotentials of pristine and TM doped ZnX (X = S and Se) nanostructures.</description>
      <author>Feifei Xia, Shu Li, Fengli Yang, Yingpin Wen, Chunzhi Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04011b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic studies on defective hBN-supported metal-nonmetal synergistic catalysis for urea electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161230</link>
      <description>Ziyang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402495689

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degradation of amine-functionalized adsorbents in carbon capture and direct air capture applications: Mechanism and solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129586</link>
      <description>Shu Zhao, Yiran Zhang, Linjia Li, Jiaqi Feng, Qiuping Wei, Yudong Ning, Zhen Huang, He Lin, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402328721

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shu Zhao, Yiran Zhang, Linjia Li, Jiaqi Feng, Qiuping Wei, Yudong Ning, Zhen Huang, He Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of External Field Effects on Electrocatalysis: Machine Learning Guided Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408870</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, Xuyan Zhou, Zhenlin Luo, Sida Liu, Shengying Yue, Yan Chen, Yilun Liu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402411627

                Abstract External field&#8208;enhanced electrocatalysis is a novel and promising approach for boosting the efficiency of electrocatalytic reactions, potentially achieving significant enhancement without altering the composition and structure of electrocatalysts. In addition, the scaling relations of electrocatalysis typically lead to similar variations of initial&#8208;state and transition&#8208;state (TS) energy, which minimally impacts the reaction energy barrier. A sophisticated design of the external field effects shall break these scaling relations. This review provides a comprehensive overview of current research on the effect of mechanical, electric, and magnetic fields on electrocatalysis. It meticulously details the mechanisms underlying activity enhancement based on external field regulations, spanning from the synthesis of electrocatalytic materials to their behavior during the reaction process and modulation of the electrolyte environment. Additionally, the applications of emerging machine learning (ML) technologies in electrocatalysis design, including machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) to simulate large&#8208;scale and dynamic chemical reaction processes, data&#8208;driven design and optimization of electrocatalysis performance, are briefly reviewed. In addition, the significant potential of ML technologies in conjunction with external field regulation, envisioning them as effective tools for optimizing or reverse designing electrocatalysis, considering both thermodynamic and kinetic factors as well as the dynamic effect of electrocatalyst surfaces under extreme external fields, is highlighted.</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, Xuyan Zhou, Zhenlin Luo, Sida Liu, Shengying Yue, Yan Chen, Yilun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective improvement of lithium-ion battery anode performance of Ti3C2 by alkali metal ion treatment strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161209</link>
      <description>Tingting Xu, Jinting Chen, Jinghan Zhang, Haixiang Huang, Bogu Liu, Yawei Li, Xiaohong Chen, Hong Zeng, Ying Wu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402423943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Xu, Jinting Chen, Jinghan Zhang, Haixiang Huang, Bogu Liu, Yawei Li, Xiaohong Chen, Hong Zeng, Ying Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161209</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The cultural identity of first-generation adult immigrants: A meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/15298868.2024.2399559</link>
      <description>D&#233;bora B. Maehler, Jessica Daikeler, Self and Identity. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402339395

                No abstract</description>
      <author>D&#233;bora B. Maehler, Jessica Daikeler</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/15298868.2024.2399559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the cryogenic treatment on the electrocatalytic performance of the active self-supporting nanoporous Pd&#8211;Ag catalyst with high-index facets&#8217; preferred orientation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05798-6</link>
      <description>Jihai Duan, Fang Si, Jiafen Wang, Linlin Lu, Jia Liu, Yanyan Song, Jiahui Mo, Jiaxin Yu, Jinlong Gao, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402354303

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jihai Duan, Fang Si, Jiafen Wang, Linlin Lu, Jia Liu, Yanyan Song, Jiahui Mo, Jiaxin Yu, Jinlong Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05798-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast joule-heating synthesis of FeCoMnCuAl high-entropy-alloy nanoparticles as efficient OER electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.08.005</link>
      <description>Xindong Zhu, Wen Huang, Yu Lou, Zhongzheng Yao, Huiqiang Ying, Min Dong, Lan Tan, Jianrong Zeng, Hua Ji, He Zhu, Si Lan, Progress in Natural Science Materials International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402472017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xindong Zhu, Wen Huang, Yu Lou, Zhongzheng Yao, Huiqiang Ying, Min Dong, Lan Tan, Jianrong Zeng, Hua Ji, He Zhu, Si Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.08.005</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
