<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 01:04:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Novel Cube-Embedded MnO2/ZnO Nanocomposite for OER Activity and Supercapacitor Performance Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-06559-6</link>
      <description>Muhammad Suleman Waheed, Sarah A. Alsalhi, Shaimaa A. M. Abdelmohsen, Sher Zaman, Shandar Ahmad, Salma Aman, Zubair Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, T.A. Taha, JOM. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396216669

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Suleman Waheed, Sarah A. Alsalhi, Shaimaa A. M. Abdelmohsen, Sher Zaman, Shandar Ahmad, Salma Aman, Zubair Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, T.A. Taha</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-06559-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation on the Structural Characteristics and Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction Mechanism of G-C3n4 Supported Ag/Au Single Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4811081</link>
      <description>Hui&#8208;ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396217729

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui&#8208;ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4811081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of p-Block Metal Single-Atom-Loaded Carbon Nitride Catalyst for Photocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29092030</link>
      <description>Meng-Ning Chen, Yidi Wu, Qiang Wan, Sen Lin, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396220936

                Graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4), recognized for its considerable potential as a heterogeneous photocatalyst in water splitting, has attracted extensive research interest. By using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the regulatory role of p-block metal (PM) single atoms on the photocatalytic activity of g-C3N4 in overall water splitting was systematically explored. The incorporation of PM atoms (Ge, Sn and Pb) led to a reduction in the overpotentials required for both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Combined with the electronic structures analysis via hybrid functional, it was found that the introduction of Ge, Sn or Pb optimizes the positions of the valence band maximum (VBM) and the conduction band minimum (CBM), providing a robust driving force for HER and ensuring substantial driving force for OER. Meanwhile, the presence of these three PMs induces the spatial separation of VBM and CBM, inhibiting the recombination of carriers. These findings have significant implications for the design and preparation of efficient photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Meng-Ning Chen, Yidi Wu, Qiang Wan, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29092030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Interface Polarization Effects on the Electrical Double Layer with Efficient Open Boundary Simulations under Potential Control</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03615</link>
      <description>Margherita Buraschi, Andrew P. Horsfield, Clotilde S. Cucinotta, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396221327

                A major challenge in modeling interfacial processes in electrochemical (EC) devices is performing simulations at constant potential. This requires an open-boundary description of the electrons, so that they can enter and leave the computational cell. To enable realistic modeling of EC processes under potential control we have interfaced density functional theory with the hairy probe method in the weak coupling limit (Zauchner et al. Phys. Rev. B 2018, 97, 045116). Our implementation was systematically tested using simple parallel-plate capacitor models with pristine surfaces and a single layer of adsorbed water molecules. Remarkably, our code's efficiency is comparable with a standard DFT calculation. We reveal that local field effects at the electrical double layer induced by the change of applied potential can significantly affect the energies of chemical steps in heterogeneous electrocatalysis. Our results demonstrate the importance of an explicit modeling of the applied potential in a simulation and provide an efficient tool to control this critical parameter.</description>
      <author>Margherita Buraschi, Andrew P. Horsfield, Clotilde S. Cucinotta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03615</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Orbital Coupling: An Adsorption Mechanism in Single-Atom Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13119</link>
      <description>Chen He, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Lei Meng, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Zhe Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396222769

                Quantitative understanding of the chemisorption on single-atom catalysts (SACs) by their electronic properties is crucial for the catalyst design. However, the physical mechanism is still under debate. Here, the CO catalytic oxidation on single transition metal (i.e., Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni) dopants is used as a theoretical model to explore the correlations between the characteristics of electronic structures and the chemisorption on SACs. For these metal dopants, their atomic d orbitals form several nondegenerate and localized electronic states that are found to be selectively coupled with the &#960;* orbital of the adsorbed O2, which we defined as selective orbital coupling. Based on the selective orbital coupling, we find that the alignment between the selected d state and the &#960;* state determines the bond strength, regardless of the electron occupation number of the selected d states; the electron transfer to form M&#8211;O bonding can be provided by the support. Such electron transfer can be related with the electronic metal&#8211;support interaction. We attribute the origin of the chemisorption mechanism to the coexistence of the localized orbital of the single transition metal and the continuous energy band of the Au support. Finally, we illustrate how this mechanism dominates the variation trend of the reaction barriers. Our results unravel a fundamental adsorption mechanism in SAC systems.</description>
      <author>Chen He, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Lei Meng, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Zhe Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Effects of FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Active Sites Surrounded by Fourteen-Membered Ring Ligands on Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity and Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01122</link>
      <description>Zhiqing Feng, Shizuyo Honda, Junya Ohyama, Y. Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Hiroshi Yoshida, Masato Machida, K&#245;tar&#245; Higashi, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Ryoichi Kojima, Makoto Moriya, Hideo Notsu, Seiji Nagata, Manabu Miyoshi, Teruaki Hayakawa, Yuta Nabae, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396222845

                FeN4 active sites have been studied as non-Pt group metal (non-PGM) catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The authors recently developed Fe(II) 1,14:7,8-ditethenotetrapyrido-[2,1,6-de:2&#8242;,1&#8242;6&#8242;-gh:2&#8243;,1&#8243;,6&#8243;-na][1,3,5,8,10,12] hexaazacyclotetradecine (Fe-14MR) as an FeN4 complex incorporating a 14-membered ring. This complex exhibited higher ORR activity and greater durability than Fe phthalocyanine, a conventional FeN4 complex having a 16-membered ring. In the present study, the ORR activity and durability of this Fe-14MR complex supported on C (Fe-14MR/C) were enhanced through modification of the active site structure by heating at 600 &#176;C and removing protons on amine groups in the Fe-14MR. Density functional theory calculations indicated that the Fe-14MR/C structure generated by heating resulted in oxygen species absorption energies close to optimal values for the ORR. The improved durability of the heat-treated Fe-14MR/C was attributed to reduced distortion of the FeN4 sites. The results suggest that designing Fe-14MR structures can be a promising approach to developing non-PGM catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhiqing Feng, Shizuyo Honda, Junya Ohyama, Y. Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Hiroshi Yoshida, Masato Machida, K&#245;tar&#245; Higashi, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Ryoichi Kojima, Makoto Moriya, Hideo Notsu, Seiji Nagata, Manabu Miyoshi, Teruaki Hayakawa, Yuta Nabae</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single transition-metal atoms anchored on a novel Dirac-dispersive &#960;-&#960; conjugated holey graphitic carbon nitride substrate: computational screening toward efficient bifunctional OER/ORR electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02652-6</link>
      <description>Chunyao Fang, Xihang Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Di Liu, Xiaomeng Cui, Jingcheng Xu, Chenglong Shi, Mengyu Yang, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396224837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunyao Fang, Xihang Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Di Liu, Xiaomeng Cui, Jingcheng Xu, Chenglong Shi, Mengyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02652-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO adsorption and *CO hydrogenation for efficient CO2 deep reduction on MnCu-NC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104426</link>
      <description>Zhiyun Hu, Huang Liangai, Liu Jianchuan, Zhong Wenwu, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396231739

                In CO2RR, enhancing CO adsorption could suppress desorption and increase *CO concentration for deep reduction. An underlying concern is that strong adsorption might result in high thermodynamic barrier for *CO hydrogenation, however, kinetic barrier firstly dominates the reaction pathway and determines the products selectivity. Directed by above idea, CO2RR performance on Mn, Cu doped nitrogenated carbon (MnCu-NC) is comprehensively studied using density functional theory (DFT). MnCu-NC shows a mild limiting potential of -0.59 V (*CO &#8594; *CHO) for CH3OH and CH4 products. CO poisoning is likely to cause catalyst deactivation, while CO modified MnCu-NC shows a slightly increased limiting potential of -0.63 V (*COCO &#8594; *COCHO) for CH3OH and CH4, and hydrogen evolution is significantly suppressed. Further comparative studies indicate that kinetic barrier for *CO hydrogenation is crucial for deep reduction, and C&#8722;O activation, as well as CO adsorption is enhanced by &#928;-backbonding. Besides, introduction Cu to dual-atom catalyst (DAC) could help retain more electrons and Mn has strong magnetization for charge transfer, both of which improve the charge densities and &#928;-backbonding strength, thus boosting the remarkable CO2RR performance toward CH4 and CH3OH on MnCu-NC.</description>
      <author>Zhiyun Hu, Huang Liangai, Liu Jianchuan, Zhong Wenwu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Re cluster complexes be an efficient catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction? Insights from experiments and computations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00144c</link>
      <description>Mikhail Khrizanforov, Bulat S. Akhmadeev, Polina Milyukova, Asiya R. Mustafina, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Artur Khannanov, Renat R. Nazmutdinov, Konstantin A. Brylev, Qi Shao, Rustem Zairov, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396234031

                This work presents the possibility of using a hexarenium cluster for the hydrogen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Mikhail Khrizanforov, Bulat S. Akhmadeev, Polina Milyukova, Asiya R. Mustafina, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Artur Khannanov, Renat R. Nazmutdinov, Konstantin A. Brylev, Qi Shao, Rustem Zairov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00144c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale biomolecular simulations in the exascale era</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sbi.2024.102821</link>
      <description>David Carrasco&#8208;Busturia, Emiliano Ippoliti, Simone Meloni, Ursula R&#246;thlisberger, J&#243;gvan Magnus Haugaard Olsen, Current opinion in structural biology. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396237158

                The complexity of biological systems and processes, spanning molecular to macroscopic scales, necessitates the use of multiscale simulations to get a comprehensive understanding. Quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) molecular dynamics (MD) simulations are crucial for capturing processes beyond the reach of classical MD simulations. The advent of exascale computing offers unprecedented opportunities for scientific exploration, not least within life sciences, where simulations are essential to unravel intricate molecular mechanisms underlying biological processes. However, leveraging the immense computational power of exascale computing requires innovative algorithms and software designs. In this context, we discuss the current status and future prospects of multiscale biomolecular simulations on exascale supercomputers with a focus on QM/MM MD. We highlight our own efforts in developing a versatile and high-performance multiscale simulation framework with the aim of efficient utilization of state-of-the-art supercomputers. We showcase its application in uncovering complex biological mechanisms and its potential for leveraging exascale computing.</description>
      <author>David Carrasco&#8208;Busturia, Emiliano Ippoliti, Simone Meloni, Ursula R&#246;thlisberger, J&#243;gvan Magnus Haugaard Olsen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sbi.2024.102821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty-biased molecular dynamics for learning uniformly accurate interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01254-1</link>
      <description>Viktor Zaverkin, David Holzm&#252;ller, Henrik Christiansen, Federico Errica, Francesco Alesiani, Makoto Takamoto, Mathias Niepert, Johannes K&#228;stner, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396239146

                Abstract Efficiently creating a concise but comprehensive data set for training machine-learned interatomic potentials (MLIPs) is an under-explored problem. Active learning, which uses biased or unbiased molecular dynamics (MD) to generate candidate pools, aims to address this objective. Existing biased and unbiased MD-simulation methods, however, are prone to miss either rare events or extrapolative regions&#8212;areas of the configurational space where unreliable predictions are made. This work demonstrates that MD, when biased by the MLIP&#8217;s energy uncertainty, simultaneously captures extrapolative regions and rare events, which is crucial for developing uniformly accurate MLIPs. Furthermore, exploiting automatic differentiation, we enhance bias-forces-driven MD with the concept of bias stress. We employ calibrated gradient-based uncertainties to yield MLIPs with similar or, sometimes, better accuracy than ensemble-based methods at a lower computational cost. Finally, we apply uncertainty-biased MD to alanine dipeptide and MIL-53(Al), generating MLIPs that represent both configurational spaces more accurately than models trained with conventional MD.</description>
      <author>Viktor Zaverkin, David Holzm&#252;ller, Henrik Christiansen, Federico Errica, Francesco Alesiani, Makoto Takamoto, Mathias Niepert, Johannes K&#228;stner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01254-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interoperable workflows by exchanging grid-based data between quantum-chemical program packages</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0201701</link>
      <description>Kevin Focke, Matteo De Santis, Mario Wolter, Jessica A. Martinez B., Val&#233;rie Vallet, Andr&#233; Severo Pereira Gomes, Ma&#322;gorzata Olejniczak, Christoph R. Jacob, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396494992

                Quantum-chemical subsystem and embedding methods require complex workflows that may involve multiple quantum-chemical program packages. Moreover, such workflows require the exchange of voluminous data that go beyond simple quantities, such as molecular structures and energies. Here, we describe our approach for addressing this interoperability challenge by exchanging electron densities and embedding potentials as grid-based data. We describe the approach that we have implemented to this end in a dedicated code, PyEmbed, currently part of a Python scripting framework. We discuss how it has facilitated the development of quantum-chemical subsystem and embedding methods and highlight several applications that have been enabled by PyEmbed, including wave-function theory (WFT) in density-functional theory (DFT) embedding schemes mixing non-relativistic and relativistic electronic structure methods, real-time time-dependent DFT-in-DFT approaches, the density-based many-body expansion, and workflows including real-space data analysis and visualization. Our approach demonstrates, in particular, the merits of exchanging (complex) grid-based data and, in general, the potential of modular software development in quantum chemistry, which hinges upon libraries that facilitate interoperability.</description>
      <author>Kevin Focke, Matteo De Santis, Mario Wolter, Jessica A. Martinez B., Val&#233;rie Vallet, Andr&#233; Severo Pereira Gomes, Ma&#322;gorzata Olejniczak, Christoph R. Jacob</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0201701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous and Scalable Laser Synthesis of Atom Clusters with Tunable Surface Oxidation for Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00342</link>
      <description>Meike Tack, Muhammad Usama, Norbert Kazamer, Kai S. Exner, Michael Brodmann, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396495047

                The laser-based synthesis of colloidal nanoparticles consists of several established methods to produce high-purity, active, and durable metal and oxide catalysts. Among them, only laser fragmentation in a liquid jet produces monodisperse, sub-5 nm nanoparticles in a fully continuous operation. However, the nanoparticle yield and laser power-specific productivity are still below the established gram-scale laser ablation method. In addition, little is known about how the initial particle size, oxidation, and the number of laser pulses affect the generated particle size and oxidation state, especially when using commercial microparticles. In this work, we address these shortcomings with the example of iridium as an important benchmark catalyst for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction. Starting from iridium microparticles, a significant improvement in the laser power-specific productivity of nanoparticles was observed when the initial particle concentrations were increased to several grams per liter. The number of applied laser pulses controls the degree of nanoparticles' surface oxidation, as shown by XPS measurements and DFT calculations, while the monodisperse &#8764;2 nm product particle diameter was unaffected by the initial particle size and concentration, highlighting the process robustness. Additionally, the particles exhibit a benchmark level of catalytic activity with the lowest overpotential of 0.33 V vs RHE @ 10 mA/cm2. To summarize, the continuous laser fragmentation of microparticles in water has great potential in the green synthesis of ultrasmall catalysts.</description>
      <author>Meike Tack, Muhammad Usama, Norbert Kazamer, Kai S. Exner, Michael Brodmann, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation on the reaction mechanism and stability of Ruddlesden-Popper structure Srn+1BnO3n+1 (B=Ru, Ir, n=1, 2) as an oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalyst in acidic medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.299</link>
      <description>Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Jiahao Zhang, Jun Ren, Hai&#8208;Lei Li, Meina Chen, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396498908

                R&#8211;P structured catalysts have attracted attention due to their low noble metal content and long-term stability. In this paper, we calculated the synthesis difficulty, Sr segregation, and OER catalytic activity of SrBO3, Srn+1BnO3n+1 (BRu, Ir, n = 1, 2), taking into account the effects of perovskite layer numbers and strain. The synthesis difficulty was calculated: SrBO3 &lt; Sr2BO4 &lt; Sr3B2O7. The perovskite layer numbers of R&#8211;P catalysts were also found to affect the OER process, from n = 1 to 2, the rate-controlling step changes from O*&#8594;OOH* to OOH*&#8594;O2. Sr2IrO4 was calculated to have the best catalytic activity but is very prone to Sr segregation. Due to the unique layered nature, Sr2IrO4 is still considered the most promising OER catalyst. Furthermore, we also concluded that applying strain impairs the OER catalytic performance of R&#8211;P oxides. Our work investigated the OER catalytic mechanisms of R&#8211;P oxides, which is significant for the development of water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Jiahao Zhang, Jun Ren, Hai&#8208;Lei Li, Meina Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Consequences of Hierarchical Pore Architectures within MFI and FAU Zeolites for Polyethylene Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01213</link>
      <description>Jun Zhi Tan, M. Ortega, Stephen J. Miller, Cole W. Hullfish, H.G. Kim, Sung M. Kim, Wenda Hu, Jianzhi Hu, Johannes A. Lercher, Bruce E. Koel, Michele L. Sarazen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396499244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Zhi Tan, M. Ortega, Stephen J. Miller, Cole W. Hullfish, H.G. Kim, Sung M. Kim, Wenda Hu, Jianzhi Hu, Johannes A. Lercher, Bruce E. Koel, Michele L. Sarazen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the potential of transition metals as single atom catalyst in Graphene/WS2 van der Waals heterostructure for enhanced HER performance &#8211; A first principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.281</link>
      <description>Deepak Arumugam, Mohanapriya Subramani, Divyakaaviri Subramani, Ravi Shankar, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396505102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deepak Arumugam, Mohanapriya Subramani, Divyakaaviri Subramani, Ravi Shankar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inducing Microstrain in Electrodeposited Pt through Polymer Addition for Highly Active Oxygen Reduction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01244</link>
      <description>Qi Hua, Xinyi Chen, Junfeng Chen, Nawal M. Alghoraibi, Yoon Min Lee, Toby J. Woods, Richard T. Haasch, Steven C. Zimmerman, Andrew A. Gewirth, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396506273

                We investigate an approach to tune the d-band center and enhance the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity of Pt material without relying on foreign metals or the process of alloying/dealloying. It is known that Pt exhibits suboptimal ORR catalytic activity due to its strong binding to oxygen, therefore requiring a downshift in the d-band center by approximately 0.2 eV to weaken the Pt-O binding energy and boost ORR kinetics. We found that the d-band center can be tuned by inducing microstrain in the Pt electrodeposit, simply achieved by introducing polymer into the electrodeposition bath. Pt electrodes (Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA) prepared with the addition of poly-N-(6-aminohexyl)acrylamide (P1) or poly-l-arginine (PLA) exhibit improved ORR activity compared to Pt electrodeposited without polymer addition (Pt-alone) in both acidic and basic environments, with the order of activity being Pt-P1 &gt; Pt-PLA &gt; Pt-alone. Pt-P1 exhibits a positive shift of E1/2 by 90 mV vs Pt-alone in basic solution, comparable to other reported high-activity ORR catalysts. Scanning electron microscopy shows the presence of agglomerates with diameters between 5 and 20 &#956;m and tip-splitting growth structure due to diffusion-limited aggregation on Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA. Characterization using X-ray photoemission spectroscopy and X-ray diffraction, combined with Rietveld refinement analysis reveal a trend of downshifted d-band center, increased microstrain, and slightly increased compressive strain as the ORR activity increased among the three catalysts. The presence of more defective sites on Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA is the cause of the increased microstrain, which further leads to the downshift of the Pt d-band center and enhancement of ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Qi Hua, Xinyi Chen, Junfeng Chen, Nawal M. Alghoraibi, Yoon Min Lee, Toby J. Woods, Richard T. Haasch, Steven C. Zimmerman, Andrew A. Gewirth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in Biomass Electro&#8208;Valorization for Paired Electrosynthesis of Valuable Chemicals and Fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202300302</link>
      <description>Abdelkader Abderrahmane, Sophie Tingry, David Cornu, Yaovi Holade, Advanced energy and sustainability research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396507340

                Environmental and energy concerns surrounding the use of fossil fuels are driving an increasingly rapid transition to sustainable and eco&#8208;responsible processes. Electrochemical processes can provide the necessary sustainability and economic roadmap for storing intermittent and renewable electricity by synthesizing, in cogeneration electrolyzers, energy carriers and/or synthetic chemicals (hydrogen, ammonia, etc.) via flagship reduction reactions (hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR), etc.). To balance the electrochemical process, these cathodic processes have long been coupled to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which ultimately consumes almost 90% of the energy input. Recent years have witnessed an overwhelming development of anode scenarios based on biomass substrates, because OER cannot be driven below a certain potential threshold, while organics are thermodynamically more favorable. Therefore, paired electrolysis, which refers to cases where electrochemical oxidation and reduction are desired, embraces the electrocatalysis community for the electrolytic production of hydrogen, ammonia, etc. (cathode side), in parallel with value&#8208;added chemicals (anode side), all with a modest electricity input. The trade&#8208;off is selectivity at relevant current densities. This review discusses, the progress, challenges, and potential of biomass&#8208;fueled paired electrosynthesis of valuable chemicals and fuels. Fundamental principles, main biomass solubilization methods, and different scenarios for paired electrosynthesis are presented.</description>
      <author>Abdelkader Abderrahmane, Sophie Tingry, David Cornu, Yaovi Holade</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202300302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing intrinsic electric fields in 2D Janus MoOX (X=S, Se, and Te) monolayers for enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.257</link>
      <description>Zakaryae Haman, Moussa Kibbou, Nabil Khossossi, Elhoussaine Ouabida, Poulumi Dey, I. Essaoudi, A. Ainane, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396507627

                Two-dimensional (2D) Janus monolayers, distinguished by their intrinsic vertical electric fields, emerge as highly efficient and eco-friendly materials for advancing the field of hydrogen evolution reactions (HER). In this study, we explore, for the first time, the potential viability of the oxygenation phase of two-dimensional Janus transition metal dichalcogenides MoOX (X = S, Se, and Te) monolayers as an exceptionally efficient photocatalyst for hydrogen production. Based on first-principles computations, we demonstrate that all three monolayers exhibit semiconductor behavior, characterized by a band gap ranging from 0.66 to 1.55 eV. This narrow band gap renders the proposed materials highly efficient at absorbing light within the visible region. Excitingly, the introduction of an electrostatic potential difference &#916;&#934; has granted us the ability to surpass the conventional bandgap limit (Eg&#8805;1.23). Consequently, all monolayers exhibit favorable band alignment with respect to the vacuum level. Moreover, the calculated solar-to-hydrogen efficiency for the envisaged monolayer exceeds the established theoretical limit. Particularly, the MoOTe monolayer emerges as an infrared-light-driven photocatalyst, demonstrating a remarkable solar-to-hydrogen efficiency limit of up to 25,21% when considering the entire solar spectrum. A thorough examination of the Gibbs free energy differences across these monolayers has revealed that the values during the oxygenation phase are significantly smaller and approach the optimum, in contrast to the parental two-dimensional Janus transition metal dichalcogenides. Our results conclusively establish that the proposed materials exhibit exceptional efficiency as photocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reactions. Notably, their efficacy is demonstrated even in the lack of co-catalysts or sacrificial agents.</description>
      <author>Zakaryae Haman, Moussa Kibbou, Nabil Khossossi, Elhoussaine Ouabida, Poulumi Dey, I. Essaoudi, A. Ainane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanotubes from Lanthanide-Based Misfit-Layered Compounds: Understanding the Growth, Thermodynamic, and Kinetic Stability Limits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c00481</link>
      <description>M. B. Sreedhara, Azat Khadiev, Kai Zheng, Simon Hettler, Marco Serra, Ivano E. Castelli, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Dmitri Novikov, R. Tenne, Chemistry of materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396510105

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. B. Sreedhara, Azat Khadiev, Kai Zheng, Simon Hettler, Marco Serra, Ivano E. Castelli, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Dmitri Novikov, R. Tenne</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c00481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA-Anchored Single-Molecule Iron Phthalocyanine As an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00795</link>
      <description>Yi Qin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, XIA LIU, Xian Liang, Linfeng Xie, Kuan Wang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yang Liu, Yawei Chen, Zhijun Lei, Pengfei Yan, Liang Wu, Shuhong Jiao, Qing Li, Ruiguo Cao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396512258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Qin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, XIA LIU, Xian Liang, Linfeng Xie, Kuan Wang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yang Liu, Yawei Chen, Zhijun Lei, Pengfei Yan, Liang Wu, Shuhong Jiao, Qing Li, Ruiguo Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly selective electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to multi-carbon products at CuPd synergistic sites over OD-Cu based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160189</link>
      <description>Jianguo Wen, Yue Gong, Ting Tan, Tao He, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396513970

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianguo Wen, Yue Gong, Ting Tan, Tao He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction of Pt&#8211;Co diatomic sites catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.254</link>
      <description>Bin Li, Rong Cao, Zhu Hai-yan, Ping Liu, Bingbing Suo, Yawei Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396515642

                Hydrolytic Hydrogen is a clean hydrogen production method. To mitigate the substantial costs associated with water electrolysis, electrocatalysts are crucial in decreasing the cathodic reaction involved in hydrogen hydrolysis, specifically, the overpotential for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Compared to traditional catalysts and single-atom catalysts, Pt&#8211;Co diatomic sites catalyst exhibit excellent hydrogen evolution reaction activity and stability. We have established eight different structures of dual-center metal catalysts based on graphene planes. A systematic study was conducted on the catalytic performance and mechanism of these configurations, among which the structure with the best hydrogen evolution reaction activity was CoN4/PtC2N2, with a Gibbs free energy (&#916;G) of 0.004 eV. Electronic structure analysis confirms that H follows the Sabatier mechanism on diatomic catalysts, and the catalyst exhibits excellent HER performance for moderate adsorption strength of H atoms. The d-band centers of Co and Pt atoms in the electrocatalyst CoN4&#8211;PtC2N2 are lower than those of a single system, indicating that the electronic effect between the CoN4 and PtC2N2 sites can enhance the inherent HER activity of the catalyst. This study expands the application scope of dual-site catalysts and provides new insights for the design and synthesis of dual-site hydrogen evolution catalysts.</description>
      <author>Bin Li, Rong Cao, Zhu Hai-yan, Ping Liu, Bingbing Suo, Yawei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights on 3D transition metal anchored poly[5,10,15,20-tetra(4-ethynylphenyl)porphyrin]diyne as highly efficient bifunctional catalyst toward ORR and OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114188</link>
      <description>Jian Gao, Ruiping Deng, Jing Wang, Ying Wang, Kai Li, Zhijian Wu, Molecular catalysis. 561(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396516874

                Searching for highly active oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is a challenging task in the development of clean energy devices. Herein, by using the poly[5,10,15,20-tetra(4-ethynyl-phenyl)porphyrin]diyne (TEPPD), we designed ORR and OER catalysts by anchoring 3d transition metal into TEPPD (TM@TEPPD, TM = Mn-Zn). Our study indicated that Fe@TEPPD is the best bifunctional catalyst for both ORR and OER. By proposing a proper descriptor, Ni-N3@TEPPD (Ni is only coordinated with three N atoms) is designed and also predicted to be a promising bifunctional catalyst. For Fe@TEPPD, ORR and OER become inactive when the acetylene bond in TEPPD is broken. The surface Pourbaix diagram indicated that on the surface of Fe@TEPPD, ORR and OER can be carried out at the whole pH region due to the high dissolution potential of Fe2+. For Ni-N3@TEPPD, however, the dissolution potential 0.71 V for Ni2+is low. Thus, for Ni-N3@TEPPD, ORR can be carried out only after pH&gt;2.54, while OER is not likely at the whole pH region. This suggested that the conclusions from the free energy changes at URHE=0 and pH=0 could be different when different potentials and pH values are considered.</description>
      <author>Jian Gao, Ruiping Deng, Jing Wang, Ying Wang, Kai Li, Zhijian Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding selective hydrogenation of phenylacetylene on PdAg single atom alloy: DFT insights on molecule size and surface ensemble effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115523</link>
      <description>Hossam Ibrahim, Timo Weckman, Dmitry Yu. Murzin, Karoliina Honkala, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396520431

                Single atom alloys (SAAs) have proven to be effective catalysts, offering customizable properties for diverse chemical processes. Various metal combinations are used in SAAs and Pd dispersed materials are frequently employed in catalyzing hydrogenation reactions. Herein, we explore the hydrogenation of phenylacetylene to styrene and ethylbenzene on PdAg SAA using density functional theory calculations. Our results show that while PdAg SAA does improve the activity of the host Ag towards hydrogenation, a dilute PdAg SAA surface with isolated Pd-atoms is not selective towards partial hydrogenation of phenylacetylene. Additionally, we investigate how the size of the reactant molecule, the size of the metal alloy ensemble, and a ligand effect impact the hydrogenation process. The SAA enhances the binding strengths of various organic adsorbates, although this effect diminishes as the adsorbate size increases. Our findings indicate the dilute PdAg exhibits selectivity towards hydrogenation of smaller molecules such acetylene due to its distinct adsorption geometry. The selective hydrogenation of phenylacetylene necessitates a surface Pd dimer ensemble. Our research highlights the importance of both reactant molecule size and surface configurations in SAA catalysts. This is particularly crucial when dealing with the adsorption of sizable organic molecules where the functional group can adopt different adsorption modes.</description>
      <author>Hossam Ibrahim, Timo Weckman, Dmitry Yu. Murzin, Karoliina Honkala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon electrodes for the electrocatalytic synthesis of hydrogen peroxide: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5805(24)60846-2</link>
      <description>Xianhuai Huang, Xueqing Yang, Ling Gui, Shiyong Liu, Kun Wang, Hongwei Rong, Wei Wei, New carbon materials. 39(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396520736

                Electrocatalytic oxygen reduction by a 2e&#8722; pathway enables the instantaneous synthesis of H2O2, a process that is far superior to the conventional anthraquinone process. In recent years, the electrocatalytic synthesis of H2O2 using carbon electrodes has attracted more and more attention because of its excellent catalytic performance and superior stability. The relationship between material modification, wettability and the rate of H2O2 synthesis and service life is considered together with the three-phase interface. The structure of the carbon electrodes and the principles of electrocatalytic H2O2 synthesis are first introduced, and four major catalysts are reviewed, namely, monolithic carbon materials, metal-free catalysts, noble metal catalysts and non-precious metal catalysts. The effects of the metal anode and the electrolyte on the three-phase interface are described. The relationship between carbon electrode wettability and the three-phase interface is described, pointing out that modification focusing on improving the selectivity of the 2e&#8722; pathway can also impact electrode wettability. In addition, the relationship between the design of the components in the electrochemical system and their effect on the efficiency of H2O2 synthesis is discussed for carbon electrodes. Finally, we present our analysis of the current problems in the electrocatalytic synthesis of H2O2 for carbon electrodes and future research directions.</description>
      <author>Xianhuai Huang, Xueqing Yang, Ling Gui, Shiyong Liu, Kun Wang, Hongwei Rong, Wei Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5805(24)60846-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic transition of 1D ferromagnetic catalysts during the NO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115524</link>
      <description>Zhan-peng Wang, Yi-jie Chen, Shui-yang Fang, Xianjie Zhang, Wei Zhang, Fu-li Sun, Wenxian Chen, Guilin Zhuang, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396520986

                Exploration of magnetic phase transitions during electrochemical processes is of great importance for rational design of supported magnetic-metal electrocatalysts. Herein, we systematically investigated the magnetic transition between ferromagnetism (FM) and anti-ferromagnetism (AFM) in one-dimensional ferromagnetic Co chain supported on graphene (Co4N8-gra) during NO electroreduction (NORR) process, focusing on the impact of potential and acidity on the catalytic property and magnetic transition. A combination of catalytic kinetics calculations and microkinetic simulations reveals that the Co4N8-gra exhibits excellent NH3 selectivity and thermal stability. In the implicit solvent model, the general reaction follows optimal pathway: *+NO(g) &#8594; *NO &#8594; *HNO &#8594; *H2NO &#8594; *H2NOH &#8594; *NH2 &#8594; *NH3 &#8594; *+NH3, with the potential-determining step (PDS) identified as *NO &#8594; *HNO. In acidic solvent, the magnetic transitions follow the pathway (FM &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; FM) under an applied potential of &#8722;0.20 V/RHE. In neutral solvent, the magnetic transitions occur according to this pathway (FM &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; FM &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; FM) under an applied potential of &#8722;0.14 V/RHE. In an alkaline solvent, the magnetic transitions proceed along this sequence (FM &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; FM &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; FM) under an ultralow potential of &#8722;0.08 V/RHE. Essentially, the improvement of catalytic property is attributed to the synergistic influence of external potential and magnetic-state transition on the adsorption of reaction species (e.g., NO and NH3). Magnetic transitions are closely associated with ligand field effect of metal site with variable valence electron induced by applied potential. In general, this study provides valuable insights for the controllable design of magnetic metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhan-peng Wang, Yi-jie Chen, Shui-yang Fang, Xianjie Zhang, Wei Zhang, Fu-li Sun, Wenxian Chen, Guilin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory-guided construction of Cu-O-Ti-Ov active sites on Cu/TiO2 catalysts for efficient electrocatalytic nitrate reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64618-2</link>
      <description>Yuefeng Nie, H.F. Yan, Suwei Lu, Hongwei Zhang, Tingting Qi, Shijing Liang, Lilong Jiang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396521285

                Electrocatalytic nitrate reduction reaction (NO3RR) has been capturing immense interest in the industrial application of ammonia synthesis, and it involves complex reaction routes accompanied by multi-electron transfer, thus causing a challenge to achieve high efficiency for catalysts. Herein, we customized the Cu-O-Ti-Ov (oxygen vacancy) structure on the Cu/TiO2 catalyst, identified through density functional theory (DFT) calculations as the synergic active site for NO3RR. It is found that Cu-O-Ti-Ov site facilitates the adsorption/association of NOx&#8211; and promotes the hydrogenation of NO3&#8211; to NH3 via adsorbed *H species. This effectively suppresses the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and exhibits a lower reaction energy barrier for NO3RR, with the reaction pathways: NO3* &#8594; NO2* &#8594; HONO* &#8594; NO* &#8594; *NOH &#8594; *N &#8594; *NH &#8594; *NH2 &#8594; *NH3 &#8594; NH3. The optimized Cu/TiO2 catalyst with rich Cu-O-Ti-Ov sites achieves an NH3 yield rate of 3046.5 &#956;g h&#8211;1 mgcat&#8211;1 at &#8211;1.0 V vs. RHE, outperforming most of the reported activities. Furthermore, the construction of Cu-O-Ti-Ov sites significantly mitigates the leaching of Cu species, enhancing the stability of the Cu/TiO2 catalyst. Additionally, a mechanistic study, using in situ characterizations and various comparative experiments, further confirms the strong synergy between Cu, Ti, and Ov sites, which is consistent with previous DFT calculations. This study provides a new strategy for designing efficient and stable electrocatalysts in the field of ammonia synthesis.</description>
      <author>Yuefeng Nie, H.F. Yan, Suwei Lu, Hongwei Zhang, Tingting Qi, Shijing Liang, Lilong Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64618-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electrocatalytic Activity for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Alloys is Determined by Element-Specific Adsorption Sites rather than d-Band Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01084a</link>
      <description>Maximilian Schalenbach, Rebekka Tesch, Piotr M. Kowalski, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396525048

                Trends of the electrocatalytic activities across transition metals are typically explained by d-band properties such as center or upper edge positions in relation to Fermi levels. Here, the universality of...</description>
      <author>Maximilian Schalenbach, Rebekka Tesch, Piotr M. Kowalski, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01084a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photochemical hydrogen production using advanced semiconducting metal oxide nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-21456-1.00001-1</link>
      <description>Timur Sh. Atabaev, Kuralay Rustembekkyzy, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396530740

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timur Sh. Atabaev, Kuralay Rustembekkyzy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-21456-1.00001-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven physics-informed descriptors of cation ordering in multicomponent perovskite oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.101942</link>
      <description>Jiayu Peng, James Damewood, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Cell reports physical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396531391

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayu Peng, James Damewood, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.101942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergetic piezo-photocatalysis of g-C3N4/PCN-224 core-shell heterojunctions for ultrahigh H2O2 generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64629-7</link>
      <description>Lingyun Meng, Chen Zhao, Hong&#8208;Yu Chu, Yu-Hang Li, Huifen Fu, Peng Wang, Chong-Chen Wang, Hongwei Huang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396534062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingyun Meng, Chen Zhao, Hong&#8208;Yu Chu, Yu-Hang Li, Huifen Fu, Peng Wang, Chong-Chen Wang, Hongwei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64629-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourier-Transformed Alternating Current Voltammetry (FTacV) for Analysis of Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01526</link>
      <description>Rifael Z. Snitkoff-Sol, Alan M. Bond, Lior Elbaz, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396547671

                Electrocatalysts play a critical role in energy technologies, but the development of active, efficient, and durable catalysts is impeded by the lack of methodologies to deconvolute the complex interplay between various aspects influencing the activity of the catalysts, e.g., the number of active sites, turnover frequency, and the reaction pathways. Fourier-transformed alternating current voltammetry (FTacV) is an emerging tool for the analysis of electroactive species and has been successfully applied to a variety of reactions such as the oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, hydrogen evolution reaction, and hydrogen oxidation reaction. The harmonics generated from FTacV measurements neatly detect underlaying processes not visible by other, more commonly employed techniques for analysis of electrocatalysts, such as the rotating disc electrode and dc voltammetry. The harmonic components enable separating overlapping processes based on differences in kinetics or linearity of response. This paper presents a review of FTacV applied for the analysis of electrocatalysts. It highlights the importance of determining the electrochemically active site density (EASD) to decipher the intrinsic activity of a catalyst and discusses the use of FTacV in dynamic determination of the EASD over the course of a catalyst's working life, as well as the use of FTacV to understand intricate catalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Rifael Z. Snitkoff-Sol, Alan M. Bond, Lior Elbaz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the chemistry behind the electrolytic production of hydrogen peroxide by oxygenated carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.04.032</link>
      <description>Pan Xiang, Ke Yang, Qihao Yang, Yang Gao, Weiwei Xu, Zhiyi Lu, Liang Chen, Zhiming Wang, Ziqi Tian, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396554025

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pan Xiang, Ke Yang, Qihao Yang, Yang Gao, Weiwei Xu, Zhiyi Lu, Liang Chen, Zhiming Wang, Ziqi Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.04.032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy materials: Excellent energy-storage and conversion materials in the field of electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.partic.2024.04.010</link>
      <description>Jincan Li, Huiyu Duan, Long Qi, Zhang Bianjiang, Changyun Chen, Huan Pang, Particuology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396560051

                High-entropy materials (HEMs), a new type of materials, have attracted significant attention in the field of electrocatalytic reactions, batteries and energy-storage materials over the past few years owing to their unique structure, controllable elementary composition, and adjustable properties. These excellent characteristics result from four major factors: high entropy, sluggish-diffusion, severe lattice distortion, and cocktail effect, and are used widely in energy-energy applications. This review aims to summarize the recent progress of HEMs in electrochemical energy-storage. We begin with the concept, structure, and four core effects of HEMs that provide the basic information on HEMs. Next, we discuss the major properties of HEMs and analyze the relationship between their structures and properties. Furthermore, we highlight the outstanding performance of HEMs in hydrogen storage, electrode materials of batteries, catalysis, and supercapacitors, and briefly explain the mechanisms of these materials that are crucial in energy storage and conversion. This review will assist in understanding the excellent energy-storage properties, intricacies of the phase structures, elemental interactions, and reaction mechanisms associated with HEMs. Moreover, challenges and future development prospects are summarized. This work will provide insight into the factors that are crucial for designing HEMs with energy storage properties.</description>
      <author>Jincan Li, Huiyu Duan, Long Qi, Zhang Bianjiang, Changyun Chen, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.partic.2024.04.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Study on Single Atom Anchored on B2c3p Monolayer as Electrocatalysts For Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4813446</link>
      <description>Qiang Xu, Peiyi Yu, Zhenhai Liang, Chaozheng He, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396566450

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Xu, Peiyi Yu, Zhenhai Liang, Chaozheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4813446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Development of Electrocatalysts Based on Information Extracted from Literatures Using Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4813130</link>
      <description>Na Qin, Wei Kuang Lai, Haibiao Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396566466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Qin, Wei Kuang Lai, Haibiao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4813130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support effect in metal&#8211;organic framework-derived copper-based electrocatalysts facilitating the reduction of nitrate to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144348</link>
      <description>Shih-Ming Yang, Balaganesh Muthiah, Jhe-Wei Chang, Meng&#8208;Dian Tsai, Yi&#8208;Ching Wang, Yi&#8208;Pei Li, Chung&#8208;Wei Kung, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396568607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shih-Ming Yang, Balaganesh Muthiah, Jhe-Wei Chang, Meng&#8208;Dian Tsai, Yi&#8208;Ching Wang, Yi&#8208;Pei Li, Chung&#8208;Wei Kung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of amorphous subnanometric palladium nanostructures on metallic transition metal dichalcogenides for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00622d</link>
      <description>Liang Mei, Yuefeng Zhang, Zimeng Ye, Ting Han, Honglu Hu, Ruijie Yang, Ting Ying, W. Zheng, Ruixin Yan, Yue Zhang, Zhenbin Wang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581113

                Metallic transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets decorated with amorphous subnanometric Pd nanoparticles exhibit comparable HER performance to that of commercial Pt&#8211;C.</description>
      <author>Liang Mei, Yuefeng Zhang, Zimeng Ye, Ting Han, Honglu Hu, Ruijie Yang, Ting Ying, W. Zheng, Ruixin Yan, Yue Zhang, Zhenbin Wang, Zhiyuan Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00622d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Accelerated High-Throughput Computational Screening: Unveiling Bimetallic Nanoparticles with Peroxidase-Like Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01473</link>
      <description>Kaiwei Wan, Hui Wang, Xinghua Shi, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581121

                Bimetallic nanoparticles (NPs) with peroxidase-like (POD-like) activity play a crucial role in biosensing, disease treatment, environmental management, and other fields. However, their development is impeded by a vast range of tunable properties in components and structures, making the establishment of structure&#8211;effect relationships and the discovery of active materials challenging. Addressing this, we established robust scaling relationships by meticulously analyzing the catalytic reaction networks of pure metal NPs, which laid the volcano-shaped correlation between the activity and O* adsorption energy. Utilizing these relationships, we introduced an innovative and versatile descriptor of the NPs, which was then integrated into a machine learning-accelerated high-throughput computational workflow, significantly boosting the predictive accuracy for the POD-like activity of bimetallic NPs. Our methodological approach enabled the successful prediction of activities for 1260 bimetallic NPs, leading to the identification of several highly effective catalysts. Furthermore, we distilled several strategies for designing efficient bimetallic NPs based on our screening results.</description>
      <author>Kaiwei Wan, Hui Wang, Xinghua Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial synthesis of polyesters at ambient condition via consecutive CO2 electrolysis and fermentation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6658-6</link>
      <description>Guiru Zhang, Jianguo Ning, Seung Chul Lyu, Baoxin Ni, Ping Shen, Ke Yao, Yuting Wang, Xuheng Jiang, Hai Zhang, Xi Ling, Yongcheng Wang, Kun Jiang, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396585498

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guiru Zhang, Jianguo Ning, Seung Chul Lyu, Baoxin Ni, Ping Shen, Ke Yao, Yuting Wang, Xuheng Jiang, Hai Zhang, Xi Ling, Yongcheng Wang, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6658-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ exploration of oxygen electrocatalysis using core-shell nanostructure-enhanced Raman spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.03.006</link>
      <description>Zhengxin Qian, Ji&#8208;Shuang Zeng, Shuang Zhao, Qing-Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Qingchi Xu, Hua Zhang, Jian-Feng Li, Nano materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396589595

                Advancements in fuel cells and water electrolyzers have significantly bolstered the utilization of hydrogen energy. Notably, the oxidation and reduction processes of oxygen at the electrode&#8212;termed oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR)&#8212;manifest sluggish reaction kinetics, thus requiring noble metals as catalysts, which considerably impedes system efficiency and cost. The imperative for enhancing reaction rates and diminishing overpotential necessitates the development of effective catalysts, which strongly depends on the mechanistic understanding of these reactions at the molecular level. Therefore, this review summarizes our recent efforts in utilizing in situ enhanced Raman spectroscopy, especially the borrowing surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) strategy, shell-isolated nanoparticle-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SHINERS), and the SHINERS-satellite strategy, to capture oxygen intermediate species as a bridge to investigate the molecular mechanisms of OER and ORR. Combining in situ SERS with other characterization techniques and theoretical simulation, the structural evolution of active sites and intermediates, including &#8727;OOH, &#8727;OH, &#8727;OO, etc., during OER/ORR has been monitored under reaction conditions, and the reaction mechanisms together with structure-activity correlations have been identified at the molecular level. These findings may provide a pivotal scientific foundation towards the discovery of better materials for electrochemical hydrogen energy.</description>
      <author>Zhengxin Qian, Ji&#8208;Shuang Zeng, Shuang Zhao, Qing-Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Qingchi Xu, Hua Zhang, Jian-Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.03.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Computational Screening of Novel Two-Dimensional Covalent Organic Frameworks for Efficient Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00818</link>
      <description>Li Sheng, Weiyi Wang, Jiajun Wang, Wenhua Zhang, Qunxiang Li, Jinlong Yang, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396596848

                The pursuit of efficient photocatalysts toward photocatalytic water splitting has attracted wide attention. However, the low efficiency of photocatalytic reactions due to the rapid electron-hole recombination and the time-consuming searching process hinder the development of high-performance photocatalysts. Here, we proposed a data-driven screening procedure for covalent organic frameworks (COFs) as overall solar water-splitting photocatalysts. Based on a COF database through assembling different</description>
      <author>Li Sheng, Weiyi Wang, Jiajun Wang, Wenhua Zhang, Qunxiang Li, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biphenylene nanoribbon as a promising electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.054007</link>
      <description>Radha N Somaiya, Aftab Alam, Zicong Marvin Wong, Teck Leong Tan, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Physical review applied. 21(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396609366

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Radha N Somaiya, Aftab Alam, Zicong Marvin Wong, Teck Leong Tan, Brahmananda Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.054007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study on Mo-stabilized passive films: Hydroxylation effects on chromium and iron oxide surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112105</link>
      <description>Xintang Huang, Dominique Costa, Boubakar Diawara, Vincent Maurice, Philippe Marcus, Corrosion science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396609725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xintang Huang, Dominique Costa, Boubakar Diawara, Vincent Maurice, Philippe Marcus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Corrosion Induced by Surface Defects Accelerates Degradation of Platinum/Graphene Catalysts in Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310940</link>
      <description>X.L. Li, Fangyuan Su, Lingling Xie, Yan&#8208;Ru Tian, Zonglin Yi, Jie&#8208;Fei Cheng, Cheng&#8208;Meng Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396614089

                Abstract Graphene supported electrocatalysts have demonstrated remarkable catalytic performance for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). However, their durability and cycling performance are greatly limited by Oswald ripening of platinum (Pt) and graphene support corrosion. Moreover, comprehensive studies on the mechanisms of catalysts degradation under 0.6&#8211;1.6 V versus RHE (Reversible Hydrogen Electrode) is still lacking. Herein, degradation mechanisms triggered by different defects on graphene supports are investigated by two cycling protocols. In the start&#8211;up/shutdown cycling (1.0&#8211;1.6 V vs. RHE), carbon oxidation reaction (COR) leads to shedding or swarm&#8211;like aggregation of Pt nanoparticles (NPs). Theoretical simulation results show that the expansion of vacancy defects promotes reaction kinetics of the decisive step in COR, reducing its reaction overpotential. While under the load cycling (0.6&#8211;1.0 V vs. RHE), oxygen containing defects lead to an elevated content of Pt in its oxidation state which intensifies Oswald ripening of Pt. The presence of vacancy defects can enhance the transfer of electrons from graphene to the Pt surface, reducing the d&#8722;band center of Pt and making it more difficult for the oxidation state of platinum to form in the cycling. This work will provide comprehensive understanding on Pt/Graphene catalysts degradation mechanisms.</description>
      <author>X.L. Li, Fangyuan Su, Lingling Xie, Yan&#8208;Ru Tian, Zonglin Yi, Jie&#8208;Fei Cheng, Cheng&#8208;Meng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Si12C12 nanocluster with late first-row transition metals: A promising approach during single-atom catalysis toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.368</link>
      <description>Naveen Kosar, Saira Rafiq, Khurshid Ayub, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396615899

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naveen Kosar, Saira Rafiq, Khurshid Ayub, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on carbon dioxide capture materials used for carbon dioxide capture, utilization, and storage technology: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-33370-2</link>
      <description>Hongtao Dang, Bin Guan, Junyan Chen, Zeren Ma, Yujun Chen, Jinhe Zhang, Zelong Guo, Lei Chen, Jingqiu Hu, Yi Chao, Shunyu Yao, Zhen Huang, Environmental science and pollution research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396620328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongtao Dang, Bin Guan, Junyan Chen, Zeren Ma, Yujun Chen, Jinhe Zhang, Zelong Guo, Lei Chen, Jingqiu Hu, Yi Chao, Shunyu Yao, Zhen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-33370-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applied electric field induced the change of spin-electron of the Fe3GeTe2 to improve its oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118310</link>
      <description>Liwei Guo, Rui Wang, Qiuhong Li, Jingguo Hu, Jing Pan, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396621839

                Utilizing density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we investigate the influence of the external electric field on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of monolayer Fe3GeTe2. Monolayer Fe3GeTe2 has ferromagnetic metal properties and displays excellent electrocatalytic activity. The magnetism mainly comes from FeI atoms, owing to the strong Fe-Te orbitals hybridization, and FeI atoms have great effect on the active site Te atoms. The electric field induces the change of spin-electron and promotes charge redistribution in the Fe3GeTe2, resulting in the changes of the magnetic moment and magnetic anisotropic energy (MAE). Simultaneously, the applied electric field shifts the energy band and decreases the work function which facilitates carrier migration to the surface. Therefore, the OER overpotential is reduced and the catalytic performance is improved. These valuable findings can serve as vital references for the design of 2D magnetic electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Liwei Guo, Rui Wang, Qiuhong Li, Jingguo Hu, Jing Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Hydrothermally Synthesized NiFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1166/sam.2024.4691</link>
      <description>S. M. Bodhale, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, Abhijit Gurav, A.D. Teli, N.N. Kengar, A. R. Vedante, Pravin Jadhav, M.M. Abdullah, Hasan B. Albargi, Jari S. Algethami, Preeti Singh, C.M. Kanamadi, Science of advanced materials. 16(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396631293

                In this study, nickel ferrite (NiFe 2 O 4 ) nanoparticles were synthesized using the hydrothermal method at various pH values. The objective was to investigate the influence of pH variation on particle size and electrocatalytic activity. The formation of cubic phase nanoparticles was confirmed through X-ray diffraction (XRD) analysis. To characterize the electrochemical properties, the nickel ferrite nanoparticles were coated onto a stainless steel substrate using the doctor blade technique. The microstructural analysis was conducted using scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The samples were further analyzed using linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The average crystallite size, determined from the XRD pattern, was approximately 40 nm. SEM images revealed a conversion from nanoplates to a granular morphology. The synthesized electrode exhibited an overpotential of 392 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 and demonstrated good stability for 5 hours. These findings highlight the excellent electrocatalytic activity of nickel ferrite nanoparticles for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>S. M. Bodhale, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, Abhijit Gurav, A.D. Teli, N.N. Kengar, A. R. Vedante, Pravin Jadhav, M.M. Abdullah, Hasan B. Albargi, Jari S. Algethami, Preeti Singh, C.M. Kanamadi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1166/sam.2024.4691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intercalated and Surface-Adsorbed Phosphate Anions in NiFe Layered Double-Hydroxide Catalysts Synergistically Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01200</link>
      <description>Shiqing Ding, Zheng Bo, Xiao&#8208;Feng Wang, Yue Zhou, Zhongben Pan, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Guangxiang Liu, Leiming Lang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396633214

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER), a crucial semireaction in water electrolysis and rechargeable metal-air batteries, is vital for carbon neutrality. Hindered by a slow proton-coupled electron transfer, an efficient catalyst activating the formation of an O-H bond is essential. Here, we proposed a straightforward one-step hydrothermal procedure for fabricating PO</description>
      <author>Shiqing Ding, Zheng Bo, Xiao&#8208;Feng Wang, Yue Zhou, Zhongben Pan, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Guangxiang Liu, Leiming Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting oxygen reduction electrocatalytic performance of Cu-Nx by modulating electron structure via construction of Cu-Nx and Cu nanocluster coupling catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.362</link>
      <description>Kaixin Liang, Yongfeng Liang, Hui Zhang, Feiying Tang, Shun&#8208;Li Shang, Zhe Liu, Yongfeng Liang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396637528

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaixin Liang, Yongfeng Liang, Hui Zhang, Feiying Tang, Shun&#8208;Li Shang, Zhe Liu, Yongfeng Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering benzyl alcohol electrooxidation coupled with hydrogen evolution via hetero&#8208;interface construction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18469</link>
      <description>Xiaohui Du, Wenfu Xie, Yanfei Wang, Hao Li, Jinze Li, Yang Li, Yiheng Song, Zhenhua Li, Jin Yong Lee, Mingfei Shao, AIChE journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396639735

                Abstract It is still a challenge to develop electrocatalyst for the efficient adsorption and conversion of organic molecule in aqueous media. Herein, a hetero&#8208;interface structure based on CuO@Ni(OH) 2 is rationally designed to enhance the performance of benzyl alcohol oxidation to benzoic acid. A high Faradaic efficiency of 99% and the yield of 3.09 mmol cm &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 are achieved at 1.70 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode, outperforming the previously reported electrocatalysts. Furthermore, a membrane&#8208;free flow electrolyzer was assembled based on CuO@Ni(OH) 2 hetero&#8208;interface, exhibiting a much high yielding of benzoic acid (6.73 mmol cm &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 ) and hydrogen (0.35 L cm &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 ) with excellent stability. Both experimental data and density functional theory calculations verify that the electron is tend to accumulate at the hetero&#8208;interface, thus accelerating the adsorption of reactant and intermediate and reducing the energy barrier of the conversion of benzyl alcohol to benzoic acid.</description>
      <author>Xiaohui Du, Wenfu Xie, Yanfei Wang, Hao Li, Jinze Li, Yang Li, Yiheng Song, Zhenhua Li, Jin Yong Lee, Mingfei Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the Cs/Cs-O adsorbed graphene/semiconductor heterojunction anode for thermionic converters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42768-024-00191-5</link>
      <description>Wei Sun, Haoran Xu, Hao Qiu, Gang Xiao, Waste Disposal &amp; Sustainable Energy/Waste disposal &amp; sustainable energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396217244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Sun, Haoran Xu, Hao Qiu, Gang Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42768-024-00191-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Fabrication and Characterization of Amine-Functional Silica Coated Magnetic Iron Oxide Nanoparticles for Aqueous Carbon Dioxide Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10082</link>
      <description>Md. Muhyminul Islam, Md. Abdur Rahman, M. A. Alam, Md. Mahbubor Rahman, O. Thompson Mefford, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Jalil Miah, Hasan Ahmad, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581384

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Md. Muhyminul Islam, Md. Abdur Rahman, M. A. Alam, Md. Mahbubor Rahman, O. Thompson Mefford, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Jalil Miah, Hasan Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxyl-assisted globally spontaneous dynamic oxygen migration on biphenylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2024.115984</link>
      <description>Rubin Huo, Chuanjian Zhou, Boyi Situ, Zihan Yan, Hao Yang, Zhengyang Fei, Quan Jin, Ling Zhao, Z. Zhang, Yusong Tu, Physica. E, Low-dimensional systems and nanostructures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396521390

                Dynamic covalent interfaces (DCIs) can autonomously adjust their internal structures and dynamically respond to changes in the external environment, thus holding broad application prospects in drug delivery, molecular detection, and interface catalysis. However, the dynamic properties of such DCIs greatly rely on the localized exchanges or formations of chemical bonds, seriously constraining the adaptive response efficiency. To transcend the limitations of the dynamic two-dimensional (2D) scales, employing the experimentally synthesized biphenylene monolayer as a prototype, we systematically study the hydroxyl-assisted globally spontaneous dynamic oxygen migration on biphenylene interface based on the first-principles calculations and machine-learning-based molecular dynamics (MLMD) simulations. The calculated results indicate that the stable dangling oxygen atoms on the biphenylene monolayer can attract the proton in the interfacial water, which in turn undergoes a water dissociation process and produces hydroxyl groups on the biphenylene interface. Assisted by the hydroxyl groups, the dangling oxygen atoms can achieve long-range migration, exhibiting notably low energy barriers (0.09 eV, 0.04 eV) due to the reversible proton transfer reactions. Therefore, the local dynamic covalent behaviors of oxygen atoms on the biphenylene interface are broken with the oxygen atoms migrating between the adjacent C4 rings. More importantly, the charge density difference and Bader charge analysis demonstrate that the presence of hydroxyl groups significantly enhance the stability of the dangling oxygen, effectively reducing energy barriers of oxygen migration compared to epoxy on the biphenylene interface. Furthermore, the MLMD trajectories visually show the process of realizing large-area DCIs on the biphenylene monolayer. Our work not only clarifies the oxygen-related dynamic behavior of the biphenylene interface, but also provides new ideas for the realization of large-area dynamic covalent materials (DCMs) on other carbon-based or 2D materials.</description>
      <author>Rubin Huo, Chuanjian Zhou, Boyi Situ, Zihan Yan, Hao Yang, Zhengyang Fei, Quan Jin, Ling Zhao, Z. Zhang, Yusong Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2024.115984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating material property prediction using generically complete isometry invariants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59938-z</link>
      <description>Jonathan Balasingham, Viktor Zamaraev, Vitaliy Kurlin, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592660

                Abstract Periodic material or crystal property prediction using machine learning has grown popular in recent years as it provides a computationally efficient replacement for classical simulation methods. A crucial first step for any of these algorithms is the representation used for a periodic crystal. While similar objects like molecules and proteins have a finite number of atoms and their representation can be built based upon a finite point cloud interpretation, periodic crystals are unbounded in size, making their representation more challenging. In the present work, we adapt the Pointwise Distance Distribution (PDD), a continuous and generically complete isometry invariant for periodic point sets, as a representation for our learning algorithm. The PDD distinguished all (more than 660 thousand) periodic crystals in the Cambridge Structural Database as purely periodic sets of points without atomic types. We develop a transformer model with a modified self-attention mechanism that combines PDD with compositional information via a spatial encoding method. This model is tested on the crystals of the Materials Project and Jarvis-DFT databases and shown to produce accuracy on par with state-of-the-art methods while being several times faster in both training and prediction time.</description>
      <author>Jonathan Balasingham, Viktor Zamaraev, Vitaliy Kurlin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59938-z</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
