<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 01:38:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insight into defective molybdenum carbide as cathode catalyst in Li-CO2 battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fub.2025.100058</link>
      <description>Tingting Zhao, Lixiang Yan, Xueying Qiu, Liubin Song, Yanmei Nie, Yuhao Xiong, Ao Li, Yukang Su, Likai Yan, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408479150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Zhao, Lixiang Yan, Xueying Qiu, Liubin Song, Yanmei Nie, Yuhao Xiong, Ao Li, Yukang Su, Likai Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fub.2025.100058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the Ti:Al:Cr proportion on the structure and oxidation resistance of ternary intermetallic coatings produced by non-vacuum electron beam cladding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intermet.2025.108745</link>
      <description>Daria V. Lazurenko, Alexey A. Ruktuev, Yu. N. Malyutina, Gleb Dovzhenko, Lin Song, &#1053;. &#1057;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1072;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Elena Lozhkina, E. V. Domarov, Arina V. Ukhina, Intermetallics. 181(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408489714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daria V. Lazurenko, Alexey A. Ruktuev, Yu. N. Malyutina, Gleb Dovzhenko, Lin Song, &#1053;. &#1057;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1072;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Elena Lozhkina, E. V. Domarov, Arina V. Ukhina</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intermet.2025.108745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain engineering in gradient-structured metallic glasses for excellent overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.02.024</link>
      <description>Chaoqun Pei, Shuangqin Chen, Jiuyuan Xie, Shidong Feng, Mingyuan Yu, Cheng Zhan, Yuyang Qian, Guannan Yang, Yuxuan Chen, Si Lan, Erjun Kan, Yue Wang, Xiaoke Mu, Horst Hahn, Baoan Sun, Gerhard Wilde, Tao Feng, Materials Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408491533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoqun Pei, Shuangqin Chen, Jiuyuan Xie, Shidong Feng, Mingyuan Yu, Cheng Zhan, Yuyang Qian, Guannan Yang, Yuxuan Chen, Si Lan, Erjun Kan, Yue Wang, Xiaoke Mu, Horst Hahn, Baoan Sun, Gerhard Wilde, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.02.024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of novel Fe0.11V2O5.15/g-C3N4 for electrochemical paracetamol detection and electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109468</link>
      <description>Shakeel Ahmad, Iqra Fareed, Muhammad Danish Khan, Tahmina Maqsood, Muhammad Saeed Akhtar, Mashal Firdous, Zulfiqar Ali, Yahya Sandali, Muhammad Bilal Tahir, Faheem K. Butt, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 192(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408492629

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shakeel Ahmad, Iqra Fareed, Muhammad Danish Khan, Tahmina Maqsood, Muhammad Saeed Akhtar, Mashal Firdous, Zulfiqar Ali, Yahya Sandali, Muhammad Bilal Tahir, Faheem K. Butt</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Ti-Cu trimetallic sites mediated CO2 coordination model and enhanced surface frustrated Lewis pairs for controlling the selectivity of photoreduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2025.120206</link>
      <description>Hui Zhao, Jihai Duan, Zisheng Zhang, Weiwen Wang, Applied Catalysis A General. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408496460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Zhao, Jihai Duan, Zisheng Zhang, Weiwen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2025.120206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoscale high-entropy surface engineering promotes selective glycerol electro-oxidation to glycerate at high current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-025-01881-9</link>
      <description>Shuibo Wang, Yichao Lin, Y Li, Ziqi Tian, Yu Wang, Zhiyi Lu, Baoxin Ni, Kun Jiang, Hongbo Yu, Shiwei Wang, Hongfeng Yin, Liang Chen, Nature Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408502110

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuibo Wang, Yichao Lin, Y Li, Ziqi Tian, Yu Wang, Zhiyi Lu, Baoxin Ni, Kun Jiang, Hongbo Yu, Shiwei Wang, Hongfeng Yin, Liang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-025-01881-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical synthesis of methane on (110) facets of carbides via MvK mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146069</link>
      <description>Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408508284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Proton-Coupled Electron Transfer Mechanism in Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00203</link>
      <description>Muhammad Shahbaz Anwar, Yong Yu, Shahzad Rasool, Nabeela Akbar, Jianbing Huang, Manish Singh, Priyanka Gupta, Shuo Wan, Qiu&#8208;An Huang, Fan Yang, Muhammad Khalid, Rizwan Raza, Jun Wang, Yuzheng Lu, Sining Yun, Bin Zhu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408508765

                Proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) is not only an important fundamental process in energy systems but also a pivotal factor in enhancing electrocatalytic functions in fuel cells (FCs). This article investigates the PCET mechanism in low-temperature (300&#8211;500 &#176;C) protonic ceramic fuel cells, focusing on its role in catalyzing the hydrogen oxidation reaction and the oxygen reduction reaction. Our findings reveal that PCET significantly enhances the electrocatalytic activity by mitigating polarization losses, reducing charge-transfer resistance by 1 to 2 orders of magnitude, and thereby accelerating the reaction kinetics compared to scenarios without PCET. Importantly, changes in relaxation time upon proton injection evidence the robustness of PCET. The marked reduction in activation energy to 0.31 eV further illustrates how PCET overcomes energy barriers, facilitating more efficient reaction pathways. These insights highlight the critical role of PCET in optimizing the electrocatalytic performance of FCs, underscoring its significant importance in advancing FC technology.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Shahbaz Anwar, Yong Yu, Shahzad Rasool, Nabeela Akbar, Jianbing Huang, Manish Singh, Priyanka Gupta, Shuo Wan, Qiu&#8208;An Huang, Fan Yang, Muhammad Khalid, Rizwan Raza, Jun Wang, Yuzheng Lu, Sining Yun, Bin Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Photodeposited Noble Metal Nanoparticles on the Sacrificial-Agent-Free H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photosynthesis Performance of g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00311</link>
      <description>Guodan Wang, Tengfei Huang, Yongsheng Tan, Shiyan Liu, Rong Wu, Zebo Fang, Baocheng Yang, Shunhang Wei, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408513362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guodan Wang, Tengfei Huang, Yongsheng Tan, Shiyan Liu, Rong Wu, Zebo Fang, Baocheng Yang, Shunhang Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00311</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applications of machine learning in surfaces and interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0244175</link>
      <description>Shaofeng Xu, Jing&#8208;Yuan Wu, Ying Guo, Qing Zhang, Xiaoxia Zhong, Jinjin Li, Wei Ren, Chemical Physics Reviews. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408518586

                Surfaces and interfaces play key roles in chemical and material science. Understanding physical and chemical processes at complex surfaces and interfaces is a challenging task. Machine learning provides a powerful tool to help analyze and accelerate simulations. This comprehensive review affords an overview of the applications of machine learning in the study of surfaces and interfaces of chemical systems and materials. We categorize surfaces and interfaces into the following broad categories: solid&#8211;solid interface, solid&#8211;liquid interface, liquid&#8211;liquid interface, surface of solid, surface of liquid, and three-phase interfaces. High-throughput screening, combined machine learning and first-principles calculations, and machine learning force field accelerated molecular dynamics simulations are used to rational design and study physical and chemical processes of surfaces and interfaces in systems such as all-solid-state batteries, solar cells, and heterogeneous catalysis. This review provides detailed and comprehensive information on the applications of machine learning on surfaces and interfaces for chemical and material science.</description>
      <author>Shaofeng Xu, Jing&#8208;Yuan Wu, Ying Guo, Qing Zhang, Xiaoxia Zhong, Jinjin Li, Wei Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0244175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Coverage Dependence on the Thermophysical Properties of Adsorbates and Its Impact on Microkinetic Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c02167</link>
      <description>Jongyoon Bae, Bjarne Kreitz, Andrew A. Peterson, C. Franklin Goldsmith, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408528041

                This work focuses on the impact of lateral interactions on the thermophysical properties of adsorbates. We present different parametrizations for coverage-dependent enthalpy, entropy, and heat capacity in a mean-field microkinetic model. These models are tested against two systems, CO/Pt(111) and CO/Co(0001), using two different functionals. A detailed investigation into how coverage influences the thermophysical properties of CO* is presented. We place particular emphasis on studying the impact of coverage on the vibrational partition function and how this affects the entropy of adsorbates. Higher coverages typically lead to increased repulsive interactions, which should further constrain the large amplitude modes that contribute the most to the vibrational entropy. In some cases, however, the opposite effect occurred; the vibrational entropy actually increased because surface crowding forced adsorbates to different binding locations that had lower frequencies. Our results highlighted cases where coverage-dependent entropy should be included, such as for adsorbates with lateral vibrational modes and systems at high temperatures. These methods for including coverage-dependent properties into mean-field microkinetics in a thermodynamically consistent way are now available in the open-source software Cantera.</description>
      <author>Jongyoon Bae, Bjarne Kreitz, Andrew A. Peterson, C. Franklin Goldsmith</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c02167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of Ga&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Ge&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; monolayer: a promising photocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra00812c</link>
      <description>Trung D. Pham, Hien D. Tong, RSC Advances. 15(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408530124

                The Ga 2 Ge 2 S 3 Se 3 monolayer: a promising 2D photocatalyst with high solar-to-hydrogen efficiency, efficient charge separation, and electron mobility.</description>
      <author>Trung D. Pham, Hien D. Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra00812c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of 3D Metal&#8208;Based Assemblies for Efficient Electrocatalysis: Structural and Mechanistic Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410390</link>
      <description>Nicole L. D. Sui, Jong&#8208;Min Lee, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408530767

                Abstract The commercial utilization of low&#8208;dimensional catalysts has been hindered by their propensity for agglomeration and stacking, greatly minimizing their utilization of active sites. To circumvent this problem, low&#8208;dimensional materials can be assembled into systematic 3D architectures to synergistically retain the benefits of their constituent low&#8208;dimensional nanomaterials, with value&#8208;added bulk properties such as increased active surface area, improved charge transport pathways, and enhanced mass transfer, leading to higher catalytic activity and durability compared to their constituents. The hierarchical organization of low&#8208;dimensional building blocks within 3D structures also enables precise control over the catalyst's morphology, composition, and surface chemistry, facilitating tailored design for specific electrochemical applications. Despite the surge in 3D metal&#8208;based assemblies, there are no reviews encompassing the different types of metal&#8208;based 3D assemblies from low&#8208;dimensional nanomaterials for electrocatalysis. Herein, this review addresses this gap by investigating the various types of self&#8208;supported 3D assemblies and exploring how their electrocatalytic performance can be elevated through structural modifications and mechanistic studies to tailor them for various electrochemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Nicole L. D. Sui, Jong&#8208;Min Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core/Shell&#8208;Structured Carbon Support Boosting Fuel Cell Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414472</link>
      <description>Tian&#8208;Wei Song, Jun Yan, Lei Tong, Zirui Li, Chang&#8208;Song Ma, Junjie Li, Cong Xu, Shuai Li, Ru&#8208;Yang Shao, Ming J. Zuo, Shengliang Zhong, Shengqi Chu, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408536229

                Abstract To enhance the lifetime of proton exchange membrane fuel cells, developing highly durable platinum&#8208;based cathode catalysts is essential. While two degradation pathways for the cathode catalyst&#8212;carbon corrosion and electrocatalyst (platinum nanoparticles) coarsening&#8212;have been identified, current approaches to enhance its durability are limited to addressing individual degradation pathways. Herein, the study develops a core/shell&#8208;structured carbon support that is designed to afford cathode catalysts capable of simultaneously inhibiting carbon corrosion and electrocatalyst coarsening. The core/shell structure is distinguished by its bifunctional nature: the core is made of highly graphitized carbon tailored to build a robust carbon skeleton, and the shell comprises heteroatom&#8208;doped amorphous carbon engineered to prevent electrocatalyst coarsening by chemical/physical anchoring of platinum nanoparticles. Thanks to this elaborate design, the catalyst surpasses the durability targets for carbon supports and electrocatalysts set by the U.S. Department of Energy, as supported by the achieved durability metrics after the square&#8208;wave/triangle&#8208;wave accelerated stress tests: electrochemical surface area loss at 13%/3%, mass activity loss at 27%/17%, and voltage loss of 29 mV (at 0.8 A cm &#8722; 2 )/4 mV (at 1.5 A cm &#8722; 2 ).</description>
      <author>Tian&#8208;Wei Song, Jun Yan, Lei Tong, Zirui Li, Chang&#8208;Song Ma, Junjie Li, Cong Xu, Shuai Li, Ru&#8208;Yang Shao, Ming J. Zuo, Shengliang Zhong, Shengqi Chu, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trimodal Hierarchical Porous Carbon Nanoplates with Edge Curvature for Faster Mass Transfer and Enhanced Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06404</link>
      <description>Ruijing Xin, Ho Ngoc Nam, Quan Manh Phung, Jing Tang, Shengchun Ma, Josua Markus, Yuchen Dai, Azhar Alowasheeir, Nithima Khaorapapong, Jie Wang, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yusuf Valentino Kaneti, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408540705

                Although hierarchical porous carbon materials have been widely used for electrocatalysis, the role of curvature in carbon nanostructures during electrochemical reactions remains poorly understood due to a lack of experimental models featuring clearly defined curved geometries and periodic structures. In this study, we fabricate hierarchical porous cobalt- and nitrogen-containing carbon nanoplates with trimodal porosity (macro-, meso-, and micropores) and continuous, homogeneous curved edges (Co/N-CNP-CURV) using a polystyrene-directed templating approach. The Co/N-CNP-CURV catalyst exhibits excellent catalytic activity and stability for the alkaline oxygen reduction reaction, with a half-wave potential of 0.82 V and a minimal potential shift of 8 mV after 5000 cycles. The enhanced electrocatalytic activity is attributed to synergistic combinations of the trimodal porosity, abundant Co-Nx active sites, a high density of curved edges, and graphitic carbon encapsulated with cobalt nanoparticles. Density functional theory calculations reveal that the presence of curvature in Co/N-CNP-CURV is beneficial for enhancing the charge transfer from the catalyst to O2, lowering the adsorption energy of O2, and reducing the activation free energy barrier for the rate-determining step (*O2 + (H+ + e-) &#8594; *OOH). The study provides compelling experimental evidence supporting the critical role of the curvature effect in enhancing the electrocatalytic performance of nanoporous metal-containing carbon materials.</description>
      <author>Ruijing Xin, Ho Ngoc Nam, Quan Manh Phung, Jing Tang, Shengchun Ma, Josua Markus, Yuchen Dai, Azhar Alowasheeir, Nithima Khaorapapong, Jie Wang, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yusuf Valentino Kaneti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reactivity on the SiC Monolayer with Doped Topological Defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05828</link>
      <description>Wallace P. Morais, Guilherme J. Inacio, Eduardo Alves de Almeida, F&#225;bio A. L. de Souza, F. N. N. Pansini, Wendel S. Paz, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408549449

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wallace P. Morais, Guilherme J. Inacio, Eduardo Alves de Almeida, F&#225;bio A. L. de Souza, F. N. N. Pansini, Wendel S. Paz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptors of InZrO&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; vs ZnZrO&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404967</link>
      <description>Tangsheng Zou, Elisavet Tazedaki, Konstantin M. Engel, Y. Chiang, Mikhail Agrachev, Katja Raue, Frank Krumeich, Henrik Eliasson, Rolf Erni, Wendelin J. Stark, Robert N. Grass, Thaylan Pinheiro Ara&#250;jo, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408550554

                Abstract Indium&#8208;zirconium (InZrO x ) and zinc&#8208;zirconium oxides (ZnZrO x ) have emerged as highly selective and stable catalysts for CO 2 hydrogenation to methanol, a versatile energy carrier. However, the disparity in synthesis methods, catalyst formulations, and structures previously studied precludes quantitative comparisons between the two families. Herein, a rigorous framework is pioneered to benchmark InZrO x and ZnZrO x materials prepared by a standardized flame spray pyrolysis synthesis platform, enabling consistently high surface areas and tunable metal speciation ranging from isolated atoms (&lt;5 mol%) to predominantly nanoparticles (&gt;10 mol%). Isolated indium and zinc species are commonly identified to be optimal for activity and methanol selectivity in their respective families, maximizing CO 2 and H 2 activation abilities. InZrO x outperforms ZnZrO x across speciations and is less structure sensitive, as deviations from atomic dispersion is less detrimental on performance for the former. Focusing on representative catalysts featuring saturation of isolated species, the higher activity of 5 mol% InZrO x over its ZnZrO x counterpart is linked to differences in surface oxygen vacancy chemistry, a lower degree of product inhibition, and more facile hydrogenation of the formate intermediate to methoxy. The identification of reactivity descriptors governing both families facilitates the development of unified guidelines in designing reducible oxide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tangsheng Zou, Elisavet Tazedaki, Konstantin M. Engel, Y. Chiang, Mikhail Agrachev, Katja Raue, Frank Krumeich, Henrik Eliasson, Rolf Erni, Wendelin J. Stark, Robert N. Grass, Thaylan Pinheiro Ara&#250;jo, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliometric analysis and road-mapping on hydrogen production from biomass-derived glycerol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.095</link>
      <description>Usman Bello, Haruna Adamu, Shafirah Samsuri, Mohammad Qamar, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 117(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408559282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Usman Bello, Haruna Adamu, Shafirah Samsuri, Mohammad Qamar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of Electrocatalytic Selectivity during the Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Au(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04413</link>
      <description>Elias Diesen, Alexandra M. Dudzinski, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa J. Bukas, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408562170

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elias Diesen, Alexandra M. Dudzinski, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa J. Bukas</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proximity defect inductive effect of atomic Ni-N3 sites by Te atoms doping for efficient oxygen reduction and hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.003</link>
      <description>Min Li, Xiuhui Zheng, Han Guo, Xiang Feng, Yunqi Liu, Yuan Pan, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408564778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Li, Xiuhui Zheng, Han Guo, Xiang Feng, Yunqi Liu, Yuan Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The advances in innovative amorphous noble-metal-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101324</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Fan, Kexin Yin, Huiqing Wang, Jinlong Zheng, Jie Lin, Binbin Jia, Mingyuan Xu, Liqun Ye, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408573547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Fan, Kexin Yin, Huiqing Wang, Jinlong Zheng, Jie Lin, Binbin Jia, Mingyuan Xu, Liqun Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Promotion of Transition-Metal-Doped Graphene Cathodes in Li-CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06763</link>
      <description>Peter P. Bazianos, Zhen Jiang, Andrew M. Rappe, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408574372

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peter P. Bazianos, Zhen Jiang, Andrew M. Rappe</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in modeling complex materials: The rise of neuroevolution potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0259061</link>
      <description>Penghua Ying, Qian Cheng, Rui Zhao, Yanzhou Wang, Ke Xu, Feng Ding, Shunda Chen, Zheyong Fan, Chemical Physics Reviews. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408575052

                Interatomic potentials are essential for driving molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, directly impacting the reliability of predictions regarding the physical and chemical properties of materials. In recent years, machine-learned potentials (MLPs), trained against first-principles calculations, have become a new paradigm in materials modeling as they provide a desirable balance between accuracy and computational cost. The neuroevolution potential (NEP) approach, implemented in the open-source GPUMD software, has emerged as a promising machine-learned potential, exhibiting impressive accuracy and exceptional computational efficiency. This review provides a comprehensive discussion on the methodological and practical aspects of the NEP approach, along with a detailed comparison with other representative state-of-the-art MLP approaches in terms of training accuracy, property prediction, and computational efficiency. We also demonstrate the application of the NEP approach to perform accurate and efficient MD simulations, addressing complex challenges that traditional force fields typically cannot tackle. Key examples include structural properties of liquid and amorphous materials, chemical order in complex alloy systems, phase transitions, surface reconstruction, material growth, primary radiation damage, fracture in two-dimensional materials, nanoscale tribology, and mechanical behavior of compositionally complex alloys under various mechanical loadings. This review concludes with a summary and perspectives on future extensions to further advance this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <author>Penghua Ying, Qian Cheng, Rui Zhao, Yanzhou Wang, Ke Xu, Feng Ding, Shunda Chen, Zheyong Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0259061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in the synthesis of Fe-based bimetallic electrocatalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra08833f</link>
      <description>Ayesha Zafar, Adnan Majeed, Abdul Ahad, Muhammad Adnan Iqbal, Tanveer Hussain Bokhari, Zanira Mushtaq, Shahzaib Ali, RSC Advances. 15(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408578146

                Achieving carbon neutrality and mitigating global warming through efficient CO 2 reduction, by utilizing synergistic bimetallic Fe-based catalysts for enhanced electrochemical performance and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Ayesha Zafar, Adnan Majeed, Abdul Ahad, Muhammad Adnan Iqbal, Tanveer Hussain Bokhari, Zanira Mushtaq, Shahzaib Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra08833f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immunoelectrochemical assessment of human IgE in non-invasive samples of allergic individuals using PdNCs-labelled antibodies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00604-025-07083-3</link>
      <description>Alejandro Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Penedo, Estefan&#237;a Costa&#8208;Rama, Rosario Pereiro, Beatriz Fern&#225;ndez, M. Teresa Fern&#225;ndez&#8208;Abedul, Microchimica Acta. 192(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408585023

                Abstract The escalating global prevalence of allergies presents a substantial public health challenge. Immunoglobulin E (IgE) serves as a key biomarker for allergic diseases, often measured in blood serum by ELISA immunoassays. Despite recent interest in minimally invasive sampling of biological fluids, the low sample volumes and IgE concentrations demand highly sensitive methodologies, typically confined to centralized laboratories. In this article, a decentralizable approach based on competitive immunoassays using Pd nanocluster (PdNCs)-labelled antibodies for electrochemical detection is proposed. With this aim, PdNCs were successfully bioconjugated with an anti-hIgE antibody to perform competitive immunoassays. To improve the analytical capabilities of the methodology, disposable screen-printed carbon electrodes with dual working electrodes were used for enhancing precision. Prior electrodeposition of PdNCs at &#8722; 0.6 V for 90 s significantly improved sensitivity (7.1 &#181;A g ng&#8315; 1 ) and lowered the limit of detection (LoD) to 0.3 ng g&#8315; 1 for PdNCs determination. The use of PdNCs as labels resulted in an improvement in the LoD for IgE determination. Calibration curves performed using competitive immunoassays for IgE determination, ranging from 10 &#8722;5 to 10 2 ng g &#8722;1 , demonstrated sensitivity comparable to high-tech methods, with a LoD of 0.008 ng g &#8722;1 for electrochemical measurements. Bimodal detection of Pd (linear sweep voltammetry and inductively coupled plasma&#8211;mass spectrometry) in various biological fluids (saliva, tears, nasal exudate, capillary blood, and blood serum) revealed significant differences in IgE levels between allergic and non-allergic individuals. Notably, capillary blood correlated strongly with serum blood, and a certain correlation has also been found with nasal exudate. The electrochemical approach, combining sensitivity and precision with non-invasive sampling, offers a simplified alternative for IgE determination in allergic disease. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Alejandro Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Penedo, Estefan&#237;a Costa&#8208;Rama, Rosario Pereiro, Beatriz Fern&#225;ndez, M. Teresa Fern&#225;ndez&#8208;Abedul</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00604-025-07083-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Tailoring of Pt Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts at Room Temperature and Their Exceptional Performance in Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.720</link>
      <description>Joo&#8208;Won Lee, H. U. Din, Taehun Im, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Jong Min Kim, Jung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Sohee Jeong, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408589530

                ABSTRACT Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have garnered interest in designing their ligand environments, facilitating the modification of single catalytic sites toward high activity and selectivity. Despite various synthetic approaches, it remains challenging to achieve a catalytically favorable coordination structure simultaneously with the feasible formation of SACs at low temperatures. Here, a new type of coordination structure for Pt SACs is introduced to offer a highly efficient hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst, where Pt SACs are readily fabricated by atomically confining PtCl 2 on chemically driven NO 2 sites in two&#8208;dimensional nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanosheets at room temperature. The resultant Pt SACs form the NO 2 &#8211;Pt&#8211;Cl 2 coordination structure with an atomic dispersion, as revealed by X&#8208;ray spectroscopy and transmission electron microscopy investigations. Moreover, our first&#8208;principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations show strong interactions in the coordination by computing the binding energy and charge density difference between PtCl 2 and NO 2 . Pt SACs, established on the NO 2 &#8208;functionalized carbon support, demonstrate the onset potential of 25 mV, Tafel slope of 40 mV dec &#8722;1 , and high specific activity of 1.35 A mg Pt &#8722;1 . Importantly, the Pt SACs also exhibit long&#8208;term stability up to 110 h, which is a significant advance in the field of single&#8208;atom Pt catalysts. The newly developed coordination structure of Pt SACs features a single Pt active center, providing hydrogen binding ability comparable to that of Pt(111), enhanced long&#8208;term durability due to strong metal&#8208;support interactions, and the advantage of room&#8208;temperature fabrication.</description>
      <author>Joo&#8208;Won Lee, H. U. Din, Taehun Im, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Jong Min Kim, Jung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Sohee Jeong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.720</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlated Flat-Bottom Elastic Network Model for Improved Bond Rearrangement in Reaction Paths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01549</link>
      <description>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408593368

                This study introduces correlated flat-bottom elastic network model (CFB-ENM), an extension of our recently developed flat-bottom elastic network model (FB-ENM) for generating plausible reaction paths, i.e., collision-free paths preserving nonreactive parts. While FB-ENM improved upon the widely used image-dependent pair potential (IDPP) by addressing unintended structural distortion and bond breaking, it still struggled with regulating the timing of series of bond breaking and formation. CFB-ENM overcomes this limitation by incorporating structure-based correlation terms. These terms impose constraints on pairs of atom pairs, ensuring immediate formation of new bonds after breaking of existing bonds. Using the direct MaxFlux method, we generated paths for 121 reactions involving main group elements and 35 reactions involving transition metals. We found that CFB-ENM significantly improves reaction paths compared to FB-ENM. CFB-ENM paths exhibited lower maximum DFT energies along the paths in most reactions, with nearly half showing significant energy reductions of several tens of kcal/mol. In the few cases where CFB-ENM yielded higher energy paths, most increases were below 10 kcal/mol. We also confirmed that CFB-ENM reduces computational costs in subsequent precise reaction path or transition state searches compared to FB-ENM. An implementation of CFB-ENM based on the Atomic Simulation Environment is available on GitHub for use in computational chemistry research.</description>
      <author>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substitution and coordination effects of boron in Fe C and Fe N C single-atom catalysts for ORR: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115192</link>
      <description>Liang Sun, Zhiyu Wang, Yusu Wang, Yong Wang, Li Y, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408597576

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Sun, Zhiyu Wang, Yusu Wang, Yong Wang, Li Y</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposition of oxy-carbide of CrMnFeCoNi and measurement of catalytic activity on oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10800-025-02295-0</link>
      <description>Rongguang Wang, Ayumu Okawa, Mohammed Bazzaoui, Yunhan Ling, Journal of Applied Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408598548

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rongguang Wang, Ayumu Okawa, Mohammed Bazzaoui, Yunhan Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10800-025-02295-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational toolkit for predicting thickness of 2D materials using machine learning and autogenerated dataset by large language model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241511</link>
      <description>Chinedu Ekuma, AIP Advances. 15(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408612999

                The thickness of 2D materials not only plays a crucial role in determining the performance of nanoelectronic and optoelectronic devices but also introduces complexities in predicting volume-dependent properties, such as energy storage capacity, due to the intrinsic vacuum within these materials. Although a plethora of experimental techniques, including but not limited to optical contrast, Raman spectroscopy, nonlinear optical spectroscopy, near-field optical imaging, and hyperspectral imaging, facilitate the measurement of 2D material thickness, comprehensive data for many materials remain elusive. Over the past decade, the exponential proliferation of 2D materials and their heterostructures has outstripped the capabilities of conventional experimental and computational approaches. In this evolving landscape, machine learning (ML) has emerged as an indispensable tool, offering a scalable approach to augment these traditional methodologies. Addressing the critical gap, we introduce THICK2D&#8212;Thickness Hierarchy Inference and Calculation Kit for 2D Materials. This Python-based computational framework harnesses an autogenerated thickness database, developed using large language models, and advanced ML algorithms to facilitate the rapid and scalable estimation of material thickness, relying solely on crystallographic data. To demonstrate the utility and robustness of THICK2D, we successfully used the toolkit to predict the thickness of more than 8000 2D-based materials, sourced from two extensive 2D materials databases. THICK2D is disseminated as an open-source utility, accessible on GitHub at https://github.com/gmp007/THICK2D, and archived on Zenodo at https://10.5281/zenodo.11216648.</description>
      <author>Chinedu Ekuma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of order of transfer matrix exceptional points on transport at band edges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.125412</link>
      <description>Madhumita Saha, Bijay Kumar Agarwalla, Manas Kulkarni, Archak Purkayastha, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408614195

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Madhumita Saha, Bijay Kumar Agarwalla, Manas Kulkarni, Archak Purkayastha</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.125412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An overview of design strategies and recent advancements in complex 3d transition metal-based electrocatalysts for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44405-025-00001-4</link>
      <description>Seongbeom Lee, Yoojin Shin, Kyungbeen Yeom, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, No host. 1(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408622797

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical half-reaction in numerous electrochemical processes, such as water electrolysis, CO 2 reduction, and metal-air batteries, yet its sluggish kinetics significantly limit overall efficiency, requiring advanced catalysts. Earth-abundant transition metal-based multi-metal catalysts have emerged as promising alternatives to precious metal-based systems, offering tunable properties and enhanced catalytic performance, particularly in alkaline environments. Given the promising potential of these catalysts, an in-depth understanding of the relationship between their catalytic properties and activity is essential for enabling rational catalyst design. This review outlines fundamental OER mechanisms, followed by a discussion of design principles for multi-metal catalysts, focusing on activity descriptors and dynamic surface reconstruction. Recent advancements in multi-metal catalysts are evaluated, highlighting innovative strategies and breakthroughs. Lastly, the review addresses remaining challenges and future directions, emphasizing the need for deeper insights into synergistic interactions among catalyst components and the development of catalysts to meet practical-scale performance demands.</description>
      <author>Seongbeom Lee, Yoojin Shin, Kyungbeen Yeom, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44405-025-00001-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Layer Thickness Modulated the Catalytic Activity of Platinum for Oxygen Reduction and Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401978</link>
      <description>Sheng&#8208;Yao Lv, Jin Liu, Zhuoyang Xie, Li Li, Zidong Wei, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408633871

                Abstract Reducing platinum (Pt) usage and enhancing its catalytic performance in the hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are vital for advancing fuel cell technology. This study presents the design and investigation of monolayer and few&#8208;layer Pt structures with high platinum utilization, developed through theoretical calculations. By minimizing the metal thickness from 1 to 3 atomic layers, an atomic utilization rate ranging from 66.66% to 100% is achieved, in contrast to conventional multilayer Pt structures. This reduction resulted in a unique surface coordination environment. These thinner structures exhibited nonlinear fluctuations in key electronic characteristics&#8212;such as the d&#8208;band center, surface charge, and work function&#8212;as the atomic layer thickness decreased. These variations significantly impacted species adsorption and the Pt&#8208;H 2 O interfacial structure, which in turn affected the catalytic activity. Notably, 1&#8208;layer Pt exhibited the best performance for HOR, while 3&#8208;layer Pt showed high activity for both HOR and ORR. The findings establish a clear relationship between atomic layer thickness, surface characteristics, adsorption behavior, electric double&#8208;layer structure, and catalytic performance in Pt systems. This research contributes to a deeper understanding of precision atomic&#8208;structured electrocatalyst design and paves the way for the development of highly effective, low&#8208;loading Pt&#8208;based catalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Sheng&#8208;Yao Lv, Jin Liu, Zhuoyang Xie, Li Li, Zidong Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable B&#8208;Doped Cobalt Phosphide Nanosheets Engineered via Phosphorus Activation of Co&#8208;MOFs for High Efficiency Alkaline Water&#8208;Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500334</link>
      <description>Dun Chan, Jun Ho Seok, Seong Chan Cho, Manjinder Singh, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Sang Uck Lee, Seunghyun Lee, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408634657

                Abstract Introducing secondary heteroatoms and simultaneous in situ surface modification can enhance electrocatalysts by affecting their porosity for adjusting electrochemically active surface area (ECSA), number of active sites, and electronic properties, thus mitigating the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline media. Here, mesoporous 3D heterostructures of boron&#8208;doped cobalt phosphide@nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanosheet network arrays are successfully grown on Ni foam as free&#8208;standing bifunctional electrocatalysts with controlled phosphorous levels (B&#8208;CoP x @NC/NF, x = 0.25, 0.5, and 1). Boron doping induces the Co active sites to bind O* and OOH* intermediates. Meanwhile, an optimal phosphorous content also leads to ideal adsorption strength at each reaction step, satisfying the Sabatier principle well. The optimal B&#8208;CoP 0.5 @NC/NF requires low overpotentials of 248 mV for OER and 95 mV for HER with long&#8208;term stability. The B&#8208;CoP 0.5 @NC/NF (+/&#8722;) electrolyzer exhibits a low cell potential of 1.59 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for overall water&#8208;splitting, with superior activity compared to the RuO 2 /NF(+)//20%Pt/NF(&#8722;) electrolyzer at high current densities above 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . Such exceptional bifunctional activities are attributed to the modulated electronic structure, lower charge&#8208;transfer resistance, higher ECSA, and inductive effect of B&#8208;doping, thus boosting both OER and HER activities in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Dun Chan, Jun Ho Seok, Seong Chan Cho, Manjinder Singh, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Sang Uck Lee, Seunghyun Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale designing principle of M-N-C towards high performance PEMFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.91</link>
      <description>Wenxin Guo, Yinghuan Liu, Huang Zhou, Yuen Wu, Microstructures. 5(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408646567

                Among the reported non-precious-metal catalysts, metal-nitrogen-carbon (M-N-C) catalysts have emerged as a research cornerstone in the field of electrocatalysis, showcasing unparalleled activity in oxygen reduction reactions that rivals or even exceeds that of commercial Pt catalysts. Despite boasting high atom utilization and adjustable effective activity centers, M-N-C catalysts suffer from inadequate long-term stability under high-pressure and harshly acidic conditions within proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). This drawback poses a significant challenge that critically limits their potential for widespread applications. From this perspective, we commence by delineating the pivotal strategies to augment the performance of M-N-C catalysts at the microscopic level, including the tuning of the intrinsic activity of individual active sites and the manipulation of their quantity. Furthermore, we delve into the benefits derived from the synergistic effects unleashed by the incorporation of multi-component active sites. At the mesoscopic level, this perspective engages with the design principles aimed at enhancing the activity and stability of M-N-C catalysts within the intricate three-phase boundary of PEMFCs. Ultimately, we prospect the opportunities and challenges facing the future evolution of M-N-C catalysts, with the aim of offering comprehensive guidance for the design and advancement of highly stable M-N-C catalysts tailored for PEMFC applications.</description>
      <author>Wenxin Guo, Yinghuan Liu, Huang Zhou, Yuen Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.91</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orbital Matching Mechanism&#8208;Guided Synthesis of Cu&#8208;Based Single Atom Alloys for Acidic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500343</link>
      <description>Yi Xu, Jia&#8208;hui Li, Jia Chen Wu, Wenbo Li, Yuwei Yang, Haoran Wu, Huai Qin Fu, Minghui Zhu, Xue Lu Wang, Sheng Dai, Cheng Lian, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408648421

                Abstract Recent advancements in alloy catalysis have yield novel materials with tailored functionalities. Among these, Cu&#8208;based single&#8208;atom alloy (SAA) catalysts have attracted significant attention in catalytic applications for their unique electronic structure and geometric ensemble effects. However, selecting alloying atoms with robust dispersion stability on the Cu substrate is challenging, and has mostly been practiced empirically. The fundamental bottleneck is that the microscopic mechanism that governs the dispersion stability is unclear, and a comprehensive approach for designing Cu&#8208;based SAA systems with simultaneous dispersion stability and high catalytic activity is still missing. Here, combining theory and experiment, a simple yet intuitive d &#8208; p orbital matching mechanism is discovered for rapid assessment of the atomic dispersion stability of Cu&#8208;based SAAs, exhibiting its universality and extensibility for screening effective SAAs across binary, ternary and multivariant systems. The catalytic selectivity of the newly designed SAAs is demonstrated in a prototype reaction&#8208;acidic CO 2 electroreduction, where all SAAs achieve single&#8208;carbon product selectivity exceeding 70%, with Sb 1 Cu reaching a peak CO faradaic efficiency of 99.73 &#177; 2.5% at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work establishes the fundamental design principles for Cu&#8208;based SAAs with excellent dispersion stability and selectivity, and will boost the development of ultrahigh&#8208;performance SAAs for advanced applications such as electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Yi Xu, Jia&#8208;hui Li, Jia Chen Wu, Wenbo Li, Yuwei Yang, Haoran Wu, Huai Qin Fu, Minghui Zhu, Xue Lu Wang, Sheng Dai, Cheng Lian, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen evolution reaction mechanism of Ni3Mo3N catalyst with fast water dissociation kinetics in alkaline solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135083</link>
      <description>Xuehua Liu, Xiaohan Hu, Liming Cai, Song Chen, Y. T. Lin, Xiaoyun Ye, Weiguo Wang, Fuel. 394(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408650987

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuehua Liu, Xiaohan Hu, Liming Cai, Song Chen, Y. T. Lin, Xiaoyun Ye, Weiguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization strategies for carbon dioxide electroreduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161665</link>
      <description>Yingying Duan, Weidong Ruan, Jingqi Guan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408661982

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingying Duan, Weidong Ruan, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Proton Source for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electro-Reduction on Cu(100) Using Many-Body Perturbation Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14108</link>
      <description>Dongfang Cheng, Ziyang Wei, Philippe Sautet, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408666044

                The protonation of CO is recognized as the rate-determining step in the generation of C1 products during the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) on Cu surfaces. However, the detailed mechanism and the precise proton source remain elusive. While density functional theory (DFT) calculations at the GGA level have been widely used, they struggle to accurately describe adsorbate-metal interactions and surface stability. Here, we employed the Random Phase Approximation (RPA), a method based on many-body perturbation theory, to overcome these limitations. We coupled the RPA framework with the linearized Poisson&#8211;Boltzmann equation to model solvation effects and a surface charging method to account for the influence of the electrochemical potential. Our study reveals that in neutral or alkaline electrolytes, adsorbed surface water acts as the proton source for *CO reduction to *COH over a broad potential range via the Grotthuss mechanism. At highly negative potentials, solvent water becomes the primary proton donor, with multiple competing mechanisms observed. In contrast, DFT-GGA functionals significantly underestimate the reaction barriers for *COH formation and consistently predict solvent water as the proton source across all potentials of interest. Additionally, RPA offers distinct insights into H2O adsorption and highlights the significant range of reducing potentials within which surface *OH can exist, which is crucial for accurate CO2RR modeling. These insights illustrate a pronounced divergence between RPA and DFT-GGA results. Our findings offer a fresh perspective on proton transfer in CO2RR and establish a framework for future theoretical studies on electrochemical processes.</description>
      <author>Dongfang Cheng, Ziyang Wei, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Calculations of Hydrogen Absorption and Diffusivity in Bulk CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c11470</link>
      <description>J.C. Stimac, Nir Goldman, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408667030

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J.C. Stimac, Nir Goldman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c11470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase Engineering Modulates the Electronic Structure of the IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction for Efficient and Stable Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c18288</link>
      <description>Shougang Sun, Ziqi Wan, Yingying Xu, Xuemei Zhou, Wei Gao, Jinjie Qian, Jie Gao, Dong Cai, Yongjie Ge, Huagui Nie, Zhi Yang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408667767

                The engineering of dual-functional catalytic systems capable of driving complete water dissociation in acidic environments represents a critical requirement for advancing proton exchange membrane electrolyzer technology, yet significant challenges remain. In this work, we investigate an IrO2/MoS2/CNT heterostructure catalyst demonstrating enhanced bifunctional performance for both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under acidic conditions. Strategic incorporation of IrO2 into the MoS2/CNT heterojunction induces a partial phase transformation from 2H to the metastable 1T configuration in MoS2, thereby modulating the electronic structure of IrO2 and improving the catalytic performance for overall water splitting. The optimized IrO2/MoS2/CNT catalyst exhibited exceptional overpotentials of 9 mV (HER) and 182 mV (OER) at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in acidic media. Full-cell evaluations further confirmed its practical potential, showing a 1.47 V operation voltage that outperforms standard Pt/C||IrO2 counterparts by 120 mV. The experimental results revealed that the n&#8211;n heterojunction between IrO2/CNT and MoS2/CNT generates a built-in electric field, enhancing charge redistribution and electron transport. Moreover, density functional theory simulations further identify iridium centers as dominant catalytic loci, with a metastable 1T-MoS2 phase mediating charge equilibration at atomic interfaces. This modification facilitates *OH adsorption and *OOH deprotonation and lowers the kinetic barrier during the water-splitting process.</description>
      <author>Shougang Sun, Ziqi Wan, Yingying Xu, Xuemei Zhou, Wei Gao, Jinjie Qian, Jie Gao, Dong Cai, Yongjie Ge, Huagui Nie, Zhi Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c18288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive-precision potentials for large-scale atomistic simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245877</link>
      <description>David Immel, Ralf Drautz, Godehard Sutmann, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408672723

                Large-scale atomistic simulations rely on interatomic potentials, providing an efficient representation of atomic energies and forces. Modern machine-learning (ML) potentials provide the most precise representation compared to electronic structure calculations, while traditional potentials provide a less precise but computationally much faster representation and, thus, allow simulations of larger systems. We present a method to combine a traditional and a ML potential into a multi-resolution description, leading to an adaptive-precision potential with an optimum of performance and precision in large, complex atomistic systems. The required precision is determined per atom by a local structure analysis and updated automatically during simulation. We use copper as demonstrator material with an embedded atom model as classical force field and an atomic cluster expansion (ACE) as ML potential, but, in principle, a broader class of potential combinations can be coupled by this method. The approach is developed for the molecular-dynamics simulator LAMMPS and includes a load-balancer to prevent problems due to the atom dependent force-calculation times, which makes it suitable for large-scale atomistic simulations. The developed adaptive-precision copper potential represents the ACE-forces with a precision of 10 me V/&#197; and the ACE-energy exactly for the precisely calculated atoms in a nanoindentation of 4 &#215; 106 atoms calculated for 100 ps and shows a speedup of 11.3 compared with a full ACE simulation.</description>
      <author>David Immel, Ralf Drautz, Godehard Sutmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unassisted electrochemical H2O2 production coupled to glycerol oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00774-y</link>
      <description>Dongrak Oh, Seon Woo Hwang, Dong Yeon Kim, Jesse E. Matthews, Jin&#8208;Young Lee, Jaime E. Avil&#233;s Acosta, Sang&#8208;Won Lee, Yi Xu, Ara Cho, Dong Un Lee, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Dong&#8208;Hwa Seo, Ji&#8208;Wook Jang, Nature Synthesis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408672915

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongrak Oh, Seon Woo Hwang, Dong Yeon Kim, Jesse E. Matthews, Jin&#8208;Young Lee, Jaime E. Avil&#233;s Acosta, Sang&#8208;Won Lee, Yi Xu, Ara Cho, Dong Un Lee, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Dong&#8208;Hwa Seo, Ji&#8208;Wook Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00774-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNT&#8208;Supported RuNi Composites Enable High Round&#8208;Trip Efficiency in Regenerative Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500416</link>
      <description>Chunfeng Li, Danning Li, Lubing Li, Haozhou Yang, Yan Zhang, Jinzhan Su, Lei Wang, Bin Liu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408674747

                Abstract Regenerative fuel cells hold significant potential for efficient, large&#8208;scale energy storage by reversibly converting electrical energy into hydrogen and vice versa, making them essential for leveraging intermittent renewable energy sources. However, their practical implementation is hindered by the unsatisfactory efficiency. Addressing this challenge requires the development of cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts. In this study, a carbon nanotube (CNT)&#8208;supported RuNi composite with low Ru loading is developed as an efficient and stable catalyst for alkaline hydrogen and oxygen electrocatalysis, including hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, hydrogen oxidation, and oxygen reduction reaction. Furthermore, a regenerative fuel cell using this catalyst composite is assembled and evaluated under practical relevant conditions. As anticipated, the system exhibits outstanding performance in both the electrolyzer and fuel cell modes. Specifically, it achieves a low cell voltage of 1.64 V to achieve a current density of 1 A cm &#8722; 2 for the electrolyzer mode and delivers a high output voltage of 0.52 V at the same current density in fuel cell mode, resulting in a round&#8208;trip efficiency (RTE) of 31.6% without further optimization. The multifunctionality, high activity, and impressive RTE resulted by using the RuNi catalyst composites underscore its potential as a single catalyst for regenerative fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Chunfeng Li, Danning Li, Lubing Li, Haozhou Yang, Yan Zhang, Jinzhan Su, Lei Wang, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Intricacies of Glycerol Hydrodeoxygenation on Copper Surface: A Comprehensive Investigation with the Aid of Machine Learning Force Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00302</link>
      <description>Srishti Gupta, Ajin Rajan, Edvin Fako, Tiago J. Goncalves, Imke B. M&#252;ller, Jithin John Varghese, Ansgar Sch&#228;fer, Sandip De, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408682965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Srishti Gupta, Ajin Rajan, Edvin Fako, Tiago J. Goncalves, Imke B. M&#252;ller, Jithin John Varghese, Ansgar Sch&#228;fer, Sandip De</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient exploration of reaction pathways using reaction databases and active learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235715</link>
      <description>Domantas Kuryla, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Adri C. T. van Duin, Angelos Michaelides, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408687121

                The fast and accurate simulation of chemical reactions is a major goal of computational chemistry. Recently, the pursuit of this goal has been aided by machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs), which provide energies and forces at quantum mechanical accuracy but at a fraction of the cost of the reference quantum mechanical calculations. Assembling the training set of relevant configurations is key to building the MLIP. Here, we demonstrate two approaches to training reactive MLIPs based on reaction pathway information. One approach exploits reaction datasets containing reactant, product, and transition state structures. Using an SN2 reaction dataset, we accurately locate reaction pathways and transition state geometries of up to 170 unseen reactions. In another approach, which does not depend on data availability, we present an efficient active learning procedure that yields an accurate MLIP and converged minimum energy path given only the reaction end point structures, avoiding quantum mechanics driven reaction pathway search at any stage of training set construction. We demonstrate this procedure on an SN2 reaction in the gas phase and with a small number of solvating water molecules, predicting reaction barriers within 20 meV of the reference quantum chemistry method. We then apply the active learning procedure on a more complex reaction involving a nucleophilic aromatic substitution and proton transfer, comparing the results against the reactive ReaxFF force field. Our active learning procedure, in addition to rapidly finding reaction paths for individual reactions, provides an approach to building large reaction path databases for training transferable reactive machine learning potentials.</description>
      <author>Domantas Kuryla, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Adri C. T. van Duin, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Study of Tri-Atomic Catalyst-Loaded Two-Dimensional Graphenylene for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040296</link>
      <description>Zhenghao Li, Haifeng Wang, Yan Gao, Catalysts. 15(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408689546

                As the energy crisis and environmental pollution continue to intensify, the demand for clean energy has increased. Using two-dimensional materials to catalyze overall water splitting is an important pathway for clean energy production. This study investigated the catalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) of tri-atomic clusters supported on a two-dimensional material, graphenylene (GPN). The structural stability of GPN was thoroughly investigated, and materials were employed as substrates to support a series of 28 distinct trimer clusters composed of 3d, 4d, and 5d transition metals. Ideal combinations of these systems were screened and designed. The loading configurations of TM3@GPN in two different systems were systematically studied. The stability of the catalyst was assessed by calculating the binding and cohesive energies and by performing molecular dynamics simulations, to confirm the catalyst stability. The optimal bifunctional catalysts for overall water splitting were identified as Au3@GPN, Pt3@GPN, and Pd3@GPN, all of which demonstrated superior overall water splitting performance. As a novel two-dimensional material, biphenylene-based materials, when used to support metal clusters as bifunctional catalysts for water splitting, represent an efficient and innovative approach.</description>
      <author>Zhenghao Li, Haifeng Wang, Yan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender Inequality in Scientific Production at Unicamp: a scientometric analysis of female participation essential for equity (2019&#8211;2023)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/2331186x.2025.2480502</link>
      <description>M&#225;rcio Souza Martins, Francisco Tadeu Gon&#231;alves de Oliveira Foz, Oscar Eliel, Marilda Solon Teixeira Bottesi, Cogent Education. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408694460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M&#225;rcio Souza Martins, Francisco Tadeu Gon&#231;alves de Oliveira Foz, Oscar Eliel, Marilda Solon Teixeira Bottesi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/2331186x.2025.2480502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auxetic &#947;-SnO monolayer as a high-performance catalyst for light-driven water splitting and oxygen reduction: Unveiling screening descriptors via machine learning-assisted dimensionality reduction strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236811</link>
      <description>Renxian Qin, Yali Lu, Xihang Zhang, Yu-Ling Song, Qingjun Zhou, Qiang Zhang, Journal of Power Sources. 641(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408705851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Renxian Qin, Yali Lu, Xihang Zhang, Yu-Ling Song, Qingjun Zhou, Qiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Charge Dynamics in a Silver Single-Atom Catalyst During the Light-Driven Oxidation of Benzyl Alcohol to Benzaldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05208</link>
      <description>Areti Moutsiou, Andrea Olivati, Luis A. Cipriano, Alessandra Sivo, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Giovanni Di Liberto, M. A. Kanso, Robert Wojcieszak, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Annamaria Petrozza, Gianvito Vil&#233;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408706893

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Areti Moutsiou, Andrea Olivati, Luis A. Cipriano, Alessandra Sivo, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Giovanni Di Liberto, M. A. Kanso, Robert Wojcieszak, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Annamaria Petrozza, Gianvito Vil&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-specific stabilizing effect of single atoms on spinel oxides for acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100402</link>
      <description>Zhirong Zhang, Peiyu Ma, Chuanyi Jia, Wenting Gao, Mingkai Liu, Kwun Nam Hui, Ming J. Zuo, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng, eScience. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408608961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhirong Zhang, Peiyu Ma, Chuanyi Jia, Wenting Gao, Mingkai Liu, Kwun Nam Hui, Ming J. Zuo, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic simulation of batteries via machine learning force fields: from bulk to interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.02.051</link>
      <description>Jinkai Zhang, Yaopeng Li, Ming Chen, Jiaping Fu, Liang Zeng, Xi Tan, Tian Sun, Guang Feng, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408541579

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinkai Zhang, Yaopeng Li, Ming Chen, Jiaping Fu, Liang Zeng, Xi Tan, Tian Sun, Guang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.02.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning interatomic potential for the low-modulus Ti-Nb-Zr alloys in the vicinity of dynamical instability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2025.113865</link>
      <description>B. O. Mukhamedov, Ferenc Tasn&#225;di, Igor A. Abrikosov, Materials &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408702791

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. O. Mukhamedov, Ferenc Tasn&#225;di, Igor A. Abrikosov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2025.113865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk-based process design and operations through an operability approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2025.03.010</link>
      <description>Beatriz Dantas, Austin Braniff, Claudemi A. Nascimento, Theodore Malencia, Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian, Process Safety and Environmental Protection. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408703185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Beatriz Dantas, Austin Braniff, Claudemi A. Nascimento, Theodore Malencia, Fernando V. Lima, Yuhe Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2025.03.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel and efficient In2O3@RhPt catalyst for solvent-free transfer hydrogenation of TDC to HTDC: Catalytic performance and mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161742</link>
      <description>Yaqi Qu, Min He, Hualiang An, Xinqiang Zhao, Yanji Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408704559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaqi Qu, Min He, Hualiang An, Xinqiang Zhao, Yanji Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161742</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
