<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 01:25:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion power spectra as a window into dynamic materials architecture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adt6144</link>
      <description>S Fricke, Mia Salgado, Shira Haber, J&#233;r&#233;my Demarteau, Mutian Hua, Ah&#8208;Young Song, Brett A. Helms, Jeffrey A. Reimer, Science Advances. 11(15)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409357139

                Chemical recycling of commodity and specialty polymers presents a multifaceted challenge for industrial societies. On one hand, macromolecular architectures must be engineered to yield durable products that, on the other hand, rapidly deconstruct to recyclable monomers under pre-determined conditions. Polymer deconstruction is a chemical process that requires deep understanding of molecular reactivity in heterogeneous media, where porous material architectures evolve in both space and time. To build this understanding, we develop herein experimental and analytical methods describing sets of diffusive eigenmodes that exist within time-varying, non-Euclidean boundary conditions, a situation commonly encountered in the reactive deconstruction of polymers where chain fragments splay, alter their local dynamics, and evolve in their confinement of reacting media. Diffusion power spectra, discerned experimentally by NMR, yield polymer and solvent frequency-domain velocity autocorrelation functions that are analyzed in the context of physical models for chemical reactions parameterized with fractal mathematics. The results connect local motion in polymers to chemical reactivity during acidolysis of circular elastomers.</description>
      <author>S Fricke, Mia Salgado, Shira Haber, J&#233;r&#233;my Demarteau, Mutian Hua, Ah&#8208;Young Song, Brett A. Helms, Jeffrey A. Reimer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adt6144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Role of Bridge Adsorbed Hydrogen Intermediate on Pt&#8211;Ru Pair for Efficient Acidic Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202503221</link>
      <description>Hao Zhao, Baoxin Ni, Yongyu Pan, Yuze Li, Jun Li, Guo&#8208;Liang Wang, Zhiqing Zou, Kun Jiang, Qing&#8208;Qing Cheng, Lianhai Zu, Hui Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409361094

                Abstract Atop and multiple adsorbed hydrogen are considered as key intermediates on Pt&#8208;group metal for acidic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), yet the role of bridge hydrogen intermediate ( * H bridge ) is consistently overlooked experimentally. Herein, a Pt atomic chain modified fcc &#8208;Ru nanocrystal (Pt&#8211;Ru( fcc )) is developed with a co&#8208;crystalline structure, featuring * H bridge intermediate bonded on the Pt&#8211;Ru pair site. Electrons leap from the pair site to * H bridge facilitate hydrogen desorption, thus accelerating the Tafel kinetics and ensuring outstanding electrocatalytic performance, with a low overpotential (4.0 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and high turnover frequency (56.4 H 2 s &#8722;1 at 50 mV). Notably, the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer PEMWE with ultra&#8208;low loading of 10 ug Pt cm &#8722;2 shows excellent activity (1.61 V at 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 ) and low average degradation rate (4.0 &#181;V h &#8722;1 over 1000 h), significantly outperforming the benchmark Pt/C. Furthermore, the PEMWE&#8208;based 80 &#181;m Gore membrane under identical operating conditions requires only 1.54 and 1.58 V to achieve 1.0 and 1.5 A cm &#8722;2 . This finding highlights the key role of * H bridge at the Pt&#8211;Ru interface in obtaining high HER intrinsic activity and underscores the transformative potential in designing next&#8208;generation bimetallic catalysts for clean hydrogen energy.</description>
      <author>Hao Zhao, Baoxin Ni, Yongyu Pan, Yuze Li, Jun Li, Guo&#8208;Liang Wang, Zhiqing Zou, Kun Jiang, Qing&#8208;Qing Cheng, Lianhai Zu, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202503221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering innovative catalysts for efficient CO2 reduction toward carbon neutrality</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.116621</link>
      <description>Muhammad Awais, Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409371439

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Awais, Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.116621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new class of solid electrolytes with an ultra-low Na-ion migration barrier</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236979</link>
      <description>Artem D. Dembitskiy, Sergey N. Marshenya, Evgeny V. Antipov, Stanislav S. Fedotov, Dmitry A. Aksyonov, Journal of Power Sources. 642(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409371810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Artem D. Dembitskiy, Sergey N. Marshenya, Evgeny V. Antipov, Stanislav S. Fedotov, Dmitry A. Aksyonov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt 5d Density of States in Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalyst Governed by Ligand Effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00201</link>
      <description>Jiabin Xu, Jiatang Chen, Yun Mui Yiu, Jun Zhong, Yining Huang, Tsun&#8208;Kong Sham, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409372196

                In alloy systems, the strain and ligand effects are prevalent, but it is challenging to study the impact of either on the material structure independently. We conducted high-energy-resolution fluorescence detection (HERFD) X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and resonant X-ray emission spectroscopy (XES)/resonant inelastic X-ray scattering (RIXS) spectroscopy on a Pt3Mg alloy-based carbon material (Pt3Mg-N-C). By introducing a size-comparable atom, the strain effect is minimized, allowing the Pt d-density of states (d-DOS) to be primarily affected by the ligand effect. The experimental results reveal that Pt gains electrons in Pt3Mg-N-C, exhibiting a more symmetric d-band shape and a downshift of the d-band center compared to Pt metal, which is further confirmed by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The correlation between the Pt d-DOS and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity is also discussed.</description>
      <author>Jiabin Xu, Jiatang Chen, Yun Mui Yiu, Jun Zhong, Yining Huang, Tsun&#8208;Kong Sham</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiggle150: Benchmarking Density Functionals and Neural Network Potentials on Highly Strained Conformers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00015</link>
      <description>Rebecca Brew, Ian A. Nelson, Meruyert Binayeva, Amlan Nayak, W. Kyle Simmons, Joseph J. Gair, Corin Wagen, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409372236

                Accurate benchmarks are key to assessing the accuracy and robustness of computational methods, yet most available benchmark sets focus on equilibrium geometries, limiting their utility for applications involving nonequilibrium structures such as ab initio molecular dynamics and automated reaction-path exploration. To address this gap, we introduce Wiggle150, a benchmark comprising 150 highly strained conformations of adenosine, benzylpenicillin, and efavirenz. These geometries&#9472;generated via metadynamics and scored using DLPNO-CCSD(T)/CBS reference energies&#9472;exhibit substantially larger deviations in bond lengths, angles, dihedrals, and relative energies than other conformer benchmarks. We evaluate a diverse array of computational methods, including density-functional theory, composite quantum chemical methods, semiempirical models, neural network potentials, and force fields, on predicting relative energies for this challenging benchmark set. The results highlight multiple methods along the speed-accuracy Pareto frontier and identify AIMNet2 as particularly robust among the NNPs surveyed. We anticipate that Wiggle150 will be used to validate computational protocols involving nonequilibrium systems and guide the development of new density functionals and neural network potentials.</description>
      <author>Rebecca Brew, Ian A. Nelson, Meruyert Binayeva, Amlan Nayak, W. Kyle Simmons, Joseph J. Gair, Corin Wagen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Understanding of &lt;scp&gt;LaTaON&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; Decorated With Metal Cocatalysts for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70047</link>
      <description>Xiang Zhang, Yue Liu, Xin Zhou, International Journal of Quantum Chemistry. 125(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409372862

                ABSTRACT LaTaON 2 is a promising visible&#8208;light&#8208;responsive photocatalyst for water splitting because of its broad visible light absorption and suitable band edge positions. However, the high defect concentration hinders the charge transfer and results in the poor photocatalytic performance of LaTaON 2 . Loading proper cocatalysts is one of the most efficient strategies for promoting charge separation/transfer and achieving high reaction activity. In this work, we have used density functional theory calculations to study the depositions of Pt, Ru, and Ni single atom cocatalysts on LaTaON 2 (010) surface. The most stable adsorption configuration is the same site for all the elements, namely the top of the N atom on the La&#8208;terminated surface and the fourfold hollow site on the Ta&#8208;terminated surface. The adsorption of the metal single atom on Ta&#8208;termination is stronger than that on La&#8208;termination due to the formation of more bonds. Upon the deposition, no localized impurity states appear in the middle of the forbidden gap since the n d states of metal adatoms are located within the valence band and conduction band of LaTaON 2 . The efficiency of the photocatalysts is probed by investigating their ability to adsorb the H atom in a thermodynamically favorable manner. Our results reveal that the energetically favorable sites of HER are the N atom on the La&#8208;termination and the O and N atoms on the Ta&#8208;termination, respectively. Compared with the clean surface, the surfaces with Pt, Ru, and Ni single adatoms exhibit higher performance for HER because loading metal cocatalysts can further activate the surface nonmetal atoms and reduce the Gibbs free energy of hydrogen adsorption. The work gives an atom&#8208;level insight into the role of metal single atom cocatalysts in the LaTaON 2 photocatalyst for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Xiang Zhang, Yue Liu, Xin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The influence of core-shell chemical ordering on the generation and transfer of hot carriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102693</link>
      <description>Junais Habeeb Mokkath, Materials Today Chemistry. 45(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409377309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junais Habeeb Mokkath</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating d-p Band Center Distance at Metallene-Derived BOx-NiOOH to Unlock Lattice Oxygen for High-Efficient Glycerol Electrooxidation Coupled Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125368</link>
      <description>Zhenyu Li, Hao Sun, Qiaoyu Liu, Yijing Pian, Guang Yang, Jing Yu, Zexuan Zheng, Xiyang Wang, Subhajit Jana, Xinyu Bai, Zhuoyuan Ma, Xiaoxin Zou, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Haibin Chu, Yimin A. Wu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409378296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenyu Li, Hao Sun, Qiaoyu Liu, Yijing Pian, Guang Yang, Jing Yu, Zexuan Zheng, Xiyang Wang, Subhajit Jana, Xinyu Bai, Zhuoyuan Ma, Xiaoxin Zou, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Haibin Chu, Yimin A. Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the covalency of Ru-O bonds by dynamic reconstruction for efficient acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58654-0</link>
      <description>Luqi Wang, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Sheng Zhao, Yue Wang, Shengli Bi, Shaoxiong Li, Jianjie Ma, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Linlin Li, Tsung&#8208;Yi Chen, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Feng Hu, Yuping Wu, Shiling Peng, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409383439

                Developing ruthenium-based oxide catalysts capable of suppressing lattice oxygen participation in the catalytic reaction process is crucial for maintaining stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under acidic conditions. Herein, we delicately construct a RuO2 nanoparticle-anchored LiCoO2 nanosheet electrocatalyst (RuO2/LiCoO2), achieving dynamic optimization of RuO2 during the reaction process and improving catalytic stability. Benefiting from the unique electrochemical delithiation characteristics of the LiCoO2 support, the covalency of the Ru-O bond is effectively regulated during the OER process. The weakened Ru-O covalent bond inhibits the participation of lattice oxygen in the catalytic reaction and ensures the continuous operation of the Ru active sites. Moreover, the extended Ru-O bond in the optimized RuO2/LiCoO2 catalyst reduces the formation energy barrier of the *OOH intermediates, accelerating the progress of the OER. As a result, the RuO2/LiCoO2 catalyst requires only an overpotential of 150 &#177; 2 mV at 10 mA cm-2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and operates stably for 2000 h at 1 A cm-2 in a proton exchange membrane water electrolysis. This work opens new avenues for designing efficient ruthenium-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Luqi Wang, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Sheng Zhao, Yue Wang, Shengli Bi, Shaoxiong Li, Jianjie Ma, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Linlin Li, Tsung&#8208;Yi Chen, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Feng Hu, Yuping Wu, Shiling Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58654-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus-doped CuS@NF: A promising bifunctional electrocatalyst for enhanced water splitting efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163254</link>
      <description>Javid Barqi Mirzanlou, Moein Mehri, A.H. Salehi, Mohammad Zarei&#8208;Jelyani, Yalda Tarpoudi Baheri, Anisa Mutiara Badri, S. Morteza Mousavi&#8208;Khoshdel, Ximeng Liu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409383592

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Javid Barqi Mirzanlou, Moein Mehri, A.H. Salehi, Mohammad Zarei&#8208;Jelyani, Yalda Tarpoudi Baheri, Anisa Mutiara Badri, S. Morteza Mousavi&#8208;Khoshdel, Ximeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic performance of Ni-based high-entropy alloys with unique structural features in alkaline and seawater electrolysis under &#8722;10 &#176;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.071</link>
      <description>Yong Pan, Fachang Zhao, Guoning Ji, Songlin Xu, Ruiyu Li, Huiya Zhou, Rongda Zhao, Depeng Zhao, Fufa Wu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 127(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409384654

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Pan, Fachang Zhao, Guoning Ji, Songlin Xu, Ruiyu Li, Huiya Zhou, Rongda Zhao, Depeng Zhao, Fufa Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pristine metal-organic framework electrocatalysts for hydrogen production: Role of electrocatalyst properties in basic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clce.2025.100170</link>
      <description>Liberty L. Mguni, Olga K. Mmelesi, Emmanuel Kweinor Tetteh, Nombeko Graceful Sijadu, Yali Yao, Sudesh Rathilal, Cleaner Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409385084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liberty L. Mguni, Olga K. Mmelesi, Emmanuel Kweinor Tetteh, Nombeko Graceful Sijadu, Yali Yao, Sudesh Rathilal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clce.2025.100170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Pynta-Based Curriculum for ML-Accelerated Calculation of Transition States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00305</link>
      <description>Trevor Price, Saurabh Sivakumar, Matthew S. Johnson, Judit Z&#225;dor, Ambarish Kulkarni, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409396104

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Trevor Price, Saurabh Sivakumar, Matthew S. Johnson, Judit Z&#225;dor, Ambarish Kulkarni</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of CO2 Sequestration in a Stack Storage Complex in the San Juan Basin, NM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/224355-ms</link>
      <description>Vida Ama Bodi, William Ampomah, Dung Bui, Najmudeen Sibaweihi, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409400080

                ABSTRACT Effective CO2 sequestration requires not only minimizing carbon emissions but also optimizing storage efficiency while ensuring the integrity of storage sites. This research focuses on the assessment of CO2 injection in a stack storage system, specifically targeting the Entrada (high-permeability) and Bluff (low-permeability) formations within the San Juan Basin. By leveraging a single well to inject CO2 across multiple formations, the goal is to enhance storage efficiency, reduce the spatial extent of CO2 plumes, and minimize the area requiring long-term monitoring. A high-resolution hydrodynamic reservoir model was developed and validated using historical injection rates and pressure data from nearby saltwater disposal wells. This model was used to simulate 30 years of CO2 injection, aiming to store 50MtCO2f through a stacked storage configuration. Three well-completion strategies were explored: (1) a base case with injection into Entrada only, (2) a case with commingled injection into both formations through a single well, and (3) 6 scenarios using smart well-completion techniques to simultaneously inject CO2 into the Entrada and Bluff formations at controlled rates. Different injection rates were tested to identify the best scenario that minimizes CO2 plume size while meeting the storage target. Simulation results from the base case of injecting into Entrada only revealed that at an injection rate of 80MMSCFD, 50MtCO2 can be injected over 30 years. The commingled injection case showed that over 90% of injected CO2 entered the Entrada formation, leading to larger plume size (64.69 square miles after 100 years of post-injection monitoring) and an expanded area requiring monitoring. In contrast, the optimized injection strategy, with CO2 allocated at varying rates (25%, 31%, and 34% of the total injection rate of 80MMSCD) to the Bluff formation, resulted in the best scenario case significantly reducing the Entrada plume spatial extent by 22% while increasing the plume size in the Bluff formation by approximately 94%, accompanied by a 77% increment in the storage capacity. Ultimately, the best scenario reduced the total area requiring monitoring, demonstrating the effectiveness of a stack storage approach in controlling CO2 migration and pressure fronts. This study highlights the importance of optimizing CO2 in stacked storage systems to maximize sequestration efficiency. By carefully managing injection rates, the spread of CO2 plumes can be controlled, reducing monitoring costs and ensuring safe, long-term storage. The findings provide valuable insights for improving the practical implementation of CO2 capture and storage projects using stack storage systems.</description>
      <author>Vida Ama Bodi, William Ampomah, Dung Bui, Najmudeen Sibaweihi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/224355-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of Ni- and Cu-Doped Molybdenum Ditelluride Electrocatalysts for Carbon Dioxide Reduction to Formic Acid and Carbon Monoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040377</link>
      <description>Bin Zhao, Junyou Wang, Rui Wan, Zhongyao Li, Catalysts. 15(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409409343

                Under mild conditions, the effective conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into formic acid (HCOOH) and carbon monoxide (CO) represents a promising avenue for mitigating greenhouse gas emissions and addressing energy crises. In this work, we analyzed the electro-catalytic activities of six metals (Ti, Fe, Ni, Cu, Zn, and Cr) anchored on monolayer molybdenum telluride (TM@MoTe2) for the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) from CO2 to HCOOH and CO. Compared to the reversible hydrogen electrode, the limiting potential for HCOOH production on Ni@MoTe2 is only about &#8722;0.38 V, and it is only about &#8722;0.20 V for the CO production on Cu@MoTe2. The limiting potential is concerned with the free energies of *OCHO and *COOH. Both the CO2RRs suppress the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and exhibit good selectivity for the desired reaction products. These features enable the efficient conversion of CO2 into HCOOH on Ni@MoTe2 or CO on Cu@MoTe2. Our calculations could provide valuable insights for the design and synthesis of high-performance catalysts based on MoTe2.</description>
      <author>Bin Zhao, Junyou Wang, Rui Wan, Zhongyao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Adhesion Energies of Late Transition Metal Nanoparticles to Oxide Support Surfaces Using Oxide Reducibility and Metal Oxophilicity: Toward Predicting Catalyst Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06983</link>
      <description>Nida Janulaitis, Charles T. Campbell, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409410723

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nida Janulaitis, Charles T. Campbell</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Origin of Li Underpotential and Overpotential Deposition on Current Collectors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01078</link>
      <description>Jiankun Pu, Venkatasubramanian Viswanathan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409413029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiankun Pu, Venkatasubramanian Viswanathan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving MoS2 hydrogen evolution performance in anion exchange membrane water electrolysis by using LaNi5 alloy as a co-catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180420</link>
      <description>Hao Shang, Hang Shi, Haoliang Yu, Xiaohong Hu, Yan Xia, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1025(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409416058

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Shang, Hang Shi, Haoliang Yu, Xiaohong Hu, Yan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180420</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-type-II photocatalytic overall water splitting in a single covalent organic frameworks monolayer with polarized linkage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.141</link>
      <description>Chonggui Zhong, Liqun Song, Xiangqian Lu, Wei Qin, Yingcai Fan, Jingping Yu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 127(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409416234

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chonggui Zhong, Liqun Song, Xiangqian Lu, Wei Qin, Yingcai Fan, Jingping Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanadium-Modulated Molybdenum/Nickel-Based Multi-Heterostructures finely tailoring d-Band centers for electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137543</link>
      <description>Guimin Wang, Xueting Li, J J Wang, Haijing Yan, Dou Zhang, Chungui Tian, Zhang Hai-sheng, Yanqing Jiao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409417383

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guimin Wang, Xueting Li, J J Wang, Haijing Yan, Dou Zhang, Chungui Tian, Zhang Hai-sheng, Yanqing Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles insights into metallic doping effects on yttrium twin grain boundary</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112742</link>
      <description>Guanlin Lyu, Yuanxu Zhu, Yuguo Sun, Panpan Gao, Ping Qian, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409419596

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanlin Lyu, Yuanxu Zhu, Yuguo Sun, Panpan Gao, Ping Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Subspace Approximation for Random Phase Approximation Correlation Energies: Applications to Materials for Catalysis and Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01276</link>
      <description>Jacob M. Clary, Olivia Hull, Daniel Weinberg, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Mauro Del Ben, Derek Vigil&#8208;Fowler, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409424379

                Modeling complex materials using high-fidelity, ab initio methods at low cost is a fundamental goal for quantum chemical software packages. The GW approximation and random phase approximation (RPA) provide a unified description of both electronic structure and total energies using the same physics in a many-body perturbative approach that can be more accurate than generalized-gradient density functional theory (DFT) methods. However, GW/RPA implementations have historically been limited to either specific materials classes or application toward small chemical systems. The static subspace approximation allows for reduced cost full-frequency GW/RPA calculations and has previously been benchmarked thoroughly for GW calculations. Here, we describe our approach to including partial occupations of electronic orbitals in full-frequency GW and RPA calculations for the study of electrocatalysts. We benchmarked RPA total energy calculations using the subspace approximation across a diverse test suite of materials for a variety of computational parameters. The benchmarking quantifies the impact of different extrapolation procedures for representing the static polarizability at infinite screened cutoff, and shows that using screened cutoffs above 20-25 Ryd result in diminishing accuracy returns for predicting RPA total energies. Additionally, for moderately sized electrocatalytic models, 2-3 times fewer computational resources are used to compute RPA total energies by representing the static polarizability with 20-30% of the static subspace basis, with an error of approximately 0.01 eV or better in RPA adsorption energy calculations. Finally, we show that for these electrochemical models RPA can shift DFT adsorption energy shifts by up to 0.5 eV and that GW can frequently shift DFT eigenvalues of surface and adsorbate states by approximately 0.5-1 eV.</description>
      <author>Jacob M. Clary, Olivia Hull, Daniel Weinberg, Ravishankar Sundararaman, Mauro Del Ben, Derek Vigil&#8208;Fowler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Charge, Modulating the Catalytic Activity of Single-Atom Metal Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17413</link>
      <description>Hansol Choi, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Geunsu Bae, Junsic Cho, Man Ho Han, Moulay Tahar Sougrati, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409425033

                Potential-induced electrode charging is a prerequisite to initiate electrochemical reactions at the electrode-electrolyte interface. The 'interface space charge' could dramatically alter the reaction environment and the charge density of the active site, both of which potentially affect the electrochemical activity. However, our understanding of the electrocatalytic role of space charge has been limited. Here, we separately modulate the amount of space charge (characterized by the areal density, &#963;) with maintaining the electrochemical potential for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at the same level, by exploiting the unique structural feature of MeNC. We reveal that changes in &#963; control the ORR activity, which is computationally explained by the inductive polarization of the charge density at the active sites, affecting their turnover rates. To guide catalyst design including the space charge effect, we develop a new descriptor, explaining the activity trend in various metal centers and pH conditions using a single volcano. These findings offer fresh insights into the role of space charge in electrocatalysis, providing a new framework for optimizing catalyst design and performance.</description>
      <author>Hansol Choi, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Geunsu Bae, Junsic Cho, Man Ho Han, Moulay Tahar Sougrati, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pt1Co1/CeO2 bimetallic single-atom catalyst with a strong Pt-Co synergistic effect for efficient oxidation of benzene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125369</link>
      <description>Siyi Ma, Chao Feng, Fang Dong, Shixing Wu, Weiliang Han, Weigao Han, Zhicheng Tang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409429227

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siyi Ma, Chao Feng, Fang Dong, Shixing Wu, Weiliang Han, Weigao Han, Zhicheng Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion with Cu&#8208;LDHs: A Review of Computational and Experimental Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202500014</link>
      <description>Fabio Loprete, Eleonora Tosi Brandi, Francesco Calcagno, Jacopo De Maron, Andrea Fasolini, Riccardo Tarroni, Francesco Basile, Ivan Rivalta, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409431547

                Abstract Layered Double Hydroxides (LDHs) are versatile materials with tuneable properties. They show promising electro&#8208; and photo&#8208;catalytic activity in the activation and conversion of CO 2 . Their unique properties make LDHs pivotal materials in emerging sustainable strategies for mitigating the effect of CO 2 emissions. However, the intricate structure&#8208;property relationship inherent to LDHs challenges their rational design. In this review, we provide a comprehensive overview of both experimental and computational studies about LDHs for photo&#8208; and electro&#8208;catalytic conversion of CO 2 , mainly focusing on Cu&#8208;based systems due to their superior performance in producing C 2 products. We present a background framework, describing the essentials computational and experimental tools, designed to support both experimentalists and theoreticians in the development of tailored LDH materials for efficient and sustainable CO 2 valorisation. Finally, we discuss future potential advancements, emphasizing the importance of new synergistic experimental&#8208;computational studies.</description>
      <author>Fabio Loprete, Eleonora Tosi Brandi, Francesco Calcagno, Jacopo De Maron, Andrea Fasolini, Riccardo Tarroni, Francesco Basile, Ivan Rivalta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202500014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the regulation strategy of active sites to explore the intrinsic mechanism over single&#8209;atom catalysts in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137595</link>
      <description>Wen Jiang, Qiang Xiao, Weidong Zhu, Fu&#8208;Min Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 693(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409434712

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Jiang, Qiang Xiao, Weidong Zhu, Fu&#8208;Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Pairwise Interaction for Extrapolative and Interpretable Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials with Physics-Informed Neural Network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00090</link>
      <description>Hoje Chun, Minjoon Hong, Seung Hyo Noh, Byungchan Han, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409438855

                Achieving both robust extrapolation and physical interpretability in machine learning interatomic potentials (ML-IPs) for atomistic simulation remains a significant challenge, particularly in data-scarce areas such as chemical reactions or complex, multicomponent materials at extreme conditions. Here, we present a pairwise-decomposed physics-informed neural network (P2Net) that parametrizes an analytical bond-order potential (BOP) layer to decouple the energy contributions of atomic pairs. By leveraging fundamental physical principles, P2Net demonstrates excellence at extrapolating beyond its training regime and accurately capturing molecular geometries far from equilibrium. The pairwise energy decomposition further empowers the bond analyses for deprotonation and SN2 reactions, which is not easy with most ML-IPs. The atomic pair energy offers how to elucidate the evolution of interatomic interactions as a reaction proceeds. Our methodology highlights enhanced data efficiency in building ML-IPs and facilitates more informative postsimulation analysis, thereby broadening the applicability of ML-IPs to complex and reactive systems.</description>
      <author>Hoje Chun, Minjoon Hong, Seung Hyo Noh, Byungchan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering bilayer GeSe/BiOI S-scheme heterojunction for solar-driven water-splitting hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.054</link>
      <description>Nianjun Luo, Wenyi Tang, Biao Wang, Hongkuan Yuan, Hong Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 127(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409441297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nianjun Luo, Wenyi Tang, Biao Wang, Hongkuan Yuan, Hong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold-modified nanoporous silicon for photoelectrochemical regulation of intracellular condensates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-025-01878-4</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Pengju Li, Jiping Yue, Lingyuan Meng, Wen Li, Chuan&#8208;Wang Yang, Saehyun Kim, Zhe Cheng, Asha Kamath, Samira Siahrostami, Bozhi Tian, Nature Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409443008

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Pengju Li, Jiping Yue, Lingyuan Meng, Wen Li, Chuan&#8208;Wang Yang, Saehyun Kim, Zhe Cheng, Asha Kamath, Samira Siahrostami, Bozhi Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-025-01878-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in green H2O2 production via metal-based functional materials: applications, strategies, and catalytic mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03285-z</link>
      <description>Danhua Jiao, Yongjun Li, Xiaodong Cai, Qizhao Wang, Yue Wang, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409448006

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Danhua Jiao, Yongjun Li, Xiaodong Cai, Qizhao Wang, Yue Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03285-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balsa Wood-Derived Carbon Enriched with Hydroxyl Functional Groups for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Sorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c00880</link>
      <description>Yuqing Meng, Manish Neupane, Drew M. Glenna, Asmita Jana, Wenhu Wang, Haiyan Zhao, Jin Qian, Yingchao Yang, Lu&#8208;Cun Wang, Seth W. Snyder, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409449693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuqing Meng, Manish Neupane, Drew M. Glenna, Asmita Jana, Wenhu Wang, Haiyan Zhao, Jin Qian, Yingchao Yang, Lu&#8208;Cun Wang, Seth W. Snyder</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c00880</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Time-Resolved X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy Unveils Partial Re-Oxidation of Tellurium Cluster for Prolonged Lifespan in Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00167</link>
      <description>Jiayin Yuan, Chang Long, Yu Zhang, Miao Zhang, Jian Chang, Yong&#8208;Lei Wang, Hao Zhang, Rongying Liu, Sadaf Saeedi Garakani, &#214;zlem U&#287;uz, Jiayin Yuan, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409449868

                Efficient and long-lasting electrocatalysts are one of the key factors in determining their large-scale commercial viability. Although the fundamentals of deactivation and regeneration of electrocatalysts are crucial for understanding and sustaining durable activity, little has been conducted on metalloids compared to metal-derived ones. Herein, by virtue of in situ seconds-resolved X-ray absorption spectroscopy, we discovered the chemical evolution during the deactivation-regeneration cycles of tellurium clusters supported by nitrogen-doped carbon (termed Te-ACs@NC) as a high-performance electrocatalyst in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Through in situ electrochemical reduction, Te-ACs@NC, which had been deactivated due to surface phase transitions in a previous HER process, was reactivated and regenerated for the next run, where partially oxidized Te was found, surprisingly, to perform better than its nonoxidized state. After 10 consecutive deactivation-regeneration cycles over 480 h, the Te-ACs@NC retained 85% of its initial catalytic activity. Theoretical studies suggest that local oxidation modulates the electronic distribution within individual Te clusters to optimize the adsorption energy of water molecules and reduce dissociation energy. This study provides fundamental insights into the rarely explored metalloid cluster catalysts during deactivation and regeneration and will assist in the future design and development of supported catalysts with high activity and long durability.</description>
      <author>Jiayin Yuan, Chang Long, Yu Zhang, Miao Zhang, Jian Chang, Yong&#8208;Lei Wang, Hao Zhang, Rongying Liu, Sadaf Saeedi Garakani, &#214;zlem U&#287;uz, Jiayin Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating hydrogen evolution catalyst discovery via data-driven strategy for high-performance single-atom catalysts embedded in h-BN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.04.002</link>
      <description>Hwanyeol Park, Dae&#8208;Myeong Geum, Ho Jun Kim, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409450188

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hwanyeol Park, Dae&#8208;Myeong Geum, Ho Jun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.04.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing nuclear quantum effects in electrocatalysis via a machine-learning enhanced grand canonical constant potential approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58871-7</link>
      <description>Menglin Sun, Bai-Qi Jin, Xiaolong Yang, Shenzhen Xu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409452381

                Proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) is the key step for energy conversion in electrocatalysis. Atomic-scale simulation acts as an indispensable tool to provide a microscopic understanding of PCET. However, consideration of the quantum nature of transferring protons under an exact grand canonical constant potential condition is a great challenge for theoretical electrocatalysis. Here, we develop a unified computational framework to explicitly treat nuclear quantum effects (NQEs) by a sufficient grand canonical sampling, further assisted by a machine learning force field adapted for electrochemical conditions. Our work demonstrates a non-negligible impact of NQEs on PCET simulations for hydrogen evolution reaction at room temperature, and provides a physical picture that wave-like quantum characteristic of the transferring protons facilitates the particles to tunnel through classical barriers in PCET paths, leading to a remarkable activation energy reduction compared to classical simulations. Moreover, the physical insight of NQEs may reshape our fundamental understanding of other types of PCET reactions in broader scenarios of energy conversion processes.</description>
      <author>Menglin Sun, Bai-Qi Jin, Xiaolong Yang, Shenzhen Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58871-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction-driven formation of anisotropic strains in FeTeSe nanosheets boosts low-concentration nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58940-x</link>
      <description>Jiawei Liu, Yifan Xu, Ruihuan Duan, Mingsheng Zhang, Yue Hu, Mengxin Chen, Bo Han, Jinfeng Dong, Carmen Lee, L. S. R. Kumara, Okkyun Seo, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Takeshi Watanabe, Zheng Liu, Qiang Zhu, Jianwei Xu, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Dongshuang Wu, Qingyu Yan, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409453367

                FeM (M = Se, Te) chalcogenides have been well studied as promising magnets and superconductors, yet their potential as electrocatalysts is often considered limited due to anion dissolution and oxidation during electrochemical reactions. Here, we show that by using two-dimensional (2D) FeTeSe nanosheets, these conventionally perceived limitations can be leveraged to enable the reaction-driven in-situ generation of anisotropic in-plane tensile and out-of-plane compressive strains during the alkaline low-concentration nitrate reduction reaction (NO3-RR). The reconstructed catalyst demonstrates enhanced performance, yielding ammonia with a near-unity Faradaic efficiency and a high yield rate of 42.14 &#177; 2.06 mg h-1 mgcat-1. A series of operando synchrotron-based X-ray measurements and ex-situ characterizations, alongside theoretical calculations, reveal that strain formation is ascribed to chalcogen vacancies created by partial Se/Te leaching, which facilitate the adsorption and dissociation of OH-/NO3- from the electrolyte, resulting in an O(H)-doped strained lattice. Combined electrochemical and computational investigations suggest that the superior catalytic performance arises from the synergistic contributions from the exposed strained Fe sites and surface hydroxyl groups. These findings highlight the potential of 2D transition metal chalcogenides for in-situ structural engineering during electrochemical reactions to enhance catalytic activity for NO3-RR and beyond.</description>
      <author>Jiawei Liu, Yifan Xu, Ruihuan Duan, Mingsheng Zhang, Yue Hu, Mengxin Chen, Bo Han, Jinfeng Dong, Carmen Lee, L. S. R. Kumara, Okkyun Seo, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Takeshi Watanabe, Zheng Liu, Qiang Zhu, Jianwei Xu, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Dongshuang Wu, Qingyu Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58940-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A charge calibration strategy for describing the charge transfer during the electrochemical elementary step</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0240019</link>
      <description>X. C. Lv, Sheng&#8722;Jie Qian, Hao Cao, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(15)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409456230

                Constant potential modeling of electrocatalytic processes remains a significant challenge in the field of computational catalysis, primarily due to the difficulty in simultaneously considering the influence of constant potential conditions, explicit solvent environment, and the double-layer structure. In this work, we propose a charge calibration strategy for electrocatalytic processes. This strategy accounts for charge transfer in systems with explicit solvation and ions during constant-potential free energy modeling. In our strategy, interfacial counter-ions are employed to model the Helmholtz layer and determine the surface charge density, which defines the electrode potential. During the simulation of electrochemical reactions, extra charges are introduced/extracted to/from the system to compensate for electron transfer between the electrode and the reaction species and keep a constant surface charge density along the reaction profile. Our method showcases the impact of potential-dependent solvent reorganization on reaction kinetics and underscores the importance of constant potential kinetics. We anticipate that the strategy presented here will inspire further theoretical and experimental studies for electrochemistry interfaces.</description>
      <author>X. C. Lv, Sheng&#8722;Jie Qian, Hao Cao, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0240019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Volcano Relationship between d&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;z&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Electronic States and Sulfur Redox Reaction Kinetics in Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c00128</link>
      <description>Jiaming Tian, Yuan Rao, Sheng Xu, Xiangqun Xu, Yu Sun, Tianze Shi, Haoshen Zhou, Shaohua Guo, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409457705

                The d orbital physics are closely related to the catalytic activity of transition-metal-based catalysts in Li-S batteries. However, challenges remain in understanding the optimal electronic configuration, causing a lack of guidance in the precise design of catalysts. Herein, by virtue of LaCoO3-based catalysts with different combinations of low-spin states and high-spin states of Co3+, a volcano relationship between dz2 filling number (from 0.95 to 1.29) and S/Li2S redox reaction kinetics is revealed. The best kinetics are provided at the dz2 filling number of 1.12. As a result, the assembled Li-S battery shows a low decay rate of 0.026% per cycle in a 1500-cycle test and a high energy density of 460.7 Wh kg-1 in a practical pouch cell. This work reveals the critical influences of dz2 electronic states on catalyzing the S/Li2S redox reaction and provides insights into finely regulating the electronic structures of high-performance catalysts for practical Li-S batteries.</description>
      <author>Jiaming Tian, Yuan Rao, Sheng Xu, Xiangqun Xu, Yu Sun, Tianze Shi, Haoshen Zhou, Shaohua Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c00128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling electronic absorption spectra with nuclear quantum effects in constrained nuclear&#8211;electronic orbital framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0254111</link>
      <description>Xi Xu, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(15)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409457827

                Electronic absorption spectra serve as versatile and powerful tools in experiments. Accurate theoretical simulation of electronic absorption spectra is challenging because multiple factors such as environmental effects and nuclear quantum effects contribute to spectrum lineshapes. This work proposes a protocol to model electronic absorption spectra in the constrained nuclear&#8211;electronic orbital framework. Solvent effects, temperature effects, and particularly nuclear quantum effects can be taken into consideration in this unified framework. This protocol is applied to investigate the electronic absorption spectrum of the pyridine molecule in water. Nuclear quantum effects are found to induce a broadening and red shift of the absorption spectrum of pyridine.</description>
      <author>Xi Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0254111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Metal&#8208;Center Mediated Adsorption and Redox Mechanisms in a FeMn(NbTa)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; Columbite Material for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404479</link>
      <description>Patrick M. Bacirhonde, Devendra Shrestha, Kyoungin Kang, Esensil Man Hia, Nikhil Komalla, Nelson Y. Dzade, Merve Buldu&#8208;Akturk, Michelle Browne, Milan Babu Poudel, Dong Jin Yoo, Eun&#8208;Suk Jeong, Ahmed Yousef Mohamed, Bo Han, Deok&#8208;Yong Cho, Matthew T. Curnan, Geun Ho Gu, Jeong Woo Han, Chan Hee Park, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409459933

                Abstract The rising demand for sustainable green hydrogen production necessitates efficient and cost&#8208;effective water&#8208;splitting electrocatalysts. Inspired by the catalytic activities of columbite&#8208;tantalite, this study combines a scalable cutting&#8208;edge synthesis approach with atomic&#8208;level structures and metal&#8208;center&#8208;mediated mechanisms to unravel its operational performance and stability. Using ad in situ X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure combined with Density Functional Theory (DFT), the results reveal distinctive valence band peaks and moderate charge transfer from Mn and Fe sites, enabling stable adsorption and reduced activation barriers. In contrast, the high&#8208;valence Nb and Ta centers at the B&#8208;sites promote favorable d &#8208;band alignment, enhancing orbital overlap with oxygen p&#8208; orbitals. This facilites electronic delocalization, lowers charge accumulation, and reduces activation barriers of intermediates species. Fe and Mn at the A&#8208;sites exhibit strong redox reactivity and optimal adsorption for OH* and O*, supporting efficient electron fransfers. Solvation effects modeled via VASPsol further stabilize key intermediates, especially O*, reducing the energy barrier for water dissociation. Notably, FeMn(NbTa) 2 O 6 &#8208;columbite catalysts stand out with a cell voltage of 1.81 V at a current density of 700 mA cm &#8722;2 , compared to 40% Pt/C&#8208;RuO&#8322; (1.75 V) at the same current density in the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE). Also, the FeMn(NbTa) 2 O 6 &#8208;columbite exhibits long&#8208;term stability at 800 mA cm &#8722;2 , surpassing the benchmark 40% Pt Vulcan&#8208;RuO 2 after 200 h in AEMWE. This work significantly advances current research and establishes a design rule for selecting metal compositions in the development of advanced electrocatalysts in alkaline water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Patrick M. Bacirhonde, Devendra Shrestha, Kyoungin Kang, Esensil Man Hia, Nikhil Komalla, Nelson Y. Dzade, Merve Buldu&#8208;Akturk, Michelle Browne, Milan Babu Poudel, Dong Jin Yoo, Eun&#8208;Suk Jeong, Ahmed Yousef Mohamed, Bo Han, Deok&#8208;Yong Cho, Matthew T. Curnan, Geun Ho Gu, Jeong Woo Han, Chan Hee Park</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VibIR-Parallel-Compute: Enhancing Vibration and Infrared Analysis in High-Performance Computing Environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07855</link>
      <description>Kurt Irvin M. Rojas, Yoshitada Morikawa, Ikutaro Hamada, The Journal of Open Source Software. 10(108)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409460287

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kurt Irvin M. Rojas, Yoshitada Morikawa, Ikutaro Hamada</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning-assisted Design of Cathode Catalysts for Metal-Sulfur/Oxygen/Carbon Dioxide Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104261</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Rui Yang, Zhengran Wang, Yi-Fan Li, Fangbing Dong, Junjie Liu, Shenglin Xiong, Aimin Zhang, Jinkui Feng, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409472511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Rui Yang, Zhengran Wang, Yi-Fan Li, Fangbing Dong, Junjie Liu, Shenglin Xiong, Aimin Zhang, Jinkui Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mild-Condition Conversion of Methane to Acetic Acid over MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Confined Rh&#8211;Fe Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c01515</link>
      <description>Jun Mao, Chenguang Liu, Yanan Li, Meng Gao, Yunlong Zhang, Yao Song, Mo Zhang, Guilan Xu, Wu Zhou, Liang Yu, Xiaoju Cui, Dehui Deng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409476998

                The oriented conversion of CH4 to CH3COOH at low temperature, even room temperature, is both scientifically significant and industrially applicable for CH4 utilization, yet it is extremely challenging due to the difficulties associated with efficient CH4 activation and controllable C-C coupling. In this study, we for the first time achieve the room-temperature conversion of CH4 to CH3COOH using molecular O2 and CO over MoS2-confined Rh-Fe sites, which delivers an unprecedented CH3COOH selectivity of 90.3% and a productivity of 26.2 &#956;mol gcat.-1 h-1 at 25 &#176;C. Furthermore, the productivity of CH3COOH can be enhanced to 105.6 &#956;mol gcat.-1 h-1 at 80 &#176;C, while maintaining a high selectivity of 95.6%. Comprehensive experimental and theoretical investigation reveal the critical role of Rh-Fe synergy in the selective formation of CH3COOH. The confined Fe sites in MoS2 enable the activation of O2 to generate highly reactive Fe&#9552;O center for CH4 dissociation to CH3 species at room temperature, which then readily couple with adsorbed CO on adjacent Rh sites to form the key CH3CO intermediate for CH3COOH production. The unique structure of Rh-Fe sites offers synergistic catalytic properties that effectively balance C-H activation and C-C coupling, successfully addressing the trade-off between activity and selectivity in the carbonylation of CH4 to CH3COOH under mild conditions.</description>
      <author>Jun Mao, Chenguang Liu, Yanan Li, Meng Gao, Yunlong Zhang, Yao Song, Mo Zhang, Guilan Xu, Wu Zhou, Liang Yu, Xiaoju Cui, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c01515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogenation-Facilitated Spontaneous N-O Cleavage Mechanism for Effectively Boosting Nitrate Reduction Reaction on Fe2B2 MBene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081778</link>
      <description>Yuexuan He, Zhiwen Chen, Qing Jiang, Molecules. 30(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409480531

                The electrochemical reduction of toxic nitrate wastewater to green fuel ammonia under mild conditions has become a goal that researchers have relentlessly pursued. Existing designed electrocatalysts can effectively promote the nitrate reduction reaction (NO3RR), but the study of the catalytic mechanism is not extensive enough, resulting in no breakthroughs in performance. In this study, a novel mechanism of hydrogenation-facilitated spontaneous N-O cleavage was explored based on density functional theory calculations. Furthermore, the Ead&#8722;*OH (adsorption energy of the adsorbed *OH) was used as a key descriptor for predicting the occurrence of spontaneous N-O bond cleavage. We found that Ead&#8722;*OH &lt; &#8722;0.20 eV results into spontaneous N-O bond cleavage. However, excessively strong adsorption of OH* hinders the formation of water. To address this challenge, we designed the eligible Fe2B2 MBene, which shows excellent catalytic activity with an ultra-low limiting potential for NO3RR of &#8722;0.22 V under this novel reaction mechanism. Additionally, electron-deficient Fe active sites could inhibit competing hydrogen evolution reactions (HERs), which provides high selectivity. This work may offer valuable insights for the rational design of advanced electrocatalysts with enhanced performance.</description>
      <author>Yuexuan He, Zhiwen Chen, Qing Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteronuclear transition metal decorated C2N monolayer: Promising catalysts for nitrogen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.190</link>
      <description>Bilal Aladerah, Nirpendra Singh, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 127(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409481944

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bilal Aladerah, Nirpendra Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution and Carbon Dioxide Reduction Pathways on Graphitic Carbon Nitride Decorated by Single Atoms of Transition Metals&lt;sup&gt;&#8225;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08038</link>
      <description>Anna Vidal-L&#243;pez, Joan Gass&#243;-Capdevila, Miquel Sol&#224;, Albert Poater, Sergio Posada&#8208;P&#233;rez, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409484482

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna Vidal-L&#243;pez, Joan Gass&#243;-Capdevila, Miquel Sol&#224;, Albert Poater, Sergio Posada&#8208;P&#233;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Layer Restructuring of Gold Surfaces by &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Heterocyclic Carbenes over Large Surface Areas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c17517</link>
      <description>Eden Goodwin, Matthew Davies, Maram Bakiro, Emmett Desroche, Francesco Tumino, Mark D. Aloisio, Cathleen M. Crudden, Paul J. Ragogna, Mikko Karttunen, Se&#225;n T. Barry, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409487049

                Even highly planar, polished metal surfaces display varying levels of roughness that can affect their optical and electronic properties, impacting performance in state-of-the-art microelectronics. Current methods for smoothing rough metallic surfaces require either the removal or addition of substantial amounts of material using complex processes that are incompatible with 3-dimensional nanoscale features needed for state-of-the-art applications. We present a vapor-phase process that results in up to a 60% smoothing of nanometer-scale rough gold surfaces through a single exposure to a class of ligands called N-heterocyclic carbenes. This process does not require removal or addition of metal from the surface and provides smoothing at the &#197;ngstr&#246;m scale. Smoothing occurs in a single deposition, giving quantifiable differences in the adsorption behavior of the resulting surfaces. The process takes place through an adatom-extraction-driven destabilization and restructuring of the surface in a self-limiting manner. This process is achieved without the use of harsh chemical etchants or mechanical intervention, takes only minutes, and can easily be integrated with vapor-phase processing in situ in microfabrication workflows. Our observations demonstrate atomic layer restructuring, a technique that compliments atomic layer deposition and atomic layer etching in the fabrication and processing of high-precision materials.</description>
      <author>Eden Goodwin, Matthew Davies, Maram Bakiro, Emmett Desroche, Francesco Tumino, Mark D. Aloisio, Cathleen M. Crudden, Paul J. Ragogna, Mikko Karttunen, Se&#225;n T. Barry</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c17517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain Boundary Segregation and Embrittlement of Aluminum Binary Alloys from First Principles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121058</link>
      <description>Nutth Tuchinda, Gregory B. Olson, Christopher A. Schuh, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409487227

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nutth Tuchinda, Gregory B. Olson, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new catalytic merit for prediction catalytic potential of 2D materials in Li-O2 batteries: Theoretical investigation and experimental identification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmat.2025.101060</link>
      <description>Geng Cheng, Wenpei Li, Chengyan Liu, Jie Gao, Jun-Liang Chen, Ziqi Zhou, Xiaoyang Wang, Lei Miao, Journal of Materiomics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409489009

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Geng Cheng, Wenpei Li, Chengyan Liu, Jie Gao, Jun-Liang Chen, Ziqi Zhou, Xiaoyang Wang, Lei Miao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmat.2025.101060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain boundary segregation spectra from a generalized machine-learning potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2025.116682</link>
      <description>Nutth Tuchinda, Christopher A. Schuh, Scripta Materialia. 264(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409494098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nutth Tuchinda, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2025.116682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Mechanism and Intermediates of the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5006/c2025-00534</link>
      <description>S. DESHMUKH, Bruce Brown, David Young, conference. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409497658

                Abstract The Oxygen Reduction Reaction (ORR) plays a crucial role in corrosion mechanisms and the operation of electrochemical energy devices, affecting both stability and efficiency. Despite extensive research, the exact mechanisms and intermediates involved in ORR continue to be subjects of study. The literature reports a range of intermediates and mechanisms, which can be complex and, at times, contradictory. This paper conducts a comprehensive literature review with a primary focus on ORR mechanisms on steel, while also examining platinum, gold, and carbon electrodes. Recent advancements in experimental techniques and theoretical modeling have improved our understanding of ORR, which is essential for corrosion science and energy conversion technologies. This review compiles and analyzes the existing literature on the ORR, focusing on its behavior across different electrodes, including platinum, gold and steel/iron. The study identifies key intermediates such as HO2-, O2-, H2O2, OOH, and OH through electrochemical measurements and in situ spectroscopic methods, mapping their formation and consumption. Understanding these ORR pathways and their interactions with other corrosion processes contributes to the refinement of predictive corrosion models.</description>
      <author>S. DESHMUKH, Bruce Brown, David Young</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5006/c2025-00534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Electrolyte Cations on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101697</link>
      <description>Boqiang Chen, Dunwei Wang, Matthias M. Waegele, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409499312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boqiang Chen, Dunwei Wang, Matthias M. Waegele</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101697</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-copper dual-atom catalyst boosts electrocatalytic nitrate reduction from water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.138264</link>
      <description>Jinshan Wei, Hexing Lin, Yi Li, Ying Guo, Shaoqing Liu, Meng Sun, Yayun Li, Journal of Hazardous Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409500572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinshan Wei, Hexing Lin, Yi Li, Ying Guo, Shaoqing Liu, Meng Sun, Yayun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.138264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ten&#8208;Electron Count Rule of MXene&#8208;Supported Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for Sulfur Reduction in Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.70011</link>
      <description>Lujie Jin, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li, Carbon Neutralization. 4(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409501390

                ABSTRACT Lithium&#8211;sulfur (Li&#8211;S) batteries are proposed as next&#8208;generation energy storage devices due to their high theoretical capacity and specific energy. However, the actual capacity utilization is greatly limited by the poor reactivity of the sulfur reduction reaction (SRR), which motivates us to develop corresponding high&#8208;efficient catalysts. Inspired by the application of MXene and single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) in improving SRR, a virtual screening on the MXene&#8208;supported SACs from the imp2d database is carried out. Finally, six kinds of top catalysts are identified for SRR, and most of them can be considered as variants of the previous representative SRR catalysts, which reflects the rationality of our screening. Meanwhile, the stability and reactivity metrics of the SACs are calculated by density functional theory (DFT) and show obvious trends depending on the type of adatom/MXene. For the critical intermediate binding that can tune SRR activity, further electronic structure analysis reveals the so&#8208;called 10&#8208;electron count rule, whose decisive role is also reflected by the Shapley value analysis from machine learning (ML). It is noteworthy that this count rule was used to analyze the SACs for hydrogen/carbon/nitrogen&#8208;related reactions before, and our successful attempt to optimize SRR further indicates its universality in catalysis fields. Overall, the 10&#8208;electron count rule not only rationalizes the nature of SAC&#8211;adsorbate interactions but also provides intuitive design guidance for novel SRR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Lujie Jin, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.70011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Strategies for Ni3S2-Based Electrocatalysts with Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Performance: A Tutorial Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms26083771</link>
      <description>Yucheng Shen, Jixing Bai, Huijie Wei, Jun Gu, Qi Cao, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 26(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409503461

                Water electrolysis represents one of the most environmentally friendly methods for hydrogen production, while its overall efficiency is primarily governed by the electrocatalyst. Nickel sulfides, e.g., Ni3S2, are considered to be highly promising catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to their distinctive chemical structure. However, the practical application of Ni3S2-based electrocatalysts is hindered by unsatisfactory high overpotential in the HER and weakened catalytic performance under alkaline conditions. Therefore, in this regard, further research on Ni3S2-based catalysts is being carried out to tackle these challenges. This review provides a comprehensive survey of the latest advancements in Ni3S2-based in improving the HER performance of Ni3S2-based electrocatalysts. The review may offer some inspiration for the rational design and synthesis of novel transition metal-based catalysts with enhanced water electrolysis performance.</description>
      <author>Yucheng Shen, Jixing Bai, Huijie Wei, Jun Gu, Qi Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms26083771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active&#8208;Site&#8208;Switching in Medium&#8208;Entropy Metal Sulfides for Wide&#8208;Temperature High&#8208;Power Zn&#8208;Air Pouch Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202503500</link>
      <description>Tengteng Gu, Xiaoqing Liu, Jiadong Shen, Linjie Zhang, Lei Shen, Liuzhang Ouyang, Min Zhu, Jun Liu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409508479

                Abstract Quasi&#8208;solid&#8208;state Zn&#8208;air pouch cells (QZPCs) promise a high energy&#8208;to&#8208;cost ratio while ensuring inherent safety. However, addressing the challenges associated with exploring superior energy&#8208;wise cathode catalysts along with their activity origin, and the super&#8208;ionic electrolytes remains a fundamental task. Herein, the realistic high&#8208;performance QZPCs are contrived, underpinned by a robust NiVFeCo medium&#8208;entropy metal sulfides (MESs) bifunctional air cathode with a record&#8208;low potential polarization of 0.523 V, paired with a sodium polyacrylate&#8208;ionic liquid hydrogel exhibiting exceptional conductivity (234 mS cm &#8722;1 ) and water retention (93.8% at 7 days) at room temperature as the super&#8208;ionic conductor electrolyte. Through combined studies of in situ Raman, ex situ X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure analysis, and theoretic calculations, an intriguing adaptive active&#8208;sites&#8208;switching mechanism of the MESs cathode during discharging/charging processes is unveiled, revealing a dynamic role transition of Co and Ni active sites in the reversible oxygen electrocatalysis. Consequently, the persistent low cathode polarization and super ion&#8208;conductive electrolyte endorse QZPCs an excellent rate performance from 1 to 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at room temperature. Moreover, an impressively high cell&#8208;level energy density of 105 Wh kg cell &#8722;1 with an ultra&#8208;long cycle lifespan of 4000 cycles at 5 mA cm &#8722;2 and a low temperature of &#8722;30 &#176;C is achieved.</description>
      <author>Tengteng Gu, Xiaoqing Liu, Jiadong Shen, Linjie Zhang, Lei Shen, Liuzhang Ouyang, Min Zhu, Jun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202503500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Doppelg&#228;ngers in Scopus: how to build scientists control groups using sosia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11192-025-05298-y</link>
      <description>Michael E. Rose, Stefano Horst Baruffaldi, Scientometrics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409514754

                Abstract The construction of control groups of scientists is often a daunting effort. This paper presents , an open-source Python-based software designed to efficiently query the Scopus database via RESTful API. searches for researchers with publication profiles similar to a given researcher up to a given year based on all main standard bibliometric indicators. The user can choose flexibly a set of parameters to restrict the search to more or less narrow boundaries upfront and obtain additional similarity indicators to select a subset of authors after the search. Advanced settings also allow narrowing the search to a list of affiliations and to minimize the possible errors arising from ambiguous author profiles. One basic search can be set up in a few command lines and the average time of computation goes between 60 and 300 minutes. We discuss the functioning, characteristics, limitations and possible extension of the software.</description>
      <author>Michael E. Rose, Stefano Horst Baruffaldi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11192-025-05298-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O2-induced activity change in CO2 reduction on bimetallic electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106502</link>
      <description>Bo Xiong, Ziyang Zhang, Zhenzhen Li, Jing Liu, Yingju Yang, Zhongpu Fang, Bianyang He, Yaoyao Zhang, Lei Zhu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409528550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Xiong, Ziyang Zhang, Zhenzhen Li, Jing Liu, Yingju Yang, Zhongpu Fang, Bianyang He, Yaoyao Zhang, Lei Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Surface Engineering of Lithium Metal Anodes: Simultaneous Native Layer Elimination and Protective Layer Formation &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; Gas&#8211;Solid Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c03708</link>
      <description>Siwon Choi, Seongwook Chae, Taemin Kim, Hyeonsol Shin, Jin-Gyu Bae, Seung Geol Lee, Ji Hoon Lee, Hyeon Jeong Lee, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409529449

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siwon Choi, Seongwook Chae, Taemin Kim, Hyeonsol Shin, Jin-Gyu Bae, Seung Geol Lee, Ji Hoon Lee, Hyeon Jeong Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c03708</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Ni-Based Electrode Materials for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c00255</link>
      <description>Shuwei Guo, Qi Lu, Xiwen Zhou, Yihan Wang, Manni Li, Botao Liu, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409533129

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuwei Guo, Qi Lu, Xiwen Zhou, Yihan Wang, Manni Li, Botao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c00255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of elastic strains on the electrocatalytic activity of Au thin films for the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116151</link>
      <description>Jordi Redondo, J. Subbian, M.A. Moncl&#250;s, Afshin Pendashteh, Daniel Rodr&#237;guez P&#233;rez, Muhammad Mehdi, J. Ruiz-Herv&#237;as, J.M. Molina-Aldaregu&#237;a, Javier LLorca, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409533683

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jordi Redondo, J. Subbian, M.A. Moncl&#250;s, Afshin Pendashteh, Daniel Rodr&#237;guez P&#233;rez, Muhammad Mehdi, J. Ruiz-Herv&#237;as, J.M. Molina-Aldaregu&#237;a, Javier LLorca</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the synergistic regulation mechanism of N/C coordination and OH ligands on the bifunctional oxygen electrode activity in Co-N-C doped graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163298</link>
      <description>Linlin Zhang, Nan Chen, Zhen Gao, Rui He, Xinyu Zhang, Yan&#8208;Ning Wang, Kai Xiong, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409534340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linlin Zhang, Nan Chen, Zhen Gao, Rui He, Xinyu Zhang, Yan&#8208;Ning Wang, Kai Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental Approaches to Corrosion Resistant Alloy Development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5006/c2023-19410</link>
      <description>Christopher D Taylor, conference. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4409501561

                Abstract Given that the foundation of aqueous corrosion of alloys is rooted in electrochemistry, the search for new alloy formulations should be derived from the fundamental electrochemical properties of the elements and their compounds. Properties of relevance include the standard reduction potential of the elements, the electronic work function, the newly re-discovered property of the ionic work function, as well as additional properties such as the cohesive energy, the oxide formation potential, and the ability to catalyze the important cathodic reactions such as oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen reduction reaction. Following trends in &#8220;materials informatics&#8221; an approach has been developed to create work flows for exploring new element combinations that can be optimized for one or more of these features. We demonstrate in this work how the approach may be followed to suggest new alloys with superior resistance to localized corrosion, and how it may be expanded to include microstructural characteristics as well as to provide a basis for more quantitative predictions of corrosion rates in a given environmental condition.</description>
      <author>Christopher D Taylor</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5006/c2023-19410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of surface termination and tensile strain on the thermal conductivity of the Ti3C2Tx MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113890</link>
      <description>Jun Jiang, Hao Jin, Zhenzhen Xia, Yuting Zong, Jingwei Sun, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Computational Materials Science. 253(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409417078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Jiang, Hao Jin, Zhenzhen Xia, Yuting Zong, Jingwei Sun, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Investigation of the Influence of Rare Earth Element Doping on the Corrosion Characteristics of Mg (0001) surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417198</link>
      <description>Yuqi Gao, Guoning Bai, Hua Hou, Yuhong Zhao, Yongmei Zhang, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409424654

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuqi Gao, Guoning Bai, Hua Hou, Yuhong Zhao, Yongmei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417198</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
