<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 01:20:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>First principles study of V2CT2-based MXenes materials in oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118686</link>
      <description>Wang Zhang, Shanmin Gao, Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Zhongzhou Dong, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402973557

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wang Zhang, Shanmin Gao, Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Zhongzhou Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction via a Surface Reconstruction-Induced Lattice Oxygen Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03594</link>
      <description>Subin Choi, Sejun Kim, Sunghoon Han, Jian Wang, Juwon Kim, Bonho Koo, Alexander A. Ryabin, Sebastian Kunze, Hyejeong Hyun, Jeongwoo Han, Shu-Chih Haw, Keun Hwa Chae, Chang Hyuck Choi, Hyungjun Kim, Jongwoo Lim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402976597

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subin Choi, Sejun Kim, Sunghoon Han, Jian Wang, Juwon Kim, Bonho Koo, Alexander A. Ryabin, Sebastian Kunze, Hyejeong Hyun, Jeongwoo Han, Shu-Chih Haw, Keun Hwa Chae, Chang Hyuck Choi, Hyungjun Kim, Jongwoo Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Constraint-Based Orbital-Optimized Excited State Method (COOX)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00467</link>
      <description>J&#246;rg Ku&#223;mann, Yannick Lemke, Anthea Weinbrenner, Christian Ochsenfeld, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402987837

                In this work, we present a novel method to directly calculate targeted electronic excited states within a self-consistent field calculation based on constrained density functional theory (cDFT). The constraint is constructed from the static occupied-occupied and virtual-virtual parts of the excited state difference density from (simplified) linear-response time-dependent density functional theory calculations (LR-TDDFT). Our new method shows a stable convergence behavior, provides an accurate excited state density adhering to the Aufbau principle, and can be solved within a restricted SCF for singlet excitations to avoid spin contamination. This also allows the straightforward application of post-SCF electron-correlation methods like MP2 or direct RPA methods. We present the details of our constraint-based orbital-optimized excited state method (COOX) and compare it to similar schemes. The accuracy of excitation energies will be analyzed for a benchmark of systems, while the quality of the resulting excited state densities is investigated by evaluating excited state nuclear forces and excited state structure optimizations. We also investigate the performance of the proposed COOX method for long-range charge transfer excitations and conical intersections with the ground-state.</description>
      <author>J&#246;rg Ku&#223;mann, Yannick Lemke, Anthea Weinbrenner, Christian Ochsenfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoanode Applications of Polyene-Diphenylaniline Dyes Molecules Adsorbed on TiO2 Brookite Cluster</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.1005450</link>
      <description>Ife Elegbeleye, Eric Maluta, Rapela R. Maphanga, Michael Walter, Oliver Br&#252;gner, IntechOpen eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402990515

                TiO2 has excellent photoelectrochemical properties, which makes its suitable for photoanode applications. TiO2 is widely utilized as semiconductor for dye-sensitized photoanode owing to its excellent stability and availability. The brookite polymorph of TiO2 has been suggested to demonstrate better photocatalytic properties. In this work, we studied the adsorption of polyenediphenyl-aniline dyes on (TiO2) n = 8, 68 brookite clusters using density functional theory (DFT). We report our results on the UV&#8211;Vis absorption spectra of the dyes and dyes adsorbed on TiO2 clusters, adsorption energies of the dyes adsorbed on TiO2 clusters, electronic density of states and projected electronic density of states of the dyes adsorbed on TiO2 complex, and electron density of the main molecular orbitals involved in photoexcitation for dye-sensitized solar cells application. The calculated adsorption energies of D5@(TiO2)68, D7@(TiO2)68, D9@(TiO2)68, and D11@(TiO2)68 are 4.84, 4.78, 4.66 and 4.92 eV, respectively. The results of the adsorption energies are in the order D11@(TiO2)8 &gt; D9@(TiO2)8 &gt; D7@(TiO2)8 &gt; D5@(TiO2)8 and D11@ (TiO2)68 &gt; D5@ (TiO2)68 &gt; D7@ (TiO2)68 &gt; D9@ (TiO2)68. This implies that D11 dye molecule reacts more strongly with (TiO2)8 and (TiO2)68 brookite clusters than the other corresponding dye molecules.</description>
      <author>Ife Elegbeleye, Eric Maluta, Rapela R. Maphanga, Michael Walter, Oliver Br&#252;gner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.1005450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate Crystal Structure Prediction of New 2D Hybrid Organic&#8211;Inorganic Perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c06549</link>
      <description>Nima Karimitari, William J. Baldwin, Evan W. Muller, Zachary J. L. Bare, W. Joshua Kennedy, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Christopher Sutton, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402993739

                Low-dimensional hybrid organic-inorganic perovskites (HOIPs) are promising electronically active materials for light absorption and emission. The design space of HOIPs is extremely large, as a variety of organic cations can be combined with different inorganic frameworks. This not only allows for tunable electronic and mechanical properties but also necessitates the development of new tools for in silico high throughput analysis of candidate materials. In this work, we present an accurate, efficient, and widely applicable machine learning interatomic potential (MLIP) trained on 86 diverse experimentally reported HOIP materials. This MLIP was tested on 73 experimentally reported perovskite compositions and achieves a high accuracy, relative to density functional theory (DFT). We also introduce a novel random structure search algorithm designed for the crystal structure prediction of 2D HOIPs. The combination of MLIP and the structure search algorithm reliably recovers the crystal structure of 14 known 2D perovskites by specifying only the organic molecule and inorganic cation/halide. Performing this crystal structure search with ab initio methods would be computationally prohibitive but is relatively inexpensive with the MLIP. Finally, the developed procedure is used to predict the structure of a totally new HOIP with cation (</description>
      <author>Nima Karimitari, William J. Baldwin, Evan W. Muller, Zachary J. L. Bare, W. Joshua Kennedy, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Christopher Sutton</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c06549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure&#8211;Activity Relationships in Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408139</link>
      <description>Jingqi Guan, Jingru Sun, Siyu Chen, Siying Zhang, Luoluo Qi, Anaer Husile, Jingqi Guan, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402994393

                Abstract Oxygen electrocatalysis, as the pivotal circle of many green energy technologies, sets off a worldwide research boom in full swing, while its large kinetic obstacles require remarkable catalysts to break through. Here, based on summarizing reaction mechanisms and in situ characterizations, the structure&#8211;activity relationships of oxygen electrocatalysts are emphatically overviewed, including the influence of geometric morphology and chemical structures on the electrocatalytic performances. Subsequently, experimental/theoretical research is combined with device applications to comprehensively summarize the cutting&#8208;edge oxygen electrocatalysts according to various material categories. Finally, future challenges are forecasted from the perspective of catalyst development and device applications, favoring researchers to promote the industrialization of oxygen electrocatalysis at an early date.</description>
      <author>Jingqi Guan, Jingru Sun, Siyu Chen, Siying Zhang, Luoluo Qi, Anaer Husile, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Metal/Oxide Interface of IrCoCeO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; in N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#183;H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Decomposition: An Experimental and Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12306</link>
      <description>Silvio Bellomi, Daniel C. Cano-Blanco, Ilaria Barlocco, Juan J. Delgado, Xiaowei Chen, Laura Prati, Davide Ferri, Nikolaos Dimitratos, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Alberto Villa, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402996365

                Understanding the structure of a functional catalyst is crucial to disclosing the complexity of heterogeneous processes and improving their efficiency. Herein, coprecipitated cobalt-ceria (CoCeO</description>
      <author>Silvio Bellomi, Daniel C. Cano-Blanco, Ilaria Barlocco, Juan J. Delgado, Xiaowei Chen, Laura Prati, Davide Ferri, Nikolaos Dimitratos, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Alberto Villa</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing &lt;scp&gt;HER&lt;/scp&gt; catalyst screening of modified &lt;scp&gt;MXenes&lt;/scp&gt; through &lt;scp&gt;DFT&lt;/scp&gt; and machine learning integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18618</link>
      <description>Hui Xu, Wei Lv, Shaojie Yang, Shihe Yang, Yawei Liu, Feng Huo, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402997886

                Abstract MXenes doped with non&#8208;metallic and transition metal elements exhibit remarkable potential as catalysts in the hydrogen energy. Nonetheless, efficiently identifying viable materials from a vast array of candidates remains a formidable challenge. Here, we conducted density functional theory (DFT) calculations to obtain the hydrogen adsorption free energy () of 78 types of doped TiVCO 2 MXene catalysts. Then we employed machine learning models to categorize the values of the 78 catalysts, resulted in an accurate model which only uses 7 readily available elemental features but has an impressive accuracy of 93.6%. Our model successfully predicting 5 TiVCO 2 catalysts doped with S with superior performance, subsequently validated through DFT calculations. This classification methodology not only evaluates the range of effectively but also facilitates qualitative prediction and screening of catalysts, presenting a novel approach for catalytic systems with limited available data.</description>
      <author>Hui Xu, Wei Lv, Shaojie Yang, Shihe Yang, Yawei Liu, Feng Huo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Fe Intermediate Spin States via FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Cl&#8208;Ti Structure for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403899</link>
      <description>Shuren Zhang, Yitong Han, Rui Zhang, Qian Zhang, Genban Sun, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403000792

                Abstract Modulating the spin states of FeN 4 moieties is critical for enhancing the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, Ti 4 N 3 Cl x and Ti 4 N 3 O x MXenes are synthesized and functionalized with iron phthalocyanine (FePc) to form model catalysts with well&#8208;defined FeN 4 &#8208;Cl&#8208;Ti and FeN 4 &#8208;O&#8208;Ti structures, respectively. The FeN 4 &#8208;Cl&#8208;Ti structure, formed within the Ti 4 N 3 Cl x /FePc composite, enables precise modulation of FeN 4 spin states from low to intermediate spin, significantly enhancing ORR performance. In contrast, the FeN 4 &#8208;O&#8208;Ti structure in Ti 4 N 3 O x /FePc shows less effective spin state modulation, leading to comparatively lower ORR activity. Compared to FePc and Ti 4 N 3 O x /FePc, Ti 4 N 3 Cl x /FePc demonstrates superior electrochemical performance, with an ORR half&#8208;wave potential of +0.91 V versus RHE and doubled power densities in Zn&#8211;air batteries (214.5 mW cm &#8722;2 ). Theoretical studies confirm that the intermediate spin states induced by the weak&#8208;field ligand&#8208;modified FeN 4 &#8208;Cl&#8208;Ti structure in Ti 4 N 3 Cl x /FePc facilitate electron filling in the antibonding orbital composed of Fe 3dz 2 and O 2 &#960;* orbitals, greatly enhancing O&#8322; activation and ORR activity. These findings underscore the superior catalytic properties of FeN 4 &#8208;Cl&#8208;Ti compared to FeN 4 &#8208;O&#8208;Ti, advancing the understanding of spin state&#8208;related catalytic mechanisms and guiding the design of high&#8208;performance ORR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shuren Zhang, Yitong Han, Rui Zhang, Qian Zhang, Genban Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis, diverse and forever young</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145174</link>
      <description>Tristan Asset, Alexandr G. Oshchepkov, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Maillard, Galina A. Tsirlina, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403000938

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tristan Asset, Alexandr G. Oshchepkov, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Maillard, Galina A. Tsirlina</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the potential of &#945;-Ge(1 1 1) monolayer in photocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100753</link>
      <description>Vin&#237;cius G. Garcia, Guilherme J. Inacio, L. Fiorini Filho, Lu&#237;za T. Pacheco, F.N.N. Pansini, Marcos G. Menezes, Wendel S. Paz, FlatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403001015

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vin&#237;cius G. Garcia, Guilherme J. Inacio, L. Fiorini Filho, Lu&#237;za T. Pacheco, F.N.N. Pansini, Marcos G. Menezes, Wendel S. Paz</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological Synthesis of 2D High&#8208;Entropy Multimetallic (Oxy)hydroxide for Enhanced Lattice Oxygen Oxidation Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409530</link>
      <description>Sijia Liu, Baorui Jia, Sheng Wang, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Fengmei Fan, Yunpu Qin, Jianfang Liu, Yirui Jiang, Bin Sun, Hong Zhao, Hao Li, Wenxiang Zhou, Haoyang Wu, Deyin Zhang, Xuanhui Qu, Mingli Qin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403002748

                Abstract Owing to sluggish reaction kinetics and high potential, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts face a trade&#8208;off between activity and stability. Herein, an innovative topological strategy is presented for preparing 2D multimetallic (oxy)hydroxide, including ternary CoFeZn, quaternary CoFeMnZn, and high&#8208;entropy CoFeMnCuZn. The key to the synthesis lies in using Ca&#8208;rich brownmillerite oxide as a precursor, which possesses inherent structural flexibility enabling tailored elemental adjustments and topologically transforms from a point&#8208;shared structure of metal&#8208;oxygen octahedrons into an edge&#8208;shared structure under alkaline conditions. The presence of Zn in the catalysts causes a shift in the center of the O2p band toward the Fermi level, resulting in more Co 4+ species, which drive holes into oxygen ligands to promote intramolecular oxygen coupling. The triggered lattice oxidation mechanism is identified by detecting peroxo&#8208;like (O 2 2&#8722; ) negative species using tetramethylammonium chemical probe, along with 18 O isotope labeling experiments. As a result, the catalyst demonstrates an overpotential of 267 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , ranking it among the top&#8208;performing non&#8208;Ni&#8208;based catalysts. Importantly, the catalysts also show high Fe&#8208;leaching resistance during OER compared to conventional NiFe and CoFe hydroxides/(oxy)hydroxides. The assembled zinc&#8208;air battery enables stable operation for over 225 h at a low charging voltage of 1.93 V.</description>
      <author>Sijia Liu, Baorui Jia, Sheng Wang, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Fengmei Fan, Yunpu Qin, Jianfang Liu, Yirui Jiang, Bin Sun, Hong Zhao, Hao Li, Wenxiang Zhou, Haoyang Wu, Deyin Zhang, Xuanhui Qu, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monovacant Janus WSSe designed as a bifunctional photocatalyst for OER and CO2RR with multiple C1 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105206</link>
      <description>Xiunan Chen, Yuhong Huang, Haiping Lin, Ruhai Du, Xiumei Wei, Fei Ma, Jing Liu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403012848

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiunan Chen, Yuhong Huang, Haiping Lin, Ruhai Du, Xiumei Wei, Fei Ma, Jing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chalcogen vacancy-enhanced electrocatalytic activity of 2D Janus NbSSe monolayers for hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.322</link>
      <description>A. L. Verma, Anirban Dutta, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403014682

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. L. Verma, Anirban Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PtCu-a-SnO2 interface engineering on PtCu-SnO2 aerogels for ethanol oxidation electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156321</link>
      <description>Yongying Wang, Yangge Guo, Zhengwei Zhang, Zirui Wu, Chanez Maouche, Shuiyun Shen, Yi Li, Junliang Zhang, Juan Yang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403015148

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongying Wang, Yangge Guo, Zhengwei Zhang, Zirui Wu, Chanez Maouche, Shuiyun Shen, Yi Li, Junliang Zhang, Juan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review of CO2 capture for amine-based deep eutectic solvents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jil.2024.100114</link>
      <description>Maizatul Akmar Ismail, Asiah Nusaibah Masri, Naghmana Rashid, Izni Mariah Ibrahim, Journal of Ionic Liquids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403016401

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maizatul Akmar Ismail, Asiah Nusaibah Masri, Naghmana Rashid, Izni Mariah Ibrahim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jil.2024.100114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Electrolyte Adsorption on the Different Types of Layered Cathode Surfaces in Lithium-Ion Batteries via a Universal Neural Network Potential Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c02484</link>
      <description>Attila T&#225;borosi, Hiromasa Shiiba, Michihisa Koyama, Nobuyuki Zettsu, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403016978

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Attila T&#225;borosi, Hiromasa Shiiba, Michihisa Koyama, Nobuyuki Zettsu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c02484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for Carbon Support Design in Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01632</link>
      <description>Donglai Li, Haibo Jin, Zipeng Zhao, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403037163

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Donglai Li, Haibo Jin, Zipeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-Layer Deposition of the Single-Atom Pt Catalyst on Vertical Graphene for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Sensing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03416</link>
      <description>Bo Liu, Zhaojun Han, Avi Bendavid, Philip Martin, Priyank V. Kumar, Yousof Haghshenas, Mohammed Alamri, Judy Wu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403041163

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Liu, Zhaojun Han, Avi Bendavid, Philip Martin, Priyank V. Kumar, Yousof Haghshenas, Mohammed Alamri, Judy Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Engineering of Dopant and Support of Ru Oxide Catalyst Enables Ultrahigh Performance for Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408714</link>
      <description>Felix Ofori Boakye, Karim Harrath, Dantong Zhang, Ya You, Wenbin Zhang, Sheng Wang, Yong Qiu, Jiexin Zhu, Juncai Long, Jianqiu Zhu, Ghulam Yasin, Kwadwo Asare Owusu, Mohammad Tabish, Linjuan Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaofeng Shi, Mingrui He, Bin Wu, Liqiang Mai, Wei Zhao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403042989

                Abstract Active and robust electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are of crucial importance for efficient proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEM&#8208;WE). Ruthenium (Ru) oxide has attracted considerable attention due to its high activity. However, the unsatisfying stability of Ru oxide in acidic OER environments hinders the application. Here, Ce&#8208;doped RuO 2 nanoparticles are designed and supported on Co&#9472;N&#9472;C material (Ce@RuO 2 /CoNC) for acidic OER. It is demonstrated that Ce@RuO 2 /CoNC delivers a super low overpotential of 150 mV and an excellent stability of 1000 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , outperforming most previously reported Ru&#8208;based catalysts. The mass activity is estimated as 2365.5 Ag Ru &#8722;1 at 1.5 V (vs RHE), representing &#8776;2&#215; advance compared to the best prior study. Furthermore, applied in a single&#8208;cell PEM&#8208;WE device, it can steadily operate for 1000 h at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 . The studies show that Ce&#8208;doping and Co&#9472;N&#9472;C support synergistically enhance the activity and stability of Ru oxide by optimizing the free energies of OER intermediates and suppressing the dissolution of Ru.</description>
      <author>Felix Ofori Boakye, Karim Harrath, Dantong Zhang, Ya You, Wenbin Zhang, Sheng Wang, Yong Qiu, Jiexin Zhu, Juncai Long, Jianqiu Zhu, Ghulam Yasin, Kwadwo Asare Owusu, Mohammad Tabish, Linjuan Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaofeng Shi, Mingrui He, Bin Wu, Liqiang Mai, Wei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-earth metal neodymium anchored into graphene as a promising CO2 reduction electrocatalyst by regulating the coordination environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105203</link>
      <description>Siying Liu, Huohai Yang, Xingbo Ge, Yingjie Feng, Xiaoyue Fu, Xin Chen, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403044828

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siying Liu, Huohai Yang, Xingbo Ge, Yingjie Feng, Xiaoyue Fu, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing In/InN Intermediates by Electron-Deficient Carbon for Improved CO2 Electroreduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124668</link>
      <description>Jifang Chen, Xiangyu Zhu, Yu Yu, Tao Huang, Kaifu Zhang, Qiquan Luo, Shan Gao, Jinlong Yang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403048052

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jifang Chen, Xiangyu Zhu, Yu Yu, Tao Huang, Kaifu Zhang, Qiquan Luo, Shan Gao, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Active Learning and DFT for Fast-Tracking Single-Atom Alloy Catalysts in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-Fuel Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11695</link>
      <description>Xin Song, Pengxin Pu, Haisong Feng, Hu Ding, Yuan Deng, Zhen Ge, Sylvia Zhao, Tianyong Liu, Yusen Yang, Min Wei, Xin Zhang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403050550

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction (CO</description>
      <author>Xin Song, Pengxin Pu, Haisong Feng, Hu Ding, Yuan Deng, Zhen Ge, Sylvia Zhao, Tianyong Liu, Yusen Yang, Min Wei, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends and industrial prospects of NiFe-layered double hydroxide for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156219</link>
      <description>Sarmad Iqbal, Johan Ehlers, P. Rosaiah, Kaili Zhang, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403054145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarmad Iqbal, Johan Ehlers, P. Rosaiah, Kaili Zhang, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyoxometalate-derived anti-aggregation MoC nanoparticles for efficient hydrogen evolution in basic and acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118691</link>
      <description>Junwei Sun, Xiaoming Li, Yue Wang, Juan Yang, Hongwei Luo, Xiaoyan Zhang, Junfeng Chen, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403054206

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junwei Sun, Xiaoming Li, Yue Wang, Juan Yang, Hongwei Luo, Xiaoyan Zhang, Junfeng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering medium-entropy alloy nanoparticle nanotubes for efficient oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176859</link>
      <description>Qian Liu, Haoran Kang, Yu Liu, Xiaowei Zhang, Yisong Zhao, Ying Shirley Meng, Faming Gao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403063780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Liu, Haoran Kang, Yu Liu, Xiaowei Zhang, Yisong Zhao, Ying Shirley Meng, Faming Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand engineering regulates the electronic structure of Ni-N-C sites to promote electrocatalytic acetylene semi-hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115784</link>
      <description>Kai Xu, Mingqiang Liu, Song Xiaoning, Shengyuan Xu, Kefeng Xie, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403065344

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Xu, Mingqiang Liu, Song Xiaoning, Shengyuan Xu, Kefeng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative analysis of hydrogen leakage flow measurement and calculation in the on-board hydrogen system pipelines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.381</link>
      <description>Chuan Qin, Ying Tian, Zirong Yang, Dong Hao, Lili Feng, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 89(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403073499

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuan Qin, Ying Tian, Zirong Yang, Dong Hao, Lili Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surprising Dynamics Phenomena in the Diels&#8211;Alder Reaction of C&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; Uncovered with AI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.joc.4c01763</link>
      <description>Yi-Fan Hou, Quanhao Zhang, Pavlo O. Dral, The Journal of Organic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082209

                We performed an extensive artificial intelligence-accelerated quasi-classical molecular dynamics investigation of the time-resolved mechanism of the Diels-Alder reaction of fullerene C</description>
      <author>Yi-Fan Hou, Quanhao Zhang, Pavlo O. Dral</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.joc.4c01763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Effect of Crystal Facets and Sulfur Defects on the Product Selectivity of Various CdS Configurations for CO2 Photoreduction: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100688</link>
      <description>Shuai Liu, Jing Wang, Yu Zhong, Leiping Wang, Ding&#8208;Ming Xue, Lei Tong, Honglei Zhang, Tao Wu, Guangsuo Yu, Hang Xiao, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403084362

                CO2 photoreduction into valuable hydrocarbons, such as CO, CH4, and C2H4, delivers a promising approach to address both environmental and energy challenges. Transition metal chalcogenides, particularly cadmium sulfide (CdS), have emerged as prominent candidates due to their tunable electronic properties and availability. This study delves into a comprehensive investigation of how CdS crystalline facets and sulfur-deficient surfaces modulate the product selectivity. Through employing density functional theory (DFT), we unravel the catalytic performance of various CdS crystal orientations and sulfur vacancy configurations. The results have shown that different CdS facets exhibit unique electronic characteristics and surface energetics, which influence the adsorption dynamics and reaction pathways. The introduction of sulfur vacancies further modulates the nature of active sites, leading to substantial shifts in product selectivity. A detailed investigation on the reaction mechanisms unveils that specific facets preferentially facilitate the formation of CO, while others are more conducive to the generation of hydrocarbons such as CH4 and C2H4, due to the variations in activation barriers and intermediate stabilities. These findings underscore the importance of crystal facet engineering and defect manipulation in tailoring catalyst performance thus providing valuable insights for the rational design of efficient and selective CO2 reduction metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shuai Liu, Jing Wang, Yu Zhong, Leiping Wang, Ding&#8208;Ming Xue, Lei Tong, Honglei Zhang, Tao Wu, Guangsuo Yu, Hang Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Synergy between Surface Terminations and Boron Configuration in Boron-Based Ti&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; MXenes Electrocatalysts for Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03415</link>
      <description>Ling Meng, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403085318

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Meng, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty Quantification of Linear Scaling, Machine Learning, and Density Functional Theory Derived Thermodynamics for the Catalytic Partial Oxidation of Methane on Rhodium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05107</link>
      <description>Christopher M. Blais, Chao Xu, Richard H. West, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403090590

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Christopher M. Blais, Chao Xu, Richard H. West</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbothermal Reduction-Assisted Synthesis of a Carbon-Supported Highly Dispersed PtSn Nanoalloy for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03099</link>
      <description>Jia Li, Jing Liu, Chuan Zhao, Anjun Hu, Xuping Sun, Bingbao Mei, Jianping Long, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403090945

                Exploring high-performance and low-platinum-based electrocatalysts to accelerate the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at the air cathode of zinc-air batteries remains crucial. Herein, by combining electroless deposition and carbothermal reduction, a nitrogen-doped carbon-supported highly dispersed PtSn alloy nanocatalyst (PtSn/NC) was prepared for a high-efficiency ORR process. Electrochemical measurements show that PtSn/NC exhibits excellent electrocatalytic ORR activity with a half-wave potential of 0.850 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), which is higher than that of commercial Pt/C (0.815 V). The PtSn/NC-based (20 &#956;g</description>
      <author>Jia Li, Jing Liu, Chuan Zhao, Anjun Hu, Xuping Sun, Bingbao Mei, Jianping Long</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal sulfides: From design strategies to environmental and energy-related applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216237</link>
      <description>Sharafat Ali, Syed ul Hasnain Bakhtiar, Ahmed Ismail, Pir Muhammad Ismail, Salman Hayat, Amir Zada, Xiaoqiang Wu, Abdullah Alodhayb, Muhammad Zahid, Fazal Raziq, Jiabao Yi, Liang Qiao, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 523(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403093749

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sharafat Ali, Syed ul Hasnain Bakhtiar, Ahmed Ismail, Pir Muhammad Ismail, Salman Hayat, Amir Zada, Xiaoqiang Wu, Abdullah Alodhayb, Muhammad Zahid, Fazal Raziq, Jiabao Yi, Liang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab Initio Kinetics of Electrochemical Reactions Using the Computational Fc&lt;sup&gt;0&lt;/sup&gt;/Fc&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c04923</link>
      <description>Aleksandr S. Kramarenko, Dmitry Sharapa, Evgeny A. Pidko, Felix Studt, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403093990

                The current state-of-the-art electron-transfer modeling primarily focuses on the kinetics of charge transfer between an electroactive species and an inert electrode. Experimental studies have revealed that the existing Butler-Volmer model fails to satisfactorily replicate experimental voltammetry results for both solution-based and surface-bound redox couples. Consequently, experimentalists lack an accurate tool for predicting electron-transfer kinetics. In response to this challenge, we developed a density functional theory-based approach for accurately predicting current peak potentials by using the Marcus-Hush model. Through extensive cyclic voltammetry simulations, we conducted a thorough exploration that offers valuable insights for conducting well-informed studies in the field of electrochemistry.</description>
      <author>Aleksandr S. Kramarenko, Dmitry Sharapa, Evgeny A. Pidko, Felix Studt</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c04923</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly dispersed Ir nanoparticles on Ti3C2Tx MXene nanosheets for efficient oxygen evolution in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.009</link>
      <description>Meihong Fan, Lijia Liu, Yue Li, Fengmei Gu, Xingquan He, Hui Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403097736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meihong Fan, Lijia Liu, Yue Li, Fengmei Gu, Xingquan He, Hui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bismuth Vacancies Induced Lattice Strain in BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanodes Boosting Charge Separation For Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403835</link>
      <description>Boyan Liu, Li Wang, Yingjuan Zhang, Kang Wan, Liangcheng Xu, Siqing Ma, Ruoting Zhao, Songcan Wang, Wei Huang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403099600

                Abstract Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting is a promising technology for green hydrogen production. However, severe charge recombination in the photoelectrode materials is one of the key obstacles to achieving high performance. Herein, a BiVO&#8324; photoanode with lattice strain (Str&#8208;BVO) is constructed by generating Bi vacancies to promote charge separation in the bulk. The optimized Str&#8208;BVO photoanode achieves a photocurrent density of 6.20 mA cm&#8315; 2 at 1.23 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode under AM 1.5 G illumination, with an impressive charge separation efficiency close to 100%. Systematical experiments and density functional theory reveal that the surface Bi vacancies induced strain causes the distortion of a small number of VO 4 tetrahedra, which increases the antibonding state energy of most normal VO 4 tetrahedra and creates more electronic vacancy states, thereby significantly promoting electron&#8211;hole separation. By surface loading with a FeNiO x co&#8208;catalyst, the photoanode exhibits excellent PEC water&#8208;splitting performance and stability.</description>
      <author>Boyan Liu, Li Wang, Yingjuan Zhang, Kang Wan, Liangcheng Xu, Siqing Ma, Ruoting Zhao, Songcan Wang, Wei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403835</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure of zaykovite Rh3Se4, prediction, and analysis of physical properties of related materials: Pd3Se4, Ir3Se4, and Pt3Se4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232257</link>
      <description>Leonid S. Taran, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1045;&#1088;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, S. V. Streltsov, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403103981

                In this work, we explore the electronic properties and chemical bonding in the recently discovered mineral zaykovite, the first natural rhodium selenide Rh3Se4. We comprehensively studied the bulk electronic structure, hybridization of rhodium and selenium orbitals, and the influence of spin&#8211;orbit interaction on the electronic spectrum, as well as inspected its topological properties. In addition, we investigated the surface electronic structure of zaykovite and revealed the anisotropic Rashba-type spin splitting in the surface states. In addition, using calculations of the phonon spectra and enthalpy of formation, we predicted the family of similar selenides based on other 4d and 5d transition metals such as Ir, Pd, and Pt. The structural and electronic properties of these materials are discussed.</description>
      <author>Leonid S. Taran, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1045;&#1088;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, S. V. Streltsov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Oxygen Evolution: Challenges, Strategies, and Advances Toward Industrial&#8208;Scale Deployment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410618</link>
      <description>Yansong Zhou, Zhitong Wang, Minghui Cui, Haiyan Wu, Ying Liu, Qiongrong Ou, Xinlong Tian, Shuyu Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403108901

                Abstract Developing high&#8208;efficiency alkaline water splitting technology holds great promise in potentially revolutionizing the traditional petrochemical industry to a more sustainable hydrogen economy. Importantly, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) accompanied at the anode is considered as a critical bottleneck in terms of both complicated mechanism and sluggish kinetics, requiring rational design of OER electrocatalysts to elucidate the structure&#8208;performance relationship and reduce the applied overpotential. As a benchmarked non&#8208;precious metal candidate, NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts have gained enormous attention due to low&#8208;cost, earth&#8208;abundance, and remarkable intrinsic OER activity, which are expected to be implemented in industrial alkaline water splitting. In this contribution, a comprehensive overview of NiFe&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts is provided, starting with fundamental mechanisms, evaluation metrics, and synthetic protocols. Subsequently, basic principles with corresponding regulatory strategies are summarized following the sequence of substrate&#8208;catalyst&#8208;electrolyte design of efficient and robust NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts toward industrial&#8208;scale deployment. Perspectives on remaining challenges and instructive opportunities in this booming field are finally discussed.</description>
      <author>Yansong Zhou, Zhitong Wang, Minghui Cui, Haiyan Wu, Ying Liu, Qiongrong Ou, Xinlong Tian, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-functionalization of Ni Fe &#8722; Electrocatalysts from Prussian blue analogue for enhanced anode in anion exchange membrane water electrolysers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156256</link>
      <description>Beatrice Ricciardi, Williane da Silva Freitas, Barbara Mecheri, J.M. Luque-Centeno, Cinthia Alegre, David Sebasti&#225;n, M.J. L&#225;zaro, Alessandra D&#8217;Epifanio, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403112516

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Beatrice Ricciardi, Williane da Silva Freitas, Barbara Mecheri, J.M. Luque-Centeno, Cinthia Alegre, David Sebasti&#225;n, M.J. L&#225;zaro, Alessandra D&#8217;Epifanio</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atom-glue stabilized Pt-based intermetallic nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq6727</link>
      <description>Zhongliang Huang, Y Wang, Jing Xia, Shengnan Hu, Nanjun Chen, Tianyi Ding, Changhong Zhan, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Tong Shi, Xiang&#8208;Min Meng, Yong Xu, Liang Cao, Xiaoqing Huang, Science Advances. 10(40)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403114801

                Pt-based nanoparticles (NPs) have been widely used in catalysis. However, this suffers from aggregation and/or sintering at working conditions. We demonstrate a robust strategy for stabilizing PtCo NPs under high temperature with strong interaction between M&#8211;N&#8211;C and PtCo NPs with Pt&#8211;M&#8211;N coordination, namely, &#8220;atom glue.&#8221; Such atom glue for stabilizing Pt-based NPs can be extended to Zn, Mn, Fe, Ni, Co, and Cu, being a versatile strategy for stabilizing PtCo NPs, which substantially promotes the performance toward oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and fuel cell. Impressively, the mass activity (MA) reaches 2.99 A mg Pt &#8722;1 for ORR over g -Zn&#8211;N&#8211;C/PtCo, and 79.3% of the initial MA is maintained after 90K cycles in fuel cell. This work provides a versatile strategy for stabilizing Pt-based NPs via atom glue, which is likely to spark widespread interest across various fields.</description>
      <author>Zhongliang Huang, Y Wang, Jing Xia, Shengnan Hu, Nanjun Chen, Tianyi Ding, Changhong Zhan, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Tong Shi, Xiang&#8208;Min Meng, Yong Xu, Liang Cao, Xiaoqing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq6727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT and microkinetic modeling study of pressure effects on electroreduction reduction of CO2 to ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161421</link>
      <description>Xiaowen Wang, Fei Ma, Haiqiao Wei, Jiaying Pan, Wenjia Li, Jun Zhao, Xiaotao Yang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403117340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaowen Wang, Fei Ma, Haiqiao Wei, Jiaying Pan, Wenjia Li, Jun Zhao, Xiaotao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic communications between active sites on individual metallic nanoparticles in catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52997-w</link>
      <description>Dongrun Xu, Yaowei Jin, Bowen He, Xue Fang, Guokang Chen, Weiye Qu, Chenxin Xu, Junxiao Chen, Zhen Ma, Liwei Chen, Xingfu Tang, Xi Liu, Guangfeng Wei, Yaxin Chen, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403128752

                Catalytic activity of metal particles is reported to originate from the appearance of nonmetallic states, but conductive metallic particles, as an electron reservoir, should render electron delivery between reactants more favorably so as to have higher activity. We present that metallic rhodium particle catalysts are highly active in the low-temperature oxidation of carbon monoxide, whereas nonmetallic rhodium clusters or monoatoms on alumina remain catalytically inert. Experimental and theoretical results evidence the presence of electronic communications in between vertex atom active sites of individual metallic particles in the reaction. The electronic communications dramatically lower apparent activation energies via coupling two electrochemical-like half-reactions occurring on different active sites, which enable the metallic particles to show turnover frequencies at least four orders of magnitude higher than the nonmetallic clusters or monoatoms. Similar results are found for other metallic particle catalysts, implying the importance of electronic communications between active sites in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Dongrun Xu, Yaowei Jin, Bowen He, Xue Fang, Guokang Chen, Weiye Qu, Chenxin Xu, Junxiao Chen, Zhen Ma, Liwei Chen, Xingfu Tang, Xi Liu, Guangfeng Wei, Yaxin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52997-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bias-dependent surface stress by density functional theory combined with the effective screening medium method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.155409</link>
      <description>Satoshi Hagiwara, Shoji Ishibashi, Minoru Otani, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403130582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Satoshi Hagiwara, Shoji Ishibashi, Minoru Otani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.155409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oriented Crystal Polarization Tuning Bulk Charge and Single&#8208;Site Chemical State for Exceptional Hydrogen Photo&#8208;Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411339</link>
      <description>Zijian Zhu, Jingcong Hu, Cheng Hu, Yue Lu, Shengqi Chu, Fang Chen, Hongwei Huang, Hongwei Huang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140168

                Abstract Rapid bulk charge recombination and mediocre surface catalytic sites harshly restrict the photocatalytic activities. Herein, the aforementioned concerns are well addressed by coupling macroscopic spontaneous polarization and atomic&#8208;site engineering of CdS single&#8208;crystal nanorods for superb H 2 photo&#8208;production. The oriented growth of CdS nanorods along the polar axis, vectorially superimposing substantial polar units with orderly arrangement, renders a strong polarization electric field (20.1 times enhancement), which boosts bulk charge separation with an efficiency up to 72.4% (80.4&#8208;fold). Remarkably, polarization electric field alters the chemical state of Pt single sites by orderly reducing the binding energy of Pt atom with stepwise polarization enhancement of CdS substrate, which increases the onsite electron density of Pt from 10.232 to 10.261e &#8722; and *H key intermediates, providing preponderant Volmer&#8208;Tafel/Volmer&#8208;Heyrovsky reaction pathways with significantly decreased energy barriers for H 2 production. Thus, highly polarized CdS nanorods with atomically dispersed Pt sites perform an outstanding H 2 space&#8208;time yield of 118.5 mmol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 and apparent quantum efficiency of 57.7% at &#955; = 420 nm, and a record&#8208;high H 2 turnover frequency of 57798.4 h &#8722;1 , being one of the best catalysts for photocatalytic H 2 evolution. This work highlights the function of polarization in manipulating charge separation and catalytic reaction.</description>
      <author>Zijian Zhu, Jingcong Hu, Cheng Hu, Yue Lu, Shengqi Chu, Fang Chen, Hongwei Huang, Hongwei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemiresistive triethylamine detection based on the novel Ti3C2Tx/Co-BDC gas sensor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2024.136738</link>
      <description>Huan Liu, Qingcai Chen, Ting Xu, Heng Liu, Miao Lei, Wenhao Liu, Jingwen Cheng, Shu Yin, Chuanyi Wang, Jincai Zhao, Sensors and Actuators B Chemical. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140557

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Liu, Qingcai Chen, Ting Xu, Heng Liu, Miao Lei, Wenhao Liu, Jingwen Cheng, Shu Yin, Chuanyi Wang, Jincai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2024.136738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mild and rapid construction of Ti electrodes for efficient and corrosion-resistant oxidative catalysis at industrial-grade intensity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.010</link>
      <description>Rui Xiao, Ding&#8208;Kun Ji, Liugang Wu, Ziyan Fang, Yanhui Guo, Weiju Hao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403144529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Xiao, Ding&#8208;Kun Ji, Liugang Wu, Ziyan Fang, Yanhui Guo, Weiju Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surgical dissection of ignition behavior of aluminum nanoparticles using molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133316</link>
      <description>Yiming Lu, Lili Ye, Hongxin Luo, Mingshu Bi, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403146634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiming Lu, Lili Ye, Hongxin Luo, Mingshu Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Calculations and Machine Learning of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Activity of Nonmetallic Doped &#946;-Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C Support Pt Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10705</link>
      <description>Minhui Song, Mei Yang, Shuo Yang, Li Wang, Chenyang Cao, Hongfei Li, Xiao&#8208;Xu Wang, Panpan Gao, Ping Qian, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403146651

                The most widely used catalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is Pt, but the high cost and low abundance of Pt need to be urgently addressed. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have been an effective means of improving the utilization of Pt atoms. In this work, we used a nonmetal (NM = B, N, O, F, Si, P, S, Cl, As, Se, Br, Te, and I) doped &#946;-Mo</description>
      <author>Minhui Song, Mei Yang, Shuo Yang, Li Wang, Chenyang Cao, Hongfei Li, Xiao&#8208;Xu Wang, Panpan Gao, Ping Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical-bonding and lattice-deformation mechanisms unifying the stability and diffusion trends of hydrogen in TiN and AlN polymorphs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120447</link>
      <description>Qinsheng He, Tian&#8208;Yu Sun, Liang&#8208;Feng Huang, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403154326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qinsheng He, Tian&#8208;Yu Sun, Liang&#8208;Feng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanohybrids of B- and N-codoped reduced graphene oxide/CeO2&#8211;Co3O4 nanocomposite for efficient water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129984</link>
      <description>Zohreh Shaghaghi, Farnaz Ebrahimi, Sahar Jafari Nivlouei, Materials Chemistry and Physics. 328(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403156921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zohreh Shaghaghi, Farnaz Ebrahimi, Sahar Jafari Nivlouei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pathways and enhancement strategies for magnesium hardness removal in modified induced crystallization softening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122729</link>
      <description>Changgeng Li, Cheng Liu, Yun Han, Weibin Xu, Bing Yan, Aijun Du, Qin Li, Qi Yu, Journal of Environmental Management. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403157311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changgeng Li, Cheng Liu, Yun Han, Weibin Xu, Bing Yan, Aijun Du, Qin Li, Qi Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Area Epitaxy of Gallium Phosphide-Based Nanostructures on Microsphere Lithography-Patterned Si Wafers for Visible Light Optoelectronics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113126</link>
      <description>Vladimir V. Fedorov, Vladimir V. Fedorov, A. V. Pavlov, Sergey Komarov, E. I. Moiseev, Dmitry Miniv, &#1040;. &#1050;. &#1050;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, A. Smirnov, &#1044;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1040; &#1052; &#1052;&#1086;&#1078;&#1072;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Ivan S. Mukhin, Materials Research Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403157700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vladimir V. Fedorov, Vladimir V. Fedorov, A. V. Pavlov, Sergey Komarov, E. I. Moiseev, Dmitry Miniv, &#1040;. &#1050;. &#1050;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, A. Smirnov, &#1044;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1040; &#1052; &#1052;&#1086;&#1078;&#1072;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, Ivan S. Mukhin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important structural parameter for curvature effect of TM-N4 embeded C70 fullerenes as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction interpreted with machine learning and first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105233</link>
      <description>Aling Ma, Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403168428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aling Ma, Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic oxidation of 1,2-dichlorobenzene over CoxCry oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119975</link>
      <description>Chensheng Tu, Shijie Shao, Wangjia Xi, Hao Zhang, Qiguang Dai, Xingyi Wang, Yanglong Guo, Applied Catalysis A General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403169200

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chensheng Tu, Shijie Shao, Wangjia Xi, Hao Zhang, Qiguang Dai, Xingyi Wang, Yanglong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Progress in Structure Evolution and Durability Modulation of Ir&#8208; and Ru&#8208;Based OER Catalysts under Acidic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406657</link>
      <description>You Zi, Chengxu Zhang, Jian-Qiang Zhao, Ying Cheng, Jinliang Yuan, Jue Hu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403170675

                Abstract Green hydrogen energy, as one of the most promising energy carriers, plays a crucial role in addressing energy and environmental issues. Oxygen evolution reaction catalysts, as the key to water electrolysis hydrogen production technology, have been subject to durability constraints, preventing large&#8208;scale commercial development. Under the high current density and harsh acid&#8208;base electrolyte conditions of the water electrolysis reaction, the active metals in the catalysts are easily converted into high&#8208;valent soluble species to dissolve, leading to poor structural durability of the catalysts. There is an urgent need to overcome the durability challenges under acidic conditions and develop electrocatalysts with both high catalytic activity and high durability. In this review, the latest research results are analyzed in depth from both thermodynamic and kinetic perspectives. First, a comprehensive summary of the structural deactivation state process of noble metal oxide catalysts is presented. Second, the evolution of the structure of catalysts possessing high durability is discussed. Finally, four new strategies for the preparation of stable catalysts, &#8220;electron buffer (ECB) strategy&#8221;, combination strength control, strain control, and surface coating, are summarized. The challenges and prospects are also elaborated for the future synthesis of more effective Ru/Ir&#8208;based catalysts and boost their future application.</description>
      <author>You Zi, Chengxu Zhang, Jian-Qiang Zhao, Ying Cheng, Jinliang Yuan, Jue Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interaction of H2S with perfect and O-covered Pd(100) surface: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.439</link>
      <description>Tariq Usman, Asif Ilyas, Salman Ali Khan, Sajid Khan, Majed A. Alotaibi, Ming-Qiu Tan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 89(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403093953

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tariq Usman, Asif Ilyas, Salman Ali Khan, Sajid Khan, Majed A. Alotaibi, Ming-Qiu Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the selection of control structures using process operability analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conengprac.2024.106117</link>
      <description>Victor Alves, Fernando V. Lima, Control Engineering Practice. 153(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403155926

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Victor Alves, Fernando V. Lima</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conengprac.2024.106117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Molecules Together: Synergistic Coadsorption at Dopant Sites of Single Atom Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07621</link>
      <description>Fabian Berger, Julia Schumann, Romain R&#233;ocreux, Michail Stamatakis, Angelos Michaelides, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403062739

                Bringing molecules together on a catalytic surface is a prerequisite for bimolecular and recombination reactions. However, in the absence of attractive interactions between reactants, such as hydrogen bonds, this poses a challenge. In contrast, based on density functional theory, we show that coadsorption at active sites of single-atom alloys (SAAs) is favored and that coadsorption is a general phenomenon observed for catalytically relevant adsorbates on a broad range of SAAs under temperature and pressure conditions commonly employed for catalysis. Dopants located in both terrace sites and in step edge defects exhibit a preference for coadsorption, displaying similar periodic trends. Using kinetic Monte Carlo simulations, we compare the reactivity of a model reaction on both a pure metal and an SAA and show that the preference for coadsorption significantly alters the overall reaction energy profile, even when the barriers for the rate-determining elementary step are identical. In our models, the coadsorption preference enhances the catalytic activity of the SAA surface by several orders of magnitude compared to the pure metal. We also report infrared (IR) spectroscopic signatures of coadsorption, which facilitate experimental detection. Analysis reveals that in these systems repulsive lateral interactions between nearby molecules are more than compensated for by the enhanced binding at dopant sites. Among the broad range of systems considered, SAAs containing early transition metals (TMs) exhibit the strongest coadsorption preference, which can be rationalized by assuming the existence of an optimal number of electrons involved in binding. The strong coadsorption preference, together with facile product desorption from early TMs, renders these systems attractive candidates for catalysis. Moreover, these SAAs could open new routes for reduction reactions because coadsorption with hydrogen is favored.</description>
      <author>Fabian Berger, Julia Schumann, Romain R&#233;ocreux, Michail Stamatakis, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07621</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
