<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 01:12:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene-supported MN4 single-atom catalysts for multifunctional electrocatalysis enabled by axial Fe tetramer coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.132</link>
      <description>Lulu Gao, Donghai Wu, Silu Li, Haobo Li, Dongwei Ma, Journal of colloid and interface science. 676(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400672156

                Multifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are crucial for development of the key electrochemical energy storage and conversion devices, for which single-atom catalyst (SAC) has present great promises. Very recently, some experimental works showed that structurally well-defined ultra-small transition-metal clusters (such as Fe and Co tetramers, denoted as Fe</description>
      <author>Lulu Gao, Donghai Wu, Silu Li, Haobo Li, Dongwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin occupancy regulation of the Pt d-orbital for a robust low-Pt catalyst towards oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50332-x</link>
      <description>Dongping Xue, Yifang Yuan, Yue Yu, Siran Xu, Yifan Wei, Jiaqi Zhang, Haizhong Guo, Minhua Shao, Jianan Zhang, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400672738

                Disentangling the limitations of O-O bond activation and OH* site-blocking effects on Pt sites is key to improving the intrinsic activity and stability of low-Pt catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Herein, we integrate of PtFe alloy nanocrystals on a single-atom Fe-N-C substrate (PtFe@Fe</description>
      <author>Dongping Xue, Yifang Yuan, Yue Yu, Siran Xu, Yifan Wei, Jiaqi Zhang, Haizhong Guo, Minhua Shao, Jianan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50332-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the oxygen evolution reaction activity of lanthanide-doped NiFe-LDHs through lanthanide contraction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154059</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Kai-Sheng Chen, ZihaoYan, Yongjun Chen, Hongtao Liu, Pengfei Yin, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400673171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Kai-Sheng Chen, ZihaoYan, Yongjun Chen, Hongtao Liu, Pengfei Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-plane heterostructures of transition metal dichalcogenide monolayers with enhanced charge separation and effective overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.171</link>
      <description>Ling Zhu, Qihui Sun, Junwei Wang, Weiqiang Lv, Azim Khan, Yifan Liu, Nasir Mahmood, Xian Jian, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400677098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Zhu, Qihui Sun, Junwei Wang, Weiqiang Lv, Azim Khan, Yifan Liu, Nasir Mahmood, Xian Jian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of electronic and optical properties of g-CN/XTe2(X=W, Mo) heterojunctions by biaxial strain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.148</link>
      <description>Yang Shen, Pei Yuan, Zhihao Yuan, Zhen Cui, Deming Ma, Fengjiao Cheng, Ke Qin, Hanxiao Wang, Enling Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400677137

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Shen, Pei Yuan, Zhihao Yuan, Zhen Cui, Deming Ma, Fengjiao Cheng, Ke Qin, Hanxiao Wang, Enling Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Electrochemical Activity of 2D Materials Edges through Oriented Electric Fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06341</link>
      <description>Hao Chen, Ding&#8208;Rui Chen, You-Chen Lin, Po-Hsieh Lin, Jeng&#8208;Shian Chang, Jeyavelan Muthu, Mario Hofmann, Ya&#8208;Ping Hsieh, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400678584

                The edges of 2D materials have emerged as promising electrochemical catalyst systems, yet their performance still lags behind that of noble metals. Here, we demonstrate the potential of oriented electric fields (OEFs) to enhance the electrochemical activity of 2D materials edges. By atomically engineering the edge of a fluorographene/graphene/MoS</description>
      <author>Hao Chen, Ding&#8208;Rui Chen, You-Chen Lin, Po-Hsieh Lin, Jeng&#8208;Shian Chang, Jeyavelan Muthu, Mario Hofmann, Ya&#8208;Ping Hsieh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Dynamics of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation on Iron Catalysts Using ReaxFF Molecular Dynamics Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01212</link>
      <description>Quang K. Loi, Debra J. Searles, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400686575

                The conversion of CO</description>
      <author>Quang K. Loi, Debra J. Searles</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Heteroatom Doping in Enhancing the Catalytic Activities and Stability of Atomically Dispersed Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02747</link>
      <description>Xueqi Cheng, Dengfeng Wu, Hui Xu, Wei Zhang, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400692872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xueqi Cheng, Dengfeng Wu, Hui Xu, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic&#8208;Level Observation of Potential&#8208;Dependent Variations at the Surface of an Oxide Catalyst during Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403392</link>
      <description>Chang Hyun Park, Hyungdoh Lee, Jin&#8208;Seok Choi, Tae Gyu Yun, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400699451

                Understanding the intricate details of the surface atomic structure and composition of catalysts during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for developing catalysts with high stability in water electrolyzers. While many notable studies highlight surface amorphization and reconstruction, systematic analytical tracing of the catalyst surface as a function of overpotential remains elusive. Heteroepitaxial (001) films of chemically stable and lattice-oxygen-inactive LaCoO</description>
      <author>Chang Hyun Park, Hyungdoh Lee, Jin&#8208;Seok Choi, Tae Gyu Yun, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the crystallographic orientation dependent electrochemical corrosion rates of aluminum and its binary alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41529-024-00490-6</link>
      <description>Haini Jin, Yudong Sui, Xiaohua Yu, Hao Zhou, Jing Feng, Yehua Jiang, npj materials degradation. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400701152

                Abstract This paper provides a study for crystallographic orientation-dependent corrosion rate of aluminum employing an ab initio model with inputs from first-principles calculations. Results showed that the sequence of corrosion rate is in the order of (111) &lt; (410) &lt; (331) &lt; (221) &lt; (321) &lt; (211) &lt; (110) &lt; (100) &lt; (210) &lt; (320) &lt; (310) &lt; (311) for aluminum. The predicted corrosion current densities for (111), (110), and (100) surfaces are in general agreement with the experimental results. The alloying effects were further investigated employing this model with results validated via the polarization curves of alloyed aluminum.</description>
      <author>Haini Jin, Yudong Sui, Xiaohua Yu, Hao Zhou, Jing Feng, Yehua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41529-024-00490-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Atom Doping with GeC: Tuning Electronic, Magnetic and Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416320</link>
      <description>Shaoqiang Wang, Zhihao Yuan, Zhen Cui, Physica. B, Condensed matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400720298

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaoqiang Wang, Zhihao Yuan, Zhen Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Score-based denoising for atomic structure identification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01337-z</link>
      <description>Tim Hsu, Babak Sadigh, Nicolas Bertin, Cheol Woo Park, James Chapman, Vasily V. Bulatov, Fei Zhou, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400720724

                Abstract We propose an effective method for removing thermal vibrations that complicate the task of analyzing complex dynamics in atomistic simulation of condensed matter. Our method iteratively subtracts thermal noises or perturbations in atomic positions using a denoising score function trained on synthetically noised but otherwise perfect crystal lattices. The resulting denoised structures clearly reveal underlying crystal order while retaining disorder associated with crystal defects. Purely geometric, agnostic to interatomic potentials, and trained without inputs from explicit simulations, our denoiser can be applied to simulation data generated from vastly different interatomic interactions. The denoiser is shown to improve existing classification methods, such as common neighbor analysis and polyhedral template matching, reaching perfect classification accuracy on a recent benchmark dataset of thermally perturbed structures up to the melting point. Demonstrated here in a wide variety of atomistic simulation contexts, the denoiser is general, robust, and readily extendable to delineate order from disorder in structurally and chemically complex materials.</description>
      <author>Tim Hsu, Babak Sadigh, Nicolas Bertin, Cheol Woo Park, James Chapman, Vasily V. Bulatov, Fei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01337-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus and nitrogen co-doped-graphene: Stability and catalytic activity in oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2024.100379</link>
      <description>Jinmin Guo, Weiwei Shao, Hongfeng Yan, Min Zhao, Yang&#8208;Yi Liu, Qiufeng Fang, T.X. Xia, Jinlong Wang, Xiao-Chun Li, Carbon trends. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400722108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinmin Guo, Weiwei Shao, Hongfeng Yan, Min Zhao, Yang&#8208;Yi Liu, Qiufeng Fang, T.X. Xia, Jinlong Wang, Xiao-Chun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2024.100379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Evaluation of Adiabatic Proton Tunneling across the Electrified Double Layer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01336</link>
      <description>M. Askari, Reagan Huckabee, Joseph A. Gauthier, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400725059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Askari, Reagan Huckabee, Joseph A. Gauthier</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts based on two-dimensional metalloporphyrin monolayers for electrochemical nitrate reduction to ammonia by first-principles calculations and interpretable machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.200</link>
      <description>Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Aling Ma, Zhiyi Liu, Zhenzhen Wang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400728644

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Aling Ma, Zhiyi Liu, Zhenzhen Wang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Entity Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00723</link>
      <description>Thomas B. Clarke, Lynn E. Krushinski, Kathryn J. Vannoy, Guillermo S. Col&#243;n-Quintana, Kingshuk Roy, Jeffrey E. Dick, Christophe Renault, Myrtle Hill, Jeffrey E. Dick, Chemical reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400729701

                Making a measurement over millions of nanoparticles or exposed crystal facets seldom reports on reactivity of a single nanoparticle or facet, which may depart drastically from ensemble measurements. Within the past 30 years, science has moved toward studying the reactivity of single atoms, molecules, and nanoparticles, one at a time. This shift has been fueled by the realization that everything changes at the nanoscale, especially important industrially relevant properties like those important to electrocatalysis. Studying single nanoscale entities, however, is not trivial and has required the development of new measurement tools. This review explores a tale of the clever use of old and new measurement tools to study electrocatalysis at the single entity level. We explore in detail the complex interrelationship between measurement method, electrocatalytic material, and reaction of interest (e.g., carbon dioxide reduction, oxygen reduction, hydrazine oxidation, etc.). We end with our perspective on the future of single entity electrocatalysis with a key focus on what types of measurements present the greatest opportunity for fundamental discovery.</description>
      <author>Thomas B. Clarke, Lynn E. Krushinski, Kathryn J. Vannoy, Guillermo S. Col&#243;n-Quintana, Kingshuk Roy, Jeffrey E. Dick, Christophe Renault, Myrtle Hill, Jeffrey E. Dick</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the carbon nanomaterial&#8208;supported Pt complex electrocatalysts for efficient and selective chlorine evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27466</link>
      <description>Jewel Hossen, Naoki Nakatani, Journal of computational chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400735545

                Chlorine is an important chemical which has long been produced in chlor-alkali process using dimensionally stable anodes (DSA). However, some serious drawbacks of DSA inspire the development of alternative anodes for chlorine evolution reaction (CER). In this study, we focused on the graphene- and carbon nanotube-supported platinum tetra-phenyl porphyrins as electrocatalysts for CER, which have been theoretically investigated based on density functional theory. Our results reveal that the supported substrates possess potential CER electrocatalytic activity with very low thermodynamic overpotentials (0.012-0.028 V) via Cl* pathway instead of ClO*. The electronic structures analyses showed that electron transfer from the support to the adsorbed chlorine via the Pt center leads to strong Pt-Cl interactions. Furthermore, the supported electrocatalysts exhibited excellent selectivity toward CER because of high overpotentials and reaction barriers of oxygen evolution process. Therefore, our results may pave the way for designing CER electrocatalyst utilizing emerging carbon nanomaterials.</description>
      <author>Jewel Hossen, Naoki Nakatani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional platinum borides: A Dirac nodal line quantum electrocatalyst for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.202</link>
      <description>Zi Gao, Fengxian Ma, Weizhen Meng, Yalong Jiao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400735606

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zi Gao, Fengxian Ma, Weizhen Meng, Yalong Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detrimental Increase of Spin-Phonon Coupling in Molecular Qubits on Substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05728</link>
      <description>Kathleen R. Mullin, R Greer, Michael J. Waters, M. Jeremy Amdur, Lei Sun, Danna E. Freedman, James M. Rondinelli, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400736052

                Molecular qubits are a promising platform for quantum information systems. Although single molecule and ensemble studies have assessed the performance of</description>
      <author>Kathleen R. Mullin, R Greer, Michael J. Waters, M. Jeremy Amdur, Lei Sun, Danna E. Freedman, James M. Rondinelli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-level tailoring of single-atom tungsten catalysts for optimized electrochemical nitrate-to-ammonia conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.134</link>
      <description>Yujie Sun, Guoning Feng, Zhiwei Wang, Jing Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjian Sa, Qiaohong Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Zuju Ma, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400737656

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Sun, Guoning Feng, Zhiwei Wang, Jing Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjian Sa, Qiaohong Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Zuju Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning copper into an efficient and stable CO evolution catalyst beyond noble metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50436-4</link>
      <description>Jing Xue, Xue Dong, Chunxiao Liu, Jiawei Li, Yizhou Dai, Weiqing Xue, Laihao Luo, Yuan Ji, Xiao Zhang, Li Xu, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Jianping Xiao, Chuan Xia, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400746760

                Using renewable electricity to convert CO</description>
      <author>Jing Xue, Xue Dong, Chunxiao Liu, Jiawei Li, Yizhou Dai, Weiqing Xue, Laihao Luo, Yuan Ji, Xiao Zhang, Li Xu, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Jianping Xiao, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50436-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Oxides as Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Mini Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02061</link>
      <description>Yueqi Huang, Dan Wang, Yihang Yu, Zenghui Li, Xiaojing Wen, Zhiyuan Wang, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400763937

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yueqi Huang, Dan Wang, Yihang Yu, Zenghui Li, Xiaojing Wen, Zhiyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confinement effects boosted oxygen reduction reactions inside FeN4-decorated carbon nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101059</link>
      <description>Shan Li, Xiaoling Peng, Chang-Wei Wang, Xiang Zhao, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, Chang Ming Li, Chem catalysis. 4(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400769277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Li, Xiaoling Peng, Chang-Wei Wang, Xiang Zhao, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, Chang Ming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Efficiency Photocatalyst and High-Response Ultraviolet Photodetector Based on the Ga2sse/Gan Heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898950</link>
      <description>Ke Qin, Enling Li, Yang Shen, Deming Ma, Pei Yuan, Hanxiao Wang, Zhen Cui, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400769282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ke Qin, Enling Li, Yang Shen, Deming Ma, Pei Yuan, Hanxiao Wang, Zhen Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Organic Spacers and Dimensionality on Templating of Halide Perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01283</link>
      <description>Erik Fransson, Julia Wiktor, Paul Erhart, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400774317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Erik Fransson, Julia Wiktor, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An asymmetrical Zr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO/VSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; heterostructure as an efficient electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00906a</link>
      <description>Jisong Hu, Xiangyu Liu, Jiahao Wang, Jinxuan Jin, Min Ouyang, Moshang Fan, Rui Zhang, Xiao Ji, Ling Miao, Jianjun Jiang, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400781137

                Asymmetric Zr 2 CO/VSe 2 heterostructures demonstrate remarkable hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity across various stacking angles, significantly outperforming the symmetric Zr 2 CO 2 structure.</description>
      <author>Jisong Hu, Xiangyu Liu, Jiahao Wang, Jinxuan Jin, Min Ouyang, Moshang Fan, Rui Zhang, Xiao Ji, Ling Miao, Jianjun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00906a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineering and Carbon Supporting to Achieve Ni-Doped CoP3 with High Catalytic Activities for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01471-9</link>
      <description>Daowei Zha, Ruoxing Wang, Shijun Tian, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Zejun Xu, Chu Qin, Xiaoning Tian, Lin Zhao, Nano-micro letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400784939

                Abstract This work reports the use of defect engineering and carbon supporting to achieve metal-doped phosphides with high activities and stabilities for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. Specifically, the nitrogen-doped carbon nanofiber-supported Ni-doped CoP 3 with rich P defects (Pv&#183;) on the carbon cloth (p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC) is synthesized through a plasma-assisted phosphorization method. The p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC is an efficient and stable catalyst for the HER and the OER. It only needs overpotentials of 107 and 306 mV to drive 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for the HER and the OER, respectively. Its catalytic activities are higher than those of other catalysts reported recently. The high activities of the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC mainly arise from its peculiar structural features. The density functional theory calculation indicates that the Pv&#183; richness, the Ni doping, and the carbon supporting can optimize the adsorption of the H atoms at the catalyst surface and promote the strong electronic couplings between the carbon nanofiber-supported p-NiCoP with the surface oxide layer formed during the OER process. This gives the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC with the high activities for the HER and the OER. When used in alkaline water electrolyzers, the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC shows the superior activity and excellent stability for overall water splitting. Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Daowei Zha, Ruoxing Wang, Shijun Tian, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Zejun Xu, Chu Qin, Xiaoning Tian, Lin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01471-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrosynthesis: enhancing electrochemical systems, unveiling emerging applications, and seizing opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00412d</link>
      <description>Zhiping Deng, Seung-Yun Choi, Ge Li, Xiaolei Wang, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400789103

                Recent achievements in H 2 O 2 electrosynthesis are reviewed, including electrocatalyst design, electrode optimization, electrolyte engineering, reactor exploration, potential applications, and integrated systems.</description>
      <author>Zhiping Deng, Seung-Yun Choi, Ge Li, Xiaolei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00412d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-scale computational screening of all-silica zeolites for adsorptive separation of ternary (H2S/CO2/CH4) mixtures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154116</link>
      <description>S.&#8208;J. YOON, Muhammad Hassan, Yongchul G. Chung, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400798317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S.&#8208;J. YOON, Muhammad Hassan, Yongchul G. Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Property Prediction of Functional Organic Molecular Crystals with Graph Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3626203.3670584</link>
      <description>Dana O&#8217;Connor, Paola A. Buitrago, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400799096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dana O&#8217;Connor, Paola A. Buitrago</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1145/3626203.3670584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening of double-atom metals anchored on defective boron nitride for N2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11144-024-02691-1</link>
      <description>Xin Lian, Xinlin Tang, Haiyue Liao, Wenlong Guo, Yunhuai Zhang, Guangyong Gao, Reaction kinetics, mechanisms and catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Lian, Xinlin Tang, Haiyue Liao, Wenlong Guo, Yunhuai Zhang, Guangyong Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11144-024-02691-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the interactions between N-intermediates and one-dimensional conjugated coordination polymers to boost electroreduction of nitrate to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60059-8</link>
      <description>Haibo Liu, Xue&#8208;Feng Cheng, Jinyan Huo, Xiaofang Liu, Huilong Dong, Hongbo Zeng, Qingfeng Xu, Jianmei Lu, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806604

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibo Liu, Xue&#8208;Feng Cheng, Jinyan Huo, Xiaofang Liu, Huilong Dong, Hongbo Zeng, Qingfeng Xu, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60059-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of Pt-anchored single-atom alloy electrocatalysts for NO-to-NH3 conversion by density functional theory and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60078-1</link>
      <description>Jieyu Liu, Hongli Guo, Yulin Xiong, Xing Chen, Yifu Yu, Changhong Wang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806623

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jieyu Liu, Hongli Guo, Yulin Xiong, Xing Chen, Yifu Yu, Changhong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60078-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese pyrophosphate with multiple coordinated water molecules for electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60052-5</link>
      <description>Shujiao Yang, Pengfei Jiang, Kaihang Yue, Kai Guo, Luna Yang, Jinxiu Han, Xinyang Peng, Xuepeng Zhang, Haoquan Zheng, Tao Yang, Rui Cao, Ya Yan, Wei Zhang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400807161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shujiao Yang, Pengfei Jiang, Kaihang Yue, Kai Guo, Luna Yang, Jinxiu Han, Xinyang Peng, Xuepeng Zhang, Haoquan Zheng, Tao Yang, Rui Cao, Ya Yan, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60052-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Design of Mesoporous Nanospheres with High Entropic Alloy Sites for Efficient Redox Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402518</link>
      <description>Ravi Nandan, Hiroki Nara, Ho Ngoc Nam, Quan Manh Phung, Quynh Phuong Ngo, Jongbeom Na, Joel Henzie, Yusuke Yamauchi, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400808967

                Abstract High Entropy Alloys (HEAs) are a versatile material with unique properties, tailored for various applications. They enable pH&#8208;sensitive electrocatalytic transformations like hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and hydrogen oxidation reactions (HOR) in alkaline media. Mesoporous nanostructures with high surface area are preferred for these electrochemical reactions, but designing mesoporous HEA sis challenging. To overcome this challenge, a low&#8208;temperature triblock copolymer&#8208;assisted wet&#8208;chemical approach is developed to produce mesoporous HEA nanospheres composed of PtPdRuMoNi systems with sufficient entropic mixing. Owing to active sites with inherent entropic effect, mesoporous features, and increased accessibility, optimized HEA nanospheres promote strong HER/HOR performance in alkaline medium. At 30 mV nominal overpotential, it exhibits a mass activity of &#8776;167 (HER) and 151 A g Pt &#8722;1 (HOR), far exceeding commercial Pt&#8208;C electrocatalysts (34 and 48 A g Pt &#8722;1 ) and many recently reported various alloys. The Mott&#8208;Schottky analysis reveals HEA nanospheres inherit high charge carrier density, positive flat band potential, and smaller charge transfer barrier, resulting in better activity and faster kinetics. This micelle&#8208;assisted synthetic enable the exploration of the compositional and configurational spaces of HEAs at relatively low temperature, while simultaneously facilitating the introduction of mesoporous nanostructures for a wide range of catalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Ravi Nandan, Hiroki Nara, Ho Ngoc Nam, Quan Manh Phung, Quynh Phuong Ngo, Jongbeom Na, Joel Henzie, Yusuke Yamauchi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrochemical oxygen reduction to hydrogen peroxide coupled with organic oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50446-2</link>
      <description>Yining Sun, Kui Fan, Jinze Li, Li Wang, Yusen Yang, Zhenhua Li, Mingfei Shao, Xue Duan, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400809795

                Abstract The electrochemical oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) to produce hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) is appealing due to its sustainability. However, its efficiency is compromised by the competing 4e &#8722; ORR pathway. In this work, we report a hierarchical carbon nanosheet array electrode with a single-atom Ni catalyst synthesized using organic molecule-intercalated layered double hydroxides as precursors. The electrode exhibits excellent 2e &#8722; ORR performance under alkaline conditions and achieves H 2 O 2 yield rates of 0.73 mol g cat &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 in the H-cell and 5.48 mol g cat &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 in the flow cell, outperforming most reported catalysts. The experimental results show that the Ni atoms selectively adsorb O 2 , while carbon nanosheets generate reactive hydrogen species, synergistically enhancing H 2 O 2 production. Furthermore, a coupling reaction system integrating the 2e &#8722; ORR with ethylene glycol oxidation significantly enhances H 2 O 2 yield rate to 7.30 mol g cat &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 while producing valuable glycolic acid. Moreover, we convert alkaline electrolyte containing H 2 O 2 directly into the downstream product sodium perborate to reduce the separation cost further. Techno-economic analysis validates the economic viability of this system.</description>
      <author>Yining Sun, Kui Fan, Jinze Li, Li Wang, Yusen Yang, Zhenhua Li, Mingfei Shao, Xue Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50446-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal&#8208;Phase&#8208; and B&#8208;Content&#8208;Dependent Electrochemical Behavior of Pd&#9472;B Nanocrystals toward Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402271</link>
      <description>Hafidatul Wahidah, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Woo Hyeok Kim, Tae Wu Kim, Seok Ki Kim, Jong Wook Hong, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400833633

                Abstract The manipulation of crystal phases in metal&#8211;nonmetal interstitial alloy nanostructures has attracted considerable attention due to the formation of unique electronic structures and surface atomic arrangements, resulting in unprecedented catalytic performances. However, achieving simultaneous control over crystal phase and nonmetal elements in metal&#8211;nonmetal interstitial alloy nanostructures has remained a formidable challenge. Here, a novel synthesis approach is presented for Pd&#9472;B interstitial alloy nanocrystals (NCs) that allows investigation of the crystal&#8208;phase&#8208; and B&#8208;content&#8208;dependent catalytic performance. Through comparison of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) properties of Pd&#9472;B X interstitial alloy NCs with different crystal phases and B contents, achieved by precise control of reaction temperature and time, the influences of crystal phase and B contents in the Pd&#9472;B X interstitial alloy NCs on ORR are precisely investigated. The hexagonal closed packed (hcp) PdB 0.5 NCs exhibit superior catalytic activity, with mass activities reaching 2.58 A mg &#8722;1 , surpassing Pd/C by 10.3 times, attributed to synergistic effects by the hcp crystal phase and relatively high B contents. This study not only provides a novel approach to fabricate interstitial alloy nanostructures with unconventional crystal phases and finely controlled nonmetal elements but also elucidates the importance of crystal phase and nonmetal element content in optimizing electrocatalytic efficiency.</description>
      <author>Hafidatul Wahidah, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Woo Hyeok Kim, Tae Wu Kim, Seok Ki Kim, Jong Wook Hong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimentally validating sabatier plot by molecular level microenvironment customization for oxygen electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50377-y</link>
      <description>Bingyu Huang, Qiao Gu, Xiannong Tang, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400834814

                Microenvironmental modifications on metal sites are crucial to tune oxygen reduction catalytic behavior and decrypt intrinsic mechanism, whereas the stochastic properties of traditional pyrolyzed single-atom catalysts induce vague recognition on structure-reactivity relations. Herein, we report a theoretical descriptor relying on binding energies of oxygen adsorbates and directly associating the derived Sabatier volcano plot with calculated overpotential to forecast catalytic efficiency of cobalt porphyrin. This Sabatier volcano plot instructs that electron-withdrawing substituents mitigate the over-strong *OH intermediate adsorption by virtue of the decreased proportion of electrons in bonding orbital. To experimentally validate this speculation, we implement a secondary sphere microenvironment customization strategy on cobalt porphyrin-based polymer nanocomposite analogs. Systematic X-ray spectroscopic and in situ electrochemical characterizations capture the pronounced accessible active site density and the fast interfacial/outward charge migration kinetics contributions for the optimal carboxyl group-substituted catalyst. This work offers ample strategies for designing single-atom catalysts with well-managed microenvironment under the guidance of Sabatier volcano map.</description>
      <author>Bingyu Huang, Qiao Gu, Xiannong Tang, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50377-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating oxygen reduction reaction barriers: An in-depth first-principles exploration of high-entropy alloy as catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107782</link>
      <description>Mingyi Chen, Ngoc Thanh Thuy Tran, Wen-Dung Hsu, Electrochemistry communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400849852

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyi Chen, Ngoc Thanh Thuy Tran, Wen-Dung Hsu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic Synthesis Catalyzed by Supported Metal Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-4573-9_4</link>
      <description>Ming Bao, Jiasheng Wang, Xiujuan Feng, Jingjie Luo, Jian Sun, Molecular catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400850787

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming Bao, Jiasheng Wang, Xiujuan Feng, Jingjie Luo, Jian Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-4573-9_4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Modeling of the Local Reaction Environment in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00234</link>
      <description>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling, Accounts of chemical research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400851781

                ConspectusElectrocatalytic reactions, such as oxygen reduction/evolution reactions and CO</description>
      <author>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling chemical processes in explicit solvents with machine learning potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50418-6</link>
      <description>Hanwen Zhang, Veronika Jur&#225;skov&#225;, Fernanda Duarte, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400857864

                Abstract Solvent effects influence all stages of the chemical processes, modulating the stability of intermediates and transition states, as well as altering reaction rates and product ratios. However, accurately modelling these effects remains challenging. Here, we present a general strategy for generating reactive machine learning potentials to model chemical processes in solution. Our approach combines active learning with descriptor-based selectors and automation, enabling the construction of data-efficient training sets that span the relevant chemical and conformational space. We apply this strategy to investigate a Diels-Alder reaction in water and methanol. The generated machine learning potentials enable us to obtain reaction rates that are in agreement with experimental data and analyse the influence of these solvents on the reaction mechanism. Our strategy offers an efficient approach to the routine modelling of chemical reactions in solution, opening up avenues for studying complex chemical processes in an efficient manner.</description>
      <author>Hanwen Zhang, Veronika Jur&#225;skov&#225;, Fernanda Duarte</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50418-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Conductive Metal-Organic Frameworks Electrocatalyst: Design Principle and Energy Conversion Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101652</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, Rahul Anil Borse, Gui Wang, Zhe Xiao, Hua Zhu, Yiling Sun, Zhengfang Qian, Shuaiqi Zhong, Renheng Wang, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400865804

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, Rahul Anil Borse, Gui Wang, Zhe Xiao, Hua Zhu, Yiling Sun, Zhengfang Qian, Shuaiqi Zhong, Renheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101652</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on hydrogen generation based on inorganic metal oxide nano-catalyst using water electrolysis approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/revic-2024-0026</link>
      <description>Muhammad Naeem Ayub, Kwang&#8208;Hyun Baek, Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Saad M. Al-Baqami, Khalid Ahmed Alzahrani, Md. Reazuddin Repon, Md. Rezaur Rahman, Mohammad Mizanur Rahman Khan, Muhammad Nadeem Arshad, Reviews in Inorganic Chemistry. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400836369

                Abstract Today world is looking for a cheap, environment friendly and efficient substitute of fossil fuel. Because due to large consumption of the fossil fuels on daily basis in whole world, emission of hazardous gases have produced lethal effects on human being. In this scenario hydrogen energy has emerged in form of clean, renewable and more efficient energy. Now the key challenge is that efficient production of the green hydrogen at commercial scale to meet demand of hydrogen. The electrolysis of water is the best pathway to achieve efficient hydrogen production. For this purpose the synthesis and improvement of low cast, active as well as stable catalysts or electrolysis is prerequisite for hydrogen production by electro-catalytic method for splitting of water. Main focus of this review is that, how we can perform the electrolysis of water by various techniques using novel methods especially electro-catalysts in term of activity, efficiency, large surface area, porosity, and stability. This will be performed by the method of two-half cell reaction one is the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) other one Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), where reaction proceeded in both medium acidic as well as alkaline phases. Particular attention is given to produce green clean hydrogen production from usable water and its physical and chemical storages for further uses for the support of human sustainability. Basically the recent strategy is to prepare, design and development of nanoscale materials/composite with non-noble metals and with also nanostructured with noble-metals will be discussed in this approach. The increased efficiency and utility have been the focal points of the use of diverse materials from different classes. To increase the electro-catalytic efficiency in OER and HER, we will discuss about new analyses methods and insights into studying the chemical compositions, shapes, surface area, porosity, and synergy of catalysts and the active sites of nanostructured electro-catalysts. This review will further provide the picture of current state of developments as well as recent progress for mechanized efficient production of clean hydrogen (i.e., HER) from water by electrocatalytic method using various nanoscale materials in a broad scale.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Naeem Ayub, Kwang&#8208;Hyun Baek, Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Saad M. Al-Baqami, Khalid Ahmed Alzahrani, Md. Reazuddin Repon, Md. Rezaur Rahman, Mohammad Mizanur Rahman Khan, Muhammad Nadeem Arshad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/revic-2024-0026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing cost-effective pyrocarbon for highly efficient gold retrieval from e-waste leachate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50595-4</link>
      <description>Kaixing Fu, Xia Liu, Xiaolin Zhang, Shenghui Zhou, Nanwen Zhu, Yong Pei, Jinming Luo, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400847545

                Abstract Addressing burdens of electronic waste (E-waste) leachate while achieving sustainable and selective recovery of noble metals, such as gold, is highly demanded due to its limited supply and escalating prices. Here we demonstrate an environmentally-benign and practical approach for gold recovery from E-waste leachate using alginate-derived pyrocarbon sorbent. The sorbent demonstrates potent gold recovery performance compared to most previously reported advanced sorbents, showcasing high recovery capacity of 2829.7 mg g &#8722;1 , high efficiency (&gt;99.5%), remarkable selectivity ( K d ~ 3.1 &#215; 10 8 mL g &#8722;1 ), and robust anti-interference capabilities within environmentally relevant contexts. The aromatic structures of pyrocarbon serve as crucial electrons sources, enabling a hydroxylation process that simultaneously generates electrons and phenolic hydroxyls for the reduction of gold ions. Our investigations further uncover a &#8220;stepwise&#8221; nucleation mechanism, in which gold ions are reduced as intermediate gold-chlorine clusters, facilitating rapid reduction process by lowering energy barriers from 1.08 to &#8722;21.84 eV. Technoeconomic analysis demonstrates its economic viability with an input-output ratio as high as 1370%. Our protocol obviates the necessity for organic reagents whilst obtaining 23.96 karats gold product from real-world central processing units (CPUs) leachates. This work introduces a green sorption technique for gold recovery, emphasizing its role in promoting a circular economy and environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Kaixing Fu, Xia Liu, Xiaolin Zhang, Shenghui Zhou, Nanwen Zhu, Yong Pei, Jinming Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50595-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ Regulating the Phase Structure of Ce-based Catalytic Sites to Boost the Performance of Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110030</link>
      <description>Jianping Liu, Yuanbin Jin, Rong Jin, Yao Liu, Zili Ma, Chaozhong Guo, Lei Yu, Lingtao Sun, Haifeng Chen, Yujun Si, Sha Li, Honglin Li, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400849460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianping Liu, Yuanbin Jin, Rong Jin, Yao Liu, Zili Ma, Chaozhong Guo, Lei Yu, Lingtao Sun, Haifeng Chen, Yujun Si, Sha Li, Honglin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallocorroles as bifunctional electrocatalysts for water-splitting: A theoretical investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.125535</link>
      <description>Akbar Omidvar, Hadise Soleymani, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400849829

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akbar Omidvar, Hadise Soleymani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.125535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkaline Electrochemical Oxygen Reduction Boosted by Trimetallic Palladium&#8211;Copper&#8211;Gold Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175630</link>
      <description>M.D. Obradovi&#263;, U.&#268;. La&#269;njevac, V. Radmilovi&#263;, A. Gavrilovi&#263;, Janez Kova&#269;, Jelena Rogan, Sanja Stevanovi&#263;, Velimir Radmilovi&#263;, S.Lj. Gojkovi&#263;, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400849958

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M.D. Obradovi&#263;, U.&#268;. La&#269;njevac, V. Radmilovi&#263;, A. Gavrilovi&#263;, Janez Kova&#269;, Jelena Rogan, Sanja Stevanovi&#263;, Velimir Radmilovi&#263;, S.Lj. Gojkovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective reduction of CO2 to ethanol over Si/Cu(1 1 1) surface: An insights from the first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114781</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, Dan Wang, Boting Yang, Song Jiang, Gang Sun, Yong&#8208;Qing Qiu, Chun&#8208;Guang Liu, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400867054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, Dan Wang, Boting Yang, Song Jiang, Gang Sun, Yong&#8208;Qing Qiu, Chun&#8208;Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuFe nanoparticles coupled Cu&#8211;Nx for enhancing oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134890</link>
      <description>Xiaoting Cao, Lvzhou Li, Xu Dong, Xi Wang, Xiaoshuang Zhou, Jiangnan Li, Jianning Ding, Xiaoshuang Zhou, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400871646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoting Cao, Lvzhou Li, Xu Dong, Xi Wang, Xiaoshuang Zhou, Jiangnan Li, Jianning Ding, Xiaoshuang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Studies on Defective Hbn-Supported Metal-Nonmetal Synergistic Catalysis for Urea Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901881</link>
      <description>Ziyang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400872758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Doped into Layered Double Hydroxide as Efficient Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901876</link>
      <description>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400872888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Realistic Models of the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00171</link>
      <description>Travis E. Jones, Detre Teschner, Simone Piccinin, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400875520

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Travis E. Jones, Detre Teschner, Simone Piccinin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solid-State Stepwise Temperature-Programmable Synthesis of Bioinspired Fe-N-C Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalyst Featuring Fe-N5 Configuration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901392</link>
      <description>Wei Sang, Somboon Chaemchuen, Longyang Zhang, Zechen Wang, Xingchuan Li, Naoki Ogiwara, Ming Xiong, Naoki Ogiwara, Cheng Chen, Francis Verpoort, Shichun Mu, Zongkui Kou, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400879780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Sang, Somboon Chaemchuen, Longyang Zhang, Zechen Wang, Xingchuan Li, Naoki Ogiwara, Ming Xiong, Naoki Ogiwara, Cheng Chen, Francis Verpoort, Shichun Mu, Zongkui Kou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition from amorphous to crystalline in FeW oxides: Alterations in active center spin state to improve OER performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154218</link>
      <description>Zhenlong Wang, Ke&#8208;An Wang, Xuechun Xiao, Hai&#8208;Bin Zhu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881313

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenlong Wang, Ke&#8208;An Wang, Xuechun Xiao, Hai&#8208;Bin Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electroreduction of Captured CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on Silver Catalysts: Influence of the Capture Agent and Proton Source</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03915</link>
      <description>Robert M. Kowalski, Avishek Banerjee, Chudi Yue, S. Gracia, Dongfang Cheng, Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, Philippe Sautet, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400884259

                In the context of carbon reutilization, the direct electroreduction of captured CO</description>
      <author>Robert M. Kowalski, Avishek Banerjee, Chudi Yue, S. Gracia, Dongfang Cheng, Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO Methanation over Ni&#8211;Fe Alloy Catalysts: An Inverse Design Problem</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02449</link>
      <description>Wenqiang Yang, Zhenbin Wang, Jens K. N&#248;rskov, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqiang Yang, Zhenbin Wang, Jens K. N&#248;rskov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2-to-methanol electroconversion on a molecular cobalt catalyst facilitated by acidic cations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01197-2</link>
      <description>Sunmoon Yu, Hiroki Yamauchi, Shuo Wang, Abhishek Aggarwal, Junghwa Kim, Kiarash Gordiz, Botao Huang, Hai Tao Xu, Daniel J. Zheng, Xiao Wang, Haldrian Iriawan, Davide Menga, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400888998

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sunmoon Yu, Hiroki Yamauchi, Shuo Wang, Abhishek Aggarwal, Junghwa Kim, Kiarash Gordiz, Botao Huang, Hai Tao Xu, Daniel J. Zheng, Xiao Wang, Haldrian Iriawan, Davide Menga, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01197-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Photophysics and Photocatalytic Activity of Heteroleptic Rh(III) Transition-Metal Complexes Using High-Throughput Experimentation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02420</link>
      <description>Stephen DiLuzio, Mitchell A. Baumer, R. Guzm&#225;n, Husain N. Kagalwala, Eric M. Lopato, Savannah Talledo, Joshua Kangas, Stefan Bernhard, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400849302

                High-throughput synthesis and screening (HTSS) methods were used to investigate the photophysical properties of 576 heteroleptic Rh(III) transition-metal complexes through measurement of the UV-visible absorption spectra, deaerated excited-state lifetime, and phosphorescent emission spectra. While 4d transition-metal photophysics are often highly influenced by deleterious metal-centered deactivation channels, the HTSS of structurally diverse cyclometalating and ancillary ligands attached to the metal center facilitated the discovery of photoactive complexes exhibiting long-lived charge-transfer phosphorescence (0.15-0.95 &#956;s) spanning a substantial portion of the visible region (546-620 nm) at room temperature. Further photophysical and electrochemical investigations were then carried out on select complexes with favorable photophysics to understand the underlying features controlling these superior properties. Heteroleptic Ir(III) complexes with identical ligand morphology were also synthesized to compare these features to this family of well understood chromophores. A number of these Rh(III) complexes contained the requisite properties for photocatalytic activity and were consequently tested as photocatalysts (PCs) in a water reduction system using a Pd water reduction cocatalyst. Under certain conditions, the activity of the Rh(III) PC actually surpassed that of the Ir(III) PC, uncovering the potential of this often-overlooked class of transition metals as both efficient photoactive chromophores and PCs.</description>
      <author>Stephen DiLuzio, Mitchell A. Baumer, R. Guzm&#225;n, Husain N. Kagalwala, Eric M. Lopato, Savannah Talledo, Joshua Kangas, Stefan Bernhard</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02420</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
