<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 01:17:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking commercial RuO2 for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100289</link>
      <description>Yuxiang Song, Zheng Wei, Weili Shi, Biaobiao Zhang, Next Materials. 6(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4401106249

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxiang Song, Zheng Wei, Weili Shi, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of highly efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen peroxide synthesis using single transition metal atoms embedded in carbon vacancy fullerene C60</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120571</link>
      <description>Yongyong Cao, Tianye Liu, Jinfeng Chen, Shengbao Cai, Jiayi Liu, Hongjie Huang, Weichan Zhong, Yuxiao Meng, Rongxin Zhang, Qineng Xia, Zhangfeng Shen, Bowei Zhang, Bo Quan, Wenqiang Hu, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401047186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongyong Cao, Tianye Liu, Jinfeng Chen, Shengbao Cai, Jiayi Liu, Hongjie Huang, Weichan Zhong, Yuxiao Meng, Rongxin Zhang, Qineng Xia, Zhangfeng Shen, Bowei Zhang, Bo Quan, Wenqiang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward an ab Initio Description of Adsorbate Surface Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02250</link>
      <description>Saurabh Sivakumar, Ambarish Kulkarni, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401049059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saurabh Sivakumar, Ambarish Kulkarni</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Basal-Plane S Sites on MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by Dual Ti and N Plasma Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05758</link>
      <description>Ning Pang, Yukui Zhang, Li Wang, Xin Tong, Mengqiu Wang, Huiyun Shi, Dajun Wu, Dayuan Xiong, Shaohui Xu, &#1055;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077;&#1083; &#1041;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1082;&#1080;&#1085;, Lianwei Wang, Lin Jiang, Paul K. Chu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401049464

                Atomic engineering of the basal plane active sites in MoS</description>
      <author>Ning Pang, Yukui Zhang, Li Wang, Xin Tong, Mengqiu Wang, Huiyun Shi, Dajun Wu, Dayuan Xiong, Shaohui Xu, &#1055;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077;&#1083; &#1041;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1082;&#1080;&#1085;, Lianwei Wang, Lin Jiang, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced C&#8211;C coupling in CO2 electroreduction on dual-atom catalysts modified by bridge O/OH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160837</link>
      <description>Zhinan Ma, Zhaolong Zhong, Yaying Dou, Shouxin Zhang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401052778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhinan Ma, Zhaolong Zhong, Yaying Dou, Shouxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical core-shell Ce-doped NiO@MoO2 architecture with Ni 3d-band center modulation for enhanced high-current-density oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124455</link>
      <description>Huijie He, Fanfan Shang, Bei An, Xiaoxiao Zeng, Xiaoqian Li, Weitong Wang, Hairui Cai, Shengchun Yang, Chao Liang, Li Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401057376

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huijie He, Fanfan Shang, Bei An, Xiaoxiao Zeng, Xiaoqian Li, Weitong Wang, Hairui Cai, Shengchun Yang, Chao Liang, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124455</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding intermediates adsorption in oxygen reduction/evolution reactions from the local aromaticities of catalyst sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160843</link>
      <description>Yinsheng Zhao, Peng Jin, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401059280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yinsheng Zhao, Peng Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janus structural TaON/Graphene-like carbon dual-supported Pt electrocatalyst enables efficient oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.167</link>
      <description>Zhongliang Li, Lili Cao, Ting Yang, Jinwei He, Zelin Wang, Jinlu He, Yan Zhao, Zhanli Chai, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401061830

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongliang Li, Lili Cao, Ting Yang, Jinwei He, Zelin Wang, Jinlu He, Yan Zhao, Zhanli Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneously Producing H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by Photocatalytic Water Splitting: Recent Progress and Future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404285</link>
      <description>Shuang Cao, Tong Sun, Yong Peng, Xianghui Yu, Qin&#8208;Zhu Li, Fan Lu Meng, Jing Wang, Sheng Wang, Yunhui Xie, Chun&#8208;Chao Hou, Qiang Xu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401063773

                Abstract The solar&#8208;driven overall water splitting (2H 2 O&#8594;2H 2 + O 2 ) is considered as one of the most promising strategies for reducing carbon emissions and meeting energy demands. However, due to the sluggish performance and high H 2 cost, there is still a big gap for the current photocatalytic systems to meet the requirements for practical sustainable H 2 production. Economic feasibility can be attained through simultaneously generating products of greater value than O 2 , such as hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 , 2H 2 O&#8594;H 2 + H 2 O 2 ). Compared with overall water splitting, this approach is more kinetically feasible and generates more high&#8208;value products of H 2 and H 2 O 2 . In several years, there has been an increasing surge in exploring the possibility and substantial progress has been achieved. In this review, a concise overview of the importance and underlying principles of PIWS is first provided. Next, the reported typical photocatalysts for PIWS are discussed, including commonly used semiconductors and cocatalysts, essential design features of these photocatalysts, and connections between their structures and activities, as well as the selected approaches for enhancing their stability. Then, the techniques used to quantify H 2 O 2 and the operando characterization techniques that can be employed to gain a thorough understanding of the reaction mechanisms are summarized. Finally, the current existing challenges and the direction needing improvement are presented. This review aims to provide a thorough summary of the most recent research developments in PIWS and sets the stage for future advancements and discoveries in this emerging area.</description>
      <author>Shuang Cao, Tong Sun, Yong Peng, Xianghui Yu, Qin&#8208;Zhu Li, Fan Lu Meng, Jing Wang, Sheng Wang, Yunhui Xie, Chun&#8208;Chao Hou, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in the oxygen adsorption energy derived from the thermodynamic potential model for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114963</link>
      <description>Isabela C. Man, Ionu&#355; Tranca, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401074058

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Isabela C. Man, Ionu&#355; Tranca</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Vacancy-Induced Enhancement of BiVO4 Bifunctional Photoelectrochemical Activity for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14151270</link>
      <description>Huailiang Fu, Qingxiu Qi, Yushu Li, Jing Pan, Chonggui Zhong, Nanomaterials. 14(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401076347

                Hydrogen generation via photoelectrochemical (PEC) overall water splitting is an attractive means of renewable energy production so developing and designing the cost-effective and high-activity bifunctional PEC catalysts both for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been focused on. Based on first-principles calculations, we propose a feasible strategy to enhance either HER or OER performance in the monoclinic exposed BiVO4 (110) facet by the introduction of oxygen vacancies (Ovacs). Our results show that oxygen vacancies induce charge rearrangements, which enhances charge transfer between active sites and adatoms. Furthermore, the incorporation of oxygen vacancies reduces the work function of the system, which makes charge transfer from the inner to the surface more easily; thus, the charges possess stronger redox capacity. As a result, the Ovac reduces both the hydrogen adsorption-free energy (&#916;GH*) for the HER and the overpotential for the OER, facilitating the PEC activity of overall water splitting. The findings provide not only a method to develop bifunctional PEC catalysts based on BiVO4 but also insight into the mechanism of enhanced catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Huailiang Fu, Qingxiu Qi, Yushu Li, Jing Pan, Chonggui Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14151270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Electrophilicity of Co Surface for Favorable toward Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Metal Cation Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/4097180</link>
      <description>MinJoong Kim, DongHoon Song, Jeonghoon Lim, Junu Bak, JeongHan Roh, SeKwon Oh, EunAe Cho, International Journal of Energy Research. 2024(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401084128

                The chemical coupling of molybdenum carbide (Mo 2 C) to cobalt (Co) promotes oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics on the Co surface by making the surface more electrophilic. Here, to gain a deeper understanding of the effects of the surface electrophilic properties on the OER kinetics of Co and to obtain high OER activity, Fe and Ni are additionally incorporated into Co nanoparticles that are coupled with Mo 2 C nanoparticles (Co&#8208;Mo 2 C). Considering the oxidation states of Fe (Fe 3+ ), Co (Co 2+ /Co 3+ ), and Ni (Ni 2+ ) ions, Fe and Ni are expected to affect the electronic structure of Co in the opposite direction. Lewis acidic Fe 3+ doping makes the Co surface oxide more electrophilic, promoting the formation of OER&#8208;active CoOOH by strongly attracting hydroxide ions (OH &#8722; ). Thus, the OER kinetics is facilitated on the Co surface of Fe&#8208;doped Co&#8208;Mo 2 C, resulting in a significantly lower overpotential for the OER. On the other hand, the Ni 2+ doping makes the Co surface oxide less electrophilic, leading to an increase in the overpotential for the OER. Tailoring the electrophilic properties of the Co surface is presented as a key parameter in the design of a Co&#8208;based OER catalyst for alkaline water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>MinJoong Kim, DongHoon Song, Jeonghoon Lim, Junu Bak, JeongHan Roh, SeKwon Oh, EunAe Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/4097180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructured ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/Ni&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P/NiS on Nickel Foam as Self-Supported pH-All Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01108</link>
      <description>Jingwen Lin, Dongliang Chen, Zhenyun Zhao, Sai Gu, Xu Cheng, Dongdong Yu, Zhizhen Ye, Bin Lu, Jianguo L&#252;, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401094737

                The existing approach of preparing hydrogen through electrocatalytic water splitting is hindered by several factors, including the scarcity of efficient electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction that can function well under a variety of pH settings. The development of compounds with diverse active ingredients could contribute to the heterostructured electrocatalysts' ability to effectively react with a range of reactants. Moreover, assembling active species on a substrate to produce self-supported electrocatalysts can reduce the need for electricity. Here, we utilized nickel foam as the conductive substrate to produce heterostructured electrocatalysts with active species of ZnIn2S4, Ni2P, and NiS (denoted as ZnIn2S4/Ni2P/NiS@NF). The ZnIn2S4/Ni2P/NiS@NF only needs tiny overpotentials to drive high current densities and can be operated with long-term operational durability across a broad pH range.</description>
      <author>Jingwen Lin, Dongliang Chen, Zhenyun Zhao, Sai Gu, Xu Cheng, Dongdong Yu, Zhizhen Ye, Bin Lu, Jianguo L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Enhanced Raman Scattering Coupled with In Situ Raman Spectroscopy for the Detection of the OER Mechanism: A Mini-Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03607</link>
      <description>Suprobhat Singha Roy, Sreenivasan Nagappan, Asha K. Satheesan, Arun Karmakar, Subrata Kundu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401094877

                Electrocatalysis has emerged as a pivotal field for sustainable energy and environmental solutions, fueling the development of diverse electrocatalysts over the past 2 decades. However, a comprehensive understanding of the intricate dynamical processes governing electrochemical reactions remains elusive and is hampering efficient catalyst design. Surface-sensitive techniques like in situ/operando Raman spectroscopy are indispensable for characterizing these dynamic processes and guiding the development of novel catalysts. This review systematically summarizes recent advances in employing in situ/operando Raman techniques, with a particular emphasis on surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS), for probing various electrocatalytic systems. It discusses the development, advantages, and available configurations of these Raman techniques. Moreover, the review underscores the potential of in situ SERS in unraveling the intricate mechanisms of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) through innovative strategies and methodological advancements. Notably, leveraging SERS for novel OER catalysts, such as single-atom catalysts, metal&#8211;organic frameworks, and electrolyte&#8211;electrode interfaces, can unveil unexplored reaction pathways, guiding the development of superior catalytic materials. Overcoming challenges and harnessing SERS' capabilities can deepen our mechanistic understanding of the OER, enabling the rational design of efficient and durable electrocatalysts crucial for renewable energy advancement.</description>
      <author>Suprobhat Singha Roy, Sreenivasan Nagappan, Asha K. Satheesan, Arun Karmakar, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fcc/hcp PtNi heterostructured alloy nanocrystals with ultrathin Pt shell for enhanced catalytic performance towards hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6872-2</link>
      <description>Tianchun Cheng, Zhi Wang, Siyuan Fang, Hui Jin, Chongzhi Zhu, Shaorong Zhao, Gui&#8722;Lin Zhuang, Qiaoli Chen, Qiaoli Chen, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401103985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianchun Cheng, Zhi Wang, Siyuan Fang, Hui Jin, Chongzhi Zhu, Shaorong Zhao, Gui&#8722;Lin Zhuang, Qiaoli Chen, Qiaoli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6872-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism study of trimetallic single-cluster catalysts loaded on graphdiyne for highly efficient oxygen-reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160860</link>
      <description>Mengran Liu, Jinrui Huang, Shixiang Hu, Zhichao Ma, Yingjie Yang, Ye Chen, Haibo Liu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401105351

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengran Liu, Jinrui Huang, Shixiang Hu, Zhichao Ma, Yingjie Yang, Ye Chen, Haibo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>150 years of oxygen chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00670-z</link>
      <description>, Nature Computational Science. 4(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401121830

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00670-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational electrochemistry of oxygen 150 years after Priestley</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00664-x</link>
      <description>De&#8208;en Jiang, Nature Computational Science. 4(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401121876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>De&#8208;en Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00664-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Catalytic Potential of 2D Metal Membranes for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03389</link>
      <description>Huimin Hu, Jin&#8208;Ho Choi, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401129520

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huimin Hu, Jin&#8208;Ho Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03389</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationally designed Ru catalysts supported on TiN for highly efficient and stable hydrogen evolution in alkaline conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50691-5</link>
      <description>Jia Li, Ricardo Urrego-Ortiz, Nan Liao, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Jingshan Luo, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401135152

                Electrocatalysis holds the key to enhancing the efficiency and cost-effectiveness of water splitting devices, thereby contributing to the advancement of hydrogen as a clean, sustainable energy carrier. This study focuses on the rational design of Ru nanoparticle catalysts supported on TiN (Ru NPs/TiN) for the hydrogen evolution reaction in alkaline conditions. The as designed catalysts exhibit a high mass activity of 20 A mg</description>
      <author>Jia Li, Ricardo Urrego-Ortiz, Nan Liao, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Jingshan Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50691-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial Energy Band Modulation of Semiconducting Hexagonal GaTe Quantum Wells by Layer Thickness and Mirror Twin Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c05858</link>
      <description>Wenzhi Quan, Yue Lu, Qilong Wu, Yingjie Cheng, Jingyi Hu, Zehui Zhang, Jialong Wang, Zhenzhu Li, Lili Wang, Qingqing Ji, Yanfeng Zhang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401141014

                Exploring emerging two-dimensional (2D) van der Waals (vdW) semiconducting materials and precisely tuning their electronic properties at the atomic level have long been recognized as crucial issues for developing their high-end electronic and optoelectronic applications. As a III-VI semiconductor, ultrathin layered hexagonal GaTe (</description>
      <author>Wenzhi Quan, Yue Lu, Qilong Wu, Yingjie Cheng, Jingyi Hu, Zehui Zhang, Jialong Wang, Zhenzhu Li, Lili Wang, Qingqing Ji, Yanfeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c05858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anisotropic Heterobimetallic Nanomaterials with Controlled Composition for Efficient Oxygen Reduction at Ultralow Loading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411006</link>
      <description>Siyi Ming, Samuel J. Cobb, Motiar Rahaman, Nicholas Sammy, Erwin Reisner, Andrew E. H. Wheatley, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401146601

                Abstract Hydrogen fuel cells represent a leading technology in developing green energy targeting net&#8208;zero emissions goals by mid&#8208;century. However, the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) have hitherto demanded substantial quantities of expensive platinum (Pt) group metals. Advances in catalyst design, including the controllable fabrication of highly branched morphologies to increase the surface area&#8208;to&#8208;volume ratio, intermixing Pt with more affordable transition metals, and controlling composition, offer solutions that can further enhance activity and reduce expense. In this context, Pt/M (M = Fe, Ni, Co) nanopods and nanodendrites with precise composition control using more affordable starting materials are designed and crafted. The method is highly efficient, taking only 30 min and avoiding the need for high&#8208;pressure equipment, making it highly scalable. These catalysts show superior ORR performance at an electrode loading as low as 0.0022 mg Pt cm &#8722;2 . One, nanodendritic Pt/Ni, achieves a mass activity of at 0.9 V versus RHE, making it 87 times more efficient in terms of Pt&#8208;content than a commercial 10 wt% Pt/C nanoparticle standard. These findings provide new opportunities for developing next&#8208;generation, cost&#8208;efficient Pt&#8208;based catalysts, by potentially advancing hydrogen fuel cell technology through performance enhancement and addressing cost challenges through catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Siyi Ming, Samuel J. Cobb, Motiar Rahaman, Nicholas Sammy, Erwin Reisner, Andrew E. H. Wheatley</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Revealing the Electrocatalytic Mechanism for Hydrogen Energy Conversion System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405008</link>
      <description>Mingxin Cai, Yiran Zhang, Peilei He, Zhicheng Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401150154

                In light of the intensifying global energy crisis and the mounting demand for environmental protection, it is of vital importance to develop advanced hydrogen energy conversion systems. Electrolysis cells for hydrogen production and fuel cell devices for hydrogen utilization are indispensable in hydrogen energy conversion. As one of the electrolysis cells, water splitting involves two electrochemical reactions, hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. And oxygen reduction reaction coupled with hydrogen oxidation reaction, represent the core electrocatalytic reactions in fuel cell devices. However, the inherent complexity and the lack of a clear understanding of the structure-performance relationship of these electrocatalytic reactions, have posed significant challenges to the advancement of research in this field. In this work, the recent development in revealing the mechanism of electrocatalytic reactions in hydrogen energy conversion systems is reviewed, including in situ characterization and theoretical calculation. First, the working principles and applications of operando measurements in unveiling the reaction mechanism are systematically introduced. Then the application of theoretical calculations in the design of catalysts and the investigation of the reaction mechanism are discussed. Furthermore, the challenges and opportunities are also summarized and discussed for paving the development of hydrogen energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Mingxin Cai, Yiran Zhang, Peilei He, Zhicheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe2N5P dual-atom catalysts: a pathway to efficient hydrogen evolution in renewable energy applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129785</link>
      <description>Mohamed J. Saadh, Ali Basem, Mohammad H. Khaddour, Pawan Sharma, Laith Yassen Qassem, Abhishek Kumar, Rahadian Zainul, Shahabe Saquib Abullais, M. Sa&#239;ful Islam, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401154928

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohamed J. Saadh, Ali Basem, Mohammad H. Khaddour, Pawan Sharma, Laith Yassen Qassem, Abhishek Kumar, Rahadian Zainul, Shahabe Saquib Abullais, M. Sa&#239;ful Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction mechanism of metal-free borophene catalyst electrochemical reduction of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134933</link>
      <description>Meiling Liu, Rao Fu, Tao Xu, Qiming Fu, Chao Liu, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. 701(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401158459

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meiling Liu, Rao Fu, Tao Xu, Qiming Fu, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting stable lithium deposition via Li3N-Enriched inorganic SEI induced by a polycationic polymer layer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.246</link>
      <description>Wenzhu Cao, Weimin Chen, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Tian Du, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401160073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenzhu Cao, Weimin Chen, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Tian Du, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrosion and Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution in Electrochemical Reduction of Ammonium Carbamate on Transition Metal Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01638</link>
      <description>Jounghwan Choi, Shawn Chiu, Avishek Banerjee, Robert L. Sacci, Gabriel M. Veith, S. Chantal E. Stieber, Christopher Hahn, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401167274

                Experiments and theory are combined to search for catalyst activity and stability descriptors for the direct reactive capture and conversion (RCC) of CO</description>
      <author>Jounghwan Choi, Shawn Chiu, Avishek Banerjee, Robert L. Sacci, Gabriel M. Veith, S. Chantal E. Stieber, Christopher Hahn, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Carlos G. Morales&#8208;Guio</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping High entropy State Spaces for Novel Material Discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120237</link>
      <description>Johnathan von der Heyde, Walter Malone, Abdelkader Kara, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401168949

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Johnathan von der Heyde, Walter Malone, Abdelkader Kara</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Metallic-Oxygen Semiconductors Systems Towards Solar-Hydrogen Production and Investigating Mechanisms Through Different Characterization Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101525</link>
      <description>Lingpu Jia, Jafar Hussain Shah, Yuan Luo, Lida Huang, Wenlong Liao, Kunping Liu, Zhiming Wang, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401170220

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingpu Jia, Jafar Hussain Shah, Yuan Luo, Lida Huang, Wenlong Liao, Kunping Liu, Zhiming Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elastic plate basis for the deformation and electron diffraction of twisted bilayer graphene on a substrate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.024116</link>
      <description>Moon&#8208;ki Choi, Suk Hyun Sung, Robert Hovden, Ellad B. Tadmor, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401174216

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Moon&#8208;ki Choi, Suk Hyun Sung, Robert Hovden, Ellad B. Tadmor</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.024116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity versus stability of atomically dispersed transition-metal electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41578-024-00703-z</link>
      <description>Gang Wu, Piotr Zelenay, Nature Reviews Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401178518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Wu, Piotr Zelenay</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41578-024-00703-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low&#8208;Cost Self&#8208;Reconstructed High Entropy Oxide as an Ultra&#8208;Durable OER Electrocatalyst for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402241</link>
      <description>S. Karthikeyan, S. Ramakrishnan, Sampath Prabhakaran, Mohan Raj Subramaniam, Mohamed Mamlouk, Do Hwan Kim, Dong Jin Yoo, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401179912

                Abstract Future energy loss can be minimized to a greater extent via developing highly active electrocatalysts for alkaline water electrolyzers. Incorporating an innovative design like high entropy oxides, dealloying, structural reconstruction, in situ activation can potentially reduce the energy barriers between practical and theoretical potentials. Here, a Fd&#8208;3m spinel group high entropy oxide is developed via a simple solvothermal and calcination approach. The developed (FeCoMnZnMg) 3 O 4 electrocatalyst shows a near equimolar distribution of all the metal elements resulting in higher entropy (&#916;S &#8776;1.61R) and higher surface area. The self&#8208;reconstructed spinel high entropy oxide (S&#8208;HEO) catalyst exhibited a lower overpotential of 240 mV to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and enhanced reaction kinetics (59 mV dec &#8722;1 ). Noticeably, the S&#8208;HEO displayed an outstanding durability of 1000 h without any potential loss, significantly outperforming most of the reported OER electrocatalysts. Further, S&#8208;HEO is evaluated as the anode catalyst for an anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) in 1 m , 0.1 m KOH, and DI water at 20 and 60 &#176;C. These results demonstrate that S&#8208;HEO is a highly attractive, non&#8208;noble class of materials for high active oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts allowing fine&#8208;tuning beyond the limits of bi&#8208; or trimetallic oxides.</description>
      <author>S. Karthikeyan, S. Ramakrishnan, Sampath Prabhakaran, Mohan Raj Subramaniam, Mohamed Mamlouk, Do Hwan Kim, Dong Jin Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Earth&#8208;Abundant Catalysts toward Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407102</link>
      <description>Jianpeng Guo, Yousof Haghshenas, Yiran Jiao, Priyank V. Kumar, Boris I. Yakobson, Ajit K. Roy, Yan Jiao, Klaus Regenauer&#8208;Lieb, David Nguyen, Zhenhai Xia, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401191227

                Abstract Catalysis is crucial for clean energy, green chemistry, and environmental remediation, but traditional methods rely on expensive and scarce precious metals. This review addresses this challenge by highlighting the promise of earth&#8208;abundant catalysts and the recent advancements in their rational design. Innovative strategies such as physics&#8208;inspired descriptors, high&#8208;throughput computational techniques, and artificial intelligence (AI)&#8208;assisted design with machine learning (ML) are explored, moving beyond time&#8208;consuming trial&#8208;and&#8208;error approaches. Additionally, biomimicry, inspired by efficient enzymes in nature, offers valuable insights. This review systematically analyses these design strategies, providing a roadmap for developing high&#8208;performance catalysts from abundant elements. Clean energy applications (water splitting, fuel cells, batteries) and green chemistry (ammonia synthesis, CO 2 reduction) are targeted while delving into the fundamental principles, biomimetic approaches, and current challenges in this field. The way to a more sustainable future is paved by overcoming catalyst scarcity through rational design.</description>
      <author>Jianpeng Guo, Yousof Haghshenas, Yiran Jiao, Priyank V. Kumar, Boris I. Yakobson, Ajit K. Roy, Yan Jiao, Klaus Regenauer&#8208;Lieb, David Nguyen, Zhenhai Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of bonding filling on HER/OER/ORR multifunctional catalytic activity in transition-metals-doped PdPX (X = S, Se, Te)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02924-1</link>
      <description>Hai&#8208;Hua Huang, Wei Li, Chengchao Hu, Xueqin Sun, Li-Qiang Lu, Xiaofeng Fan, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401196366

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hai&#8208;Hua Huang, Wei Li, Chengchao Hu, Xueqin Sun, Li-Qiang Lu, Xiaofeng Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02924-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing the Hydrogen Bonding Interaction with *OOH toward Efficient H2O2 Electrosynthesis via Remote Electronic Tuning of Co-N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124448</link>
      <description>Jiawei Zhang, Hongwei Zeng, Bingling He, Ying Liu, Jing Xu, Tengfei Niu, Chengsi Pan, Ying Zhang, Yang Lou, Yao Wang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401198331

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Zhang, Hongwei Zeng, Bingling He, Ying Liu, Jing Xu, Tengfei Niu, Chengsi Pan, Ying Zhang, Yang Lou, Yao Wang, Yuming Dong, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of inert surface of monolayer MoS2 by transition metal and nitrogen co-doping to promote hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141504</link>
      <description>Yu&#8208;Cheng Chen, Yafei Zhao, Haoshan Gao, Liang He, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401199160

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu&#8208;Cheng Chen, Yafei Zhao, Haoshan Gao, Liang He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Recoverable Symmetric Protonic Ceramic Fuel Cell with Smart Reversible Exsolution/Dissolution Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404846</link>
      <description>Yuhao Wang, Zheng Wang, Kaichuang Yang, Jiapeng Liu, Yufei Song, Jingwei Li, Zhiwei Hu, Matthew J. Robson, Zhiqi Zhang, Yunfeng Tian, Sai Xu, Ying Lu, Ho Mei Law, Feng Liu, Qing Chen, Zhibin Yang, Francesco Ciucci, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401222606

                Abstract This study unveils a novel concept of symmetric protonic ceramic fuel cells (symm&#8208;PCFCs) with the introduction of a self&#8208;recoverable electrode design, employing the innovative material BaCo 0.4 Fe 0.4 Zr 0.1 Y 0.1 O 3&#8208;&#948; (BCFZY). This research marks a significant milestone as it demonstrates the bi&#8208;functional electrocatalytic activity of BCFZY for the first time. Utilizing density functional theory simulations, the molecular orbital interactions and defect chemistry of BCFZY are explored, uncovering its unique capability for the reversible exsolution and dissolution of Co&#8208;Fe nanoparticles under redox conditions. This feature is pivotal in promoting both hydrogen oxidation and oxygen reduction reactions. Leveraging this insight, a cell is fabricated exhibiting high electrocatalytic activity and fuel flexibility as evidenced by the peak power densities of &#8776;350, 287, and 221 mW cm &#8722;2 (at 600 &#176;C) with hydrogen, methanol, and methane as fuels, respectively. Experiments also show that the reversible exsolution/dissolution mitigates performance degradation, enabling prolonged operational life through self&#8208;recovery. This approach paves the way for novel, advanced, durable, and commercially viable symm&#8208;PCFCs.</description>
      <author>Yuhao Wang, Zheng Wang, Kaichuang Yang, Jiapeng Liu, Yufei Song, Jingwei Li, Zhiwei Hu, Matthew J. Robson, Zhiqi Zhang, Yunfeng Tian, Sai Xu, Ying Lu, Ho Mei Law, Feng Liu, Qing Chen, Zhibin Yang, Francesco Ciucci</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic assessment of various universal machine&#8208;learning interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.58</link>
      <description>Haochen Yu, Matteo Giantomassi, Giuliana Materzanini, Junjie Wang, Gian&#8208;Marco Rignanese, Materials Genome Engineering Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401233871

                Abstract Machine&#8208;learning interatomic potentials have revolutionized materials modeling at the atomic scale. Thanks to these, it is now indeed possible to perform simulations of ab initio quality over very large time and length scales. More recently, various universal machine&#8208;learning models have been proposed as an out&#8208;of&#8208;box approach avoiding the need to train and validate specific potentials for each particular material of interest. In this paper, we review and evaluate four different universal machine&#8208;learning interatomic potentials (uMLIPs), all based on graph neural network architectures which have demonstrated transferability from one chemical system to another. The evaluation procedure relies on data both from a recent verification study of density&#8208;functional&#8208;theory implementations and from the Materials Project. Through this comprehensive evaluation, we aim to provide guidance to materials scientists in selecting suitable models for their specific research problems, offer recommendations for model selection and optimization, and stimulate discussion on potential areas for improvement in current machine&#8208;learning methodologies in materials science.</description>
      <author>Haochen Yu, Matteo Giantomassi, Giuliana Materzanini, Junjie Wang, Gian&#8208;Marco Rignanese</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.58</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel oxide modified FeCoNi alloy composites prepared with one-step pyrolytic reduction as bifunctional catalyst for ORR/OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175802</link>
      <description>Qing Chen, Peng Mao, Qiongyu Liu, Meixiu Wan, Maocong Hu, Zhenhua Yao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1004(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401242556

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Chen, Peng Mao, Qiongyu Liu, Meixiu Wan, Maocong Hu, Zhenhua Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile construction of plasmonic Ag/Nb2O5 films and their photocatalytic activity against organic dye and nanoplastics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105881</link>
      <description>Te Hu, Liang Hao, Qian Zhao, Rong Jia, Sujun Guan, Yiqiang He, Yun Lu, Journal of Water Process Engineering. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401243725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Te Hu, Liang Hao, Qian Zhao, Rong Jia, Sujun Guan, Yiqiang He, Yun Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven Design of Catalytic Materials in Methane Oxidation Based on a Site Isolation Concept</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02103</link>
      <description>Aliaksei Mazheika, M. Geske, Matthias M&#252;ller, Stephan A. Schunk, Frank Rosowski, Ralph Kraehnert, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401246258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aliaksei Mazheika, M. Geske, Matthias M&#252;ller, Stephan A. Schunk, Frank Rosowski, Ralph Kraehnert</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Fe&#8208;Doped Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;NiS@Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanorod Array with Regulated Heterostructural Interface and Band Structure for Expediting Alkaline Electrocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409849</link>
      <description>Ruidong Shi, Yuanting Li, Xiaoxin Xu, Xue Wang, Gongbing Zhou, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401260932

                Abstract Aiming to efficiently expedite alkaline overall water splitting (OWS) by addressing challenges such as sluggish kinetics and limited stability, a hollow Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 &#8208;NiS@Ni(OH) 2 nanorod array with surface nanosheets is devised, featuring a high&#8208;index Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 (101)&#8208;NiS(211) heterostructural interface and an upshifted d &#8208;band center. This nanoarchitecture intensifies the adsorption and interaction of H 2 O and OH &#8722; reactants on the electrocatalyst surface, suitably bonds the * H intermediate in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and accelerates electron movement of * H, minimizes the energy requirement of the rate&#8208;limiting phase ( * OH &#8594; * O) in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by facilitating O&#9472;H cleavage of * OH and optimally adsorbs * O, amplifies the exposure of surface&#8208;active centers, and ultimately reduces the apparent activation energy. Consequently, the overpotentials are as low as 66.4 mV (HER) and 254.9 mV (OER) at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , alongside high turnover frequencies of 142 s &#8722;1 (H 2 ) and 279 s &#8722;1 (O 2 ) at 100 and 300 mV, respectively, markedly outperforming direct&#8208;electrodeposited analogues. When functioning as a bifunctional electrode in OWS, this material merely requires 1.57 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and sustains an operation for 168 h, approaching Pt/C||RuO 2 benchmark.</description>
      <author>Ruidong Shi, Yuanting Li, Xiaoxin Xu, Xue Wang, Gongbing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uniting activity design principles of anode catalysts for direct liquid fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00100a</link>
      <description>Daniel J. Zheng, Jiayu Peng, Kaylee McCormack, Hongbin Xu, Jin Soo Kang, Zhenshu Wang, Zhichu Ren, Ju Li, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, EES Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401263876

                This review provides a comprehensive overview of liquid fuel oxidation electrocatalysts, from fundamental principles to state-of-the-art materials in an effort to unify design principles for future materials.</description>
      <author>Daniel J. Zheng, Jiayu Peng, Kaylee McCormack, Hongbin Xu, Jin Soo Kang, Zhenshu Wang, Zhichu Ren, Ju Li, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00100a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmed electrochemical reconstruction of NiCoxMo4-xN5 for making Core-Shell shaped Schottky junction electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154473</link>
      <description>Selvaraj Seenivasan, Miyeon Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Junhyeok Seo, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401268956

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Selvaraj Seenivasan, Miyeon Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Junhyeok Seo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biaxial strain induced OH engineer for accelerating alkaline hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50942-5</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Qitong Ye, Zhidong Han, Qingyi Liu, Yipu Liu, Dongshuang Wu, Hong Jin Fan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401277047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Qitong Ye, Zhidong Han, Qingyi Liu, Yipu Liu, Dongshuang Wu, Hong Jin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50942-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Intrinsic Mechanism of High&#8208;Performance Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Fixation by Heterogenization of Homonuclear Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12803</link>
      <description>Yue&#8208;Fei Zhang, Yang Yu, Yu Zhang, Xuefei Liu, Wenjun Xiao, Degui Wang, Gang Wang, Zhen Wang, Jinshun Bi, Jincheng Liu, Xun Zhou, Wentao Wang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401277908

                A heteronuclear dual transition metal atom catalyst is a promising strategy to solve and relieve the increasing energy and environment crisis. However, the role of each atom still does not efficiently differentiate due to the high activity but low detectability of each transition metal in the synergistic catalytic process when considering the influence of heteronuclear induced atomic difference for each transition metal atom, thus seriously hindering intrinsic mechanism finding. Herein, we proposed coordinate environment vary induced heterogenization of homonuclear dual&#8208;transition metal, which inherits the advantage of heteronuclear transition metal atom catalyst but also controls the variable of the two atoms to explore the underlying mechanism. Based on this proposal, employing density functional theory study and machine learning, 23 kinds of homonuclear transition metals are doping in four asymmetric C 3 N for heterogenization to evaluate the underlying catalytic mechanism. Our results demonstrate that five catalysts exhibit excellent catalytic performance with a low limiting potential of &#8722;0.28 to &#8722;0.48 V. In the meantime, a new mechanism, &#8220;capture&#8211;charge distribution&#8211;recapture&#8211;charge redistribution&#8221;, is developed for both side&#8208;on and end&#8208;on configuration. More importantly, the pronate site of the first hydrogenation is identified based on this mechanism. Our work not only initially makes a deep understanding of the transition dual metal&#8208;based heteronuclear catalyst indirectly but also broadens the development of complicated homonuclear dual&#8208;atom catalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Yue&#8208;Fei Zhang, Yang Yu, Yu Zhang, Xuefei Liu, Wenjun Xiao, Degui Wang, Gang Wang, Zhen Wang, Jinshun Bi, Jincheng Liu, Xun Zhou, Wentao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlloyBERT: Alloy property prediction with large language models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113256</link>
      <description>Akshat Chaudhari, Chakradhar Guntuboina, Hongshuo Huang, Amir Barati Farimani, Computational Materials Science. 244(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401194786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akshat Chaudhari, Chakradhar Guntuboina, Hongshuo Huang, Amir Barati Farimani</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113256</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
