<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 01:16:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Solar energy powered electrochemical reduction of CO2 on In2O3 nanosheets with high energy conversion efficiency at a large current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.177</link>
      <description>Wei Xing Zheng, Peihao Sun, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Wenzheng Nie, Huihui Bao, Linglan Men, Qing Li, Zhong Su, Yangyang Wan, Changlei Xia, Huan Xie, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 678(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4402034343

                Electrochemical CO</description>
      <author>Wei Xing Zheng, Peihao Sun, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Wenzheng Nie, Huihui Bao, Linglan Men, Qing Li, Zhong Su, Yangyang Wan, Changlei Xia, Huan Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activation and Dissociation on Exsolved Ni/La&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04270</link>
      <description>P.G.A. Kumar, Dayadeep S. Monder, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401989044

                In this study, we performed spin-polarized periodic density functional theory (DFT) calculations to understand the electronic structure and catalytic activity of exsolved Ni nanoparticles supported on La2O3 (i.e., Ni/La2O3) as reported in the recent experimental literature. We used simple slab models to study the electronic structure and reactivity of the Ni/La2O3 overlayer surfaces. The modifications in the electronic and geometric properties of Ni/La2O3 as successive layers of Ni are added on top of La2O3 are systematically investigated by using the d-band model as well as by studying the adsorption and dissociation of CO2. We examined the interaction of CO2 on the surface of Ni/La2O3 by computing adsorption energetics, optimized geometries, charge transfer, and density of states. As the interaction between CO2 and the Ni surface is weak, we employed van der Waal corrections in our calculations. Our results suggest that the adsorption of CO2 is more favorable on the Ni/La2O3 surface compared to that on the simple Ni(111) surface. Furthermore, we have also found that the activation barrier for CO2 dissociation increases with an increase in the number of Ni layers from one layer to three and that the energy of the reaction becomes less exothermic. This shows that the dissociation of CO2 becomes both kinetically and thermodynamically less favorable as we increase the number of Ni layers over La2O3. Thus, a single monolayer of Ni/La2O3 is the most active among the surfaces investigated here for the adsorption and dissociation of CO2. We show how this is due to the synergistic effect of geometric and electronic factors. The energetics of the CO2 dissociation reaction follow a Bro&#823;nsted&#8211;Evans&#8211;Polanyi relationship where the activation energy is linearly correlated to the reaction energy for all the surfaces studied here. The present study's findings offer valuable perspectives on the correlation between the electronic configuration and catalytic capabilities of Ni/La2O3 catalysts. Consequently, these insights are expected to be useful in the design of novel, high-performance, supported metal catalysts for a range of important reactions.</description>
      <author>P.G.A. Kumar, Dayadeep S. Monder</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced HER activity in Pd/Pt-decorated Janus XSeI (X = Sb, Bi) monolayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.240</link>
      <description>Utsav P. Prajapati, Rishit S. Shukla, Vidit B. Zala, Sanjeev K. Gupta, P. N. Gajjar, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 85(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401991659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Utsav P. Prajapati, Rishit S. Shukla, Vidit B. Zala, Sanjeev K. Gupta, P. N. Gajjar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.240</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Mechanistic Pathways of N2 Reduction to Ammonia on (110) Facets of Transition Metal Carbides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14090770</link>
      <description>Atef Iqbal, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Younes Abghoui, Crystals. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401991839

                The conversion of molecular dinitrogen into ammonia under mild conditions is a significant pursuit in chemistry due to its potential for sustainable and clean ammonia production. The electrochemical reduction of N2 offers a promising route for achieving this goal with reduced energy consumption, utilizing renewable energy sources. However, the exploration of effective electrocatalysts for this process, particularly at room temperature and atmospheric pressure, remains under exploration. This study addresses this gap by conducting a comprehensive investigation of potential catalysts for nitrogen electro-reduction to ammonia under ambient conditions. Using density functional theory calculations, we explore the (110) facets of rock salt structures across 11 transition metal carbides. Catalytic activity is evaluated through the construction of free energy diagrams for associative, dissociative, and Mars&#8211;van Krevelen reaction mechanisms. Additionally, we assess material stability against electrochemical poisoning and decomposition of parent metals during operation. Our findings suggest that a few of the candidates are promising for nitrogen reduction reactions, such as TaC and WC, with moderate onset potentials (&#8722;0.66 V and &#8722;0.82 V vs. RHE) under ambient conditions.</description>
      <author>Atef Iqbal, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14090770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A metadynamics study of water oxidation reactions at (001)-WO3/liquid-water interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101085</link>
      <description>Rangsiman Ketkaew, Fabrizio Creazzo, Kevin Sivula, Sandra Luber, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401995869

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rangsiman Ketkaew, Fabrizio Creazzo, Kevin Sivula, Sandra Luber</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward accelerated discovery of solid catalysts using extrapolative machine learning approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/chemle/upae163</link>
      <description>Takashi Toyao, Chemistry Letters. 53(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402001862

                Abstract Designing novel catalysts is pivotal for overcoming numerous energy and environmental challenges. Although data science approaches, particularly machine learning (ML) approaches, hold promise for accelerating catalyst development, discovering truly novel catalysts through ML remains rare. This is largely due to the perceived inability of the ML models to extrapolate and identify exceptional materials. In this Review, I present our approach taken to tackle this limitation. Specifically, we employed an advanced ML methodology that could make extrapolative predictions. This approach led to the discovery of multielemental solid catalysts for CO2 hydrogenation to CO. The results not only demonstrate the immense potential of ML in catalysis research but also set a new standard for the rapid development of high-performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Takashi Toyao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/chemle/upae163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis of hydrogen and oxygen electrode reactions in alkaline media by Rh-modified polycrystalline Ni electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144983</link>
      <description>Ljiljana Vasi&#263;, Nikola Tri&#269;kovi&#263;, Zaharije Bo&#353;kovi&#263;, Aleksandar Z. Jovanovi&#263;, Dana Vasiljevi&#263;-Radovi&#263;, Natalia V. Skorodumova, Slavko Mentus, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402008586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ljiljana Vasi&#263;, Nikola Tri&#269;kovi&#263;, Zaharije Bo&#353;kovi&#263;, Aleksandar Z. Jovanovi&#263;, Dana Vasiljevi&#263;-Radovi&#263;, Natalia V. Skorodumova, Slavko Mentus, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Relationship Between Team Diversity and Team Performance: Reconciling Promise and Reality Through a Comprehensive Meta-Analysis Registered Report</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10869-024-09977-0</link>
      <description>Lukas Wallrich, Victoria Opara, Miki Weso&#322;owska, Ditte Barnoth, Somayeh Yousefi, Journal of Business and Psychology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402018951

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lukas Wallrich, Victoria Opara, Miki Weso&#322;owska, Ditte Barnoth, Somayeh Yousefi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10869-024-09977-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalyst&#8211;Driven Hybrid Water Splitting for Energy&#8208;Saving Coproduction of Green H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Valuable Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394234110.ch10</link>
      <description>Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Bao Yu Xia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402030913

                Electrocatalytic water splitting to generate green H 2 with renewable energy inputs is attractive to relieve the environmental contamination and energy dilemma. Restricted by the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and single functionality of cathode/anode catalysts, conventional overall water splitting (OWS) suffers from high overpotentials and respective synthesis of monofunctional electrocatalysts, leading to high cost. Moreover, the generated O 2 bears low value and its possible mixing with H 2 poses safety issues. In response, hybrid water splitting (HWS) that integrates hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with favorable oxidative upgrading reactions over bifunctional electrocatalysts can generate H 2 and value-added chemicals simultaneously with lower energy input and avoid the explosive H 2 /O 2 mixtures. Hence, this chapter focuses on the recent progress in bifunctional electrocatalyst&#8211;driven HWS for energy-saving coproduction of highly valuable chemicals and green H 2 . Firstly, the fundamentals of HER, OER, OWS, and HWS are introduced, followed by a discussion on the electrochemical reconstruction of bifunctional electrocatalysts during OWS and HWS. Next, the HWS based on bifunctional electrocatalysts is summarized, wherein the alternative oxidation reactions include upgrading of alcohol, aldehydes, amines, biomass, and plastic waste. Finally, a brief overview of current challenges and perspective for bifunctional electrocatalyst&#8211;driven HWS is discussed.</description>
      <author>Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394234110.ch10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Challenges in Metal Oxide&#8211;Based Carbon Capture Technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394234110.ch5</link>
      <description>Berfu Kocabas, Olgu C. Cosar, Arpad Mihai Rostas, &#304;pek Deniz Y&#305;ld&#305;r&#305;m, Ahmet G&#252;ng&#246;r, Emre Erdem, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402030979

                The global pursuit of sustainable industrial practices is confronted by the escalating challenge of controlling carbon dioxide emissions, primarily from key industrial processes such as power generation, cement production, and metal manufacturing. In response to this pressing issue, the deployment of carbon capture technologies has gained considerable traction as a viable strategy to mitigate the environmental impact of carbon dioxide emissions. This overview chapter critically examines the recent advancements and challenges in metal oxide-based carbon capture methodologies, focusing on their pivotal role in mitigating the adverse effects of climate change and fostering sustainable industrial operations.</description>
      <author>Berfu Kocabas, Olgu C. Cosar, Arpad Mihai Rostas, &#304;pek Deniz Y&#305;ld&#305;r&#305;m, Ahmet G&#252;ng&#246;r, Emre Erdem</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394234110.ch5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Embedded MoS2 as efficient Trifunctional Electrocatalyst: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144968</link>
      <description>K. Simmy Joseph, Shweta D. Dabhi, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402034466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Simmy Joseph, Shweta D. Dabhi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-scale computational study of high-temperature corrosion and the design of corrosion-resistant alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101359</link>
      <description>Terrence Wenga, Digby D. Macdonald, Wenchao Ma, Progress in Materials Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402043969

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Terrence Wenga, Digby D. Macdonald, Wenchao Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the clean energy: Phosphorus-alkynyl covalent organic frameworks for photocatalytic hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.459</link>
      <description>Cong Wang, Xin Wang, Kai Gong, Donglai Han, Jing Song, Min Zhang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402050194

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cong Wang, Xin Wang, Kai Gong, Donglai Han, Jing Song, Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.459</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Fe3O4-wrapped copper microstructure to enhance copper&#8211;slag separation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12613-024-2861-4</link>
      <description>Xiaopeng Chi, Sheng Wang, Jun Xia, Hang Chen, Xiangtao Yu, Wei Weng, Shuiping Zhong, International Journal of Minerals Metallurgy and Materials. 31(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402050597

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaopeng Chi, Sheng Wang, Jun Xia, Hang Chen, Xiangtao Yu, Wei Weng, Shuiping Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12613-024-2861-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the Precursor Metal Salt on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction for NiFe Oxide Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400151</link>
      <description>A. Zuber, Ilias M. Oikonomou, Lee Gannon, I. I. Chunin, L.A. Reith, Berrin Zeliha Can, Mailis Lounasvuori, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Cormac McGuinness, Prashanth W. Menezes, Valeria Nicolosi, Michelle P. Browne, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402055549

                Abstract Bimetallic nickel&#8208;iron based oxides are regarded as one of the most promising catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, we show that the precursor metal salts can affect the OER activity of the resulting Ni/Fe oxide under the same hydrothermal synthesis conditions. Pure sulfate, pure nitrate and mixed sulfate/nitrate metal salts were used to fabricate NiFe based oxide materials and to study the importance of the precursor choice for the OER. The results show that the nature of the precursor used in the synthesis of the bimetallic nickel&#8208;iron materials can influence different multi&#8208;phase catalysts to form which effects the OER.</description>
      <author>A. Zuber, Ilias M. Oikonomou, Lee Gannon, I. I. Chunin, L.A. Reith, Berrin Zeliha Can, Mailis Lounasvuori, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Cormac McGuinness, Prashanth W. Menezes, Valeria Nicolosi, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CELL: a Python package for cluster expansion with a focus on complex alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01363-x</link>
      <description>Santiago Rigamonti, Maria Troppenz, Martin Kub&#225;&#328;, Axel H&#252;bner, Claudia Draxl, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402069282

                Abstract We present the Python package , which provides a modular approach to the cluster expansion (CE) method. can treat a wide variety of substitutional systems, including one-, two-, and three-dimensional alloys, in a general multi-component and multi-sublattice framework. It is capable of dealing with complex materials comprising several atoms in their parent lattice . uses state-of-the-art techniques for the construction of training data sets, model selection, and finite-temperature simulations. The user interface consists of well-documented Python classes and modules ( http://sol.physik.hu-berlin.de/cell/ ). also provides visualization utilities and can be interfaced with virtually any ab initio package, total-energy codes based on interatomic potentials, and more. The usage and capabilities of are illustrated by a number of examples, comprising a Cu-Pt surface alloy with oxygen adsorption, featuring two coupled binary sublattices, and the thermodynamic analysis of its order-disorder transition; the demixing transition and lattice-constant bowing of the Si-Ge alloy; and an iterative CE approach for a complex clathrate compound with a parent lattice consisting of 54 atoms.</description>
      <author>Santiago Rigamonti, Maria Troppenz, Martin Kub&#225;&#328;, Axel H&#252;bner, Claudia Draxl</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01363-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of chemical inhomogeneity on the structure and properties of the two-layer TiAl-based coating obtained by non-vacuum electron beam cladding: experimental investigations and density functional theory simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176239</link>
      <description>Daria V. Lazurenko, Gleb Dovzhenko, K. I. &#201;murlaev, V. S. Shikalov, N. Alexandrova, E. V. Domarov, Alexey A. Ruktuev, Ruslan Kuzmin, Ivan A. Bataev, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402073483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daria V. Lazurenko, Gleb Dovzhenko, K. I. &#201;murlaev, V. S. Shikalov, N. Alexandrova, E. V. Domarov, Alexey A. Ruktuev, Ruslan Kuzmin, Ivan A. Bataev</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and volumetric effects on structural and dielectric properties of hybrid perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51396-5</link>
      <description>Andrzej Nowok, Szymon Sobczak, Kinga Roszak, Anna Z. Szeremeta, Miros&#322;aw M&#261;czka, Andrzej Katrusiak, Sebastian Pawlus, Filip Formalik, Antonio J. Barros dos Santos, Waldeci Paraguassu, Adam Sieradzki, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402077844

                Three-dimensional organic-inorganic perovskites are rapidly evolving materials with diverse applications. This study focuses on their two representatives - acetamidinium manganese(II) formate (AceMn) and formamidinium manganese(II) formate (FMDMn) - subjected to varying temperature and pressure. We show that AceMn undergoes atypical pressure-induced structural transformations at room temperature, increasing the symmetry from ambient-pressure P2</description>
      <author>Andrzej Nowok, Szymon Sobczak, Kinga Roszak, Anna Z. Szeremeta, Miros&#322;aw M&#261;czka, Andrzej Katrusiak, Sebastian Pawlus, Filip Formalik, Antonio J. Barros dos Santos, Waldeci Paraguassu, Adam Sieradzki</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51396-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competing Kinetic Consequences of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on the Oxidative Degradation of Branched Poly(ethylenimine)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08126</link>
      <description>Sichi Li, Yoseph A. Guta, Marcos F. Calegari Andrade, Elwin Hunter&#8208;Sellars, Amitesh Maiti, Anthony J. Varni, Pingying Tang, Carsten Sievers, Simon H. Pang, Christopher W. Jones, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079119

                Amine-functionalized porous solid materials are effective sorbents for direct air capture (DAC) of CO</description>
      <author>Sichi Li, Yoseph A. Guta, Marcos F. Calegari Andrade, Elwin Hunter&#8208;Sellars, Amitesh Maiti, Anthony J. Varni, Pingying Tang, Carsten Sievers, Simon H. Pang, Christopher W. Jones</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of tunable ultra-thin anodes for long-lasting and high-energy-density lithium metal batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155256</link>
      <description>Tian Du, Weimin Chen, Yue Shen, Wenzhu Cao, Wenwen Miao, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Shanshan Yang, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402080004

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tian Du, Weimin Chen, Yue Shen, Wenzhu Cao, Wenwen Miao, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Shanshan Yang, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ichor: A Python library for computational chemistry data management and machine learning force field development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27477</link>
      <description>Yulian Manchev, Matthew J. Burn, Paul L. A. Popelier, Journal of Computational Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402093726

                Abstract We present ichor , an open&#8208;source Python library that simplifies data management in computational chemistry and streamlines machine learning force field development. Ichor implements many easily extensible file management tools, in addition to a lazy file reading system, allowing efficient management of hundreds of thousands of computational chemistry files. Data from calculations can be readily stored into databases for easy sharing and post&#8208;processing. Raw data can be directly processed by ichor to create machine learning&#8208;ready datasets. In addition to powerful data&#8208;related capabilities, ichor provides interfaces to popular workload management software employed by High Performance Computing clusters, making for effortless submission of thousands of separate calculations with only a single line of Python code. Furthermore, a simple&#8208;to&#8208;use command line interface has been implemented through a series of menu systems to further increase accessibility and efficiency of common important ichor tasks. Finally, ichor implements general tools for visualization and analysis of datasets and tools for measuring machine&#8208;learning model quality both on test set data and in simulations. With the current functionalities, ichor can serve as an end&#8208;to&#8208;end data procurement, data management, and analysis solution for machine&#8208;learning force&#8208;field development.</description>
      <author>Yulian Manchev, Matthew J. Burn, Paul L. A. Popelier</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advancements in two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenide materials towards hydrogen-evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.08.009</link>
      <description>Jianmin Yu, Gongao Peng, Lishan Peng, Qingjun Chen, Chenliang Su, Lu Shang, Tierui Zhang, Green Energy &amp; Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402096433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianmin Yu, Gongao Peng, Lishan Peng, Qingjun Chen, Chenliang Su, Lu Shang, Tierui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2024.08.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Potential-Determining Steps of Reduction of Nitrate to Ammonia on Transition Metal Porphyrins Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105022</link>
      <description>Chun&#8208;Ying Wu, Yanqing Shen, Xiaogang Wang, Lingling Lv, Xianghui Meng, Xiangqian Jiang, Dewei Gong, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402096483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chun&#8208;Ying Wu, Yanqing Shen, Xiaogang Wang, Lingling Lv, Xianghui Meng, Xiangqian Jiang, Dewei Gong, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorbtive removal of HF toxic gas via tinsulfide monolayer modification: A molecular perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143231</link>
      <description>Masoud Arabieh, Mohammad-Reza Basaadat, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402099609

                Hydrofluoric Acid (HF) is considered one of the most hazardous chemicals used in industrial plants. Even small exposures to HF can have fatal consequences if not promptly and properly treated. Various research teams have presented numerous substances with the objective of capturing or detecting toxic HF gas. In this study, we explore the impact of HF gas on a single layer of SnS by employing density functional theory (DFT). The interaction nature between the gas molecule and the adsorbent is elucidated by analyzing the related adsorption energy, electronic structure properties and differential charge transfer. The findings indicate that HF is physically adsorbed on the pristine SnS with an adsorption energy value of -0.63 eV. By introducing a Sn mono vacancy defect, the modification of SnS enhances the adsorption energy to -1.26 eV, resulting in a chemisorption process. Molecular fluorine (F2) was discovered to undergo a barrierless reaction with SnS, resulting in the formation of fluorine-substituted SnS. It has been discovered that the substitution of fluorine atoms enhances the reactivity of SnS towards hydro- gen fluoride gas. The adsorption potential of the studied structures towards HF gas was determined to be in the following order: F2SnS &gt; VSn-SnS &gt; VS-SnS &#8764; SnS. The current study is anticipated to offer new molecular insights that could lead to the creation of innovative devices for detecting or eliminating HF toxic gas from a specific atmosphere.</description>
      <author>Masoud Arabieh, Mohammad-Reza Basaadat</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXene introduced between CoNi LDH and NiMoO4 nanorods arrays: A bifunctional multistage composite for OER catalyst and supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.466</link>
      <description>Li Wang, N&#252; Wang, Xiangyang Zhou, Zhongren Yue, Yan Shan, Kezheng Chen, Xuegang Yu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402115937

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, N&#252; Wang, Xiangyang Zhou, Zhongren Yue, Yan Shan, Kezheng Chen, Xuegang Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A compendium of all-in-one solar-driven water splitting using ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-based photocatalysts: guiding the path from the past to the limitless future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01040f</link>
      <description>Wei&#8208;Kean Chong, Boon&#8208;Junn Ng, Lling&#8208;Lling Tan, Siang&#8208;Piao Chai, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402127839

                We discuss the unique properties of zinc indium sulfide associated with the exploitation of multifarious material design strategies to realise sustainable solar-driven overall water splitting for green hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Wei&#8208;Kean Chong, Boon&#8208;Junn Ng, Lling&#8208;Lling Tan, Siang&#8208;Piao Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01040f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the size gap between experiment and theory: large-scale DFT calculations on realistic sized Pd particles for acetylene hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03369h</link>
      <description>Apostolos Kordatos, Khaled M. H. Mohammed, Reza Vakili, Haresh Manyar, Alexandre Goguet, Emma K. Gibson, Marina Carravetta, Peter P. Wells, Chris&#8208;Kriton Skylaris, RSC Advances. 14(38)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402138240

                The hydrogenation of acetylene on entire large Pd/PdC x nanoparticles has been investigated via large-scale DFT simulations. The impact of interstitial C has been examined whilst addressing the challenge of the simulation system size.</description>
      <author>Apostolos Kordatos, Khaled M. H. Mohammed, Reza Vakili, Haresh Manyar, Alexandre Goguet, Emma K. Gibson, Marina Carravetta, Peter P. Wells, Chris&#8208;Kriton Skylaris</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03369h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma&#8208;Induced Oxygen Defect Engineering in Perovskite Oxide for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404239</link>
      <description>Kaiteng Wang, Jun Zhou, Lei Fu, Yunqing Kang, Zilin Zhou, Zhengdong Wang, Kai Wu, Yusuke Yamauchi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402146252

                Abstract Perovskite oxides are considered highly promising candidates for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts due to their low cost and adaptable electronic structure. However, modulating the electronic structure of catalysts without altering their nanomorphology is crucial for understanding the structure&#8208;property relationship. In this study, a simple plasma bombardment strategy is developed to optimize the catalytic activity of perovskite oxides. Experimental characterization of plasma&#8208;treated LaCo 0.9 Fe 0.1 O 3 (P&#8208;LCFO) reveals abundant oxygen vacancies, which expose numerous active sites. Additionally, X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure analyses indicate a low Co valence state in P&#8208;LCFO, likely due to the presence of these oxygen vacancies, which contributes to an optimized electronic structure that enhances OER performance. Consequently, P&#8208;LCFO exhibits significantly improved OER catalytic activity, with a low overpotential of 294 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , outperforming commercial RuO 2 . This work underscores the benefits of plasma engineering for studying structure&#8208;property relationships and developing highly active perovskite oxide catalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Kaiteng Wang, Jun Zhou, Lei Fu, Yunqing Kang, Zilin Zhou, Zhengdong Wang, Kai Wu, Yusuke Yamauchi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational study on single atom anchored on B2C3P monolayer as electrocatalysts for nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114817</link>
      <description>Qiang Xu, Peiyi Yu, Zhenhai Liang, Chaozheng He, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. 1240(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402159301

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Xu, Peiyi Yu, Zhenhai Liang, Chaozheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational study of electrochemical CO2 reduction on two-dimensional TiB2 monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0225796</link>
      <description>Dewyani Patil, Aarti Shukla, AIP conference proceedings. 3203(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402159442

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dewyani Patil, Aarti Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0225796</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counter ion-regulated heterostructured Co@Fe-based core@shell materials: as remarkable bifunctional electrodes for green H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02785j</link>
      <description>G. Rajeshkhanna, Apurba Borah, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402161581

                The exceptional bifunctional catalytic activity of Co@Fe-based core@shell materials, when Co 2 P@Fe 2 P/NF was used as both the anode and cathode, achieving outstanding performance in alkaline water splitting, excelling in both the OER and the HER.</description>
      <author>G. Rajeshkhanna, Apurba Borah, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02785j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decorated and reconstructed perovskite-oxide electrodes for oxygen electrocatalysis and Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.002</link>
      <description>Guichan Chen, Jiapeng Liu, Dengjie Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402163900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guichan Chen, Jiapeng Liu, Dengjie Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Catalysts: Exploring Discharge Product Growth and Intrinsic Overpotential in Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00789</link>
      <description>Zhengxuan Yin, Chuying Ouyang, Neil Qiang Su, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402167300

                The lithium&#8211;oxygen (Li&#8211;O2) battery, renowned for its exceptionally high theoretical energy density, is poised to revolutionize next-generation energy storage systems. However, its practical application depends on overcoming several challenges, particularly the high cathode overpotential, which significantly diminishes the battery's energy efficiency and durability. This study delves into the interactions at the cathode surface during oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER), extending the analysis beyond the initial reaction stages to encompass the extensive charge&#8211;discharge process. We introduce and define the concepts of intrinsic equilibrium potential and intrinsic overpotential, demonstrating that these critical parameters are predominantly influenced by the growth of discharge products, rather than the catalysts, thereby underscoring the inherent properties of the battery. This shift in focus from merely enhancing cathode catalysts to understanding and leveraging the intrinsic characteristics of the battery discharge process opens new avenues for optimizing and enhancing the performance of large-scale Li&#8211;O2 batteries. Furthermore, our findings indicate potential broader applications to other metal&#8211;oxygen systems, paving the way for the design of high-capacity, high-efficiency energy storage technologies.</description>
      <author>Zhengxuan Yin, Chuying Ouyang, Neil Qiang Su</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the adsorption strength of oxygen intermediates on &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;NiC&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;O&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; by Fe doping to improve the oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.095801</link>
      <description>Xilin Zhang, Sheng Rui, Y. C. Zhai, Rui Zheng, Shan Wang, Zhongjun Ma, Zongxian Yang, Physical Review Materials. 8(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402168197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xilin Zhang, Sheng Rui, Y. C. Zhai, Rui Zheng, Shan Wang, Zhongjun Ma, Zongxian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.095801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origins of enhanced oxygen reduction activity of transition metal nitrides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-024-01998-7</link>
      <description>Rui Zeng, Huiqi Li, Zixiao Shi, Lang Xu, Jinhui Meng, Weixuan Xu, Hongsen Wang, Qihao Li, Christopher J. Pollock, Tianquan Lian, Manos Mavrikakis, David A. Muller, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Nature Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402171768

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Zeng, Huiqi Li, Zixiao Shi, Lang Xu, Jinhui Meng, Weixuan Xu, Hongsen Wang, Qihao Li, Christopher J. Pollock, Tianquan Lian, Manos Mavrikakis, David A. Muller, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-024-01998-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace silver doping improved the efficiency of copper-based Fenton-like catalysts cathode for wastewater treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135261</link>
      <description>Hui Ming, Changkai Yin, Zhigang Huang, Le Xu, Zhongming Zheng, Xiuqin Yang, Libo Zhang, Junwei Hou, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402184623

                The treatment of highly concentrated and recalcitrant organic pollutants in industrial wastewater has garnered significant attention, with Fenton oxidation emerging as a promising approach. However, traditional iron-based Fenton reagents present certain limitations, and copper-based Fenton systems are often less efficient. Thus, it is necessary to develop innovative copper-based Fenton catalytic materials. In this study, Cu&#8322;O and Ag-modified activated carbon fibers (Cu&#8322;O-Ag@ACF) were synthesized via liquid-phase reduction. The composition, structure, and morphology of Cu&#8322;O-Ag@ACF were systematically characterized. The Cu&#8322;O-Ag@ACF was employed as a functionalized cathode in the electro-Fenton process to degrade a highly concentrated organic pollutant solution, with methylene blue serving as a model contaminant. The loading of Cu&#8322;O and Ag not only enhances the electrochemical performance of ACF but also improves its Fenton oxidation efficiency. Cu&#8322;O-Ag@ACF exhibitd less than 1% performance degradation after five cycles of use, highlighting its potential for industrial applications under simulated realistic conditions. Moreover, the electro-Fenton system parameters, including current density, pH, electrode spacing, and solution temperature, were optimized. Under the optimal conditions, the degradation rate of methylene blue by Cu&#8322;O-Ag@ACF reached 92.8% within 120 minutes. Kinetic analysis indicated that the reaction followed a first-order kinetic model, with a rate constant of 0.253 min&#8315;&#185;. Furthermore, this study revealed that trace silver doping significantly accelerated the generation of reactive oxygen species, thereby enhancing the efficiency of the Cu-based Fenton-like catalysts. In conclusion, this work presents a convenient strategy for the sustainable and efficient purification of industrial wastewater, contributing to the improvement of human life quality.</description>
      <author>Hui Ming, Changkai Yin, Zhigang Huang, Le Xu, Zhongming Zheng, Xiuqin Yang, Libo Zhang, Junwei Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Principles for the Descriptor-Based Design of Supported Gold Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04049</link>
      <description>Lavie Rekhi, Quang Thang Tr&#7883;nh, Asmee M. Prabhu, Tej S. Choksi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402190568

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lavie Rekhi, Quang Thang Tr&#7883;nh, Asmee M. Prabhu, Tej S. Choksi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular engineering of renewable cellulose biopolymers for solid-state battery electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-024-01414-7</link>
      <description>Jinyang Li, Ziyang Hu, Sidong Zhang, Hongshen Zhang, Sijie Guo, Guiming Zhong, Yan Qiao, Zhangquan Peng, Yutao Li, Shuguang Chen, GuanHua Chen, Amin Cao, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402194446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinyang Li, Ziyang Hu, Sidong Zhang, Hongshen Zhang, Sijie Guo, Guiming Zhong, Yan Qiao, Zhangquan Peng, Yutao Li, Shuguang Chen, GuanHua Chen, Amin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-024-01414-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect engineering for surface reconstruction of metal oxide catalysts during OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101091</link>
      <description>Jingxuan Zheng, Zhao Wang, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402194918

                The bigger pictureChallenges and opportunities:&#8226;The scarcity of active sites limits the large-scale application of metal oxides as commercial oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts. However, the rational design of defect structures can boost their catalytic activity&#8226;The precise design of catalyst defect structures requires a comprehensive understanding of the structure-activity relationship between defects and OER performance. Current research primarily focuses on the correlation between defects and thermodynamic parameters. However, our understanding of the intrinsic relationship between defects and the kinetics and mechanisms of OERs remains limited&#8226;In the adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM), defect structures can accelerate the evolution of active surfaces, promote OH&#8315; adsorption and deprotonation, and facilitate the desorption of the product O&#8322;. In the lattice oxygen intermediate mechanism (LOM), defect structures can enhance the covalency of metal&#8211;oxygen bonds and provide OH&#8315; adsorption sites, facilitating their involvement in lattice oxygen oxidation processesSummaryThe development of electrochemical processes, such as water electrolysis for hydrogen production and rechargeable metal-air batteries, offers promising solutions to the energy crisis and environmental pollution. However, challenges like sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics, high costs of precious metal catalysts, and scarce active sites in transition metal oxides hinder large-scale commercial applications. Defect engineering has emerged as a promising strategy to optimize transition metal oxides by improving their electronic structure, conductivity, and active site availability. Early research focused on static thermodynamic parameters, such as impedance, overpotential, and band gap, neglecting dynamic factors like catalyst surface restructuring and mechanism transformation during reactions. This perspective highlights the intrinsic connection between defect structures, catalyst surface reconstruction, and reaction mechanisms. It also discusses the need for advanced experimental and theoretical computational studies to better understand the surface evolution of catalysts during OERs.Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Jingxuan Zheng, Zhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing accuracy by prescribing precision: Bayesian error estimation of point defect energetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211543</link>
      <description>Andrew Timmins, Rachel C. Kurchin, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402195786

                With density functional theory (DFT), it is possible to calculate the formation energy of charged point defects and in turn to predict a range of experimentally relevant quantities, such as defect concentrations, charge transition levels, or recombination rates. While prior efforts have led to marked improvements in the accuracy of such calculations, comparatively modest effort has been directed at quantifying their uncertainties. However, in the broader DFT research space, the development of Bayesian Error Estimation Functionals (BEEF) has enabled uncertainty quantification (UQ) for other properties. In this paper, we investigate the utility of BEEF as a tool for UQ of defect formation energies. We build a pipeline for propagating BEEF energies through a formation-energy calculation and test it on intrinsic defects in several materials systems spanning a variety of chemistries, bandgaps, and crystal structures, comparing to prior published results where available. We also assess the impact of aligning to a deep-level transition rather than to the VBM (valence band maximum). We observe negligible dependence of the estimated uncertainty upon a supercell size, though the relationship may be obfuscated by the fact that finite-size corrections cannot be computed separately for each member of the BEEF ensemble. Additionally, we find an increase in estimated uncertainty with respect to the absolute charge of a defect and the relaxation around the defect site without deep-level alignment, but this trend is absent when the alignment is applied. While further investigation is warranted, our results suggest that BEEF could be a useful method for UQ in defect calculations.</description>
      <author>Andrew Timmins, Rachel C. Kurchin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic micro-environment regulation of ZIF-67 with broadened pore structure and unsaturated coordination sites for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.368</link>
      <description>Lingxiang Liu, Li Wang, Shasha Cui, T. Li, Xiaomeng Yang, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402208249

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingxiang Liu, Li Wang, Shasha Cui, T. Li, Xiaomeng Yang, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Pathways to Sustainable Energy: Advancements in Clean Coal Technologies in Bangladesh - A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clet.2024.100805</link>
      <description>Faysal Ahamed Akash, Shaik Muntasir Shovon, Md. Abdur Rahman, Wahida Rahman, Prosenjeet Chakraborty, Md. Nazwanul Haque, Minhaj Uddin Monir, Md. Ahosan Habib, Arup Kumar Biswas, Shahariar Chowdhury, Mohammad Forrukh Hossain Khan, Tofan Agung Eka Prasetya, Cleaner Engineering and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402215720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faysal Ahamed Akash, Shaik Muntasir Shovon, Md. Abdur Rahman, Wahida Rahman, Prosenjeet Chakraborty, Md. Nazwanul Haque, Minhaj Uddin Monir, Md. Ahosan Habib, Arup Kumar Biswas, Shahariar Chowdhury, Mohammad Forrukh Hossain Khan, Tofan Agung Eka Prasetya</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clet.2024.100805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative study of electrochemical adsorption and oxidation on Pt(111) and its vicinal surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145014</link>
      <description>Francesc Valls Mascar&#243;, Marc T. M. Koper, Marcel J. Rost, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402218622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Francesc Valls Mascar&#243;, Marc T. M. Koper, Marcel J. Rost</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Ru nanoclusters for robust oxygen reduction in aqueous wide-temperature zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2024.08.005</link>
      <description>Rupeng Liu, Chunhuan Jiang, Jin-Han Guo, Yang Zheng, Leting Zhang, Xiaolong Liang, Huimin Gao, Jiancheng Zhao, Yunhang Fan, Qing Chen, Wenhui He, Lehui Lu, Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402223338

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rupeng Liu, Chunhuan Jiang, Jin-Han Guo, Yang Zheng, Leting Zhang, Xiaolong Liang, Huimin Gao, Jiancheng Zhao, Yunhang Fan, Qing Chen, Wenhui He, Lehui Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2024.08.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Zero Total Charge Predicts Cation Effects for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01897</link>
      <description>Jay T. Bender, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Angel E. Valles, Alyssa K. Uvodich, Delia J. Milliron, John R. Kitchin, Joaquin Resasco, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402230343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jay T. Bender, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Angel E. Valles, Alyssa K. Uvodich, Delia J. Milliron, John R. Kitchin, Joaquin Resasco</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of oxygen vacancies in different valence states on the electronic structure and photoelectric properties of 2D-TiO2(001): N under biaxial strain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.498</link>
      <description>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402236076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.498</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Embedding Techniques in Multimodal Retrieval Augmented Generation A Comprehensive Study on Cross Modal AI Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/h8wf8vah</link>
      <description>Zhou Ren, Journal of Computing and Electronic Information Management. 13(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402026964

                Our study presents significant advancements in the handling of multimodal data through an extended Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) model. By integrating advanced embedding techniques, efficient retrieval mechanisms, and robust generative capabilities, our model demonstrates notable improvements in retrieval accuracy, real-time efficiency, generative quality, and scalability. The retrieval accuracy of our model reached 85%, showing a 10% improvement over existing benchmarks. Furthermore, the retrieval time was reduced by 40%, enhancing real-time application performance. The model's generative quality was also significantly improved, with BLEU and ROUGE scores increasing by 15% and 12%, respectively. These results validate the effectiveness of our approach and its applicability to various AI applications, including information retrieval, recommendation systems, and content creation. Future research directions include the integration of additional modalities and further optimization of retrieval mechanisms to broaden the applicability of our model.</description>
      <author>Zhou Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/h8wf8vah</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting error bars on density functional theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-69194-w</link>
      <description>Simuck F. Yuk, Irmak Sargin, Noah Meyer, Jaron T. Krogel, Scott P. Beckman, Valentino R. Cooper, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402049949

                Predicting the error in density functional theory (DFT) calculations due to the choice of exchange-correlation (XC) functional is crucial to the success of DFT, but currently, there are limited options to estimate this a priori. This is particularly important for high-throughput screening of new materials. In this work, the structure and elastic properties of binary and ternary oxides are computed using four XC functionals: LDA, PBE-GGA, PBEsol, and vdW-DF with C09 exchange. To analyze the systemic errors inherent to each XC functional, we employed materials informatics methods to predict the expected errors. The predicted errors were also used to better the DFT-predicted lattice parameters. Our results emphasize the link between the computed errors and the electron density and hybridization errors of a functional. In essence, these results provide "error bars" for choosing a functional for the creation of high-accuracy, high-throughput datasets as well as avenues for the development of XC functionals with enhanced performance, thereby enabling the accelerated discovery and design of new materials.</description>
      <author>Simuck F. Yuk, Irmak Sargin, Noah Meyer, Jaron T. Krogel, Scott P. Beckman, Valentino R. Cooper</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-69194-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and Comparative Analysis of CO2 Absorption Columns in Electrochemical and Thermochemical Carbon Capture Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x7xkz-v2</link>
      <description>Katelyn M. Ripley, Fikile R. Brushett, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402072119

                Deployment of post-combustion carbon dioxide (CO2) capture technologies is needed to reduce emissions from power and industrial sources. Comparisons between existing thermochemical CO2 capture methods and emerging electrochemical concepts can help contextualize the promise of these new approaches. Here, we investigate the required absorber sizes for three capture systems: amine scrubbing using monoethanolamine (MEA), direct electrochemical (redox-active sorbent), and indirect electrochemical (pH-swing). For the electrochemical systems, we study how column size varies as a function of molecular properties and operating conditions, finding that parameters most closely related to CO2 uptake rates (i.e., rate constants and pKa) have the greatest impact. Through a Monte Carlo analysis, we find that the direct process can be designed to have column sizes similar to the thermochemical process, however, the CO2 uptake rate in the indirect process is too slow to enable smaller columns. Broadly, this work connects system input parameters to absorber performance for electrochemical CO2 capture and provides a foundation for technoeconomic and engineering analyses.</description>
      <author>Katelyn M. Ripley, Fikile R. Brushett</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x7xkz-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discerning molecular-level CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; adsorption behavior in amine-modified sorbents within a controlled CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O environment towards direct air capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05578k</link>
      <description>Ah&#8208;Young Song, John Young, Jie&#8208;Yu Wang, S Fricke, Katia Piscina, Raynald Giovine, Susana Garc&#237;a, Mijndert van der Spek, Jeffrey A. Reimer, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402236934

                CO 2 adsorption is influenced by its concentration and H 2 O presence. While concentration governs chemisorbed species formation, H 2 O significantly impacts CO 2 adsorption capacity, especially under dilute conditions mimicking direct air capture (DAC).</description>
      <author>Ah&#8208;Young Song, John Young, Jie&#8208;Yu Wang, S Fricke, Katia Piscina, Raynald Giovine, Susana Garc&#237;a, Mijndert van der Spek, Jeffrey A. Reimer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05578k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anion-Exchange Membrane Oxygen Separator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsorginorgau.4c00052</link>
      <description>Maisa Faour, Karam Yassin, Dario R. Dekel, ACS Organic &amp; Inorganic Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401991440

                Anion-exchange membranes (AEMs), known for enabling the high conductivity of hydroxide anions through dense polymeric structures, are pivotal components in fuel cells, electrolyzers, and other important electrochemical systems. This paper unveils an unprecedented utilization of AEMs in an electrochemical oxygen separation process, a new technology able to generate enriched oxygen from an O2/N2 mixture using a small voltage input. We demonstrate a first-of-its-kind AEM-based electrochemical device that operates under mild conditions, is free of liquid electrolytes or sweep gases, and produces oxygen of over 96% purity. Additionally, we develop and apply a one-dimensional time-dependent and isothermal model, which accurately captures the unique operational dynamics of our device, demonstrates good agreement with the experimental data, and allows us to explore the device's potential capabilities. This novel technology has far-reaching applications in many industrial processes, medical oxygen therapy, and other diverse fields while reducing operational complexity and environmental impact, thereby paving the way for sustainable on-site oxygen generation.</description>
      <author>Maisa Faour, Karam Yassin, Dario R. Dekel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsorginorgau.4c00052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin Manipulation of Co sites in Co&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;/Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CT&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Mott&#8211;Schottky Heterojunction for Boosting the Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407301</link>
      <description>Shuai Zhang, Weihua Zhao, Jiameng Liu, Zheng Tao, Yinpeng Zhang, Shuangrun Zhao, Zhihong Zhang, Miao Du, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402193924

                Abstract Regulating the adsorption of an intermediate on an electrocatalyst by manipulating the electron spin state of the transition metal is of great significance for promoting the activation of inert nitrogen molecules (N 2 ) during the electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR). However, achieving this remains challenging. Herein, a novel 2D/2D Mott&#8211;Schottky heterojunction, Co 9 S 8 /Nb 2 CT x &#8208;P, is developed as an eNRR catalyst. This is achieved through the in situ growth of cobalt sulfide (Co 9 S 8 ) nanosheets over a Nb 2 CT x MXene using a solution plasma modification method. Transformation of the Co spin state from low (t 2g 6 e g 1 ) to high (t 2g 5 e g 2 ) is achieved by adjusting the interface electronic structure and sulfur vacancy of Co 9 S 8 /Nb 2 CT x &#8208;P. The adsorption ability of N 2 is optimized through high spin Co(II) with more unpaired electrons, significantly accelerating the *N 2 &#8594;*NNH kinetic process. The Co 9 S 8 /Nb 2 CT x &#8208;P exhibits a high NH 3 yield of 62.62 &#181;g h &#8722;1 mg cat. &#8722;1 and a Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 30.33% at &#8722;0.40 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) in 0.1 m HCl. Additionally, it achieves an NH 3 yield of 41.47 &#181;g h &#8722;1 mg cat. &#8722;1 and FE of 23.19% at &#8722;0.60 V versus RHE in 0.1 m Na 2 SO 4 . This work demonstrates a promising strategy for constructing heterojunction electrocatalysts for efficient eNRR.</description>
      <author>Shuai Zhang, Weihua Zhao, Jiameng Liu, Zheng Tao, Yinpeng Zhang, Shuangrun Zhao, Zhihong Zhang, Miao Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407301</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
