<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 01:24:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>The Stabilization Mechanisms of CL-20 Crystals by Intercalation of Graphene Oxide Coated with Polydopamine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.5c05464</link>
      <description>Haorui Zhang, Mingjie Wen, Xue-Xue Zhang, Jie-Yao Lyu, Geng Xu, Qingzhao Chu, Dongping Chen, Qi&#8208;Long Yan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry B. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414082664

                Hexaazaisowurtzitane (CL-20) is a high-energy-density compound with poor thermal stability, which hinders its application in composite energetic systems. A bi-interface structure of polydopamine-coated graphene oxide (GO@PDA) is shown to markedly improve thermal stability compared with pristine CL-20 and single-layer coatings. Reactive molecular dynamics simulations enhanced by a neural network potential (NNP) reveal that the delayed onset of decomposition arises from suppressed NO2 release and altered spatial density distribution, while interfacial -OH and -COOH groups consume intermediates, redirect decomposition pathways, and inhibit autocatalytic chain reactions. This dual-modulation mechanism produces controlled energy release, reduced mechanical sensitivity, and a more gradual decomposition profile. The findings demonstrate the potential of interfacial nanostructures to regulate the thermal response of energetic crystals and suggest a generalizable strategy for enhancing the stability and safety of functional energetic composites.</description>
      <author>Haorui Zhang, Mingjie Wen, Xue-Xue Zhang, Jie-Yao Lyu, Geng Xu, Qingzhao Chu, Dongping Chen, Qi&#8208;Long Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.5c05464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isotope-dependent Tafel analysis probes proton transfer kinetics during electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01934-5</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Ran Wang, Hongyuan Sheng, Xiaorong Zhu, R. Dominic Ross, Daxing Hua, Lin Lei, Yafei Li, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Xianjie Wang, Ping Xu, Jun L&#252;, Sida Jiang, Jiecai Han, Bo Song, Song Jin, Nature Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414083407

                Proton transfer plays an important role in both hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions during electrocatalytic water splitting to produce green hydrogen. However, directly adapting the conventional proton/deuterium kinetic isotope effect to study proton transfer in heterogeneous electrocatalytic processes is challenging. Here we propose using the shift in the Tafel slope between protic and deuteric electrolytes, or the Tafel slope isotope effect, as an effective probe of proton transfer characteristics. Comparison of the Tafel slope isotope effect for diverse hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts in different pH environments reveals that proton transfer is both pH and structure dependent. Using ruthenium oxide as an example, we show that local structure modification can change the rate-determining step from an electrochemical, concerted proton-electron transfer step to a chemical step and improve the oxygen evolution activity in acid. The isotope-dependent Tafel analysis will facilitate a better understanding of the proton transfer behaviours during electrocatalytic processes and provide guidance for designing efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Ran Wang, Hongyuan Sheng, Xiaorong Zhu, R. Dominic Ross, Daxing Hua, Lin Lei, Yafei Li, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Xianjie Wang, Ping Xu, Jun L&#252;, Sida Jiang, Jiecai Han, Bo Song, Song Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01934-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient, Hierarchical, and Object-Oriented Electronic Structure Interfaces for Direct Nonadiabatic Dynamics Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00878</link>
      <description>Sascha Mausenberger, Severin Polonius, Sebastian Mai, Leticia Gonz&#225;lez, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414084320

                We present a novel, flexible framework for electronic structure interfaces designed for nonadiabatic dynamics simulations, implemented in Python 3 using concepts of object-oriented programming. This framework streamlines the development of new interfaces by providing a reusable and extendable code base. It supports the computation of energies, gradients, various couplings&#9472;like spin-orbit couplings, nonadiabatic couplings, and transition dipole moments&#9472;and other properties for an arbitrary number of states with any multiplicities and charges. A key innovation within this framework is the introduction of hybrid interfaces, which can use other interfaces in a general hierarchical manner. Hybrid interfaces are capable of using one or more child interfaces to implement multiscale approaches, such as quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics where different child interfaces are assigned to different regions of a system. The concept of hybrid interfaces can be extended through nesting, where hybrid parent interfaces use hybrid child interfaces to easily setup complex workflows without the need for additional coding. We demonstrate the versatility of hybrid interfaces with two examples: one at the method level and one at the workflow level. The first example showcases the numerical differentiation of wave function overlaps, implemented as a hybrid interface and used to optimize a minimum-energy conical intersection with numerical nonadiabatic couplings. The second example presents an adaptive learning workflow, where nested hybrid interfaces are used to iteratively refine a machine learning model. This work lays the groundwork for more modular, flexible, and scalable software design in excited-state dynamics.</description>
      <author>Sascha Mausenberger, Severin Polonius, Sebastian Mai, Leticia Gonz&#225;lez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Transition State Search and Ligand Screening for Organometallic Catalysis with Reactive Machine Learning Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01047</link>
      <description>Kun Tang, Yujing Zhao, Lei Zhang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Qilei Liu, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414084992

                Organometallic catalysis lies at the heart of numerous industrial processes that produce bulk and fine chemicals. The search for transition states and screening for organic ligands are vital in designing highly active organometallic catalysts with efficient reaction kinetics. However, identifying accurate transition states necessitates computationally intensive quantum chemistry calculations. In this work, a reactive machine learning potential (RMLP) model is developed to accelerate transition state optimizations and ligand screening for organometallic catalysis based on an automated transition state database construction method and a higher-order equivariant message passing neural network. In case studies involving the ethylene hydrogenation reaction catalyzed by organometallic catalysts, RMLP rapidly predicts potential energy surfaces along intrinsic reaction coordinate paths, achieving speeds nearly 3 orders of magnitude faster than those of rigorous quantum chemistry calculations. Meanwhile, it maintains comparable accuracy with a root-mean-square deviation of 0.307 &#197; for transition state geometries and a mean absolute error of 0.871 kJ&#183;mol-1 for reaction barriers on the external test set, significantly outperforming semiempirical quantum chemistry methods. Our RMLP model offers an effective alternative to both rigorous and semiempirical quantum chemistry approaches for rapid and precise transition state optimizations, facilitating high-throughput screening of advanced organometallic catalyst ligands.</description>
      <author>Kun Tang, Yujing Zhao, Lei Zhang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Qilei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain for Credentialing and Academic Record-Keeping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3373-2185-1.ch014</link>
      <description>B. Subashini, Anna Anbumozhi, S. Praveenkumar, N. Vasudevan, Venkatesh Kaliamoorthy, Advances in computational intelligence and robotics book series. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414089994

                In the digital era, ensuring the security, authenticity, and accessibility of academic credentials is crucial. Traditional credentialing and academic record-keeping systems suffer from inefficiencies, security vulnerabilities, and verification issues. Blockchain technology offers a decentralized, tamper-proof, and transparent solution to these challenges. This chapter explores blockchain's potential in academic credentialing, examining its benefits, challenges, and real-world applications. Academic institutions currently rely on centralized authorities, which can be inefficient and susceptible to fraud. Blockchain provides an immutable ledger that enables secure issuance, decentralized verification, and fraud prevention. By leveraging cryptographic security and smart contracts, institutions can issue digital diplomas and certificates that are instantly verifiable, eliminating the need for intermediary verification. Blockchain also enhances lifelong learning records by allowing students to consolidate academic achievements into a single digital identity. This improves global mobility.</description>
      <author>B. Subashini, Anna Anbumozhi, S. Praveenkumar, N. Vasudevan, Venkatesh Kaliamoorthy</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3373-2185-1.ch014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The augmented potential method: Multiscale modeling toward a spectral defect genome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2025.116969</link>
      <description>Nutth Tuchinda, Changle Li, Christopher A. Schuh, Scripta Materialia. 271(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414090801

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nutth Tuchinda, Changle Li, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2025.116969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretation of X-ray Photoelectron Spectra of Ge(111), GeO2/Ge(111), and C60F18/Ge(111) Samples Using Quantum Chemical Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1027451025700685</link>
      <description>E. A. Shramkov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, Ratibor G. Chumakov, V. G. Stankevich, &#1051;. &#1055;. &#1057;&#1091;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Journal of Surface Investigation X-ray Synchrotron and Neutron Techniques. 19(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414095106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. A. Shramkov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, Ratibor G. Chumakov, V. G. Stankevich, &#1051;. &#1055;. &#1057;&#1091;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1027451025700685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Hexagonal &lt;scp&gt;V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; Monolayer as a Promising Nonprecious Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction: Insights from First&#8208;Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70137</link>
      <description>Ziqi Li, Xue Li, Sheng Wang, Siyu Lu, Guochun Yang, Zhiyong Tang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100023

                The development of efficient, cost&#8208;effective, and durable electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is critical for advancing sustainable energy systems and enabling the widespread adoption of hydrogen&#8208;based energy technologies. In this study, we discover a stable hexagonal V 2 B 2 monolayer that serves as a promising HER catalyst via an unbiased swarm&#8208;intelligence structural method as implemented in CALYPSO code. First&#8208;principles calculations show that the predicted V 2 B 2 monolayer exhibits excellent metallic properties and promising catalytic activity for HER, suggesting CALYPSO's utility for accelerating the discovery of efficient electrocatalysts. Further doping engineering, incorporating transition metals (TM&#8242; = Sc, Y, Ti, Zr, Hf), reveals that the introduction of Sc, Y, and Zr significantly enhances the catalytic performance. Bader charge analysis reveals a linear correlation between the electron gain by the hydrogen atom and &#916; G H* , suggesting that this relationship could serve as an effective descriptor for HER activity in TM'&#8208;doped V 2 B 2 systems. Our findings provide valuable insights into nonprecious HER electrocatalysts and contribute to a deeper understanding of high catalytic performance in newly proposed 2D HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ziqi Li, Xue Li, Sheng Wang, Siyu Lu, Guochun Yang, Zhiyong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin State Modulation in M&#8211;N&#8211;C Single-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04591</link>
      <description>Hyeonjung Jung, Roman Fanta, Md Delowar Hossain, Michal Bajdich, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyeonjung Jung, Roman Fanta, Md Delowar Hossain, Michal Bajdich</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering enhanced high mass specific activity and robust Pt/PtSe2 electrode for large current hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136750</link>
      <description>Bing Hao, Jingjing Guo, Feng Chen, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Yanhui Song, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo, Fuel. 405(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Hao, Jingjing Guo, Feng Chen, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Yanhui Song, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure optimization of transition metal dichalcogenides via Cu doping for enhanced nitrate reduction reaction efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107649</link>
      <description>Jiacheng Li, Wei Lang, Lei Rao, Peifang Wang, Chongchong Liu, Y.C. Zhou, Yi Chen, Gang Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414106340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiacheng Li, Wei Lang, Lei Rao, Peifang Wang, Chongchong Liu, Y.C. Zhou, Yi Chen, Gang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Study to Assess the Influence of Elastic Strains on the Catalytic Activity of Au Surfaces for the HER and ORR Including the Effect of Coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01962</link>
      <description>Diego Schaefer-Dalmau, Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Javier LLorca, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414111269

                The influence of different surface coverages and the effect of biaxial elastic strains on the catalytic properties for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) were analyzed using the example of a Au fcc(111) surface. The adsorption energies of H, O, and OH for the corresponding intermediate reactions were obtained by density functional theory calculations. While for H and O, the adsorption energy increased with coverage, for OH, the lowest adsorption energy was observed at 0.5 ML. Then, after elastic strains were applied, the trends observed for the unstrained slab were maintained for the three adsorbates. Although neither tension nor compression modified the optimum coverage, they did change the differences in relative energies. This is considered to be a consequence of the deformations promoted on the surface. Finally, the catalytic activity of the HER and ORR was computed for the distinct coverages and elastic strains. Catalytic activity plots confirmed for both reactions that the more favorable adsorption energy promoted by tensile strains leads to an increment of the activity and that the most active coverage is 0.25 ML. Furthermore, an analysis of the free energies of each step of the dissociative mechanism of the ORR unveils that both coverage and elastic strains can modify the rate-limiting step and, therefore, the catalytic activity of a material. The results presented in this work provide ample characterization of the Au fcc(111) surface as a catalyst for the HER and ORR and offer, for the first time, an analysis of the influence of both coverage and elastic strain engineering on the catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Diego Schaefer-Dalmau, Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Javier LLorca, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Hydroxylated Mn-Doped RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as an Efficient and Stable Electrocatalyst for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04487</link>
      <description>Qian Dang, Zhe Shang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414112879

                The role of surface hydroxylation in the performance of RuO2-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial but still unclear. Using first-principles calculations, we comprehensively studied the impact of surface hydroxylation states on the activity and stability of Mn-doped RuO2-based electrocatalysts (denoted as nOH-Mn0.1Ru0.9O2, n = 1&#8211;5) in acidic OER. It was revealed that the moderately hydroxylated Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 demonstrates better performance than the fully hydroxylated structure, and 4OH-Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 holds the lowest reaction barrier of 0.14 eV in solvation under the constant potential of 1.5 V, which is lower than those of both pure RuO2 (0.28 eV) and Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 (0.23 eV). Such an increase in catalytic activity stems from the nonstrong-and-nonweak charge transfer of reaction sites. In addition, the synergistic effect of doping and hydroxylation can also increase the stability of RuO2 through inhibition of structure collapse caused by the dissolution of Ru and the loss of lattice oxygen. The present study has provided a novel strategy for the design of efficient and stable RuO2-based acidic OER catalysts through surface hydroxylation.</description>
      <author>Qian Dang, Zhe Shang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Hydrogenationof Lignin Derivatives For Sustainable Synthesis of Value-Added Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00981-3</link>
      <description>Ning L&#252;, Congxin Chen, Xiaokang Zhao, Xinxin Li, Dehua Xiong, Zan Li, Guangyuan Yang, Lei Wang, Li Guo, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414116679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning L&#252;, Congxin Chen, Xiaokang Zhao, Xinxin Li, Dehua Xiong, Zan Li, Guangyuan Yang, Lei Wang, Li Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00981-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy, exergy, environmental, and exergoeconomic (4E) analysis of a fossil fuel power plant with carbon capture unit for a sustainable future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2025.08.056</link>
      <description>Tahir Abdul Hussain Ratlamwala, Khurram Kamal, Hafsa Javed, Sheikh Muhammad Ali Haider, &#1052;uhammad Abid, Sayem Zafar, Mohammed Alkahtani, Alexandria Engineering Journal. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414116771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tahir Abdul Hussain Ratlamwala, Khurram Kamal, Hafsa Javed, Sheikh Muhammad Ali Haider, &#1052;uhammad Abid, Sayem Zafar, Mohammed Alkahtani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2025.08.056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing carbon capture and storage (CCS) infrastructure development using a python tool for source-sink matching and cluster formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146563</link>
      <description>Amina Togay, Gaini Serik, Woojin Lee, Journal of Cleaner Production. 525(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414118433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amina Togay, Gaini Serik, Woojin Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel Janus InN/PtSSe heterostructure for highly efficient overall water splitting via a third-generation Z-scheme: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151360</link>
      <description>Khawla Chaoui, Ali Hamidani, Kamel Zanat, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 174(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414120014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Khawla Chaoui, Ali Hamidani, Kamel Zanat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable optoelectronic and hydrogen evolution reaction properties of decorated 2D materials (Ga2O3 monolayer, ZnO monolayer and borophene)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2025.116372</link>
      <description>Rongzhi Wang, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, Physica E Low-dimensional Systems and Nanostructures. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414120360

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rongzhi Wang, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2025.116372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced stability catalytic performance: a strategy for stability enhancement of Ru-based catalysts in acidic OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/01614940.2025.2556094</link>
      <description>Bin Liu, Yong Zhao, Yuhao Wu, Yanxuan Wen, Zonglin Liu, Pengfei Wang, Jie Shu, Ting-Feng Yi, Catalysis Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414123085

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Liu, Yong Zhao, Yuhao Wu, Yanxuan Wen, Zonglin Liu, Pengfei Wang, Jie Shu, Ting-Feng Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/01614940.2025.2556094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Electrolyte Ions on Iridium Oxide-Based Water Oxidation Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03970</link>
      <description>Boqiang Chen, Pengpeng Wang, Dongyoon Shin, Wei Li, Tianying Liu, Matthias M. Waegele, Dunwei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414125155

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boqiang Chen, Pengpeng Wang, Dongyoon Shin, Wei Li, Tianying Liu, Matthias M. Waegele, Dunwei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tandem amine scrubbing and CO2 electrolysis via direct piperazine carbamate reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01869-8</link>
      <description>Peng Li, Yu Mao, Heejong Shin, Qi Yang, Xuan Cheng, Yitong Li, Kangkang Li, Hai Yu, Roger J. Mulder, Wei Kong Pang, Huanyu Jin, Yong Zhao, Zhifeng Zheng, E. P. Finch, Kyle N. Hearn, Baohua Jia, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Ziyun Wang, Tianyi Ma, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414131647

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Li, Yu Mao, Heejong Shin, Qi Yang, Xuan Cheng, Yitong Li, Kangkang Li, Hai Yu, Roger J. Mulder, Wei Kong Pang, Huanyu Jin, Yong Zhao, Zhifeng Zheng, E. P. Finch, Kyle N. Hearn, Baohua Jia, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Ziyun Wang, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01869-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of monoatomic boron electronic structure to improve catalytic activity for electrocatalytic acetonitrile reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151428</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Song, Liang Yu, Yi Yang, Xiaoqing Gong, Mingqiang Liu, Kai Xu, Daming Sun, Kefeng Xie, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 174(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414141625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Song, Liang Yu, Yi Yang, Xiaoqing Gong, Mingqiang Liu, Kai Xu, Daming Sun, Kefeng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-engineered Ga2SSe/SnS2 van der Waals heterojunction as an efficient S-scheme photocatalyst for solar water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107637</link>
      <description>Junhao Zhu, Zhengdong Sun, Jiaxin Ma, Yifei Shen, Xiao Wang, Meng Zhang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414148250

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junhao Zhu, Zhengdong Sun, Jiaxin Ma, Yifei Shen, Xiao Wang, Meng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials Engineering for High Performance and Durability Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01989</link>
      <description>Pablo A. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Salaberri, Lonneke van Eijk, William Bangay, Kara J. Ferner, M.H. Ha, M. S. Moore, Ivan Perea, Ahmet Kusoglu, Fei Wei, Prodip K. Das, Nausir Firas, Svitlana Pylypenko, Melissa Novy, Michael Yandrasits, Suvash C. Saha, Ali Bayat, Shawn Litster, Iryna V. Zenyuk, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414155218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pablo A. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Salaberri, Lonneke van Eijk, William Bangay, Kara J. Ferner, M.H. Ha, M. S. Moore, Ivan Perea, Ahmet Kusoglu, Fei Wei, Prodip K. Das, Nausir Firas, Svitlana Pylypenko, Melissa Novy, Michael Yandrasits, Suvash C. Saha, Ali Bayat, Shawn Litster, Iryna V. Zenyuk</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non&#8208;oxide High&#8208;Entropy Ceramics for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.70048</link>
      <description>Gang Wang, Xuguang Guo, Lihua Lyu, Ruihui Gan, Yongping Zheng, Hyoyoung Lee, Xiaodong Shao, Carbon Neutralization. 4(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414155426

                ABSTRACT As fossil energy resources deplete and environmental challenges escalate, the development of clean energy technologies has gained global consensus. Among emerging strategies, electrochemical water splitting for hydrogen production stands out due to its zero&#8208;carbon emissions. However, the oxygen evolution reaction suffers from sluggish kinetics and typically depends on precious metal catalysts. Recently, non&#8208;oxygen anion (e.g., S, P, N, F, C, etc.) high&#8208;entropy ceramics (NOHECs), a subclass of high&#8208;entropy materials doped with diverse elements, have demonstrated significant OER potential, offering a cost&#8208;effective solution with high activity and excellent stability. This review delineates the synthesis methods for NOHECs from two distinct perspectives: liquid&#8208;phase synthesis routes and gas&#8208;phase synthesis routes. Subsequently, the catalytic mechanisms and performance breakthroughs of various NOHECs are reviewed in detail, which are categorized by the types of coordinated non&#8208;oxygen anions. Importantly, this review critically explores future research directions for these materials from multiple perspectives, including innovative synthetic routes, novel NOHEC designs, theoretical simulations, advanced material characterization techniques, industrial feasibility, and expanded applications. Ultimately, it aims to provide a theoretical foundation and technical references for the integration of NOHECs in energy conversion systems while highlighting promising pathways for further advancement in this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <author>Gang Wang, Xuguang Guo, Lihua Lyu, Ruihui Gan, Yongping Zheng, Hyoyoung Lee, Xiaodong Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.70048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Perspective On Materials, Electrochemistry, and Cell Concepts for Redox&#8208;Mediated CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Direct Air Capture Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ceur.202500236</link>
      <description>Tilmann J. Neubert, Martin Oschatz, ChemistryEurope. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414128369

                Anthropogenic emissions of previously sequestered carbon continue to disrupt the natural carbon cycle, driving atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) concentrations beyond 420 ppm. This has resulted in global temperatures rising beyond 1.5 &#176;C above the pre&#8208;industrial level. Direct air capture (DAC) of CO 2 has emerged as a complementary mitigation strategy. However, current DAC technologies are limited by the high energy requirements inherent to the thermal release of captured CO 2 , which are caused by the low thermodynamic efficiency of heat&#8208;driven processes, as constrained by Carnot principles. Redox&#8208;mediated electrochemical carbon capture (RMECC) offers a promising pathway to overcome these limitations. RMECC with DAC application remains in an early developmental stage and requires further optimization to enable energy&#8208;efficient, cost&#8208;effective, and scalable deployment. In this perspective the design of sorbents, electrolytes, and electrochemical cell configurations in the field of RMECC are discussed with an emphasis on sustainable approaches for the demands of DAC applications. The challenges arising from the atmospheric dilution of CO 2 within the more abundant and disruptive competitor oxygen are highlighted as a critical factor influencing sorbent performance. Recent advancements in RMECC are reviewed, key challenges are identified, and future directions are outlined to accelerate electrochemically mediated DAC towards practical implementation.</description>
      <author>Tilmann J. Neubert, Martin Oschatz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ceur.202500236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SurFF: a foundation model for surface exposure and morphology across intermetallic crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00839-0</link>
      <description>Jun Yin, Honghao Chen, Ju Qiu, Wentao Li, Peng He, Jiali Li, Iftekhar A. Karimi, Xiaocheng Lan, Tiefeng Wang, Xiaonan Wang, Nature Computational Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414083590

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Yin, Honghao Chen, Ju Qiu, Wentao Li, Peng He, Jiali Li, Iftekhar A. Karimi, Xiaocheng Lan, Tiefeng Wang, Xiaonan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00839-0</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
