<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 01:36:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Direct seawater electrolysis: Breaking the dependency on noble metal-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.387</link>
      <description>Mi Gyoung Lee&#8236;, Seoungyeon Kim, Yong-Kul Lee, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409790242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mi Gyoung Lee&#8236;, Seoungyeon Kim, Yong-Kul Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourteen-Membered Macrocyclic Cobalt Complex Structure as a Potential Basis for Durable and Active Non-platinum Group Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c01306</link>
      <description>Zhiqing Feng, Junya Ohyama, Soutaro Honda, Yasushi Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Masato Machida, Masayuki Tsushida, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Makoto Moriya, Yuta Nabae, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409791038

                Non-platinum group metal catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under acidic conditions were developed using a CoN4 complex with a 14-membered-ring hexaazamacrocyclic ligand (Co-14MR). The carbon-supported Co-14MR catalyst (Co-14MR/C) showed higher ORR and HER activities than a conventional carbon-supported 16-membered-ring Co phthalocyanine (CoPc/C) catalyst. Heat treatment of Co-14MR/C at 600 &#176;C further enhanced its ORR and HER activity through structural modification of the Co active center via deprotonation of ligand amine groups. Density functional theory calculations indicated that the structural modifications of Co-14MR induced by heat treatment adjusted the adsorption energies of important intermediates in the ORR and HER toward optimal values, resulting in enhanced catalytic activity. The Co-14MR/C catalysts also exhibited higher durability in the ORR and HER than CoPc/C and Fe-14MR/C catalysts. Structural analysis suggested that the short Co-N bond lengths and small distortion of the CoN4 active site of the Co-14MR catalysts are the reasons for their high durability. These findings suggest that the Co-14MR structure is a promising design for non-platinum group metal catalysts for proton-exchange membrane fuel cells and water splitting.</description>
      <author>Zhiqing Feng, Junya Ohyama, Soutaro Honda, Yasushi Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Masato Machida, Masayuki Tsushida, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Makoto Moriya, Yuta Nabae</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c01306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating the screening of catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction in graphene materials based on DFT calculations and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115152</link>
      <description>Zikai Xiong, Shengjun Huo, Wanglai Cen, Jikun Feng, Jia&#8208;Hao Zeng, Meiling Hou, Yu Liu, Molecular Catalysis. 581(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409793550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zikai Xiong, Shengjun Huo, Wanglai Cen, Jikun Feng, Jia&#8208;Hao Zeng, Meiling Hou, Yu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser Irradiated Noble Metal&#8208;Free High Entropy Oxide 2&#8208;D Sheets for Highly Efficient Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202507930</link>
      <description>H. Denny Kamaruddin, Jianghong Zhang, Yu Lu, Mingzhen Xiu, Yuefan Wei, Yizhong Huang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409810275

                Abstract High entropy oxides (HEOs) have recently emerged as excellent alternative catalysts that can potentially replace noble metal catalysts such as RuO 2 and IrO 2 for water splitting applications. However, existing methods of synthesizing these catalysts are often tedious. In this work, a straightforward method is proposed using ultra&#8208;fast laser irradiation to synthesize heavily wrinkled noble metal&#8208;free (CoCuFeMnNi) 3 O 4 HEO 2&#8208;D sheets on nickel foam for excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. These sheets facilitate the OER at a low overpotential of only 245 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and is stable after 100 h of testing. This performance outmatches the majority of recently reported noble and noble metal&#8208;free HEA and HEO catalysts. As an anode in anion exchange water electrolyzer (AEMWE), a remarkably high current density of 1.722 A cm &#8722;2 is achieved at 2.0 V with negligible catalyst deterioration despite 70 h of testing. This result outranks the majority of other state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art AEMWE catalysts reported today. This work proves that laser irradiation synthesis enables the synthesis of efficient HEO catalysts, and is a pioneer synthesis of HEO 2&#8208;D interconnected sheets using laser irradiation. Crucially, this work proves that noble&#8208;metal free HEOs are highly efficient and durable catalysts in industrial AEMWE devices.</description>
      <author>H. Denny Kamaruddin, Jianghong Zhang, Yu Lu, Mingzhen Xiu, Yuefan Wei, Yizhong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202507930</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Single-Atom Catalysis for Hydrogen Evolution and Storage: A DFT Insight into First-Row Transition Metal-Porphyrin Complexes (Porph@TMs)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgsce.2025.205646</link>
      <description>Faheem Abbas, Saleem Nawaz Khan, Sadaf Bibi, Muhammad Yousaf, Francis M. Enujekwu, Muhammad Salman Khan, Sami Ullah, Mohammed A. Assiri, Gas Science and Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409828949

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faheem Abbas, Saleem Nawaz Khan, Sadaf Bibi, Muhammad Yousaf, Francis M. Enujekwu, Muhammad Salman Khan, Sami Ullah, Mohammed A. Assiri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgsce.2025.205646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Fe&#8208;Modulating Raney&#8208;Ni Electrodes toward High&#8208;Efficient and Durable AEM Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202501634</link>
      <description>Tao Jiang, Xinge Jiang, Chongyang Jiang, Jian Wang, Yoann Danlos, Taikai Liu, Chunming Deng, Chaoyue Chen, Hanlin Liao, Vasileios Kyriakou, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409832059

                Abstract Anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolysis holds promise for green hydrogen production. One of the main challenges is the preparation of highly efficient electrodes with scalable techniques. Herein, a novel Fe&#8208;modulating Raney&#8208;Ni electrode (NFA&#8208;CA) is developed through atmospheric plasma spraying and chemical etching techniques. The resulting electrode demonstrates high bifunctional catalytic activities with low overpotentials and Tafel slopes (HER: 27 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , 20 mV dec &#8722;1 ; OER: 169 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , 49 mV dec &#8722;1 ), competing for precious&#8208;metal catalysts and leading transition&#8208;metal&#8208;based compounds reported in the literature. Moreover, the corresponding AEM electrolyzer only requires 1.56 V to drive 1 A cm &#8722;2 and exceptional durability for 1000 h. Moreover, the AEM cell can reach 2 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.79 V, exceeding the United States Department of Energy target for AWE systems (2 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.80 V). The highly efficient and durable performance is attributed to the NiFe nanocrystals (core)&#8208;NiFe hydroxide (shell) nanostructures created by the treatment. This structure not only facilitates superior electrocatalytic properties but it is also maintained after 1000 h of continuous operation. It is consider that the present approach can offer an attractive route for scalable fabrication of NiFe&#8208;based electrodes for industrial AEM water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Tao Jiang, Xinge Jiang, Chongyang Jiang, Jian Wang, Yoann Danlos, Taikai Liu, Chunming Deng, Chaoyue Chen, Hanlin Liao, Vasileios Kyriakou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202501634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyoxometalated metal-organic framework superstructure for stable water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.ads1466</link>
      <description>Kaihang Yue, Ruihu Lu, Mingbin Gao, Fei Song, Yao Dai, Chenfeng Xia, Bingbao Mei, Hongliang Dong, Ruijuan Qi, Daliang Zhang, Jiangwei Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Fuqiang Huang, Bao Yu Xia, Ya Yan, Science. 388(6745)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409833855

                Stable, nonprecious catalysts are vital for large-scale alkaline water electrolysis. Here, we report a grafted superstructure, MOF@POM, formed by self-assembling a metal-organic framework (MOF) with polyoxometalate (POM). In situ electrochemical transformation converts MOF into active metal (oxy)hydroxides to produce a catalyst with a low overpotential of 178 millivolts at 10 milliamperes per square centimeter in alkaline electrolyte. An anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer incorporating this catalyst achieves 3 amperes per square centimeter at 1.78 volts at 80&#176;C and stable operation at 2 amperes per square centimeter for 5140 hours at room temperature. In situ electrochemical spectroscopy and theoretical studies reveal that the synergistic interactions between metal atoms create a fast electron-transfer channel from catalytic iron and cobalt sites, nickel, and tungsten in the polyoxometalate to the electrode, stabilizing the metal sites and preventing dissolution.</description>
      <author>Kaihang Yue, Ruihu Lu, Mingbin Gao, Fei Song, Yao Dai, Chenfeng Xia, Bingbao Mei, Hongliang Dong, Ruijuan Qi, Daliang Zhang, Jiangwei Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Fuqiang Huang, Bao Yu Xia, Ya Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.ads1466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomalous Diffusion of Metal Atoms on Oxide Surfaces: A Machine Learning Molecular Dynamics Study of Pt&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08512</link>
      <description>U. Saleem, Shaama Mallikarjun Sharada, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409835024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>U. Saleem, Shaama Mallikarjun Sharada</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering dynamic structural modulation of exogenous Fe3+ integrated into Ni-based anode toward oxygen electrocatalysis for rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111071</link>
      <description>Jingyi Han, Changmin Hou, Shihui Jiao, Xiaodi Niu, Lina Li, Jingqi Guan, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409841602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingyi Han, Changmin Hou, Shihui Jiao, Xiaodi Niu, Lina Li, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of Oxygen Evolution Performance of water splitting at High Current Density by Novel Electrodeposited NiFe-LDH Coatings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146332</link>
      <description>Sim&#243;n G. Quiroz, Santiago Cartagena, Jorge A. Calder&#243;n, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409846753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sim&#243;n G. Quiroz, Santiago Cartagena, Jorge A. Calder&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles investigation of grain boundary effects on fluorine-induced initial corrosion of NiCr alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113903</link>
      <description>Hamdy Arkoub, Miaomiao Jin, Computational Materials Science. 255(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409846985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hamdy Arkoub, Miaomiao Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single &#8211; atom Fe/N-embedded graphdiyne as catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction: A DFT approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.136</link>
      <description>Tung Pham, Minh T&#226;m L&#234;, Minh Thi Hong Le, Hoang Anh Nguyen, Hengquan Guo, Seung Geol Lee, Hsueh&#8208;Shih Chen, Nguyet N. T. Pham, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409850235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tung Pham, Minh T&#226;m L&#234;, Minh Thi Hong Le, Hoang Anh Nguyen, Hengquan Guo, Seung Geol Lee, Hsueh&#8208;Shih Chen, Nguyet N. T. Pham</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and performance evaluation of HfS2/AlSe heterostructure for enhanced photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.344</link>
      <description>Lijun He, Cheng Mi, Qijun Huang, Liyan Wang, Kang Ma, Liang She, Mi Yu, Yong Qin, Ping Yang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409850380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lijun He, Cheng Mi, Qijun Huang, Liyan Wang, Kang Ma, Liang She, Mi Yu, Yong Qin, Ping Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.04.344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicted Cyclic Voltammetry Simulations on Iridium Oxide Surfaces with Comparisons To Experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02093-0</link>
      <description>Soonho Kwon, William A. Goddard, Topics in Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409856607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soonho Kwon, William A. Goddard</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02093-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant-Induced Hexagonal to Orthorhombic Phase Transition in Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;P Nanorods and Its Influence on the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03479</link>
      <description>Jordon Baker, Danyang Wang, Md. Kawsar Alam, Ka Un Lao, Indika U. Arachchige, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409867737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jordon Baker, Danyang Wang, Md. Kawsar Alam, Ka Un Lao, Indika U. Arachchige</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Penta-SiAsP Monolayer: A Highly Stable Pentagonal Ternary Material with Photocatalytic Potential for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-025-05015-7</link>
      <description>Chenghao Yang, Yanqing Shen, Kexin Wang, Xiangqian Jiang, Long Pang, E Peng, Zhongxiang Zhou, Catalysis Letters. 155(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409868693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenghao Yang, Yanqing Shen, Kexin Wang, Xiangqian Jiang, Long Pang, E Peng, Zhongxiang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-025-05015-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Defluorination Mechanism of Sodium Fluoro-Aluminates on Graphite: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c00956</link>
      <description>Min Tan, Jingjing Yan, Si Chung Chang, Hui He, Tao Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409870458

                The graphitized carbon blocks are used as cathode and anode materials on modern aluminum electrolyzers, which provide a reaction interface between molten salts and a graphitized cathode for the electrochemical reaction. The first-principle calculations were performed to clarify the defluorination mechanism of fluoro-aluminates on graphite cathodes in aluminum electrolysis for energy efficiency and carbon emission reduction. The adsorption behaviors of intermediates involved in defluorination reactions on graphite surfaces are analyzed, revealing their spontaneous adsorption based on their adsorption energies and charge density differences. Furthermore, the defluorination pathways of both single Na3AlF6 clusters and fluoride-aluminate polymers are elucidated. Notably, Na3AlF6, after undergoing the thermochemical defluorination process to obtain AlF3, preferentially undergoes electrochemical defluorination via Al-F-Al polymerization. The key findings indicate that the chemical defluorination of Na3AlF6 leading to NaAlF4 serves as a pivotal step, facilitating the overall defluorination process and enhancing the aluminum production efficiency. This work provides fundamental insights into optimizing aluminum electrolysis processes.</description>
      <author>Min Tan, Jingjing Yan, Si Chung Chang, Hui He, Tao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c00956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protons Accumulate at the Graphene&#8211;Water Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c02053</link>
      <description>Xavier R. Advincula, Kara D. Fong, Angelos Michaelides, Christoph Schran, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409871406

                Water's ability to autoionize into hydroxide and hydronium ions profoundly influences surface properties, rendering interfaces either basic or acidic. While it is well-established that protons show an affinity to the air-water interface, a critical knowledge gap exists in technologically relevant surfaces like the graphene-water interface. Here we use machine learning-based simulations with first-principles accuracy to unravel the behavior of hydroxide and hydronium ions at the graphene-water interface. Our findings reveal that protons accumulate at the graphene-water interface, with the hydronium ion predominantly residing in the first contact layer of water. In contrast, the hydroxide ion exhibits a bimodal distribution, found both near the surface and further away from it. Analysis of the underlying electronic structure reveals local polarization effects, resulting in counterintuitive charge rearrangement. Proton propensity to the graphene-water interface challenges the interpretation of surface experiments and is expected to have far-reaching consequences for ion conductivity, interfacial reactivity, and proton-mediated processes.</description>
      <author>Xavier R. Advincula, Kara D. Fong, Angelos Michaelides, Christoph Schran</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c02053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational High-Throughput Screening of High-Performance Transition Metal C8n8 Single-Atom Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5234301</link>
      <description>Keyuan Chen, X.L. Zhang, Li Ma, Yongzhi Wu, Haijin Li, Jueyi Ye, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Zhaohua Liu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409875350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Keyuan Chen, X.L. Zhang, Li Ma, Yongzhi Wu, Haijin Li, Jueyi Ye, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Zhaohua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5234301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation the Coordination of Fe-Co Diatomic Sites with Boron Atom for Fuel Cells and Zn-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5233860</link>
      <description>Dai Dang, Lin Zhang, Guifa Long, Chao Liu, Wenjun Fan, Jie Zheng, Tiejun Wang, Quanbing Liu, Xiaopeng Han, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409882712

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dai Dang, Lin Zhang, Guifa Long, Chao Liu, Wenjun Fan, Jie Zheng, Tiejun Wang, Quanbing Liu, Xiaopeng Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5233860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting electrocatalysts design combining general thermodynamic evaluation and specific kinetic study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116175</link>
      <description>Lu Han, Jun Long, Huan Li, Hao Li, Jianping Xiao, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409887124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Han, Jun Long, Huan Li, Hao Li, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Size Fits All? Development of the CPOSS209 Data Set of Experimental and Hypothetical Polymorphs for Testing Computational Modeling Methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00255</link>
      <description>Louise S. Price, Matteo Paloni, Matteo Salvalaglio, Sarah L. Price, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409887865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Louise S. Price, Matteo Paloni, Matteo Salvalaglio, Sarah L. Price</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A pH-dependent microkinetic modeling guided synthesis of porous dual-atom catalysts for efficient oxygen reduction in Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ee00215j</link>
      <description>Ting&#8208;Ting Li, Di Zhang, Yun Zhang, Dujuan Yang, Runxin Li, Fuyun Yu, Kengqiang Zhong, Xiaozhi Su, Tian&#8208;Wei Song, Long Jiao, Hai&#8208;Long Jiang, Guo&#8208;Ping Sheng, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Zhenyu Wu, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409889319

                Guided by the pH-field microkinetic model, we developed an porous Fe 1 Co 1 &#8211;N&#8211;C ORR catalyst, which exhibited excellent performance in zinc&#8211;air batteries and provided insights for advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ting&#8208;Ting Li, Di Zhang, Yun Zhang, Dujuan Yang, Runxin Li, Fuyun Yu, Kengqiang Zhong, Xiaozhi Su, Tian&#8208;Wei Song, Long Jiao, Hai&#8208;Long Jiang, Guo&#8208;Ping Sheng, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Zhenyu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ee00215j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dissolution: Paths in High-Entropy Alloy Composition Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00057-3</link>
      <description>Mads K. Plenge, Jack K. Pedersen, Luis A. Cipriano, Jan Rossmeisl, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409906731

                Abstract The stability of a nanoparticle catalyst during electrochemical reaction is crucial for its application. Despite increasing interest in multi-metallic alloy nanoparticles, such as high-entropy alloys (HEAs), for electrocatalysis and emerging models for their catalytic activity, there is limited work on frameworks that can predict the metastability of these alloys under reaction conditions, including stability against electrochemical surface dissolution. Incorporating electrochemical stability in multi-objective optimization would advance HEAs as a catalyst discovery platform. To address the knowledge gap on electrochemical stability, we propose a methodology for simulating the dissolution of n-element alloy nanoparticles comprised of density functional theory and machine-learning regression to calculate the dissolution potentials of the surface atoms. We demonstrate the methodology for the Ag&#8211;Au&#8211;Cu&#8211;Ir&#8211;Pd&#8211;Pt&#8211;Rh&#8211;Ru HEA system with the conditions of the oxygen reduction reaction. We investigated trends in stability against dissolution through a compositional grid search for the octo-metallic composition space, uncovering two alloying strategies to increase stability against electrochemical surface dissolution: Alloying with a noble metal or a metal with high relative surface energy. In the simulations, stabilization ensues from forming a protective surface layer, and consequently, the dissolution of persistent alloyed nanoparticles results in core&#8211;shell structures. The model enables tracing the evolution of the surface and dissolved composition during electrochemical dissolution, forming paths of dissolution and revealing unretainable surface compositions. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Mads K. Plenge, Jack K. Pedersen, Luis A. Cipriano, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00057-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing economic viability in carbon capture and storage with enhanced oil recovery projects: A dynamic stochastic approach to CO2 monitoring cost optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cie.2025.111187</link>
      <description>Peng Wu, Shansen Wei, Chengwei Lv, Qiangqiang Ren, Hong Wang, Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409907428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Wu, Shansen Wei, Chengwei Lv, Qiangqiang Ren, Hong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cie.2025.111187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High entropy alloy CoCrFeNiAlMox coatings as cost-effective bifunctional catalysts for enhanced water electrolysis efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163357</link>
      <description>Xiaoran Huo, Yuanwu Zhang, Jinyuan Zhong, Ge Zhou, Xiaojiao Zuo, Nannan Zhang, Xuelu Xu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409911950

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoran Huo, Yuanwu Zhang, Jinyuan Zhong, Ge Zhou, Xiaojiao Zuo, Nannan Zhang, Xuelu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Solution for Modeling Electrocatalysis on Two-Dimensional Single-Atom Catalysts with Grand Canonical DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00199</link>
      <description>Zhen Liu, Yifan Sun, Yinghong Wang, Wei Zhang, Li&#8208;Hua Gan, Xiaohong Liu, Liu&#8208;Bin Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409914615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhen Liu, Yifan Sun, Yinghong Wang, Wei Zhang, Li&#8208;Hua Gan, Xiaohong Liu, Liu&#8208;Bin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sr and Co Co-doping on Thermochemical Energy Storage Properties of CaMnO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00261</link>
      <description>Ruiqing Zhang, Guanyu Li, Shiyi Chen, Wenguo Xiang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409917877

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruiqing Zhang, Guanyu Li, Shiyi Chen, Wenguo Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tribological and micromechanical performance of hard yet tough TiSiN/WN coatings: An experimental analysis of multilayer effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrmhm.2025.107212</link>
      <description>Olga Maksakova, Kateryna Smyrnova, Barbora Ludrovcov&#225;, Miroslav Sahul, Mari&#225;n Har&#353;&#225;ni, Martin Truchl&#253;, Miroslav Sahul, Tom&#225;&#353; Vopat, Matej Pa&#353;&#225;k, A.O. Kozak, A.D. Pogrebnjak, International Journal of Refractory Metals and Hard Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409919530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Olga Maksakova, Kateryna Smyrnova, Barbora Ludrovcov&#225;, Miroslav Sahul, Mari&#225;n Har&#353;&#225;ni, Martin Truchl&#253;, Miroslav Sahul, Tom&#225;&#353; Vopat, Matej Pa&#353;&#225;k, A.O. Kozak, A.D. Pogrebnjak</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrmhm.2025.107212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold-catalyzed construction of atomically rough surfaces towards high-efficiency ethanol electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2025.04.051</link>
      <description>Qing Zeng, Mengyuan Ma, Hui Liu, Lin Xu, Shaonan Tian, Dong Chen, Jing Wang, Jun Yang, Science Bulletin. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409920621

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Zeng, Mengyuan Ma, Hui Liu, Lin Xu, Shaonan Tian, Dong Chen, Jing Wang, Jun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2025.04.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced phosphoric acid tolerance and intrinsic activity of ordered platinum-zinc alloy catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137739</link>
      <description>Hong Zhang, Huanqiao Li, Xiaoming Zhang, Shansheng Yu, Suli Wang, Gongquan Sun, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409922306

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Zhang, Huanqiao Li, Xiaoming Zhang, Shansheng Yu, Suli Wang, Gongquan Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen electrocatalytic enhancement through strong hybridization of active centers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146348</link>
      <description>Xi Chen, Huating Liu, Xiang Qi, Jianxin Zhong, Zongyu Huang, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409922436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xi Chen, Huating Liu, Xiang Qi, Jianxin Zhong, Zongyu Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A grain boundary embrittlement genome for substitutional cubic alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0264543</link>
      <description>Nutth Tuchinda, G. B. Olson, Christopher A. Schuh, Applied Physics Letters. 126(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409933088

                Grain boundary chemistry plays a critical role for the properties of metals and alloys, yet there is a lack of consistent datasets for alloy design and development. With the advent of artificial intelligence and machine learning in materials science, open materials models and datasets can be used to overcome such challenges. Here, we use a universal interatomic potential to compute a grain boundary segregation and embrittlement genome for the &#931;5[001](210) grain boundary for FCC and BCC binary alloys. The grain boundary database calculated here serves as a design tool for the embrittlement of high-angle grain boundaries for alloys across 30 base metals of Ag, Al, Au, Ba, Ca, Ce, Co, Cr, Cs, Cu, Fe (both BCC and FCC), Ir, K, Li, Mo, Na, Nb, Ni, Pb, Pd, Pt, Rb, Rh, Sr, Ta, Ti, V, W, Yb, and Zr with 75 solute elements for each.</description>
      <author>Nutth Tuchinda, G. B. Olson, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0264543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Nickel&#8208;Based Catalysts for Alkaline Water Electrolysis: Comprehensive Review of Current Research Direction for HER and OER Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202500049</link>
      <description>Ivana Perovi&#263;, Stefan Mitrovi&#263;, Sne&#382;ana Brkovi&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409950640

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;based catalysts are among the most promising materials for electrocatalytic water splitting, particularly for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. Their abundance, cost&#8208;effectiveness, and tunable electrochemical properties make them attractive alternatives to precious metal catalysts. This review provides a comprehensive analysis of the advancements in nickel&#8208;based catalysts, including pure nickel, alloys, oxides, hydroxides, and spinels, emphasizing their synthesis methods, structural properties, and electrocatalytic performance. Recent nanostructuring, doping, and hybridization innovations with conductive supports have significantly enhanced catalytic activity, stability, and efficiency. Despite notable progress, challenges remain in improving long&#8208;term durability, minimizing surface degradation, and scaling up production for industrial applications. Addressing these limitations through advanced catalyst design, in situ characterization, and integration with renewable energy sources will be crucial for widely adopting nickel&#8208;based catalysts in sustainable hydrogen production. This review highlights the key developments and future directions in the field, underscoring the role of nickel&#8208;based materials in enabling the hydrogen economy and global decarbonization efforts.</description>
      <author>Ivana Perovi&#263;, Stefan Mitrovi&#263;, Sne&#382;ana Brkovi&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202500049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into the Activation and Conversion of Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on 3&lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt; Transition Metal&#8208;Doped Cu(111) Stepped Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500095</link>
      <description>Lihong Yin, Jinxian Feng, Weng Fai Ip, Guangfu Luo, Hui Pan, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409959087

                The activation of CO 2 is essential for efficient electrochemical conversion, yet its weak physisorption on pristine Cu surfaces severely hinders catalytic performance. To overcome this limitation, we designed Cu stepped structures to create highly reactive sites for enhanced CO 2 adsorption and further doped the edges with 3 d transition metals (V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, and Ni) to improve CO 2 reduction. Density functional theory calculations reveal that these dopants significantly reduce the O&#63743;C&#63743;O angles and elongate the C&#63743;O bonds, transforming CO 2 from its original linear configuration into a bent geometry at the interface. Notably, dual&#8208;V and dual&#8208;Fe doping on Cu stepped surfaces demonstrates a strong interaction with CO 2 , leading to a high degree of activation. The computational results demonstrate that these modifications significantly enhance CO 2 activation and favor methane generation. This study provides valuable insights into the design of advanced Cu&#8208;based electrocatalysts for efficient and selective CO 2 activation, offering a pathway toward sustainable CO 2 utilization.</description>
      <author>Lihong Yin, Jinxian Feng, Weng Fai Ip, Guangfu Luo, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internal hydrogen-bond enhanced two-electron oxygen reduction reaction for &#960;-d conjugated metal-organic framework to H2O2 synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58628-2</link>
      <description>Zhiyuan Sang, Yuqian Qiao, Rui Chen, Lichang Yin, Feng Hou, Ji Liang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409965445

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyuan Sang, Yuqian Qiao, Rui Chen, Lichang Yin, Feng Hou, Ji Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58628-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni Foam Supported Pd&#8208;Doped Zinc Spinel Oxide Nano&#8208;Electrocatalyst for Efficient Hydrogen Production Supported by DFT Study as Well Validated With Experimental Data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500142</link>
      <description>Refah S. Alkhaldi, M. Abdulwahab, M.A. Gondal, Mohamed Jaffer Sadiq Mohamed, M.A. Almessiere, A. Baykal, Abduljabar Q. Alsayoud, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409966799

                Abstract An innovative palladium&#8208;doped zinc cobalt oxide nanoelectrocatalyst, ZnPd x Co 2&#8208;x O 4 (0.00 &#8804; x &#8804; 0.08)@NF, is successfully synthesized using a hydrothermal method. The resulting material exhibits a spinel oxide phase, as confirmed by X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD). The electrocatalytic performance of ZnPd x Co 2&#8208;x O 4 (0.00 &#8804; x &#8804; 0.08)@NF is evaluated for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The results show significant improvements in efficient hydrogen production, with an overpotential of 31 mV, a Tafel slope of 54.36 mV dec&#8315; 1 , and sustained stability for over 72 h, using chronopotentiometry methods. Doping with 8.0% Pd concentration enhances the highest electrochemical performance of the nanoelectrocatalyst, supporting the idea that Pd doping improves HER activity. The results suggest that the increased electrochemical active surface area (ECSA) and faster charge transfer kinetics at the interface between the semiconductor and electrolyte contribute to enhanced performance. The DFT calculations performed in this work confirm the role of Pd in improving the catalytic activity of the ZnCo 2 O 4 spinel catalyst. Overall, this study has made a significant contribution to the development of sustainable energy solutions, offering a promising path toward the efficient production of hydrogen fuel.</description>
      <author>Refah S. Alkhaldi, M. Abdulwahab, M.A. Gondal, Mohamed Jaffer Sadiq Mohamed, M.A. Almessiere, A. Baykal, Abduljabar Q. Alsayoud</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A mini review on revolutionizing hydrogenation catalysis: unleashing transformative power of artificial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06376-x</link>
      <description>Anurag Mishra, Vikesh G. Lade, Jyoti Ramesh Barmar, Ankush B. Bindwal, Ramesh P. Birmod, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 31(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409968805

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anurag Mishra, Vikesh G. Lade, Jyoti Ramesh Barmar, Ankush B. Bindwal, Ramesh P. Birmod</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06376-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Electric Fields and Strain Modulated Photocatalytic Performance in Monolayer Janus Piezoelectric AlBX2(X = O/S/Se/Te)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417339</link>
      <description>Hao An, Zhiyang Yuan, Chun-Sheng Liu, Lan Meng, Wei Yan, Xiaohong Yan, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409978877

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao An, Zhiyang Yuan, Chun-Sheng Liu, Lan Meng, Wei Yan, Xiaohong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand Engineering of Co&#8208;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for Highly&#8208;Active and Stable Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202502230</link>
      <description>Taewon Jeong, Ki-Won Kim, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Chang Hyuck Choi, Joonhee Kang, Myeongjin Kim, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409983570

                The development of stable and efficient single-atom catalysts (SACs) for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media remains challenging. This work reports a novel NH3-assisted pyrolysis strategy to synthesize Co-N4 SACs with controlled nitrogen coordination environments on crumpled graphene supports. The pyrrolic N4-coordinated Co sites demonstrate superior OER activity compared to their pyridinic counterparts, achieving an overpotential of 351 mV at 10 mA cm-2 in 0.5 m H2SO4. Combined density functional theory calculations and operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy reveal that the pyrrolic coordination environment facilitates enhanced OH- adsorption and subsequent OER kinetics due to its unique electronic structure and geometric flexibility. A multi-layered protective mechanism in the pyrrolic system enables exceptional stability during long-term acidic OER operation, stemming from higher defect formation energy of Co sites and strategic distribution of sacrificial nitrogen species in the graphene network. These findings provide fundamental insights into designing stable single-atom catalysts for challenging electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Taewon Jeong, Ki-Won Kim, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Chang Hyuck Choi, Joonhee Kang, Myeongjin Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202502230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Electrostatic Shielding Effect by 18-Crown-6 Ether for Achieving Stable Deposition of Potassium Metal Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00797</link>
      <description>Hyokyeong Kang, Hyeona Park, Josef Rizell, Aleksandar Matic, Shizhao Xiong, Dong&#8208;Kyu Kim, Hyeyoung Shin, Yangyang Liu, Xieyu Xu, Yang&#8208;Kook Sun, Jang&#8208;Yeon Hwang, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409983816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyokyeong Kang, Hyeona Park, Josef Rizell, Aleksandar Matic, Shizhao Xiong, Dong&#8208;Kyu Kim, Hyeyoung Shin, Yangyang Liu, Xieyu Xu, Yang&#8208;Kook Sun, Jang&#8208;Yeon Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realizing Direct Hot-Electron Transfer from Metal Nanoparticles to Per- and Polyfluoroalkyl Substances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00373</link>
      <description>P. K. Verma, Samir Kumar Nayak, Khushboo Bhardwaj, Sharma S. R. K. C. Yamijala, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409984514

                Per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) are a group of forever synthetic chemicals. They are widely utilized in industries and household appliances because of their remarkable stability and distinctive oil- and water-repellent properties. Despite their broad applications, unfortunately, PFAS are hazardous to all forms of life, including humans. In recent years, the environmental persistence of PFAS has raised significant interest in degrading these substances. However, the strong C-F bonds in these chemicals pose several challenges to their degradation. Plasmons of noble metal nanoparticles (NPs) offer many exciting applications, including photocatalytic reactions. However, an atomistic understanding of plasmon-driven processes remains elusive. In this work, using the real-time time-dependent density functional theory, we have studied the real-time formation of plasmons, hot-carrier generation, and subsequent direct hot-carrier transfer from metal NPs to the PFAS. Our simulations show that there is an apparent direct hot-electron transfer from NPs to PFAS. Moreover, using Ehrenfest dynamics simulations, we demonstrated that the transferred hot electrons can efficiently degrade PFAS without requiring any external thermal bath. Thus, our work provides an atomistic picture of plasmon-induced direct hot-carrier transfer from NPs to PFAS and the efficient degradation of PFAS. We strongly believe that this work generates the impetus to utilize plasmonic NPs to mitigate PFAS.</description>
      <author>P. K. Verma, Samir Kumar Nayak, Khushboo Bhardwaj, Sharma S. R. K. C. Yamijala</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAGNet: better electron density prediction for LCAO-based data and drug-like substances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s13321-025-01010-7</link>
      <description>Konstantin Ushenin, Kuzma Khrabrov, Artem Tsypin, Anton Ber, Egor Rumiantsev, Artur Kadurin, Journal of Cheminformatics. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409922207

                The electron density is an important object in quantum chemistry that is crucial for many downstream tasks in drug design. Recent deep learning approaches predict the electron density around a molecule from atom types and atom positions. Most of these methods use the plane wave (PW) numerical method as a source of ground-truth training data. However, the drug design field mostly uses the Linear Combination of Atomic Orbitals (LCAO) for computation of quantum properties. In this study, we focus on prediction of the electron density for drug-like substances and training neural networks with LCAO-based datasets. Our experiments show that proper handling of large amplitudes of core orbitals is crucial for training on LCAO-based data. We propose to store the electron density with the standard grids instead of the uniform grid. This allowed us to reduce the number of probing points per molecule by 43 times and reduce storage space requirements by 8 times. Finally, we propose a novel architecture based on the DeepDFT model that we name LAGNet. It is specifically designed and tuned for drug-like substances and &#8711;2 DFT dataset.</description>
      <author>Konstantin Ushenin, Kuzma Khrabrov, Artem Tsypin, Anton Ber, Egor Rumiantsev, Artur Kadurin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s13321-025-01010-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evolving role of programming and LLMs in the development of self-driving laboratories</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0266757</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, APL Machine Learning. 3(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409962774

                Machine learning and automation are transforming scientific research, yet the implementation of self-driving laboratories (SDLs) remains costly and complex, and it remains difficult to learn how to use these facilities. To address this, we introduce Claude-Light, a lightweight, remotely accessible instrument designed for prototyping automation algorithms and machine learning workflows. Claude-Light integrates a REST API, a Raspberry Pi-based control system, and an RGB LED with a photometer that measures ten spectral outputs, providing a controlled but realistic experimental environment. This device enables users to explore automation at multiple levels, from basic programming and experimental design to machine learning-driven optimization. We demonstrate the application of Claude-Light in structured automation approaches, including traditional scripting, statistical design of experiments, and active learning methods. In addition, we explore the role of large language models (LLMs) in laboratory automation, highlighting their use in instrument selection, structured data extraction, function calling, and code generation. While LLMs present new opportunities for streamlining automation, they also introduce challenges related to reproducibility, security, and reliability. We discuss strategies to mitigate these risks while leveraging LLMs for enhanced efficiency in self-driving laboratories. Claude-Light provides a practical and accessible platform for students and researchers to develop automation skills and test algorithms before deploying them in larger-scale SDLs. By lowering the barrier to entry for automation in scientific research, this tool facilitates broader adoption of AI-driven experimentation and fosters innovation in autonomous laboratories.</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0266757</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
