<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 01:28:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>The Chemistry of Bimetallic Surfaces - Evolution of an Atomic-scale Picture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122677</link>
      <description>R. J&#252;rgen Behm, Axel Gro&#223;, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404948122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. J&#252;rgen Behm, Axel Gro&#223;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-induced interface engineering of NiCu/Ni3N heterostructures for enhanced alkaline hydrogen oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60142-7</link>
      <description>Jinchi Li, Wanhai Zhou, Shuqi Yu, Qing Chen, Jian He, Liang Zeng, Yao Wang, Yungui Chen, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 67(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404950295

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinchi Li, Wanhai Zhou, Shuqi Yu, Qing Chen, Jian He, Liang Zeng, Yao Wang, Yungui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60142-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction mechanism on platinum dioxide surfaces based on density functional theory calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115020</link>
      <description>Xiru Cao, Zhibin Tan, Ji Chen, Changwei Pan, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. 1244(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404958222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiru Cao, Zhibin Tan, Ji Chen, Changwei Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping and characterization of the surface structure and electronic properties of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e678" altimg="si103.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;&#946;&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-Ag&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e683" altimg="si104.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;MoO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e691" &#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105530</link>
      <description>Thiago T. Dorini, Felipe Lipsky, Andr&#233; Rodrigues, Ju&#225;n Andr&#233;s, E. Longo, Miguel A. San&#8208;Miguel, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404958629

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thiago T. Dorini, Felipe Lipsky, Andr&#233; Rodrigues, Ju&#225;n Andr&#233;s, E. Longo, Miguel A. San&#8208;Miguel</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-free nitrogen-doped carbon-based electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction in microbial fuel cells: Advances, challenges, and future directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110537</link>
      <description>Seyed Masoud Parsa, Zhijie Chen, Siran Feng, Yuanying Yang, Li Luo, Huu Hao Ngo, Wei Wei, Bing&#8208;Jie Ni, Wenshan Guo, Nano Energy. 134(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404958697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seyed Masoud Parsa, Zhijie Chen, Siran Feng, Yuanying Yang, Li Luo, Huu Hao Ngo, Wei Wei, Bing&#8208;Jie Ni, Wenshan Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Applications of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage in Civil Engineering: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236046</link>
      <description>D. S. Vijayan, Selvakumar Gopalaswamy, Arvindan Sivasuriyan, Eugeniusz Koda, Wiktor Sitek, Magdalena Daria Vaverkov&#225;, Anna Podlasek, Energies. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404960467

                This paper thoroughly examines the latest developments and diverse applications of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage (CCUS) in civil engineering. It provides a critical analysis of the technology&#8217;s potential to mitigate the effects of climate change. Initially, a comprehensive outline of CCUS technologies is presented, emphasising their vital function in carbon dioxide (CO2) emission capture, conversion, and sequestration. Subsequent sections provide an in-depth analysis of carbon capture technologies, utilisation processes, and storage solutions. These serve as the foundation for an architectural framework that facilitates the design and integration of efficient systems. Significant attention is given to the inventive application of CCUS in the building and construction industry. Notable examples of such applications include using carbon (C) in cement and promoting sustainable cement production. Economic analyses and financing mechanisms are reviewed to assess the commercial feasibility and scalability of CCUS projects. In addition, this review examines the technological advances and innovations that have occurred, providing insight into the potential future course of CCUS progress. A comprehensive analysis of the environmental and regulatory environments is conducted to evaluate the feasibility and compliance with the policies of CCUS technology deployment. Case studies from the real world are provided to illustrate effectiveness and practical applications. It concludes by emphasising the importance of continued research, policy support, and innovation in developing CCUS technologies as a fundamental component of sustainable civil engineering practices. A tenacious stride toward carbon neutrality is underscored.</description>
      <author>D. S. Vijayan, Selvakumar Gopalaswamy, Arvindan Sivasuriyan, Eugeniusz Koda, Wiktor Sitek, Magdalena Daria Vaverkov&#225;, Anna Podlasek</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17236046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of ligand chain length on the HER performance of atomically precise Pt&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;(SR)&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03316g</link>
      <description>Lipipuspa Sahoo, Supriti Dutta, Aarti Devi, Rashi, Swapan K. Pati, Amitava Patra, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404962276

                This study investigates the impact of ligand chain length on the electrocatalytic HER performance of atomically precise Pt 6 (thiolate ligand, SR) 12 nanoclusters. Analysis reveals that a shorter ligand chain enhances the electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Lipipuspa Sahoo, Supriti Dutta, Aarti Devi, Rashi, Swapan K. Pati, Amitava Patra</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03316g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Evolution of Stapes Controls the Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Bimetallic Cu&#8208;doped Gold Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408531</link>
      <description>Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez&#8208;Al&#233;, Jiajun Hu, Josep Albero, Laura Simonelli, Carlo Marini, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Noelia Barrab&#233;s, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Sara Goberna&#8208;Ferr&#243;n, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404977497

                Abstract Ligand protected gold nanoclusters have been proposed for electrochemical CO 2 reduction (eCO 2 R) as an alternative to polycrystalline catalysts, showing higher selectivity control due to the tailored composition and precise microenvironment. Here, two gold cluster families are studied with different staple motifs (Au 25 (SR) 18 and Au 144 (SR) 60 , where SR = thiolate) doped with Ag or Cu to understand the interplay between the composition and the performance of these catalysts. Detailed cluster characterization and Density Functional Theory simulations demonstrate that the dynamic aspects involving ligand removal are crucial to unraveling the role of the dopant, the cluster curvature, and the staple structure. The best activity performance toward CO is obtained for Cu&#8208;doped Au 144 (SR) 60 at U = &#8211;0.8 V RHE as ligands are only partially depleted and the staple can bend to stabilize *CO intermediate, while Cu&#8208;containing Au 25 (SR) 18 can produce formate but shows worse CO selectivity. This study points toward the importance of ligand stability during eCO 2 R on bimetallic gold nanoclusters, paving the way for improving the design and operation of this family of catalysts.</description>
      <author>Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez&#8208;Al&#233;, Jiajun Hu, Josep Albero, Laura Simonelli, Carlo Marini, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Noelia Barrab&#233;s, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Sara Goberna&#8208;Ferr&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Intrinsic Effects of Lattice Strain on the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction via Electric-Field-Induced Strain in FePt Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16120</link>
      <description>Hong Hong, Dongxue Liu, Bo Yang, Qingqi Cao, Chaoran Liu, Liqian Wu, Dunhui Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404992503

                Strain engineering has the potential to modify the adsorption process and enhance the electrocatalytic activity, especially in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, the introduction of lattice strain in electrocatalysts is often accompanied by a change in chemical composition, surface morphology, or phase structure to a certain extent, impeding the investigation of the intrinsic strain effect on HER. In this work, the FePt film was deposited on a Pb(Mg</description>
      <author>Hong Hong, Dongxue Liu, Bo Yang, Qingqi Cao, Chaoran Liu, Liqian Wu, Dunhui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic N2 Reduction Driven by Mo-Based Double-Atom Catalysts Anchored on Graphdiyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120879</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Chi, Yaqi Cang, Jianhua Wang, Qing Li, Xing Fan, Haiping Lin, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404993416

                An electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR) presents an appealing strategy for ammonia (NH3) production at ambient conditions. Through systematic density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the eNRR performance of 23 double-atom catalysts has been investigated. These catalysts are composed of a Mo atom and a transition metal atom anchored on the graphdiyne (GDY), and they are named MoM-GDYs. Among the 23 MoM-GDYs studied, 14 MoM-GDYs highlighted catalytic selectivity by inhibiting a competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and demonstrated commendable eNRR catalytic performance. MoRu-GDY, MoMo-GDY, MoFe-GDY and MoY-GDY exhibited excellent eNRR catalytic activity with limiting potentials of &#8722;0.05 V, &#8722;0.13 V, &#8722;0.21 V and &#8722;0.24 V, respectively. These 14 catalysts favor N2 adsorption compared to H and exhibit less negative UL than the &#8722;0.98 V benchmark of the stepped Ru(0001) surface. Among them, MoRu-GDY has the best catalytic activity with an UL of &#8722;0.05 V. The excellent catalytic performance originates from the synergistic effect of the dual catalytic sites, where the alternation of the consecutive and enzymatic paths effectively reduces the limiting potentials. In addition, the catalytic activity can be evaluated using &#916;G*NH3 &#8722; &#916;G*NH2 as a theoretical descriptor, while UL and the &#916;G*NH3 &#8722; &#916;G*NH2 fit coefficient R2 reached 0.99. These findings not only contribute to the development of dual-atom electrocatalysts for eNRR but also offer a valuable pathway for identifying new eNRR catalysts with high activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Chi, Yaqi Cang, Jianhua Wang, Qing Li, Xing Fan, Haiping Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using a Single-Atom FeN4 Catalyst on Defective Graphene for the Efficient Reduction of NO to Alanine: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120876</link>
      <description>Yu Tian, Xiaoxi Yuan, Zexuan Guo, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Tingting Zhao, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404994156

                The use of a single-atom FeN4 catalyst on defective graphene (Fe-NC) has recently emerged as an effective method for the synthesis of amino acids. Herein, we investigated the mechanism of alanine formation on FeN4-doped graphene using comprehensive density functional theory (DFT) computations. The alanine formation reaction begins with the activation of NO molecules on the surface, followed by their reaction with hydrogen atoms provided in the system. The computational results show that NO molecules can be effectively activated on Fe-NC, facilitating the subsequent alanine formation at a relatively lower potential. The potential-limiting step in alanine production involves either the formation of HNO* or HNOH* intermediates on Fe-NG, as the free energy changes (&#916;G) in these two elementary steps are nearly equivalent. Notably, the formation of HNO* exhibits a higher activation energy (Ea) compared to HNOH* formation. This study provides valuable insights into the C&#8211;N coupling reaction and the mechanism of amino acid synthesis on single-atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yu Tian, Xiaoxi Yuan, Zexuan Guo, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Tingting Zhao, Zhong&#8208;Min Su</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian optimization of atomic structures with prior probabilities from universal interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.123802</link>
      <description>Peder Lyngby, Casper Larsen, Karsten W. Jacobsen, Physical Review Materials. 8(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404994554

                The optimization of atomic structures plays a pivotal role in understanding and designing materials with desired properties. However, conventional computational methods often struggle with the formidable task of navigating the vast potential energy surface, especially in high-dimensional spaces with numerous local minima. Recent advancements in machine learning-driven surrogate models offer a promising avenue for alleviating this computational burden. In this study, we propose anapproach that combines the strengths of universal machine learning potentials with a Bayesian approach using Gaussian processes. By using the machine learning potentials as priors for the Gaussian process, the Gaussian process has to learn only the difference between the machine learning potential and the target energy surface calculated for example by density functional theory. This turns out to improve the speed by which the global optimal structure is identified across diverse systems for a well-behaved machine learning potential. The approach is tested on periodic bulk materials, surface structures, and a cluster.</description>
      <author>Peder Lyngby, Casper Larsen, Karsten W. Jacobsen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.123802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase transitions of correlated systems from graph neural networks with quantum embedding techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.245111</link>
      <description>Rishi Rao, Li Zhu, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404994847

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rishi Rao, Li Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.245111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>relentless: Transparent, reproducible molecular dynamics simulations for optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0233683</link>
      <description>Adithya N Sreenivasan, C. Levi Petix, Zachary M. Sherman, Michael P. Howard, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405003135

                relentless is an open-source Python package that enables the optimization of objective functions computed using molecular dynamics simulations. It has a high-level, extensible interface for model parameterization; setting up, running, and analyzing simulations natively in established software packages; and gradient-based optimization. We describe the design and implementation of relentless in the context of relative entropy minimization, and we demonstrate its abilities to design pairwise interactions between particles that form targeted structures. relentless aims to streamline the development of computational materials design methodologies and promote the transparency and reproducibility of complex workflows integrating molecular dynamics simulations.</description>
      <author>Adithya N Sreenivasan, C. Levi Petix, Zachary M. Sherman, Michael P. Howard</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0233683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of compositional tuning on Ni-B electrocatalyst for efficient hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118847</link>
      <description>Susmita S. Patil, Aasiya S. Jamadar, Rohit B. Sutar, Reshma V. Khandeker, Tukaram D. Dongale, Jyotiprakash B. Yadav, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405009319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Susmita S. Patil, Aasiya S. Jamadar, Rohit B. Sutar, Reshma V. Khandeker, Tukaram D. Dongale, Jyotiprakash B. Yadav</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive insight into the interfacial adsorption mechanism of pyridine derivatives by molecular dynamics simulations, GFN-xTB and first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105567</link>
      <description>Zhaojing Jiang, Jiashun Duan, Wei Xiong, Chaofang Dong, H.F. Liu, G.A. Zhang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405012661

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaojing Jiang, Jiashun Duan, Wei Xiong, Chaofang Dong, H.F. Liu, G.A. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pH Dependence of Noble Metals Dissolution: Iridium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145450</link>
      <description>Matej Zlatar, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Cornelius Simon, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Kevin Stojanovski, Serhiy Cherevko, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405013272

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matej Zlatar, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Cornelius Simon, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Kevin Stojanovski, Serhiy Cherevko</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black-box optimization technique for investigation of surface phase diagram</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229856</link>
      <description>Makoto Urushihara, Kenji Yamaguchi, Ryo Tamura, AIP Advances. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405016963

                Surface phase diagrams are useful in material design for understanding catalytic reactions and deposition processes and are usually obtained by numerical calculations. However, a large number of calculations are required, and a strategy to reduce the computation time is necessary. In this study, we proposed a black-box optimization strategy to investigate the surface phase diagram with the smallest possible number of calculations. Our method was tested to examine the phase diagram in which two types of adsorbates, i.e., oxygen and carbon monoxide, were adsorbed onto a palladium surface. In comparison with a random calculation without using machine learning, we confirmed that the proposed method obtained a surface phase diagram with a small number of calculations. In conclusion, our strategy is a general-purpose method that can contribute to the rapid study of various types of surface phase diagrams.</description>
      <author>Makoto Urushihara, Kenji Yamaguchi, Ryo Tamura</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling activity-stability paradox of reconstructed NiIrOx electrocatalysts by bridged W-O moiety</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54987-4</link>
      <description>Muhammad Imran Abdullah, Fang Yu-sheng, Xiaobing Wu, Meiqi Hu, Jing Shao, Youkun Tao, Haijiang Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405022664

                One challenge remaining in the development of Ir-based electrocatalyst is the activity-stability paradox during acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), especially for the surface reconstructed IrOx catalyst with high efficiency. To address this, a phase selective Ir-based electrocatalyst is constructed by forming bridged W-O moiety in NiIrOx electrocatalyst. Through an electrochemical dealloying process, an nano-porous structure with surface-hydroxylated rutile NiWIrOx electrocatalyst is engineered via Ni as a sacrificial element. Despite low Ir content, NiWIrOx demonstrates a minimal overpotential of 180 mV for the OER at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2. It maintains a stable 300 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 current density during an approximately 300 h OER at 1.8 VRHE and shows a stability number of 3.9 &#215; 105 noxygen &#183; nIr&#8722;1. The resulting W &#8211; O&#8211;Ir bridging motif proves pivotal for enhancing the efficacy of OER catalysis by facilitating deprotonation of OER intermediates and promoting a thermodynamically favorable dual-site adsorbent evolution mechanism. Besides, the phase selective insertion of W-O in NiIrOx enabling charge balance through the W-O-Ir bridging motif, effectively counteracting lattice oxygen loss by regulating Ir-O co-valency. One challenge remaining in the electrocatalysts for acidic water electrolysis is the activity-stability paradox. Here, the authors report a facile approach to tackle the challenge by introducing a bridged W-O moiety in NiIrOx electrocatalyst, enhancing the efficacy and stability simultaneously.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Imran Abdullah, Fang Yu-sheng, Xiaobing Wu, Meiqi Hu, Jing Shao, Youkun Tao, Haijiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54987-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Properties optimisation of nanostructures via machine learning: Progress and perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enganabound.2024.106063</link>
      <description>Nurul Akmal Che Lah, Engineering Analysis with Boundary Elements. 171(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405023212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nurul Akmal Che Lah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enganabound.2024.106063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a unified pH-performance picture of active sites in nitrogen-doped carbon materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124908</link>
      <description>Peiyao Bai, Lang Xu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405024756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peiyao Bai, Lang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Species mass transfer governs the selectivity of gas diffusion electrodes toward H2O2 electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55091-3</link>
      <description>Lele Cui, &#1041;&#1080;&#1085; &#1063;&#1101;&#1085;, Dongxu Chen, Chen He, Yi Liu, Hongyi Zhang, Jian Qiu, Le Liu, Wenheng Jing, Zhenghua Zhang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405035184

                The meticulous design of advanced electrocatalysts and their integration into gas diffusion electrode (GDE) architectures is emerging as a prominent research paradigm in the H2O2 electrosynthesis community. However, it remains perplexing that electrocatalysts and assembled GDE frequently exhibit substantial discrepancies in H2O2 selectivity during bulk electrolysis. Here, we elucidate the pivotal role of mass transfer behavior of key species (including reactants and products) beyond the intrinsic properties of the electrocatalyst in dictating electrode-scale H2O2 selectivity. This tendency becomes more pronounced in high reaction rate (current density) regimes where transport limitations are intensified. By utilizing diffusion-related parameters (DRP) of GDEs (i.e., wettability and catalyst layer thickness) as probe factors, we employ both short- and long-term electrolysis in conjunction with in-situ electrochemical reflection-absorption imaging and theoretical calculations to thoroughly investigate the impact of DRP and DRP-controlled local microenvironments on O2 and H2O2 mass transfer. The mechanistic origins of diffusion-dependent conversion selectivity at the electrode scale are unveiled accordingly. The fundamental insights gained from this study underscore the necessity of architectural innovations for mainstream hydrophobic GDEs that can synchronously optimize mass transfer of reactants and products, paving the way for next-generation GDEs in gas-consuming electroreduction scenarios. Electrocatalysts and assembled gas diffusion electrodes frequently exhibit discrepancies in selectivity during H2O2 electrosynthesis. Here, the authors report the pivotal role of key species transport beyond the intrinsic properties of electrocatalysts in dictating electrode-scale H2O2 selectivity.</description>
      <author>Lele Cui, &#1041;&#1080;&#1085; &#1063;&#1101;&#1085;, Dongxu Chen, Chen He, Yi Liu, Hongyi Zhang, Jian Qiu, Le Liu, Wenheng Jing, Zhenghua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55091-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Heptazine-Based Graphitic Carbon Nitride Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting by Effectively Assembling Double-Unit Polymers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05801</link>
      <description>Ruilin Guan, Anqi Shi, Xiuyun Zhang, Bing Wang, Yongtao Li, Xianghong Niu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405039581

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruilin Guan, Anqi Shi, Xiuyun Zhang, Bing Wang, Yongtao Li, Xianghong Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanically mixing copper and iron at subnanometric scale for catalyzing hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120630</link>
      <description>Xin-Zhuo Hu, Chuanqi Cheng, Xin Ji, Yi Feng, Zhe Li, Ling-Kun Meng, Wenjing Kang, Hui Liu, Pengfei Yin, Rui Zhang, Lei Cui, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405040387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Zhuo Hu, Chuanqi Cheng, Xin Ji, Yi Feng, Zhe Li, Ling-Kun Meng, Wenjing Kang, Hui Liu, Pengfei Yin, Rui Zhang, Lei Cui, Xi&#8208;Wen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Engineering TiN Surfaces with Single-Atom Catalysts for Targeted Nitrate Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105564</link>
      <description>Guoning Feng, Yujie Sun, Jing Wang, Zhiwei Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjian Sa, Qinye Li, Chenghua Sun, Zuju Ma, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405040708

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoning Feng, Yujie Sun, Jing Wang, Zhiwei Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjian Sa, Qinye Li, Chenghua Sun, Zuju Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional group combination synergistically regulates the selectivity of 2/4e-ORR in carbon catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145484</link>
      <description>Yuhui Wang, Tong Zhang, Yong Huang, Shaonan Gu, Shu Zhang, Zhi Wang, Junhao Liu, Xuzhong Gong, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405046095

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhui Wang, Tong Zhang, Yong Huang, Shaonan Gu, Shu Zhang, Zhi Wang, Junhao Liu, Xuzhong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating CALPHAD-Based Phase Diagram Predictions in Complex Alloys Using Universal Machine Learning Potentials: Opportunities and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5043251</link>
      <description>Siya Zhu, Do&#287;uhan Sar&#305;t&#252;rk, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405057972

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siya Zhu, Do&#287;uhan Sar&#305;t&#252;rk, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5043251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and Simulation of Electric&#8211;Hydrogen Coupled Integrated Energy System Considering the Integration of Wind&#8211;PV&#8211;Diesel&#8211;Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/modelling5040101</link>
      <description>Shuguang Zhao, Yuqiang Han, Qicheng Xu, Ziping Wang, Yinghao Shan, Modelling&#8212;International Open Access Journal of Modelling in Engineering Science. 5(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405071782

                Hydrogen energy plays an increasingly vital role in global energy transformation. However, existing electric&#8211;hydrogen coupled integrated energy systems (IESs) face two main challenges: achieving stable operation when integrated with large-scale networks and integrating optimal dispatching code with physical systems. This paper conducted comprehensive modeling, optimization and joint simulation verification of the above IES. Firstly, a low-carbon economic dispatching model of an electric&#8211;hydrogen coupled IES considering carbon capture power plants is established at the optimization layer. Secondly, by organizing and selecting representative data in the optimal dispatch model, an electric&#8211;hydrogen coupled IES planning model considering the integration of wind, photovoltaic (PV), diesel and storage is constructed at the physical layer. The proposed electric&#8211;hydrogen coupling model mainly consists of the following components: an alkaline electrolyzer, a high-pressure hydrogen storage tank with a compressor and a proton exchange membrane fuel cell. The IES model proposed in this paper achieved the integration of optimal dispatching mode with physical systems. The system can maintain stable control and operation despite unpredictable changes in renewable energy sources, showing strong resilience and reliability. This electric&#8211;hydrogen coupling model also can integrate with large-scale IES for stable joint operation, enhancing renewable energy utilization and absorption of PV and wind power. Co-simulation verification showed that the optimized model has achieved a 29.42% reduction in total system cost and an 83.66% decrease in carbon emissions. Meanwhile, the simulation model proved that the system&#8217;s total harmonic distortion rate is controlled below 3% in both grid-connected and islanded modes, indicating good power quality.</description>
      <author>Shuguang Zhao, Yuqiang Han, Qicheng Xu, Ziping Wang, Yinghao Shan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/modelling5040101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-Independent Correlations for Site-Specific Binding Energies of Relevant Catalytic Intermediates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00759</link>
      <description>Shyama Charan Mandal, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405075971

                Establishing energy correlations among different metals can accelerate the discovery of efficient and cost-effective catalysts for complex reactions. Using a recently introduced coordination-based model, we can predict site-specific metal binding energies (&#916;EM) that can be used as a descriptor for chemical reactions. In this study, we have examined a range of metals including Ag, Au, Co, Cu, Ir, Ni, Os, Pd, Pt, Rh, and Ru and found linear correlations between predicted &#916;EM and adsorption energies of CH and O (&#916;ECH and &#916;EO) at various coordination environments for all the considered metals. Interestingly, all the metals correlate with one another under specific surface site coordination, indicating that different metals are interrelated in a particular coordination environment. Furthermore, we have tested and verified for PtPd- and PtIr-based alloys that they follow a similar behavior. Moreover, we have expanded the metal space by taking some early transition metals along with a few s-block metals and shown a cyclic behavior of the adsorbate binding energy (&#916;EA) versus &#916;EM. Therefore, &#916;ECH and &#916;EO can be efficiently interpolated between metals, alloys, and intermetallics based on information related to one metal only. This simplifies the process of screening new metal catalyst formulations and their reaction energies.</description>
      <author>Shyama Charan Mandal, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of Cathode Materials for Na-Ion Batteries: Comparison Between Machine Learning Predictions and Density Functional Theory Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10120431</link>
      <description>Claudio Ronchetti, Sara Marchio, Francesco Buonocore, Simone Giusepponi, Sergio Ferlito, Massimo Celino, Batteries. 10(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405079572

                Energy storage technologies have experienced significant advancements in recent decades, driven by the growing demand for efficient and sustainable energy solutions. The limitations associated with lithium&#8217;s supply chain, cost, and safety concerns have prompted the exploration of alternative battery chemistries. For this reason, research to replace widespread lithium batteries with sodium-ion batteries has received more and more attention. In the present work, we report cutting-edge research, where we explored a wide range of compositions of cathode materials for Na-ion batteries by first-principles calculations using workflow chains developed within the AiiDA framework. We trained crystal graph convolutional neural networks and geometric crystal graph neural networks, and we demonstrate the ability of the machine learning algorithms to predict the formation energy of the candidate materials as calculated by the density functional theory. This materials discovery approach is disruptive and significantly faster than traditional physics-based computational methods.</description>
      <author>Claudio Ronchetti, Sara Marchio, Francesco Buonocore, Simone Giusepponi, Sergio Ferlito, Massimo Celino</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10120431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valorization of lignocellulosic biomass forest residues in quebec via the integrated hydropyrolysis and hydroconversion (IH2) technology: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biombioe.2024.107516</link>
      <description>A. Velumani Ganesan, Olivier Rezazgui, Jimmy Barco Burgos, Patrice Mangin, Simon Barnab&#233;, Biomass and Bioenergy. 193(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405088477

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Velumani Ganesan, Olivier Rezazgui, Jimmy Barco Burgos, Patrice Mangin, Simon Barnab&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biombioe.2024.107516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Metal Site Materials for Hydrogen Energy Utilization: Theoretical and Experimental Study in Fuel Cells and Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.decarb.2024.100091</link>
      <description>Xinxing Zhan, Xin Tong, Hao Ye, Zijian Gao, Tian Juan, Jinliang Zhuang, Gaixia Zhang, Shuhui Sun, DeCarbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405095404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinxing Zhan, Xin Tong, Hao Ye, Zijian Gao, Tian Juan, Jinliang Zhuang, Gaixia Zhang, Shuhui Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.decarb.2024.100091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size-dependent guest-memory switching of the flexible and robust adsorption characteristics of layered metal-organic frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adr1387</link>
      <description>Satoshi Watanabe, Shotaro Hiraide, Homare Arima, Akiko Fukuta, Miyuki Mori, Hideki Tanaka, Minoru T. Miyahara, Science Advances. 10(49)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405103471

                Flexible-robust metal-organic frameworks (MOFs), which exhibit unique hybrid nature comprising both flexible and rigid framework characteristics, exhibit high potential for hydrocarbon separations. However, no clear guidelines have been established to regulate their hybrid characteristics owing to limited understanding of their adsorption mechanism. This study investigates the effects of the particle size of a flexible-robust MOF on its adsorption and structural transition behaviors. The robust nature originates from the structural transition of a metastable guest-free structure, while its flexible nature arises from another guest-free structure. The type of guest-free structure is predominantly determined by the particle size; particles below the critical size are trapped in the metastable guest-free structure. Notably, the critical size varies with the type of guest molecule to be removed; consequently, the difference in critical size results in guest-memory characteristics, enabling guest-free structure switching. These results underscore the importance of controlling the particle size to fine-tune hybrid adsorption characteristics of flexible-robust MOFs.</description>
      <author>Satoshi Watanabe, Shotaro Hiraide, Homare Arima, Akiko Fukuta, Miyuki Mori, Hideki Tanaka, Minoru T. Miyahara</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adr1387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling electrocatalyst reaction mechanisms in water electrolysis: &lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; Raman spectra</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232980</link>
      <description>Chao Huang, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Ping Qin, Qingdong Ruan, Dorsa Dehghan&#8208;Baniani, Xiang Peng, Babak Mehrjou, Paul K. Chu, Applied Physics Reviews. 11(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405103486

                Electrocatalysis is crucial for sustainable energy solutions, focusing on energy harvesting, storage, and pollution control. Despite the development of various electrocatalysts, understanding the dynamic processes in electrochemical reactions is still limited, hindering effective catalyst design. In situ Raman spectra have emerged as a critical tool, providing molecular-level insights into surface processes under operational conditions and discussing their development, advantages, and configurations. This review emphasizes new findings at the catalyst&#8211;electrolyte interface, especially interface water molecule state, during the hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction in recent years. Finally, the challenges and future directions for in situ Raman techniques in electrocatalysis are discussed, emphasizing their importance in advancing understanding and guiding novel catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Chao Huang, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Ping Qin, Qingdong Ruan, Dorsa Dehghan&#8208;Baniani, Xiang Peng, Babak Mehrjou, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief overview of deep generative models and how they can be used to discover new electrode materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101629</link>
      <description>Anders Hellman, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405105990

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anders Hellman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reactivity of Single-crystal LaNiO3-&#948; Films via Tuning Oxygen Vacancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113934</link>
      <description>Zhiying Chen, Bin Du, Zhuanglin Weng, Jinlai Zhao, Xierong Zeng, Yuying Meng, Chuanwei Huang, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405111159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiying Chen, Bin Du, Zhuanglin Weng, Jinlai Zhao, Xierong Zeng, Yuying Meng, Chuanwei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113934</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic-Cycling Zinc Sites Promote Ruthenium Oxide for Sub-Ampere Electrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c04485</link>
      <description>Meihuan Liu, Xiaoxia Chen, Shiyu Li, C.Y. Ni, Yiwen Chen, Hui Su, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405113290

                Although iridium-based electrocatalysts are commonly regarded as the sole stable operating acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts in proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) devices, their exorbitant cost and scarcity severely restrict their widespread application. Herein, we introduce a promising alternative to iridium: zinc-doped ruthenium dioxide (TE-Zn/RuO2), which exhibits remarkable and enduring activity for acidic OER. In situ characterizations elucidate that the dynamic cycling of zinc dopants serves as both electron acceptors and donors, facilitating the activation of Ru sites at low overpotentials while thwarting peroxidation at high overpotentials, thus concurrently achieving heightened activity and robust stability. Additionally, the incorporation of zinc induces weakened Ru&#8211;O covalency, thereby stabling *OOH intermediates and instigating a sustained adsorbate evolution mechanism, dramatically stabilizing the RuO2 lattice. Importantly, the TE-Zn/RuO2 catalyst as an anode exhibits good stability over 300 h at a water-splitting current of 500 mA cm&#8211;2 in the PEMWE device, underscoring its considerable promise for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Meihuan Liu, Xiaoxia Chen, Shiyu Li, C.Y. Ni, Yiwen Chen, Hui Su</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c04485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Novel Single-Atom Catalysts of Transition-Metal-Doped 2D AlN Monolayer as Highly Effective Electrocatalysts for Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235768</link>
      <description>Xiaopeng Shen, Qinfang Zhang, Molecules. 29(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405122489

                The single-atom catalysts (SACs) for the electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) have garnered significant attention in recent years. The NRR is regarded as a milder and greener approach to ammonia synthesis. The pursuit of highly efficient and selective electrocatalysts for the NRR continues to garner substantial interest, yet it poses a significant challenge. In this study, we employed density functional theory calculations to investigate the stability and catalytic activity of 29 transition metal atoms loaded on the two-dimensional (2D) AlN monolayer with Al monovacancy (TM@AlN) for the conversion of N2 to NH3. After screening the activity and selectivity of NRR, it was found that Os@AlN exhibited the highest activity for NRR with a very low limiting potential of &#8722;0.46 V along the distal pathway. The analysis of the related electronic structure, Bader charge, electron localization function, and PDOS revealed the origin of NRR activity from the perspective of energy and electronic properties. The high activity and selectivity towards the NRR of SACs are closely associated with the Os-3N coordination. Our findings have expanded the scope of designing innovative high-efficiency SACs for NRR.</description>
      <author>Xiaopeng Shen, Qinfang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235768</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchoring Ultrafine Ru Nanoparticles Triggers 2H MoS2 Basal Plane for Efficient Dual-pH Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145485</link>
      <description>Yingde Wang, Yanan Li, Dongxu Yang, Yunsi Wang, Fuan Wei, Bingxin Liu, Peng Zhang, Benhua Xu, Yongcheng Li, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405122642

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingde Wang, Yanan Li, Dongxu Yang, Yunsi Wang, Fuan Wei, Bingxin Liu, Peng Zhang, Benhua Xu, Yongcheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting hydrogen evolution via work-function-accelerated electronic reconfiguration of Mo-based heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3190-7</link>
      <description>Xiang Chen, Shuai Feng, Song Xie, Yaping Miao, Biao Gao, Xuming Zhang, Li Huang, Yun Li, Paul K. Chu, Xiang Peng, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405124635

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Chen, Shuai Feng, Song Xie, Yaping Miao, Biao Gao, Xuming Zhang, Li Huang, Yun Li, Paul K. Chu, Xiang Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3190-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven compositional optimization of La(Fe,Si)13-based magnetocaloric compounds for cryogenic applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2024.116486</link>
      <description>A.K. Srinithi, A. Bolyachkin, Xin Tang, H. Sepehri&#8208;Amin, Sae Dieb, Akiko Saito, T. Ohkubo, K. Hono, Scripta Materialia. 258(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405126013

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A.K. Srinithi, A. Bolyachkin, Xin Tang, H. Sepehri&#8208;Amin, Sae Dieb, Akiko Saito, T. Ohkubo, K. Hono</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2024.116486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SrTi1-Ir O3 solid solution as a robust electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.013</link>
      <description>Cheng Yan, Xiyu He, Yunzhu Du, Jing Li, Yongjian Su, Jiewei Yin, Qiaodan Hu, Fan Yang, Junliang Zhang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 97(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405129884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Yan, Xiyu He, Yunzhu Du, Jing Li, Yongjian Su, Jiewei Yin, Qiaodan Hu, Fan Yang, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into electrocatalysis through in situ electrochemical surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100352</link>
      <description>Xiu&#8208;Mei Lin, Yulin Sun, Yanxin Chen, Shunxing Li, Jianfeng Li, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405135126

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiu&#8208;Mei Lin, Yulin Sun, Yanxin Chen, Shunxing Li, Jianfeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-0274-2_1</link>
      <description>Lunbo Duan, Dennis Lu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405143171

                Abstract Climate change is currently one of the most challenging issues to the global ecosystem, which has already caused serious consequences in many aspects, such as increasing wildfires, heat waves, drought, and ice sheet disintegration.</description>
      <author>Lunbo Duan, Dennis Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-0274-2_1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Metal&#8211;Support Interaction on the Structure and Activity of Carbon-Supported Ni Nanoparticle Catalysts for Alkaline Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15120</link>
      <description>Yoshiki Akamine, Fumiya Nishino, Takashi Yamashita, Masayuki Tsushida, Keisuke Awaya, Masato Machida, Syeda Mushrifa Zahan, Dario R. Dekel, Junya Ohyama, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405161821

                The effect of the carbon support&#9472;Ketjenblack (C</description>
      <author>Yoshiki Akamine, Fumiya Nishino, Takashi Yamashita, Masayuki Tsushida, Keisuke Awaya, Masato Machida, Syeda Mushrifa Zahan, Dario R. Dekel, Junya Ohyama</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the role of intrinsic defects in N/S Co-Doped hard carbon for superior sodium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158441</link>
      <description>Yunlei Yang, Chang Liu, Junjun Yao, Zhiyuan Tang, Ying Sun, Kun Zhang, Hui Li, Tianyi Ma, Jieshan Qiu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405172919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunlei Yang, Chang Liu, Junjun Yao, Zhiyuan Tang, Ying Sun, Kun Zhang, Hui Li, Tianyi Ma, Jieshan Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles investigation of hydrogen evolution reaction on doped 2D transition metal sulfides in mackinawite structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.014</link>
      <description>Thillai Govindaraja Senthamaraikannan, Dong&#8208;Hee Lim, Young-Soo Han, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 97(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405173856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thillai Govindaraja Senthamaraikannan, Dong&#8208;Hee Lim, Young-Soo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reduction of CO2 on pure and doped Cu2O(1 1 1)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.056</link>
      <description>H. Y. Liu, Lei Zhu, Zhichao Yu, Haoyun Bai, Hui Pan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405175780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Y. Liu, Lei Zhu, Zhichao Yu, Haoyun Bai, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilization of Novel (KNbO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;1&#8722;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;(Ba&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;FeNbO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; (&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; = 0.1, 0.2, 0.3) Solid Solutions for Efficient Photo&#8208;Assisted Fenton Degradation of Methylene Blue Dye</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400246</link>
      <description>Celal Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Peter Kraus, Suna Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Julian T. M&#252;ller, Aleksander Gurlo, Maged F. Bekheet, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405180780

                Novel (KNbO 3 ) 1&#8722; x (Ba 2 FeNbO 6 ) x ( x = 0.1, 0.2, 0.3) solid solutions corresponding to K 0.82 Ba 0.18 Fe 0.09 Nb 0.91 O 3 , K 0.64 Ba 0.36 Fe 0.18 Nb 0.82 O 3 , and K 0.46 Ba 0.54 Fe 0.27 Nb 0.73 O 3 compounds have been synthesized via molten salt method. X&#8208;ray diffraction confirms the formation of solid solutions, while transmission electron microscopy combined with energy&#8208;dispersive spectroscopy results demonstrates a homogeneous distribution of elements. The obtained solid solutions crystallized in a cubic crystal structure, whereas the parent KNbO 3 possesses an orthorhombic structure. The wide bandgap semiconductor KNbO 3 transformed into a visible&#8208;light&#8208;active material, with its bandgap energy reduced from 3.56 eV to &#8776;2.4 eV. The substitution of K in KNbO 3 with Ba is responsible for structural modification from orthorhombic to cubic symmetry, whereas both structural modification and the substitution of Nb with Fe correlated with optical properties. The photocatalytic activities of all obtained solid solutions are improved compared with the parent KNbO 3 and Ba 2 FeNbO 6 compounds for photocatalytic degradation of methylene blue (MB) dye. Among the series of solid solutions, K 0.82 Ba 0.18 Fe 0.09 Nb 0.91 O 3 photocatalysts show the highest MB removal efficiency owing to its relatively higher surface area, suppressed charge carrier recombination, and more negative conduction band edge. Moreover, K 0.82 Ba 0.18 Fe 0.09 Nb 0.91 O 3 photocatalyst (0.1 g) combined with hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) to form a novel photo&#8208;Fenton system, achieving almost complete degradation of 100 mL of 10 mg L &#8722;1 MB dye in 30 min.</description>
      <author>Celal Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Peter Kraus, Suna Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Julian T. M&#252;ller, Aleksander Gurlo, Maged F. Bekheet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating electronic structure of CoS2 nanorods by Fe doping for efficient electrocatalytic overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110564</link>
      <description>Qiang Shi, Zhiyong Li, Siqi He, Hu Zhou, Yu Zhang, Xia Cao, Aihua Yuan, Jian&#8208;Ping Zou, Jianchun Wu, Yanxin Qiao, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405183473

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Shi, Zhiyong Li, Siqi He, Hu Zhou, Yu Zhang, Xia Cao, Aihua Yuan, Jian&#8208;Ping Zou, Jianchun Wu, Yanxin Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic mechanism for the enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction activity of Cu alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120644</link>
      <description>Ruoyu Wu, Xiongjun Liu, Zhibin Li, S L Li, Huihui Zhu, Haonan Zhong, Hui Wan, Yuan Wu, Suihe Jiang, Shouxin Zhang, Xianzhen Wang, Zhaoping Lu, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405183687

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruoyu Wu, Xiongjun Liu, Zhibin Li, S L Li, Huihui Zhu, Haonan Zhong, Hui Wan, Yuan Wu, Suihe Jiang, Shouxin Zhang, Xianzhen Wang, Zhaoping Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core@Shell Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co@Pt/C Nanoparticles as an Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05129</link>
      <description>Junfang Cheng, Hao Chen, Enping Wang, Huimin Wang, Zehao Tan, Yan Cheng, Yongjian Su, Xinyi Li, Aiming Wu, Yangge Guo, Guanghua Wei, Junliang Zhang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405187954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfang Cheng, Hao Chen, Enping Wang, Huimin Wang, Zehao Tan, Yan Cheng, Yongjian Su, Xinyi Li, Aiming Wu, Yangge Guo, Guanghua Wei, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Sensitivity of Pourbaix Diagrams to Computational Protocols: Electrochemical Stability of Ni Oxides as a Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06788</link>
      <description>Wenyu Sun, Nitish Govindarajan, Aditya Prajapati, Jeremy T. Feaster, Christopher Hahn, Sneha A. Akhade, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405189245

                Pourbaix diagrams stand as a useful tool in assessing and visualizing materials' electrochemical stability and are widely used for electrocatalyst design. However, their reliability hinges on the accuracy of the chemical potentials of involved phases, which may bear uncertainties and can be significantly impacted by decision-making steps in the computational protocol. This study introduces a robust sensitivity analysis framework, exemplified through a detailed examination of the computational Pourbaix diagram of Ni, the oxides of which are used as high-activity and cost-friendly catalysts for many electrochemical reactions. Quantities of interest derived from the Pourbaix diagram include the appearance and stability domain of the catalytically active Ni oxide phases along with the onset electrochemical potentials of phase transitions. These metrics can guide the design of operational conditions for Ni oxide electrocatalysts. We find that the employed DFT exchange-correlation functional has the most significant influence on the computed Pourbaix diagram. Uncertainties on crystal structures, along with their related ab initio energetics, are also found to affect the size of the phase stability domain. Higher-order coupling among input parameters is found to play a crucial role in influencing the appearance and distribution of Ni phases in the diagram. Our findings suggest a need to consider variations and uncertainties associated with the computational procedures on predicted Pourbaix diagrams for materials design.</description>
      <author>Wenyu Sun, Nitish Govindarajan, Aditya Prajapati, Jeremy T. Feaster, Christopher Hahn, Sneha A. Akhade</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements and Challenges in Electrode and Electrolyte Materials for Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/er/9529659</link>
      <description>Konlayutt Punyawudho, Mariyappan Raja Pugalenthi, Xiong Shu, Satoshi Kaneco, Tanakorn Wongwuttanasatian, Amnart Suksri, Laksamee Payattikul, International Journal of Energy Research. 2024(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405195150

                Proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) technology is vital for a cleaner and more sustainable future, offering high efficiency, quiet operation, fuel flexibility, and zero&#8208;emission energy production with versatile applications. The drawbacks of PEMFC include its high cost, susceptibility to degradation, and challenges in scaling up production for commercial use. The gas diffusion layer (GDL), the catalyst layer (CL), and the polymer electrolyte are all very important parts of fuel cell technology. Through the optimization of these components, researchers may strive to develop fuel cells that are more efficient, cost&#8208;effective, durable, and high&#8208;performing, therefore enabling the provision of clean and sustainable energy. In this article, we have reviewed the various components of GDL, CL, and polymer electrolyte materials and their impact on the performance of PEMFC. The various characteristics of the GDL such as porosity, hydrophobic/hydrophilic, polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE), and carbon materials, are fully discussed in this review article. These topics also cover the CL&#8217;s properties, including the catalyst, carbon support, ionomer, and solvent. Explore the different polymer electrolytes that are based on aliphatic Nafion and aromatic hydrocarbons&#8208;based membrane. Finally, this review paper gives suggestions for the way forward in regard to creating electrodes and electrolytes for PEMFCs that are cost&#8208;effective, efficient, and durable.</description>
      <author>Konlayutt Punyawudho, Mariyappan Raja Pugalenthi, Xiong Shu, Satoshi Kaneco, Tanakorn Wongwuttanasatian, Amnart Suksri, Laksamee Payattikul</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/er/9529659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution activity of nickel-based phosphates and effects of their electronic orbitals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00794h</link>
      <description>Yuuki Sugawara, Y Nakase, Gopinathan M. Anilkumar, Keigo Kamata, Takeo Yamaguchi, Nanoscale Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405196768

                This study reports nickel-based phosphate nanoparticles as outstanding electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction and uncovers main factors determining their activities.</description>
      <author>Yuuki Sugawara, Y Nakase, Gopinathan M. Anilkumar, Keigo Kamata, Takeo Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00794h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer-aided amine solvent design for carbon capture based on desorption thermodynamic and reaction kinetic models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130984</link>
      <description>Yujing Zhao, Sheng Xiang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Jianbing Chen, Ming Gao, Bing Xing, Qilei Liu, Lei Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405198919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujing Zhao, Sheng Xiang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Jianbing Chen, Ming Gao, Bing Xing, Qilei Liu, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding of the synergetic effect of FeCoN8C dual active centers catalyst for oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162055</link>
      <description>Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405199310

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D MOF Structure Tuning Atomic Ru Sites for Efficient and Robust Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410657</link>
      <description>Jia Wang, De Wang, Zelin Zhao, Ganggang Chang, Wei Guo, Jun Xu, Yinyu Xiang, Junrui Li, Junsheng Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405200807

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;based HER electrocatalysts as alternatives to commercial Pt/C is crucial for the advancement of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). However, the strong hydrogen adsorption of Ru&#8208;based catalysts restricts its activity. Herein, a strategy is reported to tune the electronic structure and improve mass transfer by implanting Ru atoms onto the (002) facet of two&#8208;dimensional zeolitic imidazolate framework&#8208;67 (Ru@ L ZIF (002) ) to optimize the d &#8208;band center ( &#949; d ) of Ru and the hydrogen spillover behavior. Benefiting from the ultrathin nanosheet structure and optimized &#949; d of Ru, the over&#8208;strong H adsorption energy is weakened and the electron/mass transfer is facilitated. Ru@ L ZIF (002) exhibits an overpotential of 9.2 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a long&#8208;lasting stability of 35 days at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . The mass activity and price activity of Ru@ L ZIF (002) is 2.9 and 14.7 times higher than Pt/C, respectively. More impressively, Ru@ L ZIF (002) delivers a cell voltage of 2.01 V at a high current density of 4 A cm &#8722;2 in PEMWE. The excellent long&#8208;term durability of 1200 hours operating at 4 A cm &#8722;2 with an ultralow decay rate of 7.5 &#215; 10 &#8722;3 mV h &#8722;1 has been achieved, making it promising as a cost&#8208;effective alternative to Pt/C catalyst for PEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Jia Wang, De Wang, Zelin Zhao, Ganggang Chang, Wei Guo, Jun Xu, Yinyu Xiang, Junrui Li, Junsheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice modulation strategy toward efficient and durable &lt;scp&gt;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;based catalysts for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18665</link>
      <description>Linkai Han, Zhonghua Xiang, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405201017

                Abstract Rutile RuO 2 is recognized for its outstanding acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and notable cost advantage compared to iridium oxide for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). However, the unsatisfactory stability of RuO 2 hinders its practical application. Here, we report a lattice modulation strategy to enhance both the OER activity and stability of RuO 2 . Interestingly, the newly synthesized Mo 0.15 Nb 0.05 &#8208;RuO 2 , with Mo doped first and then Nb, presents the greatest lattice spacing and possesses an overpotential of merely 205 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , which significantly outperforms Nb 0.05 Mo 0.15 &#8208;RuO 2 (239 mV), where Nb was doped first followed by Mo, as well as the initial RuO 2 (323 mV). Remarkably, Mo 0.15 Nb 0.05 &#8208;RuO 2 requires only 1.76 V to achieve 1 A cm &#8722;2 and exhibits exceptional stability in PEMWE testing, with a voltage rise of only 58 mV at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 for more than 80 h.</description>
      <author>Linkai Han, Zhonghua Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling the Activity Trend of Metal&#8208;Loaded Metal Nitride Catalysts for NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis by a First&#8208;Principles Microkinetic Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408863</link>
      <description>Qianqian Yang, Qijun Gao, Jia Song, Anqi Cheng, Xinhe Wu, Pengfei Liu, Hua Yang, Haiyang Yuan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405201888

                Abstract Ammonia (NH 3 ) is one of the most widely produced chemicals globally, primarily synthesized through the Haber&#8208;Bosch process, which requires high temperatures and pressures. Dual&#8208;site catalysts can activate N 2 and H 2 at spatially separated sites, enabling efficient NH 3 synthesis under milder conditions. Despite the rapid experimental progress of the dual&#8208;site catalysts (e.g., Ni&#8208;LaN), the feasibility and design of dual&#8208;site catalysts are challenged recently. Herein, the different metal&#8208;loaded metal nitride catalyst models are employed, and their activity map for NH 3 synthesis is explored by the first&#8208;principles microkinetic simulation. The optimum active region of this type of dual&#8208;site catalyst is identified in terms of the formation energy ( E v ) of nitrogen vacancy (N vac ) on metal nitride and the adsorption energy ( E H ) of hydrogen atom on metal cluster, with E v and E H ideally located around &#8776;1.50 and &#8776;&#8722;0.30 eV, respectively. This offers a framework for designing effective metal&#8208;loaded metal nitride catalysts for NH 3 synthesis. Importantly, this trend aligns with and rationalizes the current experimental observations of metal&#8208;loaded metal nitride reported for NH 3 synthesis. This theoretical work provides significant insights into NH 3 synthesis on dual&#8208;site mechanism, and provides a rational direction for designing metal&#8208;loaded metal nitride catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qianqian Yang, Qijun Gao, Jia Song, Anqi Cheng, Xinhe Wu, Pengfei Liu, Hua Yang, Haiyang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capturing Surface Coverage Effects in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05086</link>
      <description>Alyssa J. R. Hensley, Neeru Chaudhary, Naseeha Cardwell, Isaac G. Onyango, Yong Wang, Di Wu, Jean&#8208;Sabin McEwen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404960710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alyssa J. R. Hensley, Neeru Chaudhary, Naseeha Cardwell, Isaac G. Onyango, Yong Wang, Di Wu, Jean&#8208;Sabin McEwen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6&#8211;16 Membrane Enhanced Reactors for Methanol Reforming to Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15740-0.00146-4</link>
      <description>V&#237;ctor M. Alvarado, Guadalupe L&#243;pez L&#243;pez, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405126120

                No abstract</description>
      <author>V&#237;ctor M. Alvarado, Guadalupe L&#243;pez L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15740-0.00146-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data efficiency of classification strategies for chemical and materials design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00298a</link>
      <description>Quinn Gallagher, Michael Webb, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404961437

                We benchmark the performance of space-filling and active learning algorithms on classification problems in materials science, revealing trends in optimally data-efficient algorithms.</description>
      <author>Quinn Gallagher, Michael Webb</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00298a</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
