<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 01:27:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Design Criteria for Active and Selective Catalysts in the Nitrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00058</link>
      <description>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Kai S. Exner, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405746625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the production distribution in Ni-Cu nanoparticle mediated nitrile hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.179</link>
      <description>Zihan Lv, Zeng Hong, Da Ke, Chao Qian, Xinzhi Chen, Shaodong Zhou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 683(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405747184

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihan Lv, Zeng Hong, Da Ke, Chao Qian, Xinzhi Chen, Shaodong Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Melamine-Driven Solvation Effect Promotes Oxygen Reduction on a Platinum Catalyst: Machine Learning-Aided Free Energy Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03437</link>
      <description>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Saori Minami, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405749721

                The modification of Pt surfaces with organic compounds like melamine enhances oxygen reduction reaction activity and catalyst durability. Through first-principles free energy calculations utilizing thermodynamic integration and finite-temperature molecular dynamics, enhanced by machine learning force fields for efficient sampling of nanosecond-scale interfacial water fluctuations and incorporating corrections to accurately reproduce first-principles free energies, we demonstrate that melamine destabilizes OH adsorbates, facilitating their removal and enhancing catalytic activity. Unlike alloys, where OH destabilization is driven by changes in electronic structure and surface strain, melamine disrupts hydrogen bonding between OH and interfacial water. Structural and vibrational analyses reveal that melamine alters the water solvation structure, which is evident in modified radial distribution functions and a blue shift in the O&#8211;H stretching vibrations. These findings indicate that manipulating interfacial solvation with organic compounds could be a promising approach to enhance catalytic activity without compromising durability.</description>
      <author>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Saori Minami</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant-Tuned Restructuring Kinetic for the Formation of Heterophase-Confined Metal-Nonmetal Diatomic Sites for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03060</link>
      <description>Xinyi Li, Feiyan Liu, Wenting Lu, Huafeng Fan, Meiling Xiao, Xiaoqiang Cui, Lu Li, Xiaoxin Zou, Weitao Zheng, Xiao Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405751831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyi Li, Feiyan Liu, Wenting Lu, Huafeng Fan, Meiling Xiao, Xiaoqiang Cui, Lu Li, Xiaoxin Zou, Weitao Zheng, Xiao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The &lt;i&gt;On&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;Off&lt;/i&gt; pH-Dependent Electrocatalytic Activity of the Perfluorinated Iron Phthalocyanine for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Electrochemical Hardness as a Reactivity Descriptor: Experimental and Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06957</link>
      <description>Luis Acu&#241;a-Saavedra, Ana Mar&#237;a M&#233;ndez&#8208;Torres, Gloria C&#225;rdenas&#8208;Jir&#243;n, Rub&#233;n O&#241;ate, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Allende, Ricardo Venegas, Roberto Bernal, Francisco Melo, Elizabeth Imbarack, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Ingrid Ponce, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405755151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luis Acu&#241;a-Saavedra, Ana Mar&#237;a M&#233;ndez&#8208;Torres, Gloria C&#225;rdenas&#8208;Jir&#243;n, Rub&#233;n O&#241;ate, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Allende, Ricardo Venegas, Roberto Bernal, Francisco Melo, Elizabeth Imbarack, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Ingrid Ponce</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the influence of coexistence of Zn vacancies (VZn) and H interstices (Hi) on the photoelectrocatalytic performance of wurtzite ZnO (001) monolayer: Li/Na/K</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113981</link>
      <description>Gang Zhang, Qingyu Hou, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma, Riguleng Si, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405757090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Zhang, Qingyu Hou, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma, Riguleng Si</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating photocatalytic H2O2 rate over inter-molecular Z-scheme heterojunction via dual production paths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115192</link>
      <description>Yaodan Cao, Y. C. Zhai, Wenwen Lv, Hongyan Liu, J. Zhuo, Shouchun Ma, Maoquan Wu, Wanting Hui, Wenqi Ding, Tongjie Yao, Jiaxu Zhang, Jie Wu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405761097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaodan Cao, Y. C. Zhai, Wenwen Lv, Hongyan Liu, J. Zhuo, Shouchun Ma, Maoquan Wu, Wanting Hui, Wenqi Ding, Tongjie Yao, Jiaxu Zhang, Jie Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional metal&#8211;organic frameworks with dual active sites for electrochemical CO2 reduction: A computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131275</link>
      <description>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405775281

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Ru&#8211;B&#8211;Cr Moieties to Activate the Ru Site for Acidic Water Electrolysis under Industrial-Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c05113</link>
      <description>Weimo Li, Linfeng Zhang, Lipo Ma, Jiawei Wang, Ruikai Qi, Yang Pang, Meijiao Xu, Chengji Zhao, Ce Wang, Mingbin Gao, Xiaofeng Lu, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405775903

                Developing highly efficient non-iridium-based active sites for acidic water splitting is still a huge challenge. Herein, unique Ru-B-Cr moieties have been constructed in RuO</description>
      <author>Weimo Li, Linfeng Zhang, Lipo Ma, Jiawei Wang, Ruikai Qi, Yang Pang, Meijiao Xu, Chengji Zhao, Ce Wang, Mingbin Gao, Xiaofeng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c05113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A computational survey of layered mixed phases Mn1&#8722;xNixPS3 for water splitting: Modulation of the band gap and the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.364</link>
      <description>Nicol&#225;s Forero-Correa, Carolina Aliaga, Evgenia Spodine, Catalina Cort&#233;s, Tatiana G&#243;mez, Javiera Cabezas-Escares, Francisco Mu&#241;oz, Carlos C&#225;rdenas, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 99(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405782916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicol&#225;s Forero-Correa, Carolina Aliaga, Evgenia Spodine, Catalina Cort&#233;s, Tatiana G&#243;mez, Javiera Cabezas-Escares, Francisco Mu&#241;oz, Carlos C&#225;rdenas</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au atomic clusters on MoS2 nanosheets for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105691</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Tian, Lei Hou, Wei Pei, Xueke Yu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405790966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Tian, Lei Hou, Wei Pei, Xueke Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational studies on transition metal and nitrogen atoms co-doped fullerene as an efficient electrocatalyst for nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-024-02443-w</link>
      <description>Faiza Shafiq, Lei Yang, Weihua Zhu, Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405795555

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faiza Shafiq, Lei Yang, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-024-02443-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing localized surface plasmon resonance and hydrogen spillover effects on AgPt NPs/d-Siloxene heterostructure for enhanced electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134178</link>
      <description>Yixin Yang, Zhi&#8208;Xin Liao, Cuicui Du, Jun&#8208;Feng Qin, Min Hong, Xiaohua Zhang, Jinhua Chen, Fuel. 385(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405800079

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yixin Yang, Zhi&#8208;Xin Liao, Cuicui Du, Jun&#8208;Feng Qin, Min Hong, Xiaohua Zhang, Jinhua Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of In&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ru&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Alloys for Efficient Electrocatalytic Reduction of Nitrate to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06598</link>
      <description>Qingchao Fang, M. T. Nasir, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Xuxin Kang, Yun Han, Cheng Yan, Anthony P. O&#8217;Mullane, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405801950

                The electrochemical reduction of nitrate to ammonia is considered a feasible strategy to address the imbalance of the global nitrogen cycle by eliminating N-containing pollutants in wastewater while producing ammonia in a sustainable way. In this work, we systematically investigate the reduction of nitrate to ammonia on p-block indium (In), noble metal ruthenium (Ru), and their alloys (InRu3, In3Ru). We found that pure In and Ru candidates exhibit various performances for nitrate reduction with low limiting potentials for the potential-determining step of &#8722;0.31 V and &#8722;0.14 V, respectively. However, the incorporation of In into Ru to create alloys leads to excellent activity for the reduction of nitrate to ammonia. Ammonia production on InRu3 and In3Ru alloys demonstrates higher catalytic activity and selectivity as the byproducts of NO2 and NO can be inhibited, while the parasitic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) can also be significantly suppressed. Our work not only proposes efficient electrocatalysts for nitrate reduction but also provides a new strategy for the rational design of alloy catalysts for improved catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Qingchao Fang, M. T. Nasir, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Xuxin Kang, Yun Han, Cheng Yan, Anthony P. O&#8217;Mullane, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electrical Double Layer in Electrocatalytic Reactions: Fundamentals, Characterizations and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actphy.2024.100041</link>
      <description>Xueting Cao, Shuangshuang Cha, Ming Gong, Acta Physico-Chimica Sinica. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405802144

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xueting Cao, Shuangshuang Cha, Ming Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actphy.2024.100041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique Cu+/Cu0 active-site switches in Cu-loaded g-C3N4 nanosheets for efficient photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.12.010</link>
      <description>Dongxiao Wen, Nan Wang, Jiahe Peng, Tetsuro Majima, Jizhou Jiang, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405802199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongxiao Wen, Nan Wang, Jiahe Peng, Tetsuro Majima, Jizhou Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.12.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights into the adjustable electronic buffering effect of C60 under electric fields for single-atom Cu catalysis in CO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115054</link>
      <description>Lei-Xian Chen, Zi-Yang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, W. P. Wang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405802485

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei-Xian Chen, Zi-Yang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, W. P. Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox photocatalysis CuFe-BTC for nitrate reduction and formaldehyde oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158995</link>
      <description>Huang Xu, Kai-Yin Wu, Fei Yang, Rui Fu, Yunfei Ji, Wei Kong, Chao Su, Beibei Xiao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405812911

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huang Xu, Kai-Yin Wu, Fei Yang, Rui Fu, Yunfei Ji, Wei Kong, Chao Su, Beibei Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of NO and CO on the Rh(100) surface at room temperature and atmospheric pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122679</link>
      <description>Dajo Boden, J&#246;rg Meyer, Irene M. N. Groot, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405825745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dajo Boden, J&#246;rg Meyer, Irene M. N. Groot</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Approach to the Extraction of Clusters from ZSM-5 Zeolite for Quantum-Chemical Search for Zn2+ Cation-Exchange Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s0965544124080012</link>
      <description>V. A. Koveza, A. S. Giliazutdinova, &#1054;. &#1042;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072;&#1087;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Petroleum Chemistry. 64(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405827832

                No abstract</description>
      <author>V. A. Koveza, A. S. Giliazutdinova, &#1054;. &#1042;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072;&#1087;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s0965544124080012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Adaptive Optimization of Coefficients in Multi-Objective Loss Functions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3688671.3688742</link>
      <description>Spilios Dellis, Eleonora Ricci, Dimitrios-Paraskevas Gerakinis, Niki Vergadou, George Giannakopoulos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405830646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Spilios Dellis, Eleonora Ricci, Dimitrios-Paraskevas Gerakinis, Niki Vergadou, George Giannakopoulos</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1145/3688671.3688742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Simulation of Coarse-grained Systems using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3688671.3688739</link>
      <description>Dimitrios-Paraskevas Gerakinis, Eleonora Ricci, George Giannakopoulos, Vangelis Karkaletsis, Doros N. Theodorou, Niki Vergadou, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405831045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dimitrios-Paraskevas Gerakinis, Eleonora Ricci, George Giannakopoulos, Vangelis Karkaletsis, Doros N. Theodorou, Niki Vergadou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1145/3688671.3688739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Ni doping on the catalytic activity and stability of RuO2 electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122691</link>
      <description>Hyunwoo Jang, Seungwon Shim, Youngho Kang, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405835202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyunwoo Jang, Seungwon Shim, Youngho Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Relations for Ammonia Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115179</link>
      <description>Rachelle M. Choueiri, Stephen W. Tatarchuk, O. F. Parker, William Cooper, Leanne D. Chen, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405835668

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rachelle M. Choueiri, Stephen W. Tatarchuk, O. F. Parker, William Cooper, Leanne D. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Nitrate Electroconversion to Ammonia Using an Entangled Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/Graphene Nanoribbon Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18269</link>
      <description>Marci&#233;lli K. R. Souza, Eduardo S. F. Cardoso, L.M.C. Pinto, Irma Crivelli, Clauber D. Rodrigues, Robson da Silva Souto, Ary T. Rezende-Filho, Marcos R.V. Lanza, Gilberto Maia, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405839604

                There has been huge interest among chemical scientists in the electrochemical reduction of nitrate (NO3&#8211;) to ammonia (NH4+) due to the useful application of NH4+ in nitrogen fertilizers and fuel. To conduct such a complex reduction reaction, which involves eight electrons and eight protons, one needs to develop high-performance (and stable) electrocatalysts that favor the formation of reaction intermediates that are selective toward ammonia production. In the present study, we developed and applied Co3O4/graphene nanoribbon (GNR) electrocatalysts with excellent properties for the effective reduction of NO3&#8211; to NH4+, where NH4+ yield rate of 42.11 mg h&#8211;1 mgcat&#8211;1, FE of 98.7%, NO3&#8211; conversion efficiency of 14.71%, and NH4+ selectivity of 100% were obtained, with the application of only 37.5 &#956;g cm&#8211;2 of the catalysts (for the best catalyst &#9472;Co3O4(Cowt %55)GNR, only 20.6 &#956;g cm&#8211;2 of Co was applied), confirmed by loadings ranging from 19&#8211;150 &#956;g cm&#8211;2. The highly satisfactory results obtained from the application of the proposed catalysts were favored by high average values of electrochemically active surface area (ECSA) and low Rct values, along with the presence of several planes in Co3O4 entangled with GNR and the occurrence of a kind of "(Co3(Co(CN)6)2(H2O)12)1.333 complex" structure on the catalyst surface, in addition to the effective migration of NO3&#8211; from the cell cathodic branch to the anodic branch, which was confirmed by the experiment conducted using a H-cell separated by a Nafion 117 membrane. The in situ FTIR and Raman spectroscopy results helped identify the adsorbed intermediates, namely, NO3&#8211;, NO2&#8211;, NO, and NH2OH, and the final product NH4+, which are compatible with the proposed NO3&#8211; electroreduction mechanism. The Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations helped confirm that the Co3O4(Cowt %55)GNR catalyst exhibited a better performance in terms of nitrate electroreduction in comparison with Co3O4(Cowt %75), considering the intermediates identified by the in situ FTIR and Raman spectroscopy results and the rate-determining step (RDS) observed for the transition of *NO to *NHO (0.43 eV).</description>
      <author>Marci&#233;lli K. R. Souza, Eduardo S. F. Cardoso, L.M.C. Pinto, Irma Crivelli, Clauber D. Rodrigues, Robson da Silva Souto, Ary T. Rezende-Filho, Marcos R.V. Lanza, Gilberto Maia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction activity of Ni3(PO4)2 and bimetallic Ni3M3(PO4)4 (M = Mn, Fe, Co): Insights from DFT and experimental validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134183</link>
      <description>Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, C. Mariani, Fadjar Fathurrahman, Brian Yuliarto, Hermawan Kresno Dipojono, Hamad AlMohamadi, Sasfan Arman Wella, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Fuel. 385(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405841347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, C. Mariani, Fadjar Fathurrahman, Brian Yuliarto, Hermawan Kresno Dipojono, Hamad AlMohamadi, Sasfan Arman Wella, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity&#8211;Stability Relationship in Compositionally Tuned Magnetron Co&#8208;Sputtered Bimetallic Catalysts for Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/fuce.202400095</link>
      <description>Martin Ors&#225;g, Athira Lekshmi Mohandas Sandhya, Xianxian Xie, Jan Ku&#269;era, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Yu. V. Yakovlev, Milan Dopita, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Ivan Khalakhan, Fuel Cells. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405847485

                ABSTRACT In the present study, magnetron&#8208;sputtered Pt x M 100&#8722; x (M = Co, Cu, and Y; x = 25, 50, 75, and 100) bimetallic alloys were investigated as PEMFC cathodes. Accurate composition and layer thickness control enabled a systematic study of the correlation between the alloy composition, its activity, and stability. The catalysts underwent thorough characterization, employing a diverse portfolio of characterization techniques such as scanning electron microscopy, energy&#8208;dispersive X&#8208;ray spectroscopy, X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy, X&#8208;ray diffraction, and cyclic voltammetry. The activity of all investigated alloys was tested directly in a fuel cell device, whereas stability was assessed through potentiodynamic cycling in a half&#8208;cell. The activity&#8211;stability index, considering experimental results for both activity and stability, was calculated and compared for all investigated catalysts. All alloys exhibited a volcano&#8208;type trend in the activity&#8211;stability index as a function of the concentration of the alloying element with maxima observed for Pt 50 Co 50 , Pt 50 Cu 50 , and Pt 75 Y 25 for respective alloys, surpassing that of monometallic platinum. Overall, Pt 50 Co 50 emerged as a catalyst with the highest activity&#8211;stability ratio.</description>
      <author>Martin Ors&#225;g, Athira Lekshmi Mohandas Sandhya, Xianxian Xie, Jan Ku&#269;era, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Yu. V. Yakovlev, Milan Dopita, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Ivan Khalakhan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/fuce.202400095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the C&#8211;C Coupling Mechanism on Dual-Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CO Reduction Reaction: The Critical Role of CO Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03123</link>
      <description>Minghao He, Changshuang Jiang, Huimin Yan, Guofeng Wang, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405850979

                The electrochemical reduction reaction (RR) of CO to high value multicarbon products is highly desirable for carbon utilization. Dual transition metal atoms dispersed by N-doped graphene are able to be highly efficient catalysts for this process due to the synergy of the bimetallic sites for C&#8211;C coupling. In this work, we screened homonuclear dual-atom catalysts dispersed by N-doped graphene to investigate the potential in CO reduction to C2+ products by employing density functional theory calculations. We have demonstrated that the two adsorbed CO species on bimetallic sites cannot directly couple unless one of the CO molecules is hydrogenated. All the dual metal atom catalysts prefer a similar coupling mechanism, i.e., the asymmetric coupling of *CO on the bridged site and *CHO on the top site, while the Ni2 and Cu2 catalysts exhibit much better performance with moderate adsorption energies and low energy barriers. The enhanced activities are attributed to the decrease of the energy levels of *CO 2p states that weakens the metal&#8211;C bonding and thus facilitates the feasible C&#8211;C coupling with both low reaction energies and low barriers. These insights have revealed the significant role of the hydrogenation of CO species prior to the coupling step and may provide a theoretical perspective to understand the generation of C2+ products in the CO2/CORR.</description>
      <author>Minghao He, Changshuang Jiang, Huimin Yan, Guofeng Wang, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aqueous redox flow batteries using iron complex and oxygen as redox couple with anthraquinone-2,7-disulfonate redox mediator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.125225</link>
      <description>Mingyu Shin, Hyeonsoo Lim, Kyuhwan Hyun, Yongchai Kwon, Applied Energy. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405851000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyu Shin, Hyeonsoo Lim, Kyuhwan Hyun, Yongchai Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.125225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-supported iron-series alloy catalysts for zinc-air batteries: A mini-review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101785</link>
      <description>Zhikang Wu, &#173;Jun Li&#173;, Sisi Xin, Menglin Zhou, Xuguang An, Guangzhi Hu, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405854879

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhikang Wu, &#173;Jun Li&#173;, Sisi Xin, Menglin Zhou, Xuguang An, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materiales de un &#250;nico &#225;tomo de hierro-nitr&#243;geno-carbono para la reducci&#243;n electroqu&#237;mica de ox&#237;geno y CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62534/rseq.aq.2003</link>
      <description>Jorge Torrero, Jes&#250;s Barrio, Deleted Journal. 120(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405860090

                Los materiales de un &#250;nico &#225;tomo metal-nitr&#243;geno-carbono son la mejor alternativa a los catalizadores de metales preciosos en las celdas de combustible de hidr&#243;geno y los electrolizadores de CO2. Sin embargo, su s&#237;ntesis est&#225; limitada por la pir&#243;lisis a alta temperatura, lo que conlleva la formaci&#243;n de nanopart&#237;culas y resulta en un bajo n&#250;mero de sitios activos poco accesibles. Por lo tanto, las t&#233;cnicas sint&#233;ticas que permiten la coordinaci&#243;n de &#225;tomos aislados en una matriz de carbono post-pir&#243;lisis han recibido mucha atenci&#243;n. En esta perspectiva, comentamos los trabajos m&#225;s recientes en el campo de los electrocatalizadores Fe-N-C, y nos enfocamos en las t&#233;cnicas sint&#233;ticas de reemplazo de cationes Zn y Mg para evitar la agregaci&#243;n de Fe.</description>
      <author>Jorge Torrero, Jes&#250;s Barrio</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62534/rseq.aq.2003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acetonitrile-driven universal CO production across diverse metal catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2416-0</link>
      <description>Benqiang Tian, Yan Xu, Haoyang Wu, Zhong Yang, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Haijun Xu, Yun Kuang, Jiazhan Li, Xiaoming Sun, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405860289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benqiang Tian, Yan Xu, Haoyang Wu, Zhong Yang, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Haijun Xu, Yun Kuang, Jiazhan Li, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2416-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Exploration of Ti&#8211;V&#8211;Nb&#8211;Mo Carbide MXenes Using Neural Network Potentials and Their Evaluation as Catalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16965</link>
      <description>Mohammed Wasay Mudassir, Sriram Goverapet Srinivasan, Mahesh Mynam, Beena Rai, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405860570

                Realization of a sustainable hydrogen economy in the future requires the development of efficient and cost-effective catalysts for its production at scale. MXenes (Mn+1Xn) are a class of 2D materials with 'n' layers of carbon or nitrogen (X) interleaved by 'n+1' layers of transition metal (M) and have emerged as promising materials for various applications including catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Their properties are intimately related to both their composition and their atomic structure. Recently, high entropy MXenes were synthesized, opening a vast compositional space of potentially stable and functionally superior materials. Detailed atomistic modeling enables us to systematically explore this extensive design space, which is otherwise infeasible in experiments. We have developed a Neural Network Potential (NNP) to model (TixVyNbzMop)n+1Cn MXenes (x+y+z+p = 1; n = 1,2,3) by training against Density Functional Theory (DFT) data in an active learning fashion. We then used the developed NNP to perform hybrid Monte Carlo-Molecular Dynamics (MC-MD) simulations to identify thermodynamically stable compositions and investigate the relative arrangement of transition metal atoms within and across layers. Thermodynamic stability increased with Mo content and its presence on the surface layer. We further investigated the catalytic performance of stable MXenes for the HER and observed that the center of the oxygen p-band (&#949;p) correlated well with the energy of adsorption of a hydrogen atom &#916;G(*H). Subsurface metal atoms significantly influenced the &#916;G(*H) values at the surface via both ligand and strain effects. Our work expands the space of potentially stable MXene compositions, providing targets for synthesis and their evaluation in various applications.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Wasay Mudassir, Sriram Goverapet Srinivasan, Mahesh Mynam, Beena Rai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in electric field induced by defected carbons adjacent to graphitic nitrogen valley for efficient oxygen reduction reaction and zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.021</link>
      <description>Na Li, Tingting Ma, Huihui Wang, Jiayi Li, D.L. Qiu, Zhen Meng, Jiangdu Huang, Lijun Sui, Faming Han, Huidan Lu, Yongping Liu, Sundaram Chandrasekaran, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405865451

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Li, Tingting Ma, Huihui Wang, Jiayi Li, D.L. Qiu, Zhen Meng, Jiangdu Huang, Lijun Sui, Faming Han, Huidan Lu, Yongping Liu, Sundaram Chandrasekaran</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction and structural activities of single-, dual-, and triple-phase nickel phosphides for hydrogen evolution reaction in acidic and alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.388</link>
      <description>Abebe Reda Woldu, Jintao Zhang, Rui Li, Zanling Huang, Zhiyuan Wang, J. Li, Guo-Ling Li, Liangsheng Hu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 100(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405870576

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abebe Reda Woldu, Jintao Zhang, Rui Li, Zanling Huang, Zhiyuan Wang, J. Li, Guo-Ling Li, Liangsheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin-polarized binuclear transition metal doping on g-C&#8323;N&#8324; for photocatalytic CO&#8322; reduction to C2 products: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114798</link>
      <description>Xiaoyi Hu, Qingyu Li, Weiguo Li, Yixin Deng, Diwen Liu, Yanjie Zhang, Rusheng Yuan, Zuju Ma, Jiming Zhang, Rongjian Sa, Molecular Catalysis. 572(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405876574

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyi Hu, Qingyu Li, Weiguo Li, Yixin Deng, Diwen Liu, Yanjie Zhang, Rusheng Yuan, Zuju Ma, Jiming Zhang, Rongjian Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Synthesis of PtPdNiCoMn High&#8208;Entropy Alloy Electrocatalyst for Enhanced Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction: A Theoretically Supported Predictive Design Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418644</link>
      <description>Athira Chandran M, Pritha Dutta, Prashant Singh, Ashutosh K. Singh, B. L. V. Prasad, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405879984

                Abstract Electrocatalytic hydrogen generation requires a cutting&#8208;edge, multifunctional electrocatalyst with abundant active sites to drive multielectron transfer reactions. High entropy alloys (HEA) are complex five or more&#8208;element alloy systems with high configurational entropy which makes them unique materials for next&#8208;generation electrocatalysts. Here, in this work, based on new screening guidelines for catalyst selections that combine density&#8208;functional theory calculated Gibbs formation&#8208;enthalpy with bond length and electronegativity variance, a novel HEA electrocatalyst consisting of five elements, namely, Pt, Pd, Ni, Co, and Mn is designed. By simple room temperature electrodeposition, the designed catalyst is prepared and its hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is explored and validated through experimental and theoretical approaches. The HEA demonstrated a superior HER activity with an overpotential of 22.6 mV at &#8722;10 mA cm &#8722;2 which outperforms Pt/C commercial catalyst. No evident degradation of the material is detected even after 100 hours of continuous operation under high current density. Moreover, the HEA has shown exceptional performance in harsh electrolyte conditions such as in simulated seawater and actual seawater. Remarkably, the density&#8208;functional theory calculated small Gibbs formation&#8208;enthalpy (&#8776;0 eV) compared to Pt/C places the new HEA near the apex of Trasatti's model of Volcano plot, which is also suggestive of superior HER activity.</description>
      <author>Athira Chandran M, Pritha Dutta, Prashant Singh, Ashutosh K. Singh, B. L. V. Prasad</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT study on the structural properties and CO2 electrocatalytic reduction activity of monolayer graphitic carbon nitride supported Ag/Au single atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122692</link>
      <description>Hui-Ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405882115

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui-Ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reactions in Two-Dimensional Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks by a Constant Potential Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04034</link>
      <description>Jin Yu, Tianyun Liu, Xuefei Liu, Wei Deng, Wenjun Xiao, Yaqiong Su, Xiaosi Qi, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Xu Wang, Changsong Gao, Hui Xiong, Xiangyu Wu, Jiajin Ge, Jinshun Bi, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405884135

                The evolution of bifunctional catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts that are highly active, stable, and conductive is crucial for advancing metal-air batteries and fuel cells. We have here thoroughly explored the OER and ORR performance for a category of two-dimensional (2D) metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) called TM3(HADQ)2, and Rh3(HADQ)2 exhibits a promising bifunctional OER/ORR activity, with an overpotential of 0.31 V for both OER and ORR. The d-band center (&#949;d) and crystal orbital Hamilton populations (COHP) are utilized to study the relationship between OER/ORR activity and the electronic structure of catalysts, and it is found that the elementary d-electron number (Ne) of the central TM for TM3(HADQ)2, as well as the electronegativity of the ligand TM-N4 and the intermediate O atom, are the main reason that affects the catalytic activity of OER/ORR. Additionally, Rh3(HADQ)2 can be proven through the constant potential method (CPM) and microkinetics method that it is an acidic OER/ORR bifunctional catalyst. Rh3(HADQ)2 has a high toxicity tolerance, making it a potential bifunctional catalyst. Our research contributes to both the rational design of SACs for various catalytic processes and the fabrication of bifunctional, cost-effective oxygen-electric catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jin Yu, Tianyun Liu, Xuefei Liu, Wei Deng, Wenjun Xiao, Yaqiong Su, Xiaosi Qi, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Xu Wang, Changsong Gao, Hui Xiong, Xiangyu Wu, Jiajin Ge, Jinshun Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A fluorinated hydrophobic metal&#8211;organic framework for CH4 purification from seven-component C1/C2/C3 hydrocarbons mixture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131359</link>
      <description>Tong Li, Xiaomin Li, Yong Wang, Xiaoxia Jia, Hui Chen, Yongjian Li, Jiangfeng Yang, Jinping Li, Libo Li, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405884275

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tong Li, Xiaomin Li, Yong Wang, Xiaoxia Jia, Hui Chen, Yongjian Li, Jiangfeng Yang, Jinping Li, Libo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Borophene: Puckering Mechanism and the Role of Coordination Number</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c08031</link>
      <description>Yi Sheng Ng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405893138

                Using the free energy of hydrogen adsorption (&#916;GH) as the indicator, five borophene phases are previously shown to possess high catalytic activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). On these borophene phases, we investigate the role of the coordination number (CN = 4, 5, 6) of the adsorption sites and the puckering of the adsorption site. CN is discovered to have a profound effect on the &#916;GH distribution, charge, and puckering height (h) of adsorption sites. Employing bonding indicators, we investigated the puckering mechanism. An increase in h directly increases the bond order and bond strength of the adsorption bond, but the associated energy cost of bond stretching hinders further puckering. The occupation and localization of &#963; orbitals determine the strength of local &#963; bonds&#9472;the key factors determining h. External biaxial strain is revealed to monotonically modulate the 2s character in local &#963; bonds, thus affecting bond stretchability, altering h and &#916;GH subsequently. These insights are valuable for borophene-based HER applications and provide an analytical framework for the adsorption on 2D materials.</description>
      <author>Yi Sheng Ng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c08031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt nanoparticles supported on in-situ growth titanium dioxide nanowire arrays with oxygen vacancies for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162257</link>
      <description>Shipeng Wang, Le Sang, Zipan Jiao, Feiyan Zhang, Yingde Wang, Benhua Xu, Peng Zhang, Bingxin Liu, Yunsi Wang, Yongcheng Li, Riming Hu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shipeng Wang, Le Sang, Zipan Jiao, Feiyan Zhang, Yingde Wang, Benhua Xu, Peng Zhang, Bingxin Liu, Yunsi Wang, Yongcheng Li, Riming Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering acidic oxygen reduction selectivity of single-atom catalysts through the second sphere effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55116-x</link>
      <description>Haiyuan Zou, Siyan Shu, Wenqiang Yang, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Minglun Cheng, Hongliang Dong, Hong Liu, Fan Li, Junhui Hu, Zhenbin Wang, Wei Liu, Hao Ming Chen, Lele Duan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894806

                Natural enzymes feature distinctive second spheres near their active sites, leading to exquisite catalytic reactivity. However, incumbent synthetic strategies offer limited versatility in functionalizing the second spheres of heterogeneous catalysts. Here, we prepare an enzyme-mimetic single Co&#8211;N4 atom catalyst with an elaborately configured pendant amine group in the second sphere via 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition, which switches the oxygen reduction reaction selectivity from the 4e&#8722; to the 2e&#8722; pathway under acidic conditions. Proton inventory studies and theoretical calculations reveal that the introduced pendant amine acts as a proton relay and promotes the protonation of *O2 to *OOH on the Co&#8211;N4 active site, facilitating H2O2 production. The second sphere-tailored Co&#8211;N4 sites reach optima H2O2 selectivity of 97% &#177; 1.13%, showing a 3.46-fold enhancement to bare Co&#8211;N4 catalyst (28% &#177; 1.75%). This work provides an appealed approach for enzyme-like catalyst design, bridging the gap between enzymatic and heterogeneous catalysis. Here, the authors present a Co-N4 single-atom catalyst with pendant amine group in the second sphere, which shifts the oxygen reduction reaction selectivity toward hydrogen peroxide production.</description>
      <author>Haiyuan Zou, Siyan Shu, Wenqiang Yang, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Minglun Cheng, Hongliang Dong, Hong Liu, Fan Li, Junhui Hu, Zhenbin Wang, Wei Liu, Hao Ming Chen, Lele Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55116-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically synthesized H2O2 at industrial-level current densities enabled by in situ fabricated few-layer boron nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55071-7</link>
      <description>Yuhan Wu, Yuying Zhao, Qixin Yuan, Hao Sun, Ao Wang, Kang Sun, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Ziyun Wang, Jingjie Wu, Jianchun Jiang, Mengmeng Fan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894857

                Carbon nanomaterials show outstanding promise as electrocatalysts for hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) synthesis via the two-electron oxygen reduction reaction. However, carbon-based electrocatalysts that are capable of generating H2O2 at industrial-level current densities (&gt;300 mA cm&#8722;2) with high selectivity and long-term stability remain to be discovered. Herein, few-layer boron nanosheets are in-situ introduced into a porous carbon matrix, creating a metal-free electrocatalyst (Bn-C) with H2O2 production rates of industrial relevance in neutral or alkaline media. Bn-C maintained &gt; 95% Faradaic efficiency during a 140-hour test at 300 mA cm&#8722;2 and 0.1 V vs. RHE, and delivered a mass activity of 25.1 mol gcatalyst&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 in 1.0 M Na2SO4 using a flow cell. Theoretical simulations and experimental studies demonstrate that the superior catalytic performance originates from B atoms with adsorbed O atoms in the boron nanosheets. Bn-C outperforms all metal-based and metal-free carbon catalysts reported to date for H2O2 synthesis at industrial-level current densities. Carbon nanomaterials show promise for H2O2 synthesis, but carbon electrocatalysts with industrial-level performance and stability require more research. Here the authors report few-layer boron nanosheets for H2O2 electrochemical production with &gt; 95% Faradaic efficiency during 140-hour test at 300 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Yuhan Wu, Yuying Zhao, Qixin Yuan, Hao Sun, Ao Wang, Kang Sun, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Ziyun Wang, Jingjie Wu, Jianchun Jiang, Mengmeng Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55071-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of structural and electronic properties and water splitting electrocatalytic performance of TM-decorated (TM = Mn, Fe, Co, and Ni) biphenylene monolayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-024-02444-9</link>
      <description>Seifollah Jalili, Faezeh Taravat, Atena Pakzadiyan, Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405895627

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seifollah Jalili, Faezeh Taravat, Atena Pakzadiyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-024-02444-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying and Analyzing Extremely Productive Authors in Intensive Care Medicine: A scientometric analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tacc.2024.101515</link>
      <description>Francesco Zarantonello, Nicol&#242; Sella, Alessandro De Cassai, Giulia Aviani Fulvio, Annalisa Boscolo, Tommaso Pettenuzzo, Giulia Mormando, Paolo Navalesi, Trends in Anaesthesia and Critical Care. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405904997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Francesco Zarantonello, Nicol&#242; Sella, Alessandro De Cassai, Giulia Aviani Fulvio, Annalisa Boscolo, Tommaso Pettenuzzo, Giulia Mormando, Paolo Navalesi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tacc.2024.101515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unbiased dataset for methane dry reforming and catalyst design guidelines obtained by high-throughput experimentation and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115930</link>
      <description>Wentao Du, Patchanee Chammingkwan, Keisuke Takahashi, Toshiaki Taniike, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405847595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wentao Du, Patchanee Chammingkwan, Keisuke Takahashi, Toshiaki Taniike</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115930</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning prediction of materials properties from chemical composition: Status and prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235541</link>
      <description>Mohammed Alghadeer, Nyimas Aisyah, Mahmoud Hezam, Saad M. Alqahtani, Ahmer A.B. Baloch, Fahhad H. Alharbi, Chemical Physics Reviews. 5(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405813232

                In materials science, machine learning (ML) has become an essential and indispensable tool. ML has emerged as a powerful tool in materials science, particularly for predicting material properties based on chemical composition. This review provides a comprehensive overview of the current status and future prospects of using ML in this domain, with a special focus on physics-guided machine learning (PGML). By integrating physical principles into ML models, PGML ensures that predictions are not only accurate but also interpretable, addressing a critical need in the physical sciences. We discuss the foundational concepts of statistical learning and PGML, outline a general framework for materials informatics, and explore key aspects such as data analysis, feature reduction, and chemical composition representation. Additionally, we survey the latest advancements in the prediction of geometric structures, electronic properties, and other material characteristics from chemical formulas. The review also provides resource tables listing essential databases, tools, and predictors, offering a valuable reference for researchers. As the field rapidly expands, this review aims to guide future efforts in harnessing ML for materials discovery and development.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Alghadeer, Nyimas Aisyah, Mahmoud Hezam, Saad M. Alqahtani, Ahmer A.B. Baloch, Fahhad H. Alharbi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Thermal Stability Challenges in Top&#8208;Emission OLEDs: The Role of Buffer Layer in Preventing Pixel Shrinkage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202402832</link>
      <description>Seung Ju Ok, Thi Na Le, Ji Hee Son, Seung Yong Song, Min Chul Suh, Advanced Optical Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405820617

                Abstract This study introduces a strategic buffer layer approach to mitigate thermal&#8208;induced pixel shrinkage in top&#8208;emission organic light&#8208;emitting diodes (TEOLEDs), enhancing both thermal stability and efficiency. A new cathode composed of binary alloy from silver (Ag) and copper (Cu) is developed for their moderately high binding energy, improving film uniformity and boosting optical and electrical performance. High surface energy metals, aluminum (Al) and Cu are employed as buffer layers to regulate the growth mechanism, resulting in an exceptionally smooth cathode film. The optimal device is designed by incorporating a bilayer electron injection layer consisting of lithium fluoride (LiF) and ytterbium (Yb) along with the buffer layer. The TEOLEDs achieved an impressive efficiency of 178 cd A &#8722;1 and luminance of 247,000 cd m &#8722; 2 while demonstrating superior thermal stability, with the absence of cathode shrinkage after 240 h at 85 &#176;C. This stability is attributed to the suppression of thermal diffusion and aggregation, facilitated by the high surface energy buffer layer and innovative cathode compositions employed.</description>
      <author>Seung Ju Ok, Thi Na Le, Ji Hee Son, Seung Yong Song, Min Chul Suh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202402832</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
