<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:44:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Micromechanical Dilution of PLA/PETG&#8211;Glass/Iron Nanocomposites: A More Efficient Molecular Dynamics Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c08264</link>
      <description>William A. Pisani, Dane N. Wedgeworth, Jedadiah F. Burroughs, Travis L. Thornell, Jennifer F. Newman, Manoj K. Shukla, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392934927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>William A. Pisani, Dane N. Wedgeworth, Jedadiah F. Burroughs, Travis L. Thornell, Jennifer F. Newman, Manoj K. Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c08264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Activity and Electrochemical Stability of Ru&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (M = Zr, Nb, Ta): Computational and Experimental Study of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01408</link>
      <description>Francisco Ospina&#8208;Acevedo, Luis A Albiter, Kathleen O. Bailey, Jos&#233; Fernando God&#237;nez-Salom&#243;n, Christopher P. Rhodes, Perla B. Balbuena, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392939927

                We use computations and experiments to determine the effect of substituting zirconium, niobium, and tantalum within rutile RuO2 on the structure, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) mechanism and activity, and electrochemical stability. Calculated electronic structures altered by Zr, Nb, and Ta show surface regions of electron density depletion and accumulation, along with anisotropic lattice parameter shifts dependent on the substitution site, substituent, and concentration. Consistent with theory, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy experiments show shifts in binding energies of O-2s, O-2p, and Ru-4d peaks due to the substituents. Experimentally, the substituted materials showed the presence of two phases with a majority phase that contains the metal substituent within the rutile phase and a second, smaller-percentage RuO2 phase. Our experimental analysis of OER activity shows Zr, Nb, and Ta substituents at 12.5 atom % induce lower activity relative to RuO2, which agrees with computing the average of all sites; however, Zr and Ta substitution at specific sites yields higher theoretical OER activity than RuO2, with Zr substitution suggesting an alternative OER mechanism. Metal dissolution predictions show the involvement of cooperative interactions among multiple surface sites and the electrolyte. Zr substitution at specific sites increases activation barriers for Ru dissolution, however, with Zr surface dissolution rates comparable to those of Ru. Experimental OER stability analysis shows lower Ru dissolution from synthesized RuO2 and Zr-substituted RuO2 compared to commercial RuO2 and comparable amounts of Zr and Ru dissolved from Zr-substituted RuO2, aligned with our calculations.</description>
      <author>Francisco Ospina&#8208;Acevedo, Luis A Albiter, Kathleen O. Bailey, Jos&#233; Fernando God&#237;nez-Salom&#243;n, Christopher P. Rhodes, Perla B. Balbuena</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the effects of Li/Na/K doping and point defects on the magnetic and photocatalytic properties of monolayer GaN (0 0 1)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113156</link>
      <description>Jianxiao Si, Qingyu Hou, Weiya Li, Yanxia Zhang, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392946948

                In the experimental preparation of monolayer GaN (0 0 1) by chemical-vapor deposition, H impurities inevitably remain, and the intrinsic defect VGa inevitably forms. In this research, generalized gradient approximation + U plane-wave ultrasoft pseudopotentials are computed using the density-functional theory framework. The effects of Li/Na/K doping and point defect (Hi-VGa) coexistence on the magnetic properties and photocatalytic properties of monolayer GaN (0 0 1) surfaces are investigated. Results show that the monolayer Ga34MN36 (M = Li/Na/K) (0 0 1) surfaces are magnetic, and the source of its magnetism is primarily the itinerant electrons of N2&#8722; ions. The monolayer Ga34MHiN36 (0 0 1) surfaces are relatively more stable, and the separation degree of carriers is better than the monolayer Ga34MN36 (0 0 1) surfaces. In particular, the monolayer Ga34LiHiN36 (0 0 1) surface has a large electric-dipole moment, strong carrier activity, strong absorption efficiency, and strong oxidation-reduction properties. Therefore, the monolayer Ga34LiHiN36 (0 0 1) surface is the most suitable photocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Jianxiao Si, Qingyu Hou, Weiya Li, Yanxia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of transition metal dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction based on high-throughput calculation and searching surrogate prediction model using simple features</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159942</link>
      <description>J. Wang, Wei Xu, Jun He, Hao Ma, Wanglai Cen, Yu Shen, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392948917

                Dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction have received widespread attention, but precise screening and prediction of high-performance catalysts through simple methods remains a challenge. In this study, we perform high-throughput density functional theory (DFT) calculation and machine learning (ML) to screen and predict the transition metal dual-atom catalysts with N-doped graphene support (TMDACs) for acidic hydrogen evolution reaction. The Fe_Zn and V_Fe DACs were proposed to be the most promising candidates for Pt-based catalyst toward acidic HER from 406 TMDACs, based on the characteristics of HER activity, formation, thermodynamic stability, abundance, environmental friendliness. The Fe_Zn and V_Fe DACs with excellent HER performance is due to the synergistic effect deriving from the interaction between H and dual metal atoms in TMDACs. By determining 6 different ML models with four kind of input features, we find the artificial neural networks (ANN) model can predict the HER performance of TMDACs most accurately only using simple input features, including one-hot-encoding of atomic number and Gibbs free energy of transition metal single-atom catalyst. This work not only proposed the potential TMDACs with high HER performance, but also verified that the ANN model can accurately predict the HER activity of diatomic catalysts with simple input features.</description>
      <author>J. Wang, Wei Xu, Jun He, Hao Ma, Wanglai Cen, Yu Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF/MXene Composites: Synthesis, Application and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400011</link>
      <description>Sakina Bibi, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, Mamona Nazir, Mohamed H. Helal, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, Sultan Ullah, Muhammad Ahmad Wattoo, Aziz ur Rehman, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392951886

                Abstract 2D MXenes family creates an interest in environmental cleaning and energy conversion. It shows large surface functional groups, electronic transmission, and electrical conductivity. This research focuses on Metal Organic Framework&#8208;based Ti 3 C 2 heterojunctions, directing on surface morphology control, customizable electrical structure, high performance in Ti 3 C 2 &#8208;based electrocatalytic devices, and energy storage as a supercapacitor. In addition, future development obstacles and viable research possibilities are presented. MXene detailed analysis reveals a fundamental study, structure&#8208;activity connections, and potential research paths for environmental applications. Specially developed MOF/MXene nanoarchitectures with remarkable features are highlighted in several study fields, including the chemical sciences, environmental engineering, physics, catalysis, and nanotechnology. They represent a new class of cutting&#8208;edge developing materials. Mainly, the presented review describes multiple synthesis approaches by adjusting conditions for MOF/MXene nanoarchitectures with varying morphologies, and intriguing properties can also be developed for electrochemical energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Sakina Bibi, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, Mamona Nazir, Mohamed H. Helal, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, Sultan Ullah, Muhammad Ahmad Wattoo, Aziz ur Rehman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru/Ir&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Conditions: From Mechanisms, Optimizations to Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202309364</link>
      <description>Qin Rong, Guanzhen Chen, Xueting Feng, Jian Weng, Yunhu Han, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392953409

                Abstract The generation of green hydrogen by water splitting is identified as a key strategic energy technology, and proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) is one of the desirable technologies for converting renewable energy sources into hydrogen. However, the harsh anode environment of PEMWE and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) involving four&#8208;electron transfer result in a large overpotential, which limits the overall efficiency of hydrogen production, and thus efficient electrocatalysts are needed to overcome the high overpotential and slow kinetic process. In recent years, noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts (e.g., Ru/Ir&#8208;based metal/oxide electrocatalysts) have received much attention due to their unique catalytic properties, and have already become the dominant electrocatalysts for the acidic OER process and are applied in commercial PEMWE devices. However, these noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts still face the thorny problem of conflicting performance and cost. In this review, first, noble metal Ru/Ir&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts are briefly classified according to their forms of existence, and the OER catalytic mechanisms are outlined. Then, the focus is on summarizing the improvement strategies of Ru/Ir&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts with respect to their activity and stability over recent years. Finally, the challenges and development prospects of noble metal&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts are discussed.</description>
      <author>Qin Rong, Guanzhen Chen, Xueting Feng, Jian Weng, Yunhu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202309364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Synthesis of CuPd Icosahedra Supercrystals Studied by In Situ X&#8208;Ray Scattering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311714</link>
      <description>Davide Derelli, Kilian Frank, Lukas Grote, Federica Mancini, Ann Christin Dippel, Olof Gutowski, Bert Nickel, Dorota Koziej, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392954128

                Abstract Nanocrystal self&#8208;assembly into supercrystals provides a versatile platform for creating novel materials and devices with tailored properties. While common self&#8208;assembly strategies imply the use of purified nanoparticles after synthesis, conversion of chemical precursors directly into nanocrystals and then supercrystals in simple procedures has been rarely reported. Here, the nucleation and growth of CuPd icosahedra and their consecutive assembly into large closed&#8208;packed face&#8208;centered cubic (fcc) supercrystals are studied. To this end, the study simultaneously and in situ measures X&#8208;ray total scattering with pair distribution function analysis (TS&#8208;PDF) and small&#8208;angle X&#8208;ray scattering (SAXS). It is found that the supercrystals' formation is preceded by an intermediate dense phase of nanocrystals displaying short&#8208;range order (SRO). It is further shown that the organization of oleic acid/oleylamine surfactants into lamellar structures likely drives the emergence of the SRO phase and later of the supercrystals by reducing the volume accessible to particle diffusion. The supercrystals' formation as well as their disassembly are triggered by temperature. The study demonstrates that ordering of solvent molecules can be crucial in the direct synthesis of supercrystals. The study also provides a general approach to investigate novel preparation routes of supercrystals in situ and across several length scales via X&#8208;ray scattering.</description>
      <author>Davide Derelli, Kilian Frank, Lukas Grote, Federica Mancini, Ann Christin Dippel, Olof Gutowski, Bert Nickel, Dorota Koziej</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biorefinery products from algal biomass by advanced biotechnological and hydrothermal liquefaction approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42452-024-05777-6</link>
      <description>Mathiyazhagan Narayanan, Discover Applied Sciences. 6(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392960733

                Abstract Algal biomass is a promising feedstock for the environmentally friendly production of a diverse range of high-value products, including bioproducts and biofuels. After extracting the essential macro- and biomolecules, the remaining algae biomass can be used as feedstock and processed into valuable additional goods. Advanced biotechnology techniques and efficient hydrothermal liquefaction (HTL) technologies are used to produce beneficial products such as bioenergy and biochemicals. Carbohydrates, lipids, and proteins are essential biochemical components of algal biomass that can be used to produce biofuel. Hence, algae biomass is gaining popularity as a biorefinery alternative. HTL is a process of converting biomass to a liquid byproduct by intricate chemical reactions. The purpose of this review is to highlight modern biotechnological and hydrothermal liquefaction techniques for extracting biological products from algae. A large number of documents were reviewed and analytically structured to lay the groundwork for the subsequent steps. This review also included information on a simple reaction mechanism for the biomass that algae produce, as well as the impact of process parameters.</description>
      <author>Mathiyazhagan Narayanan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42452-024-05777-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Layered Heterojunctions for Photoelectrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c12274</link>
      <description>Mengjiao Wang, Michal Langer, Roberto Altieri, Matteo Crisci, Silvio Osella, Teresa Gatti, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392970424

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengjiao Wang, Michal Langer, Roberto Altieri, Matteo Crisci, Silvio Osella, Teresa Gatti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c12274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a 3D Ni-Mn Binary Oxide Anode for Energy-Efficient Electro-Oxidation of Organic Pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112562</link>
      <description>Keyvan Mirehbar, Jaime S. Sanchez, Sergio Pinilla, Freddy E. Oropeza, Ignasi Sir&#233;s, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Jes&#250;s Palma, Julio J. Lado, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392974422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Keyvan Mirehbar, Jaime S. Sanchez, Sergio Pinilla, Freddy E. Oropeza, Ignasi Sir&#233;s, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Jes&#250;s Palma, Julio J. Lado</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin Amorphous NaIrRuOx Nanosheets with Rich Oxygen Vacancies for Efficient Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114660</link>
      <description>Junan Gao, Xiaofeng Wu, Xinying Teng, Xin Jing, Sung Lai Jimmy Yun, Hong Zhao, Jianwei Li, Jie Zhang, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392976595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junan Gao, Xiaofeng Wu, Xinying Teng, Xin Jing, Sung Lai Jimmy Yun, Hong Zhao, Jianwei Li, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal Intercalation/Alloying Hybrid Mechanism with &#8208;ICOHP Criterion in MAX Toward Steadily Ascending Lithium&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400099</link>
      <description>Xueyi Guo, Quan Zhou, Changda Wang, Yong Cao, Xiya Yang, Shiqiang Wei, Wenjie Xu, Shuangming Chen, Kehua Zhu, Pengjun Zhang, Hongwei Shou, Yixiu Wang, Peter Joseph Chimtali, Xiaojun Wu, Song Li, Xiaosong Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392978666

                Abstract Profiting from the unique atomic laminated structure, metallic conductivity, and superior mechanical properties, transition metal carbides and nitrides named MAX phases have shown great potential as anodes in lithium&#8208;ion batteries. However, the complexity of MAX configurations poses a challenge. To accelerate such application, a minus integrated crystal orbital Hamilton populations descriptor is innovatively proposed to rapidly evaluate the lithium storage potential of various MAX, along with density functional theory computations. It confirms that surface A&#8208;element atoms bound to lithium ions have odds of escaping from MAX. Interestingly, the activated A&#8208;element atoms enhance the reversible uptake of lithium ions by MAX anodes through an efficient alloying reaction. As an experimental verification, the charge compensation and Sn x Li y phase evolution of designed Zr 2 SnC MAX with optimized structure is visualized via in situ synchrotron radiation XRD and XAFS technique, which further clarifies the theoretically expected intercalation/alloying hybrid storage mechanism. Notably, Zr 2 SnC electrodes achieve remarkably 219.8% negative capacity attenuation over 3200 cycles at 1 A g &#8722;1 . In principle, this work provides a reference for the design and development of advanced MAX electrodes, which is essential to explore diversified applications of the MAX family in specific energy fields.</description>
      <author>Xueyi Guo, Quan Zhou, Changda Wang, Yong Cao, Xiya Yang, Shiqiang Wei, Wenjie Xu, Shuangming Chen, Kehua Zhu, Pengjun Zhang, Hongwei Shou, Yixiu Wang, Peter Joseph Chimtali, Xiaojun Wu, Song Li, Xiaosong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Effect of Solvent for Hydrogen Evolution in Pt-Doped Mxenes and Corresponding High-Entropy Phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4762261</link>
      <description>Zheng Shu, Zhangsheng Shi, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Teck Leong Tan, Yongqing Cai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392978980

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Zheng Shu, Zhangsheng Shi, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Teck Leong Tan, Yongqing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4762261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type Label Framework for Bonded Force Fields in LAMMPS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c08419</link>
      <description>Jacob R. Gissinger, Ilia Nikiforov, Yaser Afshar, Brendon Waters, Moon Han Choi, Daniel S. Karls, Alexander Stukowski, Wonpil Im, Hendrik Heinz, Axel Kohlmeyer, Ellad B. Tadmor, The Journal of Physical Chemistry B. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392987296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jacob R. Gissinger, Ilia Nikiforov, Yaser Afshar, Brendon Waters, Moon Han Choi, Daniel S. Karls, Alexander Stukowski, Wonpil Im, Hendrik Heinz, Axel Kohlmeyer, Ellad B. Tadmor</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c08419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of Stable Surfaces with Extreme Work Functions by High&#8208;Throughput Density Functional Theory and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401764</link>
      <description>Peter Schindler, Evan R. Antoniuk, Gowoon Cheon, Yanbing Zhu, Evan J. Reed, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392991859

                Abstract The work function is the key surface property that determines the energy required to extract an electron from the surface of a material. This property is crucial for thermionic energy conversion, band alignment in heterostructures, and electron emission devices. This work presents a high&#8208;throughput workflow using density functional theory (DFT) to calculate the work function and cleavage energy of 33,631 slabs (58,332 work functions) that are created from 3,716 bulk materials. The number of calculated surface properties surpasses the previously largest database by a factor of &#8776;27. Several surfaces with an ultra&#8208;low (&lt;2 eV) and ultra&#8208;high (&gt;7 eV) work function are identified. Specifically, the (100)&#8208;Ba&#8208;O surface of BaMoO 3 and the (001)&#8208;F surface of Ag 2 F have record&#8208;low (1.25 eV) and record&#8208;high (9.06 eV) steady&#8208;state work functions. Based on this database a physics&#8208;based approach to featurize surfaces is utilized to predict the work function. The random forest model achieves a test mean absolute error (MAE) of 0.09 eV, comparable to the accuracy of DFT. This surrogate model enables rapid predictions of the work function (&#8776; 10 5 faster than DFT) across a vast chemical space and facilitates the discovery of material surfaces with extreme work functions for energy conversion and electronic device applications.</description>
      <author>Peter Schindler, Evan R. Antoniuk, Gowoon Cheon, Yanbing Zhu, Evan J. Reed</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Activity of Trimetallic Oxygen Reduction PtNiMo/C Catalysts Through Initial Conditioning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400070</link>
      <description>Bilal Danisman, Guirong Zhang, Adrian F. Baumunk, Juntao Yang, Olaf Brummel, Philipp Darge, Dominik Dworschak, Karl Johann Jakob Mayrhofer, J&#246;rg Libuda, Xin Zhou, Mingjian Wu, Erdmann Spiecker, Marc Ledendecker, Bastian J. M. Etzold, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392993818

                Abstract This study investigates the importance of preconditioning in Pt&#8208;alloy catalysts for oxygen&#8211;reduction reactions. Previous research indicated that slower scanning rates during preconditioning initially boost activity, but this is followed by a rapid decline. The study reveals the required number of cycles to achieve the first constant steady state activity in PtNiMo/C catalysts when using slower scanning rates during preconditioning. It also highlights the resulting activity differences. Remarkably, a catalyst preconditioned with 150 slow cycles showed an activity of approximately 1.25 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0.90 V RHE , significantly higher than one preconditioned at a fast rate (0.82 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Both ex&#8211;situ and in&#8211;situ analyses revealed that Pt, along with Ni, was leached during pretreatment. At slower scan rates of 20 mV s &#8722;1 , the dissolved Pt redeposited as highly active, small&#8208;sized clusters or single atoms. Fast scan rates of of 500 mV s &#8722;1 , in contrast, resulted in fewer such clusters. Accelerated stress tests up to 1.10 V RHE confirmed the high stability of these clusters, demonstrating a substantial activity increase even after 24,000 cycles.</description>
      <author>Bilal Danisman, Guirong Zhang, Adrian F. Baumunk, Juntao Yang, Olaf Brummel, Philipp Darge, Dominik Dworschak, Karl Johann Jakob Mayrhofer, J&#246;rg Libuda, Xin Zhou, Mingjian Wu, Erdmann Spiecker, Marc Ledendecker, Bastian J. M. Etzold</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Extraction Process During Initial Oxidation of Pt(111): Effect of Hydrophilic/Hydrophobic Cations in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11334</link>
      <description>Tomoaki Kumeda, Kengo Kondo, Syunnosuke Tanaka, Osami Sakata, Nagahiro Hoshi, Masashi Nakamura, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392994699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tomoaki Kumeda, Kengo Kondo, Syunnosuke Tanaka, Osami Sakata, Nagahiro Hoshi, Masashi Nakamura</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Metastability-Triggered Reactivity of Pt&lt;sub&gt;7,8&lt;/sub&gt; Clusters on Graphene: Unraveling Statistical Ensemble Representation for ORR in Gas and Implicit Solvent Phases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00376</link>
      <description>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392999038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Quality and Reliability of Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials through Better Reporting Practices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00028</link>
      <description>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393002362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity and stability of catalysts for electrocatalytic water splitting in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2727-5</link>
      <description>Zhenbin Wang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393004005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenbin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2727-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Accuracy Matters: Applications of Machine Learned Potential Energy Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03405</link>
      <description>Silvan K&#228;ser, Markus Meuwly, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393025231

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silvan K&#228;ser, Markus Meuwly</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the crucial contribution of additive chromate to efficient and stable alkaline seawater oxidation on Ni-based layered double hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.132</link>
      <description>Lin Yang, Yao Ding, Xueqing Niu, Xinyue Xu, Kaicai Fan, Wen Ye, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Xiaofan Du, Tianrong Zhan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393029507

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lin Yang, Yao Ding, Xueqing Niu, Xinyue Xu, Kaicai Fan, Wen Ye, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Xiaofan Du, Tianrong Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Locating Transition States by Variational Reaction Path Optimization with an Energy-Derivative-Free Objective Function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01246</link>
      <description>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393031108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Machine Learning Model Focusing on Active Sites for the Discovery of Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts in Binary Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17377</link>
      <description>C Y Wang, Bing Wang, Changhao Wang, Zhipeng Chang, Mengqi Yang, Ruzhi Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393039373

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C Y Wang, Bing Wang, Changhao Wang, Zhipeng Chang, Mengqi Yang, Ruzhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converging Divergent Paths: Constant Charge vs Constant Potential Energetics in Computational Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07954</link>
      <description>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Simeon D. Beinlich, Karsten Reuter, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393040617

                Using the example of a proton adsorption process, we analyze and compare two prominent modeling approaches in computational electrochemistry at metallic electrodes&#9472;electronically canonical, constant-charge and electronically grand-canonical, constant-potential calculations. We first confirm that both methodologies yield consistent results for the differential free energy change in the infinite cell size limit. This validation emphasizes that, fundamentally, both methods are equally valid and precise. In practice, the grand-canonical, constant-potential approach shows superior interpretability and size convergence as it aligns closer to experimental ensembles and exhibits smaller finite-size effects. On the other hand, constant-charge calculations exhibit greater resilience against discrepancies, such as deviations in interfacial capacitance and absolute potential alignment, as their results inherently only depend on the surface charge and not on the modeled charge vs potential relation. The present analysis thus offers valuable insights and guidance for selecting the most appropriate ensemble when addressing diverse electrochemical challenges.</description>
      <author>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Simeon D. Beinlich, Karsten Reuter</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Neural Network Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00004</link>
      <description>Timothy T. Duignan, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393037991

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timothy T. Duignan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on Advancing Sustainable CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion Processes: Trinomial Technology, Environment, and Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07133</link>
      <description>Lourdes F. Vega, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Ismail I.I. Alkhatib, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393097423

                CO2 can be converted into value-added products such as fuels, chemicals, and building materials, adding an economic incentive for CO2 capture and green economy, while also reducing the environmental footprint of hard-to-abate industries such as aviation, construction, and metallurgy. Nonetheless, most available technologies for direct CO2 conversion, while promising, are still in early development stages, facing technical and economic challenges for their scale-up, questioning their viability to truly instill a timely impact on global CO2 emissions. Furthermore, a clear environmental benefit should be obtained for the new processes versus the traditional ones they are replacing in the market. In this perspective, we examine the range of available technologies for direct CO2 conversion using thermal, electrical, and photochemical routes and mineralization including the advancements in their role in synthesizing a range of resulting products from methanol, methane, carbon monoxide, and solid carbonates. We offer insights on the trends in current research and development and the required direction to expedite the technological readiness of attractive CO2 conversion technologies in terms of catalytic material and reactor design. We also highlight the important role of modeling (molecular and process levels) as an enabling tool to deploy these technologies at the commercial scale originating from understanding their behavior at the molecular level. Lastly, we highlight the significance of carrying out reliable life cycle analysis in identifying the environmental hotspots as well as gaps in the technology that allows improving their environmental footprint and economic attractiveness.</description>
      <author>Lourdes F. Vega, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Ismail I.I. Alkhatib</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending the definition of atomic basis sets to atoms with fractional nuclear charge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0196383</link>
      <description>Giorgio Domenichini, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393152656

                Alchemical transformations showed that perturbation theory can be applied also to changes in the atomic nuclear charges of a molecule. The alchemical path that connects two different chemical species involves the conceptualization of a non-physical system in which an atom possess a non-integer nuclear charge. A correct quantum mechanical treatment of these systems is limited by the fact that finite size atomic basis sets do not define exponents and contraction coefficients for fractional charge atoms. This paper proposes a solution to this problem and shows that a smooth interpolation of the atomic orbital coefficients and exponents across the periodic table is a convenient way to produce accurate alchemical predictions, even using small size basis sets.</description>
      <author>Giorgio Domenichini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0196383</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface structure determination by exhaustive search of asymmetric unit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.115430</link>
      <description>Xingxing Dong, Caiyun He, Chao He, Hui Wang, Shaogang Xu, Hu Xu, Physical review. 109(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393157853

                Determining surface structures is a substantial challenge due to the limitations of experimental techniques and the complexity of theoretical models. In this work, we use a method called the exhaustive search of asymmetric unit (ESAU), designed to identify surface structures through a detailed analysis of the asymmetric unit. This method employs two main strategies: narrowing the research area by focusing on a smaller, unique segment rather than the entire unit cell, and transforming the infinite possibilities of atomic positions into discrete, manageable units. These strategies allow us to systematically enumerate all potential surface structures. Employing the ESAU method, we have successfully replicated a variety of known surface structures, including two-dimensional materials on substrates, and have also uncovered some previously unknown structures. Importantly, the ESAU method shows significant promise not only in utilizing experimental data but also in predicting surface and crystal structures without prior experimental evidence. Our results affirm that the ESAU approach provides a comprehensive and efficient tool for uncovering material structures, paving the way for more in-depth studies on the properties and behaviors of materials.</description>
      <author>Xingxing Dong, Caiyun He, Chao He, Hui Wang, Shaogang Xu, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.115430</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
