<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 01:40:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Computational High-Throughput Screening of High-Performance Transition Metal C8n8 Single-Atom Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5234301</link>
      <description>Keyuan Chen, X.L. Zhang, Li Ma, Yongzhi Wu, Haijin Li, Jueyi Ye, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Zhaohua Liu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409875350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Keyuan Chen, X.L. Zhang, Li Ma, Yongzhi Wu, Haijin Li, Jueyi Ye, Ju Rong, Xiaohua Yu, Zhaohua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5234301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation the Coordination of Fe-Co Diatomic Sites with Boron Atom for Fuel Cells and Zn-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5233860</link>
      <description>Dai Dang, Lin Zhang, Guifa Long, Chao Liu, Wenjun Fan, Jie Zheng, Tiejun Wang, Quanbing Liu, Xiaopeng Han, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409882712

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dai Dang, Lin Zhang, Guifa Long, Chao Liu, Wenjun Fan, Jie Zheng, Tiejun Wang, Quanbing Liu, Xiaopeng Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5233860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting electrocatalysts design combining general thermodynamic evaluation and specific kinetic study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116175</link>
      <description>Lu Han, Jun Long, Huan Li, Hao Li, Jianping Xiao, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409887124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Han, Jun Long, Huan Li, Hao Li, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Size Fits All? Development of the CPOSS209 Data Set of Experimental and Hypothetical Polymorphs for Testing Computational Modeling Methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00255</link>
      <description>Louise S. Price, Matteo Paloni, Matteo Salvalaglio, Sarah L. Price, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409887865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Louise S. Price, Matteo Paloni, Matteo Salvalaglio, Sarah L. Price</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A pH-dependent microkinetic modeling guided synthesis of porous dual-atom catalysts for efficient oxygen reduction in Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ee00215j</link>
      <description>Ting&#8208;Ting Li, Di Zhang, Yun Zhang, Dujuan Yang, Runxin Li, Fuyun Yu, Kengqiang Zhong, Xiaozhi Su, Tian&#8208;Wei Song, Long Jiao, Hai&#8208;Long Jiang, Guo&#8208;Ping Sheng, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Zhenyu Wu, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409889319

                Guided by the pH-field microkinetic model, we developed an porous Fe 1 Co 1 &#8211;N&#8211;C ORR catalyst, which exhibited excellent performance in zinc&#8211;air batteries and provided insights for advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ting&#8208;Ting Li, Di Zhang, Yun Zhang, Dujuan Yang, Runxin Li, Fuyun Yu, Kengqiang Zhong, Xiaozhi Su, Tian&#8208;Wei Song, Long Jiao, Hai&#8208;Long Jiang, Guo&#8208;Ping Sheng, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Zhenyu Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ee00215j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dissolution: Paths in High-Entropy Alloy Composition Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00057-3</link>
      <description>Mads K. Plenge, Jack K. Pedersen, Luis A. Cipriano, Jan Rossmeisl, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409906731

                Abstract The stability of a nanoparticle catalyst during electrochemical reaction is crucial for its application. Despite increasing interest in multi-metallic alloy nanoparticles, such as high-entropy alloys (HEAs), for electrocatalysis and emerging models for their catalytic activity, there is limited work on frameworks that can predict the metastability of these alloys under reaction conditions, including stability against electrochemical surface dissolution. Incorporating electrochemical stability in multi-objective optimization would advance HEAs as a catalyst discovery platform. To address the knowledge gap on electrochemical stability, we propose a methodology for simulating the dissolution of n-element alloy nanoparticles comprised of density functional theory and machine-learning regression to calculate the dissolution potentials of the surface atoms. We demonstrate the methodology for the Ag&#8211;Au&#8211;Cu&#8211;Ir&#8211;Pd&#8211;Pt&#8211;Rh&#8211;Ru HEA system with the conditions of the oxygen reduction reaction. We investigated trends in stability against dissolution through a compositional grid search for the octo-metallic composition space, uncovering two alloying strategies to increase stability against electrochemical surface dissolution: Alloying with a noble metal or a metal with high relative surface energy. In the simulations, stabilization ensues from forming a protective surface layer, and consequently, the dissolution of persistent alloyed nanoparticles results in core&#8211;shell structures. The model enables tracing the evolution of the surface and dissolved composition during electrochemical dissolution, forming paths of dissolution and revealing unretainable surface compositions. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Mads K. Plenge, Jack K. Pedersen, Luis A. Cipriano, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00057-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing economic viability in carbon capture and storage with enhanced oil recovery projects: A dynamic stochastic approach to CO2 monitoring cost optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cie.2025.111187</link>
      <description>Peng Wu, Shansen Wei, Chengwei Lv, Qiangqiang Ren, Hong Wang, Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409907428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Wu, Shansen Wei, Chengwei Lv, Qiangqiang Ren, Hong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cie.2025.111187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High entropy alloy CoCrFeNiAlMox coatings as cost-effective bifunctional catalysts for enhanced water electrolysis efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163357</link>
      <description>Xiaoran Huo, Yuanwu Zhang, Jinyuan Zhong, Ge Zhou, Xiaojiao Zuo, Nannan Zhang, Xuelu Xu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409911950

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoran Huo, Yuanwu Zhang, Jinyuan Zhong, Ge Zhou, Xiaojiao Zuo, Nannan Zhang, Xuelu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Solution for Modeling Electrocatalysis on Two-Dimensional Single-Atom Catalysts with Grand Canonical DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00199</link>
      <description>Zhen Liu, Yifan Sun, Yinghong Wang, Wei Zhang, Li&#8208;Hua Gan, Xiaohong Liu, Liu&#8208;Bin Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409914615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhen Liu, Yifan Sun, Yinghong Wang, Wei Zhang, Li&#8208;Hua Gan, Xiaohong Liu, Liu&#8208;Bin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sr and Co Co-doping on Thermochemical Energy Storage Properties of CaMnO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00261</link>
      <description>Ruiqing Zhang, Guanyu Li, Shiyi Chen, Wenguo Xiang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409917877

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruiqing Zhang, Guanyu Li, Shiyi Chen, Wenguo Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tribological and micromechanical performance of hard yet tough TiSiN/WN coatings: An experimental analysis of multilayer effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrmhm.2025.107212</link>
      <description>Olga Maksakova, Kateryna Smyrnova, Barbora Ludrovcov&#225;, Miroslav Sahul, Mari&#225;n Har&#353;&#225;ni, Martin Truchl&#253;, Miroslav Sahul, Tom&#225;&#353; Vopat, Matej Pa&#353;&#225;k, A.O. Kozak, A.D. Pogrebnjak, International Journal of Refractory Metals and Hard Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409919530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Olga Maksakova, Kateryna Smyrnova, Barbora Ludrovcov&#225;, Miroslav Sahul, Mari&#225;n Har&#353;&#225;ni, Martin Truchl&#253;, Miroslav Sahul, Tom&#225;&#353; Vopat, Matej Pa&#353;&#225;k, A.O. Kozak, A.D. Pogrebnjak</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrmhm.2025.107212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold-catalyzed construction of atomically rough surfaces towards high-efficiency ethanol electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2025.04.051</link>
      <description>Qing Zeng, Mengyuan Ma, Hui Liu, Lin Xu, Shaonan Tian, Dong Chen, Jing Wang, Jun Yang, Science Bulletin. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409920621

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Zeng, Mengyuan Ma, Hui Liu, Lin Xu, Shaonan Tian, Dong Chen, Jing Wang, Jun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2025.04.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced phosphoric acid tolerance and intrinsic activity of ordered platinum-zinc alloy catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137739</link>
      <description>Hong Zhang, Huanqiao Li, Xiaoming Zhang, Shansheng Yu, Suli Wang, Gongquan Sun, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409922306

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Zhang, Huanqiao Li, Xiaoming Zhang, Shansheng Yu, Suli Wang, Gongquan Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen electrocatalytic enhancement through strong hybridization of active centers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146348</link>
      <description>Xi Chen, Huating Liu, Xiang Qi, Jianxin Zhong, Zongyu Huang, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409922436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xi Chen, Huating Liu, Xiang Qi, Jianxin Zhong, Zongyu Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A grain boundary embrittlement genome for substitutional cubic alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0264543</link>
      <description>Nutth Tuchinda, G. B. Olson, Christopher A. Schuh, Applied Physics Letters. 126(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409933088

                Grain boundary chemistry plays a critical role for the properties of metals and alloys, yet there is a lack of consistent datasets for alloy design and development. With the advent of artificial intelligence and machine learning in materials science, open materials models and datasets can be used to overcome such challenges. Here, we use a universal interatomic potential to compute a grain boundary segregation and embrittlement genome for the &#931;5[001](210) grain boundary for FCC and BCC binary alloys. The grain boundary database calculated here serves as a design tool for the embrittlement of high-angle grain boundaries for alloys across 30 base metals of Ag, Al, Au, Ba, Ca, Ce, Co, Cr, Cs, Cu, Fe (both BCC and FCC), Ir, K, Li, Mo, Na, Nb, Ni, Pb, Pd, Pt, Rb, Rh, Sr, Ta, Ti, V, W, Yb, and Zr with 75 solute elements for each.</description>
      <author>Nutth Tuchinda, G. B. Olson, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0264543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Nickel&#8208;Based Catalysts for Alkaline Water Electrolysis: Comprehensive Review of Current Research Direction for HER and OER Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202500049</link>
      <description>Ivana Perovi&#263;, Stefan Mitrovi&#263;, Sne&#382;ana Brkovi&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409950640

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;based catalysts are among the most promising materials for electrocatalytic water splitting, particularly for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. Their abundance, cost&#8208;effectiveness, and tunable electrochemical properties make them attractive alternatives to precious metal catalysts. This review provides a comprehensive analysis of the advancements in nickel&#8208;based catalysts, including pure nickel, alloys, oxides, hydroxides, and spinels, emphasizing their synthesis methods, structural properties, and electrocatalytic performance. Recent nanostructuring, doping, and hybridization innovations with conductive supports have significantly enhanced catalytic activity, stability, and efficiency. Despite notable progress, challenges remain in improving long&#8208;term durability, minimizing surface degradation, and scaling up production for industrial applications. Addressing these limitations through advanced catalyst design, in situ characterization, and integration with renewable energy sources will be crucial for widely adopting nickel&#8208;based catalysts in sustainable hydrogen production. This review highlights the key developments and future directions in the field, underscoring the role of nickel&#8208;based materials in enabling the hydrogen economy and global decarbonization efforts.</description>
      <author>Ivana Perovi&#263;, Stefan Mitrovi&#263;, Sne&#382;ana Brkovi&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202500049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into the Activation and Conversion of Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on 3&lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt; Transition Metal&#8208;Doped Cu(111) Stepped Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500095</link>
      <description>Lihong Yin, Jinxian Feng, Weng Fai Ip, Guangfu Luo, Hui Pan, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409959087

                The activation of CO 2 is essential for efficient electrochemical conversion, yet its weak physisorption on pristine Cu surfaces severely hinders catalytic performance. To overcome this limitation, we designed Cu stepped structures to create highly reactive sites for enhanced CO 2 adsorption and further doped the edges with 3 d transition metals (V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, and Ni) to improve CO 2 reduction. Density functional theory calculations reveal that these dopants significantly reduce the O&#63743;C&#63743;O angles and elongate the C&#63743;O bonds, transforming CO 2 from its original linear configuration into a bent geometry at the interface. Notably, dual&#8208;V and dual&#8208;Fe doping on Cu stepped surfaces demonstrates a strong interaction with CO 2 , leading to a high degree of activation. The computational results demonstrate that these modifications significantly enhance CO 2 activation and favor methane generation. This study provides valuable insights into the design of advanced Cu&#8208;based electrocatalysts for efficient and selective CO 2 activation, offering a pathway toward sustainable CO 2 utilization.</description>
      <author>Lihong Yin, Jinxian Feng, Weng Fai Ip, Guangfu Luo, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internal hydrogen-bond enhanced two-electron oxygen reduction reaction for &#960;-d conjugated metal-organic framework to H2O2 synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58628-2</link>
      <description>Zhiyuan Sang, Yuqian Qiao, Rui Chen, Lichang Yin, Feng Hou, Ji Liang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409965445

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyuan Sang, Yuqian Qiao, Rui Chen, Lichang Yin, Feng Hou, Ji Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58628-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni Foam Supported Pd&#8208;Doped Zinc Spinel Oxide Nano&#8208;Electrocatalyst for Efficient Hydrogen Production Supported by DFT Study as Well Validated With Experimental Data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500142</link>
      <description>Refah S. Alkhaldi, M. Abdulwahab, M.A. Gondal, Mohamed Jaffer Sadiq Mohamed, M.A. Almessiere, A. Baykal, Abduljabar Q. Alsayoud, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409966799

                Abstract An innovative palladium&#8208;doped zinc cobalt oxide nanoelectrocatalyst, ZnPd x Co 2&#8208;x O 4 (0.00 &#8804; x &#8804; 0.08)@NF, is successfully synthesized using a hydrothermal method. The resulting material exhibits a spinel oxide phase, as confirmed by X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD). The electrocatalytic performance of ZnPd x Co 2&#8208;x O 4 (0.00 &#8804; x &#8804; 0.08)@NF is evaluated for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The results show significant improvements in efficient hydrogen production, with an overpotential of 31 mV, a Tafel slope of 54.36 mV dec&#8315; 1 , and sustained stability for over 72 h, using chronopotentiometry methods. Doping with 8.0% Pd concentration enhances the highest electrochemical performance of the nanoelectrocatalyst, supporting the idea that Pd doping improves HER activity. The results suggest that the increased electrochemical active surface area (ECSA) and faster charge transfer kinetics at the interface between the semiconductor and electrolyte contribute to enhanced performance. The DFT calculations performed in this work confirm the role of Pd in improving the catalytic activity of the ZnCo 2 O 4 spinel catalyst. Overall, this study has made a significant contribution to the development of sustainable energy solutions, offering a promising path toward the efficient production of hydrogen fuel.</description>
      <author>Refah S. Alkhaldi, M. Abdulwahab, M.A. Gondal, Mohamed Jaffer Sadiq Mohamed, M.A. Almessiere, A. Baykal, Abduljabar Q. Alsayoud</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A mini review on revolutionizing hydrogenation catalysis: unleashing transformative power of artificial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06376-x</link>
      <description>Anurag Mishra, Vikesh G. Lade, Jyoti Ramesh Barmar, Ankush B. Bindwal, Ramesh P. Birmod, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 31(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409968805

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anurag Mishra, Vikesh G. Lade, Jyoti Ramesh Barmar, Ankush B. Bindwal, Ramesh P. Birmod</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06376-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Electric Fields and Strain Modulated Photocatalytic Performance in Monolayer Janus Piezoelectric AlBX2(X = O/S/Se/Te)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417339</link>
      <description>Hao An, Zhiyang Yuan, Chun-Sheng Liu, Lan Meng, Wei Yan, Xiaohong Yan, Physica B Condensed Matter. 712(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409978877

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao An, Zhiyang Yuan, Chun-Sheng Liu, Lan Meng, Wei Yan, Xiaohong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand Engineering of Co&#8208;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for Highly&#8208;Active and Stable Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202502230</link>
      <description>Taewon Jeong, Ki-Won Kim, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Chang Hyuck Choi, Joonhee Kang, Myeongjin Kim, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409983570

                The development of stable and efficient single-atom catalysts (SACs) for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media remains challenging. This work reports a novel NH3-assisted pyrolysis strategy to synthesize Co-N4 SACs with controlled nitrogen coordination environments on crumpled graphene supports. The pyrrolic N4-coordinated Co sites demonstrate superior OER activity compared to their pyridinic counterparts, achieving an overpotential of 351 mV at 10 mA cm-2 in 0.5 m H2SO4. Combined density functional theory calculations and operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy reveal that the pyrrolic coordination environment facilitates enhanced OH- adsorption and subsequent OER kinetics due to its unique electronic structure and geometric flexibility. A multi-layered protective mechanism in the pyrrolic system enables exceptional stability during long-term acidic OER operation, stemming from higher defect formation energy of Co sites and strategic distribution of sacrificial nitrogen species in the graphene network. These findings provide fundamental insights into designing stable single-atom catalysts for challenging electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Taewon Jeong, Ki-Won Kim, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Chang Hyuck Choi, Joonhee Kang, Myeongjin Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202502230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Electrostatic Shielding Effect by 18-Crown-6 Ether for Achieving Stable Deposition of Potassium Metal Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00797</link>
      <description>Hyokyeong Kang, Hyeona Park, Josef Rizell, Aleksandar Matic, Shizhao Xiong, Dong&#8208;Kyu Kim, Hyeyoung Shin, Yangyang Liu, Xieyu Xu, Yang&#8208;Kook Sun, Jang&#8208;Yeon Hwang, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409983816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyokyeong Kang, Hyeona Park, Josef Rizell, Aleksandar Matic, Shizhao Xiong, Dong&#8208;Kyu Kim, Hyeyoung Shin, Yangyang Liu, Xieyu Xu, Yang&#8208;Kook Sun, Jang&#8208;Yeon Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realizing Direct Hot-Electron Transfer from Metal Nanoparticles to Per- and Polyfluoroalkyl Substances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00373</link>
      <description>P. K. Verma, Samir Kumar Nayak, Khushboo Bhardwaj, Sharma S. R. K. C. Yamijala, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409984514

                Per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) are a group of forever synthetic chemicals. They are widely utilized in industries and household appliances because of their remarkable stability and distinctive oil- and water-repellent properties. Despite their broad applications, unfortunately, PFAS are hazardous to all forms of life, including humans. In recent years, the environmental persistence of PFAS has raised significant interest in degrading these substances. However, the strong C-F bonds in these chemicals pose several challenges to their degradation. Plasmons of noble metal nanoparticles (NPs) offer many exciting applications, including photocatalytic reactions. However, an atomistic understanding of plasmon-driven processes remains elusive. In this work, using the real-time time-dependent density functional theory, we have studied the real-time formation of plasmons, hot-carrier generation, and subsequent direct hot-carrier transfer from metal NPs to the PFAS. Our simulations show that there is an apparent direct hot-electron transfer from NPs to PFAS. Moreover, using Ehrenfest dynamics simulations, we demonstrated that the transferred hot electrons can efficiently degrade PFAS without requiring any external thermal bath. Thus, our work provides an atomistic picture of plasmon-induced direct hot-carrier transfer from NPs to PFAS and the efficient degradation of PFAS. We strongly believe that this work generates the impetus to utilize plasmonic NPs to mitigate PFAS.</description>
      <author>P. K. Verma, Samir Kumar Nayak, Khushboo Bhardwaj, Sharma S. R. K. C. Yamijala</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional alkali auride bimetallene semiconductors for activating photocatalytic water splitting: Synergistic interaction of electronegativity difference and carrier mobility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137723</link>
      <description>Jinbo Hao, Bixuan Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Chunling Zhang, Ge Wu, Yuanzi Li, Qiyu Li, Shuli Gao, Jiaojiao Pan, Hengfeng Gong, Pengfei Lu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409999744

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinbo Hao, Bixuan Zhang, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Chunling Zhang, Ge Wu, Yuanzi Li, Qiyu Li, Shuli Gao, Jiaojiao Pan, Hengfeng Gong, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Cu&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; in the Oxygen Evolution Activity of Copper Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18147</link>
      <description>Pooja Basera, Yang Zhao, Angel T. Garcia&#8208;Esparza, Finn Babbe, Neha Bothra, John Vinson, Dimosthenis Sokaras, Junko Yano, Shannon W. Boettcher, Michal Bajdich, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410002913

                Cu-based oxides and hydroxides represent an important class of materials from a catalytic and corrosion perspective. In this study, we investigate the formation of bulk and surface Cu3+ species that are stable under water oxidation catalysis in alkaline media. So far, no direct evidence existed for the presence of hydroxides (CuOOH) or oxides, which were primarily proposed by theory. This work directly places CuOOH in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) Pourbaix stability region with a calculated free energy of -208.68 kJ/mol, necessitating a revision of known Cu-H2O phase diagrams. We also predict that the active sites of CuOOH for the OER are consistent with a bridge O* site between the two Cu3+ atoms with onset at &#8805;1.6 V vs the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), aligning with experimentally observed Cu2+/3+ oxidation waves in cyclic voltammetry of Fe-free and Fe-spiked copper in alkaline media. Trace amounts of Fe (2 &#956;g/mL (ppm) to 5 &#956;g/mL) in the solution measurably enhance the catalytic activity of the OER, likely due to the adsorption of Fe species that serve as the active sites . Importantly, modulation excitation X-ray absorption spectroscopy (ME-XAS) of a Cu thin-film electrode shows a distinct Cu3+ fingerprint under OER conditions at 1.8 V vs RHE. Additionally, in situ Raman spectroscopy of polycrystalline Cu in 0.1 mol/L (M) KOH revealed features consistent with those calculated for CuOOH in addition to CuO. Overall, this work provides direct evidence of bulk electrochemical Cu3+ species under OER conditions and expands our longstanding understanding of the oxidation mechanism and catalytic activity of copper.</description>
      <author>Pooja Basera, Yang Zhao, Angel T. Garcia&#8208;Esparza, Finn Babbe, Neha Bothra, John Vinson, Dimosthenis Sokaras, Junko Yano, Shannon W. Boettcher, Michal Bajdich</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Femtosecond laser-induced diffusion and desorption of CO adsorbed on a weak electron&#8211;phonon coupling surface: Cu(110)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0256832</link>
      <description>Federico J. Gonzalez, Alberto S. Muzas, J. I. Juaristi, M. Alducin, H. F. Busnengo, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410005931

                In this work, we perform molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of CO molecules chemisorbed on Cu(110) under femtosecond laser irradiation. We use the two temperature model and a previously developed potential energy surface based on density functional theory total energies (obtained using the nonlocal vdW-DF2 functional) and parameterized using artificial neural networks. We find that laser irradiation induces diffusion parallel to [1&#772;10] much more efficiently than parallel to [001] due to a significantly smaller energy barrier in the former case (i.e., 0.12 vs 0.49 eV). We also observe photoinduced desorption (an endothermic process characterized by &#916;E = 0.6 eV) with a probability that exhibits a power law dependence with laser fluence. At the lowest fluence studied (F = 30 J m-2), for which experimental data are available, the theoretical photoinduced diffusion probabilities both parallel and perpendicular to [1&#772;10] agree with the measured values, whereas our calculations predict desorption probabilities smaller than those obtained in experiments. Our MD simulations show that (i) the energy exchange with the hot electron bath is the main responsible for photoinduced processes and (ii) phonons tend to reduce the kinetic energy of the adsorbate, as keeping fixed the position of the Cu atoms during the simulations (thereby quenching CO-phonon energy exchange) significantly increases CO diffusion and desorption probabilities. Thus, our study advances the understanding of ultrafast surface dynamics on metal surfaces with weak electron-phonon coupling, and we hope that it will motivate further experimental investigations.</description>
      <author>Federico J. Gonzalez, Alberto S. Muzas, J. I. Juaristi, M. Alducin, H. F. Busnengo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0256832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles analysis of effects of cerium doping on electrochemical corrosion behaviors of steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2025.04.027</link>
      <description>Xiangjun Liu, Zhongqiao Ma, Changqiao Yang, Xiang Li, Jichun Yang, Huiping Ren, Hui Ma, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410012128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangjun Liu, Zhongqiao Ma, Changqiao Yang, Xiang Li, Jichun Yang, Huiping Ren, Hui Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2025.04.027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The application and research progress of d-band center theory in the field of water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.305</link>
      <description>Kui Li, Zhiwei Tao, Xinxia Ma, Jiang Wu, Tianyu Wu, Chengjie Guo, Yumin Qi, Jinlei Yu, Jiaqi Zheng, Jianying Xue, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 132(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410016001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kui Li, Zhiwei Tao, Xinxia Ma, Jiang Wu, Tianyu Wu, Chengjie Guo, Yumin Qi, Jinlei Yu, Jiaqi Zheng, Jianying Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational exploration of codoped Fe and Ru single-atom catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116163</link>
      <description>Haojun Jia, Chenru Duan, Gianmarco Terrones, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410016665

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haojun Jia, Chenru Duan, Gianmarco Terrones, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese-containing electrocatalysts for sustainable acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100427</link>
      <description>Wenqi Jia, Licheng Miao, Xuejie Cao, Xiaojie Chen, Ting Jin, Fangyi Cheng, Lifang Jiao, Jun Chen, eScience. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410022192

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqi Jia, Licheng Miao, Xuejie Cao, Xiaojie Chen, Ting Jin, Fangyi Cheng, Lifang Jiao, Jun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From pages to patterns: Towards extracting catalytic knowledge from structure and text for transition-metal complexes and metal-organic frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116174</link>
      <description>Aditya Nandy, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410023182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aditya Nandy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeePMD-kit v3: A Multiple-Backend Framework for Machine Learning Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00340</link>
      <description>Jinzhe Zeng, Duo Zhang, Anyang Peng, Xiangyu Zhang, S Z He, Yan Wang, Xinzijian Liu, Hangrui Bi, Yifan Li, Chun Cai, Chengqian Zhang, Yiming Du, Jiaxin Zhu, Pinghui Mo, Zhengtao Huang, Qiyu Zeng, Shaochen Shi, Xuejian Qin, Zhaoxi Yu, Chenxing Luo, Ye Ding, Yun&#8208;Pei Liu, Ruosong Shi, Zhenyu Wang, Sigbj&#248;rn L&#248;land Bore, Junhan Chang, Zhe Deng, Zhaonan Ding, Siyuan Han, Wanrun Jiang, Guolin Ke, Zhaoqing Liu, Denghui Lu, Koki Muraoka, Hananeh Oliaei, Anurag Kumar Singh, Haohui Que, Weihong Xu, Zhangmancang Xu, Yong&#8208;Bin Zhuang, Jiayu Dai, Timothy J. Giese, Weile Jia, Ben Bin Xu, Darrin M. York, Linfeng Zhang, Han Wang, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410027863

                In recent years, machine learning potentials (MLPs) have become indispensable tools in physics, chemistry, and materials science, driving the development of software packages for molecular dynamics (MD) simulations and related applications. These packages, typically built on specific machine learning frameworks, such as TensorFlow, PyTorch, or JAX, face integration challenges when advanced applications demand communication across different frameworks. The previous TensorFlow-based implementation of the DeePMD-kit exemplified these limitations. In this work, we introduce DeePMD-kit version 3, a significant update featuring a multibackend framework that supports TensorFlow, PyTorch, JAX, and PaddlePaddle backends, and demonstrate the versatility of this architecture through the integration of other MLP packages and of differentiable molecular force fields. This architecture allows seamless back-end switching with minimal modifications, enabling users and developers to integrate DeePMD-kit with other packages using different machine learning frameworks. This innovation facilitates the development of more complex and interoperable workflows, paving the way for broader applications of MLPs in scientific research.</description>
      <author>Jinzhe Zeng, Duo Zhang, Anyang Peng, Xiangyu Zhang, S Z He, Yan Wang, Xinzijian Liu, Hangrui Bi, Yifan Li, Chun Cai, Chengqian Zhang, Yiming Du, Jiaxin Zhu, Pinghui Mo, Zhengtao Huang, Qiyu Zeng, Shaochen Shi, Xuejian Qin, Zhaoxi Yu, Chenxing Luo, Ye Ding, Yun&#8208;Pei Liu, Ruosong Shi, Zhenyu Wang, Sigbj&#248;rn L&#248;land Bore, Junhan Chang, Zhe Deng, Zhaonan Ding, Siyuan Han, Wanrun Jiang, Guolin Ke, Zhaoqing Liu, Denghui Lu, Koki Muraoka, Hananeh Oliaei, Anurag Kumar Singh, Haohui Que, Weihong Xu, Zhangmancang Xu, Yong&#8208;Bin Zhuang, Jiayu Dai, Timothy J. Giese, Weile Jia, Ben Bin Xu, Darrin M. York, Linfeng Zhang, Han Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles investigation of Pt-doped Zr2CSeT (T = F, Cl, Br, I) as high-performance bifunctional ORR/OER catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417348</link>
      <description>Pengfei Liu, Xiao&#8208;Hong Li, Rui-Zhou Zhang, Hong&#8208;Ling Cui, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410031087

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Liu, Xiao&#8208;Hong Li, Rui-Zhou Zhang, Hong&#8208;Ling Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untangling the Mechanisms in Magneto&#8208;Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412852</link>
      <description>Amy Radford, Dorottya Szalay, Qiming Chen, Mengfan Ying, Mingyu Luo, Xuelei Pan, Michail Stamatakis, Yiyang Li, Chen Wu, Shik Chi Edman Tsang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410035834

                Abstract External magnetic fields emerge as a promising method for enhancing the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), yet the underlying magneto&#8208;electric (ME) mechanisms are not well understood. The slow kinetics of OER make it a key challenge in electrocatalytic water&#8208;splitting, a promising technique for sustainable H 2 fuel production. Herein, a systematic approach is presented to analyzing the ME mechanisms governing OER, using metallic&#8208;plate (Ni foam, Ni sheet, and Pt sheet) and powder&#8208;based (Co 3 O 4 /BaFe 12 O 19 on carbon paper) electrodes. Through controlled experiments using varying magnetic field strengths and orientations, Lorentz force and spin&#8208;polarization mechanisms are separated. For metallic electrodes, the effects are orientation&#8208;dependent, indicating domination by Lorentz force. Magnetic flux density about the electrode surface is shown to govern the Lorentz force behavior. Interestingly, a &#8220;pseudo&#8221; effect is discovered which results from the relative position of the reference electrode, highlighting the importance of experimental design. The Co 3 O 4 systems display minimal orientation dependence, indicating spin&#8208;polarization domination. Introducing BaFe 12 O 19 as a magnetic co&#8208;catalyst further amplifies the ME effect, marking the first demonstration of magnetic co&#8208;catalyst enhancement in magneto&#8208;electrocatalysis. This work provides key insights into ME mechanisms, linking electrode composition, magnetism, and geometry to performance, offering new pathways for optimizing future magneto&#8208;electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Amy Radford, Dorottya Szalay, Qiming Chen, Mengfan Ying, Mingyu Luo, Xuelei Pan, Michail Stamatakis, Yiyang Li, Chen Wu, Shik Chi Edman Tsang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Size and Shape Effects on the Structure Sensitivity of the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Methanation Reaction on Nickel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c08084</link>
      <description>Giulia Spano, Matteo Ferri, Raffaele Cheula, Matteo Monai, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Matteo Maestri, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410037436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Giulia Spano, Matteo Ferri, Raffaele Cheula, Matteo Monai, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Matteo Maestri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c08084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven discovery of single-atom catalysts for CO2 reduction considering the pH-dependency at the reversible hydrogen electrode scale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0267969</link>
      <description>Yue Chu, Yuhang Wang, Di Zhang, Xuedan Song, Chang Yu, Hao Li, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410045038

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) represents a promising approach to mitigating climate change and addressing energy challenges by converting CO2 into value-added chemicals. Among various CO2RR products, CO is attractive due to its economic viability and industrial relevance. By integrating large-scale data mining (with 939 experimental performance data), we reveal that the catalytic performance of d-block transition metal-based single-atom catalysts (SACs) for CO2RR is influenced not only by the coordination environment but also significantly by pH. However, the unified model that could accurately depict the pH-dependent CO2RR to CO activity of d-block SACs is urgently needed. Herein, we conducted pH-dependent microkinetic modeling based upon density functional theory calculations and pH-electric field coupled microkinetic modeling to analyze CO2RR performance of 101 SACs. Our data-driven screening identifies 12 high-performance SACs with promising CO selectivity across different pH conditions, primarily based on Fe, Cu, and Ni centers. We establish a scaling relation between key intermediates (*COOH and *CO) and analyze their adsorption behaviors under varying electrochemical conditions. Furthermore, our pH-dependent microkinetic modeling reveals the critical role of electric field effects in determining catalytic performance, aligning well with experimental turnover frequency values. Most importantly, our theoretical model accurately captures the pH-dependent performance of CO2RR-to-CO on d-block SACs, which is experimentally validated and serves as a general theoretical framework for the rational design of high-performance CO2RR catalysts. Based on this model, we identify a series of promising M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts, providing a universal design principle for optimizing CO2-to-CO conversion.</description>
      <author>Yue Chu, Yuhang Wang, Di Zhang, Xuedan Song, Chang Yu, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0267969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical study on ion irradiation engineered defect formation and hydrogen evolution on two-dimensional MoS2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2025.100873</link>
      <description>Jiahua Xu, Tianzhao Li, Wenjin Gao, Miaogen Chen, Jinge Wu, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou, FlatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410055577

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahua Xu, Tianzhao Li, Wenjin Gao, Miaogen Chen, Jinge Wu, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2025.100873</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Study on Direct Z-Scheme SnC/SnS2 Heterostructures for Photocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7030076</link>
      <description>Sisi Zhou, Yuliang Mao, Chemistry. 7(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410069172

                Direct Z-scheme heterojunctions are known for their unique carrier mobility mechanism, which significantly improves photocatalytic water splitting efficiency. In this study, we use first-principles simulations to determine the stability, electrical, and photocatalytic properties of a SnC/SnS2 heterojunction. Analyses of the projected energy band and state density demonstrate that the SnC/SnS2 heterojunction exhibits an indirect band gap of 0.80 eV and a type-II band alignment. Analysis of its work function shows that the SnC/SnS2 heterojunction has a built-in electric field pointing from the SnC monolayer to the SnS2 monolayer. The band edge position and the differential charge density indicate that the SnC/SnS2 heterostructure exhibits a Z-scheme photocatalytic mechanism. Furthermore, the SnC/SnS2 heterojunction exhibits excellent visible-light absorption and high solar-to-hydrogen efficiency of 32.8%. It is found that the band gap and light absorption of the heterojunction can be effectively tuned by biaxial strain. These results demonstrate that the fabricated SnC/SnS2 heterojunction has significant photocatalysis potential.</description>
      <author>Sisi Zhou, Yuliang Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7030076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAGNet: better electron density prediction for LCAO-based data and drug-like substances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s13321-025-01010-7</link>
      <description>Konstantin Ushenin, Kuzma Khrabrov, Artem Tsypin, Anton Ber, Egor Rumiantsev, Artur Kadurin, Journal of Cheminformatics. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409922207

                The electron density is an important object in quantum chemistry that is crucial for many downstream tasks in drug design. Recent deep learning approaches predict the electron density around a molecule from atom types and atom positions. Most of these methods use the plane wave (PW) numerical method as a source of ground-truth training data. However, the drug design field mostly uses the Linear Combination of Atomic Orbitals (LCAO) for computation of quantum properties. In this study, we focus on prediction of the electron density for drug-like substances and training neural networks with LCAO-based datasets. Our experiments show that proper handling of large amplitudes of core orbitals is crucial for training on LCAO-based data. We propose to store the electron density with the standard grids instead of the uniform grid. This allowed us to reduce the number of probing points per molecule by 43 times and reduce storage space requirements by 8 times. Finally, we propose a novel architecture based on the DeepDFT model that we name LAGNet. It is specifically designed and tuned for drug-like substances and &#8711;2 DFT dataset.</description>
      <author>Konstantin Ushenin, Kuzma Khrabrov, Artem Tsypin, Anton Ber, Egor Rumiantsev, Artur Kadurin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s13321-025-01010-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evolving role of programming and LLMs in the development of self-driving laboratories</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0266757</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, APL Machine Learning. 3(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409962774

                Machine learning and automation are transforming scientific research, yet the implementation of self-driving laboratories (SDLs) remains costly and complex, and it remains difficult to learn how to use these facilities. To address this, we introduce Claude-Light, a lightweight, remotely accessible instrument designed for prototyping automation algorithms and machine learning workflows. Claude-Light integrates a REST API, a Raspberry Pi-based control system, and an RGB LED with a photometer that measures ten spectral outputs, providing a controlled but realistic experimental environment. This device enables users to explore automation at multiple levels, from basic programming and experimental design to machine learning-driven optimization. We demonstrate the application of Claude-Light in structured automation approaches, including traditional scripting, statistical design of experiments, and active learning methods. In addition, we explore the role of large language models (LLMs) in laboratory automation, highlighting their use in instrument selection, structured data extraction, function calling, and code generation. While LLMs present new opportunities for streamlining automation, they also introduce challenges related to reproducibility, security, and reliability. We discuss strategies to mitigate these risks while leveraging LLMs for enhanced efficiency in self-driving laboratories. Claude-Light provides a practical and accessible platform for students and researchers to develop automation skills and test algorithms before deploying them in larger-scale SDLs. By lowering the barrier to entry for automation in scientific research, this tool facilitates broader adoption of AI-driven experimentation and fosters innovation in autonomous laboratories.</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0266757</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
