<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 01:15:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Bi6Fe2Ti3O18 ferroelectrics with various morphologies under mild conditions by crystal growth control for promoted adsorption-piezo-photocatalytic degradation performances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129293</link>
      <description>Zhaoxia Rao, Rui Huang, Wei Cai, Fengqi Wang, Wenfu Yan, Xue Yang, Fei Long, Zhenhua Wang, Yilong Ma, Rongli Gao, Gang Chen, Xiaoling Deng, Xiang Lei, Chunlin Fu, Separation and Purification Technology. 354(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4401831925

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaoxia Rao, Rui Huang, Wei Cai, Fengqi Wang, Wenfu Yan, Xue Yang, Fei Long, Zhenhua Wang, Yilong Ma, Rongli Gao, Gang Chen, Xiaoling Deng, Xiang Lei, Chunlin Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-efficiency photocatalyst and high-response ultraviolet photodetector based on the Ga2SSe@GaN heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104996</link>
      <description>Ke Qin, Enling Li, Yang Shen, Deming Ma, Pei Yuan, Hanxiao Wang, Zhen Cui, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401798598

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ke Qin, Enling Li, Yang Shen, Deming Ma, Pei Yuan, Hanxiao Wang, Zhen Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalysis of oxygen reduction on Se-Modified platinum single crystal electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115728</link>
      <description>Tingting Mao, Zhen Wei, Jun Cai, Yanxia Chen, Juan M. Feli&#250;, Enrique Herrero, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401802477

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Mao, Zhen Wei, Jun Cai, Yanxia Chen, Juan M. Feli&#250;, Enrique Herrero</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A first principles study of the oxygen reduction reaction mechanism on porous Ag and Ag-TM nanostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssc.2024.115665</link>
      <description>Kelvin Fu, Jingjing Wu, Xin Tang, Solid State Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401802539

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kelvin Fu, Jingjing Wu, Xin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssc.2024.115665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong interaction between promoter and metal in Pd-Ba/TiO2 catalysts for formaldehyde oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.166</link>
      <description>Xudong Chen, Qi Qin, Jingyi Wang, Wen Wei, Xiaofeng Liu, Chunying Wang, Zhou Li&#8208;ping, Hua Deng, Yaobin Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401802633

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xudong Chen, Qi Qin, Jingyi Wang, Wen Wei, Xiaofeng Liu, Chunying Wang, Zhou Li&#8208;ping, Hua Deng, Yaobin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated electrocatalytic synthesis of ammonium nitrate from dilute NO gas on metal organic frameworks-modified gas diffusion electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51256-2</link>
      <description>Donglai Pan, Muthu Austeria P, In Su Lee, Ho-Sub Bae, Fei He, Geun Ho Gu, Wonyong Choi, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401807513

                The electrocatalytic conversion of NO offers a promising technology for not only removing the air pollutant but also synthesizing valuable chemicals. We design an integrated-electrocatalysis cell featuring metal organic framework (MOF)-modified gas diffusion electrodes for simultaneous capture of NO and generation of NH</description>
      <author>Donglai Pan, Muthu Austeria P, In Su Lee, Ho-Sub Bae, Fei He, Geun Ho Gu, Wonyong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51256-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting oxygen evolution reaction by FeNi hydroxide-organic framework electrocatalyst toward alkaline water electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51521-4</link>
      <description>Yuzhen Chen, Qiuhong Li, Yuxing Lin, Jiao Liu, Jing Pan, Jingguo Hu, Xiaoyong Xu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401808265

                The oxygen evolution reaction plays a vital role in modern energy conversion and storage, and developing cost-efficient oxygen evolution reaction catalysts with industrially relevant activity and durability is highly desired but still challenging. Here, we report an efficient and durable FeNi hydroxide organic framework nanosheet array catalyst that competently affords long-term oxygen evolution reaction at industrial-grade current densities in alkaline electrolyte. The desirable high-intensity performance is attributed to three aspects as follows. First, two-dimensional nanosheet porous arrays with maximum specific surface facilitate mass/charge transfer to accommodate high-current-density catalysis. Second, in situ derived FeNi hydroxide motifs offer bimetallic synergistic catalysis centers with high intrinsic activity. Third, carboxyl ligands alleviate metal oxidation favorable for charge tolerability against peroxidation dissolution under strong polarization. As a result, this catalyst requires an overpotential of only 280 mV to deliver high current density up to 1 A/cm2 with long durability over 1000 h. Moreover, an alkaline water electrolyzer with this catalyst alternative demonstrates an increased economic effectiveness compared to commercial levels at present. Developing cost-efficient catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction is crucial for various modern energy technologies. Here the authors report an efficient and durable NiFe hydroxide organic framework catalyst for water oxidation at 1 A/cm2 with long durability over 1000 h.</description>
      <author>Yuzhen Chen, Qiuhong Li, Yuxing Lin, Jiao Liu, Jing Pan, Jingguo Hu, Xiaoyong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51521-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy storage and electrocatalytic applications of nanoclay composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13390-9.00012-6</link>
      <description>K.P. Revathy, Akshay Kumar K. Padinjareveetil, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401811287

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K.P. Revathy, Akshay Kumar K. Padinjareveetil</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13390-9.00012-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational catalysis on the conversion of CO2 to methane&#8212;an update</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11705-024-2484-3</link>
      <description>Prince Joby, Yesaiyan Manojkumar, Antony Rajendran, Rajadurai Vijay Solomon, Frontiers of Chemical Science and Engineering. 18(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401812135

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Prince Joby, Yesaiyan Manojkumar, Antony Rajendran, Rajadurai Vijay Solomon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11705-024-2484-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Order in Disorder: Tracking the Formation of High Entropy Solid Solutions and High Entropy Intermetallics by in situ PXRD/XAS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k1v88</link>
      <description>Nicolas Schlegel, Stefanie Punke, Christian M. Clausen, Ulrik Friis-Jensen, Adam F. Sapnik, Dragos Stoian, Olivia Aalling-Frederiksen, Divyansh Gautam, Jan Rossmeisl, Rebecca Pittkowski, Matthias Arenz, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401815001

                The recent focus on high entropy alloys in the field of electrocatalysis has led to a corresponding increase in interest in nanosizing these materials. Nevertheless, the precise mechanism by which they are formed at low temperatures remains unclear. In this study, we investigate the formation and subsequent growth of PtFeCoNiPd particles following a facile and industrial-scalable incipient wetness impregnation approach using quasi-simultaneous in situ powder X-ray diffraction (PXRD) and X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS). The initial formation of crystallites with a size of 2-3 nm and an fcc structure, which are rich in Pt and Pd, was observed. A continuous incorporation of the non-precious elements at elevated temperatures leads to crystallite growth while maintaining an fcc structure. Upon reaching a temperature of 330 &#176;C, Bragg peaks corresponding to a face-centered tetragonal phase emerge, indicating a transition to an intermetallic species. The degree of ordering was found to be dependent on the atomic ratio of precious to non-precious elements in the samples, with the synthesis temperature program also influencing this degree of ordering. This suggests the possibility of synthetic control.</description>
      <author>Nicolas Schlegel, Stefanie Punke, Christian M. Clausen, Ulrik Friis-Jensen, Adam F. Sapnik, Dragos Stoian, Olivia Aalling-Frederiksen, Divyansh Gautam, Jan Rossmeisl, Rebecca Pittkowski, Matthias Arenz, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k1v88</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic properties of two-dimensional rectangular graphyne based on phenyl-like building blocks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2024.100395</link>
      <description>Anderson Gomes Vieira, Marcelo Lopes Pereira, Vincent Meunier, Eduardo Costa Gir&#227;o, Carbon Trends. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401819632

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anderson Gomes Vieira, Marcelo Lopes Pereira, Vincent Meunier, Eduardo Costa Gir&#227;o</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2024.100395</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasmall high-entropy alloy nanoparticles on hierarchical N-doped carbon nanocages for tremendous electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6924-7</link>
      <description>Manman Jia, Jietao Jiang, Jingyi Tian, Xizhang Wang, Lijun Yang, Qiang Wu, Zheng Hu, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401820749

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manman Jia, Jietao Jiang, Jingyi Tian, Xizhang Wang, Lijun Yang, Qiang Wu, Zheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6924-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping&#8208;Induced Enhancement of Hydrogen Evolution at MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400349</link>
      <description>Sander &#216;. Hanslin, Hannes J&#243;nsson, Jaakko Akola, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401821404

                Abstract Rate theory and DFT calculations of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) on MoS 2 with Co, Ni and Pt impurities show the significance of dihydrogen (H 2 *) complex where both hydrogen atoms are interacting with the surface. Stabilization of such a complex affects the competing Volmer&#8211;Heyrovsky (direct H 2 release) and Volmer&#8208;Tafel (H 2 * intermediate) pathways. The resulting evolution proceeds with a very small overpotential for all dopants ( =0.1 to 0.2 V) at 25 % edge substitution, significantly reduced from the already low =0.27 V for the undoped edge. At full edge substitution, Co&#8208;MoS 2 remains highly active ( =0.18 V) while Ni&#8208; and Pt&#8208;MoS 2 are deactivated ( =0.4 to 0.5 V) due to unfavorable interaction with H 2 *. Instead of the single S&#8208;vacancy, the site of intrinsic activity in the basal plane was found to be the undercoordinated central Mo&#8208;atom in threefold S&#8208;vacancy configurations, enabling hydrogen evolution with =0.52 V via a H 2 * intermediate. The impurity atoms interact favorably with the intrinsic sulfur vacancies on the basal plane, stabilizing but simultaneously deactivating the triple vacancy configuration. The calculated shifts in overpotential are consistent with reported measurements, and the dependence on doping level may explain variations in experimental observations.</description>
      <author>Sander &#216;. Hanslin, Hannes J&#243;nsson, Jaakko Akola</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-guided Design, Synthesis, and Characterization of Atomically Dispersed Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101578</link>
      <description>Sirui Li, Hanguang Zhang, Edward F. Holby, Piotr Zelenay, Wilton J. M. Kort-Kamp, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401822663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sirui Li, Hanguang Zhang, Edward F. Holby, Piotr Zelenay, Wilton J. M. Kort-Kamp</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New mechanistic insights into CO2 electroreduction to methane on penta-octa-graphene catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.017</link>
      <description>Yirong Ma, Jinbo Hao, Baonan Jia, Xin-Hui Zhang, Chunling Zhang, Ge Wu, Changcheng Chen, Yuanzi Li, Zhiyuan Zhou, Qiyu Li, Pengfei Lu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401826986

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yirong Ma, Jinbo Hao, Baonan Jia, Xin-Hui Zhang, Chunling Zhang, Ge Wu, Changcheng Chen, Yuanzi Li, Zhiyuan Zhou, Qiyu Li, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of NiCo2O4 nanosheets efficient for electrocatalysis of water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161013</link>
      <description>Yujie Wang, Yan Duan, Yaogang Chen, Man Zhang, Yuchen Wang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Xiaodie Zhang, Yutong Zhang, Rongliang Qiu, Kai Yan, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401831611

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Wang, Yan Duan, Yaogang Chen, Man Zhang, Yuchen Wang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Xiaodie Zhang, Yutong Zhang, Rongliang Qiu, Kai Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unparalleled single-atom catalytic efficiency of TM@Al12P12 (TM = Fe, Co, Ni, Cu) nanoclusters toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113014</link>
      <description>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Naveen Kosar, Tariq Mahmood, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Nadeem S. Sheikh, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401831912

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Naveen Kosar, Tariq Mahmood, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Nadeem S. Sheikh, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of CO oxidation over polyoxometalate-supported Au cluster catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115724</link>
      <description>Tomohisa Yonemori, Yasutaka Hamada, Tamao Ishida, Toru Murayama, Takahito Nakajima, Shusuke Yamanaka, Mitsutaka Okumura, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401832081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tomohisa Yonemori, Yasutaka Hamada, Tamao Ishida, Toru Murayama, Takahito Nakajima, Shusuke Yamanaka, Mitsutaka Okumura</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkaline oxygen reduction/evolution reaction electrocatalysis: A critical review focus on orbital structure, non-noble metal catalysts, and descriptors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155005</link>
      <description>Xiaoqi Zhao, Zhou Hao, Xue Zhang, Lijun Li, Yanfang Gao, Ling Liu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401833037

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoqi Zhao, Zhou Hao, Xue Zhang, Lijun Li, Yanfang Gao, Ling Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the C-C coupling mechanism of CO2 electroreduction on bimetallic sites embedded in N-doped carbon catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114449</link>
      <description>Hui Gao, Peng Jin, Molecular Catalysis. 567(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401835421

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Gao, Peng Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating challenges and possibilities for improving polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells via Pt electrocatalyst, support and ionomer advancements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.323</link>
      <description>Md. Ahsanul Haque, Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Yuichi Negishi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 85(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401836660

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Md. Ahsanul Haque, Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Yuichi Negishi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of intrinsic point defects on electrocatalytic activity of a metal-free two-dimensional Polyaramid for enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.255</link>
      <description>Archana Sharma, Brahmananda Chakraborty, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 85(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401836747

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Archana Sharma, Brahmananda Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling High&#8208;Entropy Core with Rh Shell for Efficient pH&#8208;Universal Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403353</link>
      <description>Min Wei, Yuyan Sun, Junyu Zhang, Jianrong Zeng, Jike Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401844907

                Abstract Constructing high&#8208;entropy alloys (HEAs) with core&#8211;shell (CS) nanostructure is efficient for enhancing catalytic activity. However, it is extremely challenging to incorporate the CS structure with HEAs. Herein, PtCoNiMoRh@Rh CS nanoparticles (PtCoNiMoRh@Rh) with &#8764;5.7 nm for pH&#8208;universal hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are reported for the first time. The PtCoNiMoRh@Rh just require 9.1, 24.9, and 17.1 mV to achieve &#8722;10 mA cm &#8722;2 in acid, neutral, and alkaline electrolyte, and the corresponding mass activity are 5.8, 2.79, and 91.8 times higher than that of Rh/C. Comparing to PtCoNiMoRh nanoparticles, the PtCoNiMoRh@Rh exhibit excellent HER activity attributed to the decrease of Rh 4d especially 4d 5/2 unoccupied state induced by the multi&#8208;active sites in HEA, as well as the synergistic effect in Rh shell and HEA core. Theorical calculation exhibits that Rh&#8208;d yz , d x2 , and d xz orbitals experience a negative shift with shell thickness increasing. The HEAs with CS structure would facilitate the rational design of high&#8208;performance HEAs catalysts.</description>
      <author>Min Wei, Yuyan Sun, Junyu Zhang, Jianrong Zeng, Jike Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tosr: Create the Tree of Science from WoS and Scopus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5530/jscires.13.2.36</link>
      <description>Sebasti&#225;n Robledo, Luis Eduardo Pel&#225;ez Valencia, Martha Zuluaga, &#211;scar Echeverri, Jorge William Arboleda Valencia, Journal of Scientometric Research. 13(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401845777

                Sebastian Robledo1, Luis Valencia2, Martha Zuluaga1, Oscar Arbelaez Echeverri3 and Jorge W. Arboleda Valencia45 Author informationPDFCitations 1Direcci&#243;n Acad&#233;mica, Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Sede de La Paz, Cesar, COLOMBIA 2Centro de Bioinform&#225;tica y Biolog&#237;a Computacional de Colombia &#8211; BIOS, COLOMBIA 3Core of Science, IRELAND 4FITOBIOL, Instituto de Biolog&#237;a, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales, Universidad de</description>
      <author>Sebasti&#225;n Robledo, Luis Eduardo Pel&#225;ez Valencia, Martha Zuluaga, &#211;scar Echeverri, Jorge William Arboleda Valencia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5530/jscires.13.2.36</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular dynamics of liquid&#8211;electrode interface by integrating &lt;scp&gt;Coulomb&lt;/scp&gt; interaction into universal neural network potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27487</link>
      <description>Kaoru Hisama, Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Michihisa Koyama, Journal of Computational Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401851483

                Abstract Computational understanding of the liquid&#8211;electrode interface faces challenges in efficiently incorporating reactive force fields and electrostatic potentials within reasonable computational costs. Although universal neural network potentials (UNNPs), representing pretrained machine learning interatomic potentials, are emerging, current UNNP models lack explicit treatment of Coulomb potentials, and methods for integrating additional charges on the electrode remain to be established. We propose a method to analyze liquid&#8211;electrode interfaces by integrating a UNNP, known as the preferred potential, with Coulomb potentials using the ONIOM method. This approach extends the applicability of UNNPs to electrode&#8211;liquid interface systems. Through molecular dynamics simulations of graphene&#8211;water and graphene oxide (GO)&#8211;water interfaces, we demonstrate the effectiveness of our method. Our findings emphasize the necessity of incorporating long&#8208;range Coulomb potentials into the water potential to accurately describe water polarization at the interface. Furthermore, we observe that functional groups on the GO electrode influence both polarization and capacitance.</description>
      <author>Kaoru Hisama, Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key role of nonprecious oxygen-evolving active site in NiOOH electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161066</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Na Song, Ming Fang, Yixing Li, Xuedi Chen, Yue Li, Lei He, Wenbiao Zhang, Xiaoyu Ma, Xianzhang Lei, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401858995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Na Song, Ming Fang, Yixing Li, Xuedi Chen, Yue Li, Lei He, Wenbiao Zhang, Xiaoyu Ma, Xianzhang Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain engineering of CoSAN C catalyst toward enhancing the oxygen reduction reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.165</link>
      <description>Hong Yin, Yuehong Deng, Zhe He, Wenyuan Xu, Zhaohui Hou, Binhong He, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Jo&#227;o Cunha, Maryam Karimi, Zhipeng Yu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401862691

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Yin, Yuehong Deng, Zhe He, Wenyuan Xu, Zhaohui Hou, Binhong He, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Jo&#227;o Cunha, Maryam Karimi, Zhipeng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafine ruthenium-based nanoclusters regulated by a three-phase heterogeneous interface exhibiting superior mass activity for alkaline hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144953</link>
      <description>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Bozhi Yang, Shujie Yang, Jie Li, Yanghong Li, Manjun Zhan, Xin Min, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401829933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Bozhi Yang, Shujie Yang, Jie Li, Yanghong Li, Manjun Zhan, Xin Min</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallated graphynes as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114489</link>
      <description>Ting Yao, Huohai Yang, Xiaoyue Fu, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Qiang Ke, Xin Chen, Molecular Catalysis. 567(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401844774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Yao, Huohai Yang, Xiaoyue Fu, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Qiang Ke, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site heterogeneity and broad surface-binding isotherms in modern catalysis: Building intuition beyond the Sabatier principle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115725</link>
      <description>James M. Mayer, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401892778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>James M. Mayer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837674497-part2</link>
      <description>, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401960484

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837674497-part2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Low-Temperature CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis: Current Status and Outlook</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00583</link>
      <description>Hojeong Lee, Seontaek Kwon, Namgyoo Park, Sun Gwan, Eunyoung Lee, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kong, Jihoo Cha, Youngkook Kwon, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401843733

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction (eCO2R) in membrane electrode assemblies (MEAs) has brought e-chemical production one step closer to commercialization because of its advantages of minimized ohmic resistance and stackability. However, the current performance of reported eCO2R in MEAs is still far below the threshold for economic feasibility where low overall cell voltage (&lt;2 V) and extensive stability (&gt;5 years) are required. Furthermore, while the production cost of e-chemicals heavily relies on the carbon capture and product separation processes, these areas have received much less attention compared to CO2 electrolysis, itself. In this perspective, we examine the current status of eCO2R technologies from both academic and industrial points of view. We highlight the gap between current capabilities and commercialization standards and offer future research directions for eCO2R technologies with the hope of achieving industrially viable e-chemical production.</description>
      <author>Hojeong Lee, Seontaek Kwon, Namgyoo Park, Sun Gwan, Eunyoung Lee, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kong, Jihoo Cha, Youngkook Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles data for solid solution niobium-tantalum-vanadium alloys with body-centered-cubic structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03720-3</link>
      <description>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, German D. Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Jong Youl Choi, Junqi Yin, Ying Yang, Scientific Data. 11(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401819288

                We present four open-source datasets that provide results of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of ground-state properties of refractory solid solution binary alloys niobium-tantalum (NbTa), niobium-vanadium (NbV), tantalum-vanadium (TaV), and ternary alloys NbTaV ordered in body-centered-cubic (BCC) structures with 128 Bravais lattice sites. The first-principles code used to run the calculations is the Vienna Ab-Initio Simulation Package. The calculations have been collected by uniformly sampling chemical compositions across the entire compositional range. For each chemical composition, the calculations have been run for 100 randomized arrangements of the constituents on the BCC lattice sites. This sampling methodology resulted in running DFT simulations for a total of 3,100 randomized atomic configurations over 31 chemical compositions for each of the three binary alloys Nb-Ta, Nb-V, Ta-V, and a total of 10,500 randomized atomic structures over 105 chemical compositions for the ternary alloys Nb-Ta-V. For each atomic configuration, geometry optimization has been performed, and the data released contains information about each step of geometry optimization for each atomic configuration.</description>
      <author>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, German D. Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Jong Youl Choi, Junqi Yin, Ying Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03720-3</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
