<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 01:25:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Rational catalyst design for N2 electro-reduction: Regulation strategies and quick screen towards enhanced conversion efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111056</link>
      <description>Jinzhou Zheng, Chaozheng He, Chenxu Zhao, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408168060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinzhou Zheng, Chaozheng He, Chenxu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monoatomic metalloporphyrinoid catalysts for efficient oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03151-4</link>
      <description>Yao Ying, Xiaoting Chen, Xinyuan Zhang, Shangbin Jin, Zhihong Tian, Guoliang Li, Liming Yang, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408175409

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Ying, Xiaoting Chen, Xinyuan Zhang, Shangbin Jin, Zhihong Tian, Guoliang Li, Liming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03151-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From waste to fuel cells. In situ preparation of an atomically precise Pd(II)-catalyst by selective extraction of Pd(II) from a mixture of metal ions using modified multi walled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) and its implementation in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in alkaline solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236661</link>
      <description>Marco Bonechi, Carlotta Cappanni, Pietro Gentilesca, Carla Bazzicalupi, Walter Giurlani, Massimo Innocenti, Leonardo Lari, Francesco Montanari, Matteo Savastano, Mirko Severi, Antonio Bianchi, Journal of Power Sources. 639(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408177228

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marco Bonechi, Carlotta Cappanni, Pietro Gentilesca, Carla Bazzicalupi, Walter Giurlani, Massimo Innocenti, Leonardo Lari, Francesco Montanari, Matteo Savastano, Mirko Severi, Antonio Bianchi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236661</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Pt/C and PtCu/C electrocatalysts for improved oxygen reduction reaction in proton-exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10757-1</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Kirill Paperzh, Angelina Pavlets, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, A. K. Nevelskaya, Yulia Bayan, M. V. Danilenko, Ilya Pankov, &#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408181426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Kirill Paperzh, Angelina Pavlets, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, A. K. Nevelskaya, Yulia Bayan, M. V. Danilenko, Ilya Pankov, &#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10757-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single metal atom anchored graphitic carbon nitride monolayers as promising multifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162840</link>
      <description>Shan Peng, Xiaolin Wu, Wengang Cheng, Xinhua Li, Zihao Cheng, De&#8208;Bing Long, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408185444

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Peng, Xiaolin Wu, Wengang Cheng, Xinhua Li, Zihao Cheng, De&#8208;Bing Long</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Three-Tiered Hierarchical Computational Framework Bridging Molecular Systems and Junction-Level Charge Transport</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01711</link>
      <description>Xuan Ji, Qiang Qi, Yueqi Chen, Chen Zhou, Xi Yu, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408186192

                The nonequilibrium Green's function (NEGF) method combined with ab initio calculations has been widely used to study charge transport in molecular junctions. However, the significant computational demands of high-resolution calculations for all device components pose challenges in simulating junctions with complex molecular junction structures and understanding the functionality of molecular devices. In this study, we developed a series of computational methods capable of effectively handling the molecular Hamiltonian, electrode electronic structures, and their interfacial coupling at different theoretical levels. As three-tiered hierarchical levels, they enable efficient charge transport computations ranging from individual molecules to complete junction systems, achieving an optimal balance between computational cost and accuracy. Moreover, integrated into a Question-Driven Hierarchical Computation (QDHC) framework, we show this three-tiered framework is able to address specific research objectives by isolating and analyzing the dominant factors governing charge transport, thus significantly enhancing the efficiency of analyzing charge transport mechanisms, as validated through a series of benchmark studies on diverse molecular junction systems.</description>
      <author>Xuan Ji, Qiang Qi, Yueqi Chen, Chen Zhou, Xi Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01711</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of the Electronic Properties of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; through Bi Octahedral Doping for Enhanced Activity in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07911</link>
      <description>Damian Gorylewski, Filip Zasada, Grzegorz S&#322;owik, Magdalena Lofek, Gabriela Grzybek, Katarzyna Tyszczuk&#8208;Rotko, Andrzej Kotarba, Pawe&#322; Stelmachowski, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408190039

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Damian Gorylewski, Filip Zasada, Grzegorz S&#322;owik, Magdalena Lofek, Gabriela Grzybek, Katarzyna Tyszczuk&#8208;Rotko, Andrzej Kotarba, Pawe&#322; Stelmachowski</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07911</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Accelerated Interfacial Fluxionality in Ni-Supported Metal Nitride Ammonia Synthesis Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168150</link>
      <description>Pranav Roy, Brandon C. Bukowski, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408190436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pranav Roy, Brandon C. Bukowski</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Exploration of Codoped Fe and Ru Single-Atom Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168151</link>
      <description>Haojun Jia, Chenru Duan, Gianmarco Terrones, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408190457

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haojun Jia, Chenru Duan, Gianmarco Terrones, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Imaging of Chirality Transfer Induced by Glycosidic Bond Stereochemistry in Carbohydrate Self-Assemblies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16088</link>
      <description>Shuning Cai, Joakim S. Jestil&#228;, Peter Liljeroth, Adam S. Foster, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408192153

                Carbohydrates, essential biological building blocks, exhibit functional mechanisms tied to their intricate stereochemistry. Subtle stereochemical differences, such as those between the anomers maltose and cellobiose, lead to distinct properties due to their differing glycosidic bonds; the former is digestible by humans, while the latter is not. This underscores the importance of precise structural determination of individual carbohydrate molecules for deeper functional insights. However, their structural complexity and conformational flexibility, combined with the high spatial resolution needed, have hindered direct imaging of carbohydrate stereochemistry. Here, we employ noncontact atomic force microscopy integrated with a data-efficient, multifidelity structure search approach accelerated by machine learning integration to determine the precise 3D atomic coordinates of two carbohydrate anomers on Au(111). We observe that the stereochemistry of the glycosidic bond regulates on-surface chiral selection in carbohydrate self-assemblies. The reconstructed models, validated against experimental data, provide reliable atomic-scale structural evidence, uncovering the origin of the on-surface chirality from carbohydrate anomerism. Our study confirms that nc-AFM is a reliable technique for real-space discrimination of carbohydrate stereochemistry at the single-molecule level, providing a pathway for bottom-up investigations into the structure-property relationships of carbohydrates in biological research and materials science.</description>
      <author>Shuning Cai, Joakim S. Jestil&#228;, Peter Liljeroth, Adam S. Foster</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning assisted screening of non-metal doped MXenes catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.469</link>
      <description>Mei Yang, Changxin Wang, Minhui Song, Lu Xie, Ping Qian, Yanjing Su, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 113(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408194232

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mei Yang, Changxin Wang, Minhui Song, Lu Xie, Ping Qian, Yanjing Su</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface hydrogen migration significantly promotes electroreduction of acetonitrile to ethylamine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57462-w</link>
      <description>Yulong Tang, J. Li, Yichao Lin, Miaomiao Cheng, Shuibo Wang, Ziqi Tian, Junjie Zhou, H. M. Zhang, Yunan Wang, Liang Chen, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408196546

                The electrochemical reduction of acetonitrile (AN) to ethylamine (EA) is an attractive yet challenging process, primarily due to the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This study demonstrates the ability to halt the HER at Volmer step, where protons migrate to the unsaturated bond of AN on a self-supported CuO@Cu heterostructure. The CuO@Cu catalyst exhibits nearly 100% Faradaic efficiency (FE) over the entire range of potentials tested from -0.1 to -0.4 V vs. RHE, demonstrating remarkable stability over 1000 h at a constant current density of 0.2 A cm-2. CuO is identified as the active component driving the reaction, while the metallic Cu facilitates efficient electron transfer. Theoretical simulations and experimental evidences indicate that a synergistic hydrogenation process contributes to the AN reduction reaction (ARR), which involves both surface hydrogen migration and proton addition from solution. This study provides an insight into understanding of ARR process, and suggests an efficient strategy to enhance the electrochemical hydrogenation of organic molecules by regulating the Volmer step.</description>
      <author>Yulong Tang, J. Li, Yichao Lin, Miaomiao Cheng, Shuibo Wang, Ziqi Tian, Junjie Zhou, H. M. Zhang, Yunan Wang, Liang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57462-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom alloys 2.0: Exploiting undercoordination for stronger dissociative CH4 chemisorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122735</link>
      <description>Debtanu Maiti, Michael P. Harold, Lars C. Grabow, Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408200122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Debtanu Maiti, Michael P. Harold, Lars C. Grabow</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights of nitrate reduction to ammonia on partially reduced In2O3 surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114991</link>
      <description>Qingchao Fang, M. T. Nasir, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Yun Han, Xuxin Kang, Cheng Yan, Anthony P. O&#8217;Mullane, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du, Molecular Catalysis. 577(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408202856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingchao Fang, M. T. Nasir, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Yun Han, Xuxin Kang, Cheng Yan, Anthony P. O&#8217;Mullane, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114991</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature dependent mechanism transition effect stabilized ruthenium-based oxides for water oxidation in proton exchange membrane electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4097038/v1</link>
      <description>Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, Rui Wu, Heng Liu, Sihua Feng, Sheng Zhu, Jie Xu, Hengli Duan, Ruiqi Liu, Yingkang Qin, Wensheng Yan, Xiaozhi Su, Hao Li, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408203568

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER), as the anodic reaction of many electrochemical devices, plays a crucial role in such energy conversion process. However, the poor OER stability of non-iridium-based materials has tremendously limited the large-scale application of related devices. Here, using a novel home-made operando differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy, for the first time we report a temperature dependent mechanism transition (TDMT) effect of RhRu3Ox, a non-iridium-based electrocatalyst, in OER process, which makes us realize the important role of temperature in triggering OER mechanism transition, and further enriches our toolbox for manipulating OER kinetics. To evaluate the potential of RhRu3Ox for practical applications, we assembled it as an anode in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, demonstrating its stability at room temperature for over 1000 hours at 200 mA cm-2 compared with the unstable pristine RuO2. Techno-economic analysis shows that the cost of H2 production using solar photovoltaic and onshore wind as power sources is already lower than the global average levelized cost of H2 from coal. Density functional theory studies reveal that the existence of kinetic barrier related to lattice oxygen activation might be the reason for the OER TDMT of RhRu3Ox at elevated temperature.</description>
      <author>Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, Rui Wu, Heng Liu, Sihua Feng, Sheng Zhu, Jie Xu, Hengli Duan, Ruiqi Liu, Yingkang Qin, Wensheng Yan, Xiaozhi Su, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4097038/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ion Irradiation Engineered Defect Formation and Hydrogen Evolution on Two-Dimensional Mos2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5167848</link>
      <description>Jiahua Xu, Tianzhao Li, Wenjin Gao, Miaogen Chen, Jinge Wu, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408204590

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahua Xu, Tianzhao Li, Wenjin Gao, Miaogen Chen, Jinge Wu, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5167848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial metal&#8211;coordinated bifunctional PtCo for practical fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adt4914</link>
      <description>Zhongliang Huang, Qi Xiao, Tianyi Ding, Jing Xia, Changhong Zhan, Xiangmin Meng, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Y Wang, Nanjun Chen, Liang Cao, Xiaoqing Huang, Science Advances. 11(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408223155

                Platinum (Pt) has been documented as the top-tier fuel cell catalyst, yet it faces a notable challenge regarding its poor CO tolerance and sluggish oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), particularly when using CO-contaminated blue and gray H 2 . Here, we present an interfacial metal coordination strategy to design a bifunctional platinum-cobalt (PtCo) intermetallic catalyst integrated with a tin-nitrogen-carbon (Sn&#8211;N&#8211;C) support, which forms Pt&#8211;Sn&#8211;N bonds that substantially boost both ORR activity and CO tolerance. The PtCo/Sn&#8211;N&#8211;C-made fuel cell achieves a topmost peak power density of 2.11 watts per square centimeter in 100 parts per million (ppm) of CO-containing H 2 , surpassing all previously reported PEMFCs. In addition, it operates stably at a rated voltage for over 710 hours in 100 ppm of CO/H 2 -air. This work demonstrates the feasibility of fuel cells directly using CO-contaminated gray &amp; blue H 2 , paving the way for PEMFC-driven energy vehicles.</description>
      <author>Zhongliang Huang, Qi Xiao, Tianyi Ding, Jing Xia, Changhong Zhan, Xiangmin Meng, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Y Wang, Nanjun Chen, Liang Cao, Xiaoqing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adt4914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Dichroism in Strong-Coupled Chiral Molecule-Plasmon Nanoparticle System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00721</link>
      <description>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yurui Fang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408223641

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yurui Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of alkali and alkaline earth defects on the Electronic, magnetic properties and work function of 2H-CrS2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113822</link>
      <description>Xuejiao Wang, Xintao Li, Longhua Li, Computational Materials Science. 253(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408225487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuejiao Wang, Xintao Li, Longhua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Descriptor toward Optimizing Electrocatalytic N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxidation to HNO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Performance over Graphene-Based Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00234</link>
      <description>Chuang Zhi, Shouyu Cai, Dengning Sun, Juan Yang, Zhongti Sun, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408226563

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) exhibit tremendous advantages in the electrochemical N2 oxidation reaction (EN2OR) to HNO3, which is an eco-friendly alternative to the synthesis of conventional industrial nitric acid and nitrates, but methods to rationally design and rapidly screen high-efficiency EN2OR SACs are unclear. Herein, taking pyridinic nitrogen-doped graphene-supported SACs as an example, a simple descriptor has been proposed to evaluate the EN2OR performance through systematically constructing a surface reaction phase diagram. This descriptor is comprised of merely the geometric information and inherent atomic properties (occupied d electron number, electronegativity, and coordinate number) that can accurately predict the activity and selectivity of EN2OR, independent of DFT simulations. Based on this descriptor, high-throughput screening has been executed on partially N/C/O coordinated SACs, including 160 candidates; 13 candidates with the overpotential of less than 1.0 V are selected and then validated by DFT calculations with a mean absolute error (MAE) as low as 0.09 V, indicating the reliability of the descriptor. Meanwhile, the screened CoO2N2-G and RhO2N2-G SACs exhibit lower EN2OR overpotential of 0.64 and 0.68 V and more negative UL(EN2OR) - UL(OER) values of -0.34 and -0.44 V in comparison to other candidates, respectively, demonstrating the excellent activity and selectivity of EN2OR. This work offers a route to rapid discovery of high-performance SACs for EN2OR.</description>
      <author>Chuang Zhi, Shouyu Cai, Dengning Sun, Juan Yang, Zhongti Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quasi Fe MIL-53 nanozyme inducing ferroptosis and immunogenic cell death for cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57542-x</link>
      <description>Zhaoxiong Yan, Yang Bai, Songtao Zhang, Lingyi Kong, Yu Wang, Han Sun, Yi Li, Lin Qiu, Ruijie Zhang, Pengju Jiang, Donghui Zhao, Zhongyan Chen, Yafei Li, Huan Pang, Jianhao Wang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408229481

                Nanozymes offer diverse therapeutic potentials for cancer treatment which is dependent on the development of nanomaterials. Quasi-metal-organic framework is a class of metal-organic framework-derived nanomaterials with a transition state from metal-organic frameworks towards metal oxide featuring porous structure and high activity. Herein an iron-based quasi-metal-organic framework nanozyme Q-MIL-53(Fe) is reported via a controlled deligandation strategy, exhibiting enhanced peroxidase-/catalase-mimic activity and glutathione depletion capacity, whose underlying mechanisms are studied via density functional theory calculations. Q-MIL-53(Fe) demonstrates biocompatibility and superior antitumor efficacy compared to pristine MIL-53(Fe). It can activate antitumor immune response by inducing ferroptosis and immunogenic cell death, promoting dendritic cell maturation and T lymphocytes infiltration. Furthermore, a combination of Q-MIL-53(Fe) and programmed cell death protein 1 antibody amplifies cancer immunotherapy. This study validates the antitumor activity of quasi-metal-organic frameworks and its immunotherapy induction potential. It would broaden the application of quasi-metal-organic frameworks and open avenues for developing antitumor nanozymes. Nanozymes offer diverse therapeutic avenues for cancer treatment. In this work, the authors report an iron-based quasi-metal organic framework nanozyme Q-MIL-53(Fe) with enhanced peroxidase and catalase-mimicking activity and glutathione depletion capacity and use it for tumor immunotherapy via inducing ferroptosis and immunogenic cell death.</description>
      <author>Zhaoxiong Yan, Yang Bai, Songtao Zhang, Lingyi Kong, Yu Wang, Han Sun, Yi Li, Lin Qiu, Ruijie Zhang, Pengju Jiang, Donghui Zhao, Zhongyan Chen, Yafei Li, Huan Pang, Jianhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57542-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-efficient construction of high-fidelity graph deep learning interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01550-4</link>
      <description>Tsz Wai Ko, Shyue Ping Ong, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408231448

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tsz Wai Ko, Shyue Ping Ong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01550-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupled Differential Electrochemical Mass Spectrometry and Surface-Enhanced Infrared Absorption Spectroscopic Studies Unravel the Mechanism of Nitric Oxide Electroreduction on Platinum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16057</link>
      <description>Hongsen Wang, H&#232;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408231674

                The nitric oxide electroreduction reaction (NORR) has received considerable attention due to its importance in electrochemical denitrification of nitrogen oxides in groundwater and industrial waste gases and electrochemical ammonia synthesis. However, the detailed mechanism and the factors that affect product selectivity are far less understood. Employing coupled differential electrochemical mass spectrometry (DEMS) and attenuated total reflection-surface-enhanced infrared absorption (ATR-SEIRA) spectroscopy, adsorbed species and volatile solution products, during the adsorption of NO and NORR on Pt in both alkaline and acidic media, have been simultaneously studied, enabling us to correlate the potential-dependent product selectivity with the surface ad-species. NOad,M, NOad,B, NOad,L, and NO2,ad were identified using SEIRA spectroscopy as surface ad-species, with their potential-dependent intensities having a strong correlation with the product selectivity. N2O is the only reduction product at potentials beyond the hydrogen region and is attributed to the reduction of weakly adsorbed NO. In contrast, the formation of NH3 and NH2OH occurs only in the hydrogen region and is ascribed to the reaction between strongly adsorbed NO and adsorbed H. N2 is a minor product, and is formed through further reduction of N2O by adsorbed H. The formation of N2 is significantly suppressed in acidic media due to the fast kinetics of NO reduction to NH3/NH2OH, and thus lowering of NO coverage in the hydrogen region. To achieve the selective reduction of NO to NH3/NH2OH, the potential should remain at 0.1-0.2 V (vs RHE) in both acidic and alkaline media while a slow NO supply, and acidic media are preferred over alkaline media due to the faster kinetics. These new spectroscopic results and insights about the NORR could advance the design of more effective NORR catalysts and help develop optimal conditions for selective ammonia synthesis.</description>
      <author>Hongsen Wang, H&#232;ctor D. Abru&#241;a</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Engineering the Optoelectronic and HER Behavior of MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/ZnO Heterojunction: A DFT Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03605</link>
      <description>Jian Yang, LI Xiao-wen, Yu Yang, Ruifen Dou, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408236348

                The rational design of heterojunctions by coupling two or more two-dimensional (2D) materials is regarded as a feasible strategy to efficiently enhance photocatalytic-hydrogen performance by capturing solar energy to address the increasing global energy crisis. In this work, a functional MoS2/ZnO heterojunction is proposed based on first-principles simulation. Our results reveal that the photogenerated electrons and holes in the MoS2/ZnO heterojunction follow a specific Z-scheme pathway, highly facilitating redox reactions and optimizing optical properties in the visible-light region. Under external strain, the MoS2/ZnO heterojunction demonstrates improved HER performance and remarkable optical-harvesting capabilities. Interestingly, the HER free energy for the heterojunction is only -0.04 eV under -5% compressive strain, highlighting its promising potential for photocatalytic hydrogen production. We observe that the absorption edge of the spectrum shifts gradually to the infrared region with increasing tensile biaxial strains, whereas compressive biaxial strains result in a blue-shift absorption spectrum. Additionally, all heterojunctions achieve excellent solar-to-hydrogen (STH) efficiencies exceeding 10%, demonstrating their capability to store sufficient solar energy. Our work offers a novel strategy for exploring highly efficient photocatalysts in the field of hydrogen energy with the ability to modulate their activity through external strain.</description>
      <author>Jian Yang, LI Xiao-wen, Yu Yang, Ruifen Dou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-defined monolayers, bilayers and trilayers of two-dimensional Janus MoSSe and Ga2SSe van der Waals homojunctions as potential photocatalysts for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122829</link>
      <description>Fan Yang, Marie&#8208;Christine Record, Pascal Boulet, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408236886

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan Yang, Marie&#8208;Christine Record, Pascal Boulet</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin and scarcity of breathing pyrochlore lattices in spinel oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.033602</link>
      <description>Valentina Mazzotti, Solveig S. Aamlid, Abraham A. Mancilla, Janna Machts, Megan Rutherford, J&#246;rg Rottler, Kenji Kojima, Alannah M. Hallas, Physical Review Materials. 9(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408241532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Valentina Mazzotti, Solveig S. Aamlid, Abraham A. Mancilla, Janna Machts, Megan Rutherford, J&#246;rg Rottler, Kenji Kojima, Alannah M. Hallas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.033602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructured Electrocatalysts: from Fundamental Microkinetic Model to Electron Configuration and Interfacial Reactive Microenvironment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418146</link>
      <description>Yun Li, Md. Samim Hassan, Xin Zhao, Andrey L. Rogach, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408244233

                Electrocatalysts can efficiently convert earth-abundant simple molecules into high-value-added products. In this context, heterostructures, which are largely determined by the interface, have emerged as a pivotal architecture for enhancing the activity of electrocatalysts. In this review, the atomistic understanding of heterostructured electrocatalysts is considered, focusing on the reaction kinetic rate and electron configuration, gained from both empirical studies and theoretical models. We start from the fundamentals of the microkinetic model, adsorption energy theory, and electric double layer model. The importance of heterostructures to accelerate electrochemical processes via modulating electron configuration and interfacial reactive microenvironment is highlighted, by considering rectification, space charge region, built-in electric field, synergistic interactions, lattice strain, and geometric effect. We conclude this review by summarizing the challenges and perspectives in the field of heterostructured electrocatalysts, such as the determination of transition state energy, their dynamic evolution, refinement of the theoretical approaches, and the use of machine learning.</description>
      <author>Yun Li, Md. Samim Hassan, Xin Zhao, Andrey L. Rogach</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Nernstian Effects in Theoretical Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00803</link>
      <description>Dipam Manish Patel, Georg Kastlunger, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408244670

                Electrocatalysis is one of the principal pathways for the transition to sustainable chemistry, promising greater energy efficiency and reduced emissions. As the field has grown, our theoretical understanding has matured. The influence of the applied potential on reactivity has developed from the first-order predictions based on the Nernst equation to the implicit inclusion of second-order effects including the interaction of reacting species with the interfacial electric field. In this review, we explore these non-Nernstian field effects in electrocatalysis, aiming to both understand and exploit them through theory and computation. We summarize the critical distinction between Nernstian and non-Nernstian effects and outline strategies to address the latter in theoretical studies. Subsequently, we examine the specific energetic contributions of the latter on capacitive and faradaic processes separately. We also underscore the importance of considering non-Nernstian effects in catalyst screening and mechanistic analysis. Finally, we provide suggestions on how to experimentally unravel these effects, offering insights into practical approaches for advancing the field.</description>
      <author>Dipam Manish Patel, Georg Kastlunger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The QCML dataset, Quantum chemistry reference data from 33.5M DFT and 14.7B semi-empirical calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-025-04720-7</link>
      <description>Stefan Ganscha, Oliver T. Unke, Daniel Ahlin, Hartmut Maennel, Sergii Kashubin, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller, Scientific Data. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408246939

                Abstract Machine learning (ML) methods enable prediction of the properties of chemical structures without computationally expensive ab initio calculations. The quality of such predictions depends on the reference data that was used to train the model. In this work, we introduce the QCML dataset: A comprehensive dataset for training ML models for quantum chemistry. The QCML dataset systematically covers chemical space with small molecules consisting of up to 8 heavy atoms and includes elements from a large fraction of the periodic table, as well as different electronic states. Starting from chemical graphs, conformer search and normal mode sampling are used to generate both equilibrium and off-equilibrium 3D structures, for which various properties are calculated with semi-empirical methods (14.7 billion entries) and density functional theory (33.5 million entries). The covered properties include energies, forces, multipole moments, and other quantities, e.g., Kohn-Sham matrices. We provide a first demonstration of the utility of our dataset by training ML-based force fields on the data and applying them to run molecular dynamics simulations.</description>
      <author>Stefan Ganscha, Oliver T. Unke, Daniel Ahlin, Hartmut Maennel, Sergii Kashubin, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-025-04720-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation to explore PdSnSe2-n/PdPSe (n = 0, 1, 2) heterostructures as advanced photocatalysts for water splitting applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162899</link>
      <description>Jia-Yi Lin, Chia&#8208;Ying Wu, Chen&#8208;Hao Yeh, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408248170

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia-Yi Lin, Chia&#8208;Ying Wu, Chen&#8208;Hao Yeh</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the catalytic performance of rare earth single atom catalysts for electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136591</link>
      <description>Yongmao Hu, Ruochen Zhu, Xinyuan Yang, Haoyu Wang, Chunyi Lv, Xiaolong Zhou, Yanan Yu, Riming Hu, Shengqiang Zhang, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408252177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongmao Hu, Ruochen Zhu, Xinyuan Yang, Haoyu Wang, Chunyi Lv, Xiaolong Zhou, Yanan Yu, Riming Hu, Shengqiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition tuning and heterostructure construction of Fe-doped Co-Ni hydroxide nanosheets for boosting oxygen electrocatalysis in rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161248</link>
      <description>Zihan Zhang, Zhicheng Zheng, Nattapol Ma, Emmanuel Picheau, Nobuyuki Sakai, Yoshiyuki Sugahara, Takayoshi Sasaki, Renzhi Ma, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408258101

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihan Zhang, Zhicheng Zheng, Nattapol Ma, Emmanuel Picheau, Nobuyuki Sakai, Yoshiyuki Sugahara, Takayoshi Sasaki, Renzhi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Nucleation via Transient Bonds to Oxygen-Functionalized Graphite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08614</link>
      <description>Frederik Doktor S. Simonsen, Niels M. Mikkelsen, Signe Kyrkjeb&#248;, Prashant Srivastava, Richard Balog, Bj&#248;rk Hammer, Karina Morgenstern, Liv Hornek&#230;r, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408273073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Frederik Doktor S. Simonsen, Niels M. Mikkelsen, Signe Kyrkjeb&#248;, Prashant Srivastava, Richard Balog, Bj&#248;rk Hammer, Karina Morgenstern, Liv Hornek&#230;r</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08614</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding AuPd Alloy Nanoparticle Structure under Vacuum Using DFT and Monte Carlo Methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08571</link>
      <description>Conor T. Waldt, Rajeev Kumar, David Hibbitts, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408274680

                AuPd is a miscible metal alloy that is often used in catalysis. Supported AuPd catalysts, at high Au/Pd ratios, form single-atom alloys (SAAs) that have been shown to enhance rates and/or selectivities for many catalytic reactions, including (de)hydrogenations, hydrogenolysis, and C&#8211;C and C&#8211;O coupling reactions. While many computational studies have examined the stability of AuPd structures (the arrangement of atoms within the miscible alloy), most focused on generic alloys rather than SAAs and those that have closely investigated SAAs focused on single crystal surfaces. In this work, we use density functional theory (DFT) to calculate exchange energies (swapping an Au atom with a Pd atom) in a 201-atom truncated octahedral nanoparticle model with a focus on particles with high Au/Pd ratios. We calculate these exchange energies as a function of Pd location within the nanoparticle, the number of Pd atoms neighboring and near those exchange sites, and the total Pd content in the nanoparticle. These DFT-calculated exchange energies are also used to inform simple physics-based models (in contrast to cluster expansion or neural network models) that show good agreement with DFT-calculated values with relatively few regressed parameters. These models are then implemented into Monte Carlo (MC) simulations to predict the nanoparticle structure as a function of composition and temperature. The results show that Pd prefers to be in the subsurface of nanoparticles and that Pd prefers to be isolated from itself within Au. Both observations agree well with prior experimental and computational studies of single-crystal systems. We also show that the overall composition of the nanoparticle influences exchange energies by changing the electronic properties (e.g., Fermi level) of the system, which is relevant as Pd has one fewer valence electron than Au. MC simulations show that, in a vacuum, Pd begins to populate the surface of these &#8764;2 nm nanoparticles at around 20 mol % Pd (at 298 K) and that the number of Pd surface monomers, desired for SAA applications, goes through a maximum near 40 mol % Pd. As the temperature increases, Pd is more prevalent at the surface, but the influence of temperature is relatively muted. While AuPd structures are known to change in the presence of reactive gases (e.g., CO or O2), these studies characterize the baseline thermodynamic arrangements that can be used to understand surface restructuring during catalyst characterization and reaction studies.</description>
      <author>Conor T. Waldt, Rajeev Kumar, David Hibbitts</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy Engineering in the First Coordination Shell of Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for Enhanced Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412000</link>
      <description>Xinqi Chen, Tong Zhou, Tianwei He, Qingju Liu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408286006

                Abstract Modulating the coordination environment of active centers has been proven to be an effective strategy for tuning the activity and selectivity of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs). However, most current research primarily focuses on altering non&#8208;metallic elements coordinating with the single metal atom. In this study, a novel approach is presented by introducing various vacancies into the first coordination shell of single&#8208;atom doped boron&#8211;carbon&#8211;nitride (BCN) catalysts, systematically evaluating their hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions performances. Results indicate that the introduction of vacancy defects enhances the stability of M&#8208;B X C Y N Z structures. Furthermore, adjusting the coordinating atoms around metal sites modulates charge distribution, influencing the binding propensity of intermediates on the adsorption sites and promoting synergistic effects between metal and nonmetal, thereby altering catalytic activity. Specifically, among 147 M&#8208;B X C Y N Z and M&#8208;B X C Y N Z &#8208;vacancy structures, 17 catalysts with excellent HER performance have been identified. Notably, C&#8208;vacancy modulated Ni&#8208;BC 2 N exhibits an OER overpotential of only 0.36V, suggesting that Ni&#8208;BC 2 N&#8208;C1 may serve as an efficient multifunctional electrocatalyst for water&#8208;splitting reactions. This work employs vacancy engineering to precisely modulate the first coordination shell of single&#8208;atom catalysts, not only screening out efficient HER/OER electrocatalysts but also providing guidance for the development of potential BCN&#8208;based multifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xinqi Chen, Tong Zhou, Tianwei He, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed dual-active-site catalyst for enhanced oxygen reduction reaction: Synergistic effects of Fe and V in M&#8722;N&#8722;C structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161441</link>
      <description>Qi&#8208;Dong Ruan, Rui Feng, Lu Liu, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Ya-Cheng Shi, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408286463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi&#8208;Dong Ruan, Rui Feng, Lu Liu, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Ya-Cheng Shi, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Non&#8208;Resonant Infrared Optical Second Harmonic Generation in Bulk Crystals of Van der Waals Semiconductor, SnP&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202402649</link>
      <description>Jadupati Nag, Saugata Sarker, Safdar Imam, Abishek K. Iyer, Michael J. Waters, Albert Suceava, James M. Rondinelli, Mercouri G. Kanatzidis, Venkatraman Gopalan, Advanced Optical Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408287469

                Abstract 2D van der Waals (vdW) materials have emerged as a highly promising candidates for nonlinear optical (NLO) applications. This study presents the synthesis, comprehensive linear optical, and optical second harmonic generation (SHG) characterization of a novel 2D vdW semiconductor SnP 2 Se 6 in its bulk single crystal form. It exhibits an indirect bandgap of &#8776;1.47 eV and an exceptional non&#8208;resonant SHG coefficient of d 33 &#8764; &#8722;222 &#177; 30 pm V &#8722;1 at a fundamental wavelength of 2 &#181;m, which is &#8776;7 times larger than that of the commercial AgGaSe 2 with a comparable bandgap. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations of the linear and nonlinear optical properties exhibit reasonable agreement with the experimental measurements, revealing the chemical origin of the enhanced properties. Moreover, SnP 2 Se 6 can exhibit both type&#8208;I and type&#8208;II phase matching over a wide spectral range, fulfilling one of the key criteria for an ideal NLO crystal. These exceptional properties position SnP 2 Se 6 as a highly promising candidate for NLO applications.</description>
      <author>Jadupati Nag, Saugata Sarker, Safdar Imam, Abishek K. Iyer, Michael J. Waters, Albert Suceava, James M. Rondinelli, Mercouri G. Kanatzidis, Venkatraman Gopalan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202402649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Adsorption Isotherm That Includes the Interactions between Adsorbates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08754</link>
      <description>Simon I. Hansen, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Tejs Vegge, Anker Degn Jensen, Jakob Munkholt Christensen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408291776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simon I. Hansen, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Tejs Vegge, Anker Degn Jensen, Jakob Munkholt Christensen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size-effect induced controllable Cu0-Cu+ sites for ampere-level nitrate electroreduction coupled with biomass upgrading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57097-x</link>
      <description>Yuxuan Lu, Feng Yue, Tianyang Liu, Yucheng Huang, Feng Fu, Yu Jing, Hengquan Yang, Chunming Yang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408292176

                The synergistic Cu0-Cu+ sites is regarded as the active species towards NH3 synthesis from the nitrate electrochemical reduction reaction (NO3-RR) process. However, the mechanistic understanding and the roles of Cu0 and Cu+ remain exclusive. The big obstacle is that it is challenging to effectively regulate the interfacial motifs of Cu0-Cu+ sites. In this paper, we describe the tunable construction of Cu0-Cu+ interfacial structure by modulating the size-effect of Cu2O nanocube electrocatalysts to NO3-RR performance. We elucidate the formation mechanism of Cu0-Cu+ motifs by correlating the macroscopic particle size with the microscopic coordinated structure properties, and identify the synergistic effect of Cu0-Cu+ motifs on NO3-RR. Based on the rational design of Cu0-Cu+ interfacial electrocatalyst, we develop an efficient paired-electrolysis system to simultaneously achieve the efficient production of NH3 and 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid at an industrially relevant current densities (2 A cm&#8722;2), while maintaining high Faradaic efficiencies, high yield rates, and long-term operational stability in a 100 cm2 electrolyzers, indicating promising practical applications. It is challenging to regulate the interfacial motifs of Cu0-Cu+ sites to understand roles of Cu0 and Cu+ for nitrate electrochemical reduction reaction. Here, the authors report a tunable construction of Cu0-Cu+ interfacial structure by modulating the size-effect of Cu2O electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuxuan Lu, Feng Yue, Tianyang Liu, Yucheng Huang, Feng Fu, Yu Jing, Hengquan Yang, Chunming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57097-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom-Embedded Nitrogen-Doped Graphene as Efficient Electrocatalysts for the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00728</link>
      <description>Yinlong Tan, Y. Niu, Ji Xu, X.Y. Cui, Haiming Duan, Qun Jing, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408300849

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have displayed unprecedented activity and selectivity for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Herein, a series of metal single atoms embedded on nitrogen-doped graphene (M&#8211;N4G, where M = In, Tl, Ge, Sn, Pb, Sb, and Bi) is systematically evaluated as CO2RR electrocatalysts by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The computational results show that most M&#8211;N4G exhibit better CO2RR selectivity over the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Ge/Pb&#8211;N4G exhibits excellent electrocatalytic performance in the generation of HCOOH from the CO2RR with low limiting potentials of &#8722;0.292 and &#8722;0.306 eV, which surpass the performance of the vast majority of electrocatalysts. Adsorption energy of the key intermediate *HCOO can be used as an effective reactivity reaction descriptor to screen promising CO2RR catalysts. The results of this work highlight M&#8211;N4G as an ideal electrochemical for the electrocatalytic CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yinlong Tan, Y. Niu, Ji Xu, X.Y. Cui, Haiming Duan, Qun Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering TM&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@C&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Covalent-Organic Frameworks for Enhanced Water-Splitting and Oxygen Reduction Reactions: A Constant Potential and Feature Coevaluation Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c05368</link>
      <description>Yajuan Feng, Xihang Zhang, Renxian Qin, Qingjun Zhou, Yu-Ling Song, Qiang Zhang, Chunping Hou, Zhenjin Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408301839

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yajuan Feng, Xihang Zhang, Renxian Qin, Qingjun Zhou, Yu-Ling Song, Qiang Zhang, Chunping Hou, Zhenjin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c05368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of increasing bending rigidity of graphene with temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120150</link>
      <description>Martin T&#248;mterud, Simen K. Hellner, Sabrina D. Eder, Stiven Forti, Domenica Convertino, J. R. Manson, Camilla Coletti, Thomas Frederiksen, Bodil Holst, Carbon. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408304783

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Martin T&#248;mterud, Simen K. Hellner, Sabrina D. Eder, Stiven Forti, Domenica Convertino, J. R. Manson, Camilla Coletti, Thomas Frederiksen, Bodil Holst</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ adsorption-coupled-oxidation enabled mercury vapor capture over sp-hybridized graphdiyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57197-8</link>
      <description>Honghu Li, Chuanqi Pan, Xiyan Peng, Biluan Zhang, Siyi Song, Ze Xu, Xiaofeng Qiu, Yun-Long Liu, Jinlong Wang, Yanbing Guo, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408305564

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Honghu Li, Chuanqi Pan, Xiyan Peng, Biluan Zhang, Siyi Song, Ze Xu, Xiaofeng Qiu, Yun-Long Liu, Jinlong Wang, Yanbing Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57197-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoparticle-Driven cathode for hydrogen production in microbial electrolysis cell: Synergies and impact</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135020</link>
      <description>Pankaj Kumar, Suraj Prakash Singh Rana, Sakshi, Abdulaziz A.M. Abahussain, Lakhveer Singh, Fuel. 393(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408306343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pankaj Kumar, Suraj Prakash Singh Rana, Sakshi, Abdulaziz A.M. Abahussain, Lakhveer Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Regulation Strategies of Atomic Cobalt Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423552</link>
      <description>Mengyu Chen, Jingqi Guan, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408307736

                Abstract Oxygen electrocatalysis is a core reaction in renewable energy devices, greatly promoting the transformation and upgrading of the energy structure. Nonetheless, the performance of energy conversion devices is hindered by the large overpotential and slow kinetics of oxygen electrocatalytic reactions. Recently, single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as promising contenders in the field of oxygen electrocatalysis because of their exceptional metal atom utilization, distinctive coordination environment, and adjustable electronic properties. This review presents the latest advancements in the design of Co&#8208;based SACs for oxygen electrocatalysis. First, the OER and ORR mechanisms are introduced. Subsequently, the strategies for regulating the electronic structure of Co&#8208;based SACs are summarized in three aspects, including coordination environment, metal centers, and support carriers. A particular emphasis is given to the relationship between the structure and properties of catalysts. Afterward, the latest applications of Co&#8208;based SACs in energy conversion devices are explored. Ultimately, the challenges and prospects for Co&#8208;based SACs are prospected.</description>
      <author>Mengyu Chen, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Flexocatalytic Potential of Wide&#8208;Bandgap Spinel Oxides: Light&#8208;Free Hydrogen Evolution via Strain&#8208;Induced Polarization and Oxygen Vacancy Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424279</link>
      <description>K. Tu, Hsun&#8208;Yen Lin, Jyh&#8208;Pin Chou, Jyh Ming Wu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408307788

                Abstract Wide&#8208;bandgap spinel oxides, such as ZnAl 2 O 4 (ZAO) and ZnCr 2 O 4 (ZCO), are traditionally limited by poor electron activation under light irradiation, resulting in suboptimal photocatalytic performance. This study investigates a novel approach to overcoming these limitations by leveraging the flexoelectric effect in centrosymmetric porous nanoparticles with wrinkled surfaces. The inhomogeneous strain gradients generated under mechanical force induce flexoelectric polarization, offering a promising pathway to enhance photocatalytic activity. ZAO outperforms ZCO due to the smaller atomic radius of aluminum, allowing greater atomic displacement and higher polarization, which prolongs electron&#8208;hole recombination. Oxygen vacancies (O V ) further enhance ZAO performance, with ZAO&#8208;200 (annealed at 200 &#176;C) achieving the longest carrier lifetime (4.65 ns) and an exceptional hydrogen evolution rate of 3737 &#181;mol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 &#8212;206% higher than pristine ZAO&#8212;without light stimulation. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations confirm a lower hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) energy barrier for ZAO (&#916;G H = &#8722;0.13 eV) compared to ZCO (1.34 eV) and reveal spontaneous water splitting at O V sites without energy input. A unique butterfly curve validates flexoelectric potential generation from strain gradients. These findings establish a novel framework for eco&#8208;friendly hydrogen production, demonstrating that flexoelectric polarization and O V engineering can surpass traditional photocatalytic methods in sustainability and efficiency.</description>
      <author>K. Tu, Hsun&#8208;Yen Lin, Jyh&#8208;Pin Chou, Jyh Ming Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lighting the Path to Practical Applications of Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts in Photocatalysis: The Role of Platinum Group Single Atoms in Enhancing Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202400804</link>
      <description>Zi Qi Chen, Aldrich Ngan, Christopher T. Chan, Jaeha Lee, David Dwi Sanjaya, Frank Gu, Solar RRL. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408308385

                Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) show promise because of their efficient use of precious metals, unique coordination and electronic structures, and excellent tunability. Photocatalysis can harvest solar energy to drive energetically unfavorable reactions under mild conditions, offering a sustainable alternative to energy&#8208;intensive reactions. However, the efficiency of solar photocatalysis is limited by poor solar spectrum utilization and rapid charge recombination. Integrating single atoms into semiconductor photocatalysts is a promising route to address these limitations. Mechanistic understanding of single&#8208;atom photocatalysis is crucial for developing efficient catalysts as they guide effective material design. This work provides an overview of the current knowledge on platinum group SACs applied to photocatalytic applications with a focus on the role of single atoms in photocatalytic reactions. The review begins with a summary of the unique advantages of platinum group metal SACs as well as their common structures. A concise summary of synthesis methods is then provided, followed by a comprehensive review of characterization methods for SAC structure, photoelectronic properties, and mechanisms of action. Next, the role of single atoms in improving general photocatalytic processes as well as specific reactions are discussed. Finally, future outlooks for SAC development are included to guide further advancements in the field.</description>
      <author>Zi Qi Chen, Aldrich Ngan, Christopher T. Chan, Jaeha Lee, David Dwi Sanjaya, Frank Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202400804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168152</link>
      <description>Gbolagade Olajide, Khagendra Baral, Sophia Ezendu, Ademola Soyemi, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408190752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gbolagade Olajide, Khagendra Baral, Sophia Ezendu, Ademola Soyemi, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operability for Process Flowsheet Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100229</link>
      <description>Ulysses Guilherme Ferreira, S&#233;rgio Mauro da Silva Neiro, Lu&#237;s Cl&#225;udio Oliveira-Lopes, Thiago V. Costa, Heleno Bispo, Fernando V. Lima, Digital Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408186083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ulysses Guilherme Ferreira, S&#233;rgio Mauro da Silva Neiro, Lu&#237;s Cl&#225;udio Oliveira-Lopes, Thiago V. Costa, Heleno Bispo, Fernando V. Lima</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic Assessment of Ligand-Exchanging Catalytic Cycles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00348</link>
      <description>Orkhan Abdullayev, Diego Garay&#8208;Ruiz, Berta Bori-Bru, Carles B&#243;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408192594

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Orkhan Abdullayev, Diego Garay&#8208;Ruiz, Berta Bori-Bru, Carles B&#243;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inferring the cross-sectional area profile of an unseen solid in a draining tank from liquid level dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121488</link>
      <description>Gbenga Fabusola, Cory M. Simon, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408240913

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gbenga Fabusola, Cory M. Simon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121488</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
