<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 01:39:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the synergistic regulation mechanism of N/C coordination and OH ligands on the bifunctional oxygen electrode activity in Co-N-C doped graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163298</link>
      <description>Linlin Zhang, Nan Chen, Zhen Gao, Rui He, Xinyu Zhang, Yan&#8208;Ning Wang, Kai Xiong, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409534340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linlin Zhang, Nan Chen, Zhen Gao, Rui He, Xinyu Zhang, Yan&#8208;Ning Wang, Kai Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Twisted Two-Dimensional Heterostructures and Performance Regulation Descriptor for Electrocatalytic Ammonia Production from Nitric Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c02696</link>
      <description>Xingxing Wen, Oleg V. Prezhdo, Lai Xu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409538585

                The electrocatalytic reduction of nitric oxide (NO) to ammonia (NH3) represents an attractive alternative for valorizing waste NO streams (NORR). However, discovering efficient catalysts for NO-to-NH3 conversion remains challenging. We have designed metal-intercalated twisted graphene-BN heterostructures, in which metal atoms act as electron-transfer bridges. The twisted configuration facilitates cross-interface charge transfer, redistributing electrons from the graphene-metal interface to the metal-BN interface and BN surface. This electronic modulation enables boron atom adjacent to the metal center in BN to serve as active sites, promoting strong chemisorption and enhanced activation of NO. After high-throughput screening of the stability and NO capture ability of various transition metal-intercalated twisted heterostructures, we have investigated systematically the NORR pathways across 30 candidates. The results show that the rBN-Ti-G&#952; and rBN-V-G&#952; heterostructures exhibit exceptional NO-to-NH3 catalytic performance under optimized twisting conditions. Additionally, using sure independence screening and sparsifying operator (SISSO) for model training, we propose a descriptor and establish a relationship between the twist angle and catalytic activity. This study bridges the gap in applying twisted heterostructures to NORR electrocatalysis and provides new insights and strategies for designing high-performance NORR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xingxing Wen, Oleg V. Prezhdo, Lai Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c02696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrochemical Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Over Low Work Function Cu/ZnO Film Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500414</link>
      <description>Yixuan Yang, Bo Gao, Heng Fu, Chunhui Xiao, Xiaoye Du, Zhongxiao Song, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409538948

                Abstract Cu&#8208;based catalysts for electrochemical CO 2 reduction reactions facilitate the transformation of CO 2 into economically viable multicarbon products. There remains a pressing need to design efficient, stable, and cost&#8208;effective catalysts to enhance the selectivity for these multicarbon products. Metal&#8208;oxide heterogeneous interface can modify the electronic structure of metal surfaces, influencing the adsorption energy of crucial intermediates and thereby enhancing the selectivity for multicarbon products. In this study, Cu/ZnO electrodes are prepared by magnetron sputtering to achieve a Faraday efficiency of 51.2% for C 2 H 4 at &#8722;1.17 V. The Cu/ZnO heterogeneous interface provided abundant active sites for the reaction, and the lower work function facilitated the multi&#8208;electron transfer process necessary for the reduction of CO 2 to C 2 H 4 , thereby enhances the catalytic performance. DFT calculations reveal that the upward shift in the d&#8208;band center of Cu/ZnO, compared to pure Cu, enhances the adsorption energy of the crucial intermediate * CO. Moreover, the C&#8208;C coupling achieved on Cu/ZnO through the * CHO&#8208; * CHO pathway, which features lower energy barriers, ensures high selectivity in the conversion of CO 2 to C 2 H 4 . This work provides a promising and effective strategy for the large&#8208;scale development of metal&#8208;oxide catalysts for the electrochemical reduction of CO 2 to C 2 H 4 .</description>
      <author>Yixuan Yang, Bo Gao, Heng Fu, Chunhui Xiao, Xiaoye Du, Zhongxiao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joule Heating-Driven sp2-C Domains Modulation in Biomass Carbon for High-Performance Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-025-01725-0</link>
      <description>Jiawei He, Yuying Zhao, Lijun Yang, Qixin Yuan, Yuhan Wu, Kui Wang, Kang Sun, Jingjie Wu, Jianchun Jiang, Baohua Zhang, Liang Wang, Mengmeng Fan, Nano-Micro Letters. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409543342

                Abstract Natural biomass-derived carbon material is one promising alternative to traditional graphene-based catalyst for oxygen electrocatalysis. However, their electrocatalytic performance were constrained by the limited modulating strategy. Herein, using N-doped commercial coconut shell-derived activated carbon (AC) as catalyst model, the controllably enhanced sp 2 -C domains, through an flash Joule heating process, effectively improve the edge defect density and overall graphitization degree of AC catalyst, which tunes the electronic structure of N configurations and accelerates electron transfer, leading to excellent oxygen reduction reaction performance (half-wave potential of 0.884 V RHE , equivalent to commercial 20% Pt/C, with a higher kinetic current density of 5.88 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and oxygen evolution reaction activity (overpotential of 295 mV at 10 mA cm 2 ). In a Zn-air battery, the catalyst shows outstanding cycle stability (over 1200 h) and a peak power density of 121 mW cm &#8722;2 , surpassing commercial Pt/C and RuO 2 catalysts. Density functional theory simulation reveals that the enhanced catalytic activity arises from the axial regulation of local sp 2 -C domains. This work establishes a robust strategy for sp 2 -C domain modulation, offering broad applicability in natural biomass-based carbon catalysts for electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Jiawei He, Yuying Zhao, Lijun Yang, Qixin Yuan, Yuhan Wu, Kui Wang, Kang Sun, Jingjie Wu, Jianchun Jiang, Baohua Zhang, Liang Wang, Mengmeng Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-025-01725-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural, mechanical, and electronic properties of single graphyne layers based on a 2D biphenylene network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2025.100506</link>
      <description>Mateus Silva R&#234;go, M&#225;rio Rocha dos Santos, Marcelo Lopes Pereira, Eduardo Costa Gir&#227;o, Vincent Meunier, Paloma Vieira Silva, Carbon Trends. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409546201

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mateus Silva R&#234;go, M&#225;rio Rocha dos Santos, Marcelo Lopes Pereira, Eduardo Costa Gir&#227;o, Vincent Meunier, Paloma Vieira Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2025.100506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of charging in constant potential electrochemistry modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116148</link>
      <description>Henrik H. Kristoffersen, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409546898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Henrik H. Kristoffersen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-engineered ZrSSe/Ga2SSe vdW heterostructure with enhanced visible light harvesting and high solar-to-hydrogen efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.micrna.2025.208174</link>
      <description>Isam Allaoui, A. El Kenz, A. Benyoussef, Mohamed Khuili, Nejma Fazouan, Micro and Nanostructures. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409547773

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Isam Allaoui, A. El Kenz, A. Benyoussef, Mohamed Khuili, Nejma Fazouan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.micrna.2025.208174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Br&#248;nsted&#8211;Evans&#8211;Polanyi relationship in N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; adsorption driven by potential-dependent repositioning of frontier orbitals: a sweet marriage of machine learning-assisted screening and the electric double-layer effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta09221j</link>
      <description>Yali Lu, Ning Guo, Qiang Zhang, Zongjin Hu, Chenglong Shi, Weiju Hao, Yu-Ling Song, Qingjun Zhou, Jianglong Mu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409555450

                We conducted an upgrade prediction for NRR electrocatalysts on g-C 16 N 5 featuring the local coordinationof TM&#8211;N 4 , with Mo@g-C 16 N 5 standing out. Using the constant-potential method and an implicit solvent model, we find the electric double-layer capacitance is key in modulating the kinetic barrier.</description>
      <author>Yali Lu, Ning Guo, Qiang Zhang, Zongjin Hu, Chenglong Shi, Weiju Hao, Yu-Ling Song, Qingjun Zhou, Jianglong Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta09221j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological materials: A roadmap for enhanced catalytic performance in hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.391</link>
      <description>Shivendra Kumar Gupta, Saurabh Kumar Sen, Poorva Singh, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409567582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shivendra Kumar Gupta, Saurabh Kumar Sen, Poorva Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.391</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical and Experimental Insights into CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture and Methanation over Amine-Grafted Ru-Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08009</link>
      <description>Shyam Deo, Thomas Ludwig, Melinda L. Jue, Nathan C. Ellebracht, Mathew J. Rasmussen, James M. Crawford, Matthew M. Yung, Sneha A. Akhade, Simon H. Pang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409569897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shyam Deo, Thomas Ludwig, Melinda L. Jue, Nathan C. Ellebracht, Mathew J. Rasmussen, James M. Crawford, Matthew M. Yung, Sneha A. Akhade, Simon H. Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare earth single atom supported on C2N catalysts for electrochemical CO2 reduction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2025.04.008</link>
      <description>Yu Ren, Qiannan Zhou, Xiaofei Song, Yangyang Song, Zean Xie, Xuehua Yu, Zhen Zhao, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409571744

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Ren, Qiannan Zhou, Xiaofei Song, Yangyang Song, Zean Xie, Xuehua Yu, Zhen Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2025.04.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M-N-C single-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction: Design concept, advanced characterizations, pathways and challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216678</link>
      <description>Muhammad Humayun, Sajjad Ali, Abbas Khan, Pir Muhammad Ismail, Chundong Wang, M. Bououdina, Muhammad Israr, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 538(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409574386

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Humayun, Sajjad Ali, Abbas Khan, Pir Muhammad Ismail, Chundong Wang, M. Bououdina, Muhammad Israr</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand Regulated the Coordination Environment of Cobalt-Group-MOF for Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00419</link>
      <description>Kun Xie, Dongbin Wang, Long Lin, Pengtao Wang, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409574466

                In recent years, the TMN4 moieties have demonstrated significant catalytic activity for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in graphene, CxNy, and other carbon-based two-dimensional (2D) support materials. Modifying the coordination number and species of N atoms in the TMN4 moieties has proven to be an effective approach to regulate their catalytic activity. In this research, by incorporating different triphenylene ligands, we have successfully constructed TMA2B2 (TM = Co, Rh, Ir; A/B = N, O, S, Se) moieties with varying coordination environments within 2D metal organic frameworks (MOFs), which are linked by TM and triphenylene. These moieties serve as an effective model to elucidate the structure-property relationship of two-dimensional 2D-MOFs in OER and ORR. Our findings confirm that alterations in the coordination environment can finely tune the d-band electron distribution of the TM within the TMA2B2 unit, particularly activating the dyz and dz2 orbitals of O2, thereby influencing the interactions between TM and key intermediates. We discovered that the regulatory effect of the coordination environment is closely linked to the electronegativity of the coordinating atoms, which led us to establish reliable descriptors such as &#966;1 and &#966;2 to elucidate the impact of coordination environments on the performance of OER/ORR. This criterion can be applied to numerous other 2D-MOFs and provides an in-depth understanding of the structure-activity relationship facilitates the development of highly efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for OER and ORR applications.</description>
      <author>Kun Xie, Dongbin Wang, Long Lin, Pengtao Wang, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Liquid Crystalline Materials Based on Interfacial Photocatalytic Processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03397</link>
      <description>Ayushi Tripathi, Trenton J. Wolter, Robert J. Twieg, Manos Mavrikakis, Nicholas L. Abbott, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409577870

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ayushi Tripathi, Trenton J. Wolter, Robert J. Twieg, Manos Mavrikakis, Nicholas L. Abbott</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Layer Deposition of PdRu&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Alloy Nanoparticles for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00794</link>
      <description>Yu Liu, Tao&#8208;Qing Zi, Yue Huang, Shuai Zhang, Jawad Ali Shah Syed, Li Gao, Wei-Min Li, Aidong Li, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409579688

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Liu, Tao&#8208;Qing Zi, Yue Huang, Shuai Zhang, Jawad Ali Shah Syed, Li Gao, Wei-Min Li, Aidong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00794</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pulsed Tandem Electrocatalysis Strategy for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00633</link>
      <description>Hao Sun, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409582450

                Electroreduction of CO2 to value-added C2 products remains hindered by sluggish C-C coupling kinetics and competing side reactions. Inspired by the tandem catalytic mechanisms of multienzyme systems, we designed a dual-site single-atom nanozyme (DSAN) comprising FeN4 and FeO4 sites (FeN4-FeO4). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations under constant potential reveal that the FeN4 site functions as a CO generator, while the FeO4 site facilitates CO migration, C-C coupling, and subsequent C2 product formation. To further optimize the catalytic efficiency, we introduced a pulsed electrocatalysis strategy by alternating between zero potential and -0.7 V. This approach dynamically modulates active-site functions: at -0.70 V, CO2 adsorption and *CH3CH2OH formation are facilitated, while at 0 V, CO migration and C-C coupling are enhanced due to the spin-state transitions during potential switching. Additionally, the zero potential suppresses excessive hydrogenation of key intermediates, thereby improving CH3CH2OH selectivity. These findings highlight the synergistic strategy integrating tandem catalysis and pulsed potential control, offering a novel and effective approach for CO2-to-C2 conversion using SAN catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hao Sun, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00633</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic electroreduction of nitrate to ammonia via bimetallic Fe-Cu sites supported on hierarchical porous carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tramat.2025.100030</link>
      <description>Yu Li, Pengpeng Qiu, Chunhong Qi, Minghao Li, Meng Xie, Guihua Zhu, Wei Luo, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409583434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Li, Pengpeng Qiu, Chunhong Qi, Minghao Li, Meng Xie, Guihua Zhu, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tramat.2025.100030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ formation of SrCO3 microcrystals-decorated Fe3O4 nanosheets as an efficient and long-lasting catalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162842</link>
      <description>Amina Lahrichi, Youness El Issmaeli, Bruno G. Pollet, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409590121

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amina Lahrichi, Youness El Issmaeli, Bruno G. Pollet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational insights into the photocatalytic conversion of CO2 to C2H4 on synergistic dual sites in tandem rhenium-bipyridine/copper-porphyrinic system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116144</link>
      <description>Debo Ding, Xiahe Chen, Hongli Wu, Hai&#8208;Min Shen, Teng&#8208;Shuo Zhang, Keke Wang, Yun&#8208;Fang Yang, Yuanbin She, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409605256

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Debo Ding, Xiahe Chen, Hongli Wu, Hai&#8208;Min Shen, Teng&#8208;Shuo Zhang, Keke Wang, Yun&#8208;Fang Yang, Yuanbin She</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Study on the CO2 Reduction Reaction (CO2RR) Performance of h-BN-Based Single-Atom Catalysts Modified with Transition Metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15080628</link>
      <description>Xiansheng Yu, Can Zhao, Qiaoyue Chen, Wei Lai, Xucai Zhao, Lili Zhang, Liqian Wu, Yineng Huang, Nanomaterials. 15(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409607392

                The reasonable design of low-cost, high-activity single-atom catalysts (SACs) is crucial for achieving highly efficient electrochemical CO2RR. In this study, we systematically explore, using density functional theory (DFT), the performance of transition metal (TM = Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn)-doped defect-type hexagonal boron nitride (h-BN) SACs TM@B&#8722;1N (B vacancy) and TM@BN&#8722;1 (N vacancy) in both CO2RR and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Integrated crystal orbital Hamiltonian population (ICOHP) analysis reveals that these catalysts weaken the sp orbital hybridization of CO2, which promotes the formation of radical-state intermediates and significantly reduces the energy barrier for the hydrogenation reaction. Therefore, these theoretical calculations indicate that the Mn, Fe, Co@B&#8722;1N, and Co@BN&#8722;1 systems demonstrate excellent CO2 chemical adsorption properties. In the CO2RR pathway, Mn@B&#8722;1N exhibits the lowest limiting potential (UL = &#8722;0.524 V), and its higher d-band center (&#8722;0.334 eV), which aligns optimally with the adsorbate orbitals, highlights its excellent catalytic activity. Notably, Co@BN&#8722;1 exhibits the highest activity in HER, while UL is &#8722;0.217 V. Furthermore, comparative analysis reveals that Mn@B&#8722;1N shows 16.4 times higher selectivity for CO2RR than for HER. This study provides a theoretical framework for designing bifunctional SACs with selective reaction pathways. Mn@B&#8722;1N shows considerable potential for selective CO2 conversion, while Co@BN&#8722;1 demonstrates promising prospects for efficient hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Xiansheng Yu, Can Zhao, Qiaoyue Chen, Wei Lai, Xucai Zhao, Lili Zhang, Liqian Wu, Yineng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15080628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The use of an Rh-intercalated SiC/graphene interface for CO2 electrochemical reduction: A theoretical investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122760</link>
      <description>Munusamy Rajendran Ashwin Kishore, Karin Larsson, Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409619063

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munusamy Rajendran Ashwin Kishore, Karin Larsson</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of the Key Proton Activities in Hydrogen Evolution Reaction by Electrochromic Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500631</link>
      <description>Yaping Jiang, Jun Hu, Hang Cai, Hongxiang Zeng, Hongyu Wang, Jiangbei Wan, Zhen Wang, Zhigang Chen, Zhigang Zhao, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409620546

                Abstract The electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is a promising route to produce sustainable hydrogen energy carrier for global carbon neutrality. The HER performance is largely determined by the overall proton activities, but the identification of such key proton activities in microscopic HER process is rather difficult. Herein, the study demonstrates a visualized HER concept by integrating the fundamental HER process with electrochromic technology on a well&#8208;designed Pt@WO 3 platform in acidic electrolyte, where the overall proton activities in HER process can be rapidly discriminated by the color changes of Pt@WO 3 electrochromic electrode. In contrast to bare WO 3 counterpart, the Pt@WO 3 electrochromic electrode displays a rather more positive potential of initial&#8208;coloration state and faster decoloration rate associated with significantly improved reaction kinetics of hydrogen intercalation and deintercalation within WO 3 component. Correspondingly, the as&#8208;prepared Pt@WO 3 catalyst electrode exhibits a remarkable HER activity with a lower onset&#8208;potential (45 mV, proton adsorption and accumulation) and smaller Tafel slope (50 mV dec &#8722;1 , proton desorption), nearly 11.1&#8208; and 3.5&#8208;fold enhancement than those of bare WO 3 counterpart. It is believed that the work in integrating the interesting visualization functionality into fundamental HER process may improve the readability of such microscopic electrocatalytic reaction and advance the exploration of more intelligent electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yaping Jiang, Jun Hu, Hang Cai, Hongxiang Zeng, Hongyu Wang, Jiangbei Wan, Zhen Wang, Zhigang Chen, Zhigang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrooxidation of Thymol or Carvacrol to Obtain Thymoquinone on Defective Pt/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424617</link>
      <description>Liang Zhang, Wei Chen, Yuxuan Lu, Yimin Jiang, Liguang Lin, Shengkai Li, Fang Wang, Jianfeng Jia, Zhengjun Wang, Jun Li, Huile Jin, Jingjing Lv, Yuqin Zou, Shuangyin Wang, Shun Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409621900

                Abstract Thymoquinone (TQ), a compound with diverse pharmacological benefits, faces limited availability from natural sources. In this study, the design of a highly efficient electrocatalyst, Pt clusters loaded on CeO 2 with rich oxygen vacancies (Vo&#8208;Pt/CeO 2 ), for the electrocatalytic oxidation of thymol (TY) or carvacrol to produce TQ is reported. The introduction of oxygen vacancies to the surface of Vo&#8208;Pt/CeO 2 significantly reduces the adsorption energy of TQ, facilitating its desorption and preventing product accumulation and catalyst poisoning. As a result, Vo&#8208;Pt/CeO 2 demonstrates exceptional electrocatalytic performance, achieving &#8776;100% selectivity and up to 98% yield of TQ under 1.2 V RHE . In situ, Raman spectroscopy indicates that the electrocatalytic oxidation mechanism of TY involves water attacking the TY intermediate to form thymohydroquinone, which is subsequently oxidized to TQ. Overall, this work provides novel insights into the catalyst design and presents a new strategy for sustainable TQ synthesis.</description>
      <author>Liang Zhang, Wei Chen, Yuxuan Lu, Yimin Jiang, Liguang Lin, Shengkai Li, Fang Wang, Jianfeng Jia, Zhengjun Wang, Jun Li, Huile Jin, Jingjing Lv, Yuqin Zou, Shuangyin Wang, Shun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N, S coordination in Co single atom catalyst promoting CO2RR towards HCOOH at negative potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115137</link>
      <description>H. L. Zhang, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Siyuan Liu, Hongyu Chen, Yiqun Lisa Yin, Zhongyuan Yue, Shuxian Wei, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing L&#252;, Molecular Catalysis. 581(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409624180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. L. Zhang, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Siyuan Liu, Hongyu Chen, Yiqun Lisa Yin, Zhongyuan Yue, Shuxian Wei, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Perspective on Multiscale Modeling of Explicit Solvation-Enabled Simulations of Catalysis at Liquid&#8211;Solid Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01563</link>
      <description>Ricardo A. Garc&#237;a C&#225;rcamo, Jiexin Shi, Ali Estejab, Tianjun Xie, Sanchari Bhattacharjee, Sayani Biswas, Cameron J. Bodenschatz, Xiuting Chen, Manish Maurya, Xiaohong Zhang, Rachel B. Getman, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409625181

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ricardo A. Garc&#237;a C&#225;rcamo, Jiexin Shi, Ali Estejab, Tianjun Xie, Sanchari Bhattacharjee, Sayani Biswas, Cameron J. Bodenschatz, Xiuting Chen, Manish Maurya, Xiaohong Zhang, Rachel B. Getman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances of HKUST-1 metal&#8211;organic frameworks in the biomedical applications: A comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162753</link>
      <description>Mohashin Kabir, Mahbubur Rahman, Tarikul Islam, Qi Meng, Hailei Liu, Minghua Li, Shaohua Wu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409626122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohashin Kabir, Mahbubur Rahman, Tarikul Islam, Qi Meng, Hailei Liu, Minghua Li, Shaohua Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Recent Progress of High-Entropy Layered Double Hydroxides and High-Entropy Amorphous Materials for Water Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.decarb.2025.100110</link>
      <description>Tadele Hunde Wondimu, Yong Zuo, A.A. Shah, Puiki Leung, Yilkal Dessie, Filimon Hadish, Cristina Flox, Qiang Liao, DeCarbon. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409638521

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tadele Hunde Wondimu, Yong Zuo, A.A. Shah, Puiki Leung, Yilkal Dessie, Filimon Hadish, Cristina Flox, Qiang Liao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.decarb.2025.100110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Coupling of Ni-Oxalate Prism and Layered FeOOH for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125393</link>
      <description>Sukhwa Hong, Jiseon Kim, Soonho Kwon, Kahyun Ham, Haowei Long, William A. Goddard, Kangwoo Cho, Paul J. A. Kenis, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409644052

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sukhwa Hong, Jiseon Kim, Soonho Kwon, Kahyun Ham, Haowei Long, William A. Goddard, Kangwoo Cho, Paul J. A. Kenis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One dimensional AWO4 and A2O3 structured high entropy oxide nanowires and their superior oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180556</link>
      <description>Lei Yang, Yiting Dong, Xiaoxian Tian, Jun Yin, Qingwan Wang, Wanxin Wu, Yingguo Yang, Lulu Tang, Xueqin Yuan, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409644800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Yang, Yiting Dong, Xiaoxian Tian, Jun Yin, Qingwan Wang, Wanxin Wu, Yingguo Yang, Lulu Tang, Xueqin Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of NiW@Pd nanocrystals for the electro-catalytic application in the fuel cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6317277/v1</link>
      <description>Ahmed B.M. Ibrahim, Mohamed A. Habib, Sidra Munir, Fawad Ahmad, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409648191

                Abstract The effective inter-conversion of electricity and chemicals via an electrochemical reaction, is significant for energy storage devices such as batteries and fuel cells. These fuel cells are regarded as promising solution to energy crisis in 21st century. The slow kinetics of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is one of the topmost barriers in this discipline and Pt-based catalysts are needed to boost the durability and activity of ORR. To cope with high cost and less accessibility of Pt/C catalyst, Pd based alloys are being expressed as potential replacements for Pt-based electro catalysts in fuel cells as cathodes for oxygen reduction reactions (ORR). But its performance and stability are less than those of Pt. The morphology and composition can be altered by alloying process to enhance their catalytic properties towards ORR. In this study, alloys of Pd with tungsten(W) and nickel(Ni) were synthesized and deposited the prepared material (NiWPd) onto the glassy carbon. Electrochemical investigations confirmed that NiWPd catalysts have improved electro catalytic activities towards oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) with higher specific and mass activities in comparison to Pd/C and Pt/C catalysts. 1.5% NiWPd showed highest ORR performance. Its mass activity came out to be 2.2mA/cm2 that was superior to Pd/C and Pt/C electro catalyst, due to dopants and geometrical impact.</description>
      <author>Ahmed B.M. Ibrahim, Mohamed A. Habib, Sidra Munir, Fawad Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6317277/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nucleation in Confinement: A Pathway to Size-Controlled Ultrasmall Icosahedral Silver Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00288</link>
      <description>Rohan Parmar, Raj Kumar Ramamoorthy, Pierre Roblin, Nicolas Ratel&#8208;Ramond, Lise&#8208;Marie Lacroix, Isaac Rodr&#237;guez-Ruiz, S&#233;bastien Teychen&#233;, Guillaume Viau, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409655754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rohan Parmar, Raj Kumar Ramamoorthy, Pierre Roblin, Nicolas Ratel&#8208;Ramond, Lise&#8208;Marie Lacroix, Isaac Rodr&#237;guez-Ruiz, S&#233;bastien Teychen&#233;, Guillaume Viau</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening and mechanism exploration of excellent OER/HER catalysts for Janus 2H-WSSe monolayer adsorbed transition metal single atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109598</link>
      <description>Zefang Li, Gangbing Song, Yukai An, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 194(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409657957

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zefang Li, Gangbing Song, Yukai An</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically precise Ni clusters inducing active NiN2 sites with uniform-large vacancies towards efficient CO2-to-CO conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59079-5</link>
      <description>Guangyuan Xu, Xingjie Peng, Chuanqiang Wu, Shibo Xi, Huixin Xiang, Lei Feng, Zhendong Liu, Yi Duan, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Si Chen, Yuan Kong, Yanzhe Ma, F.L. Nie, Jie Zhao, Xiao Hai, Su&#8208;Huai Wei, Meng Zhou, Tianfu Wang, Chuanhao Yao, Wu Zhou, Huan Yan, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409661358

                CO2 electroreduction to CO promises to give an efficient strategy for CO2 fixation and transformation. However, current reported active sites fail to deliver sufficient activity with high CO Faradic efficiency (FEco) over a wide range of potential. Here, we show a general synthetic protocol to fabricate a batch of highly pure and active NiN2 catalysts with precise engineering of the uniform-large (UL) vacancy around the active sites, which is accomplished through the 'pre-deposition + pyrolysis' of various atomically precise Ni clusters (Nin) and in-situ etching of the support by the 'nano bomb' (sulfur-ligand in the clusters). The NiN2 sites with UL vacancies could achieve a high turnover frequency (TOF) of 350000 h-1 with ~100% FEco in a wide potential range of 1500 mV. In-situ infrared spectra and theoretical calculations reveal that a highly pure NiN2 site with UL vacancy contributes to this remarkable catalytic performance compared to the counterparts. This general synthetic strategy enables us to simultaneously engineer active sites and surrounding vacancies with the employment of atomically precise metal clusters, thereby enhancing catalytic performance for other specific reactions.</description>
      <author>Guangyuan Xu, Xingjie Peng, Chuanqiang Wu, Shibo Xi, Huixin Xiang, Lei Feng, Zhendong Liu, Yi Duan, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Si Chen, Yuan Kong, Yanzhe Ma, F.L. Nie, Jie Zhao, Xiao Hai, Su&#8208;Huai Wei, Meng Zhou, Tianfu Wang, Chuanhao Yao, Wu Zhou, Huan Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59079-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hexaminobenzene in conductive metal-organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for overall water splitting and metal-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237126</link>
      <description>Anyang Wang, Xiting Wang, Xuhao Wan, Jun Jia, Zeyuan Li, Ke Xue, Rong Han, Zhaofu Zhang, Jun Wang, Yuzheng Guo, Journal of Power Sources. 644(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409661938

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anyang Wang, Xiting Wang, Xuhao Wan, Jun Jia, Zeyuan Li, Ke Xue, Rong Han, Zhaofu Zhang, Jun Wang, Yuzheng Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph neural network-driven prediction of high-performance CO2 reduction catalysts based on Cu-based high-entropy alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60264-0</link>
      <description>Zihao Jiao, C. Zhang, Ya Liu, Liejin Guo, Ziyun Wang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 71(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409665084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihao Jiao, C. Zhang, Ya Liu, Liejin Guo, Ziyun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60264-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning d-band electronic structure of Ni-Fe oxyhydroxides via doping engineering boosts seawater oxidation performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60255-x</link>
      <description>Liyuan Xiao, Xue Bai, Jingyi Han, Zhenl&#252; Wang, Jingqi Guan, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 71(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409665270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liyuan Xiao, Xue Bai, Jingyi Han, Zhenl&#252; Wang, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60255-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into Structure-Activity Relationships between Y Zeolites and their n-C10 Hydrocracking Performances via Machine Learning Approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60259-7</link>
      <description>Qianyi Ma, Hong Nie, Ping Yang, Jianqiang Liu, Hongyi Gao, Wei David Wang, Shihao Dong, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 71(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409665333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianyi Ma, Hong Nie, Ping Yang, Jianqiang Liu, Hongyi Gao, Wei David Wang, Shihao Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60259-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combining reinforcement learning with graph convolutional neural networks for efficient design of TiAl/TiAlN interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20590</link>
      <description>Xinyu Jiang, Haofan Sun, Qiong Nian, Houlong Zhuang, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409668079

                Abstract Ti/TiN coatings are used in a wide range of engineering applications due to their superior properties such as high hardness and toughness. Doping Al into Ti/TiN can further enhance properties and lead to even higher performance. Therefore, studying the atomic&#8208;level behavior of the TiAl/TiAlN interface is important. However, due to the large number of possible combinations for the 50 mol% Al&#8208;doped Ti/TiN system, it is time&#8208;consuming to use the DFT&#8208;based Monte Carlo methods to find the optimal TiAl/TiAlN system with a high work of adhesion. In this study, we use a graph convolutional neural network as an interatomic potential, combined with reinforcement learning, to improve the efficiency of finding optimal structures with a high work of adhesion. By inspecting the features of structures in neural networks, we found that the optimal structures follow a certain pattern of doping Al near the interface. The electronic structure and bonding analysis indicate that the optimal TiAl/TiAlN structures have higher bonding strength. We expect our approach to significantly accelerate the design of advanced ceramic coatings, which can lead to more durable and efficient materials for engineering applications.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Jiang, Haofan Sun, Qiong Nian, Houlong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-metal synergistic integration for electronic structure regulation in schreibersite-type Mo2Fe0.8Ru0.2P electrocatalysts: exceptional enhancement of activity and stability for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.04.020</link>
      <description>Peng Zhang, Shiyu Xu, Hao Li, Chenglin Cui, Sheng-Yang Huang, Zhengyang Li, Hyun Jun Song, Lirui Mao, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Ho Seok Park, Jin Yong Lee, Ji Man Kim, Pil J. Yoo, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409670884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Zhang, Shiyu Xu, Hao Li, Chenglin Cui, Sheng-Yang Huang, Zhengyang Li, Hyun Jun Song, Lirui Mao, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Ho Seok Park, Jin Yong Lee, Ji Man Kim, Pil J. Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.04.020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Amsterdam Modeling Suite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0258496</link>
      <description>Evert Jan Baerends, N&#233;stor F. Aguirre, N. Austin, Jochen Autschbach, F. Matthias Bickelhaupt, Rosa E. Bulo, Chiara Cappelli, Adri C. T. van Duin, Franco Egidi, C&#233;lia Fonseca Guerra, A. F&#246;rster, Mirko Franchini, T. P. M. Goumans, Thomas Heine, Matti Hellstr&#246;m, Christoph R. Jacob, Lasse Jensen, Mykhaylo Krykunov, Erik van Lenthe, Artur Michalak, Mariusz P. Mitoraj, Johannes Neugebauer, Valentin Paul Nicu, Pier Philipsen, Harry Ramanantoanina, Robert R&#252;ger, Georg Schreckenbach, Mauro Stener, Marcel Swart, J. M. Thijssen, Tom&#225;&#353; Trnka, Lucas Visscher, Alexei Yakovlev, Stan van Gisbergen, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(16)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409679285

                In this paper, we present the Amsterdam Modeling Suite (AMS), a comprehensive software platform designed to support advanced molecular and materials simulations across a wide range of chemical and physical systems. AMS integrates cutting-edge quantum chemical methods, including Density Functional Theory (DFT) and time-dependent DFT, with molecular mechanics, fluid thermodynamics, machine learning techniques, and more, to enable multi-scale modeling of complex chemical systems. Its design philosophy allows for seamless coupling between components, facilitating simulations that range from small molecules to complex biomolecular and solid-state systems, making it a versatile tool for tackling interdisciplinary challenges, both in industry and in academia. The suite also emphasizes user accessibility, with an intuitive graphical interface, extensive scripting capabilities, and compatibility with high-performance computing environments.</description>
      <author>Evert Jan Baerends, N&#233;stor F. Aguirre, N. Austin, Jochen Autschbach, F. Matthias Bickelhaupt, Rosa E. Bulo, Chiara Cappelli, Adri C. T. van Duin, Franco Egidi, C&#233;lia Fonseca Guerra, A. F&#246;rster, Mirko Franchini, T. P. M. Goumans, Thomas Heine, Matti Hellstr&#246;m, Christoph R. Jacob, Lasse Jensen, Mykhaylo Krykunov, Erik van Lenthe, Artur Michalak, Mariusz P. Mitoraj, Johannes Neugebauer, Valentin Paul Nicu, Pier Philipsen, Harry Ramanantoanina, Robert R&#252;ger, Georg Schreckenbach, Mauro Stener, Marcel Swart, J. M. Thijssen, Tom&#225;&#353; Trnka, Lucas Visscher, Alexei Yakovlev, Stan van Gisbergen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0258496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Transition-Metal-Anchored Indium Nitride Single-Atom Catalysts for Enhanced Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00569</link>
      <description>Muhammad Tariq, K. Raghu Raja Pandiyan, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409684380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Tariq, K. Raghu Raja Pandiyan, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Host-guest interactions and Stability of Amine-Functionalised Silica Sorbents for Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101123</link>
      <description>Briggs Martins Onyinyechukwu Ogunedo, Basil Wadi, Vasilije Manovi&#263;, Seyed Ali Nabavi, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409537458

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Briggs Martins Onyinyechukwu Ogunedo, Basil Wadi, Vasilije Manovi&#263;, Seyed Ali Nabavi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of electrochemical carbon dioxide capture towards practical application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100660</link>
      <description>Changhong Wang, Kaiqi Jiang, Hai Yu, Shuai Li, Yong Zhao, Zhi Zheng, Harry Liu, Xinbing Xia, Pengfei Zhao, Yibo Li, Hong Liu, Shenghai Yang, Yu Yang, W. Zhang, Hangbo Zheng, Fengwang Li, Kangkang Li, Next Materials. 8(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409568430

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changhong Wang, Kaiqi Jiang, Hai Yu, Shuai Li, Yong Zhao, Zhi Zheng, Harry Liu, Xinbing Xia, Pengfei Zhao, Yibo Li, Hong Liu, Shenghai Yang, Yu Yang, W. Zhang, Hangbo Zheng, Fengwang Li, Kangkang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regressing the self-consistent Hamiltonian and density from the non-self-consistent Hamiltonian</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6347952/v1</link>
      <description>S. Richter, Thomas D. K&#252;hne, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409637053

                Abstract We show that the non-self-consistent electronic Hamiltonian can be used as a chemical descriptor with all common invariances (i.e. translation, rotation, reflection, and permutation) via simple orthonormal matrix transformations. We used a linear regression on a labeled dataset of water dimer clusters with the aforementioned non-self-consistent Hamiltonian matrices as inputs to evaluate their potential as descriptors for predicting the self-consistent Hamiltonian and the corresponding ground-state electron density. Our regression tests were performed as a single layer ANN with a linear activation function to facilitate a relevance analysis. We further mapped our feature space data for non-linear regression up to third order polynomial multivariate regression. To further investigate the influence of the invariances a simplified relevance analysis on the input matrices was done using the trained weights of the input layer. This analysis revealed a shift in relevance from the intra-molecular part (without invariances) to the inter-molecular part of the input matrices when our invariances were applied.</description>
      <author>S. Richter, Thomas D. K&#252;hne</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6347952/v1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
