<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 01:18:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Coupling of Ni-Oxalate Prism and Layered Feooh for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5119480</link>
      <description>Sukhwa Hong, Jiseon Kim, Soonho Kwon, Kahyun Ham, Hongjun Long, William A. Goddard, Kangwoo Cho, Paul J. A. Kenis, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407020794

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sukhwa Hong, Jiseon Kim, Soonho Kwon, Kahyun Ham, Hongjun Long, William A. Goddard, Kangwoo Cho, Paul J. A. Kenis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5119480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of Activities on Multimetal Oxide-type Electrocatalysts for Water Electrolysis Based on Their Crystal Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2320/materia.64.73</link>
      <description>Yuuki Sugawara, Materia Japan. 64(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407022081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuuki Sugawara</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2320/materia.64.73</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing dual active sites modified crystalline carbon nitride with diminished excitation binding energy for overall photosynthesis of H2O2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160091</link>
      <description>Lei Zeng, Chuang&#8208;Dao Jiang, Yueyang Tan, Wei Yang, Qiushi Hu, Xihan Chen, Yabin Jiang, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Wulin Song, Limin Huang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407024094

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zeng, Chuang&#8208;Dao Jiang, Yueyang Tan, Wei Yang, Qiushi Hu, Xihan Chen, Yabin Jiang, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Wulin Song, Limin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening of single-metal atom deposited on 2D BC3N2 monolayers for NO electrocatalytic reduction to NH3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162605</link>
      <description>Wenlong Guo, Xinlin Tang, Haiyue Liao, Peng Jia, Xin Lian, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407024294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenlong Guo, Xinlin Tang, Haiyue Liao, Peng Jia, Xin Lian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of methyl phosphate by molecular dynamics simulations based on first principles and on machine-learning force fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.127062</link>
      <description>Vincenzo Turco Liveri, Sandro L. Fornili, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407027041

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vincenzo Turco Liveri, Sandro L. Fornili</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.127062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-orbital engineering of single-atom catalysts: unlocking high-efficiency nitrate reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08757g</link>
      <description>Chun&#8208;Ying Wu, Yanqing Shen, Lingling Lv, Xianghui Meng, Xin Yang, Xinyu Wang, Xiangqian Jiang, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407040968

                The crucial role of heteroatom doping-induced coordination symmetry breaking in SACs is reported and provides vital insights into the impact of coordination microenvironments on electrocatalytic mechanisms and the rational design of NO 3 RR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chun&#8208;Ying Wu, Yanqing Shen, Lingling Lv, Xianghui Meng, Xin Yang, Xinyu Wang, Xiangqian Jiang, Qing Ai, Yong Shuai, Zhongxiang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08757g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in Experimental Methods Using Model Electrodes for the Development of Noble&#8208;Metal&#8208;Based Oxygen Electrocatalysts in Fuel Cells and Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401851</link>
      <description>Kensaku Kodama, Naoto Todoroki, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407049795

                Abstract Hydrogen plays a key role in maximizing the benefits of renewable energy, and the widespread adoption of water electrolyzers and fuel cells, which convert the chemical energy of hydrogen and electrical energy into each other, is strongly desired. Electrocatalysts used in these devices, typically in the form of nanoparticles, are crucial components because they significantly affect cell performance, but their raw materials rely on limited resources. In catalyst research, electrochemical experimental studies using model catalysts, such as single&#8208;crystal electrodes, have provided valuable information on reaction and degradation mechanisms, as well as catalyst development strategies aimed at overcoming the trade&#8208;off between activity and durability, across spatial scales ranging from the atomic to the nanoscale. Traditionally, these experiments are conducted using well&#8208;defined, simple model surfaces like bare single&#8208;crystal electrodes in pure systems. However, in recent years, experimental methods using more complex interfaces&#8212;while still precisely controlling elemental distribution, microstructure, and modification patterns&#8212;have been established. This paper reviews the history of those studies focusing on noble&#8208;metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions, which account for the majority of efficiency losses in fuel cells and water electrolyzers, respectively. Furthermore, potential future research themes in experimental studies using model electrodes are identified.</description>
      <author>Kensaku Kodama, Naoto Todoroki</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles and machine-learning approaches for interpreting and predicting the properties of MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-025-00529-5</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; D. Gouveia, Tiago L. P. Galv&#227;o, Kais Iben Nassar, Jos&#233; R. B. Gomes, npj 2D Materials and Applications. 9(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407052268

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; D. Gouveia, Tiago L. P. Galv&#227;o, Kais Iben Nassar, Jos&#233; R. B. Gomes</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-025-00529-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air-breathing cathode for aluminum&#8211;air battery: From architecture to fabrication and evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.100942</link>
      <description>Yejian Xue, Jiashu Yuan, Xinfeng Yu, Shanshan Sun, Houcheng Zhang, Wei Zhou, Jiujun Zhang, Yonggao Xia, Materials Science and Engineering R Reports. 163(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407052888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yejian Xue, Jiashu Yuan, Xinfeng Yu, Shanshan Sun, Houcheng Zhang, Wei Zhou, Jiujun Zhang, Yonggao Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.100942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron donation from carbon support enhances the activity and stability of ultrasmall ruthenium dioxide nanoparticles in acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.280</link>
      <description>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 686(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407064505

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic descriptors for designing high-entropy alloy electrocatalysts by leveraging local chemical environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56421-9</link>
      <description>Guolin Cao, Sha Yang, Ji&#8208;Chang Ren, Wei Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407065902

                High-entropy alloys (HEAs) present a vast compositional space for fine-tuning electrocatalytic activities, leveraging millions of distinct active sites on the surface. However, the intricate local chemical environment poses challenges to the rational and efficient design of HEA electrocatalysts with high reactivity. Here, focusing on noble-metal HEAs for oxygen reduction reactions, we propose a straightforward yet effective descriptor for quantitively determining the local reactivities of HEAs. This descriptor is based on a linear combination of the intrinsic d-band filling of the active center and the neighborhood electronegativity. Our model offers an accurate and robust description of the binding strengths of intermediates with different adsorption configurations on HEAs, supported by external density functional theory calculations. Importantly, the local environmental electronegativity of the HEA surface is strongly related to the d-band profile of the center atom(s) embedded within. Finally, we establish a library of activity maps for HEAs encompassing nine noble-metal elements, suggesting that Pd-rich and Ir-rich alloys, such as Pd&#8211;Ag, Ir&#8211;Pt, Ir&#8211;Au compositions, hold promise as potential candidates for optimal electrocatalysts. High entropy alloys hold promises for enhanced oxygen reduction reaction. Here, the authors develop a straightforward yet effective descriptor for rational designing high entropy alloy electrocatalysts with the aid of surface local chemical environments.</description>
      <author>Guolin Cao, Sha Yang, Ji&#8208;Chang Ren, Wei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56421-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screened (Co, Rh, Ir)&#8211;N4 graphene single atom catalysts for hydrogen production via tunable surrounding coordination shell: Computation and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.448</link>
      <description>Jiu-Ning Wang, Wei Xu, Hao Ma, Qasim, Wanglai Cen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 106(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407067075

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiu-Ning Wang, Wei Xu, Hao Ma, Qasim, Wanglai Cen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crash testing machine learning force fields for molecules, materials, and interfaces: molecular dynamics in the TEA challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06530a</link>
      <description>Igor Poltavsky, Mirela Puleva, Anton Charkin-Gorbulin, Gr&#233;gory Fonseca, Ilyes Batatia, Nicholas J. Browning, Stefan Chmiela, Mengnan Cui, J. Thorben Frank, Stefan Heinen, Bing Huang, Silvan K&#228;ser, Adil Kabylda, Danish Khan, Carolin M&#252;ller, Alastair J. A. Price, Kai Riedmiller, Kai T&#246;pfer, Tsz Wai Ko, Markus Meuwly, Matthias Rupp, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Johannes T. Margraf, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407081389

                We present a comprehensive analysis of the capabilities of modern machine learning force fields to simulate long-term molecular dynamics at near-ambient conditions for molecules, molecule-surface interfaces, and materials within TEA Challenge 2023.</description>
      <author>Igor Poltavsky, Mirela Puleva, Anton Charkin-Gorbulin, Gr&#233;gory Fonseca, Ilyes Batatia, Nicholas J. Browning, Stefan Chmiela, Mengnan Cui, J. Thorben Frank, Stefan Heinen, Bing Huang, Silvan K&#228;ser, Adil Kabylda, Danish Khan, Carolin M&#252;ller, Alastair J. A. Price, Kai Riedmiller, Kai T&#246;pfer, Tsz Wai Ko, Markus Meuwly, Matthias Rupp, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Johannes T. Margraf, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller, Alexandre Tkatchenko</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06530a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting electrocatalytic urea synthesis using a two-dimensional descriptor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-025-01424-2</link>
      <description>Amy Wuttke, Alexander Bagger, Communications Chemistry. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407084091

                Electrochemical synthesis routes powered by renewable electricity can provide sustainable chemical commodities by replacing conventional fossil-based processes. Increasing research focuses on value-added chemicals like the indispensable fertilizer urea, which also constitutes a study case for electrochemical CN-coupling. To guide the identification of highly selective catalysts, we aim to provide new insight by analysing existing experimental data on the selectivity of transition metal catalysts towards electrochemically synthesized urea. Firstly, we project high dimensional experimental data using principal component analysis (PCA) to lower dimensions, and thereby confirm that urea selectivity is correlated with the selectivity towards CO and NH3. Furthermore, we identified the most suitable two-dimensional descriptors for selectivity prediction out of various adsorption energies calculated using density functional theory (DFT). We suggest that the adsorption energies of *H and *O on transition metal slabs predict the selectivity towards urea in the co-reduction of CO2 and nitrite ( NO2- ).</description>
      <author>Amy Wuttke, Alexander Bagger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-025-01424-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking linear scaling relationships in oxygen evolution via dynamic structural regulation of active sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55150-9</link>
      <description>Zheye Zhang, Hongyan Zhao, Shibo Xi, Xiaoxu Zhao, Xiao Chi, Hong Bin Yang, Zhongxin Chen, Xiaojiang Yu, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Bin Liu, Peng Chen, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407087380

                The universal linear scaling relationships between the adsorption energies of reactive intermediates limit the performance of catalysts in multi-step catalytic reactions. Here, we show how these scaling relationships can be circumvented in electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction by dynamic structural regulation of active sites. We construct a model Ni-Fe2 molecular catalyst via in situ electrochemical activation, which is able to deliver a notable intrinsic oxygen evolution reaction activity. Theoretical calculations and electrokinetic studies reveal that the dynamic evolution of Ni-adsorbate coordination driven by intramolecular proton transfer can effectively alter the electronic structure of the adjacent Fe active centre during the catalytic cycle. This dynamic dual-site cooperation simultaneously lowers the free energy change associated with O&#8211;H bond cleavage and O&#8211;O bond formation, thereby disrupting the inherent scaling relationship in oxygen evolution reaction. The present study not only advances the development of molecular water oxidation catalysts, but also provides an unconventional paradigm for breaking the linear scaling relationships in multi-intermediates involved catalysis. Circumventing linear scaling relationships in multi-step catalytic reactions is meaningful but challenging. Here, the authors report a method to break this scaling relationship in the oxygen evolution reaction through dynamic regulation of the active site in a Ni-Fe molecular complex catalyst.</description>
      <author>Zheye Zhang, Hongyan Zhao, Shibo Xi, Xiaoxu Zhao, Xiao Chi, Hong Bin Yang, Zhongxin Chen, Xiaojiang Yu, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Bin Liu, Peng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55150-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost-Effective and Stable Biosensing of Biochemical Oxygen Demand in Wastewater Treatment: Exsolved Rhodium-Titanate Perovskite Catalyst in Microbial Fuel Cell-based Biosensors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115692</link>
      <description>Anna Salvian, Shailza Saini, Marina Ram&#237;rez-Moreno, Claudio Avignone&#8208;Rossa, John R. Varcoe, Kalliopi Kousi, Siddharth Gadkari, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407088118

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna Salvian, Shailza Saini, Marina Ram&#237;rez-Moreno, Claudio Avignone&#8208;Rossa, John R. Varcoe, Kalliopi Kousi, Siddharth Gadkari</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Kinetic Monte Carlo Simulations for Single-Cluster Catalysis: Study of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion on Pt/HfC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07877</link>
      <description>H&#232;ctor Prats, Michail Stamatakis, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407089508

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H&#232;ctor Prats, Michail Stamatakis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bias Dependence of the Transition State of the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18638</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; M. Gisbert-Gonz&#225;lez, Carlos G&#243;mez-Rodellar, J. G. F. Druce, Eduardo Ortega, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Sebastian Z. Oener, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407093930

                The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is one of the most prominent electrocatalytic reactions of green energy transition. However, the kinetics across materials and electrolyte pH and the impact of hydrogen coverage at high current densities remain poorly understood. Here, we study the HER kinetics over a large set of nanoparticle catalysts in industrially relevant acidic and alkaline membrane electrode assemblies that are only operated with pure water humidified gases. We discover distinct kinetic fingerprints between the iron triad (Fe, Ni, Co), coinage (Au, Cu, Ag), and platinum group metals (Ir, Pt, Pd, Rh). Importantly, the applied bias changes not only the activation energy (EA) but also the pre-exponential factor (A). We interpret these changes as entropic changes in the interfacial solvent that differ between acid and base and entropic changes on the surface due to a changing hydrogen coverage. Finally, we observe that anions can induce Butler&#8211;Volmer behavior for the coinage metals in acid. Our results provide a new foundation to understand HER kinetics and, more broadly, highlight the pressing need to update common understanding of basic concepts in the field of electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; M. Gisbert-Gonz&#225;lez, Carlos G&#243;mez-Rodellar, J. G. F. Druce, Eduardo Ortega, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Sebastian Z. Oener</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Activation on Single-Atom Catalysts: Importance of the Supporting Matrix</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02064-5</link>
      <description>Matteo Spotti, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Topics in Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407103613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matteo Spotti, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02064-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the electronic structure of CoMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; La doping for efficient and durable electrochemical water splitting reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06599a</link>
      <description>A. Bharathi, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, Pandian Mannu, Ranjit Thapa, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, A. Anto Jeffery, Seong&#8208;Cheol Kim, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407103960

                Metal molybdates (M&#8242;MoO 4 , M = Fe, Co, and Ni) are recognized as active catalysts for water-splitting reactions.</description>
      <author>A. Bharathi, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, Pandian Mannu, Ranjit Thapa, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, A. Anto Jeffery, Seong&#8208;Cheol Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06599a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Density Dependence of the OER Activity and Mechanism in Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07614</link>
      <description>Karim Harrath, Yafei Jiang, Cong&#8208;Qiao Xu, Jun Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407108095

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karim Harrath, Yafei Jiang, Cong&#8208;Qiao Xu, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07614</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstitial Manganese&#8208;Tuned Nickel&#8211;Iron Diselenide Anode for Efficient and Durable Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411397</link>
      <description>Shihao Wang, Ming Li, Haolin Tang, Haining Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407110286

                Abstract Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) employing Ir/Ru&#8208;free anodes emerges as a bright prospect for green hydrogen society. Here, a Ni 0.8 Fe 0.2 Mn 0.1 Se 2 nanosheet electrocatalyst is reported, in situ grown on stainless&#8208;steel paper, as an efficient and durable self&#8208;supporting AEMWE anode for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The interstitial [MnSe 4 ] tetrahedra elevate the Fermi level and narrows the band gap of the electrocatalyst, thereby expediting electrode reaction kinetics and increasing the electrical conductivity. In addition, the interstitial Mn atoms attenuate the electron density of Ni and Fe and motivate phase transition to actual active (Mn, Fe)&#8208;doped &#947; &#8208;NiOOH species. The downward d &#8208;band center of Ni active center facilitates the rate&#8208;limiting * OOH desorption step, refreshing the active center, and reducing the free energy barriers for OER. Accordingly, the Ni 0.8 Fe 0.2 Mn 0.1 Se 2 electrode achieves OER overpotentials of 149 and 232 mV at 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH. The AEMWE cell incorporating Ni 0.8 Fe 0.2 Mn 0.1 Se 2 anode demonstrates high performance (1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.68 V cell ) and durability (at 1 A cm &#8722;2 for 300 h), surpassing most AEMWE cells that use NiFe&#8208;based anodes. This work highlights the potential of noble&#8208;metal&#8208;free anodes for efficient and durable AEMWE.</description>
      <author>Shihao Wang, Ming Li, Haolin Tang, Haining Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Crystalline M&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Sb&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt; (M&#9552;Fe, Co, and Ni) Nanocrystals Tuned by Antimony for Boosting Overall Water Splitting Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202405275</link>
      <description>Yan Zhang, Jiwen Si, Zihan Chen, Longxin Zhao, Fagui Qiu, Wenqing Li, Wei Zhang, Shiding Miao, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407110430

                Abstract Six types of M x Sb y compounds (Fe, Co, and Ni antimonides) are synthesized in form of mono&#8208;dispersed nanocrystallites (NCs) via a hot&#8208;injection metathesis&#8208;reduction. Various contents of Sb atoms are found to drive crystallographic structure and re&#8208;coordination in the M x Sb y materials, leading to rhythmical changes of orthorhombic M 3 Sb&#8594;hexagonal MSb&#8594;monoclinic (or orthorhombic) MSb 2 . The crystallography is identified as crucial factor in electrocatalysis of water splitting at cathodic and anodic electrodes, respectively. Owning to the in&#8208;plane microstrain distributed along (001) plane, the synthesized Ni 3 Sb NCs are more suitable to catalyzing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), sharing overpotential (&#951; 10 ) of 93 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 with Tafel slope of 45 mV dec &#8722;1 , and extremely low hydrogen adsorption resistance (0.019 &#937;) is obtained. The orthorhombic FeSb 2 NCs featured with larger deprotonation capacity of 13.71 mC V &#8722;1 excelled in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrolysis, and is confirmed to facilitate minimal deformation of the OOH * . The integrated devices (FeSb 2 &#8214;Ni 3 Sb) are tested as efficient catalyst for overall water splitting (1.58 V@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) with long stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations elucidated the particular coordination of Sb with proper electronegativity (2.05) is able to adjust active sites, relax electronic attraction, and benefit electrochemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Yan Zhang, Jiwen Si, Zihan Chen, Longxin Zhao, Fagui Qiu, Wenqing Li, Wei Zhang, Shiding Miao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202405275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles of coordination structure design of single-atom catalysts in electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03085-x</link>
      <description>Shihang Zhao, Yuan Pan, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407113186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shihang Zhao, Yuan Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03085-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple and Efficient Non&#8208;Noble Cathode Catalyst Based on Carbon Hollow Nanocapsules Containing Cobalt&#8208;Based Materials for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411019</link>
      <description>Sivaprakasam Radhakrishnan, S. Ramakrishnan, Santhosh Kumar Jayaraj, Mohamed Mamlouk, Byoung&#8208;Suhk Kim, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407113430

                Abstract An efficient approach for fabrication of non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalyst is desirable for designing the energy storage and conversion devices in real&#8208;world usages due to low cost and excellent catalytic properties. The preparation of hollow carbon capsules (HCC) containing cobalt (Co)&#8208;based electrocatalyst is reported by a simple synthesis process without using templates for the first time. Initially, cobalt phenylphosphonate (Co&#8208;MOF) nanorods are fabricated through a simple hydrothermal approach. The as&#8208;formed Co&#8208;MOF is covered with a thin coating of polydopamine (DP&#8208;Co&#8208;MOF) through chemical polymerization of dopamine in Tris&#8208;HCl (pH 8.5). The DP&#8208;Co&#8208;MOF is used as self&#8208;degraded template for the formation of HCC under pyrolysis. The formation mechanism and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity of HCC are investigated. The hollow structure derived under N 2 exhibits a low overpotential (295 mV at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ) with excellent stability (90.98%) for 150 h, which is further verified by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Finally, the designed anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolyzer based on C&#9472;Co&#9472;N as cathode delivers a current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 (at 2.19 V) and 1000 mAcm &#8722;2 (at 2.33 V) in 1.0 m KOH at 60 &#176;C. The fabricated new Co&#8208;based electrocatalyst is highly beneficial for the fabrication of cost&#8208;effective and high&#8208;performance AEMWEs.</description>
      <author>Sivaprakasam Radhakrishnan, S. Ramakrishnan, Santhosh Kumar Jayaraj, Mohamed Mamlouk, Byoung&#8208;Suhk Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star-shaped ZIF-derived carbon-based electrocatalysts with FeNX active sites for enhanced oxygen reduction reaction in high-performance zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118991</link>
      <description>Shuo Tian, Shang Wu, Jincai Yang, Jiankun Li, Chaoyang Liu, Jiali Shi, Xiang Xiao-ming, Lihong Wang, Yuzhi Sun, Quanlu Yang, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407116134

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuo Tian, Shang Wu, Jincai Yang, Jiankun Li, Chaoyang Liu, Jiali Shi, Xiang Xiao-ming, Lihong Wang, Yuzhi Sun, Quanlu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118991</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational design of two-dimensional Co-based boridenes: Functional group-dependent electronic properties and bifunctional HER/OER catalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.493</link>
      <description>Xiangang Wan, Fengxian Ma, Hongbo Wu, Yalong Jiao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 106(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407116201

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangang Wan, Fengxian Ma, Hongbo Wu, Yalong Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChemTexts: a resource for good scientific practice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11144-025-02804-4</link>
      <description>G&#225;bor Lente, Reaction Kinetics Mechanisms and Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407121394

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G&#225;bor Lente</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11144-025-02804-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Computational Methods for Simulating Depolymerization Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c09953</link>
      <description>Shunsuke Mieda, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407131489

                A chemical recycling process that reduces polymers to their raw materials plays a crucial role in circular economy. To contribute to chemical recycling, this study proposes a system that simulates the process of depolymerization from polymer-to-monomer using reactive molecular dynamics (MD). Two MD methods, Reax force field (ReaxFF) and neural network potential (NNP), were employed to simulate the depolymerization of a polystyrene model. We validated the simulation accuracies by comparing monomer yields and decomposition products with experimental results. The results showed that NNP-MD accurately replicated the degradation and redecomposition processes and achieved consistency with the experimental data at various temperatures. ReaxFF-MD, however, was less able to represent the depolymerization process. We conclude that NNP-MD is capable of simulating polymer depolymerization results that are consistent with experimental observations. These results contribute to the development of methods for efficient chemical recycling and the broader realization of a circular economy.</description>
      <author>Shunsuke Mieda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c09953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly dispersed MoC quantum dots assist CeO2 for photocatalytic hydrogen production under visible light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.492</link>
      <description>Guoyang Qiu, Xingyan Yang, Yumin Zhang, Jianhong Zhao, Qingju Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 106(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407132089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoyang Qiu, Xingyan Yang, Yumin Zhang, Jianhong Zhao, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2 electrochemical reduction on single-atom catalysts with optimized environmental, central and axial chemical ambient</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.015</link>
      <description>Zhongze Bai, Xi Zhuo Jiang, Kai Luo, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407133649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongze Bai, Xi Zhuo Jiang, Kai Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The activity origin of two-dimensional MN4-contained periodical macrocyclic structures towards electro-catalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.022</link>
      <description>Mengmeng Xu, Yunpeng Shu, Xu Wang, Yanjun Chen, Juan Xie, Youyong Li, Huilong Dong, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407133660

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengmeng Xu, Yunpeng Shu, Xu Wang, Yanjun Chen, Juan Xie, Youyong Li, Huilong Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmentation of Universal Potentials for Broad Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.056201</link>
      <description>Joe Pitfield, Florian Brix, Zeyuan Tang, Andreas M&#248;ller Slavensky, Nikolaj R&#248;nne, Mads-Peter V. Christiansen, Bj&#248;rk Hammer, Physical Review Letters. 134(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407134245

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joe Pitfield, Florian Brix, Zeyuan Tang, Andreas M&#248;ller Slavensky, Nikolaj R&#248;nne, Mads-Peter V. Christiansen, Bj&#248;rk Hammer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.056201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical&#8211;chemical coupling in gas&#8211;surface interaction: A study of strain effects on the catalytic properties of SiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245036</link>
      <description>Yue Gao, Songhe Meng, Qiang Yang, Zexuan Wang, Bo Gao, Fan Yang, Physics of Fluids. 37(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407136149

                In actual flight conditions, the surface of thermal protection materials may experience stress, and the impact of surface strain on catalytic reaction and mechanical&#8211;chemical coupling has not been fully explored. In this study, a surface gas&#8211;solid interaction model was constructed using reaction molecular dynamics and density functional theory methods. The surface catalytic reaction characteristics of &#945;-SiO2 (001) under up to 2% uniaxial and biaxial tensile strain were investigated. Results indicate that both uniaxial stretching along the X axis and biaxial stretching along the X and Y axes inhibit the catalytic recombination reaction at higher surface temperatures. For the uniaxial stretching model, when the strain reaches 2%, the catalytic coefficient decreases by 21.2%, whereas for the biaxial stretching model, it decreases by 34.3%. From the perspectives of surface morphology and energy, the study reveals that tensile strain reduces the undercoordination degree of Si atoms on the surface, reduces the surface energy of &#945;-SiO2 (001), increases the activation energy of the atomic oxygen recombination reaction, alters the recombination pathways of oxygen atoms, strain-induced selective desorption of oxygen atoms reduces the recombination probabilities of both Eley&#8211;Rideal and Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood pathways, ultimately decreasing the catalytic recombination coefficient.</description>
      <author>Yue Gao, Songhe Meng, Qiang Yang, Zexuan Wang, Bo Gao, Fan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rules Describing CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activation on Single-Atom Alloys from DFT-Meta-GGA Calculations and Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07178</link>
      <description>Herzain I. Rivera-Arrieta, Lucas Foppa, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407136518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Herzain I. Rivera-Arrieta, Lucas Foppa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge Transfer Modulation in g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Composites: Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c05341</link>
      <description>Xueli Mei, Xueyang Zhao, Hongtao Xie, Nemanja Gavrilov, Qin Geng, Qin Li, Huawei Zhuo, Yali Cao, Yizhao Li, Fan Dong, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407137887

                The electrocatalytic two-electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e-ORR) represents one of the most prospective avenues for the in situ synthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2). However, the four-electron competition reaction constrains the efficiency of H2O2 synthesis. Therefore, there is an urgent need to develop superior catalysts to facilitate the H2O2 synthesis. In this study, graphite-phase carbon nitride and cerium dioxide composites (g-C3N4/CeO2) with varying CeO2 loadings were prepared with favorable 2e-ORR electrocatalysts. The optimized composite, containing 20 wt % CeO2 (g-C3N4/CeO2-20%) exhibited the highest Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 97% and notable H2O2 yielding of 9.84 mol gcat.&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 at the potential of 0.3 V (vs RHE) in a 0.1 M KOH electrolyte. Density functional theory calculations revealed that the improvement of the selectivity and yield of H2O2 for the composites were attributed to the charge transfer between g-C3N4 and CeO2, which causes the active site C atom donating electrons to form C+, thereby enhancing the adsorption and desorption of *OOH intermediates. Additionally, the g-C3N4/CeO2-20% composite exhibits excellent 2e-ORR performance in neutral and acidic electrolytes and demonstrates superior capability in electro-Fenton degradation of organic pollutants. This study not only provides new insights into the electrocatalytic mechanism of g-C3N4/CeO2 composites but also demonstrates an effective method for designing 2e-ORR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xueli Mei, Xueyang Zhao, Hongtao Xie, Nemanja Gavrilov, Qin Geng, Qin Li, Huawei Zhuo, Yali Cao, Yizhao Li, Fan Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c05341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Electrocatalytic Activity of Metallophthalocyanine-Based Covalent Organic Frameworks Toward CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07500</link>
      <description>Kahkasha Parveen, Srimanta Pakhira, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407140873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kahkasha Parveen, Srimanta Pakhira</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABFML: A problem-oriented package for rapidly creating, screening, and optimizing new machine learning force fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0247559</link>
      <description>Xingze Geng, Jianing Gu, Gaowu Qin, Lin&#8208;Wang Wang, Xiangying Meng, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407141817

                Machine Learning Force Fields (MLFFs) require ongoing improvement and innovation to effectively address challenges across various domains. Developing MLFF models typically involves extensive screening, tuning, and iterative testing. However, existing packages based on a single mature descriptor or model are unsuitable for this process. Therefore, we developed a package named ABFML, based on PyTorch, which aims to promote MLFF innovation by providing developers with a rapid, efficient, and user-friendly tool for constructing, screening, and validating new force field models. Moreover, by leveraging standardized module operations and cutting-edge machine learning frameworks, developers can swiftly establish models. In addition, the platform can seamlessly transition to the graphics processing unit environments, enabling accelerated calculations and large-scale parallel simulations of molecular dynamics. In contrast to traditional from-scratch approaches for MLFF development, ABFML significantly lowers the barriers to developing force field models, thereby expediting innovation and application within the MLFF development domains.</description>
      <author>Xingze Geng, Jianing Gu, Gaowu Qin, Lin&#8208;Wang Wang, Xiangying Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0247559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supramolecular Engineering of Vinylene&#8208;Linked Covalent Organic Framework &#8211; Ruthenium Oxide Hybrids for Highly Active Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417374</link>
      <description>Kexin Wang, Shunqi Xu, Dashuai Wang, Zhenhui Kou, Yubin Fu, Michal&#823; Bielejewski, Ver&#243;nica Montes&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Bin Han, Artur Ciesielski, Yang Hou, Paolo Samor&#305;&#769;, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407149229

                Abstract The controlled formation of a functional adlayer at the catalyst&#8208;water interface is a highly challenging yet potentially powerful strategy to accelerate proton transfer and deprotonation for ultimately improving the performance of proton&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). In this study, the synthesis of robust vinylene&#8208;linked covalent organic frameworks (COFs) possessing high proton conductivities is reported, which are subsequently hybridized with ruthenium dioxide yielding high&#8208;performance anodic catalysts for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In situ spectroscopic measurements corroborated by theoretical calculations reveal that the assembled hydrogen bonds formed between COFs and adsorbed oxo&#8208;intermediates effectively orient interfacial water molecules, stabilizing the transition states for intermediate formation of OER. This determines a decrease in the energy barriers of proton transfer and deprotonation, resulting in exceptional acidic OER performance. When integrated into a PEMWE device, the system achieves a record current density of 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at only 1.54 V cell voltage, with a long&#8208;term stability exceeding 180 h at industrial&#8208;level 200 mA cm &#8722;2 . The approach relying on the self&#8208;assembly of an oriented hydrogen&#8208;bonded adlayer highlights the disruptive potential of COFs with customizable structures and multifunctional sites for advancing PEMWE technologies.</description>
      <author>Kexin Wang, Shunqi Xu, Dashuai Wang, Zhenhui Kou, Yubin Fu, Michal&#823; Bielejewski, Ver&#243;nica Montes&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Bin Han, Artur Ciesielski, Yang Hou, Paolo Samor&#305;&#769;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental studies of &lt;scp&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; and &lt;scp&gt;NO&lt;/scp&gt; mitigation using potential adsorbents in a standby power generation unit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14553</link>
      <description>Maniarasu Ravi, Sushil Kumar Rathore, Murugan Sivalingam, Environmental Progress &amp; Sustainable Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407151073

                Abstract This current investigation evaluates the feasibility of employing potential adsorbents obtained from various biomass waste substances, namely, (i) coconut shell, (ii) rice husk, and (iii) eucalyptus wood, for carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) capture applications. Activated carbons are obtained from abundantly available renewable biomass residues by single&#8208;stage activation. The adsorption properties are evaluated using advanced techniques. Further, the adsorbents are packed in an in&#8208;house fabricated post&#8208;combustion adsorption chamber. In this investigation, the feasibility of employing adsorbents for capturing CO 2 and NO by using an adsorption technique in a diesel engine&#8208;operated standby diesel generator set intended to supply electrical power to a guest house, hostels, faculty quarters, and residential area in an educational institution in India is investigated. Essential parameters such as (i) maximum adsorption capacity, (ii) fractional adsorption kinetics, (iii) regenerability and reusability, (iv) dynamic adsorption of the breakthrough curve, and (v) isosteric enthalpy of adsorption of adsorbent samples are also examined. Compared to the other adsorbents examined, eucalyptus wood adsorbent mitigates CO 2 and NO by 50% and 36% at full load, respectively.</description>
      <author>Maniarasu Ravi, Sushil Kumar Rathore, Murugan Sivalingam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Pt3Ni Catalysts, Plasma-Etched Multiscale Membrane, and Flow Field with Micro-Channel for High-Performance Fuel Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40684-024-00690-0</link>
      <description>Jue&#8208;Hyuk Jang, Changwook Seol, Segeun Jang, Jinwon Lee, Sang Moon Kim, Sung Jong Yoo, International Journal of Precision Engineering and Manufacturing-Green Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407154300

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jue&#8208;Hyuk Jang, Changwook Seol, Segeun Jang, Jinwon Lee, Sang Moon Kim, Sung Jong Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40684-024-00690-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Functionalized Graphene as Highly Active Catalysts for C&#8211;N Bond Formation in Electrochemical Urea Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07971</link>
      <description>Tsai-Jen Lin, Wei-Sen Chen, Hsien-Chin Li, Chaoyang Chen, Hansaem Choi, Youngkook Kwon, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407159128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tsai-Jen Lin, Wei-Sen Chen, Hsien-Chin Li, Chaoyang Chen, Hansaem Choi, Youngkook Kwon, Mu&#8208;Jeng Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Transformation of Copper-Coordinated COFs Drives Enhanced Multi-Carbon Selectivity in CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125131</link>
      <description>Jian Yu, Yang Zheng, Bo Lv, Aiming Huang, Junjun Zhang, Zizi Wang, Yifan Zhang, Yang Wu, Yanan Zhou, Yong Wang, Wen Luo, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407164905

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Yu, Yang Zheng, Bo Lv, Aiming Huang, Junjun Zhang, Zizi Wang, Yifan Zhang, Yang Wu, Yanan Zhou, Yong Wang, Wen Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A first-principles study into the development of a bifunctional, single-atom catalyst for nickel loading on melon carbon nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162640</link>
      <description>Xiao-Kuan Wu, Xinying Teng, Zhao Hong, Zhigang Lei, Jie Zhang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407165140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao-Kuan Wu, Xinying Teng, Zhao Hong, Zhigang Lei, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cathode materials and novel strategies for improving bioenergy production in microbial electrolysis cell: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115718</link>
      <description>Miaomiao Yang, Shuai Luo, Rongfang Yuan, Rongrong Hou, Beihai Zhou, Huilun Chen, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407171832

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miaomiao Yang, Shuai Luo, Rongfang Yuan, Rongrong Hou, Beihai Zhou, Huilun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic Modelling of Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Ir(111)@N&#8208;Graphene Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400907</link>
      <description>Adyasa Priyadarsini, Bhabani S. Mallik, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407172985

                Abstract We have explored the thermodynamics and microkinetic aspects of oxygen evolution catalysis on low loading of Ir(111) on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene at constant potential. The electronic modification induced by N&#8208;doping is the reason for the reduced overpotential of OER. The N&#8208;induced defect in the charge density is observed with increasing charge&#8208;depleted region around the Ir atoms. The lattice contraction shifts the d&#8208;band center away from the Fermi level, which increases the barrier for OH* and O* formation on Ir(111) supported on NGr (Ir(111)@NGr). Thus, highly endothermic O* formation reduces the OOH* formation, which is the potential determining step. For comparison, all electronic and binding energy calculations were also performed against Ir NP supported on Gr (Ir(111)@Gr). The stepwise potential&#8208;dependent activation barrier ( ) was obtained using the charge extrapolation method. The third step remains the RDS in all ranges of water oxidation potentials. The potential dependent is further applied to the Eyring rate equation to obtain the current density ( ) and correlation between and pH dependence, i. e., OH &#8722; concentration. The microkinetic progression leads to a Tafel slope value of 30 mV dec &#8722;1 at pH=14.0, requiring .</description>
      <author>Adyasa Priyadarsini, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Speeds Up the Discovery of Efficient Porphyrinoid Electrocatalysts for Ammonia Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12888</link>
      <description>Wenfeng Hu, Bingyi Song, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407178198

                Two&#8208;dimensional transition metal porphyrinoid materials (2DTMPoidMats), due to their unique electronic structure and tunable metal active sites, have the potential to enhance interactions with nitrogen molecules and promote the protonation process, making them promising electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR) electrocatalysts. Experimentally screening a large number of catalysts for eNRR catalytic performance would consume considerable time and economic resources. First&#8208;principles calculations and machine learning (ML) algorithms could greatly improve the efficiency of catalyst screening. Using this approach, we selected 86 candidates capable of catalyzing eNRR from 1290 types of 2DTMPoidMats, and verified the results with density functional theory (DFT) computations. Analysis of the full reaction pathway shows that MoPp&#8208;meso&#8208;F&#8208;&#946;&#8208;Py, MoPp&#8208;&#946;&#8208;Cl&#8208;meso&#8208;Diyne, MoPp&#8208;meso&#8208;Ethinyl, and WPp&#8208;&#946;&#8208;Pz exhibit the best catalytic performance with the onset potential of &#8722;0.22, &#8722;0.19, &#8722;0.23, and &#8722;0.35 V, respectively. This work provides valuable insights into efficient design and screening of eNRR catalysts and promotes the application of ML algorithmic models in the field of catalysis.</description>
      <author>Wenfeng Hu, Bingyi Song, Li&#8208;Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite Oxides for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen/Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400648</link>
      <description>Lu Lu, Mingzi Sun, Tong Wu, Qiuyang Lu, Baian Chen, Cheuk Hei Chan, Hon Ho Wong, Zikang Li, Bolong Huang, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407179736

                Abstract Since the excessive exploitation of fossil fuels will cause wars for oil, developing sustainable and eco&#8208;friendly energy resources to solve the energy crisis and realize the carbon&#8208;neutrality goal has been a hot issue. Water electrolysis has been acknowledged as a promising technology for hydrogen (H 2 )/oxygen (O 2 ) evolution reaction (HER/OER) since the overall water splitting reaction rates can be well controlled by applying appropriate electrode voltage. Whereas the sluggish electrochemical reactions kinetics on both the cathode and anode have greatly restricted the energy conversion efficiency. Thus, developing highly active electrocatalysts to reduce the overpotentials required for electrolytic HER/OER is of great significance in increasing the utilization rates of electrical power and lowering production costs. ABO 3 &#8208;structured perovskite&#8208;oxides based electrocatalysts possess the merits of low cost, high structural stability, and lattice compatibility, and thus they have attracted intense research attention in recent decays. To inspire both theoretical and experimental researchers to design novel perovskite&#8208;oxide electrocatalysts for efficient HER/OER, the fundamental electrode reaction mechanisms, the effects of synthetic methods on material morphologies, recently reported perovskite&#8208;oxide electrocatalysts and effective tuning strategies on enhancing the electrocatalytic activities of existing perovskite&#8208;oxides have been fully discussed in this review.</description>
      <author>Lu Lu, Mingzi Sun, Tong Wu, Qiuyang Lu, Baian Chen, Cheuk Hei Chan, Hon Ho Wong, Zikang Li, Bolong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced theoretical modeling methodologies for electrocatalyst design in sustainable energy conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235572</link>
      <description>Tianyi Wang, Qilong Wu, Yun Han, Zhongyuan Guo, Jun Chen, Chuangwei Liu, Applied Physics Reviews. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407191563

                Electrochemical reactions are pivotal for energy conversion and storage to achieve a carbon-neutral and sustainable society, and optimal electrocatalysts are essential for their industrial applications. Theoretical modeling methodologies, such as density functional theory (DFT) and molecular dynamics (MD), efficiently assess electrochemical reaction mechanisms and electrocatalyst performance at atomic and molecular levels. However, its intrinsic algorithm limitations and high computational costs for large-scale systems generate gaps between experimental observations and calculation simulation, restricting the accuracy and efficiency of electrocatalyst design. Combining machine learning (ML) is a promising strategy to accelerate the development of electrocatalysts. The ML-DFT frameworks establish accurate property&#8211;structure&#8211;performance relations to predict and verify novel electrocatalysts' properties and performance, providing a deep understanding of reaction mechanisms. The ML-based methods also accelerate the solution of MD and DFT. Moreover, integrating ML and experiment characterization techniques represents a cutting-edge approach to providing insights into the structural, electronic, and chemical changes under working conditions. This review will summarize the DFT development and the current ML application status for electrocatalyst design in various electrochemical energy conversions. The underlying physical fundaments, application advancements, and challenges will be summarized. Finally, future research directions and prospects will be proposed to guide novel electrocatalyst design for the sustainable energy revolution.</description>
      <author>Tianyi Wang, Qilong Wu, Yun Han, Zhongyuan Guo, Jun Chen, Chuangwei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additively Manufactured High Surface Area 3D Cathodes for Efficient and Productive Electro-Bio-Methanation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00109</link>
      <description>Buddhinie Srimali Jayathilake, Swetha Chandrasekaran, J&#246;rg S. Deutzmann, Frauke Kracke, C. Allin Cornell, Matthew A. Worthington, Megan C. Freyman, Melinda L. Jue, Alfred M. Spormann, Simon H. Pang, Sarah E. Baker, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407200148

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Buddhinie Srimali Jayathilake, Swetha Chandrasekaran, J&#246;rg S. Deutzmann, Frauke Kracke, C. Allin Cornell, Matthew A. Worthington, Megan C. Freyman, Melinda L. Jue, Alfred M. Spormann, Simon H. Pang, Sarah E. Baker</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anisotropic Janus monolayers BXY (X = P, as or Sb, Y = S, Se or Te) for photocatalytic water splitting: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solener.2025.113320</link>
      <description>Yanfu Zhao, Bofeng Zhang, Jiahe Lin, Solar Energy. 288(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407203428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanfu Zhao, Bofeng Zhang, Jiahe Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solener.2025.113320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-dimensional Pd@PtIrM ( M = Mn, Fe, Co, Ni) core&#8211;shell nanowires for efficient oxygen reduction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134581</link>
      <description>Hong Pan, Qian Liu, Jiabo Geng, Luo Sheng-quan, Xiaoxuan Ren, Faming Gao, Fuel. 389(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407203532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Pan, Qian Liu, Jiabo Geng, Luo Sheng-quan, Xiaoxuan Ren, Faming Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134581</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand canonical view on electrochemical energetics at applied potential in a nutshell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101656</link>
      <description>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407204775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Sensitivity of N 1s Excitations in &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Methylacetamide Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03487</link>
      <description>Eemeli A. Eronen, Anton Vladyka, Christoph J. Sahle, Jyrki Niskanen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407206267

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eemeli A. Eronen, Anton Vladyka, Christoph J. Sahle, Jyrki Niskanen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Prediction of Ionic Epitaxial Interfaces with Ogre Demonstrated for Colloidal Heterostructures of Lead Halide Perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c12713</link>
      <description>Stefano Toso, Derek Dardzinski, Liberato Manna, Noa Marom, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407075497

                Colloidal epitaxial heterostructures are nanoparticles composed of two different materials connected at an interface, which can exhibit properties different from those of their individual components. Combining dissimilar materials offers exciting opportunities to create a wide variety of functional heterostructures. However, assessing structural compatibility&#9472;the main prerequisite for epitaxial growth&#9472;is challenging when pairing complex materials with different lattice parameters and crystal structures. This complicates both the selection of target heterostructures for synthesis and the assignment of interface models when new heterostructures are obtained. Here, we demonstrate Ogre as a powerful tool to accelerate the design and characterization of colloidal heterostructures. To this end, we implemented developments tailored for the high-efficiency prediction of epitaxial interfaces between ionic/polar materials, which encompass most colloidal semiconductors. These include the use of pre-screening candidate models based on charge balance at the interface and the use of a classical potential for fast energy evaluations, with parameters automatically calculated based on the input bulk structures. These developments are validated for perovskite-based CsPbBr3/Pb4S3Br2 heterostructures, where Ogre produces interface models in excellent agreement with density functional theory and experiments. Furthermore, we use Ogre to rationalize the templating effect of CsPbCl3 on the growth of lead sulfochlorides, where perovskite seeds induce the formation of Pb4S3Cl2 rather than Pb3S2Cl2 due to better epitaxial compatibility. Finally, combining Ogre simulations with experimental data enables us to unravel the structure and composition of the hitherto unsolved CsPbBr3/BixPbySz interface, and to assign a structure to several other reported metal halide- and oxide-based interfaces. The Ogre package is available on GitHub or via the OgreInterface desktop application, available for Windows, Linux, and Mac.</description>
      <author>Stefano Toso, Derek Dardzinski, Liberato Manna, Noa Marom</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c12713</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated &lt;i&gt;Systems-to-Atoms&lt;/i&gt; (S2A) Framework for Designing Resilient and Efficient Hydrogen Infrastructure Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05903</link>
      <description>Mengyao Yuan, Giovanna Bucci, Tanusree Chatterjee, Shyam Deo, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird, Wenqin Li, Thomas Moore, Corey Myers, Wenyu Sun, Ethan M. Sunshine, Bo-Xun Wang, Matthew J. McNenly, Sneha A. Akhade, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407089073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyao Yuan, Giovanna Bucci, Tanusree Chatterjee, Shyam Deo, John R. Kitchin, Carl D. Laird, Wenqin Li, Thomas Moore, Corey Myers, Wenyu Sun, Ethan M. Sunshine, Bo-Xun Wang, Matthew J. McNenly, Sneha A. Akhade</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05903</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
