<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 01:23:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances and challenges in single-atom catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100553</link>
      <description>Wei Xia, Jinyang Zhang, Guangyu Xu, Ting Jin, Qing&#8208;Lun Wang, Lifang Jiao, Next Materials. 8(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407763613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Xia, Jinyang Zhang, Guangyu Xu, Ting Jin, Qing&#8208;Lun Wang, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on hydrogen evolution performance of monatomic Mo/C electrocatalysts modified by metal atom X (X= Fe, Co, Ni or Cu) : A first-principles based approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.087</link>
      <description>Yutong Yu, Lisheng Zhong, Ke Shi, Enci Han, Jianhong Peng, Yunhua Xu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 109(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407778090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yutong Yu, Lisheng Zhong, Ke Shi, Enci Han, Jianhong Peng, Yunhua Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating crystal structure search through active learning with neural networks for rapid relaxations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01523-7</link>
      <description>Stefaan S. P. Hessmann, Kristof T. Sch&#252;tt, Niklas W. A. Gebauer, Michael Gastegger, Tamio Oguchi, Tomoki Yamashita, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407779411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefaan S. P. Hessmann, Kristof T. Sch&#252;tt, Niklas W. A. Gebauer, Michael Gastegger, Tamio Oguchi, Tomoki Yamashita</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01523-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Physics-inspired Machine Learning to Design Nanocluster Catalysts for Dehydrogenating Liquid Organic Hydrogen Carriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125192</link>
      <description>Chuhong Lin, Bryan Lee, Uzma Anjum, Asmee Prabhu, Neeru Chaudhary, Rong Xu, Tej S. Choksi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407791548

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuhong Lin, Bryan Lee, Uzma Anjum, Asmee Prabhu, Neeru Chaudhary, Rong Xu, Tej S. Choksi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Energies of Formation Reactions for Adsorbates on Late Transition Metal Surfaces: a Database Update</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122714</link>
      <description>Charles T. Campbell, Jan Fingerhut, Alec M. Wodtke, Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407795942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Charles T. Campbell, Jan Fingerhut, Alec M. Wodtke</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoreduction Efficiency of Carbon Nitride via S&#8208;scheme g&#8208;C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;TiO&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202422055</link>
      <description>Gustavo Bulgraen dos Santos, Liang Tian, Renato V. Gon&#231;alves, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Liane M. Rossi, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407798383

                Abstract Photocatalysis has emerged as an alternative to high energy&#8208;demanding CO 2 reduction reactions. Among the widely studied photocatalysts, g&#8208;C 3 N 4 stands out due to its composition based on earth&#8208;abundant elements, its ability to absorb visible light, and its suitable band structure. In this study, a photocatalyst based on an S&#8208;scheme heterojunction formed by g&#8208;C 3 N 4 and nanosized Fe 2 TiO 5 is successfully prepared via simple hydrothermal assembly of both pre&#8208;synthesized semiconductors. Modifications induced on g&#8208;C 3 N 4 during the heterojunction preparation play a crucial role in the efficiency of the CO 2 photoreduction reaction. Under simulated sunlight irradiation, the g&#8208;C 3 N 4 /Fe 2 TiO 5 heterojunction exhibits higher photocatalytic performance than the pristine materials for both CO 2 reduction to produce CO and CH 4 , and H 2 O reduction reaction, producing H 2 . The results obtained correspond to a 1.5&#8208;fold improvement compared to pristine g&#8208;C 3 N 4 . When [Ru(bpy) 3 ] 2+ is applied as a sensitizer, the visible light (&gt;380 nm) activity of the photocatalytic system is restored, showing lower activity but higher selectivity toward CO and H 2 production, a route to renewable syngas.</description>
      <author>Gustavo Bulgraen dos Santos, Liang Tian, Renato V. Gon&#231;alves, Hermenegildo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Liane M. Rossi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202422055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation of Single-Atom Catalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Based on Two-Dimensional Tetragonal V2C2 and V3C3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18050931</link>
      <description>Bo Xue, Qingfeng Zeng, Shuyin Yu, Kehe Su, Materials. 18(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407807377

                Developing stable and effective catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) has been a long-standing pursuit. In this work, we propose a series of single-atom catalysts (SACs) by importing transition-metal atoms into the carbon and vanadium vacancies of tetragonal V2C2 and V3C3 slabs, where the transition-metal atoms refer to Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, and Cu. By means of first-principles computations, the possibility of applying these SACs in HER catalysis was investigated. All the SACs are conductive, which is favorable to charge transfer during HER. The Gibbs free energy change (&#916;GH*) during hydrogen adsorption was adopted to assess their catalytic ability. For the V2C2-based SACs with V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Ni, and Cu located at the carbon vacancy, excellent HER catalytic performance was achieved, with a |&#916;GH*| smaller than 0.2 eV. Among the V3C3-based SACs, apart from the SAC with Mn located at the carbon vacancy, all the SACs can act as outstanding HER catalysts. According to the &#916;GH*, these excellent V2C2- and V3C3-based SACs are comparable to the best-known Pt-based HER catalysts. However, it should be noted that the V2C2 and V3C3 slabs have not been successfully synthesized in the laboratory, leading to a pure investigation without practical application in this work.</description>
      <author>Bo Xue, Qingfeng Zeng, Shuyin Yu, Kehe Su</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18050931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industrial&#8208;current Ammonia Synthesis by Polarized Cuprous Cyanamide Coupled to Valorization of Glycerol at 4,000 mA cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;2&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418451</link>
      <description>Jiacheng Wang, Huong Thi Bui, Huashuai Hu, Shuyi Kong, Xunlu Wang, Hongbo Zhu, Junqing Ma, Jintao Xu, Yihong Liu, Lijia Liu, Wei Chen, Hui Bi, Minghui Yang, Fuqiang Huang, Tore Brinck, Jiacheng Wang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407808326

                Abstract The electrocatalytic nitrate reduction (NO 3 RR) holds significance in both NH 3 synthesis and nitrate contamination remediation. However, achieving industrial&#8208;scale current and high stability in membrane electrode assembly (MEA) electrolyzer remains challenging due to inherent high full&#8208;cell voltage for sluggish NO 3 RR and water oxidation. Here, Cu 2 NCN with positive surface electrostatic potential V S (r) is applied as highly efficient NO 3 RR electrocatalysts to achieve industrial&#8208;current and low&#8208;voltage stable NH 3 production in MEA electrolyzer with coupled anodic glycerol oxidation. This paired electro&#8208;refinery (PER) system reaches 4000 mA cm &#8722;2 at 2.52 V and remains stable at industrial&#8208;level 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for 100 h with the NH 3 production rate of 97000 &#181;g NH3 h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 and a Faradaic efficiency of 83%. Theoretical calculations elucidate that the asymmetric and electron&#8208;withdrawing [N&#8722;C&#8801;N] units enhance polarization and V S (r), promoting robust and asymmetric adsorption of NO 3 * on Cu 2 NCN to facilitate O&#8722;N bond dissociation. A comprehensive techno&#8208;economic analysis demonstrates the profitability and commercial viability of this coupled system. Our work opens a new avenue and marks a significant advancement in MEA systems for industrial NH 3 synthesis.</description>
      <author>Jiacheng Wang, Huong Thi Bui, Huashuai Hu, Shuyi Kong, Xunlu Wang, Hongbo Zhu, Junqing Ma, Jintao Xu, Yihong Liu, Lijia Liu, Wei Chen, Hui Bi, Minghui Yang, Fuqiang Huang, Tore Brinck, Jiacheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Modification of Layered Double Hydroxides&#8208;Based Compounds in Electrocatalytic Water Splitting: a Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412576</link>
      <description>Mingyang Li, Dandan Ma, Xiangbo Feng, Chuanqi Zhi, Yufei Jia, Jinfan Zhang, Yi Zhang, Yu Chen, Le Shi, Jian&#8208;Wen Shi, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407808534

                Abstract Layered double hydroxides (LDHs) exhibit great potential in electrocatalytic water splitting due to the unique 2D feature and an adjustable structure composed of different metal centers. In addition, LDHs have the advantage of being inherently inexpensive compared to other catalysts and have good stability in electrocatalytic water splitting. Up to now, numerous methods have been put forward to improve the activity of LDHs in electrocatalytic water splitting, a comprehensive introduction and comb to the fabrication methods and modification strategies is helpful for the followers to get a clear vein to carry out efficient manipulation to the development of high promising LDHs catalysts. In this review, the basic principles of water electrolysis, and the evaluation indexes are introduced first, and then the basic properties and commonly utilized methods in the fabrication of LDHs are introduced. After that, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and overall water splitting (OWS) performance of different LDHs&#8208;based catalysts and analyze the merits and shortcomings of LDHs in electrocatalytic water splitting is compared. Based on this, the advanced strategies for improving the performance of LDHs is introduced and give a brief prospect for the development of LDHs&#8208;based materials in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Mingyang Li, Dandan Ma, Xiangbo Feng, Chuanqi Zhi, Yufei Jia, Jinfan Zhang, Yi Zhang, Yu Chen, Le Shi, Jian&#8208;Wen Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Composition and Surface Engineering of Ruthenium&#8208;Cobalt Hydroxide Nanowires for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409151</link>
      <description>Young Jun Jang, Jungwoo Choi, Jun Hwan Moon, Hyuck Mo Lee, Young Keun Kim, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407808992

                Abstract Developing efficient electrocatalysts that improve the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) kinetics is crucial to addressing the kinetically sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This study introduces ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;cobalt(II) hydroxide (Co(OH)&#8322;) electrocatalysts for high&#8208;performance OER by combining compositional and thermodynamic surface engineering. Density functional theory (DFT) is employed to identify the ideal composition, with experimental validation conducted through electrodeposition, enabling facile control over a wide range of compositions for nanowire catalyst synthesis. Pourbaix diagram analysis helps establish precise synthesis conditions for developing surface nanostructures. The optimized Ru&#8208;Co(OH)&#8322; catalyst demonstrates exceptional performance, achieving overpotentials of 189 mV at 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 and 292 mV at 50 mA cm&#8315; 2 , significantly outperforming other compositions. The exceptional electrocatalytic performance can be attributed to two key factors: strengthened OH adsorption energy due to optimal composition, which lowers the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step in the OER, and increased specific surface area resulting from surface nanostructure formation.</description>
      <author>Young Jun Jang, Jungwoo Choi, Jun Hwan Moon, Hyuck Mo Lee, Young Keun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru Single Atoms and Sulfur Anions Dual&#8208;Doped NiFe Layered Double Hydroxides for High&#8208;Current&#8208;Density Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202500554</link>
      <description>Yiming Zhu, Jiaao Wang, G. Weiser, Malte Klingenhof, Toshinari Koketsu, Shangheng Liu, Yecan Pi, Graeme Henkelman, Xinyue Shi, Jiayi Li, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Min&#8208;Hsin Yeh, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Peter Strasser, Jiwei Ma, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407809022

                Abstract New anodic electrocatalysts with high performance and cost&#8208;effectiveness at large current densities help advance the emerging anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) technology. To this end, a ruthenium (Ru) single atoms and sulfur (S) anions dual&#8208;doped NiFe layered double hydroxides (Ru&#8208;S&#8208;NiFe LDH) catalyst is reported with remarkably low alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) overpotentials, high mass activities and prolonged stabilities at high current densities. Inspiringly, the AEMWE performance on Ru&#8208;S&#8208;NiFe LDH is also superior to the NiFe LDH. In&#8208;depth mechanism investigations reveal that Ru single atoms not only act as the highly active sites, but also facilitate the conductivity of NiFe LDH. Meanwhile, S anions accelerate the electrochemical reconstruction of NiFe LDH to OER&#8208;active NiFeOOH and alleviate the over&#8208;oxidation issue on Ru active sites. Benefiting from these, Ru&#8208;S&#8208;NiFe LDH shows significantly enhanced OER activity and stability. Theoretical calculations further validate the decreased OER free energy difference brought about by the Ru single atoms and S anions dual&#8208;doping. This study offers a proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept that the noble metal single atoms and anions dual&#8208;doping is a feasible strategy to construct the promising 3 d transition metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts toward the practical alkaline water electrolyzer.</description>
      <author>Yiming Zhu, Jiaao Wang, G. Weiser, Malte Klingenhof, Toshinari Koketsu, Shangheng Liu, Yecan Pi, Graeme Henkelman, Xinyue Shi, Jiayi Li, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Min&#8208;Hsin Yeh, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Peter Strasser, Jiwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202500554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Radical-Assisted Approach to High-Entropy Alloy Nanoparticle Electrocatalysts under Ambient Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14294</link>
      <description>Xu Li, Jianyun Cao, G. Chen, Jiyang Xie, Chengding Gu, Xiaohong Li, Frank C. Walsh, Yaming Wang, Wanbiao Hu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407809077

                High-entropy alloy (HEA) nanoparticles are rising as promising catalysts but face challenges in both facile synthesis and correlation of the structure with properties. Herein, utilizing the highly reductive carbon-centered isopropyl alcohol radicals generated by UV irradiation, we report a simple yet robust wet chemical method to synthesize HEA nanoparticles under ambient conditions. These isopropanol radicals verified by electron paramagnetic resonance spectroscopy impose very large overpotentials to reduce diverse metal ions into HEA nanoparticles with five to seven different elements. Specially, the PtPdIrRhAuAgCu HEA nanoparticles on a reduced electrochemical graphene oxide (rEGO) support (PtPdIrRhAuAgCu-rEGO) demonstrate superior activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) across the entire pH range, with very small overpotentials of 11, 30, and 31 mV to deliver a current density of -10 mA cm-2 in 1 M KOH, 1 M phosphate buffer saline, and 0.5 M H2SO4, respectively. The excellent HER performance of PtPdIrRhAuAgCu-rEGO surpasses that of commercial Pt/C and most contemporary HER catalysts in the literature. Density functional theory calculations using random structures mimicking the chemical disordering in PtPdIrRhAuAgCu HEA confirm its superior HER activity and imply a possible correlation between HER activity and d-band centers of the nearest atoms in a face-centered cubic hollow site.</description>
      <author>Xu Li, Jianyun Cao, G. Chen, Jiyang Xie, Chengding Gu, Xiaohong Li, Frank C. Walsh, Yaming Wang, Wanbiao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Common Nature of O and S Doping in Improving Electrochemical O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction Performance of FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06491</link>
      <description>Yuan Yuan, Jiapeng Ma, Baotao Kang, Jin Yong Lee, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407809956

                Heteroatom-doped Fe-N-C catalysts have emerged as promising alternatives to noble metals for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) due to their lower cost. However, the underlying mechanisms responsible for their enhanced performance, particularly electrochemical stability, remain a subject of debate. This study leverages density functional theory calculations coupled with a constant potential and implicit solvent model to investigate the electrochemical stabilities and activities of pyridinic (PD-) and pyrrolic FeN4C (PL-FeN4C) catalysts. Our findings reveal that the hydrogenation susceptibility of coordinating nitrogen atoms is a critical determinant of electrochemical stability within FeN4C catalysts. Moreover, we demonstrate that oxygen and sulfur doping exerts similar effects on enhancing the overall ORR performance of PD-FeN4C catalysts: (1) by reducing the p-band center of the coordinating nitrogen, thereby improving their resistance to hydrogenation, and (2) by increasing the valence electrons of iron, leading to stronger adsorption of reaction intermediates and consequently enhanced ORR activity. Finally, our predictions suggest that O/S-doped PL-FeN4C catalysts could achieve significantly improved electrochemical stability and superior ORR performance in both acidic and alkaline environments. These insights contribute to a deeper understanding of microenvironment engineering in single-atom catalysts (SACs) and offer valuable guidelines for the development of unprecedented M-N-C catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuan Yuan, Jiapeng Ma, Baotao Kang, Jin Yong Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the properties, types, and performance of atomic site catalysts in electrochemical hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00333k</link>
      <description>M. Nur Hossain, Lei Zhang, Roberto Neagu, Shuhui Sun, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407812467

                This review investigates atomic site catalysts (ASCs) for electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), discussing their properties, types, performance, significance, activity, selectivity, stability, challenges, and future research directions.</description>
      <author>M. Nur Hossain, Lei Zhang, Roberto Neagu, Shuhui Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00333k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Bubbly Flow on the Ohmic Overpotential of Electrochemical Reactions in a Microchannel Reactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00187</link>
      <description>Kezhen Gao, Xin-Ting Liu, Siyuan Zheng, Kai Wang, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407820478

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kezhen Gao, Xin-Ting Liu, Siyuan Zheng, Kai Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali Cation Inhibition of Imidazolium-Mediated Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Silver</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16635</link>
      <description>Francois Nkurunziza, Saudagar Dongare, Soumya Chatterjee, Bhavna A. Shah, Manu Gautam, Baleeswaraiah Muchharla, Bijandra Kumar, Michael J. Janik, Burcu Gurkan, Robert L. Sacci, Joshua M. Spurgeon, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407820539

                Imidazolium-based ionic liquids have led to enhanced CO2 electroreduction activity due to cation effects at the cathode surface, stabilizing the reaction intermediates and decreasing the activation energy. In aqueous media, alkali cations are also known to improve CO2 reduction activity on metals such as Ag, with the enhancement attributed to electrical double layer effects and trending with the size of the alkali cation. However, the effect of a mixed catholyte solution of alkali cations in the presence of an imidazolium-based ionic liquid has not been well-explored. Herein, 1-ethyl-3-methylimidazolium tetrafluoroborate, [EMIM][BF4], in water was investigated with alkali salts to unravel the interaction effects for CO2 electroreduction on Ag. Although both [EMIM]+ and alkali cations have individually improved CO2 to CO conversion on Ag in water, electrochemical results showed that alkali cations hindered imidazolium-mediated CO2 electroreduction in most conditions. Li+, in particular, was sharply inhibitory compared to other alkali cations and strongly redirected the selectivity to hydrogen evolution. The nature of the alkali cation inhibition was investigated with spectroscopic techniques, including in situ surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) and dynamic electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (DEIS). Along with computational insights from density functional theory (DFT), the electrochemical and spectroscopic data suggest that alkali cations inhibit [EMIM]-mediated CO2 reduction by competing for surface adsorption sites, preventing the potential-dependent structural reorientation of imidazolium, and promoting hydrogen evolution by bringing solvated water to the cathode surface.</description>
      <author>Francois Nkurunziza, Saudagar Dongare, Soumya Chatterjee, Bhavna A. Shah, Manu Gautam, Baleeswaraiah Muchharla, Bijandra Kumar, Michael J. Janik, Burcu Gurkan, Robert L. Sacci, Joshua M. Spurgeon</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16635</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating alkaline hydrogen evolution kinetics via interfacial modulation of hydrogen-bond networks by porous amine cages</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56962-z</link>
      <description>Shiqi Zhou, Wei Cao, Lu Shang, Yunxuan Zhao, Xuyang Xiong, Jian&#8208;Ke Sun, Tierui Zhang, Jiayin Yuan, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407820646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiqi Zhou, Wei Cao, Lu Shang, Yunxuan Zhao, Xuyang Xiong, Jian&#8208;Ke Sun, Tierui Zhang, Jiayin Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56962-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Janus Structures and Rich Electron Pool in 2D TMTe Nanostructures To Achieve OER/ORR Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04704</link>
      <description>Qian Tang, Mingyue Lv, Guangtao Yu, Wei Chen, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407823779

                Through first-principles structure search calculations, we have identified ten hitherto unknown two-dimensional (2D) Janus-wrinkled TMTe monolayers (TM = Ni, Pd, Pt, Co, Rh, Ir, Fe, Ru, Os, and Hf) by screening 3d, 4d, and 5d transition metal atoms. These monolayers exhibit high stability and metallic conductivity. Among the discovered materials, the 2D PdTe (&#951;OER/ORR = 0.46/0.22 V) and PtTe (&#951;OER/ORR = 0.46/0.32 V) monolayers can demonstrate superior bifunctional catalytic performance for oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions (OER/ORR), with lower overpotential than the state-of-the-art IrO2 for OER and Pt (111) for ORR, respectively. The TM- and Te-sides originating from the unique Janus configurations play a crucial role in the high OER and ORR catalytic activities, respectively. Furthermore, by stacking the monolayer structures, eight new (TMTe)2 bilayers with high stability and metallic conductivity can be achieved, which possess an internal metal layer, forming a rich electron pool. This effectively improves oxygen adsorption and activity on some bilayers, including (PdTe)2, (PtTe)2, (RhTe)2, and (IrTe)2, by transferring more electrons to the adsorbed O2 molecule, leading to considerably high ORR catalytic performance (&#951;ORR = 0.16&#8211;0.44 V). Moreover, detailed analyses of the catalytic mechanisms have been conducted. These intriguing findings can offer new insights for designing low-cost and high-performance electrocatalysts for OER and ORR reactions, with the potential to replace related noble metal catalysts used in water splitting, fuel cells, metal-air batteries, etc.</description>
      <author>Qian Tang, Mingyue Lv, Guangtao Yu, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and mechanical properties of refractory Nb30X25Ti25Al15V5 (&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1898" altimg="si90.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;X&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;= Zr, Mo) high-entropy alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2025.148053</link>
      <description>Jo&#227;o H. Mazo, Carolina Soares, Guilherme K. Inui, Marcelo Fal&#231;&#227;o de Oliveira, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Materials Science and Engineering A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407834918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jo&#227;o H. Mazo, Carolina Soares, Guilherme K. Inui, Marcelo Fal&#231;&#227;o de Oliveira, Juarez L. F. Da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2025.148053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution: A comprehensive comparative review in alkaline and acidic medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236571</link>
      <description>Amisha Soni, Sarvatej Kumar Maurya, Rishabh Mishra, Journal of Power Sources. 636(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407839630

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amisha Soni, Sarvatej Kumar Maurya, Rishabh Mishra</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymeric ionic liquid promotes acidic electrocatalytic CO2 conversion to multicarbon products with ampere level current on Cu</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57095-z</link>
      <description>Zhonghao Tan, Jianling Zhang, Yisen Yang, Jiajun Zhong, Yingzhe Zhao, Yunan Teng, Buxing Han, Zhongjun Chen, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407841141

                The acidic electroreduction of CO2 into multicarbon (C2+) products is much attractive for the improved carbon utilization than alkaline or neutral electroreduction. How to improve the efficiency of C2+ products generation by acidic electroreduction of CO2, is important, especially at high current density and in electrolyte with low K+ concentration. Herein, we propose a strategy of capping Cu surface with a polymeric ionic liquid (PIL) adlayer for boosting the acidic electrocatalytic CO2 conversion to C2+ products at high current densities (ampere-level) and low K+ concentration. In the electrolyte with a relatively low K+ concentration (1.0 M), the Faradaic efficiency (FE) for C2+ products reaches 82.2% under a current density 1.0 A&#183;cm&#8722;2 in acidic environment (pH=1.8). Particularly, when the current density is as high as 1.5 A&#183;cm&#8722;2, the C2+ FE still keeps 75.8%. Experimental and theoretical studies reveal that the presence of PIL adlayer on Cu catalyst can well inhibit H+ diffusion to catalyst surface, enrich more K+ and facilitate C-C coupling reaction. Acidic electrocatalytic CO2 reduction is a promising way for CO2 utilization, of which the selectivity and activity need improvement. Here, the authors report polymeric ionic liquid can boost the acidic electrocatalytic CO2 reduction into multicarbon products on Cu at ampere level current density.</description>
      <author>Zhonghao Tan, Jianling Zhang, Yisen Yang, Jiajun Zhong, Yingzhe Zhao, Yunan Teng, Buxing Han, Zhongjun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57095-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of precatalysts and controlled evolution of catalyst-electrolyte interface for efficient hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57056-6</link>
      <description>Anquan Zhu, Lulu Qiao, Kai Liu, Guoqiang Gan, Chuhao Luan, Dewu Lin, Yin Zhou, Shuyu Bu, Tian Zhang, Kunlun Liu, Tianyi Song, Heng Liu, Hao Li, Hong Guo, Wenjun Zhang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407847690

                The concept of precatalyst is widely accepted in electrochemical water splitting, but the role of precatalyst activation and the resulted changes of electrolyte composition is often overlooked. Here, we elucidate the impact of potential-dependent changes for both precatalyst and electrolyte using Co2Mo3O8 as a model system. Potential-dependent reconstruction of Co2Mo3O8 precatalyst results in an electrochemically stable Co(OH)2@Co2Mo3O8 catalyst and additional Mo dissolved as MoO42&#8722; into electrolyte. The Co(OH)2/Co2Mo3O8 interface accelerates the Volmer reaction and negative potentials induced Mo2O72&#8722; (from MoO42&#8722;) further enhances proton adsorption and H2 desorption. Leveraging these insights, the well-designed MoO42&#8722;/Mo2O72&#8722; modified Co(OH)2@Co2Mo3O8 catalyst achieves a Faradaic efficiency of 99.9% and a yield of 1.85 mol h&#8722;1 at &#8722;0.4 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) for hydrogen generation. Moreover, it maintains stable over one month at approximately 100 mA cm&#8722;2, highlighting its industrial suitability. This work underscores the significance of understanding on precatalyst reconstruction and electrolyte evolution in catalyst design. The significance of precatalyst activation and its impact on electrolyte properties in water electrocatalysis is crucial but often overlooked. The authors report an efficient transition metal catalyst for hydrogen production by manipulating both precatalyst reconstruction and electrolyte composition.</description>
      <author>Anquan Zhu, Lulu Qiao, Kai Liu, Guoqiang Gan, Chuhao Luan, Dewu Lin, Yin Zhou, Shuyu Bu, Tian Zhang, Kunlun Liu, Tianyi Song, Heng Liu, Hao Li, Hong Guo, Wenjun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57056-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Atoms Supported by a NbSSe Monolayer for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08357</link>
      <description>Junkai Xu, Xiaoxue Yu, Yuebo Gao, Yunhao Wang, Jianjun Fang, Jing Li, Xian-Fang Yue, A. J. C. Varandas, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407850868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junkai Xu, Xiaoxue Yu, Yuebo Gao, Yunhao Wang, Jianjun Fang, Jing Li, Xian-Fang Yue, A. J. C. Varandas</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in Structure and IR Spectra of Mixed H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O/CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Ices of Astrochemical Relevance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsearthspacechem.4c00353</link>
      <description>Niels M. Mikkelsen, Thanja Lamberts, Mie Andersen, ACS Earth and Space Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407856726

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Niels M. Mikkelsen, Thanja Lamberts, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsearthspacechem.4c00353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MORE-Q, a dataset for molecular olfactorial receptor engineering by quantum mechanics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-025-04616-6</link>
      <description>Li Chen, Leonardo Medrano Sandonas, Philipp Traber, Arezoo Dianat, Nina Tverdokhleb, Mattan Hurevich, Shlomo Yitzchaik, Rafael Guti&#233;rrez, Alexander Croy, Gianaurelio Cuniberti, Scientific Data. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407857451

                Abstract We introduce the MORE-Q dataset, a quantum-mechanical (QM) dataset encompassing the structural and electronic data of non-covalent molecular sensors formed by combining 18 mucin-derived olfactorial receptors with 102 body odor volatilome (BOV) molecules. To have a better understanding of their intra- and inter-molecular interactions, we have performed accurate QM calculations in different stages of the sensor design and, accordingly, MORE-Q splits into three subsets: i) MORE-Q-G1: QM data of 18 receptors and 102 BOV molecules, ii) MORE-Q-G2: QM data of 23,838 BOV-receptor configurations, and iii) MORE-Q-G3: QM data of 1,836 BOV-receptor-graphene systems. Each subset involves geometries optimized using GFN2-xTB with D4 dispersion correction and up to 39 physicochemical properties, including global and local properties as well as binding features, all computed at the tightly converged PBE+D3 level of theory. By addressing BOV-receptor-graphene systems from a QM perspective, MORE-Q can serve as a benchmark dataset for state-of-the-art machine learning methods developed to predict binding features. This, in turn, can provide valuable insights for developing the next-generation mucin-derived olfactory receptor sensing devices.</description>
      <author>Li Chen, Leonardo Medrano Sandonas, Philipp Traber, Arezoo Dianat, Nina Tverdokhleb, Mattan Hurevich, Shlomo Yitzchaik, Rafael Guti&#233;rrez, Alexander Croy, Gianaurelio Cuniberti</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-025-04616-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully automated high-throughput computer-based catalytic material screening framework and its application on the new-generation Tianhe supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113775</link>
      <description>Can Leng, Xuguang Chen, Jie Liu, Chunye Gong, Bo Yang, Zhuo Tang, Wangdong Yang, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang, Yi&#8208;Ge Zhou, Maosong Mo, Kenli Li, Keqin Li, Computational Materials Science. 252(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407864847

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Can Leng, Xuguang Chen, Jie Liu, Chunye Gong, Bo Yang, Zhuo Tang, Wangdong Yang, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang, Yi&#8208;Ge Zhou, Maosong Mo, Kenli Li, Keqin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Water Dissociation for Ampere-Level CO2-to-Ethanol Conversion over La(OH)3@Cu Hollow-fiber Penetration Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125202</link>
      <description>Jiayu Xia, Shoujie Li, Xiaohu Liu, Xiao Dong, Jianing Mao, Aohui Chen, Huanyi Zhu, Xiaotong Wang, Ziran Xu, Yiheng Wei, Guihua Li, Yanfang Song, Wei Wei, Wei Chen, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407867111

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayu Xia, Shoujie Li, Xiaohu Liu, Xiao Dong, Jianing Mao, Aohui Chen, Huanyi Zhu, Xiaotong Wang, Ziran Xu, Yiheng Wei, Guihua Li, Yanfang Song, Wei Wei, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wastewater as a resource for carbon capture: A comprehensive overview and perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124608</link>
      <description>Rufan Zhou, Yueping Ren, Chunqing Jiang, Qingye Lu, Journal of Environmental Management. 377(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407869267

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rufan Zhou, Yueping Ren, Chunqing Jiang, Qingye Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Z-scheme SnS2/InS heterostructure for efficient visible-light photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.334</link>
      <description>Yifan Yang, Nan Zhou, Dong-Lan Zhang, Tong Chen, Cheng Gong, Lingling Wang, Kejun Dong, Liang Xu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 111(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407874301

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Yang, Nan Zhou, Dong-Lan Zhang, Tong Chen, Cheng Gong, Lingling Wang, Kejun Dong, Liang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice dynamics modeling of thermal transport in solids using machine-learned atomic cluster expansion potentials: A tutorial</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0251119</link>
      <description>Liangshuai Guo, Yuanbin Liu, Lei Yang, Bing Cao, Journal of Applied Physics. 137(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407882290

                Lattice dynamics (LD) plays a crucial role in investigating thermal transport in terms of not only underlying physics but also novel properties and phenomena. Recently, machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) have emerged as powerful tools in computational physics and chemistry, showing great potential in providing reliable predictions of thermal transport properties with high efficiency. This tutorial provides a comprehensive guideline for MLIPs&#8217; development and how they are used for the computational modeling of thermal transport. Using atomic cluster expansion (ACE) as the paradigmatic potential, we introduce the essential fundamentals of MLIPs, including data construction, model training, and hyperparameter optimization. With the developed ACE potentials, we further showcase their applications in the LD modeling of thermal transport for crystalline silicon and amorphous carbon. The corresponding code implementations for MLIP applications in calculating thermal conductivity are also provided for beginners to follow.</description>
      <author>Liangshuai Guo, Yuanbin Liu, Lei Yang, Bing Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0251119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction of MXene-based Single-atom Catalysts M-Ti&amp;amp;lt;sub&amp;amp;gt;2&amp;amp;lt;/sub&amp;amp;gt;CO&amp;amp;lt;sub&amp;amp;gt;2&amp;amp;lt;/sub&amp;amp;gt; (M=Cu, Fe, Co, Ni) Applied in the Electroreduction of CO&amp;amp;lt;sub&amp;amp;gt;2&amp;amp;lt;/sub&amp;amp;gt; for Methanol Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/2097-213x.2025.jfct.0005</link>
      <description>Xinyao Zou, Chongqing Yang, Simin Liu, Ang Li, Lei Zhu, Zhen Huang, Journal of Fuel Chemistry and Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407884224

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyao Zou, Chongqing Yang, Simin Liu, Ang Li, Lei Zhu, Zhen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/2097-213x.2025.jfct.0005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the potential of chemical-assisted water electrolysis for green hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4im00163j</link>
      <description>Jiwoo Lee, Sol A Lee, Tae Hyung Lee, Ho Won Jang, Industrial Chemistry and Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407885004

                Chemical-assisted water electrolysis is gaining attraction as an alternative to conventional water electrolysis to produce hydrogen, but high overpotential is a major challenge. This review covers advanced strategies to reduce the operation voltage.</description>
      <author>Jiwoo Lee, Sol A Lee, Tae Hyung Lee, Ho Won Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4im00163j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxylation Strategy Enables Ru&#8211;Mn Oxide for Stable Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis under 1 A cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;2&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c15900</link>
      <description>Susu Zhao, Qian Dang, Aiqing Cao, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Hai Liu, Jian Peng, Yameng Fan, Hui Li, Fengmei Wang, Yun Kuang, Xiaoming Sun, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407892266

                Ruthenium (Ru)-based catalysts have demonstrated promising utilization potentiality to replace the much expensive iridium (Ir)-based ones for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) due to their high electrochemical activity and low cost. However, the susceptibility of RuO2-based materials to easily be oxidized to high-valent and soluble Ru species during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acid media hinders the practical application, especially under current density above 500 mA cm&#8211;2. Here, a manganese-doped RuO2 catalyst with the hydroxylated metal sites (i.e., H&#8211;Mn0.1Ru0.9O2) is synthesized for acidic OER assisted by hydrogen peroxide, where the hydroxylation results in the valence state of the Ru sites below +4. The H&#8211;Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 catalyst demonstrates an overpotential of 169 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and promising stability for an OER over 1000 h in an acidic electrolyte. A PEMWE device fabricated with the H&#8211;Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 catalyst as the anode shows a current density of 1 A cm&#8211;2 at &#8764;1.65 V, along with a low degradation over continuous tens of hours. Differential electrochemical mass spectrometry (DEMS) results and theoretical calculations confirm that H&#8211;Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 performs the OER through the adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) pathway, where the synergistic effect of hydroxylation and Mn doping in RuO2 can effectively enhance the stability of Ru sites and lattice oxygen atoms.</description>
      <author>Susu Zhao, Qian Dang, Aiqing Cao, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Hai Liu, Jian Peng, Yameng Fan, Hui Li, Fengmei Wang, Yun Kuang, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c15900</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radio frequency plasma-engraved vacancy engineering towards robust hydrogen-evolving catalysts with large-current stable catalytic activity for over 1000 h</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3247-8</link>
      <description>Yong Zhang, Haiman Huang, Weiqiang Xie, Qian Zhou, Xiang Hu, Guanghua Wang, Wangbing Yu, Haiqing Zhou, Yu Fang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407895554

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Zhang, Haiman Huang, Weiqiang Xie, Qian Zhou, Xiang Hu, Guanghua Wang, Wangbing Yu, Haiqing Zhou, Yu Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3247-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional ferroelectric metal CuCrX2 (X=S, Se) for efficient electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commt.2025.100029</link>
      <description>Ying Wang, Chengliang Lu, Menghao Wu, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407901529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Wang, Chengliang Lu, Menghao Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commt.2025.100029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the development of electrocatalysts through an automated comprehensive literature review using NLP</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacomc.2025.100067</link>
      <description>Na Qin, Lei Liu, Wei Lai, Haibiao Chen, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407901776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Qin, Lei Liu, Wei Lai, Haibiao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacomc.2025.100067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single&#8208;Atom Enables Reverse Hydrogen Spillover for High&#8208;Performance Protonic Ceramic Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202501387</link>
      <description>Sunce Zhao, Wenjia Ma, Beibei He, Yihan Ling, Yonglong Huang, Feng Hu, Zhu Shu, Ling Zhao, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407908043

                Protonic ceramic fuel cells (PCFCs) offer a promising avenue for sustainable energy conversion, however, their commercial potential is hindered by sluggish proton-involved oxygen reduction reaction (P-ORR) kinetics and inadequate durability of cathode materials. Here, a novel single-atom Ru anchor on BaCe0.125Fe0.875O3-&#948; (BCF) perovskite, synthesized by a facile and scalable solid-state approach, as a potential cathode for PCFCs is reported. Theoretical and experimental analyses demonstrate that the single-atom Ru on BCF, characterized by a unique 4-coordinate Ru-O-Fe configuration, not only induces reverse hydrogen spillover but also acts as an active site for P-ORR. The application of the optimized 2Ru-BCF (2 wt.% Ru) cathode in a single cell delivers an exceptional peak power density of 1.78 W cm-2 at 700 &#176;C, along with excellent operational stability over 200 h. These findings provide new insights into single-atom engineering, advancing the commercial viability of PCFCs.</description>
      <author>Sunce Zhao, Wenjia Ma, Beibei He, Yihan Ling, Yonglong Huang, Feng Hu, Zhu Shu, Ling Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202501387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting selective CO2 reduction via strong spin-spin coupling on dual-atom spin-catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.173</link>
      <description>Yueyue Shao, Jia Zhou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407909575

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yueyue Shao, Jia Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.02.173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional TiNBr as photocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.025802</link>
      <description>Yatong Wang, Geert Brocks, Ceren Tayran, S&#252;leyman Er, Physical Review Materials. 9(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407910776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yatong Wang, Geert Brocks, Ceren Tayran, S&#252;leyman Er</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.025802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of hydration energies of adsorbates at Pt(111) and liquid water interfaces using machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0248572</link>
      <description>Jiexin Shi, Xiaohong Zhang, Venkata Rohit Punyapu, Rachel B. Getman, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407917932

                Aqueous phase heterogeneous catalysis is important to various industrial processes, including biomass conversion, Fischer&#8211;Tropsch synthesis, and electrocatalysis. Accurate calculation of solvation thermodynamic properties is essential for modeling the performance of catalysts for these processes. Explicit solvation methods employing multiscale modeling, e.g., involving density functional theory and molecular dynamics have emerged for this purpose. Although accurate, these methods are computationally intensive. This study introduces machine learning (ML) models to predict solvation thermodynamics for adsorbates on a Pt(111) surface, aiming to enhance computational efficiency without compromising accuracy. In particular, ML models are developed using a combination of molecular descriptors and fingerprints and trained on previously published water&#8211;adsorbate interaction energies, energies of solvation, and free energies of solvation of adsorbates bound to Pt(111). These models achieve root mean square error values of 0.09 eV for interaction energies, 0.04 eV for energies of solvation, and 0.06 eV for free energies of solvation, demonstrating accuracy within the standard error of multiscale modeling. Feature importance analysis reveals that hydrogen bonding, van der Waals interactions, and solvent density, together with the properties of the adsorbate, are critical factors influencing solvation thermodynamics. These findings suggest that ML models can provide rapid and reliable predictions of solvation properties. This approach not only reduces computational costs but also offers insights into the solvation characteristics of adsorbates at Pt(111)&#8211;water interfaces.</description>
      <author>Jiexin Shi, Xiaohong Zhang, Venkata Rohit Punyapu, Rachel B. Getman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0248572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A practical guide to machine learning interatomic potentials &#8211; Status and future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cossms.2025.101214</link>
      <description>Ryan Jacobs, D. A. Morgan, Siamak Attarian, Jun Meng, Chen Shen, Zhenghao Wu, Clare Yijia Xie, Julia H. Yang, Nongnuch Artrith, Ben Blaiszik, Gerbrand Ceder, Kamal Choudhary, G&#225;bor Cs&#225;nyi, Ekin D. Cubuk, Bowen Deng, Ralf Drautz, Xiang Fu, Jonathan Godwin, Honavar Vasant, Olexandr Isayev, Anders Johansson, Stefano Martiniani, Shyue Ping Ong, Igor Poltavsky, K. J. Schmidt, So Takamoto, Aidan P. Thompson, Julia Westermayr, Brandon M. Wood, Boris Kozinsky, Current Opinion in Solid State and Materials Science. 35(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407925765

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ryan Jacobs, D. A. Morgan, Siamak Attarian, Jun Meng, Chen Shen, Zhenghao Wu, Clare Yijia Xie, Julia H. Yang, Nongnuch Artrith, Ben Blaiszik, Gerbrand Ceder, Kamal Choudhary, G&#225;bor Cs&#225;nyi, Ekin D. Cubuk, Bowen Deng, Ralf Drautz, Xiang Fu, Jonathan Godwin, Honavar Vasant, Olexandr Isayev, Anders Johansson, Stefano Martiniani, Shyue Ping Ong, Igor Poltavsky, K. J. Schmidt, So Takamoto, Aidan P. Thompson, Julia Westermayr, Brandon M. Wood, Boris Kozinsky</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cossms.2025.101214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum-promoted nickel catalysts for CO2 methanation: a critical review and informetric perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43938-025-00076-x</link>
      <description>Stephen Okiemute Akpasi, Yusuf Makarfi Isa, Thembisile Patience Mahlangu, Sammy Lewis Kiambi, Peterson Thokozani Ngema, Discover Chemical Engineering. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407934426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stephen Okiemute Akpasi, Yusuf Makarfi Isa, Thembisile Patience Mahlangu, Sammy Lewis Kiambi, Peterson Thokozani Ngema</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43938-025-00076-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing the Preparation Strategy of High-Performance Integrated Electrodes for eCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR via Sublimation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c21322</link>
      <description>Hao Zeng, Xuan Zou, Han Liu, Muyao Gao, Zhaoyu Chen, Yang Liu, Ming Yang, Bing Li, Ming Liu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407941575

                The uniform dispersion and loading of phthalocyanine molecular catalysts on conductive carbon substrates are crucial for exposing their active sites. The significant amount of solvent needed to achieve appropriate dispersion of phthalocyanine leads to the risk of reaggregation during solvent evaporation. Hence, a solventless strategy is adopted by many to bypass the use of a solvent. In this study, we showcase the deposition of transition metal phthalocyanine (TMPc) molecules onto a self-supporting conductive carbon cloth electrode using an environmentally friendly sublimation technique for efficient electrocatalytic CO2 reduction. We meticulously investigated the preparation conditions, including the heating temperature and TMPc type, to assess their impact on the CO2 reduction activity. The as-prepared CC-CoPc-450 electrode demonstrated an outstanding comprehensive performance, showcasing a remarkable maximum CO Faradaic efficiency (FECO) of 97.1% at -0.86 V with a current density of 8.3 mA cm-2. The electrode exhibited excellent stability during the 16 h long-term eCO2RR process. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrated the role of d-orbitals in TM-N4 and the synergy with &#960;-conjugation electrons in facilitating the efficient electron transfer process in eCO2RR. This study offers a fresh perspective on the eco-friendly dispersion of TMPcs on conductive substrates and provides insights into the design of &#960;-species macrocyclic electrocatalyst electrodes.</description>
      <author>Hao Zeng, Xuan Zou, Han Liu, Muyao Gao, Zhaoyu Chen, Yang Liu, Ming Yang, Bing Li, Ming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c21322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surfactant-free colloidal gold nanoparticles: room temperature synthesis, size control and opportunities for catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2025.100600</link>
      <description>Dionysis Panagopoulos, Armin Asghari Alamdari, Jonathan Quinson, Materials Today Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407942392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dionysis Panagopoulos, Armin Asghari Alamdari, Jonathan Quinson</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2025.100600</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic conversion of CO2 to CO via a non-stoichiometric zinc-fluorine amorphous interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161002</link>
      <description>Hanyu Wu, Chia&#8208;Chen Lin, Chu-Hsin Yang, Yu-Wei Huang, Chen&#8208;Hao Yeh, Yu&#8208;Jen Chou, Ta&#8208;Chung Liu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407943433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hanyu Wu, Chia&#8208;Chen Lin, Chu-Hsin Yang, Yu-Wei Huang, Chen&#8208;Hao Yeh, Yu&#8208;Jen Chou, Ta&#8208;Chung Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the OER Activity of Titania Via Doping and Adlayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/open.202400085</link>
      <description>Anna Gomer, Thomas Bredow, ChemistryOpen. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407945453

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) was investigated theoretically on modified rutile(110) surfaces at density functional theory level in search for inexpensive but active catalyst materials required for water electrolysis. Ti substitution by Nb in rutile and furthermore adding adlayers of transition metal (TM) oxides, with TM =${ = }$ Ir, Ru and Rh, substantially improves titania OER activity. The catalytic activity was assessed by the overpotential of the OER which was calculated from adsorption energies of the intermediates M-O, M-OH and M-OOH. Different reaction mechanisms were suggested depending on the presence or absence of M-OOH. Materials with iridium dioxide in the top layer have similar overpotentials, both as adlayer on (doped) TiO2${{\rm{TiO}}_{\rm{2}} }$ and as pure IrO2${{\rm{IrO}}_{\rm{2}} }$ . Thus, the percentage of this expensive and scarce element can be drastically reduced without deteriorating the activity. A monolayer of RuO2${{\rm{RuO}}_{\rm{2}} }$ on rutile TiO2${{\rm{TiO}}_{\rm{2}} }$ has an even lower overpotential compared to pure RuO2${{\rm{RuO}}_{\rm{2}} }$ . In addition, RhO2${{\rm{RhO}}_{\rm{2}} }$ and RhO2${{\rm{RhO}}_{\rm{2}} }$ : Nb1/3Ti2/3O2${{\rm{Nb}}_{{\rm{1/3}}} {\rm{Ti}}_{{\rm{2/3}}} {\rm{O}}_{\rm{2}} }$ were identified as catalysts with higher OER activity than IrO2${{\rm{IrO}}_{\rm{2}} }$ .</description>
      <author>Anna Gomer, Thomas Bredow</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/open.202400085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart monitoring and control systems for hydrogen fuel cells using AI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.232</link>
      <description>Somtochukwu Godfrey Nnabuife, Chinonyelum Udemu, Abdulhammed K. Hamzat, Caleb Kwasi Darko, Ato Kwamena Quainoo, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 110(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4407803379

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Somtochukwu Godfrey Nnabuife, Chinonyelum Udemu, Abdulhammed K. Hamzat, Caleb Kwasi Darko, Ato Kwamena Quainoo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of an oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalyst of TiO2 supported IrO2 (IrO2@TiO2) for enhancing performance and durability of polymer electrolyte membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.271</link>
      <description>Tuan Linh Doan, Ta Nam Nguyen, Hyunmin Hong, Taekeun Kim, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 110(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4407847816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tuan Linh Doan, Ta Nam Nguyen, Hyunmin Hong, Taekeun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphology, Deformations, and Photocatalytic Activity of Thermally Treated Brookite Titanium Dioxide Thin Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08479</link>
      <description>Pritha Biswas, Min&#8208;Ju Choi, Krishna Prasad Koirala, Hyo Ju Park, Mark Bowden, Lyndi E. Strange, Zhan Zhang, Hua Zhou, Janet Tate, Yingge Du, Dongsheng Li, Peter V. Sushko, Tiffany C. Kaspar, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407810010

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pritha Biswas, Min&#8208;Ju Choi, Krishna Prasad Koirala, Hyo Ju Park, Mark Bowden, Lyndi E. Strange, Zhan Zhang, Hua Zhou, Janet Tate, Yingge Du, Dongsheng Li, Peter V. Sushko, Tiffany C. Kaspar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic modelling assisted rate equation development for ammonia decomposition over alumina supported nickel catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125205</link>
      <description>Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Shreepad Gunge, A. S. Russel, Goutam Deo, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407870755

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Shreepad Gunge, A. S. Russel, Goutam Deo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water&#8211;Gas Shift Reaction over Cu&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O/Cu(111) (&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; &amp;lt; 2) from a DFT-MKM-kMC Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06825</link>
      <description>Yu-Bi Huang, Gui&#8208;Chang Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407893963

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Bi Huang, Gui&#8208;Chang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Force Field for Optimization of Isolated and Supported Transition Metal Particles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01606</link>
      <description>Alexandre Boucher, Cameron Beevers, Bertrand Gauthier, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407920414

                Computational modeling is an integral part of catalysis research. With it, new methodologies are being developed and implemented to improve the accuracy of simulations while reducing the computational cost. In particular, specific machine-learning techniques have been applied to build interatomic potential from ab initio results. Here, we report an energy-free machine-learning calculator that combines three individually trained neural networks to predict the energy and atomic forces of metallic particles. The investigated structures were a monometallic Pd nanoparticle, a bimetallic AuPd nanoalloy, and supported Pd metal crystallites on silica. Atomic energies were predicted via a graph neural network, leading to a mean absolute error (MAE) within 0.004 eV from density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The task of predicting atomic forces was split over two feed-forward networks, one predicting the force norm and another its direction. The force prediction resulted in a MAE within 0.080 eV/&#197; against DFT results. The interpretability of the graph neural network predictions was demonstrated by underlying the physics of the monometallic particle in the form of cohesion energy.</description>
      <author>Alexandre Boucher, Cameron Beevers, Bertrand Gauthier, Alberto Rold&#225;n</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01606</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
