<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 01:39:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>An excellent-performance electrocatalyst in oxygen reduction reaction: Pt anchored on a bulk-engineered black titania synthesized by nitrogen gliding arc plasma</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168027</link>
      <description>Xuanhe Li, Xiaosong Li, Jinglin Liu, Xiaobing Zhu, Ai&#8208;Min Zhu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414044710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuanhe Li, Xiaosong Li, Jinglin Liu, Xiaobing Zhu, Ai&#8208;Min Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface engineering and electronegativity effects on the catalytic performance of Hf&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e874" altimg="si31.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;CO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e882" altimg="si31.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; MXene: An ab initio study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.113152</link>
      <description>Souhila Khobzaoui, Tarik Ouahrani, &#193;ngel Morales&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Daniel Errandonea, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414051059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Souhila Khobzaoui, Tarik Ouahrani, &#193;ngel Morales&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Daniel Errandonea</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.113152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Classical and Machine Learning Force Fields for Modeling Deformation of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks Relevant for Direct Air Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04020</link>
      <description>Logan M. Brabson, Andrew J. Medford, David S. Sholl, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414052857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Logan M. Brabson, Andrew J. Medford, David S. Sholl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface-Engineered Ag/Co2P Heterostructured Nanocatalysts Enable Durable Solar-Driven PEM and AEM Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5456995</link>
      <description>Xinyao Guo, Yiming Xia, Yousof Haghshenas, Priyank V. Kumar, Chaudhry Muhammad Furqan, Hanyu Xu, Rose Amal, Rahman Daiyan, Xiaojing Hao, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414056124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyao Guo, Yiming Xia, Yousof Haghshenas, Priyank V. Kumar, Chaudhry Muhammad Furqan, Hanyu Xu, Rose Amal, Rahman Daiyan, Xiaojing Hao, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5456995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-Scheme TpPa/C6N7 heterobilayer: conjugated microporous polymers/covalent organic frameworks-based photocatalyst for efficient overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138981</link>
      <description>Qing Zhao, Junjie Cao, Zhihua Zhang, Xikui Ma, Liqun Song, Juan Wang, Yingcai Fan, Mingwen Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414057614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Zhao, Junjie Cao, Zhihua Zhang, Xikui Ma, Liqun Song, Juan Wang, Yingcai Fan, Mingwen Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface-Engineered Ag/Co2P Heterostructured Nanocatalysts Enable Durable Solar-Driven PEM and AEM Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5456999</link>
      <description>Xinyao Guo, Yiming Xia, Yousof Haghshenas, Priyank V. Kumar, Chaudhry Muhammad Furqan, Hanyu Xu, Rose Amal, Rahman Daiyan, Xiaojing Hao, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414064034

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyao Guo, Yiming Xia, Yousof Haghshenas, Priyank V. Kumar, Chaudhry Muhammad Furqan, Hanyu Xu, Rose Amal, Rahman Daiyan, Xiaojing Hao, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5456999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment effects in electrochemical CO2 reduction from first-principles multiscale modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01399-2</link>
      <description>Francesca Lorenzutti, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Evan F. Johnson, Santiago Morandi, Pavle Nika&#269;evi&#263;, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Sophia Haussener, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414065128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Francesca Lorenzutti, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Evan F. Johnson, Santiago Morandi, Pavle Nika&#269;evi&#263;, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Sophia Haussener</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01399-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxophilic Sites Mediated Dynamic Oxygen Replenishment to Stabilize Lattice Oxygen Catalysis in Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c09939</link>
      <description>Shaoxiong Li, Sheng Zhao, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Liming Deng, Luqi Wang, Fengyuan Shi, Ao Dong, Ying Zhang, Tsung&#8208;Yi Chen, Feng Hu, Linlin Li, Seeram Ramakrishna, Yuping Wu, Shiling Peng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414065423

                Developing efficient and durable catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media is essential for advancing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). However, catalyst instability caused by lattice oxygen (OL) depletion and metal dissolution remains a critical barrier. Here, we propose an oxophilic-site-mediated dynamic oxygen replenishment mechanism (DORM), in which OL actively participates in O-O bond formation and is continuously refilled by water-derived species. Oxophilic dopants modulate the local electronic structure, lower the energy barrier for oxygen vacancy healing, and reorganize the interfacial hydrogen-bond network to enhance water mobility, orientation, and proton accessibility, collectively promoting water dissociation and stabilizing OL catalysis. The optimized catalyst achieves a low overpotential of 289 mV and exceptional durability, operating continuously for 650 h at 10 mA cm-2 in acidic electrolyte and maintaining stable performance for 280 h at 1 A cm-2 in a PEMWE. This work establishes a mechanistic framework for dynamic OL redox and provides a rational strategy for designing robust, noble-metal-free acidic OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Shaoxiong Li, Sheng Zhao, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Liming Deng, Luqi Wang, Fengyuan Shi, Ao Dong, Ying Zhang, Tsung&#8208;Yi Chen, Feng Hu, Linlin Li, Seeram Ramakrishna, Yuping Wu, Shiling Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c09939</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Mars&#8211;van Krevelen Mechanism for CO Capture on the Surface of Carbides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30173637</link>
      <description>Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui, Molecules. 30(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414066804

                Electrochemical reduction processes enable the CO to be converted into a useful chemical fuel. Our study employs density functional theory calculations to analyze the (110) facets of the transition metal carbide surfaces for CO capture, incorporating the Mars-van Krevelen (MvK) mechanism. All the possible adsorption sites on the surface, including carbon, metal, and bridge sites, were fully investigated. The findings indicate that the carbon site is more active relative to the other adsorption sites examined. The CO hydrogenation paths have been comprehensively investigated on all the surfaces, and the free energy diagrams have been constructed towards the product. The results conclude that the TiC is the most promising candidate for the formation of methane, exhibiting an onset potential of -0.44 V. The predicted onset potential for CrC, MoC, NbC, VC, WC, ZrC, and HfC are -0.86, -0.61, -0.61, -0.93, -0.87, -0.61, and -0.81 V, respectively. Our calculated results demonstrate that MvK is selectively relevant to methane synthesis. Additionally, we investigated the stability of these surfaces against decomposition and conversion to pure metals concerning thermodynamics and kinetics. It was found that these carbides could remain stable under ambient conditions. The exergonic adsorption of hydrogen on carbon sites, requiring smaller potential values for product formation, and stability against decomposition indicate that these surfaces are highly suitable for CO reduction reactions using the MvK mechanism.</description>
      <author>Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30173637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Science: The Foundation of Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c10064</link>
      <description>Alasdair Fairhurst, Chaewon Lim, Minki Jun, Benjamin J. Ransom, Filip Mackowicz, Dominik Haering, Vojislav R. Stamenkovi&#263;, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414069797

                The research community in the electrochemical field is increasingly moving toward device-level investigations in a push to demonstrate practical applicability and widen the adoption of advanced energy conversion and storage technologies. Electrochemical devices, however, are highly complex systems and require a multidisciplinary approach to reveal the fundamental processes and key physical parameters of the materials employed that determine their functional properties. These processes occur in the near-surface region of the electrodes that catalyze electrochemical reactions. Here, we present our view on the critical importance and enduring relevance of a surface science approach to advance knowledge in electrocatalysis, with foundations built on well-defined planar surfaces that could be linked to corresponding nanostructured interfaces.</description>
      <author>Alasdair Fairhurst, Chaewon Lim, Minki Jun, Benjamin J. Ransom, Filip Mackowicz, Dominik Haering, Vojislav R. Stamenkovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c10064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Trapping Capability and Diffusion Suppression Effect of Silicon Carbide Surface on Tritium: A First Principle Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c10266</link>
      <description>Ziling Zhou, Zhengzhe Qu, Mengjie Wu, Yu Wang, Feng Xie, Jiejuan Tong, Yanwei Wen, Bin Shan, Feng Xie, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414070079

                Silicon carbide (SiC) has attracted considerable interest for use in electronics, aerospace, and nuclear energy applications owing to its excellent electrical and mechanical properties. In the nuclear industry, SiC serves as an effective tritium permeation barrier. However, a significant discrepancy remains between the experimentally measured diffusion coefficients and the theoretical predictions. In addition, a steep tritium concentration gradient exists near the surface, whereas the concentration remains nearly uniform through the bulk, a phenomenon that is not yet fully understood. In this study, first-principles calculations were performed to investigate the influences of vacancies, grain boundaries, and surfaces on tritium diffusion in 3C-SiC. Vacancies and grain boundaries were found to have a negligible impact on the effective diffusion coefficient. In contrast, the surface exhibited a high diffusion barrier, demonstrating a strong tritium-trapping behavior. Incorporation of the surface effect into a multilayer diffusion model resulted in good agreement between the theoretical predictions and the experimental results, while also explaining the observed steep concentration gradient near the surface. These findings enhance the fundamental understanding of the tritium behavior in SiC and provide theoretical guidance for the design of high-performance tritium permeation barrier materials.</description>
      <author>Ziling Zhou, Zhengzhe Qu, Mengjie Wu, Yu Wang, Feng Xie, Jiejuan Tong, Yanwei Wen, Bin Shan, Feng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c10266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Halide Perovskites: An Emerging Electrocatalyst for Oxygen and Hydrogen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500713</link>
      <description>F. Jefin, Chaithra Rajeev, Anil Kumar U., Luqman Shahid, Asis Sethi, Harshal Agarwal, Sachin Thawarkar, Vishal M. Dhavale, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414071765

                Abstract Halide perovskites are a significant class of compounds with ABX 3 crystal structure and have shown remarkable potential in renewable energy applications such as supercapacitors, photocatalysis, and photo&#8208;electrocatalysis. Their efficient charge carrier mobility, superior optoelectronic properties derived from optimal bandgap and tunable composition are beneficial for the applications of halide perovskites in the sustainable energy conversion and storage field. This review highlights the inherent potential of halide perovskites as electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen electrocatalysis. Oxygen evolution reaction (OER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are the bottlenecks for sustainable water splitting reactions, for fuel cells, metal&#8208;air batteries, etc., which require electrocatalysts that offer good activity and excellent stability. Though noble metal catalysts offer thriving performance, their cost and stability&#8208;related issues hinder their widespread usage. Non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based perovskite oxide has already established its stronghold in electrocatalysis. Similarly, their halogen counterpart, perovskite halides, also prove to be efficient contenders for noble metal&#8208;free electrocatalysts. In this review, various suitable synthesis techniques, mechanisms, and the electrocatalytic activity of halide perovskites are discussed. This review aims to show yet another class of compounds (halide perovskites) to the researcher community that strives for the development of noble metal&#8208;free electrocatalysts for sustainable energy applications.</description>
      <author>F. Jefin, Chaithra Rajeev, Anil Kumar U., Luqman Shahid, Asis Sethi, Harshal Agarwal, Sachin Thawarkar, Vishal M. Dhavale</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500713</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isotope-dependent Tafel analysis probes proton transfer kinetics during electrocatalytic water splitting.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01934-5</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Ran Wang, Hongyuan Sheng, Xiaorong Zhu, R. Dominic Ross, Daxing Hua, Lin Lei, Yafei Li, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Xianjie Wang, Ping Xu, Jun L&#252;, Sida Jiang, Jiecai Han, Bo Song, Song Jin, PubMed. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414083407

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Ran Wang, Hongyuan Sheng, Xiaorong Zhu, R. Dominic Ross, Daxing Hua, Lin Lei, Yafei Li, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Xianjie Wang, Ping Xu, Jun L&#252;, Sida Jiang, Jiecai Han, Bo Song, Song Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01934-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient, Hierarchical, and Object-Oriented Electronic Structure Interfaces for Direct Nonadiabatic Dynamics Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00878</link>
      <description>Sascha Mausenberger, Severin Polonius, Sebastian Mai, Leticia Gonz&#225;lez, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414084320

                We present a novel, flexible framework for electronic structure interfaces designed for nonadiabatic dynamics simulations, implemented in Python 3 using concepts of object-oriented programming. This framework streamlines the development of new interfaces by providing a reusable and extendable code base. It supports the computation of energies, gradients, various couplings&#9472;like spin-orbit couplings, nonadiabatic couplings, and transition dipole moments&#9472;and other properties for an arbitrary number of states with any multiplicities and charges. A key innovation within this framework is the introduction of hybrid interfaces, which can use other interfaces in a general hierarchical manner. Hybrid interfaces are capable of using one or more child interfaces to implement multiscale approaches, such as quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics where different child interfaces are assigned to different regions of a system. The concept of hybrid interfaces can be extended through nesting, where hybrid parent interfaces use hybrid child interfaces to easily setup complex workflows without the need for additional coding. We demonstrate the versatility of hybrid interfaces with two examples: one at the method level and one at the workflow level. The first example showcases the numerical differentiation of wave function overlaps, implemented as a hybrid interface and used to optimize a minimum-energy conical intersection with numerical nonadiabatic couplings. The second example presents an adaptive learning workflow, where nested hybrid interfaces are used to iteratively refine a machine learning model. This work lays the groundwork for more modular, flexible, and scalable software design in excited-state dynamics.</description>
      <author>Sascha Mausenberger, Severin Polonius, Sebastian Mai, Leticia Gonz&#225;lez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Transition State Search and Ligand Screening for Organometallic Catalysis with Reactive Machine Learning Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01047</link>
      <description>Kun Tang, Yujing Zhao, Lei Zhang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Qilei Liu, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414084992

                Organometallic catalysis lies at the heart of numerous industrial processes that produce bulk and fine chemicals. The search for transition states and screening for organic ligands are vital in designing highly active organometallic catalysts with efficient reaction kinetics. However, identifying accurate transition states necessitates computationally intensive quantum chemistry calculations. In this work, a reactive machine learning potential (RMLP) model is developed to accelerate transition state optimizations and ligand screening for organometallic catalysis based on an automated transition state database construction method and a higher-order equivariant message passing neural network. In case studies involving the ethylene hydrogenation reaction catalyzed by organometallic catalysts, RMLP rapidly predicts potential energy surfaces along intrinsic reaction coordinate paths, achieving speeds nearly 3 orders of magnitude faster than those of rigorous quantum chemistry calculations. Meanwhile, it maintains comparable accuracy with a root-mean-square deviation of 0.307 &#197; for transition state geometries and a mean absolute error of 0.871 kJ&#183;mol-1 for reaction barriers on the external test set, significantly outperforming semiempirical quantum chemistry methods. Our RMLP model offers an effective alternative to both rigorous and semiempirical quantum chemistry approaches for rapid and precise transition state optimizations, facilitating high-throughput screening of advanced organometallic catalyst ligands.</description>
      <author>Kun Tang, Yujing Zhao, Lei Zhang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Qilei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain for Credentialing and Academic Record-Keeping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3373-2185-1.ch014</link>
      <description>B. Subashini, Anna Anbumozhi, S. Praveenkumar, N. Vasudevan, Venkatesh Kaliamoorthy, Advances in computational intelligence and robotics book series. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414089994

                In the digital era, ensuring the security, authenticity, and accessibility of academic credentials is crucial. Traditional credentialing and academic record-keeping systems suffer from inefficiencies, security vulnerabilities, and verification issues. Blockchain technology offers a decentralized, tamper-proof, and transparent solution to these challenges. This chapter explores blockchain's potential in academic credentialing, examining its benefits, challenges, and real-world applications. Academic institutions currently rely on centralized authorities, which can be inefficient and susceptible to fraud. Blockchain provides an immutable ledger that enables secure issuance, decentralized verification, and fraud prevention. By leveraging cryptographic security and smart contracts, institutions can issue digital diplomas and certificates that are instantly verifiable, eliminating the need for intermediary verification. Blockchain also enhances lifelong learning records by allowing students to consolidate academic achievements into a single digital identity. This improves global mobility.</description>
      <author>B. Subashini, Anna Anbumozhi, S. Praveenkumar, N. Vasudevan, Venkatesh Kaliamoorthy</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3373-2185-1.ch014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The augmented potential method: Multiscale modeling toward a spectral defect genome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2025.116969</link>
      <description>Nutth Tuchinda, Changle Li, Christopher A. Schuh, Scripta Materialia. 271(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414090801

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nutth Tuchinda, Changle Li, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2025.116969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretation of X-ray Photoelectron Spectra of Ge(111), GeO2/Ge(111), and C60F18/Ge(111) Samples Using Quantum Chemical Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1027451025700685</link>
      <description>E. A. Shramkov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, Ratibor G. Chumakov, V. G. Stankevich, &#1051;. &#1055;. &#1057;&#1091;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Journal of Surface Investigation X-ray Synchrotron and Neutron Techniques. 19(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414095106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. A. Shramkov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, Ratibor G. Chumakov, V. G. Stankevich, &#1051;. &#1055;. &#1057;&#1091;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1027451025700685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Hexagonal &lt;scp&gt;V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; Monolayer as a Promising Nonprecious Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction: Insights from First&#8208;Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70137</link>
      <description>Ziqi Li, Xue Li, Sheng Wang, Siyu Lu, Guochun Yang, Zhiyong Tang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100023

                The development of efficient, cost&#8208;effective, and durable electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is critical for advancing sustainable energy systems and enabling the widespread adoption of hydrogen&#8208;based energy technologies. In this study, we discover a stable hexagonal V 2 B 2 monolayer that serves as a promising HER catalyst via an unbiased swarm&#8208;intelligence structural method as implemented in CALYPSO code. First&#8208;principles calculations show that the predicted V 2 B 2 monolayer exhibits excellent metallic properties and promising catalytic activity for HER, suggesting CALYPSO's utility for accelerating the discovery of efficient electrocatalysts. Further doping engineering, incorporating transition metals (TM&#8242; = Sc, Y, Ti, Zr, Hf), reveals that the introduction of Sc, Y, and Zr significantly enhances the catalytic performance. Bader charge analysis reveals a linear correlation between the electron gain by the hydrogen atom and &#916; G H* , suggesting that this relationship could serve as an effective descriptor for HER activity in TM'&#8208;doped V 2 B 2 systems. Our findings provide valuable insights into nonprecious HER electrocatalysts and contribute to a deeper understanding of high catalytic performance in newly proposed 2D HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ziqi Li, Xue Li, Sheng Wang, Siyu Lu, Guochun Yang, Zhiyong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin State Modulation in M&#8211;N&#8211;C Single-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04591</link>
      <description>Hyeonjung Jung, Roman Fanta, Md Delowar Hossain, Michal Bajdich, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyeonjung Jung, Roman Fanta, Md Delowar Hossain, Michal Bajdich</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering enhanced high mass specific activity and robust Pt/PtSe2 electrode for large current hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136750</link>
      <description>Bing Hao, Jingjing Guo, Feng Chen, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Yanhui Song, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo, Fuel. 405(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Hao, Jingjing Guo, Feng Chen, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Yanhui Song, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure optimization of transition metal dichalcogenides via Cu doping for enhanced nitrate reduction reaction efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107649</link>
      <description>Jiacheng Li, Wei Lang, Lei Rao, Peifang Wang, Chongchong Liu, Y.C. Zhou, Yi Chen, Gang Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414106340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiacheng Li, Wei Lang, Lei Rao, Peifang Wang, Chongchong Liu, Y.C. Zhou, Yi Chen, Gang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Study to Assess the Influence of Elastic Strains on the Catalytic Activity of Au Surfaces for the HER and ORR Including the Effect of Coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01962</link>
      <description>Diego Schaefer-Dalmau, Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Javier LLorca, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414111269

                The influence of different surface coverages and the effect of biaxial elastic strains on the catalytic properties for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) were analyzed using the example of a Au fcc(111) surface. The adsorption energies of H, O, and OH for the corresponding intermediate reactions were obtained by density functional theory calculations. While for H and O, the adsorption energy increased with coverage, for OH, the lowest adsorption energy was observed at 0.5 ML. Then, after elastic strains were applied, the trends observed for the unstrained slab were maintained for the three adsorbates. Although neither tension nor compression modified the optimum coverage, they did change the differences in relative energies. This is considered to be a consequence of the deformations promoted on the surface. Finally, the catalytic activity of the HER and ORR was computed for the distinct coverages and elastic strains. Catalytic activity plots confirmed for both reactions that the more favorable adsorption energy promoted by tensile strains leads to an increment of the activity and that the most active coverage is 0.25 ML. Furthermore, an analysis of the free energies of each step of the dissociative mechanism of the ORR unveils that both coverage and elastic strains can modify the rate-limiting step and, therefore, the catalytic activity of a material. The results presented in this work provide ample characterization of the Au fcc(111) surface as a catalyst for the HER and ORR and offer, for the first time, an analysis of the influence of both coverage and elastic strain engineering on the catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Diego Schaefer-Dalmau, Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Javier LLorca, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Hydroxylated Mn-Doped RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as an Efficient and Stable Electrocatalyst for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04487</link>
      <description>Qian Dang, Zhe Shang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414112879

                The role of surface hydroxylation in the performance of RuO2-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial but still unclear. Using first-principles calculations, we comprehensively studied the impact of surface hydroxylation states on the activity and stability of Mn-doped RuO2-based electrocatalysts (denoted as nOH-Mn0.1Ru0.9O2, n = 1&#8211;5) in acidic OER. It was revealed that the moderately hydroxylated Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 demonstrates better performance than the fully hydroxylated structure, and 4OH-Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 holds the lowest reaction barrier of 0.14 eV in solvation under the constant potential of 1.5 V, which is lower than those of both pure RuO2 (0.28 eV) and Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 (0.23 eV). Such an increase in catalytic activity stems from the nonstrong-and-nonweak charge transfer of reaction sites. In addition, the synergistic effect of doping and hydroxylation can also increase the stability of RuO2 through inhibition of structure collapse caused by the dissolution of Ru and the loss of lattice oxygen. The present study has provided a novel strategy for the design of efficient and stable RuO2-based acidic OER catalysts through surface hydroxylation.</description>
      <author>Qian Dang, Zhe Shang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Hydrogenationof Lignin Derivatives For Sustainable Synthesis of Value-Added Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00981-3</link>
      <description>Ning L&#252;, Congxin Chen, Xiaokang Zhao, Xinxin Li, Dehua Xiong, Zan Li, Guangyuan Yang, Lei Wang, Li Guo, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414116679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning L&#252;, Congxin Chen, Xiaokang Zhao, Xinxin Li, Dehua Xiong, Zan Li, Guangyuan Yang, Lei Wang, Li Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00981-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy, exergy, environmental, and exergoeconomic (4E) analysis of a fossil fuel power plant with carbon capture unit for a sustainable future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2025.08.056</link>
      <description>Tahir Abdul Hussain Ratlamwala, Khurram Kamal, Hafsa Javed, Sheikh Muhammad Ali Haider, &#1052;uhammad Abid, Sayem Zafar, Mohammed Alkahtani, Alexandria Engineering Journal. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414116771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tahir Abdul Hussain Ratlamwala, Khurram Kamal, Hafsa Javed, Sheikh Muhammad Ali Haider, &#1052;uhammad Abid, Sayem Zafar, Mohammed Alkahtani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2025.08.056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing carbon capture and storage (CCS) infrastructure development using a python tool for source-sink matching and cluster formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146563</link>
      <description>Amina Togay, Gaini Serik, Woojin Lee, Journal of Cleaner Production. 525(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414118433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amina Togay, Gaini Serik, Woojin Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel Janus InN/PtSSe heterostructure for highly efficient overall water splitting via a third-generation Z-scheme: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151360</link>
      <description>Khawla Chaoui, Ali Hamidani, Kamel Zanat, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 174(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414120014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Khawla Chaoui, Ali Hamidani, Kamel Zanat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable optoelectronic and hydrogen evolution reaction properties of decorated 2D materials (Ga2O3 monolayer, ZnO monolayer and borophene)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2025.116372</link>
      <description>Rongzhi Wang, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, Physica E Low-dimensional Systems and Nanostructures. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414120360

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rongzhi Wang, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2025.116372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced stability catalytic performance: a strategy for stability enhancement of Ru-based catalysts in acidic OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/01614940.2025.2556094</link>
      <description>Bin Liu, Yong Zhao, Yuhao Wu, Yanxuan Wen, Zonglin Liu, Pengfei Wang, Jie Shu, Ting-Feng Yi, Catalysis Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414123085

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Liu, Yong Zhao, Yuhao Wu, Yanxuan Wen, Zonglin Liu, Pengfei Wang, Jie Shu, Ting-Feng Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/01614940.2025.2556094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Electrolyte Ions on Iridium Oxide-Based Water Oxidation Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03970</link>
      <description>Boqiang Chen, Pengpeng Wang, Dongyoon Shin, Wei Li, Tianying Liu, Matthias M. Waegele, Dunwei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414125155

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boqiang Chen, Pengpeng Wang, Dongyoon Shin, Wei Li, Tianying Liu, Matthias M. Waegele, Dunwei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tandem amine scrubbing and CO2 electrolysis via direct piperazine carbamate reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01869-8</link>
      <description>Peng Li, Yu Mao, Heejong Shin, Qi Yang, Xuan Cheng, Yitong Li, Kangkang Li, Hai Yu, Roger J. Mulder, Wei Kong Pang, Huanyu Jin, Yong Zhao, Zhifeng Zheng, E. P. Finch, Kyle N. Hearn, Baohua Jia, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Ziyun Wang, Tianyi Ma, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414131647

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Li, Yu Mao, Heejong Shin, Qi Yang, Xuan Cheng, Yitong Li, Kangkang Li, Hai Yu, Roger J. Mulder, Wei Kong Pang, Huanyu Jin, Yong Zhao, Zhifeng Zheng, E. P. Finch, Kyle N. Hearn, Baohua Jia, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Ziyun Wang, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01869-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of monoatomic boron electronic structure to improve catalytic activity for electrocatalytic acetonitrile reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151428</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Song, Liang Yu, Yi Yang, Xiaoqing Gong, Mingqiang Liu, Kai Xu, Daming Sun, Kefeng Xie, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 174(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414141625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Song, Liang Yu, Yi Yang, Xiaoqing Gong, Mingqiang Liu, Kai Xu, Daming Sun, Kefeng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-engineered Ga2SSe/SnS2 van der Waals heterojunction as an efficient S-scheme photocatalyst for solar water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107637</link>
      <description>Junhao Zhu, Zhengdong Sun, Jiaxin Ma, Yifei Shen, Xiao Wang, Meng Zhang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414148250

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junhao Zhu, Zhengdong Sun, Jiaxin Ma, Yifei Shen, Xiao Wang, Meng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials Engineering for High Performance and Durability Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01989</link>
      <description>Pablo A. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Salaberri, Lonneke van Eijk, William Bangay, Kara J. Ferner, M.H. Ha, M. S. Moore, Ivan Perea, Ahmet Kusoglu, Fei Wei, Prodip K. Das, Nausir Firas, Svitlana Pylypenko, Melissa Novy, Michael Yandrasits, Suvash C. Saha, Ali Bayat, Shawn Litster, Iryna V. Zenyuk, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414155218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pablo A. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Salaberri, Lonneke van Eijk, William Bangay, Kara J. Ferner, M.H. Ha, M. S. Moore, Ivan Perea, Ahmet Kusoglu, Fei Wei, Prodip K. Das, Nausir Firas, Svitlana Pylypenko, Melissa Novy, Michael Yandrasits, Suvash C. Saha, Ali Bayat, Shawn Litster, Iryna V. Zenyuk</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non&#8208;oxide High&#8208;Entropy Ceramics for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.70048</link>
      <description>Gang Wang, Xuguang Guo, Lihua Lyu, Ruihui Gan, Yongping Zheng, Hyoyoung Lee, Xiaodong Shao, Carbon Neutralization. 4(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414155426

                ABSTRACT As fossil energy resources deplete and environmental challenges escalate, the development of clean energy technologies has gained global consensus. Among emerging strategies, electrochemical water splitting for hydrogen production stands out due to its zero&#8208;carbon emissions. However, the oxygen evolution reaction suffers from sluggish kinetics and typically depends on precious metal catalysts. Recently, non&#8208;oxygen anion (e.g., S, P, N, F, C, etc.) high&#8208;entropy ceramics (NOHECs), a subclass of high&#8208;entropy materials doped with diverse elements, have demonstrated significant OER potential, offering a cost&#8208;effective solution with high activity and excellent stability. This review delineates the synthesis methods for NOHECs from two distinct perspectives: liquid&#8208;phase synthesis routes and gas&#8208;phase synthesis routes. Subsequently, the catalytic mechanisms and performance breakthroughs of various NOHECs are reviewed in detail, which are categorized by the types of coordinated non&#8208;oxygen anions. Importantly, this review critically explores future research directions for these materials from multiple perspectives, including innovative synthetic routes, novel NOHEC designs, theoretical simulations, advanced material characterization techniques, industrial feasibility, and expanded applications. Ultimately, it aims to provide a theoretical foundation and technical references for the integration of NOHECs in energy conversion systems while highlighting promising pathways for further advancement in this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <author>Gang Wang, Xuguang Guo, Lihua Lyu, Ruihui Gan, Yongping Zheng, Hyoyoung Lee, Xiaodong Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.70048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-Economic Analysis of Packed Bed and Structured Adsorbent for Direct Air Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100518</link>
      <description>Paul de Joannis, Christophe Castel, Mohamed Kanniche, &#201;ric Favre, Olivier Authier, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414043801

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paul de Joannis, Christophe Castel, Mohamed Kanniche, &#201;ric Favre, Olivier Authier</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Perspective On Materials, Electrochemistry, and Cell Concepts for Redox&#8208;Mediated CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Direct Air Capture Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ceur.202500236</link>
      <description>Tilmann J. Neubert, Martin Oschatz, ChemistryEurope. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414128369

                Anthropogenic emissions of previously sequestered carbon continue to disrupt the natural carbon cycle, driving atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) concentrations beyond 420 ppm. This has resulted in global temperatures rising beyond 1.5 &#176;C above the pre&#8208;industrial level. Direct air capture (DAC) of CO 2 has emerged as a complementary mitigation strategy. However, current DAC technologies are limited by the high energy requirements inherent to the thermal release of captured CO 2 , which are caused by the low thermodynamic efficiency of heat&#8208;driven processes, as constrained by Carnot principles. Redox&#8208;mediated electrochemical carbon capture (RMECC) offers a promising pathway to overcome these limitations. RMECC with DAC application remains in an early developmental stage and requires further optimization to enable energy&#8208;efficient, cost&#8208;effective, and scalable deployment. In this perspective the design of sorbents, electrolytes, and electrochemical cell configurations in the field of RMECC are discussed with an emphasis on sustainable approaches for the demands of DAC applications. The challenges arising from the atmospheric dilution of CO 2 within the more abundant and disruptive competitor oxygen are highlighted as a critical factor influencing sorbent performance. Recent advancements in RMECC are reviewed, key challenges are identified, and future directions are outlined to accelerate electrochemically mediated DAC towards practical implementation.</description>
      <author>Tilmann J. Neubert, Martin Oschatz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ceur.202500236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic Cocatalysts Driving Electron Extraction in COFs for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125941</link>
      <description>Ge Yan, Xiaolong Xu, Weixiang Kong, Anqi Qin, Yali Ma, Hui Li, Hongwei Huang, Hua Fan, Xiaodong Sun, Tianyi Ma, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414061894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ge Yan, Xiaolong Xu, Weixiang Kong, Anqi Qin, Yali Ma, Hui Li, Hongwei Huang, Hua Fan, Xiaodong Sun, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125941</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
