<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 01:14:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Colloidal copper nanospheres boost propanol electrosynthesis from CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4544481/v1</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Anna Loiudice, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez Al&#233;, Krishna Kumar, Dragos Stoian, Zan Lian, Petru P. Albertini, Ludovic Zaza, Jari Leemans, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Raffaella Buonsanti, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401323735

                Abstract Achieving a carbon neutral manufacturing of chemicals is imperative to accelerate the transition towards a sustainable future. Propanol electrosynthesis from CO electroreduction represents a promising alternative to the current manufacturing of this chemical. Yet, the catalyst features driving propanol formation are poorly understood, which limits further advancement in the performance. Herein, we report on a comprehensive mapping of the sensitivity of the CO electroreduction to the catalyst structure exploiting well-defined copper nanocrystals (NCs) with tunable shape and size synthesized via colloidal chemistry. In addition to clarify the dependence from the exposed surfaces, we discover that spheres uniquely promote n-propanol selectivity, which we explain mostly with strain effects. Driven by this novel insight, we achieve unprecedent n-propanol production via electrosynthesis with a copper catalyst. We demonstrate that colloidal copper nanospheres with a diameter of 4 nm deliver n-propanol faradaic efficiency of 39.6&#177;1.4% at 119&#177;4.2 mA/cm2 production rate, the latter being ten times the current state of the art for copper catalysts.</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Anna Loiudice, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez Al&#233;, Krishna Kumar, Dragos Stoian, Zan Lian, Petru P. Albertini, Ludovic Zaza, Jari Leemans, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Raffaella Buonsanti</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4544481/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ionic liquid&#8211;electrode interface: classification of ions, saturation of layers, and structure-determined potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144829</link>
      <description>Karl Karu, E.R. Nerut, Xueran Tao, Sergei A. Kislenko, Kaija P&#245;hako&#8208;Esko, Iuliia V. Voroshylova, Vladislav Ivani&#353;t&#353;ev, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401325023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karl Karu, E.R. Nerut, Xueran Tao, Sergei A. Kislenko, Kaija P&#245;hako&#8208;Esko, Iuliia V. Voroshylova, Vladislav Ivani&#353;t&#353;ev</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning driven advancements in catalysis for predicting hydrogen evolution reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129805</link>
      <description>Priyanka Sinha, M. V. Jyothirmai, B. Moses Abraham, Jayant K. Singh, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326351

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Priyanka Sinha, M. V. Jyothirmai, B. Moses Abraham, Jayant K. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from Up-Scaling CO2 Capture: Challenges and Experiences with Pilot work</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120576</link>
      <description>Sai Hema Bhavya Vinjarapu, Isaac A. L&#248;ge, Randi Neerup, Anders Hellerup Larsen, Valdemar Emil Rasmussen, Jens Kristian J&#248;rsboe, Sebastian Nis Bay Villadsen, S&#248;ren Holdt Jensen, Jakob Lindkvist Karlsson, Jannik Kappel, Henrik Lassen, Peter Blinksbjerg, Nicolas von Solms, Philip Loldrup Fosb&#248;l, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sai Hema Bhavya Vinjarapu, Isaac A. L&#248;ge, Randi Neerup, Anders Hellerup Larsen, Valdemar Emil Rasmussen, Jens Kristian J&#248;rsboe, Sebastian Nis Bay Villadsen, S&#248;ren Holdt Jensen, Jakob Lindkvist Karlsson, Jannik Kappel, Henrik Lassen, Peter Blinksbjerg, Nicolas von Solms, Philip Loldrup Fosb&#248;l</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spglib: a software library for crystal symmetry search</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/27660400.2024.2384822</link>
      <description>Atsushi Togo, K. Shinohara, Isao Tanaka, Science and Technology of Advanced Materials Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401339223

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Atsushi Togo, K. Shinohara, Isao Tanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/27660400.2024.2384822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano&#8208;Single&#8208;Atom Heterointerface Engineering for pH&#8208;Universal Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409089</link>
      <description>Jian Song, Sheng&#8722;Jie Qian, Wenqiang Yang, Jiali Mu, Jingwei Li, Yaping Liu, Fanfei Sun, Shuwen Yu, Feifei Xu, Xiangen Song, Dehui Deng, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Yan Li, Yunjie Ding, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401339369

                Abstract Nano&#8208;single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts have the potential to combine the respective advantages of both nano&#8208;catalysts and single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts and thus exhibit enhanced performance. Generally, the separation of active sites in space limits the interaction between single atoms and nanoparticles. Heterointerface engineering has the potential to break this limitation. Regretfully, studies on the interface effect between single atoms and nanoparticles are rarely reported. Herein, an unprecedented nano&#8208;single&#8208;atom heterointerface composed of Fe single&#8208;atoms and carbon&#8208;shell&#8208;coated FeP nanoparticles (Fe SAC/FeP@C) is demonstrated as an efficient electrocatalyst for the nitrate reduction process from alkaline to acidic. Compared with typical nano&#8208;single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts (Fe SAC/FePO 4 ) and single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts (Fe SAC), the constructed Fe SAC/FeP@C heterostructure exhibits dramatically enhanced nitrate&#8208;to&#8208;ammonia performance. Especially in acidic media, the maxmium Faradaic efficiency of ammonia (NH 3 ) can reach 95.6 &#177; 0.5%, with a maximum NH 3 yield of 36.2 &#177; 3.1 mg h &#8722;1 mg cat &#8722;1 (pH = 1.2), which is considerably higher than previously reported. Density functional theory calculations and in situ spectroscopic investigations indicate that the unique charge redistribution at the interface, together with the optimized electronic structure of Fe single&#8208;atoms, strengthens intermediate adsorption and catalytic activity. This work provides a feasible strategy for designing nano&#8208;single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts with unique heterointerfaces, as well as valuable insights into nitrate conversion under environmentally relevant wastewater conditions.</description>
      <author>Jian Song, Sheng&#8722;Jie Qian, Wenqiang Yang, Jiali Mu, Jingwei Li, Yaping Liu, Fanfei Sun, Shuwen Yu, Feifei Xu, Xiangen Song, Dehui Deng, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Yan Li, Yunjie Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum&#8208;Ruthenium Bimetallic Nanoparticle Catalysts Synthesized Via Direct Joule Heating for Methanol Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403967</link>
      <description>Yeyu Deng, Haibo Liu, Leo Lai, Fangxin She, Fangzhou Liu, Mohan Li, Zixun Yu, Jing Li, Di Zhu, Hao Li, Li Wei, Yuan Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401357624

                Platinum-Ruthenium (PtRu) bimetallic nanoparticles are promising catalysts for methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) required by direct methanol fuel cells. However, existing catalyst synthesis methods have difficulty controlling their composition and structures. Here, a direct Joule heating method to yield highly active and stable PtRu catalysts for MOR is shown. The optimized Joule heating condition at 1000 &#176;C over 50 microseconds produces uniform PtRu nanoparticles (6.32 wt.% Pt and 2.97 wt% Ru) with an average size of 2.0 &#177; 0.5 nanometers supported on carbon black substrates. They have a large electrochemically active surface area (ECSA) of 239 m</description>
      <author>Yeyu Deng, Haibo Liu, Leo Lai, Fangxin She, Fangzhou Liu, Mohan Li, Zixun Yu, Jing Li, Di Zhu, Hao Li, Li Wei, Yuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bi&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;CuCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Hollow Carbon Nanofibers Boosts NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Production from Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409696</link>
      <description>Hexing Lin, Jinshan Wei, Ying Guo, Yi Li, Xihui Lu, Chucheng Zhou, Shaoqing Liu, Ya&#8208;yun Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358428

                Abstract Ammonia, as a high&#8208;energy&#8208;density carrier for hydrogen storage, is in great demand worldwide. Electrocatalytic nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) provides a green NH 3 production process. However, the complex reaction pathways for NO 3 RR to NH 3 and the difficulty in controlling intermediate products limit the reduction process. Herein, by incorporating atomic&#8208;level bismuth (Bi) into CuCo 2 O 4 hollow carbon nanofibers, the catalytic activity of the electrocatalyst for NO 3 RR is enhanced. The maximum Faradaic efficiency of Bi 1 &#8208;CuCo 2 O 4 is 95.53%, with an NH 3 yield of 448.74 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 at &#8722;0.8 V versus RHE. Density Functional Theory calculations show that the presence of Bi lowers the reaction barrier for the hydrogenation step from *NO 2 to *NO 2 H, while promoting mass transfer on the release of *NH 3 and the reactivation of surface&#8208;active sites. Differential charge density calculations also show that after Bi doping, the charge supplied by the catalyst to NO 3 &#8722; increases from 0.62 to 0.72 e &#8208; , thus reasoned for enhanced NO 3 RR activity. The established nitrate&#8208;Zn battery shows an energy density of 2.81 mW cm &#8722;2 , thus implying the potential application.</description>
      <author>Hexing Lin, Jinshan Wei, Ying Guo, Yi Li, Xihui Lu, Chucheng Zhou, Shaoqing Liu, Ya&#8208;yun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles investigation of the two-dimensional van der Waals g-C3N4/g-ZnO heterojunction: Enhancing the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104919</link>
      <description>Xinxin Tian, Zizhou Cai, Yunlan Sun, Minggao Xu, Baozhong Zhu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401371191

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinxin Tian, Zizhou Cai, Yunlan Sun, Minggao Xu, Baozhong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Properties of Single-Atom Metal Catalysts Supported on Nitrogen-Doped Carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03232</link>
      <description>Maria G. Minotaki, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401389123

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maria G. Minotaki, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Cu Clusters on Two-Electron CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction at SnS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Surface: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03960</link>
      <description>Lingbing Ran, Da-Wei Deng, Yunbo Li, Qingxia Ge, Jiangtao Wu, Xi&#8208;Bo Li, Zhen&#8208;Kun Tang, Wen-Jin Yin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401395258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingbing Ran, Da-Wei Deng, Yunbo Li, Qingxia Ge, Jiangtao Wu, Xi&#8208;Bo Li, Zhen&#8208;Kun Tang, Wen-Jin Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Insights into the ORR Catalysis on Pt Alloy Nanoparticles from an Element Specific &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;-Band Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01912</link>
      <description>Tyler Joe Ziehl, Junrui Li, Shouheng Sun, Peng Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401395709

                Bolstered by their unique atomic structures and tailored compositions, nanoalloys exhibit extraordinary properties making them ideal materials to solve challenges in energy storage and conversion catalysis. However, a quantitative description of the structure-property relationships using an accurate descriptor-based model for nanoalloys, ranging from bimetallic to multimetallic compositions, is needed to drive efficient material design toward high-performance catalysis. In this work, we highlight the electronic property and catalytic activity relationship from an element specific</description>
      <author>Tyler Joe Ziehl, Junrui Li, Shouheng Sun, Peng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Ammonia Oxidation to Nitrite and Nitrate with NiOOH&#8208;Ni</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401675</link>
      <description>Hanwen Liu, Cheng&#8208;Jie Yang, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Jiashu Wang, Xin Zhang, Andrey Lyalin, Tetsuya Taketsugu, Zhiqi Chen, Daqin Guan, Xiaomin Xu, Zongping Shao, Zhenguo Huang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401396156

                Abstract Ammonia electrooxidation in aqueous solutions can be a highly energy&#8208;efficient process in producing nitrate and nitrite while generating hydrogen under ambient conditions. However, the kinetics of this reaction are slow and the role of catalyst in facilitating ammonia electrooxidation is not well understood. In this study, a high&#8208;performance NiOOH&#8208;Ni catalyst is introduced for converting ammonia into nitrite with Faraday efficiency of up to 90.4% and nitrate production rate of 1 mg h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 . By employing Operando techniques, the role of NiOOH catalyst is elucidated in the dynamic electrooxidation of ammonia. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations support experimental observations and reveal the mechanism of the electrochemical oxidation of ammonia to nitrite and nitrate. Overall, this research contributes to the development of a cost&#8208;effective and highly efficient catalyst for large&#8208;scale ammonia electrolysis, while shedding light on the underlying mechanism of the NiOOH catalyst in ammonia electrooxidation.</description>
      <author>Hanwen Liu, Cheng&#8208;Jie Yang, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Jiashu Wang, Xin Zhang, Andrey Lyalin, Tetsuya Taketsugu, Zhiqi Chen, Daqin Guan, Xiaomin Xu, Zongping Shao, Zhenguo Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Atom&#8211;Support Interaction in Single Atom Catalysts toward Hydrogen Peroxide Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c07916</link>
      <description>Jizhou Duan, Haitao Xu, Wang Gao, Shanshan Chen, Feng Li, Dongyuan Zhao, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401397949

                Single metal atom catalysts (SACs) have garnered considerable attention as promising agents for catalyzing important industrial reactions, particularly the electrochemical synthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H</description>
      <author>Jizhou Duan, Haitao Xu, Wang Gao, Shanshan Chen, Feng Li, Dongyuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c07916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Morphology of Layered Double Hydroxide in Electrochemical Energy Storage and Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400519</link>
      <description>Peng Song, Qianfeng Pan, Yixuan Qiao, Tiantian Wang, Nyan Lynn Htut, Bo Chen, Marc A. Anderson, Yang Wang, Han Hu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401400887

                The development of nanomaterials for energy storage and conversion has always been important. Layered double hydroxide (LDH) is a promising material due to its high capacity, tunable composition and easy synthesis. In this work, the morphology of NiCo-LDH is tuned with surfactants including sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS) and cetyltrimethylammonium bromide (CTAB), and investigated the correlation between morphology and electrochemical properties. NiCo-LDH-SDS with a layered structure exhibited a specific capacitance of 1004 C g</description>
      <author>Peng Song, Qianfeng Pan, Yixuan Qiao, Tiantian Wang, Nyan Lynn Htut, Bo Chen, Marc A. Anderson, Yang Wang, Han Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging electrocatalysts for green ammonia production: Recent progress and future outlook</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arabjc.2024.105950</link>
      <description>Sajid Mahmood, Shahid Iqbal, Sajid Mahmood, Muhammad Ammar, Muhammad Javed Iqbal, Ali Bahadur, Nasser S. Awwad, Hala A. Ibrahium, Arabian Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401406586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajid Mahmood, Shahid Iqbal, Sajid Mahmood, Muhammad Ammar, Muhammad Javed Iqbal, Ali Bahadur, Nasser S. Awwad, Hala A. Ibrahium</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arabjc.2024.105950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable topological magnetism in superlattices of nonmagnetic B20 systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.l060407</link>
      <description>Vladislav Borisov, Anna Delin, Olle Eriksson, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401418556

                We predict topological magnetic properties of B20 systems, that are organized in atomically thin multilayers. In particular, we focus on FeSi/CoSi and FeSi/FeGe superlattices with different numbers of layers and interface structures. We demonstrate that the absence of long-range magnetic order, previously observed in bulk FeSi and CoSi, is broken near the FeSi/CoSi interface, where a magnetic state with a nontrivial topological texture appears. Using the Heisenberg and Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya (DM) interactions calculated from first principles, we perform finite-temperature atomistic spin dynamics simulations for up to 2&#215;106 spins to capture the complexity of noncollinear textures. Our simulations predict the formation of antiskyrmions in a [001]-oriented FeSi/CoSi multilayer, intermediate skyrmions in a [111]-oriented FeSi/CoSi system, and Bloch skyrmions in the FeSi/FeGe (001) system, with a size between 7 and 37 nm. These varieties of topological magnetic textures in the studied systems can be attributed to the complex asymmetric structure of the DM matrix, which is different from previously known magnetic materials. We demonstrate that through structural engineering both ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic skyrmions can be stabilized, where the latter are especially appealing for applications due to the zero skyrmion Hall effect. The proposed B20 multilayers show a potential for further exploration and call for experimental confirmation. Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Vladislav Borisov, Anna Delin, Olle Eriksson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.l060407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Low Temperature Lithium-ion Battery Performance under High-rate Conditions with Niobium Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101663</link>
      <description>Elizabeth A. Pogue, Spencer Langevin, Tanner Hamann, Karun K. Rao, Marshall A. Schroeder, Nam Q. Le, Courtney McHale, Zachary Burchfield, Jesse S. Ko, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401422129

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elizabeth A. Pogue, Spencer Langevin, Tanner Hamann, Karun K. Rao, Marshall A. Schroeder, Nam Q. Le, Courtney McHale, Zachary Burchfield, Jesse S. Ko</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financiamento ambiental e a atividade de captura e armazenamento de CO2: instrumentos para efetiva&#231;&#227;o da responsabilidade de longo prazo no Brasil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.11606/t.106.2024.tde-22072024-155313</link>
      <description>Silvia Andrea Cupertino, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401422708

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silvia Andrea Cupertino</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.11606/t.106.2024.tde-22072024-155313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of Extrinsic Factors That Limit the Catalytic Performance of Transition Metal Dichalcogenides (TMDs) in Hydrogen Evolution Reactions (HER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400259</link>
      <description>Jeyavelan Muthu, Farheen Khurshid, Mario Hofmann, Ya&#8208;Ping Hsieh, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401427676

                Abstract Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) have garnered attention as potential catalysts for water splitting owing to their unique structures, diverse electronic properties, and composition from earth&#8208;abundant elements. While certain TMD catalysts, notably MoS 2 , have shown promising activity for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER), achieving performance comparable to traditional platinum catalysts remains a challenge. While significant effort has been invested into understanding the effect of TMD's structural properties, such as defectiveness and crystalline phases, recent work has emphasized the role of extrinsic factors on HER. This review summarizes the current understanding of the impact of commonly overlooked electrocatalytic effects that exhibit an enhanced importance in TMD&#8208;based HER. By combining recent advances in theoretical modeling and experimental work, we review the dominating effects of extrinsic factors including electronic resistance, interfacial barriers, surface roughness, oxidation, and valence impurities. Our work aims to provide insights into optimizing TMDs as highly efficient catalysts for HER, facilitating future advancements in hydrogen generation technology.</description>
      <author>Jeyavelan Muthu, Farheen Khurshid, Mario Hofmann, Ya&#8208;Ping Hsieh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Direct Electrochemical Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Chemistry of C&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;C&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrocarbons via Perimeter Engineering of Au&#8211;SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402062</link>
      <description>Ju Hyun Yang, Gi Beom Sim, So Jeong Park, Choong Kyun Rhee, Chang Woo Myung, Youngku Sohn, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401427793

                Abstract Traditionally, Fischer&#8211;Tropsch (FT) synthesis is performed using thermal catalysts and syngas (CO and H 2 ) under high&#8208;pressure and high&#8208;temperature conditions. However, this study introduces an approach that relies on FT chemistry assisted by electrochemistry, referred to here as direct electrochemical (EC) FT chemistry, under ambient conditions. A series of CH 4 , C n H 2n , and C n H 2n+2 hydrocarbons (n = 1&#8211;7) is successfully produced over gold (Au) nanoparticle&#8208;loaded perovskite strontium titanate (SrTiO 3 ) nanostructures grown on rutile TiO 2 supported on Ti. Au (1.0 nm)&#8211;SrTiO 3 shows the best interface formation, with the highest Faradaic efficiency for C 2+ hydrocarbons. This direct EC&#8208;FT process proceeds via a C&#9472;C coupling chain growth reaction at the Au&#8208;SrTiO 3 interface as evidenced by the hydrocarbon weight distribution analysis and density functional theory calculations. The robust combination of experimental and computational findings reveals that optimum conditions for producing surface hydrogenation and C&#9472;C coupling polymerization, initiated by surface * CO and * H are achieved by controlling the undercoordinated Au at the perimeter sites of supported Au nanoparticles and by ensuring a harmonized density of states between Au and SrTiO 3 . This EC&#8208;FT process opens a promising avenue for the direct conversion of CO 2 and H 2 O into value&#8208;added long&#8208;chain hydrocarbons.</description>
      <author>Ju Hyun Yang, Gi Beom Sim, So Jeong Park, Choong Kyun Rhee, Chang Woo Myung, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the scaling relations of effective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrochemical reduction in diatomic catalysts by adjusting the flow direction of intermediate structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03085k</link>
      <description>Yanwen Zhang, Zhaoqun Yao, Yiming Yang, Xingwu Zhai, Feng Zhang, Zhijun Guo, Xinghuan Liu, Bin Yang, Yunxia Liang, Guixian Ge, Xin Jia, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401430982

                High-throughput calculations show 11 flow directions from *CO to *CHO on DACs. The catalyst disrupting the linear adsorption relationship is linked to multiple, not just one, flow direction.</description>
      <author>Yanwen Zhang, Zhaoqun Yao, Yiming Yang, Xingwu Zhai, Feng Zhang, Zhijun Guo, Xinghuan Liu, Bin Yang, Yunxia Liang, Guixian Ge, Xin Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03085k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical enhancement for TiO2-based photoanodes: in-situ electrochemical analysis, modification strategies and mechanism studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144859</link>
      <description>Xiaoying Shang, Shouxin Zhang, Zhiwei Li, Li Fu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401433845

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoying Shang, Shouxin Zhang, Zhiwei Li, Li Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxophilic gallium single atoms bridged ruthenium clusters for practical anion-exchange membrane electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51200-4</link>
      <description>Chenhui Zhou, Jia Shi, Zhaoqi Dong, Yunqi Liu, Yan Chen, Ying Han, Lu Li, Wenyu Zhang, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Fan Lv, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437692

                The development of highly efficient and durable alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalysts is crucial for achieving high-performance practical anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) at ampere-level current density. Herein, we report a design concept by employing Ga single atoms as an electronic bridge to stabilize the Ru clusters for boosting alkaline HER performance in practical AEMWE. Experimental and theoretical results collectively reveal that the bridged Ga sites trigger strong metal-support interaction for the homogeneous distribution of Ru clusters with high density, as well as optimize the Ru-H bond strength due to the electron transfer between Ru and Ga for enhanced intrinsic HER activity. Moreover, the oxophilic Ga sites near the Ru clusters tend to adsorb the hydroxyl species and accelerate the water dissociation for sufficient proton supplement in an alkaline medium. The Ru-Ga</description>
      <author>Chenhui Zhou, Jia Shi, Zhaoqi Dong, Yunqi Liu, Yan Chen, Ying Han, Lu Li, Wenyu Zhang, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Fan Lv, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51200-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;efficient electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction to HCOOH coupling with 5&#8208;hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation using flow cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18562</link>
      <description>Jing Ren, Zixian Li, Chenjun Ning, Shaoquan Li, Luming Zhang, Hengshuo Huang, Lirong Zheng, Young Soo Kang, Mingchuan Luo, Yufei Zhao, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401444002

                Abstract Among various products from electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction (CO 2 ER), HCOOH is highly profitable one. However, the slow kinetics of anodic oxygen evolution reaction lowers overall energy efficiency, which can be replaced by an electro&#8208;oxidation reaction with low thermodynamic potential and fast kinetics. Herein, we report an electrolysis system coupling CO 2 ER with 5&#8208;hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation reaction (HMFOR). A BiOCl&#8211;CuO catalyst was designed to sustain CO 2 ER to HCOOH at partial current density of 500 mA/cm 2 with FE HCOOH above 90% and 700 mA/cm 2 with FE HCOOH above 80%. In situ and ex situ x&#8208;ray absorption fine structure was used to capture the structure transform of BiOCl&#8211;CuO into metallic Bi and Cu during CO 2 ER process, and the presence of CuO will promote this transformation which are supported by DFT calculations. Coupling HMFOR with CO 2 ER, we realize both FE HCOOH and FE FDCA above 95% simultaneously, providing new prospects vista for the electrosynthesis of value&#8208;added products from paired system.</description>
      <author>Jing Ren, Zixian Li, Chenjun Ning, Shaoquan Li, Luming Zhang, Hengshuo Huang, Lirong Zheng, Young Soo Kang, Mingchuan Luo, Yufei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing transition metal oxide&#8209;carbon heterostructures: Pioneering electrocatalysts for energy systems and other applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113171</link>
      <description>M. S., Sariga, Sandra Jose, V. Anitha, Journal of Energy Storage. 99(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401444005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. S., Sariga, Sandra Jose, V. Anitha</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refining Free-Energy Calculations for Electrochemical Reactions: Unveiling Corrections beyond Gas-Phase Errors for Solvated Species and Ions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04130</link>
      <description>Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401452021

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strength of 2D glasses explored by machine-learning force fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0215663</link>
      <description>Peter Shi, Zhiping Xu, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456504

                The strengths of glasses are intricately linked to their atomic-level heterogeneity. Atomistic simulations are frequently used to investigate the statistical physics of this relationship, compensating for the limited spatiotemporal resolution in experimental studies. However, theoretical insights are limited by the complexity of glass structures and the accuracy of the interatomic potentials used in simulations. Here, we investigate the strengths and fracture mechanisms of 2D silica, with all structural units accessible to direct experimental observation. We develop a neural network force field for fracture based on the deep potential-smooth edition framework. Representative atomic structures across crystals, nanocrystalline, paracrystalline, and continuous random network glasses are studied. We find that the virials or bond lengths control the initialization of bond-breaking events, creating nanoscale voids in the vitreous network. However, the voids do not necessarily lead to crack propagation due to a disorder-trapping effect, which is stronger than the lattice-trapping effect in a crystalline lattice, and occurs over larger length and time scales. Fracture initiation proceeds with void growth and coalescence and advances through a bridging mechanism. The fracture patterns are shaped by subsequent trapping and cleavage steps, often guided by voids forming ahead of the crack tip. These heterogeneous processes result in atomically smooth facets in crystalline regions and rough, amorphous edges in the glassy phase. These insights into 2D crystals and glasses, both sharing SiO2 chemistry, highlight the pivotal role of atomic-level structures in determining fracture kinetics and crack path selection in materials.</description>
      <author>Peter Shi, Zhiping Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0215663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Surface&#8211;Subsurface Cu Atom Exchange at the FeO/Pt(111) Surface Induced by CO Adsorption at 150 K</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06542</link>
      <description>Xuda Luo, Xiaoyuan Sun, Le Lin, Zhiyu Yi, Rentao Mu, Yanxiao Ning, Qiang Fu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401460133

                Structural evolution of solid catalyst surfaces induced by direct exposure to reaction gas has been extensively studied and is well understood. However, whether and how subsurface atomic structures are affected by the reaction atmosphere require further exploration. In this work, our results confirm that Cu clusters supported on FeO/Pt(111) (Cu</description>
      <author>Xuda Luo, Xiaoyuan Sun, Le Lin, Zhiyu Yi, Rentao Mu, Yanxiao Ning, Qiang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c06542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hysteretic Piezochromism in a Lead Iodide-Based Two-Dimensional Inorganic&#8211;Organic Hybrid Perovskite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05557</link>
      <description>Paul Steeger, Mohammad Adnan, Thorsten Deilmann, Xiang Li, Susanne M&#252;ller, Katarzyna Skrzy&#324;ska, Michael Hanfland, Efim Kolesnikov, Jutta K&#246;sters, Theresa Block, Robert Schmidt, Ilya Kupenko, Carmen Sanchez&#8208;Valle, G. Vijaya Prakash, Steffen Michaelis de Vasconcellos, Rudolf Bratschitsch, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401460158

                Two-dimensional inorganic-organic hybrid perovskites are in the limelight due to their potential applications in photonics and optoelectronics. They are environmentally stable, and their various chemical compositions offer a wide range of bandgap energies. Alternatively, crystal deformation enables in situ control over their optical properties. Here, we investigate (C</description>
      <author>Paul Steeger, Mohammad Adnan, Thorsten Deilmann, Xiang Li, Susanne M&#252;ller, Katarzyna Skrzy&#324;ska, Michael Hanfland, Efim Kolesnikov, Jutta K&#246;sters, Theresa Block, Robert Schmidt, Ilya Kupenko, Carmen Sanchez&#8208;Valle, G. Vijaya Prakash, Steffen Michaelis de Vasconcellos, Rudolf Bratschitsch</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Tight-Binding Models for Band Structures of Transition-Metal Alloys and Surfaces across the &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;-Block</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00345</link>
      <description>Filippo Balzaretti, Johannes Voss, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401461730

                First-principles electronic structure simulations are an invaluable tool for understanding chemical bonding and reactions. While machine-learning models such as interatomic potentials significantly accelerate the exploration of potential energy surfaces, electronic structure information is generally lost. Particularly in the field of heterogeneous catalysis, simulated electron band structures provide fundamental insights into catalytic reactivity. This ab initio knowledge is preserved in semiempirical methods such as density functional tight binding (DFTB), which extend the accessible computational length and time scales beyond first-principles approaches. In this paper we present Shell-Optimized Atomic Confinement (SOAC) DFTB electronic-part-only parametrizations for bulk and surface band structures of all</description>
      <author>Filippo Balzaretti, Johannes Voss</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles investigation of oxidized Si- and Ge-terminated diamond (100) surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0203185</link>
      <description>Hector Gomez, James Cruz, Cody Milne, Topojit Debnath, A. Glen Birdwell, Elias Garratt, Bradford B. Pate, S. Rudin, Dmitry Ruzmetov, James Weil, Pankaj B. Shah, Tony Ivanov, Roger K. Lake, Michael N. Groves, Mahesh R. Neupane, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401461875

                Diamond is a semiconductor material with remarkable structural, thermal, and electronic properties that has garnered significant interest in the field of electronics. Although hydrogen (H) and oxygen (O) terminations are conventionally favored in transistor designs, alternative options, such as silicon (Si) and germanium (Ge), are being explored because of their resilience to harsh processing conditions during fabrication. Density-functional theory was used to examine the non-oxidized and oxidized group-IV (Si and Ge)-terminated diamond (100) surfaces. The (3 &#215; 1) reconstructed surfaces feature an ether configuration and show relative stability compared with the bare surface. Hybrid-functional calculations of the electronic properties revealed reduced fundamental bandgaps (&amp;lt;1 eV) and lower negative electron affinities (NEAs) than those of H-terminated diamond surfaces, which is attributed to the introduction of unoccupied Si (Ge) states and the depletion of negative charges. Furthermore, oxidation of these surfaces enhanced the stability of the diamond surfaces but resulted in two structural configurations: ether and ketone. Oxidized ether configurations displayed insulating properties with energy gaps of &#8764;4.3 &#177; 0.3 eV, similar to H-terminated diamond (100) surfaces, whereas bridged ether configurations exhibited metallic properties. Oxidization of the metallic ketone configurations leads to the opening of relatively smaller gaps in the range of 1.1&#8211;1.7 eV. Overall, oxidation induced a shift from NEAs to positive electron affinities, except for the reverse-ordered ketone surface with an NEA of &#8722;0.94 eV, a value comparable to the H-terminated diamond (100) surfaces. In conclusion, oxidized group-IV-terminated diamond surfaces offer enhanced stability compared to H-terminated surfaces and display unique structural and electronic properties that are influenced by surface bonding.</description>
      <author>Hector Gomez, James Cruz, Cody Milne, Topojit Debnath, A. Glen Birdwell, Elias Garratt, Bradford B. Pate, S. Rudin, Dmitry Ruzmetov, James Weil, Pankaj B. Shah, Tony Ivanov, Roger K. Lake, Michael N. Groves, Mahesh R. Neupane</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0203185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;dxtb&lt;/i&gt;&#8212;An efficient and fully differentiable framework for extended tight-binding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0216715</link>
      <description>Marvin Friede, Christian H&#246;lzer, Sebastian Ehlert, Stefan Grimme, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401463809

                Automatic differentiation (AD) emerged as an integral part of machine learning, accelerating model development by enabling gradient-based optimization without explicit analytical derivatives. Recently, the benefits of AD and computing arbitrary-order derivatives with respect to any variable were also recognized in the field of quantum chemistry. In this work, we present dxtb&#8212;an open-source, fully differentiable framework for semiempirical extended tight-binding (xTB) methods. Developed entirely in Python and leveraging PyTorch for array operations, dxtb facilitates extensibility and rapid prototyping while maintaining computational efficiency. Through comprehensive code vectorization and optimization, we essentially reach the speed of compiled xTB programs for high-throughput calculations of small molecules. The excellent performance also scales to large systems, and batch operability yields additional benefits for execution on parallel hardware. In particular, energy evaluations are on par with existing programs, whereas the speed of automatically differentiated nuclear derivatives is only 2 to 5 times slower compared to their analytical counterparts. We showcase the utility of AD in dxtb by calculating various molecular and spectroscopic properties, highlighting its capacity to enhance and simplify such evaluations. Furthermore, the framework streamlines optimization tasks and offers seamless integration of semiempirical quantum chemistry in machine learning, paving the way for physics-inspired end-to-end differentiable models. Ultimately, dxtb aims to further advance the capabilities of semiempirical methods, providing an extensible foundation for future developments and hybrid machine learning applications. The framework is accessible at https://github.com/grimme-lab/dxtb.</description>
      <author>Marvin Friede, Christian H&#246;lzer, Sebastian Ehlert, Stefan Grimme</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0216715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First principles study for Ag-based core-shell nanoclusters with 3d-5d transition metal cores for the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2024.122301</link>
      <description>Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Peter L. Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Kessler, Fabi&#225;n Ambriz-Vargas, R.G. Garza, Rub&#237; Res&#233;ndiz-Ram&#237;rez, Jos&#233; Luis Mart&#237;nez Flores, Alfredo Ben&#237;tez Lara, M.A. Mart&#237;nez-Gamez, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro, Inorganica Chimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401474651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Peter L. Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Kessler, Fabi&#225;n Ambriz-Vargas, R.G. Garza, Rub&#237; Res&#233;ndiz-Ram&#237;rez, Jos&#233; Luis Mart&#237;nez Flores, Alfredo Ben&#237;tez Lara, M.A. Mart&#237;nez-Gamez, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2024.122301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atomic Fe-dispersed hollow carbon spheres coated with Co3O4 synergistically catalyze oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144871</link>
      <description>Zhuang Shi, Wei Yan, Feng Hao, Hao Song, Zhen Fu, Hongyan Zhuo, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401474676

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuang Shi, Wei Yan, Feng Hao, Hao Song, Zhen Fu, Hongyan Zhuo, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144871</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling relations and dynamical predictiveness of electric dipole strength on 2e- ORR catalytic property</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115699</link>
      <description>Wei Zhang, Zhaofei Chu, Yin-xiao Sheng, Fu-li Sun, Wen&#8208;Xian Chen, Gui&#8208;Lin Zhuang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401474867

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Zhang, Zhaofei Chu, Yin-xiao Sheng, Fu-li Sun, Wen&#8208;Xian Chen, Gui&#8208;Lin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115699</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Atomic Structure of Ruthenium Deposited on Pt/C Cathode Catalysts to Enhance Durability of Automotive Fuel Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124486</link>
      <description>Sang&#8208;Hoon You, Wooseok Lee, Ho Yeon Jang, Kyu&#8208;Su Kim, Jong&#8208;Beom Baek, Gogwon Choe, Sang Gu Ji, Vinod K. Paidi, Chang Hyuck Choi, Seoin Back, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401475021

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sang&#8208;Hoon You, Wooseok Lee, Ho Yeon Jang, Kyu&#8208;Su Kim, Jong&#8208;Beom Baek, Gogwon Choe, Sang Gu Ji, Vinod K. Paidi, Chang Hyuck Choi, Seoin Back, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reaction Kinetics at Constant Interfacial Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04034</link>
      <description>Huan Li, Dong Luan, Jun Long, Pu Guo, Jianping Xiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Li, Dong Luan, Jun Long, Pu Guo, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal-neural-network-potential molecular dynamics for lithium metal and garnet-type solid electrolyte interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43246-024-00595-0</link>
      <description>Rinon Iwasaki, Naoto Tanibata, Hayami Takeda, Masanobu Nakayama, Communications Materials. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401483015

                Abstract All-solid-state Li-metal batteries can conceivably improve the safety and extend the driving ranges of electric vehicles. In this regard, the garnet-type solid electrolyte Li 7 La 3 Zr 2 O 12 (LLZ) has garnered considerable attention because of its high Li-ion conductivity and nonreactivity towards molten Li metal. Here, we perform molecular dynamics (MD) simulations using a universal neural network potential (UNNP) to analyse the Li-ion exchange at the LLZ/Li interface at the atomic scale. The UNNP-MD calculations show that Li ions traverse the LLZ/Li interface and that excess Li ions relative to the stoichiometric composition accumulate in an approximately 1 nm-thick zone near the LLZ phase interface, signifying the formation of a space-charge layer. Electronic structural analysis of the UNNP-MD-derived configuration, performed using density functional theory calculations, reveals band bending near the LLZ phase interface and the simultaneous suppression of Li metal reduction. These findings can help expedite the development of rationally designed all-solid-state Li-metal batteries.</description>
      <author>Rinon Iwasaki, Naoto Tanibata, Hayami Takeda, Masanobu Nakayama</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43246-024-00595-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binary ruthenium dioxide and nickel oxide ultrafine particles loaded on carbon nanotubes for high-stability oxygen evolution reaction at high current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.047</link>
      <description>Chen Yang, Qing Zhang, Ting Li, Xiaohong Chen, Xiao Lin Li, Hong Qun Luo, Nian Bing Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401487165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Yang, Qing Zhang, Ting Li, Xiaohong Chen, Xiao Lin Li, Hong Qun Luo, Nian Bing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N&#8208;Doped Carbon Modified (Ni&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;1&#8208;x&lt;/sub&gt;)Se Supported on Vertical Graphene toward Efficient and Stable OER Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404545</link>
      <description>Beirong Ye, Yue&#8208;Fei Zhang, Chen Li, Shouxin Zhang, Yongqi Li, Ting Li, Fengyu Huang, Chong Tang, Renhong Chen, Tao Tang, Abolhassan Noori, Liujiang Zhou, Xinhui Xia, Mir F. Mousavi, Yongqi Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401490730

                Abstract NiFe&#8208;based nanomaterials are extensively studied as one of the promising candidates for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, their practical application is still largely impeded by the unsatisfied activity and poor durability caused by the severe leaching of active species. Herein, a rapid and facile combustion method is developed to synthesize the vertical graphene (VG) supported N&#8208;doped carbon modified (Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x )Se composites (NC@(Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x )Se/VG). The interconnected heterostructure of obtained materials plays a vital role in boosting the catalytic performance, offering rich active sites and convenient pathways for rapid electron and ion transport. The incorporation of Se into NiFe facilitates the formation of active species via in situ surface reconstruction. According to density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the in situ formation of a Ni 0.75 Fe 0.25 Se/Ni 0.75 Fe 0.25 OOH layer significantly enhances the catalytic activity of NC@(Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x )Se/VG. Furthermore, the surface&#8208;adsorbed selenoxide species contribute to the stabilization of the catalytic active phase and increase the overall stability. The obtained NC@(Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x )Se/VG exhibits a low overpotential of 220 mV at 20 mA cm &#8722;2 and long&#8208;term stability over 300 h. This work offers a novel perspective on the design and fabrication of OER electrocatalysts with high activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Beirong Ye, Yue&#8208;Fei Zhang, Chen Li, Shouxin Zhang, Yongqi Li, Ting Li, Fengyu Huang, Chong Tang, Renhong Chen, Tao Tang, Abolhassan Noori, Liujiang Zhou, Xinhui Xia, Mir F. Mousavi, Yongqi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superaerophobic Ni3N/Ni@W2N3 multi-heterointerfacial nanoarrays for efficient alkaline electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154776</link>
      <description>Haidong Wang, Yongxin Jiao, Guanghui Zhang, Zexi Zhang, Weiguang Ma, Chenghua Sun, Xu Zong, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401494305

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haidong Wang, Yongxin Jiao, Guanghui Zhang, Zexi Zhang, Weiguang Ma, Chenghua Sun, Xu Zong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modification of metals and ligands in two-dimensional conjugated metal-organic frameworks for CO2 electroreduction: A combined density functional theory and machine learning study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.069</link>
      <description>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Guang&#8208;Yan Sun, Jing-yao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401496468

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Guang&#8208;Yan Sun, Jing-yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and application of single-atom nanozymes in oncology: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1442689</link>
      <description>Huiyuan Liang, Yubin Xian, Xujing Wang, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401499087

                Single-atom nanozymes (SAzymes) represent a cutting-edge advancement in nanomaterials, merging the high catalytic efficiency of natural enzymes with the benefits of atomic economy. Traditionally, natural enzymes exhibit high specificity and efficiency, but their stability are limited by environmental conditions and production costs. Here we show that SAzymes, with their large specific surface area and high atomic utilization, achieve superior catalytic activity. However, their high dispersibility poses stability challenges. Our review focuses on recent structural and preparative advancements aimed at enhancing the catalytic specificity and stability of SAzymes. Compared to previous nanozymes, SAzymes demonstrate significantly improved performance in biomedical applications, particularly in tumor medicine. This progress positions SAzymes as a promising tool for future cancer treatment strategies, integrating the robustness of inorganic materials with the specificity of biological systems. The development and application of SAzymes could revolutionize the field of biocatalysis, offering a stable, cost-effective alternative to natural enzymes.</description>
      <author>Huiyuan Liang, Yubin Xian, Xujing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1442689</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles data for solid solution niobium-tantalum-vanadium alloys with body-centered-cubic structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-qpwsg-v2</link>
      <description>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, German D. Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Jong Youl Choi, Junqi Yin, Ying Yang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401335548

                We present four open-source datasets that provide results of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of ground-state properties of refractory solid solution binary alloys niobium-tantalum (NbTa), niobium-vanadium (NbV), tantalum-vanadium (TaV), and ternary alloys NbTaV ordered in body-centered-cubic (BCC) structures with 128 Bravais lattice sites. The first-principles code used to run the calculations is the Vienna Ab-Initio Simulation Package. The calculations have been collected by uniformly sampling chemical compositions across the entire compositional range. For each chemical composition, the calculations have been run for 100 randomized arrangements of the constituents on the BCC lattice sites. This sampling methodology resulted in running DFT simulations for a total of 3,100 randomized atomic configurations over 31 chemical compositions for each of the three binary alloys Nb-Ta, Nb-V, Ta-V, and a total of 10,500 randomized atomic structures over 105 chemical compositions for the ternary alloys Nb-Ta-V. For each atomic configuration, geometry optimization has been performed, and the data released contains information about each step of geometry optimization for each atomic configuration.</description>
      <author>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, German D. Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Jong Youl Choi, Junqi Yin, Ying Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-qpwsg-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially Resolved Uncertainties for Machine Learning Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00904</link>
      <description>Esther Heid, Johannes Sch&#246;rghuber, Ralf Wanzenb&#246;ck, Georg K. H. Madsen, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401386355

                Machine learning potentials have become an essential tool for atomistic simulations, yielding results close to ab initio simulations at a fraction of computational cost. With recent improvements on the achievable accuracies, the focus has now shifted on the data set composition itself. The reliable identification of erroneously predicted configurations to extend a given data set is therefore of high priority. Yet, uncertainty estimation techniques have achieved mixed results for machine learning potentials. Consequently, a general and versatile method to correlate energy or atomic force uncertainties with the model error has remained elusive to date. In the current work, we show that epistemic uncertainty cannot correlate with model error by definition but can be aggregated over groups of atoms to yield a strong correlation. We demonstrate that our method correctly estimates prediction errors both globally per structure and locally resolved per atom. The direct correlation of local uncertainty and local error is used to design an active learning framework based on identifying local subregions of a large simulation cell and performing ab initio calculations only for the subregion subsequently. We successfully utilized this method to perform active learning in the low-data regime for liquid water.</description>
      <author>Esther Heid, Johannes Sch&#246;rghuber, Ralf Wanzenb&#246;ck, Georg K. H. Madsen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00904</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Tuning Decision Trees in Random Forest Regression on Predicting Porosity of a Hydrocarbon Reservoir. Case Study: Volve Oil Field, North Sea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00313f</link>
      <description>Kushan Sandunil, Ziad Bennour, Hisham Ben Mahmud, Ausama Giwelli, Energy Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401432831

                Machine learning (ML) has emerged as a powerful tool in petroleum engineering for predicting reservoir properties such as porosity. Random forest regression (RFR) is one such widely used ML technique....</description>
      <author>Kushan Sandunil, Ziad Bennour, Hisham Ben Mahmud, Ausama Giwelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00313f</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
