<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 01:19:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study of oxygen reduction reaction activity and stability on Mn-Ni dual-atom electrocatalysts anchored at graphene edges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162495</link>
      <description>Faizal Helmi, Muhammad Hakim, Ahmad Nuruddin, Nadya Amalia, Sasfan Arman Wella, Hamad AlMohamadi, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faizal Helmi, Muhammad Hakim, Ahmad Nuruddin, Nadya Amalia, Sasfan Arman Wella, Hamad AlMohamadi, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GC-DFT simulation of coverage and potential effect for oxygen evolution reaction on RuO2-based electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</link>
      <description>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon Hybridization in Rotation Bimetallic-Chain System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07988</link>
      <description>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yongqi Chen, Yurui Fang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406743596

                Plasmon hybridization phenomena in metallic chain heterodimers represent a frontier in nanoscale optoelectronic research, offering insights into the quantum mechanisms that govern their behavior. Utilizing first-principles-based computational methods, we conduct a systematic study into the dimer configurations formed by Na8 and Mg8 chains, encompassing Na8 homodimer, Mg8 homodimer, and Na8Mg8 heterodimer. The study reveals that with the variation of bichain rotation angles, the plasmonic resonance modes within the dimers undergo significant hybridization, resulting in the emergence of new split peaks at the lower-energy range due to hybridization of the longitude mode and the transverse mode in the middle of the chain induced by it. At the high-energy range, the longitude multipole mode on the other chain is induced by the transverse center, and the interaction results in the splitting and appearance of hidden modes as the rotation angle increases. Both the excitation in the orthogonal direction and the electromagnetic field enhancement effects confirm the hybridization, which also provides the tenability of the plasmon resonance. This research provides a new theoretical perspective for understanding plasmonic hybridization phenomena at the nanoscale and offers important theoretical guidance for designing novel optoelectronic devices based on molecular plasmonics.</description>
      <author>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yongqi Chen, Yurui Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Regulation of High-Entropy Perovskite Oxides through Hole Doping for Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20338</link>
      <description>Gaoliang Fu, Ruipeng Hou, Li Sun, Huili Liu, Yaru Wei, Ruixue Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Shouren Zhang, Baocheng Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406747925

                Due to the high configuration entropy, unique atomic arrangement, and electronic structures, high-entropy materials are being actively pursued as bifunctional catalysts for both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in rechargeable zinc-air batteries (ZABs). However, a relevant strategy to enhance the catalytic activity of high-entropy materials is still lacking. Herein, a hole doping strategy has been employed to enable the high-entropy perovskite La(Cr0.2Mn0.2Fe0.2Co0.2Ni0.2)O3 to effectively catalyze the ORR and OER. Hole doping experiments rely on the substitution of Sr2+ for La3+. The optimized La0.7Sr0.3(Cr0.2Mn0.2Fe0.2Co0.2Ni0.2)O3 displays remarkable activity for the ORR and the OER, with a low potential difference of 0.880 V between the half-wave potential of the ORR and the OER potential at 10 mA cm-2, exceeding the majority of perovskite bifunctional catalysts. Further analysis of the electronic structures reveals that hole doping could regulate the eg-orbital filling of the transition-metal cations in high-entropy perovskites to an ideal position and thereby generate many highly active sites to promote the redox activity of oxygen. The assembled rechargeable ZAB with the targeted high-entropy perovskite as the cathode affords a specific capacity of 774.5 mAh gZn-1 under 10 mA cm-2 and durability for a period of 300 cycles, comparable to that of the 20%Pt/C + RuO2 ZAB. This work offers an important approach for the advancement of efficient high-entropy perovskites for ZABs.</description>
      <author>Gaoliang Fu, Ruipeng Hou, Li Sun, Huili Liu, Yaru Wei, Ruixue Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Shouren Zhang, Baocheng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening of multifunctional single-atom catalysts supported by VS2 monolayer for the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115098</link>
      <description>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406748597

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct free energy calculation from &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; path integral Monte Carlo simulations of warm dense matter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.l041114</link>
      <description>Tobias Dornheim, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Sebastian Schwalbe, Jan Vorberger, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406759192

                We carry out highly accurate path integral Monte Carlo simulations to directly estimate the free energy of various warm dense matter systems including the uniform electron gas and hydrogen without any nodal restrictions or other approximations. Since our approach is based on an effective ensemble in a bosonic configuration space, it does not increase the computational complexity beyond the usual fermion sign problem. Its application to inhomogeneous cases such as an electronic system in a fixed external ion potential is straightforward and opens up the enticing possibility to benchmark density functional theory and other existing methods. Finally, it is not limited to warm dense matter and can be applied to a gamut of other systems such as ultracold atoms and electrons in quantum dots. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>Tobias Dornheim, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Sebastian Schwalbe, Jan Vorberger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.l041114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening and research of nitrogen reduction on 2D metal&#8211;organic framework: First-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221872</link>
      <description>Zheng-Yun Xiong, Wen-qing Hong, Yu&#8208;Qing Zhao, Wen-Jin Yin, Ying Xu, Applied Physics Letters. 126(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406762355

                Developing efficient nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) catalysts remains challenging. Two-dimensional metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) stand out because of their large holes and high metal utilization. Based on first-principles high-throughput calculations, we studied the catalytic capacity of MOF catalyst TM3 (HITP)2 for NRR. Our calculated results indicate that among 29 catalytic structures, Mo3(HITP)2 and Os3(HITP)2 exhibit excellent activity for NRR, with the overpotential being 0.39 and 0.43 V, respectively. The unoccupied 4d orbitals of Mo are especially closer to the antibonding N-2p orbitals, leading to better nitrogen activation and lower overpotential. In addition, a descriptor related to charge variation and the electronegativity of metals and coordinating atoms is established, which has a good volcano plot relationship with the limiting potential of NRR and can provide ideas for catalyst screening. This research contributes valuable insights for the screening of NRR catalysts based on MOF.</description>
      <author>Zheng-Yun Xiong, Wen-qing Hong, Yu&#8208;Qing Zhao, Wen-Jin Yin, Ying Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author-Centric Pattern Detection in Scopus Citation Network via Community Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-7839-3_1</link>
      <description>R. Kiruthika, N. Radha, Lecture notes in networks and systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406772073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Kiruthika, N. Radha</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-7839-3_1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of Schottky Barrier Height and Electronic Structure in Transition-Metal@Nitrogen-Doped-Carbon Core&#8211;Shell Cocatalysts Loaded with Mn&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;S Nanorods for Enhanced Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06476</link>
      <description>Yufeng Li, Songqing Zhang, Chunmei He, Hongxia Yao, Changfa Guo, Wentao Wang, Yong Hu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406786311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yufeng Li, Songqing Zhang, Chunmei He, Hongxia Yao, Changfa Guo, Wentao Wang, Yong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applications of density functional theory to corrosion and corrosion prevention of metals: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.83</link>
      <description>Dihao Chen, Wenjie Zhou, Yucheng Ji, Dihao Chen, Materials Genome Engineering Advances. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406786726

                Abstract Recently, density functional theory (DFT) has been a powerful tool to model the corrosion behaviors of materials, provide insights into the corrosion mechanisms, predict the corrosion performance of materials, and design the corrosion&#8208;resistant alloys and organic inhibitors. DFT enables corrosion scientist to fundamentally understand the corrosion behaviors and corrosion mechanisms of materials from the perspective of atomic and electronic structures, combining with the traditional and advanced experimental tests. This review briefly summarizes the main features of DFT calculations and present a comprehensive overview of their typical applications to corrosion and corrosion prevention of metals, involving potential&#8208;pH diagrams, hydrogen evolution reaction, anodic dissolution, passivity and passivity breakdown, and organic inhibitor for metals. The paper also reviews the correlations between DFT&#8208;computed descriptors and the micro/macro physiochemical parameters of corrosion. Despite the great progress achieved by DFT, there are still some challenges in addressing corrosion issues due to the lack of bridges between the DFT&#8208;calculated electronic parameters and the macro corrosion performance of materials. The DFT modeling&#8208;experiment&#8208;engineering&#8208;theory model will be a potential method to clarify and build the links.</description>
      <author>Dihao Chen, Wenjie Zhou, Yucheng Ji, Dihao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.83</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of two critical operating factors on the enhanced catalytic conversion of aqueous NO3&#8211; to NH4+ by Pt-Co@NC and theoretical verification of its surface reaction mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159874</link>
      <description>Nurbek Nurlan, Jaewoo Jeong, Meiirzhan Nurmyrza, Hyungjun Kim, Hye&#8208;Young Shin, Woojin Lee, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406788037

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nurbek Nurlan, Jaewoo Jeong, Meiirzhan Nurmyrza, Hyungjun Kim, Hye&#8208;Young Shin, Woojin Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the structure-activity relationship of phosphorus-doped Fe-Cu@NC catalysts: Exploring the influence of different coordination layers on oxygen reduction reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236302</link>
      <description>Youzheng Wu, Penghui Ren, Ruopeng Li, Xun Zheng, Changning Bai, Yidi Liu, Meng Fan, Xuesong Peng, Lihui Xiao, Anmin Liu, Hao Xu, Dan Wang, Jinqiu Zhang, Maozhong An, Shizheng Wen, Yaqiang Li, Peixia Yang, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406791942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youzheng Wu, Penghui Ren, Ruopeng Li, Xun Zheng, Changning Bai, Yidi Liu, Meng Fan, Xuesong Peng, Lihui Xiao, Anmin Liu, Hao Xu, Dan Wang, Jinqiu Zhang, Maozhong An, Shizheng Wen, Yaqiang Li, Peixia Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the frontiers of electrocatalysis: advanced theoretical methods for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s40580-024-00467-w</link>
      <description>Seong Chan Cho, Jun Ho Seok, Hung Ngo Manh, Jae Hun Seol, Chi H. Lee, Sang Uck Lee, Nano Convergence. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406793010

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting, which encompasses the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), offers a promising route for sustainable hydrogen production. The development of efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts is crucial for advancing this technology, especially given the reliance on expensive transition metals, such as Pt and Ir, in traditional catalysts. This review highlights recent advances in the design and optimization of electrocatalysts, focusing on density functional theory (DFT) as a key tool for understanding and improving catalytic performance in the HER and OER. We begin by exploring DFT-based approaches for evaluating catalytic activity under both acidic and alkaline conditions. The review then shifts to a material-oriented perspective, showcasing key catalyst materials and the theoretical strategies employed to enhance their performance. In addition, we discuss scaling relationships that exist between binding energies and electronic structures through the use of charge-density analysis and d -band theory. Advanced concepts, such as the effects of adsorbate coverage, solvation, and applied potential on catalytic behavior, are also discussed. We finally focus on integrating machine learning (ML) with DFT to enable high-throughput screening and accelerate the discovery of novel water-splitting catalysts. This comprehensive review underscores the pivotal role that DFT plays in advancing electrocatalyst design and highlights its potential for shaping the future of sustainable hydrogen production. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Seong Chan Cho, Jun Ho Seok, Hung Ngo Manh, Jae Hun Seol, Chi H. Lee, Sang Uck Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s40580-024-00467-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating alloy design and discovery with physics-aware multimodal multiagent AI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2414074122</link>
      <description>Alireza Ghafarollahi, Markus J. Buehler, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406794696

                The design of new alloys is a multiscale problem that requires a holistic approach that involves retrieving relevant knowledge, applying advanced computational methods, conducting experimental validations, and analyzing the results, a process that is typically slow and reserved for human experts. Machine learning can help accelerate this process, for instance, through the use of deep surrogate models that connect structural and chemical features to material properties, or vice versa. However, existing data-driven models often target specific material objectives, offering limited flexibility to integrate out-of-domain knowledge and cannot adapt to new, unforeseen challenges. Here, we overcome these limitations by leveraging the distinct capabilities of multiple AI agents that collaborate autonomously within a dynamic environment to solve complex materials design tasks. The proposed physics-aware generative AI platform, AtomAgents, synergizes the intelligence of large language models (LLMs) and the dynamic collaboration among AI agents with expertise in various domains, including knowledge retrieval, multimodal data integration, physics-based simulations, and comprehensive results analysis across modalities. The concerted effort of the multiagent system allows for addressing complex materials design problems, as demonstrated by examples that include autonomously designing metallic alloys with enhanced properties compared to their pure counterparts. Our results enable accurate prediction of key characteristics across alloys and highlight the crucial role of solid solution alloying to steer the development of advanced metallic alloys. Our framework enhances the efficiency of complex multiobjective design tasks and opens avenues in fields such as biomedical materials engineering, renewable energy, and environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Alireza Ghafarollahi, Markus J. Buehler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2414074122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt-MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Hybrid Electrocatalysts Modulating Local Environment for Enhanced Activity toward Hydrogen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c02409</link>
      <description>Jueun Koh, Sohee Kim, Gyeonghye Yim, Ji&#8211;Hun Yu, Jaehwan Kim, Sang Hoon Joo, Hongje Jang, Young Jin, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406795838

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jueun Koh, Sohee Kim, Gyeonghye Yim, Ji&#8211;Hun Yu, Jaehwan Kim, Sang Hoon Joo, Hongje Jang, Young Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c02409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte effects on reaction kinetics in electrochemical CO2 reduction: The roles of pH, cations, and anions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242304</link>
      <description>Wei Chen, Xinjuan Du, Shuaikang Tao, Bo Lin, Ionu&#355; Tranca, Frederik Tielens, Ming Ma, Zhaochun Liu, Chemical Physics Reviews. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406800318

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) holds significant potential for converting CO2 into value-added fuels and chemicals under mild reaction conditions. The kinetics of CO2RR is strongly influenced by both the electrocatalysts and the local environment at the electrode/electrolyte interface. While considerable research has focused on elucidating the &#8220;structure-activity&#8221; relationships of electrocatalysts, a fundamental understanding of the role of electrolyte-related factors (such as the ionic species) near the electrode/electrolyte interface is highly important for the further enhancement in the catalytic performance of CO2RR. In this review, we discuss the effects of pH, cations, and anions in the vicinity of the catalyst, using CO2RR as a model reaction. The mechanistic understanding of these effects is also analyzed via experimental findings from in situ spectroscopic techniques and theoretical insights from density functional theory simulations. This review underscores the importance of understanding the various interactions of electrolytes with catalyst surfaces or intermediates and their impact on reaction kinetics of CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Wei Chen, Xinjuan Du, Shuaikang Tao, Bo Lin, Ionu&#355; Tranca, Frederik Tielens, Ming Ma, Zhaochun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-Fe dual-atom anchored g-C3N5 for photocatalytic overall water splitting: Fe-driven Ni-N dual sites synergy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.301</link>
      <description>Tao Ma, Xin Wang, Jiehang Wei, Hongqiang Xia, Ying-Tao Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 105(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406804136

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Ma, Xin Wang, Jiehang Wei, Hongqiang Xia, Ying-Tao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating SnSx species for electroreduction of CO2 towards formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162486</link>
      <description>Yi&#8208;Bing Yang, Xiao Yang, Shuwen Zhao, Zhipeng Liu, Yi Xiao, Lili Han, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406817545

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi&#8208;Bing Yang, Xiao Yang, Shuwen Zhao, Zhipeng Liu, Yi Xiao, Lili Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qcforever2: Advanced Automation of Quantum Chemistry Computations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70017</link>
      <description>Masato Sumita, Kei Terayama, Shoichi Ishida, K. SUGA, Shohei Saito, Koji Tsuda, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406823375

                ABSTRACT QCforever is a wrapper designed to automatically and simultaneously calculate various physical quantities using quantum chemical (QC) calculation software for blackbox optimization in chemical space. We have updated it to QCforever2 to search the conformation and optimize density functional parameters for a more accurate and reliable evaluation of an input molecule. In blackbox optimization, QCforever2 can work as compactly arranged surrogate models for costly chemical experiments. QCforever2 is the future of QC calculations and would be a good companion for chemical laboratories, providing more reliable search and exploitation in the chemical space.</description>
      <author>Masato Sumita, Kei Terayama, Shoichi Ishida, K. SUGA, Shohei Saito, Koji Tsuda</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-doping strategy for perovskite anodes towards high-performance ammonia-fueled SOFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236320</link>
      <description>Or Rahumi, Yuliy Yuferov, Louisa Meshi, Nitzan Maman, Konstantin Borodianskiy, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406828837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Or Rahumi, Yuliy Yuferov, Louisa Meshi, Nitzan Maman, Konstantin Borodianskiy</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural-property relationships of phenyl-based multifunctional hybrid ligand 2D MOFs (Ni-XnY4-n, where X, Y = NH, O, S): A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162541</link>
      <description>Jingyuan Zhou, Wen Zhao, Mingxiang Zhang, A. M. Zhang, Hao Ren, Houyu Zhu, Yuhua Chi, Wenyue Guo, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406829098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingyuan Zhou, Wen Zhao, Mingxiang Zhang, A. M. Zhang, Hao Ren, Houyu Zhu, Yuhua Chi, Wenyue Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can phosphides catalyze CO2 reduction reaction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.145755</link>
      <description>Naveed Ashraf, Diego Bitzenhofer Betolaza, H&#225;lfd&#225;n Ingi Gunnarsson, Mohammad Khatibi, Atef Iqbal, Younes Abghoui, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406829230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naveed Ashraf, Diego Bitzenhofer Betolaza, H&#225;lfd&#225;n Ingi Gunnarsson, Mohammad Khatibi, Atef Iqbal, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.145755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-doping-induced electron spin polarization activates scandium oxide as high-performance zinc-air battery cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.223</link>
      <description>Yuhui Chen, Chang Ming Li, Yiqing Chen, Ying Cheng, Xinxin Tian, Dongdong Xiao, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Linjie Zhang, Wenlie Lin, Jun Luo, Lili Han, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406834376

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhui Chen, Chang Ming Li, Yiqing Chen, Ying Cheng, Xinxin Tian, Dongdong Xiao, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Linjie Zhang, Wenlie Lin, Jun Luo, Lili Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic CO&#8722;O coupling on high-entropy alloys: A composition optimization dependent on the reaction assumptions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115983</link>
      <description>Jack K. Pedersen, Giona Mainardis, Jan Rossmeisl, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406849265

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jack K. Pedersen, Giona Mainardis, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Visualization of Temperature&#8208;Induced Phase Separation of Completely Miscible Au&#9472;Pd Alloy by In Situ TEM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408109</link>
      <description>Abhijit Roy, Simon Hettler, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406849888

                Abstract In situ transmission electron microscopy (TEM) studies reveal key insights into the structural and chemical evolution of nanoparticles (NPs) under external stimuli like heating and biasing, which is critical for evaluating their suitability in chemical reactions and their tendency toward forming novel NP systems. In this study, starting from a core@shell Au nanotriangle (AuNT)@Pd nanostructure, the formation of a phase&#8208;separated bi&#8208;metallic Au&#9472;Pd NP system at high temperature is reported, despite the fact that Au and Pd are miscible in the entire composition and temperature range. In situ TEM heating of bare AuNT@Pd core@shell structures up to 1000 &#176;C is performed. Between 400 and 800 &#176;C, an initial alloy formation is observed. Notably, higher initial loading of Pd increases the melting temperature of the bi&#8208;metallic system. However, the most important observation is the separation of the nanostructure into Au and Pd phases at temperatures above 850 &#176;C for high Pd doping. The extent of Pd separation depends on the amount of initial Pd loading. A Janus Au&#9472;Pd nanostructure is formed at the end of the thermal treatments at 1000 &#176;C. The phase&#8208;separated NP is observed to be highly stable and could be clearly beneficial for various applications, particularly in catalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Abhijit Roy, Simon Hettler, Ra&#250;l Arenal</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of strain on the nitrogen-doped graphene nanoribbons for boosting oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162538</link>
      <description>Yanan Tang, Weiguang Chen, Jinlei Shi, Mingyu Zhao, Yi Li, Zhiwen Wang, Zhen Feng, Dongwei Ma, Xianqi Dai, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406852876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Tang, Weiguang Chen, Jinlei Shi, Mingyu Zhao, Yi Li, Zhiwen Wang, Zhen Feng, Dongwei Ma, Xianqi Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162538</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the use of clustering workflows for automated microstructure segmentation of analytical STEM datasets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0246329</link>
      <description>Zhiquan Kho, Andy Bridger, Keith T. Butler, Ercin C. Duran, Mohsen Danaie, Alexander S. Eggeman, APL Materials. 13(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406854538

                This study considers the issue of automated segmentation of scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM) datasets using unsupervised machine learning approaches. To this end, a systematic comparison of two clustering workflows that had been established in previous literature was performed on two distinct material systems&#8212;an experimentally acquired Co2FeSi Heusler alloy and a simulated Au-matrix and Al2Cu precipitate. The cluster outputs were evaluated using a variety of unsupervised clustering metrics measuring separation and cohesion. It was found that the cluster output of a variational autoencoder (VAE) performed better compared to a more conventional latent transformation via Uniform Manifold Approximation &amp; Projection (UMAP) on 4D-STEM data alone. However, the UMAP workflow applied to merged 4D-STEM and STEM-energy dispersive x-ray (STEM-EDX) data produced the best cluster output overall, indicating that the correlated information provides beneficial constraints to the latent space. A potential general workflow for analyzing merged datasets to identify structural-composition changes across different material systems is proposed.</description>
      <author>Zhiquan Kho, Andy Bridger, Keith T. Butler, Ercin C. Duran, Mohsen Danaie, Alexander S. Eggeman</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0246329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biochar-anchored PtPd bimetallic nanoparticle catalyst for high-efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06091-w</link>
      <description>Yuanmeng Wang, Fan Yang, Xinyu Zhu, Yidi Zhou, Wenhao Peng, Yu Tang, Shaorou Ke, Bozhi Yang, Shujie Yang, Xiaowen Wu, Yangai Liu, Ruiyu Mi, Zhaohui Huang, Xin Min, Minghao Fang, Ionics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406854635

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanmeng Wang, Fan Yang, Xinyu Zhu, Yidi Zhou, Wenhao Peng, Yu Tang, Shaorou Ke, Bozhi Yang, Shujie Yang, Xiaowen Wu, Yangai Liu, Ruiyu Mi, Zhaohui Huang, Xin Min, Minghao Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06091-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Segregation, Water Layering, and Proton Transfer at Zirconium Oxynitride/Water Interface Examined Using Neural Network Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05857</link>
      <description>Akitaka Nakanishi, Shusuke Kasamatsu, Jun Haruyama, Osamu Sugino, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406862521

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akitaka Nakanishi, Shusuke Kasamatsu, Jun Haruyama, Osamu Sugino</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; S induced catalyst contamination in polymer electrolyte fuel cells: performance degradation and regeneration with ozone</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00194506.2025.2453444</link>
      <description>Panchali Borthakur, Nand Kishor Gour, Saswati Sarmah, Ramesh C. Deka, Biraj Kumar Kakati, Indian Chemical Engineer. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406863202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Panchali Borthakur, Nand Kishor Gour, Saswati Sarmah, Ramesh C. Deka, Biraj Kumar Kakati</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00194506.2025.2453444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derivative-Free Domain-Informed Data-Driven Discovery of Sparse Kinetic Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02981</link>
      <description>Siddharth Prabhu, Nick Kosir, Mayuresh V. Kothare, Srinivas Rangarajan, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406867479

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siddharth Prabhu, Nick Kosir, Mayuresh V. Kothare, Srinivas Rangarajan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c02981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Citation Networks Using Community Detection Approaches: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-5200-3_13</link>
      <description>R. Kiruthika, N. Radha, Smart innovation, systems and technologies. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406867948

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Kiruthika, N. Radha</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-5200-3_13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning potential model for accelerating quantum chemistry&#8208;driven property prediction and molecular design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18741</link>
      <description>Guoxin Wu, Yujing Zhao, Lei Zhang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Qilei Liu, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406884476

                Abstract Quantum chemistry (QC) calculations have significantly advanced the development of materials, drugs, and other molecular products. Molecular geometry optimization is an indispensable step for QC calculations. However, its computational cost increases dramatically with increasing molecular system complexity, hindering the large&#8208;scale molecule screening. This work proposes a deep learning&#8208;based molecular potential energy surface prediction tool (DeePEST) to significantly accelerate geometry optimizations. The key of DeePEST involves the development of a novel machine learning potential model for accurate and fast predictions of molecular energy and atomic forces. These predictions enable efficient molecular geometry optimizations for subsequent predictions of QC properties (single&#8208;point energy, dipole moment, HOMO/LUMO, and 13 C chemical shifts) and COSMO&#8208;SAC&#8208;based thermodynamic properties (activity coefficient). Moreover, DeePEST facilitates efficient computer&#8208;aided molecular designs that involve QC&#8208;based geometry optimizations. The utilization of DeePEST in geometry optimizations achieves high prediction accuracy approaching to rigorous QC methods while maintaining the computational efficiency of molecular mechanics methods.</description>
      <author>Guoxin Wu, Yujing Zhao, Lei Zhang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Qilei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Spin-Polarized Electronic States of CBVN Defects in h-BN Monolayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssc.2025.115855</link>
      <description>B. Sarikavak-Li&#351;esivdin, Cagatay Ezen, S.B. Li&#351;esivdin, Solid State Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406893961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. Sarikavak-Li&#351;esivdin, Cagatay Ezen, S.B. Li&#351;esivdin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssc.2025.115855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly activated Phosphate-Derived oxyhydroxide overlayer for enhancing photoelectrochemical ammonia Oxidation-Boosted hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160053</link>
      <description>Phuong Pham, Jong&#8208;Hun Kim, Won Tae Hong, Hyungu Han, Seung Hun Roh, Xu Yu, Heeyeop Chae, Jongwook Park, Min Cheol Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jung Kyu Kim, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406899283

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Phuong Pham, Jong&#8208;Hun Kim, Won Tae Hong, Hyungu Han, Seung Hun Roh, Xu Yu, Heeyeop Chae, Jongwook Park, Min Cheol Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competitive strain modulation of oxygen reduction reaction in monolayer binary alloy surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115988</link>
      <description>Mailde S. Oz&#243;rio, Marcus Frahm Nygaard, Jan Rossmeisl, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406902130

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mailde S. Oz&#243;rio, Marcus Frahm Nygaard, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis: From Planar Surfaces to Nanostructured Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00133</link>
      <description>Alasdair Fairhurst, Joshua Snyder, Chao Wang, Du&#353;an Strm&#269;nik, Vojislav R. Stamenkovi&#263;, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406908727

                The reactions critical for the energy transition center on the chemistry of hydrogen, oxygen, carbon, and the heterogeneous catalyst surfaces that make up electrochemical energy conversion systems. Together, the surface-adsorbate interactions constitute the electrochemical interphase and define reaction kinetics of many clean energy technologies. Practical devices introduce high levels of complexity where surface roughness, structure, composition, and morphology combine with electrolyte, pH, diffusion, and system level limitations to challenge our ability to deconvolute underlying phenomena. To make significant strides in materials design, a structured approach based on well-defined surfaces is necessary to selectively control distinct parameters, while complexity is added sequentially through careful application of nanostructured surfaces. In this review, we cover advances made through this approach for key elements in the field, beginning with the simplest hydrogen oxidation and evolution reactions and concluding with more complex organic molecules. In each case, we offer a unique perspective on the contribution of well-defined systems to our understanding of electrochemical energy conversion technologies and how wider deployment can aid intelligent materials design.</description>
      <author>Alasdair Fairhurst, Joshua Snyder, Chao Wang, Du&#353;an Strm&#269;nik, Vojislav R. Stamenkovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoherence and vibrational energy relaxation of the electronically excited PtPOP complex in solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241573</link>
      <description>Benedikt O. Birgisson, Asmus Ougaard Dohn, Hannes J&#243;nsson, Gianluca Levi, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406916558

                Understanding the ultrafast vibrational relaxation following photoexcitation of molecules in a condensed phase is essential to predict the outcome and improve the efficiency of photoinduced molecular processes. Here, the vibrational decoherence and energy relaxation of a binuclear complex, [Pt2(P2O5H2)4]4&#8722; (PtPOP), upon electronic excitation in liquid water and acetonitrile are investigated through direct adiabatic dynamics simulations. A quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) scheme is used where the excited state of the complex is modeled with orbital-optimized density functional calculations while solvent molecules are described using potential energy functions. The decoherence time of the Pt&#8211;Pt vibration dominating the photoinduced dynamics is found to be &#8764;1.6 ps in both solvents. This is in excellent agreement with experimental measurements in water, where intersystem crossing is slow (&amp;gt;10 ps). Pathways for the flow of excess energy are identified by monitoring the power of the solvent on vibrational modes. The latter are obtained as generalized normal modes from the velocity covariances, and the power is computed using QM/MM embedding forces. Excess vibrational energy is found to be predominantly released through short-range repulsive and attractive interactions between the ligand atoms and surrounding solvent molecules, whereas solute&#8211;solvent interactions involving the Pt atoms are less important. Since photoexcitation deposits most of the excess energy into Pt&#8211;Pt vibrations, energy dissipation to the solvent is inefficient. This study reveals the mechanism behind the exceptionally long vibrational coherence of the photoexcited PtPOP complex in solution and underscores the importance of short-range interactions for accurate simulations of vibrational energy relaxation of solvated molecules.</description>
      <author>Benedikt O. Birgisson, Asmus Ougaard Dohn, Hannes J&#243;nsson, Gianluca Levi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct cathodic polarization preparation of ambient CO2-derived oxygen-functionalized carbons for electro-production of H2O2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125109</link>
      <description>Ao Yu, Jia Shi, Wenhao Yang, Guoming Ma, Qi Huang, Shengwen Liu, Haiyan Mao, Ping Peng, Yang Yang, Fangfang Li, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406917193

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ao Yu, Jia Shi, Wenhao Yang, Guoming Ma, Qi Huang, Shengwen Liu, Haiyan Mao, Ping Peng, Yang Yang, Fangfang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing hydrogen evolution by heterointerface engineering of Ni/MoN catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.201</link>
      <description>Junzheng Jiang, Yunfan Qiu, Dong Hao, Lei Yang, Yaping Miao, Liwei Xiong, Biao Gao, Xuming Zhang, Paul K. Chu, Xiang Peng, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406917241

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junzheng Jiang, Yunfan Qiu, Dong Hao, Lei Yang, Yaping Miao, Liwei Xiong, Biao Gao, Xuming Zhang, Paul K. Chu, Xiang Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inert Copper Incorporation Enables the High Activity and Durability of NiW Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202405127</link>
      <description>Guimei Liu, Yushen Liu, Xiaoyi Qiu, Bingxing Zhang, Juhee Jang, Yingdan Cui, Fei Xiao, Qinglan Zhao, Wenjun Wang, Yoonseob Kim, Wei Xing, Minhua Shao, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406917478

                Abstract The slow reaction kinetics of hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) on existing catalysts in alkaline hinders the commercialization of anion exchange membrane fuel cells (AEMFCs). In this work, a Cu&#8208;incorporated NiW alloy (Cu i &#8208;NiW) without any platinum group metal (PGM) is designed and evaluated in both liquid cells and AEMFCs. This catalyst enabled the achievement of an electrochemical surface area&#8208;normalized exchange current density of 70 &#181;A cm &#8722;2 and robust stability, outperforming most PGM&#8208;free catalysts. Furthermore, the incorporation of Cu into other systems such as NiMo and NiV using the same method also showcased excellent HOR activity and durability. The fuel cells assembled with Cu i &#8208;NiW as the anode and Pt/C or Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C as the cathode delivered peak power densities of 480 and 340 mW cm &#8722;2 , respectively. Experimental and theoretical studies reveal that the incorporated Cu is chemically inert but enhances the overall oxidation resistance of the catalysts. Moreover, it weakens hydrogen adsorption and promotes the adsorption of hydroxide ions, thereby enhancing the HOR activity significantly. These results may open a door for rational design of high&#8208;performance and durable PGM&#8208;free HOR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Guimei Liu, Yushen Liu, Xiaoyi Qiu, Bingxing Zhang, Juhee Jang, Yingdan Cui, Fei Xiao, Qinglan Zhao, Wenjun Wang, Yoonseob Kim, Wei Xing, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202405127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-resolved Brownian tomography of single nanocrystals in liquid during oxidative etching</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56476-8</link>
      <description>Sungsu Kang, Joodeok Kim, Sungin Kim, Hoje Chun, Junyoung Heo, Cyril F. Reboul, Rub&#233;n Meana&#8208;Pa&#241;eda, Cong T. S. Van, Hyesung Choi, Yunseo Lee, Jinho Rhee, Minyoung Lee, Dohun Kang, Byung Hyo Kim, Taeghwan Hyeon, Byungchan Han, Peter Ercius, Won Chul Lee, Hans Elmlund, Jungwon Park, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406923420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sungsu Kang, Joodeok Kim, Sungin Kim, Hoje Chun, Junyoung Heo, Cyril F. Reboul, Rub&#233;n Meana&#8208;Pa&#241;eda, Cong T. S. Van, Hyesung Choi, Yunseo Lee, Jinho Rhee, Minyoung Lee, Dohun Kang, Byung Hyo Kim, Taeghwan Hyeon, Byungchan Han, Peter Ercius, Won Chul Lee, Hans Elmlund, Jungwon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56476-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FINANCIAL, ECONOMIC AND ORGANIZATIONAL MECHANISMS FOR ENSURING THE IMPLEMENTATION OF INNOVATIVE TECHNOLOGIES FOR REDUCING CARBON EMISSIONS IN THE CONTEXT OF STRENGTHENING NATIONAL DEFENSE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37701/ts.05.2024.11</link>
      <description>Olena Lapko, O. B. &#1042;&#1072;&#1089;&#1102;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, H. V. Kramarev, O.O Akulshin, N. Pantielieieva, &#1042;&#1080;&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1073;&#1091;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1103; &#1090;&#1072; &#1089;&#1077;&#1088;&#1090;&#1080;&#1092;&#1110;&#1082;&#1072;&#1094;&#1110;&#1103;. None(3(5))] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406854459

                Sustainable economic development to improve the quality of life and ensure the reduction of carbon emissions to minimize the threats of climate change have become global trends of modern times and strategic priorities of almost all countries of the world, including Ukraine.The article substantiates the importance of adhering to the principles of sustainable development, attracting investment resources for these purposes, using new approaches to financial, economic and organizational mechanisms for the implementation of innovative technologies for reducing carbon emissions (CCS) in the context of ensuring the strengthening of national defense.The essence and features of the technological process for CCS are revealed, the scale of participation of countries of the world in CCS projects and the predicted dynamics of reducing CO2 emissions under their implementation are analyzed. The financial, economic and organizational mechanisms for ensuring the effective implementation of CCS projects are characterized, their structure is detailed. The regulatory policy and regulatory framework of various countries supporting the deployment of CCS technologies, the practice of governments using financial and economic mechanisms, as well as attracting private financing to support investments in CCS are summarized.The initiatives of the Government of Ukraine regarding energy efficiency and the implementation of innovative technologies to reduce carbon emissions are analyzed, recommendations are provided for the expansion of financial and economic mechanisms.A correlation is identified between the implementation of innovative technologies to reduce carbon emissions and the strengthening of national defense in such key aspects as energy security and defense capability, reducing environmental risks at military facilities, using defense infrastructure to implement environmentally friendly innovations, cooperation within the framework of financial, economic and organizational mechanisms for the implementation of innovative technologies, the social aspect and strategic sustainability.It is concluded that, based on the experience of foreign countries in implementing CCS technologies, Ukraine should take a balanced approach to the development and implementation of CCS projects, improving existing financial, economic and organizational mechanisms, using international support and technical assistance from partner countries. This will allow realizing the existing potential for implementing the Strategy for Low-Carbon Development of Ukraine until 2050. The post-war reconstruction of the Ukrainian economy based on the principles of sustainable development and the orientation towards the use of the most modern innovative technologies will allow significantly modernizing its production potential, strengthening energy independence and environmental sustainability, which, of course, will have a synergistic effect on strengthening national defense.</description>
      <author>Olena Lapko, O. B. &#1042;&#1072;&#1089;&#1102;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, H. V. Kramarev, O.O Akulshin, N. Pantielieieva</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37701/ts.05.2024.11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning-assisted design of novel metallic 2D C3N3 supported single/double atom catalysts for nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162451</link>
      <description>Haikuan Liang, Jiarui Wang, Zhengping Qiao, Yan Li, Chengxin Wang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406874071

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haikuan Liang, Jiarui Wang, Zhengping Qiao, Yan Li, Chengxin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O&#8208;Bridged Co&#8208;Cu Dual&#8208;Atom Catalyst Synergistically Triggers Interfacial Proton&#8208;Coupled Electron Transfer: A New Approach to Sustainable Decontamination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423509</link>
      <description>Qin Dai, Xin Li, Jieyuan Li, Qianqian Zhu, Guangfei Yu, Yanan Wang, Lei Xing, Jing Wang, Haijiao Lu, Jianhui Wang, Tianqi Zhang, Shuai Liu, Yanlin Jiao, Yuchen Li, Fan Dong, Lidong Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406919485

                Abstract Heteroatom&#8208;bridged dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs), featuring more flexible active sites and intermetallic interaction, provide an opportunity for sustainable environmental remediation. Herein, an innovative oxygen&#8208;bridged Co&#8208;Cu DAC supported on nano&#8208;alumina (CoOCu&#8208;DAC) is fabricated using a straightforward two&#8208;step process. The as&#8208;prepared catalyst significantly enhances both decontamination kinetics and peroxymonosulfate (PMS) utilization efficiency by 1&#8211;3 orders of magnitude toward monoethanolamine (MEA, p K a = 9.5) compared to Co single&#8208;atom catalyst (Co&#8208;SAC) and bulk metal catalysts, and largely outperforms previously reported systems. In&#8208;situ ATR&#8208;FTIR and theoretical investigations reveal that the secondary introduction of Cu plays multiple important roles: it activates lattice oxygen to trigger key proton transfer (PT) of MEAH + via nucleophilic attack at the interface and subsequently favors deprotonated MEA as an efficient electron donor to accelerate electron transfer (ET) by enhancing orbital overlaps for the co&#8208;activation of O 2 and PMS. Such a stepwise proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer (PCET)&#8208;enhanced catalytic pathway mediated by CoOCu&#8208;DAC is fundamentally different from common route identified in Co&#8208;SAC&#8208;involved Fenton&#8208;like system. The established binary QSAR further substantiates the universality of PCET&#8208;enhanced strategy toward versatile nitrogen&#8208;containing organic compounds. This study offers a new perspective for sustainable water decontamination and other related areas of catalysis based on rationalized design of multifunctional catalysts at atomic level.</description>
      <author>Qin Dai, Xin Li, Jieyuan Li, Qianqian Zhu, Guangfei Yu, Yanan Wang, Lei Xing, Jing Wang, Haijiao Lu, Jianhui Wang, Tianqi Zhang, Shuai Liu, Yanlin Jiao, Yuchen Li, Fan Dong, Lidong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence interventions in 2D MXenes-based photocatalytic applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216460</link>
      <description>Durga Madhab Mahapatra, Ashish Kumar, Rajesh Kumar, Navneet Kumar Gupta, Baranitharan Ethiraj, Lakhveer Singh, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 529(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406789185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Durga Madhab Mahapatra, Ashish Kumar, Rajesh Kumar, Navneet Kumar Gupta, Baranitharan Ethiraj, Lakhveer Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning of imidazole-based ionic liquid for highly efficient and reversible direct air capture via hydrogen bonding interaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131790</link>
      <description>Kaili Wang, Jiayi Bai, Zhenyu Zhao, Zhaowei Zhang, Weiqi Mao, Lili Jiang, Haoran Li, Congmin Wang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406792619

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaili Wang, Jiayi Bai, Zhenyu Zhao, Zhaowei Zhang, Weiqi Mao, Lili Jiang, Haoran Li, Congmin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131790</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Surface Chemistry of Methanol on Cu&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Pd(111): Effects of Metal Alloying and Reaction with Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07648</link>
      <description>Kasala Prabhakar Reddy, Jeongjin Kim, Hojoon Lim, Arephin Islam, Irene Barba-Nieto, Xiao Tong, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, Jos&#233; A. Rodr&#237;guez, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406792959

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kasala Prabhakar Reddy, Jeongjin Kim, Hojoon Lim, Arephin Islam, Irene Barba-Nieto, Xiao Tong, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, Jos&#233; A. Rodr&#237;guez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biogenic CuO nanoparticles from Camellia sinensis and Pimpinella anisum plant extracts and their role as antimicrobial agents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plana.2025.100138</link>
      <description>A. Paganotti, Carolina Cunha de Freitas, Roney H. Pereira, Vitor Gon&#231;alves Vital, Giovanna S.M. Paiva, Lucas F. de Lima, Leonardo Silva, Elizabeth Teodorov, R.A.G. Silva, Suzan Pantaroto de Vasconcellos, Amedea B. Seabra, Plant Nano Biology. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406818093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Paganotti, Carolina Cunha de Freitas, Roney H. Pereira, Vitor Gon&#231;alves Vital, Giovanna S.M. Paiva, Lucas F. de Lima, Leonardo Silva, Elizabeth Teodorov, R.A.G. Silva, Suzan Pantaroto de Vasconcellos, Amedea B. Seabra</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plana.2025.100138</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
