<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:44:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of Electrochemical Oxidation in Aqueous Environments under Applied Voltage Using Classical Molecular Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.3c07455</link>
      <description>Stephen J. Holoviak, Isma&#239;la Dabo, Susan B. Sinnott, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392542839

                Reactive molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of metal electrodes under an applied voltage in an explicit water environment were performed and compared to predictions from both other calculations and simulations and experimental measurements and observations. MD simulations using the third-generation charge-optimized many body (COMB3) potentials and the electrode COMB (eCOMB) approach allow for the simulation of an externally applied voltage by modifying the equations of motion during the charge equilibration step (QEq) of the MD simulation. Unlike previous work, which prevented charge transfer between the water and metal electrodes, this work coupled the water and metal together through the QEq, which leads to an accumulation of a negative charge on the water and a positive charge on the metal before any voltage is applied. The extent of this charge accumulation is characterized, and strategies to mitigate it are explored. Root mean square deviation plots of the metal surfaces are created for each simulation to compare the extent of oxidation and dissolution. Good agreement is found between the oxidation behavior of the simulated metal surfaces and the experimental observations.</description>
      <author>Stephen J. Holoviak, Isma&#239;la Dabo, Susan B. Sinnott</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.3c07455</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modifying ring structures in lithium borate glasses under compression: MD simulations using a machine-learning potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.033602</link>
      <description>Shingo Urata, Aik Rui Tan, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Physical Review Materials. 8(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392549842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shingo Urata, Aik Rui Tan, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.033602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superior specific capacity and energy density simultaneously achieved by Sr/In co-deposition behavior of Mg-Sr-In ternary alloys as anodes for Mg-Air cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jma.2024.02.005</link>
      <description>Bo Yu, Haitao Jiang, Yun Zhang, Journal of Magnesium and Alloys. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392551410

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Yu, Haitao Jiang, Yun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jma.2024.02.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPAW: An open Python package for electronic structure calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0182685</link>
      <description>Jens J&#248;rgen Mortensen, Ask Hjorth Larsen, Mikael Kuisma, Aleksei V. Ivanov, Alireza Taghizadeh, Andrew A. Peterson, Anubhab Haldar, Asmus Ougaard Dohn, Christian Sch&#228;fer, Hannes J&#243;nsson, Eric D. Hermes, Fredrik Nilsson, Georg Kastlunger, Gianluca Levi, Hannes J&#243;nsson, Hannu H&#228;kkinen, Jakub Fojt, Jiban Kangsabanik, Joachim S&#248;dequist, Jouko Lehtom&#228;ki, Julian Heske, Jussi Enkovaara, Kirsten T. Winther, Marcin Du&#322;ak, Marko Melander, Martin Ovesen, Martti Louhivuori, Michael Walter, Morten Niklas Gjerding, Olga Lopez-Acevedo, Paul Erhart, Robert Warmbier, Rolf W&#252;rdemann, Sami Kaappa, Simone Latini, Tara Boland, Thomas Bligaard, Thorbj&#248;rn Skovhus, Toma Susi, Tristan Maxson, Tuomas P. Rossi, Xi Chen, Yorick L. A. Schmerwitz, Jakob Schi&#248;tz, Thomas Olsen, Karsten Wedel Jacobsen, Kristian Sommer Thygesen, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392552172

                We review the GPAW open-source Python package for electronic structure calculations. GPAW is based on the projector-augmented wave method and can solve the self-consistent density functional theory (DFT) equations using three different wave-function representations, namely real-space grids, plane waves, and numerical atomic orbitals. The three representations are complementary and mutually independent and can be connected by transformations via the real-space grid. This multi-basis feature renders GPAW highly versatile and unique among similar codes. By virtue of its modular structure, the GPAW code constitutes an ideal platform for the implementation of new features and methodologies. Moreover, it is well integrated with the Atomic Simulation Environment (ASE), providing a flexible and dynamic user interface. In addition to ground-state DFT calculations, GPAW supports many-body GW band structures, optical excitations from the Bethe&#8211;Salpeter Equation, variational calculations of excited states in molecules and solids via direct optimization, and real-time propagation of the Kohn&#8211;Sham equations within time-dependent DFT. A range of more advanced methods to describe magnetic excitations and non-collinear magnetism in solids are also now available. In addition, GPAW can calculate non-linear optical tensors of solids, charged crystal point defects, and much more. Recently, support for graphics processing unit (GPU) acceleration has been achieved with minor modifications to the GPAW code thanks to the CuPy library. We end the review with an outlook, describing some future plans for GPAW.</description>
      <author>Jens J&#248;rgen Mortensen, Ask Hjorth Larsen, Mikael Kuisma, Aleksei V. Ivanov, Alireza Taghizadeh, Andrew A. Peterson, Anubhab Haldar, Asmus Ougaard Dohn, Christian Sch&#228;fer, Hannes J&#243;nsson, Eric D. Hermes, Fredrik Nilsson, Georg Kastlunger, Gianluca Levi, Hannes J&#243;nsson, Hannu H&#228;kkinen, Jakub Fojt, Jiban Kangsabanik, Joachim S&#248;dequist, Jouko Lehtom&#228;ki, Julian Heske, Jussi Enkovaara, Kirsten T. Winther, Marcin Du&#322;ak, Marko Melander, Martin Ovesen, Martti Louhivuori, Michael Walter, Morten Niklas Gjerding, Olga Lopez-Acevedo, Paul Erhart, Robert Warmbier, Rolf W&#252;rdemann, Sami Kaappa, Simone Latini, Tara Boland, Thomas Bligaard, Thorbj&#248;rn Skovhus, Toma Susi, Tristan Maxson, Tuomas P. Rossi, Xi Chen, Yorick L. A. Schmerwitz, Jakob Schi&#248;tz, Thomas Olsen, Karsten Wedel Jacobsen, Kristian Sommer Thygesen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0182685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-Derived Cobalt Nanoparticles with Dispersed Iron Phthalocyanines as Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00459</link>
      <description>Jie Liu, Qiuhong Sun, Ye Qiu, Junliang Chen, Wu Yong, Yifei Ge, L. D. Zhang, Zhi Yang, Jinjie Qian, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392552944

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Liu, Qiuhong Sun, Ye Qiu, Junliang Chen, Wu Yong, Yifei Ge, L. D. Zhang, Zhi Yang, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00459</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the frontiers of condensed-phase chemistry with a general reactive machine learning potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-023-01427-3</link>
      <description>Shuhao Zhang, Ma&#322;gorzata Z. Mako&#347;, Ryan B. Jadrich, Elfi Kraka, Kipton Barros, Benjamin Nebgen, Sergei Tretiak, Olexandr Isayev, Nicholas Lubbers, Richard A. Messerly, Justin S. Smith, Nature Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392553098

                Abstract Atomistic simulation has a broad range of applications from drug design to materials discovery. Machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) have become an efficient alternative to computationally expensive ab initio simulations. For this reason, chemistry and materials science would greatly benefit from a general reactive MLIP, that is, an MLIP that is applicable to a broad range of reactive chemistry without the need for refitting. Here we develop a general reactive MLIP (ANI-1xnr) through automated sampling of condensed-phase reactions. ANI-1xnr is then applied to study five distinct systems: carbon solid-phase nucleation, graphene ring formation from acetylene, biofuel additives, combustion of methane and the spontaneous formation of glycine from early earth small molecules. In all studies, ANI-1xnr closely matches experiment (when available) and/or previous studies using traditional model chemistry methods. As such, ANI-1xnr proves to be a highly general reactive MLIP for C, H, N and O elements in the condensed phase, enabling high-throughput in silico reactive chemistry experimentation.</description>
      <author>Shuhao Zhang, Ma&#322;gorzata Z. Mako&#347;, Ryan B. Jadrich, Elfi Kraka, Kipton Barros, Benjamin Nebgen, Sergei Tretiak, Olexandr Isayev, Nicholas Lubbers, Richard A. Messerly, Justin S. Smith</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-023-01427-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the linear relationship in the activity of the oxygen reduction reaction on Pt electrodes: A decisive role of adsorbates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.050</link>
      <description>Hua Cui, Yan&#8208;Xia Chen, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392559302

                Despite substantial efforts in developing high-performance catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), the persistent challenge lies in the high onset overpotential of the ORR, and the effect of the electrolyte solution cannot be ignored. Consequently, we have systematically investigated the impact of adsorbate species and concentration, as well as solution pH, on the ORR activity on Pt(111) and Pt(poly) electrodes. The results all tend to establish a linear quantitative relationship between the onset potential for ORR and the adsorption equilibrium potential of the adsorbate. This finding indicates the decisive role of adsorbates in the onset potential for ORR, suggesting that the adsorption potential of adsorbates can serve as an intuitive criterion for ORR activity. Additional support for this conclusion is derived from experimental results obtained from the oxygen evolution reaction on Pt(poly) with different adsorbate species and from the hydrogen evolution reaction on Pt(111) with iodine adsorption. We further propose both an empirical equation for the onset potential for ORR and the concept of a potential-regulated adsorbate shielding effect to elucidate the influence of adsorbates on ORR activity. This study provides new insights into the high onset overpotential of the ORR and offers potential strategies for predicting and enhancing ORR activity in the future.</description>
      <author>Hua Cui, Yan&#8208;Xia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new 2D Janus family with multiple properties: auxetic behavior, straintunable photocatalyst, high Curie temperature ferromagnets, and piezoelectric quantum anomalous Hall insulator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2708-4</link>
      <description>Yu Liu, ShuaiYu Wang, Fengyu Li, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392559951

                Discovering new two-dimensional (2D) materials, exploring their unique properties and potentials in various applications are of paramount importance to condensed matter physics and materials science. Here based on the diverse properties of the novel square lattice S-XS2 materials found in experiments and computations, we identified 7 novel 2D Janus S-XSSe (X = Si, Sn, V, Cr, Mo, Re, Os) monolayers by means of density functional theory computations. Remarkably, both S-SiSSe and S-SnSSe monolayers possess the auxetic behavior. In addition, they can act as potential photocatalysts, and their photocatalytic performance can be enhanced by changing the pH and applying biaxial strains. Without spin-orbit coupling (SOC), the S-VSSe, S-CrSSe, and S-MoSSe are ferromagnetic half-metals, and have high Curie temperatures TC (210, 810, and 390 K, respectively). When SOC is included, the S-VSSe becomes a quantum anomalous Hall insulator with a sizable gap (45.4 meV) and one chiral edge state (Chern number C = &#8722;1). By symmetry analysis of semiconducting S-XSSe (X = Si, Sn, V) monolayers, only out-of-plane piezoelectric response can be induced by a uniaxial strain in the basal plane, and among them, S-VSSe has both the largest out-of-plane piezoelectric coefficients d31 and d32, with values of &#8722;0.013 and 0.025 pm V&#8722;1, respectively. The concurrence of ferromagnetism, topology, and piezoelectricity empowers the S-VSSe monolayer as a potential platform for multi-functional spintronics applications with a large gap and high TC. This theoretical work brings new members, also manifoldness in the properties and functions to the renown 2D materials family.</description>
      <author>Yu Liu, ShuaiYu Wang, Fengyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2708-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Charge Transfer via Heterogeneous Doping Promotes Hematite Photoelectrodes for Efficient Solar H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06110</link>
      <description>Fang Guo, Jinwei Bai, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Kai Su, Yang Yang, Xianhu Liu, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392564717

                Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting into hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) and hydrogen (H2) is a promising alternative to energy and environmentally intensive production. Bulk electronic and surface structures affect the charge transport efficiency and catalytic activity of the photoelectrode. Herein, we design and investigate a hematite (Fe2O3) nanorod photoelectrode with hafnium and titanium binary dopants for highly selective H2O2 production. The resultant photoanode shows a H2O2 yield of 0.41 &#956;mol min&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 at 1.5 VRHE with a Faradaic efficiency of 72.2%. Experimental investigations and theoretical calculations demonstrate the synergistic effect of Hf and gradient Ti doping on the hematite for the promising H2O2 performance. Hf doping effectively improves the crystallinity of Fe2O3, which favors improving the charge transport and reducing the charge recombination. Gradient Ti doping inhibits the collapse of the nanorod structure, increases the specific surface area, and introduces a large number of active sites on the surface. Ti- and Hf-codoped Ti/Hf:Fe2O3 photoanode improves the kinetics of H2O2 generation, leading to the high selectivity for H2O2 production and suppression of O2 production. This work provides the importance of hematite-based photoanodes toward the regulation of competition reactions for H2O2 production.</description>
      <author>Fang Guo, Jinwei Bai, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Kai Su, Yang Yang, Xianhu Liu, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An effective descriptor for identifying the electrocatalytic activity and selectivity of bilayer carbon-based heterojunction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119006</link>
      <description>Lei Yang, Jiake Fan, Weihua Zhu, Carbon. 222(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392571175

                The usage of composite carbon-based materials supported by graphene has emerged as a powerful selection for designing electrocatalytic electrodes due to their agile electronic transmission and diversiform redox active sites. Here, we constructed fresh electroactive organic catalysts for hydrogen carrier synthesis by stacking a series of organic molecules on transition metal azide doped graphene substrates, in anticipation of these bilayer heterostructures to breathe new life into electrocatalysis. As expected, several promising cathodic catalysts were speculated through first principles calculations, such as Co-PMDT for H2 generation and Co-PQ for ammonia (NH3) synthesis. However, facing such an intricate interface engineering and electronic structure regulation undoubtedly poses a challenge to the time-consuming computational screening work. To tackle this, an effective descriptor was proposed as a predictive tool for identifying the activity and selectivity toward diverse chemical reactions, which allows us to systematically fine-tune the catalysts' properties in order to enhance their electrocatalytic performance. Our work may offer feasible approaches for the rational design of advanced electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Lei Yang, Jiake Fan, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient C-N coupling in electrocatalytic urea generation on copper carbonate hydroxide electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.020</link>
      <description>Yinuo Wang, Yian Wang, Qinglan Zhao, Hongming Xu, Shangqian Zhu, Fei Yang, Ernest Pahuyo Delmo, Xiaoyi Qiu, Changhui Song, Juhee Jang, Tiehuai Li, Ping Gao, Meng Gu, Minhua Shao, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392571416

                Urea generation through electrochemical CO2 and NO3&#8722; co-reduction reaction (CO2NO3RR) is still limited by either the low selectivity or yield rate of urea. Herein, we report copper carbonate hydroxide (Cu2(OH)2CO3) as an efficient CO2NO3RR electrocatalyst with an impressive urea Faradaic efficiency of 45.2% &#177; 2.1% and a high yield rate of 1564.5 &#177; 145.2 &#956;g h&#8722;1 mgcat&#8722;1. More importantly, H2 evolution is fully inhibited on this electrocatalyst over a wide potential range between &#8722;0.3 and &#8722;0.8 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode. Our thermodynamic simulation reveals that the first C-N coupling follows a unique pathway on Cu2(OH)2CO3 by combining the two intermediates, *COOH and *NHO. This work demonstrates that high selectivity and yield rate of urea can be simultaneously achieved on simple Cu-based electrocatalysts in CO2NO3RR, and provide guidance for rational design of more advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yinuo Wang, Yian Wang, Qinglan Zhao, Hongming Xu, Shangqian Zhu, Fei Yang, Ernest Pahuyo Delmo, Xiaoyi Qiu, Changhui Song, Juhee Jang, Tiehuai Li, Ping Gao, Meng Gu, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An All-Atom Force Field for Dry and Water-Lubricated Carbon Tribological Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07471</link>
      <description>Thomas Reichenbach, Souleymane Sylla, Leonhard Mayrhofer, Pedro Romero, Paul Schwarz, Michael Moseler, Gianpietro Moras, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392578215

                We present a nonreactive force field for molecular dynamics simulations of interfaces between amorphous carbon surfaces and their interaction with water. The force field is tailored to surfaces with hydrogen, hydroxyl, and aromatic surface passivation and enables large-scale simulations of dry and lubricated tribological contacts. To favor its compatibility with existing force-field parameterizations for liquids and allow a straightforward extension to other types of surface passivation species, we adopt the functional form of the Optimized Potentials for Liquid Simulations. The optimization of the force-field parameters is systematic and follows a protocol that can be reused for other surface&#8211;molecule combinations. Reference data are calculated with gradient- and dispersion-corrected density functional theory and include the bonding geometry and elastic deformation of bulk and surface species as well as surface adhesion and water adsorption energy landscapes. The conventions adopted to define the different force-field atom types are based on the hybridization of carbon orbitals and enable a simple and efficient parameter optimization strategy that only requires quantum-mechanical simulations of crystalline reference structures. After testing the force field on amorphous interfaces, we present two examples of application to tribological problems. Namely, we investigate the relationships between dry friction and the corrugation of the contact potential energy surface and the dependency of friction on the thickness of interface water films. We finally discuss the limitations of the force field and propose strategies for its improvement and extension.</description>
      <author>Thomas Reichenbach, Souleymane Sylla, Leonhard Mayrhofer, Pedro Romero, Paul Schwarz, Michael Moseler, Gianpietro Moras</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Molecular Precursors to MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Monolayers: Nanoscale Mechanism of Organometallic Chemical Vapor Deposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02675</link>
      <description>Sagar Ghorai, Ananth Govind Rajan, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392593437

                The development of a fully ab initio theory for the chemical vapor deposition (CVD) synthesis of two-dimensional (2D) materials is a prominent challenge in computational chemistry and materials science. Here, quantum-mechanical density functional theory calculations are used to discover the mechanisms underlying the nucleation and growth of monolayer 2H molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) during organometallic CVD. Starting with molybdenum hexacarbonyl (Mo(CO)6) and hydrogen sulfide (H2S) as molecular precursors, we elucidate processes such as the decomposition of Mo(CO)6 to Mo(CO)3, sulfidation of Mo(CO)3, formation of metallic trigonal-phase (1T) Mo&#8211;S clusters, transition to semiconducting hexagonal-phase 2H MoS2, and the competition between the growth of Mo- and S-zigzag edges that lead to triangular and hexagonal flakes. We demonstrate thermodynamic and kinetic control over the formation of Mo- and S-zigzag edges. Additionally, we find the removal of hydrogen (H2) to be the rate-determining step in the growth process. We further compute the free energy of formation of the investigated Mo&#8211;S clusters on amorphous SiO2, demonstrating the important role played by the SiO2 substrate in the initial stages of nucleation and growth. We also show the feasibility of forming Mo&#8211;S clusters with more than two Mo atoms on the SiO2 surface. Our work lays the foundation for developing fully ab initio models of 2D material synthesis.</description>
      <author>Sagar Ghorai, Ananth Govind Rajan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Isotropic &lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt; Values of Radical Polymers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01252</link>
      <description>Davis Thomas Daniel, Souvik Mitra, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel, Diddo Diddens, Josef Granwehr, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392595502

                Methods for electronic structure computations, such as density functional theory (DFT), are routinely used for the calculation of spectroscopic parameters to establish and validate structure&#8211;parameter correlations. DFT calculations, however, are computationally expensive for large systems such as polymers. This work explores the machine learning (ML) of isotropic g values, giso, obtained from electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) experiments of an organic radical polymer. An ML model based on regression trees is trained on DFT-calculated g values of poly(2,2,6,6-tetramethylpiperidinyloxy-4-yl methacrylate) (PTMA) polymer structures extracted from different time frames of a molecular dynamics trajectory. The DFT-derived g values, gisocalc, for different radical densities of PTMA, are compared against experimentally derived g values obtained from in operando EPR measurements of a PTMA-based organic radical battery. The ML-predicted giso values, gisopred, were compared with gisocalc to evaluate the performance of the model. Mean deviations of gisopred from gisocalc were found to be on the order of 0.0001. Furthermore, a performance evaluation on test structures from a separate MD trajectory indicated that the model is sensitive to the radical density and efficiently learns to predict giso values even for radical densities that were not part of the training data set. Since our trained model can reproduce the changes in giso along the MD trajectory and is sensitive to the extent of equilibration of the polymer structure, it is a promising alternative to computationally more expensive DFT methods, particularly for large systems that cannot be easily represented by a smaller model system.</description>
      <author>Davis Thomas Daniel, Souvik Mitra, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel, Diddo Diddens, Josef Granwehr</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and Electronic Structure of Nitrogen-Doped Graphene-Supported Cu&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 1&#8211;5) Clusters in Vacuum and under Electrochemical Conditions: Toward Sensor and Catalyst Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06475</link>
      <description>M&#225;rton Guba, Tibor H&#246;ltzl, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392600142

                Here, we present a detailed computational study of the stability and the electronic structure of nitrogen-doped graphene (N4V2) supported Cun (n = 1&#8211;5) clusters, which are promising carbon-dioxide electroreduction catalysts. The binding of the clusters to the nitrogen-doped graphene and the electronic structure of these systems were investigated under vacuum and electrochemical conditions. The stability analysis showed that among the systems, the nitrogen-doped graphene bound Cu4 is the most stable in vacuum, while in an electrolyte, and at a negative potential, the N4V2&#8211;Cu3 is energetically more favorable. The ground state electronic structure of the nitrogen-doped graphene substrate undergoes topological phase transition, from a semimetallic state, and we observed a metallic and topologically trivial state after the clusters are deposited. The electrode potential adjusts the type and density of the charge carriers in the semimetallic models, while the structures containing copper exhibit bands which are deformed and relaxed by the modified number of electrons.</description>
      <author>M&#225;rton Guba, Tibor H&#246;ltzl</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental Insights on the Electrochemical Nitrogen Oxidation over Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05307</link>
      <description>J. V. P. Long, Dong Luan, Xihong Fu, Huan Li, Huijuan Jing, Jianping Xiao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392602509

                Electrocatalytic nitrogen oxidation reaction (eN2OR) has emerged as a sustainable strategy for nitrogen fixation. In this work, density functional theory calculations were performed to rationalize the reaction mechanisms, activity, and selectivity of eN2OR on metal dioxides. The anatase (101), anatase (100), and rutile (110) surfaces were investigated to obtain more generalized insights. Based on the reaction phase diagram analysis, the thermochemical mechanisms were identified as most energetically favorable for N2 and *N2O oxidation, and a theoretical activity map was constructed for eN2OR, explaining well the experimental activity trend. Anatase PtO2(100) was screened as the most active catalyst for nitrate production, which could be covered by a monolayer of *OH under the reaction conditions according to the Pourbaix diagram. A method of electric field controlling constant potential was used to calculate the electrochemical barriers on anatase PtO2(100). It was found that the electrochemical barriers of the oxygen evolution reaction will increase with the decrease of potential, while the thermochemical limiting step of the eN2OR is insensitive to potential. Thus, the eN2OR selectivity can be improved by lowering the applied potential. This work unveils fundamental insights into eN2OR and provides a unified understanding to experiments.</description>
      <author>J. V. P. Long, Dong Luan, Xihong Fu, Huan Li, Huijuan Jing, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge distribution modulation of hollow flower-like tungsten doped nickel nitride for alkaline hydrogen oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150272</link>
      <description>Liwei An, Guanyu Luo, Jun Yang, Jiang Zhu, Deli Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392603354

                Exploring efficient nickel (Ni)-based catalysts for alkaline hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) to replace platinum group metal (PGM) is highly essential for the development of anion exchange membrane fuel cells. Nevertheless, the HOR activity of Ni is far away from PGM owing to the strong hydrogen adsorption. Herein, the tungsten-doped nickel nitride (W-Ni3N) with modulated local charge distribution and hollow flower structure is presented to improve the HOR performance. Mechanism studies reveal that W doping induces the redistribution of local charge around Ni sites due to the electron transfer from Ni to W, which strengthens the hydroxyl adsorption and simultaneously weakens hydrogen adsorption. Benefitting from the optimized adsorption of HOR intermediates and hollow flower structure, W-Ni3N exhibits improved intrinsic activity and mass activity, which are 1.7 and 10 times higher than that of pure Ni3N, respectively. This work presents a promising way to design cost-effective electrocatalysts by fine-tuning the electronic structure.</description>
      <author>Liwei An, Guanyu Luo, Jun Yang, Jiang Zhu, Deli Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downshift of the Ni d band center over Ni nanoparticles &lt;i&gt;in situ&lt;/i&gt; confined within an amorphous silicon nitride matrix</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt04155g</link>
      <description>Norifumi Asakuma, S Tada, Tomoyuki Tamura, Erika Kawaguchi, Sawao Honda, Toru Asaka, Assil Bouzid, Samuel Bernard, Yuji Iwamoto, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392606271

                More covalent Ni&#8211;N bonds at Ni/amorphous Si 3 N 4 heterointerfaces resulted in downshifting the Ni d band centerand facilitating H 2 desorption.</description>
      <author>Norifumi Asakuma, S Tada, Tomoyuki Tamura, Erika Kawaguchi, Sawao Honda, Toru Asaka, Assil Bouzid, Samuel Bernard, Yuji Iwamoto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt04155g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Interactions Through the Highly Polar &#8220;Early-Late&#8221; Metal-Metal Bonds Enable Single-Atom Catalysts Good Durability and Superior Bifunctional Orr/Oer Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4750989</link>
      <description>Tingyu Yan, Simone Lang, Siyao Wang, Shiru Lin, Qinghai Cai, Jingxiang Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392614753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingyu Yan, Simone Lang, Siyao Wang, Shiru Lin, Qinghai Cai, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4750989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A doping strategy to regulate the adsorption energy of Li&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and Li&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S to promote sulfur reduction on Chevrel phase Mo&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; in lithium&#8211;sulfur batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr06009h</link>
      <description>Tengfei Duan, Dong Fan, Zhongyun Ma, Yong Pei, Nanoscale. 16(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392614779

                The reaction mechanism of sulfur reduction reaction on metal doped Mo 6 Se 8 system and the linear relationship between the overpotential and adsorption energy of Li 2 S and Li 2 S 4 were studied.</description>
      <author>Tengfei Duan, Dong Fan, Zhongyun Ma, Yong Pei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr06009h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress of Pt and iron-group transition metal alloy catalysts with high ORR activity for PEMFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118165</link>
      <description>Zhen Zhou, Huijuan Zhang, Xiaoxiong Feng, Zhong Ma, Zi-Feng Ma, Yuhua Xue, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392624259

                The performances of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs) are affected by the cathodic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Platinum (Pt)-based catalysts can effectively improve the ORR by reducing the activation energy and substantially increase the reaction rate. However, due to the scarcity and high price of Pt, the exploration of PtM alloy catalysts with low Pt loading, high ORR activity and stability has become the focus of ORR research. Therefore, this paper reviews the recent progresses of Pt and iron-group transition metal alloy catalysts with high ORR activity and stability for PEMFCs. Firstly, the ORR theoretical mechanism is introduced. Then, we discuss several types of PtM (M=Fe, Co, Ni) alloy catalysts, including binary and ternary alloys, especially to understand the effect of particle size, shape (nanostructures, hollow structure, core-shell), structure (intermetallic compounds) and supports (new carbon, MOF derivatives, metal oxides) on the utilization rate of Pt and the ORR catalytic performance, including the ORR catalytic activity and stability. Finally, we analyze the remaining challenges and the future of PtM alloy catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhen Zhou, Huijuan Zhang, Xiaoxiong Feng, Zhong Ma, Zi-Feng Ma, Yuhua Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In pursuit of a bifunctional designing toward highly efficient overall water splitting in a hydrogen-functionalized two-dimensional covalent organic framework via single transition metal mapping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.044</link>
      <description>Chunyao Fang, Di Liu, Qiang Zhang, Guiju Liu, Chenglong Shi, Jingcheng Xu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392626253

                Developing highly active metal-based single-atom catalysts (SACs), as a thriving topic in overall water-splitting, can maximum atom utilization efficiency and yet entail high activity, and bifunctional hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)/oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts can enable more efficient overall water-splitting meanwhile reducing the cost than two individual unifunctional electrocatalysts. Bifunctional HER/OER SACs are thus of enormous economic importance and scientific interest. Herein, using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, a design of the optimal bifunctional SACs was achieved, namely, C30N12Se6H12 supported Rh (Rh@CNSeH). Also worth noting is that Rh@CNSeH stands out among 23 candidates and holds the promise of as an efficient bifunctional catalyst due to low HER/OER overpotential of 0.003/0.39 V, outperforming the commercial Pt (0.09 V)/IrO2 (0.55 V) and achieving the overall water-splitting. Good stability demonstrated by calculations of ab initio molecular dynamics simulation, antioxidant capacity and Pourbaix diagram ensured the implementation of Rh@CNSeH in ambient conditions. Remarkably, &#916;GOH* can act as an energy descriptor to reveal and even predict the OER activity trend, whose changing trend can be quantitatively described by charge transfer descriptor (Bader charge analysis) and electronic structure descriptors (d-band center and integrated crystal orbital Hamilton population (ICOHP)). Moreover, an intrinsic descriptor (&#966;) coupled with the electronegativity and the d-electrons number of transition-metal can give a reasonable prediction and explanation for the catalytic activity origin. Finally, we built a bridge for structure-property relationship from intrinsic characteristics to Bader charge, to d-band center, to ICOHP and then to free energies of intermediates, which can intuitively herald the activity origin of OER and give a reasonable guidance toward high-efficient designing for SACs.</description>
      <author>Chunyao Fang, Di Liu, Qiang Zhang, Guiju Liu, Chenglong Shi, Jingcheng Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative study and screening of Single-Atom and homonuclear Dual-Atom catalysts for NO reduction via electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131432</link>
      <description>Xiuxia Zhang, Lianxin Xia, Yanze Li, Hongqing Feng, Xinwei Wang, Jiali Yu, Fuel. 366(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392637842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiuxia Zhang, Lianxin Xia, Yanze Li, Hongqing Feng, Xinwei Wang, Jiali Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable AI for optimizing oxygen reduction on Pt monolayer core&#8211;shell catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elsa.202300028</link>
      <description>Noushin Omidvar, Shih&#8208;Han Wang, Yang Huang, Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Andy Athawale, Siwen Wang, Luke E.K. Achenie, Hongliang Xin, Electrochemical science advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392644700

                Abstract As a subfield of artificial intelligence (AI), machine learning (ML) has emerged as a versatile tool in accelerating catalytic materials discovery because of its ability to find complex patterns in high&#8208;dimensional data. While the intricacy of cutting&#8208;edge ML models, such as deep learning, makes them powerful, it also renders decision&#8208;making processes challenging to explain. Recent advances in explainable AI technologies, which aim to make the inner workings of ML models understandable to humans, have considerably increased our capacity to gain insights from data. In this study, taking the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) on {111}&#8208;oriented Pt monolayer core&#8211;shell catalysts as an example, we show how the recently developed theory&#8208;infused neural network (TinNet) algorithm enables a rapid search for optimal site motifs with the chemisorption energy of hydroxyl (OH) as a single descriptor, revealing the underlying physical factors that govern the variations in site reactivity. By exploring a broad design space of Pt monolayer core&#8211;shell alloys ( candidates) that were generated from thermodynamically stable bulk structures in existing material databases, we identified novel alloy systems along with previously known catalysts in the goldilocks zone of reactivity properties. SHAP (SHapley Additive exPlanations) analysis reveals the important role of adsorbate resonance energies that originate from &#8208;band interactions in chemical bonding at metal surfaces. Extracting physical insights into surface reactivity with explainable AI opens up new design pathways for optimizing catalytic performance beyond active sites.</description>
      <author>Noushin Omidvar, Shih&#8208;Han Wang, Yang Huang, Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Andy Athawale, Siwen Wang, Luke E.K. Achenie, Hongliang Xin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elsa.202300028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Schottky Barriers and Active Sites in Bi-metallic Cluster Mesoporous Carbon Nitride Heterostructures nanocomposite for Hydrogen Evolution with In-situ insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3971500/v1</link>
      <description>Vempuluru Navakoteswara Rao, Kwon hukwon, M Nagaveni, P. Ravi, Yonghee Lee, Seong Jae Lee, Kyeounghak Kim, M.V. Shankar, Jung Ho Yoo, Chang-Hoi Ahn, Sang&#8208;Jae Kim, Jun-Mo Yang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392651361

                Abstract The advancement of photocatalysis relies on the development of novel hetero-structured materials with unique architectures. In this study, we successfully synthesized a hetero-structured g-C 3 N 4 (GCN) material with a distinctive surface modification. To further enhance its photocatalytic performance, we optimized the Ag-Ni concentration to maximize the active sites for hydrogen evolution reactions. By using systematic physicochemical characterizations and density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we elucidated the pivotal role of graphitic carbon nitride (g-C 3 N 4 ) in facilitating the formation of an efficient charge transfer channel and promoting the effective generation and separation of photo-generated carriers. From the DFT calculations, we also demonstrated that the Ag-Ni nanoparticles provide more efficient active sites than Ni nanoparticles for water splitting and hydrogen evolution and In-situ TEM exploration. Furthermore, the hetero microstructure consisting of thin g-C 3 N 4 nano scrolls has a crucial role in shortening the migration distance of the carriers, effectively suppressing carrier recombination. Consequently, these extraordinary characteristics resulted in a superior solar light-driven photocatalytic H 2 evolution rate of 2507 &#181;mol h &#8722; 1 g &#8722; 1 , surpassing the rate achieved by bulk g-C 3 N 4 by a remarkable 18.6-folds. Moreover, the apparent quantum efficiency of this hetero-structured material reached an exceptional value of 1.6% under a 1.5 G air mass filter.</description>
      <author>Vempuluru Navakoteswara Rao, Kwon hukwon, M Nagaveni, P. Ravi, Yonghee Lee, Seong Jae Lee, Kyeounghak Kim, M.V. Shankar, Jung Ho Yoo, Chang-Hoi Ahn, Sang&#8208;Jae Kim, Jun-Mo Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3971500/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorbate-Dependent Electronic Structure Descriptors for Machine Learning-Driven Binding Energy Predictions in Diverse Single Atom Alloys: A Reductionist Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07398</link>
      <description>Javad Shirani, J. R. Vald&#233;s, Alain B. Tchagang, Kirk H. Bevan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392579703

                A long-standing challenge in the design of single atom alloys (SAAs), for catalytic applications, is the determination of a feature space that maximally correlates to molecular binding energies per the Sabatier principle. The more representative a feature space is of the underlying binding properties, the greater the predictive capability of a given machine learning (ML) algorithm. Moreover, the greater the diversity and range of SAA impurities/sites examined, the greater the difficulty in arriving at such a predictive feature. In this work, we undertake to examine the degree to which adsorbate electronic structure properties might address this challenge, in a distinct departure from the traditional substrate electronic structure feature construction found in the catalysis literature. Specifically, as a model system, we explore the predictive capacity of the p-orbital projected density of states (PDOS) pertaining to the adsorption of CO molecules on a wide range of SAA substrates, impurity embeddings, and vicinal cuts. This analysis is executed in two parts. First, we explore the degree to which the entire PDOS distribution, in the form of an energy-dependent vector, can predict binding energies. Subsequently, guided by a rigorous intrinsic dimensionality analysis, uniform manifold approximation and projection visualization, and chemical intuition, we are able to reduce the predictive feature space to just three physical quantities based on semicore level properties and charge filling of the adsorbate&#8211;as embedded with the PDOS distribution. This near-intrinsic feature space and the PDOS distribution are both shown to provide significant improvements in predictive accuracy when coupled with regression-based ML methods, even when tackling highly diverse chemical datasets. The results of this analysis both further substantiate the transferability characteristics of SAAs and indicate that adsorbate-based electronic structure features (from either relaxed or unrelaxed chemical datasets) are powerful tools in the prediction of catalytic binding energies in such systems. They also underscore the predictive benefit of finding a feature space with a dimension equal to the intrinsic dimensionality of the data that can maximally correlate with the physical property under investigation when employing ML methods in catalysis studies.</description>
      <author>Javad Shirani, J. R. Vald&#233;s, Alain B. Tchagang, Kirk H. Bevan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Local and Directional Aspects of Catalytic Active Sites by the Nuclear and Surface Electrostatic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08512</link>
      <description>Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392701786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joakim Halldin Stenlid, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt molybdenum di-selenide surface modification: A path to improved trifunctional catalysis via partial oxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159834</link>
      <description>Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Applied Surface Science. 658(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392737749

                Efficient, stable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, and oxygen reduction reactions have been in demand for decades. Recently, layered transition metals (Co, Mo, Ni, and Fe) and chalcogen compounds (S/Se/Te) gained prominence in catalysis and device studies. Density functional theory identified the covalency of Co and Mo, oxygenated bimetallic selenium bond, crystal structure distortions, and adsorption properties as crucial for enhanced electrocatalytic activity. Hybridizing the Co and Mo d-orbitals around the Fermi level of 0.463 eV improves bonding with metal surface-adsorbate intermediates validated by partial density of states. Oxygenated cobalt molybdenum selenide (O-CoMoSe2) (2 1 0) exhibited remarkable electrocatalytic properties at various active sites, with Gibbs free energy and theoretical overpotential at an active site of Co = 0.086 eV, 0.41 V, and Se = 0.50 V.</description>
      <author>Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repulsive Lateral Interaction of Water Molecules at the Initial Stages of Adsorption in Microporous AlPO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-11 According to &lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;Al NMR and DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03969</link>
      <description>Ilya V. Yakovlev, A. A. Shubin, Evgeniy Papulovskiy, Alexander V. Toktarev, Olga B. Lapina, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392760814

                Lateral (adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate) interactions between adsorbed molecules affect various physical and chemical properties of microporous adsorbents and catalysts, influencing their functional properties. In this work, we studied the hydration of microporous AlPO4-11 aluminophosphate, which has an unusually ordered structure upon adsorption of water vapor, and according to 27Al NMR data, only tetrahedrally or octahedrally coordinated Al sites are present in the AlPO4-11. These 27Al NMR data are consistent with the results of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of hydrated AlPO4-11, which revealed the presence of a strong repulsive lateral interaction at the initial stage of adsorption, suppressing the adsorption of water on neighboring (separated by one &#8722;O&#8211;P&#8211;O&#8211; bridge) Al crystallographic sites. As a result, of all the different aluminum sites, only half of the Al1 sites adsorb two water molecules and acquire octahedral coordination.</description>
      <author>Ilya V. Yakovlev, A. A. Shubin, Evgeniy Papulovskiy, Alexander V. Toktarev, Olga B. Lapina</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple and Efficient Method for the Nickel&#8208;Catalyzed Synthesis of Azines from Aldehydes and Hydrazines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202304446</link>
      <description>Lei Jin, Yao Xie, Cheng&#8208;Tung Lin, Sheng Han, Da Shi, Yizhuo Han, ChemistrySelect. 9(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392548880

                Abstract Azines are organic molecules with a C=N&#8722;N=C functional range of applications. But the conventional azines synthesis process requires a high reaction temperature and long reaction time combined with complex reaction facilities, so the synthesis process needs to be further improved in terms of economic efficiency and process simplification. Here, we demonstrate a structurally well&#8208;defined inorganic ligand Ni compound, (NH 4 ) 4 [NiMo 6 O 18 (OH) 6 ](Ni&#8208;POMs). The catalysts show good activity towards the reaction of carbonyl compounds, and the corresponding products can be obtained in yields up to about 90 %. In this condition, the majority of the aldehydes (aromatic and aliphatic) can be reacted, and the products are obtained in high yields. Density functional theory (DFT) looked into the process by which benzaldehyde and hydrazine hydrate reacted on the surface of Ni&#8208;POMs. It was calculated that the whole reaction goes through two stages and the activation energy of the whole reaction is &#8722;6.72 kcal/mol. Thus, from experiment to calculation, a complete structure of the catalytic reaction cycle has been constructed.</description>
      <author>Lei Jin, Yao Xie, Cheng&#8208;Tung Lin, Sheng Han, Da Shi, Yizhuo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202304446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animal Play and Evolution: Seven Timely Research Questions about Enigmatic Phenomena</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2024.105617</link>
      <description>Gordon M. Burghardt, Sergio M. Pellis, Jeffrey C. Schank, Paul E. Smaldino, Louk J. M. J. Vanderschuren, Elisabetta Palagi, Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392558465

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gordon M. Burghardt, Sergio M. Pellis, Jeffrey C. Schank, Paul E. Smaldino, Louk J. M. J. Vanderschuren, Elisabetta Palagi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2024.105617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic distribution and dynamics as catalytic descriptors in heterogeneous catalysis: A mini review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.catcom.2024.106901</link>
      <description>Yamkela Nzuzo, Charles O. Oseghale, Amarachi Chike-Ekwughe, Mulisa Maumela, Ndzondelelo Bingwa, Catalysis Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392649337

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yamkela Nzuzo, Charles O. Oseghale, Amarachi Chike-Ekwughe, Mulisa Maumela, Ndzondelelo Bingwa</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.catcom.2024.106901</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
