<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 01:06:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enriching surface-ordered defects on WO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for photocatalytic CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; -to-CH &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; conversion by water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2319751121</link>
      <description>Sikang Xue, Sikang Xue, Changgeng Wei, Min Shen, Xiaocong Liang, Jiali Wang, Can Yang, Wandong Xing, Sibo Wang, Wei Lin, Zhiyang Yu, Yidong Hou, Jimmy C. Yu, Jimmy C. Yu, Xinchen Wang, Xinchen Wang, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395449422

                Defect engineering has been widely applied in semiconductors to improve photocatalytic properties by altering the surface structures. This study is about the transformation of inactive WO 3 nanosheets to a highly effective CO 2 -to-CH 4 conversion photocatalyst by introducing surface-ordered defects in abundance. The nonstoichiometric WO 3- x samples were examined by using aberration-corrected electron microscopy. Results unveil abundant surface-ordered terminations derived from the periodic {013} stacking faults with a defect density of 20.2%. The {002} surface-ordered line defects are the active sites for fixation CO 2 , transforming the inactive WO 3 nanosheets into a highly active catalyst (CH 4 : O 2 = 8.2: 16.7 &#956;mol h &#8722;1 ). We believe that the formation of the W-O-C-W-O species is a critical step in the catalytic pathways. This work provides an atomic-level comprehension of the structural defects of catalysts for activating small molecules.</description>
      <author>Sikang Xue, Sikang Xue, Changgeng Wei, Min Shen, Xiaocong Liang, Jiali Wang, Can Yang, Wandong Xing, Sibo Wang, Wei Lin, Zhiyang Yu, Yidong Hou, Jimmy C. Yu, Jimmy C. Yu, Xinchen Wang, Xinchen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2319751121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing electrochemical nitrogen reduction: Efficacy of two-dimensional SiP layered structures with single-atom transition metal catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.115</link>
      <description>Qingyu Li, Weiguo Li, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yuansong Ye, Yanjie Zhang, Qiang Chen, Zhibing Cheng, Yi-Ting Chen, Rongjian Sa, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395455777

                Researchers are interested in single-atom catalysts with atomically scattered metals relishing the enhanced electrocatalytic activity for nitrogen reduction and 100 % metal atom utilization. In this paper, we investigated 18 transition metals (TM) spanning 3d to 5d series as efficient nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) catalysts on defective 2D SiPV layered structures through first-principles calculation. A systematic screening identified Mo@SiPV, Nb@SiPV, Ta@SiPV and W@SiPV as superior, demonstrating enhanced ammonia synthesis with significantly lower limiting potentials (-0.25, -0.45, -0.49 and -0.15 V, respectively), compared to the benchmark -0.87 eV for the defective SiP. In addition, the descriptor &#916;G*N was introduced to establish the relationship between the different NRR intermediates, and the volcano plot of the limiting potentials were determined for their potential-determining steps (PDS). Remarkably, the limiting voltage of the NRR possesses a good linear relationship with the active center TM atom &#400;d, which is a reliable descriptor for predicting the limiting voltage. Furthermore, we verified the stability (using Ab Initio Molecular Dynamics - AIMD) and high selectivity (UL(NRR)-UL(HER) &gt; -0.5 V) of these four catalysts in vacuum and solvent environments. This study systematically demonstrates the strong catalytic potential of 2D TM@SiPV(TM = Mo, Nb, Ta, W) single-atom catalysts for nitrogen reduction electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Qingyu Li, Weiguo Li, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yuansong Ye, Yanjie Zhang, Qiang Chen, Zhibing Cheng, Yi-Ting Chen, Rongjian Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precious Metal Free Hydrogen Evolution Catalyst Design and Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00712</link>
      <description>Anders A. Feidenhans&#8217;l, Yagya N. Regmi, Yagya N. Regmi, Chao Wei, Dong Xia, Dong Xia, Jakob Kibsgaard, Laurie A. King, Laurie A. King, Chemical reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395465040

                The quest to identify precious metal free hydrogen evolution reaction catalysts has received unprecedented attention in the past decade. In this Review, we focus our attention to recent developments in precious metal free hydrogen evolution reactions in acidic and alkaline electrolyte owing to their relevance to commercial and near-commercial low-temperature electrolyzers. We provide a detailed review and critical analysis of catalyst activity and stability performance measurements and metrics commonly deployed in the literature, as well as review best practices for experimental measurements (both in half-cell three-electrode configurations and in two-electrode device testing). In particular, we discuss the transition from laboratory-scale hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst measurements to those in single cells, which is a critical aspect crucial for scaling up from laboratory to industrial settings but often overlooked. Furthermore, we review the numerous catalyst design strategies deployed across the precious metal free HER literature. Subsequently, we showcase some of the most commonly investigated families of precious metal free HER catalysts; molybdenum disulfide-based, transition metal phosphides, and transition metal carbides for acidic electrolyte; nickel molybdenum and transition metal phosphides for alkaline. This includes a comprehensive analysis comparing the HER activity between several families of materials highlighting the recent stagnation with regards to enhancing the intrinsic activity of precious metal free hydrogen evolution reaction catalysts. Finally, we summarize future directions and provide recommendations for the field in this area of electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Anders A. Feidenhans&#8217;l, Yagya N. Regmi, Yagya N. Regmi, Chao Wei, Dong Xia, Dong Xia, Jakob Kibsgaard, Laurie A. King, Laurie A. King</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Cost-Effective Metal-Doped ZrO2 for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01403-7</link>
      <description>Yuefeng Zhang, Tianyi Wang, Liang Mei, Ruijie Yang, Weiwei Guo, Hao Li, Zhiyuan Zeng, Nano-micro letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395466117

                The design of cost-effective electrocatalysts is an open challenging for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to the "stable-or-active" dilemma. Zirconium dioxide (ZrO2), a versatile and low-cost material that can be stable under OER operating conditions, exhibits inherently poor OER activity from experimental observations. Herein, we doped a series of metal elements to regulate the ZrO2 catalytic activity in OER via spin-polarized density functional theory calculations with van der Waals interactions. Microkinetic modeling as a function of the OER activity descriptor (GO*-GHO*) displays that 16 metal dopants enable to enhance OER activities over a thermodynamically stable ZrO2 surface, among which Fe and Rh (in the form of single-atom dopant) reach the volcano peak (i.e. the optimal activity of OER under the potential of interest), indicating excellent OER performance. Free energy diagram calculations, density of states, and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations further showed that Fe and Rh are the effective dopants for ZrO2, leading to low OER overpotential, high conductivity, and good stability. Considering cost-effectiveness, single-atom Fe doped ZrO2 emerged as the most promising catalyst for OER. This finding offers a valuable perspective and reference for experimental researchers to design cost-effective catalysts for the industrial-scale OER production.</description>
      <author>Yuefeng Zhang, Tianyi Wang, Liang Mei, Ruijie Yang, Weiwei Guo, Hao Li, Zhiyuan Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01403-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Bio-capture by Microalgae and Cyanobacteria Cultures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-43969-8_2</link>
      <description>Cigdem Demirkaya, Hector De la Hoz Siegler, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395471514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cigdem Demirkaya, Hector De la Hoz Siegler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-43969-8_2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructure Engineering of Cathode Layers in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells: From Catalysts to Membrane Electrode Assembly</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01113</link>
      <description>Bo Yang, Zhonghua Xiang, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395661603

                The membrane electrode assembly (MEA) is the core component of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), which is the place where the reaction occurrence, the multiphase material transfer and the energy conversion, and the development of MEA with high activity and long stability are crucial for the practical application of PEMFCs. Currently, efforts are devoted to developing the regulation of MEA nanostructure engineering, which is believed to have advantages in improving catalyst utilization, maximizing three-phase boundaries, enhancing mass transport, and improving operational stability. This work reviews recent research progress on platinum group metal (PGM) and PGM-free catalysts with multidimensional nanostructures, catalyst layers (CLs), and nano-MEAs for PEMFCs, emphasizing the importance of structure-function relationships, aiming to guide the further development of the performance for PEMFCs. Then the design strategy of the MEA interface is summarized systematically. In addition, the application of in situ and operational characterization techniques to adequately identify current density distributions, hot spots, and water management visualization of MEAs is also discussed. Finally, the limitations of nanostructured MEA research are discussed and future promising research directions are proposed. This paper aims to provide valuable insights into the fundamental science and technical engineering of efficient MEA interfaces for PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>Bo Yang, Zhonghua Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unfolding Chemical Diversity: Co-Sublimation in 2D Metal&#8211;Organic Networks for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00101</link>
      <description>Juan M. Lombardi, Doris Grumelli, Rico Gutzler, H. F. Busnengo, Paula Abufager, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395661674

                In this study, we employ density functional theory to analyze the electrocatalytic activity toward the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) of FeTPyP/Au(111) self-assembled monolayers (SAMs) and their bimetallic-organic counterpart, FeTPyP + Co/Au(111), synthesized via Co atom sublimation. Our investigation focuses on elucidating the mechanistic roles of various metal active sites, thereby establishing a correlation between the local chemical environment and the electronic properties of the active metal centers. We find that the FeTPyP + Co/Au(111) system exhibits sites with a more balanced adsorption behavior for ORR intermediates compared to FeTPyP/Au(111), which leads us to conclude that the former demonstrates enhanced ORR catalytic activity. Additionally, we introduce a methodology for rapid evaluation of the ORR performance based on the electronic structure of the metal active sites.</description>
      <author>Juan M. Lombardi, Doris Grumelli, Rico Gutzler, H. F. Busnengo, Paula Abufager</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional mechanism of oxygen evolution reaction and oxygen reduction reaction induced by surface reconstruction in Perovskite electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144339</link>
      <description>Hongpeng Chen, Haonan Xie, Chen Yang, Jingjing Pang, Naiqin Zhao, Chunnian He, Enzuo Liu, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395666630

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongpeng Chen, Haonan Xie, Chen Yang, Jingjing Pang, Naiqin Zhao, Chunnian He, Enzuo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field demonstration of a 10 MW CO2 capture pilot plant in extended operation using KoSol absorbents for treating off-gas in a coal fired power plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104134</link>
      <description>No-Sang Kwak, Jinsei Jung, Jung-Hyun Lee, Sung-Chul Han, Jong Sup Shim, Kyung-min Kim, Dongkyu Lee, International journal of greenhouse gas control. 135(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395667325

                No abstract</description>
      <author>No-Sang Kwak, Jinsei Jung, Jung-Hyun Lee, Sung-Chul Han, Jong Sup Shim, Kyung-min Kim, Dongkyu Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence and design of experiments for resource adequacy assessment in power systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esr.2024.101368</link>
      <description>Jan Priesmann, Jean Charles Munch, Marius Tillmanns, E. Ridha, Thomas Spiegel, Marius Reich, Mario Adam, Laura Nolting, Aaron Praktiknjo, Energy strategy reviews. 53(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395671125

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jan Priesmann, Jean Charles Munch, Marius Tillmanns, E. Ridha, Thomas Spiegel, Marius Reich, Mario Adam, Laura Nolting, Aaron Praktiknjo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esr.2024.101368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular dynamics simulation study on the wetting characteristics of carbon dioxide droplets on smooth and rough surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.124835</link>
      <description>Xuewen Cao, Yongqing Ma, Hengguang Cao, Zuyan Xu, Jie He, Jiang Bian, Journal of molecular liquids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395673060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuewen Cao, Yongqing Ma, Hengguang Cao, Zuyan Xu, Jie He, Jiang Bian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.124835</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoporous NiPt alloy by dealloying of amorphous NiZrPt metallic glass for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151700</link>
      <description>Junhao Qin, Hao Zhang, Wenfei Lu, Jiahua Zhu, Jinsen Tian, Jun Shen, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395678040

                The development of high-performance and low-cost alkaline hydrogen precipitation catalysts is critical for the large-scale application of hydrogen energy. In this work, the nanoporous alloy catalysts were synthesized by dealloying melt-spun NiZrPt ribbons. The optimal sample after dealloying shows excellent HER performance in alkaline medium, with a small overpotential of 15 mV to deliver 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a low Tafel slope of 20 mV/dec. The material characterization reveals that the incorporation of Ni modulates the electronic structure of Pt. After selective dealloying of Zr and Ni, a Pt-enriched nanoporous structure was formed on the catalyst surface. Meanwhile, the remaining Ni sites acted as synergistic sites to activate the Pt sites, which allowed for better hydrogen adsorption energy and faster kinetics of the catalytic reaction. Besides, the favorable mechanical flexibility of the material makes it potential for self-supporting electrode. This work presents a way to prepare low-Pt efficient catalysts by amorphous alloy dealloying.</description>
      <author>Junhao Qin, Hao Zhang, Wenfei Lu, Jiahua Zhu, Jinsen Tian, Jun Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Z-scheme InN/BTe heterostructure for enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen evolution: DFT calculation and mechanism study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.228</link>
      <description>Can Li, Hao Liang, Zhiqiang Xu, Tao Ji, Ying Zhang, Kun Dong, Lingling Wang, Liang Xu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395681798

                Hydrogen energy plays an important role in achieving green and low-carbon transformation and development. It is a feasible method to produce clean hydrogen by solar irradiation. In this paper, a new type of InN/BTe van der Waals heterojunction is designed based on density functional theory. The calculated results show that the lattice mismatch of the heterojunction is less than 2% and has good stability, which is beneficial to the experimental synthesis. Under light irradiation, the transfer path of electrons and holes generated by light excitation is Z-scheme mechanism, which accumulates in BTe conduction band and InN valence band with stronger redox activity, respectively, and improves the efficiency of photocatalytic hydrolysis. The InN/BTe heterojunction under the standard hydrogen electrode can achieve complete decomposition of water and spontaneous hydrogen evolution reaction. The high solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency (up to 17.92%) and electron mobility (1820.54 cm2/Vs) indicate that the InN/BTe heterojunction is a promising photocatalytic material.</description>
      <author>Can Li, Hao Liang, Zhiqiang Xu, Tao Ji, Ying Zhang, Kun Dong, Lingling Wang, Liang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Role of Acid Site Distribution on the Water Structure in Aluminosilicate Zeolites: Insights from Molecular Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01087</link>
      <description>Mingze Zheng, Brandon C. Bukowski, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395683506

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingze Zheng, Brandon C. Bukowski</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding highly active and durable Fe-decorated Co(OH)2 catalysts in alkaline oxygen evolution reaction by in situ XANES studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151701</link>
      <description>Du-Hyeon Kim, Yong&#8208;Kul Lee, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395683942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Du-Hyeon Kim, Yong&#8208;Kul Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotational Symmetry Effects on Multibody Lateral Interactions between Co-Adsorbates at Heterogeneous Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00019</link>
      <description>Shuqiao Wang, Alyssa J. R. Hensley, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395684873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuqiao Wang, Alyssa J. R. Hensley</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reduction of cyanide on conjugated copper-organic framework Cu3(HHTP)2 monolayer: A dispersion-corrected DFT investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.265</link>
      <description>Rongwei Shi, Yang&#8208;Xin Yu, A. N. Chibisov, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395688468

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rongwei Shi, Yang&#8208;Xin Yu, A. N. Chibisov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Ingredients for the Screening of Single Atom Catalysts for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction: The Case of Titanium Nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401058</link>
      <description>Clara Saetta, Ilaria Barlocco, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395693504

                Abstract A computational screening of Single Atom Catalysts (SACs) bound to titanium nitride (TiN) is presented, for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER), based on density functional theory. The role of fundamental ingredients is explored to account for a reliable screening of SACs. Namely, the formation of H 2 &#8208;complexes besides the classical H * one impacts the predicted HER activity, in line with previous studies on other SACs. Also, the results indicate that one needs to adopt self&#8208;interaction&#8208;corrected functionals. Finally, predicting an active catalyst is of little help without an assessment of its stability. Thus, it is included in the theoretical framework the analysis of the stability of the SACs in working conditions of pH and voltage. Once unconventional intermediates and stability are considered in a self&#8208;interaction corrected scheme, the number of potential good catalysts for HER is strongly reduced since i) some potentially good catalysts are not stable against dissolution and ii) the formation of unconventional intermediates leads to thermodynamic barriers. This study highlights the importance of including ingredients for the prediction of new systems, such as the formation of unconventional intermediates, estimating the stability of SACs, and the adoption of self&#8208;interaction corrected functionals. Also, this study highlights some interesting candidates deserving of dedicated work.</description>
      <author>Clara Saetta, Ilaria Barlocco, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ameliorating the electronic environment of NiCoP by halogen doping: A strategy for boosting hydrogen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131780</link>
      <description>Jian Su, Nan Jiang, Bolong Jiang, Yuanyuan Wang, Xueqin Wang, Zhijun Li, Hua Song, Fuel. 369(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395699780

                The design of highly efficient and robust non-noble metal water splitting catalysts for hydrogen production is crucial to reduce overpotential and energy consumption. Herein, a strategy for in-situ growth of halogen-doped NiCoP (X-NiCoP/NF, X = F, Cl, and Br) catalysts with special morphology on nickel foam is proposed. Both the experimental results and theoretical calculations reveal that the downshift of the d-band center energy can regulate the charge distribution of NiCoP owing to doping of strong electronegativity halogen, thus optimizing the Gibbs free energy of H* absorption (&#9651;GH*). The F-NiCoP/NF catalyst achieves remarkable HER activity under alkaline conditions, with overpotential at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 (&#951;10) of 59 mV and Tafel slope of 48.9 mV dec&#8722;1 in 1.0 M KOH. Moreover, F-doping significantly increases the electrochemically active surface area (ECSA) and turnover frequency (TOF), suggestive of the F promotes the formation of highly dispersed high intrinsic active sites. The F-NiCoP/NF exhibits excellent stability with a negligible decrease in activity after durability tests. This work sheds light on the facile synthesis of highly active and stable catalysts with strong electronegative atom doping for HER.</description>
      <author>Jian Su, Nan Jiang, Bolong Jiang, Yuanyuan Wang, Xueqin Wang, Zhijun Li, Hua Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131780</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental study on gas separation from the oil&#8211;water-emulsion mixture via hydrate method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120198</link>
      <description>Xiaofang Lv, Xiongwei Ni, Yan-Yun Xiao, Yang Liu, Mingguo Peng, Qianli Ma, Chuanshuo Wang, Shidong Zhou, Shangfei Song, Chemical engineering science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395701062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaofang Lv, Xiongwei Ni, Yan-Yun Xiao, Yang Liu, Mingguo Peng, Qianli Ma, Chuanshuo Wang, Shidong Zhou, Shangfei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential powered EC-SERS for sensitive detection of acetamiprid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfoodeng.2024.112109</link>
      <description>Ting Wu, Xuemei Tang, Wei Zeng, Yu Han, Sihang Zhang, Jing Wei, Long Wu, Journal of food engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395701347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Wu, Xuemei Tang, Wei Zeng, Yu Han, Sihang Zhang, Jing Wei, Long Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfoodeng.2024.112109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen evolution reaction via hydrogen plasma treatment: Unveiling the functionality of CN defects and the role of Fe in NiFe Prussian blue analogs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.36</link>
      <description>Qingdong Ruan, Dan Li, Chien-Huei Wu, Chao Huang, Paul K. Chu, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395956193

                Abstract The rational design of electronic and vacancy structures is crucial to regulating and enhancing electrocatalytic water splitting. However, creating novel vacancies and precisely controlling the number of vacancies in existing materials systems pose significant challenges. Herein, a novel approach to optimize the concentration of the CN vacancy (V CN ) in the NiFe Prussian blue analog (PBA) nanocubes is designed by incorporating the H 2 or O 2 plasma treatment. The relationship between the V CN and catalysis is analyzed, and results show that a moderate concentration of V CN (6.5%) can enormously enhance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity of NiFe PBA. However, an excessive amount of V CN disrupts the crystal structure and hinders the transportation of charge carriers, consequently leading to inferior OER. Furthermore, the V CN significantly activates the activity of Fe sites, inducing preferential adsorption of OH &#8722; on Fe sites, followed by adsorption on Ni sites, thereby optimizing the reaction pathway and significantly promoting OER performance. In addition, V CN also suppresses Fe leaching, giving the catalyst excellent durability. This study reveals the feasibility of creating unconventional defects in nanomaterials and precisely controlling the number of vacancies for diverse catalytic and energy applications.</description>
      <author>Qingdong Ruan, Dan Li, Chien-Huei Wu, Chao Huang, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.36</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero-Gap Bipolar Membrane Water Electrolyzers: Principles, Challenges and Practical Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144345</link>
      <description>Abdulhai H. Faqeeh, Mark D. Symes, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395957045

                Producing hydrogen through the electrolysis of water is an attractive method for storing intermittent, renewably-generated power in the form of a clean-burning fuel. Amongst the various types of electrolyzer that have been proposed, those employing bipolar membranes have the unique advantage of allowing the water splitting half-reactions to proceed under their &#3839;kinetically most favourable conditions, thanks to the ability of these membranes to maintain a pH gradient. Maintaining such a pH gradient enables the oxygen evolution reaction to occur in basic conditions whilst the hydrogen evolution reaction occurs in acidic conditions. However, bipolar membrane electrolysis technology remains at an early stage of development and faces several challenges, including high potential losses and low energy efficiency caused by insufficient water transport across (and ion crossover within) the bipolar membrane. In this review, the strategies and methods employed to address these challenges and to enhance the performance and efficiency of bipolar membrane water electrolysis are discussed. The scope of this review is primarily on zero-gap bipolar membrane/interface water electrolyzers, as this configuration is arguably the most relevant bipolar membrane/interface electrolyzer architecture for scaled-up devices and commercial hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Abdulhai H. Faqeeh, Mark D. Symes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced oxidation processes for water and wastewater treatment &#8211; guidance for systematic future research</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e30402</link>
      <description>Uwe H&#252;bner, Stephanie Spahr, Holger V. Lutze, Arne Wieland, Steffen R&#252;ting, Wolfgang Gernjak, Jannis Wenk, Heliyon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395961526

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Uwe H&#252;bner, Stephanie Spahr, Holger V. Lutze, Arne Wieland, Steffen R&#252;ting, Wolfgang Gernjak, Jannis Wenk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e30402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Novel Cube-Embedded MnO2/ZnO Nanocomposite for OER Activity and Supercapacitor Performance Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-06559-6</link>
      <description>Muhammad Suleman Waheed, Sarah A. Alsalhi, Shaimaa A. M. Abdelmohsen, Sher Zaman, Shandar Ahmad, Salma Aman, Zubair Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, T.A. Taha, JOM. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396216669

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Suleman Waheed, Sarah A. Alsalhi, Shaimaa A. M. Abdelmohsen, Sher Zaman, Shandar Ahmad, Salma Aman, Zubair Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, T.A. Taha</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-06559-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation on the Structural Characteristics and Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction Mechanism of G-C3n4 Supported Ag/Au Single Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4811081</link>
      <description>Hui&#8208;ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396217729

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui&#8208;ling Shui, G. S. Li, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4811081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of p-Block Metal Single-Atom-Loaded Carbon Nitride Catalyst for Photocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29092030</link>
      <description>Meng-Ning Chen, Yidi Wu, Qiang Wan, Sen Lin, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396220936

                Graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4), recognized for its considerable potential as a heterogeneous photocatalyst in water splitting, has attracted extensive research interest. By using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the regulatory role of p-block metal (PM) single atoms on the photocatalytic activity of g-C3N4 in overall water splitting was systematically explored. The incorporation of PM atoms (Ge, Sn and Pb) led to a reduction in the overpotentials required for both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Combined with the electronic structures analysis via hybrid functional, it was found that the introduction of Ge, Sn or Pb optimizes the positions of the valence band maximum (VBM) and the conduction band minimum (CBM), providing a robust driving force for HER and ensuring substantial driving force for OER. Meanwhile, the presence of these three PMs induces the spatial separation of VBM and CBM, inhibiting the recombination of carriers. These findings have significant implications for the design and preparation of efficient photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Meng-Ning Chen, Yidi Wu, Qiang Wan, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29092030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Interface Polarization Effects on the Electrical Double Layer with Efficient Open Boundary Simulations under Potential Control</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03615</link>
      <description>Margherita Buraschi, Andrew P. Horsfield, Clotilde S. Cucinotta, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396221327

                A major challenge in modeling interfacial processes in electrochemical (EC) devices is performing simulations at constant potential. This requires an open-boundary description of the electrons, so that they can enter and leave the computational cell. To enable realistic modeling of EC processes under potential control we have interfaced density functional theory with the hairy probe method in the weak coupling limit (Zauchner et al. Phys. Rev. B 2018, 97, 045116). Our implementation was systematically tested using simple parallel-plate capacitor models with pristine surfaces and a single layer of adsorbed water molecules. Remarkably, our code's efficiency is comparable with a standard DFT calculation. We reveal that local field effects at the electrical double layer induced by the change of applied potential can significantly affect the energies of chemical steps in heterogeneous electrocatalysis. Our results demonstrate the importance of an explicit modeling of the applied potential in a simulation and provide an efficient tool to control this critical parameter.</description>
      <author>Margherita Buraschi, Andrew P. Horsfield, Clotilde S. Cucinotta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03615</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Orbital Coupling: An Adsorption Mechanism in Single-Atom Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13119</link>
      <description>Chen He, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Lei Meng, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Zhe Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396222769

                Quantitative understanding of the chemisorption on single-atom catalysts (SACs) by their electronic properties is crucial for the catalyst design. However, the physical mechanism is still under debate. Here, the CO catalytic oxidation on single transition metal (i.e., Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni) dopants is used as a theoretical model to explore the correlations between the characteristics of electronic structures and the chemisorption on SACs. For these metal dopants, their atomic d orbitals form several nondegenerate and localized electronic states that are found to be selectively coupled with the &#960;* orbital of the adsorbed O2, which we defined as selective orbital coupling. Based on the selective orbital coupling, we find that the alignment between the selected d state and the &#960;* state determines the bond strength, regardless of the electron occupation number of the selected d states; the electron transfer to form M&#8211;O bonding can be provided by the support. Such electron transfer can be related with the electronic metal&#8211;support interaction. We attribute the origin of the chemisorption mechanism to the coexistence of the localized orbital of the single transition metal and the continuous energy band of the Au support. Finally, we illustrate how this mechanism dominates the variation trend of the reaction barriers. Our results unravel a fundamental adsorption mechanism in SAC systems.</description>
      <author>Chen He, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Lei Meng, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Zhe Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Effects of FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Active Sites Surrounded by Fourteen-Membered Ring Ligands on Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity and Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01122</link>
      <description>Zhiqing Feng, Shizuyo Honda, Junya Ohyama, Y. Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Hiroshi Yoshida, Masato Machida, K&#245;tar&#245; Higashi, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Ryoichi Kojima, Makoto Moriya, Hideo Notsu, Seiji Nagata, Manabu Miyoshi, Teruaki Hayakawa, Yuta Nabae, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396222845

                FeN4 active sites have been studied as non-Pt group metal (non-PGM) catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The authors recently developed Fe(II) 1,14:7,8-ditethenotetrapyrido-[2,1,6-de:2&#8242;,1&#8242;6&#8242;-gh:2&#8243;,1&#8243;,6&#8243;-na][1,3,5,8,10,12] hexaazacyclotetradecine (Fe-14MR) as an FeN4 complex incorporating a 14-membered ring. This complex exhibited higher ORR activity and greater durability than Fe phthalocyanine, a conventional FeN4 complex having a 16-membered ring. In the present study, the ORR activity and durability of this Fe-14MR complex supported on C (Fe-14MR/C) were enhanced through modification of the active site structure by heating at 600 &#176;C and removing protons on amine groups in the Fe-14MR. Density functional theory calculations indicated that the Fe-14MR/C structure generated by heating resulted in oxygen species absorption energies close to optimal values for the ORR. The improved durability of the heat-treated Fe-14MR/C was attributed to reduced distortion of the FeN4 sites. The results suggest that designing Fe-14MR structures can be a promising approach to developing non-PGM catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhiqing Feng, Shizuyo Honda, Junya Ohyama, Y. Iwata, Keisuke Awaya, Hiroshi Yoshida, Masato Machida, K&#245;tar&#245; Higashi, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Ryota Goto, Takeo Ichihara, Ryoichi Kojima, Makoto Moriya, Hideo Notsu, Seiji Nagata, Manabu Miyoshi, Teruaki Hayakawa, Yuta Nabae</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single transition-metal atoms anchored on a novel Dirac-dispersive &#960;-&#960; conjugated holey graphitic carbon nitride substrate: computational screening toward efficient bifunctional OER/ORR electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02652-6</link>
      <description>Chunyao Fang, Xihang Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Di Liu, Xiaomeng Cui, Jingcheng Xu, Chenglong Shi, Mengyu Yang, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396224837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunyao Fang, Xihang Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Di Liu, Xiaomeng Cui, Jingcheng Xu, Chenglong Shi, Mengyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02652-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO adsorption and *CO hydrogenation for efficient CO2 deep reduction on MnCu-NC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104426</link>
      <description>Zhiyun Hu, Huang Liangai, Liu Jianchuan, Zhong Wenwu, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396231739

                In CO2RR, enhancing CO adsorption could suppress desorption and increase *CO concentration for deep reduction. An underlying concern is that strong adsorption might result in high thermodynamic barrier for *CO hydrogenation, however, kinetic barrier firstly dominates the reaction pathway and determines the products selectivity. Directed by above idea, CO2RR performance on Mn, Cu doped nitrogenated carbon (MnCu-NC) is comprehensively studied using density functional theory (DFT). MnCu-NC shows a mild limiting potential of -0.59 V (*CO &#8594; *CHO) for CH3OH and CH4 products. CO poisoning is likely to cause catalyst deactivation, while CO modified MnCu-NC shows a slightly increased limiting potential of -0.63 V (*COCO &#8594; *COCHO) for CH3OH and CH4, and hydrogen evolution is significantly suppressed. Further comparative studies indicate that kinetic barrier for *CO hydrogenation is crucial for deep reduction, and C&#8722;O activation, as well as CO adsorption is enhanced by &#928;-backbonding. Besides, introduction Cu to dual-atom catalyst (DAC) could help retain more electrons and Mn has strong magnetization for charge transfer, both of which improve the charge densities and &#928;-backbonding strength, thus boosting the remarkable CO2RR performance toward CH4 and CH3OH on MnCu-NC.</description>
      <author>Zhiyun Hu, Huang Liangai, Liu Jianchuan, Zhong Wenwu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Re cluster complexes be an efficient catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction? Insights from experiments and computations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00144c</link>
      <description>Mikhail Khrizanforov, Bulat S. Akhmadeev, Polina Milyukova, Asiya R. Mustafina, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Artur Khannanov, Renat R. Nazmutdinov, Konstantin A. Brylev, Qi Shao, Rustem Zairov, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396234031

                This work presents the possibility of using a hexarenium cluster for the hydrogen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Mikhail Khrizanforov, Bulat S. Akhmadeev, Polina Milyukova, Asiya R. Mustafina, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Artur Khannanov, Renat R. Nazmutdinov, Konstantin A. Brylev, Qi Shao, Rustem Zairov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00144c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale biomolecular simulations in the exascale era</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sbi.2024.102821</link>
      <description>David Carrasco&#8208;Busturia, Emiliano Ippoliti, Simone Meloni, Ursula R&#246;thlisberger, J&#243;gvan Magnus Haugaard Olsen, Current opinion in structural biology. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396237158

                The complexity of biological systems and processes, spanning molecular to macroscopic scales, necessitates the use of multiscale simulations to get a comprehensive understanding. Quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) molecular dynamics (MD) simulations are crucial for capturing processes beyond the reach of classical MD simulations. The advent of exascale computing offers unprecedented opportunities for scientific exploration, not least within life sciences, where simulations are essential to unravel intricate molecular mechanisms underlying biological processes. However, leveraging the immense computational power of exascale computing requires innovative algorithms and software designs. In this context, we discuss the current status and future prospects of multiscale biomolecular simulations on exascale supercomputers with a focus on QM/MM MD. We highlight our own efforts in developing a versatile and high-performance multiscale simulation framework with the aim of efficient utilization of state-of-the-art supercomputers. We showcase its application in uncovering complex biological mechanisms and its potential for leveraging exascale computing.</description>
      <author>David Carrasco&#8208;Busturia, Emiliano Ippoliti, Simone Meloni, Ursula R&#246;thlisberger, J&#243;gvan Magnus Haugaard Olsen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sbi.2024.102821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty-biased molecular dynamics for learning uniformly accurate interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01254-1</link>
      <description>Viktor Zaverkin, David Holzm&#252;ller, Henrik Christiansen, Federico Errica, Francesco Alesiani, Makoto Takamoto, Mathias Niepert, Johannes K&#228;stner, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396239146

                Abstract Efficiently creating a concise but comprehensive data set for training machine-learned interatomic potentials (MLIPs) is an under-explored problem. Active learning, which uses biased or unbiased molecular dynamics (MD) to generate candidate pools, aims to address this objective. Existing biased and unbiased MD-simulation methods, however, are prone to miss either rare events or extrapolative regions&#8212;areas of the configurational space where unreliable predictions are made. This work demonstrates that MD, when biased by the MLIP&#8217;s energy uncertainty, simultaneously captures extrapolative regions and rare events, which is crucial for developing uniformly accurate MLIPs. Furthermore, exploiting automatic differentiation, we enhance bias-forces-driven MD with the concept of bias stress. We employ calibrated gradient-based uncertainties to yield MLIPs with similar or, sometimes, better accuracy than ensemble-based methods at a lower computational cost. Finally, we apply uncertainty-biased MD to alanine dipeptide and MIL-53(Al), generating MLIPs that represent both configurational spaces more accurately than models trained with conventional MD.</description>
      <author>Viktor Zaverkin, David Holzm&#252;ller, Henrik Christiansen, Federico Errica, Francesco Alesiani, Makoto Takamoto, Mathias Niepert, Johannes K&#228;stner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01254-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interoperable workflows by exchanging grid-based data between quantum-chemical program packages</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0201701</link>
      <description>Kevin Focke, Matteo De Santis, Mario Wolter, Jessica A. Martinez B., Val&#233;rie Vallet, Andr&#233; Severo Pereira Gomes, Ma&#322;gorzata Olejniczak, Christoph R. Jacob, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396494992

                Quantum-chemical subsystem and embedding methods require complex workflows that may involve multiple quantum-chemical program packages. Moreover, such workflows require the exchange of voluminous data that go beyond simple quantities, such as molecular structures and energies. Here, we describe our approach for addressing this interoperability challenge by exchanging electron densities and embedding potentials as grid-based data. We describe the approach that we have implemented to this end in a dedicated code, PyEmbed, currently part of a Python scripting framework. We discuss how it has facilitated the development of quantum-chemical subsystem and embedding methods and highlight several applications that have been enabled by PyEmbed, including wave-function theory (WFT) in density-functional theory (DFT) embedding schemes mixing non-relativistic and relativistic electronic structure methods, real-time time-dependent DFT-in-DFT approaches, the density-based many-body expansion, and workflows including real-space data analysis and visualization. Our approach demonstrates, in particular, the merits of exchanging (complex) grid-based data and, in general, the potential of modular software development in quantum chemistry, which hinges upon libraries that facilitate interoperability.</description>
      <author>Kevin Focke, Matteo De Santis, Mario Wolter, Jessica A. Martinez B., Val&#233;rie Vallet, Andr&#233; Severo Pereira Gomes, Ma&#322;gorzata Olejniczak, Christoph R. Jacob</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0201701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous and Scalable Laser Synthesis of Atom Clusters with Tunable Surface Oxidation for Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00342</link>
      <description>Meike Tack, Muhammad Usama, Norbert Kazamer, Kai S. Exner, Michael Brodmann, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396495047

                The laser-based synthesis of colloidal nanoparticles consists of several established methods to produce high-purity, active, and durable metal and oxide catalysts. Among them, only laser fragmentation in a liquid jet produces monodisperse, sub-5 nm nanoparticles in a fully continuous operation. However, the nanoparticle yield and laser power-specific productivity are still below the established gram-scale laser ablation method. In addition, little is known about how the initial particle size, oxidation, and the number of laser pulses affect the generated particle size and oxidation state, especially when using commercial microparticles. In this work, we address these shortcomings with the example of iridium as an important benchmark catalyst for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction. Starting from iridium microparticles, a significant improvement in the laser power-specific productivity of nanoparticles was observed when the initial particle concentrations were increased to several grams per liter. The number of applied laser pulses controls the degree of nanoparticles' surface oxidation, as shown by XPS measurements and DFT calculations, while the monodisperse &#8764;2 nm product particle diameter was unaffected by the initial particle size and concentration, highlighting the process robustness. Additionally, the particles exhibit a benchmark level of catalytic activity with the lowest overpotential of 0.33 V vs RHE @ 10 mA/cm2. To summarize, the continuous laser fragmentation of microparticles in water has great potential in the green synthesis of ultrasmall catalysts.</description>
      <author>Meike Tack, Muhammad Usama, Norbert Kazamer, Kai S. Exner, Michael Brodmann, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation on the reaction mechanism and stability of Ruddlesden-Popper structure Srn+1BnO3n+1 (B=Ru, Ir, n=1, 2) as an oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalyst in acidic medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.299</link>
      <description>Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Jiahao Zhang, Jun Ren, Hai&#8208;Lei Li, Meina Chen, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396498908

                R&#8211;P structured catalysts have attracted attention due to their low noble metal content and long-term stability. In this paper, we calculated the synthesis difficulty, Sr segregation, and OER catalytic activity of SrBO3, Srn+1BnO3n+1 (BRu, Ir, n = 1, 2), taking into account the effects of perovskite layer numbers and strain. The synthesis difficulty was calculated: SrBO3 &lt; Sr2BO4 &lt; Sr3B2O7. The perovskite layer numbers of R&#8211;P catalysts were also found to affect the OER process, from n = 1 to 2, the rate-controlling step changes from O*&#8594;OOH* to OOH*&#8594;O2. Sr2IrO4 was calculated to have the best catalytic activity but is very prone to Sr segregation. Due to the unique layered nature, Sr2IrO4 is still considered the most promising OER catalyst. Furthermore, we also concluded that applying strain impairs the OER catalytic performance of R&#8211;P oxides. Our work investigated the OER catalytic mechanisms of R&#8211;P oxides, which is significant for the development of water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Jiahao Zhang, Jun Ren, Hai&#8208;Lei Li, Meina Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Consequences of Hierarchical Pore Architectures within MFI and FAU Zeolites for Polyethylene Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01213</link>
      <description>Jun Zhi Tan, M. Ortega, Stephen J. Miller, Cole W. Hullfish, H.G. Kim, Sung M. Kim, Wenda Hu, Jianzhi Hu, Johannes A. Lercher, Bruce E. Koel, Michele L. Sarazen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396499244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Zhi Tan, M. Ortega, Stephen J. Miller, Cole W. Hullfish, H.G. Kim, Sung M. Kim, Wenda Hu, Jianzhi Hu, Johannes A. Lercher, Bruce E. Koel, Michele L. Sarazen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the potential of transition metals as single atom catalyst in Graphene/WS2 van der Waals heterostructure for enhanced HER performance &#8211; A first principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.281</link>
      <description>Deepak Arumugam, Mohanapriya Subramani, Divyakaaviri Subramani, Ravi Shankar, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396505102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deepak Arumugam, Mohanapriya Subramani, Divyakaaviri Subramani, Ravi Shankar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inducing Microstrain in Electrodeposited Pt through Polymer Addition for Highly Active Oxygen Reduction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01244</link>
      <description>Qi Hua, Xinyi Chen, Junfeng Chen, Nawal M. Alghoraibi, Yoon Min Lee, Toby J. Woods, Richard T. Haasch, Steven C. Zimmerman, Andrew A. Gewirth, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396506273

                We investigate an approach to tune the d-band center and enhance the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity of Pt material without relying on foreign metals or the process of alloying/dealloying. It is known that Pt exhibits suboptimal ORR catalytic activity due to its strong binding to oxygen, therefore requiring a downshift in the d-band center by approximately 0.2 eV to weaken the Pt-O binding energy and boost ORR kinetics. We found that the d-band center can be tuned by inducing microstrain in the Pt electrodeposit, simply achieved by introducing polymer into the electrodeposition bath. Pt electrodes (Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA) prepared with the addition of poly-N-(6-aminohexyl)acrylamide (P1) or poly-l-arginine (PLA) exhibit improved ORR activity compared to Pt electrodeposited without polymer addition (Pt-alone) in both acidic and basic environments, with the order of activity being Pt-P1 &gt; Pt-PLA &gt; Pt-alone. Pt-P1 exhibits a positive shift of E1/2 by 90 mV vs Pt-alone in basic solution, comparable to other reported high-activity ORR catalysts. Scanning electron microscopy shows the presence of agglomerates with diameters between 5 and 20 &#956;m and tip-splitting growth structure due to diffusion-limited aggregation on Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA. Characterization using X-ray photoemission spectroscopy and X-ray diffraction, combined with Rietveld refinement analysis reveal a trend of downshifted d-band center, increased microstrain, and slightly increased compressive strain as the ORR activity increased among the three catalysts. The presence of more defective sites on Pt-P1 and Pt-PLA is the cause of the increased microstrain, which further leads to the downshift of the Pt d-band center and enhancement of ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Qi Hua, Xinyi Chen, Junfeng Chen, Nawal M. Alghoraibi, Yoon Min Lee, Toby J. Woods, Richard T. Haasch, Steven C. Zimmerman, Andrew A. Gewirth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in Biomass Electro&#8208;Valorization for Paired Electrosynthesis of Valuable Chemicals and Fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202300302</link>
      <description>Abdelkader Abderrahmane, Sophie Tingry, David Cornu, Yaovi Holade, Advanced energy and sustainability research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396507340

                Environmental and energy concerns surrounding the use of fossil fuels are driving an increasingly rapid transition to sustainable and eco&#8208;responsible processes. Electrochemical processes can provide the necessary sustainability and economic roadmap for storing intermittent and renewable electricity by synthesizing, in cogeneration electrolyzers, energy carriers and/or synthetic chemicals (hydrogen, ammonia, etc.) via flagship reduction reactions (hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR), etc.). To balance the electrochemical process, these cathodic processes have long been coupled to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which ultimately consumes almost 90% of the energy input. Recent years have witnessed an overwhelming development of anode scenarios based on biomass substrates, because OER cannot be driven below a certain potential threshold, while organics are thermodynamically more favorable. Therefore, paired electrolysis, which refers to cases where electrochemical oxidation and reduction are desired, embraces the electrocatalysis community for the electrolytic production of hydrogen, ammonia, etc. (cathode side), in parallel with value&#8208;added chemicals (anode side), all with a modest electricity input. The trade&#8208;off is selectivity at relevant current densities. This review discusses, the progress, challenges, and potential of biomass&#8208;fueled paired electrosynthesis of valuable chemicals and fuels. Fundamental principles, main biomass solubilization methods, and different scenarios for paired electrosynthesis are presented.</description>
      <author>Abdelkader Abderrahmane, Sophie Tingry, David Cornu, Yaovi Holade</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202300302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing intrinsic electric fields in 2D Janus MoOX (X=S, Se, and Te) monolayers for enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.257</link>
      <description>Zakaryae Haman, Moussa Kibbou, Nabil Khossossi, Elhoussaine Ouabida, Poulumi Dey, I. Essaoudi, A. Ainane, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396507627

                Two-dimensional (2D) Janus monolayers, distinguished by their intrinsic vertical electric fields, emerge as highly efficient and eco-friendly materials for advancing the field of hydrogen evolution reactions (HER). In this study, we explore, for the first time, the potential viability of the oxygenation phase of two-dimensional Janus transition metal dichalcogenides MoOX (X = S, Se, and Te) monolayers as an exceptionally efficient photocatalyst for hydrogen production. Based on first-principles computations, we demonstrate that all three monolayers exhibit semiconductor behavior, characterized by a band gap ranging from 0.66 to 1.55 eV. This narrow band gap renders the proposed materials highly efficient at absorbing light within the visible region. Excitingly, the introduction of an electrostatic potential difference &#916;&#934; has granted us the ability to surpass the conventional bandgap limit (Eg&#8805;1.23). Consequently, all monolayers exhibit favorable band alignment with respect to the vacuum level. Moreover, the calculated solar-to-hydrogen efficiency for the envisaged monolayer exceeds the established theoretical limit. Particularly, the MoOTe monolayer emerges as an infrared-light-driven photocatalyst, demonstrating a remarkable solar-to-hydrogen efficiency limit of up to 25,21% when considering the entire solar spectrum. A thorough examination of the Gibbs free energy differences across these monolayers has revealed that the values during the oxygenation phase are significantly smaller and approach the optimum, in contrast to the parental two-dimensional Janus transition metal dichalcogenides. Our results conclusively establish that the proposed materials exhibit exceptional efficiency as photocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reactions. Notably, their efficacy is demonstrated even in the lack of co-catalysts or sacrificial agents.</description>
      <author>Zakaryae Haman, Moussa Kibbou, Nabil Khossossi, Elhoussaine Ouabida, Poulumi Dey, I. Essaoudi, A. Ainane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanotubes from Lanthanide-Based Misfit-Layered Compounds: Understanding the Growth, Thermodynamic, and Kinetic Stability Limits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c00481</link>
      <description>M. B. Sreedhara, Azat Khadiev, Kai Zheng, Simon Hettler, Marco Serra, Ivano E. Castelli, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Dmitri Novikov, R. Tenne, Chemistry of materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396510105

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. B. Sreedhara, Azat Khadiev, Kai Zheng, Simon Hettler, Marco Serra, Ivano E. Castelli, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Dmitri Novikov, R. Tenne</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c00481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA-Anchored Single-Molecule Iron Phthalocyanine As an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00795</link>
      <description>Yi Qin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, XIA LIU, Xian Liang, Linfeng Xie, Kuan Wang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yang Liu, Yawei Chen, Zhijun Lei, Pengfei Yan, Liang Wu, Shuhong Jiao, Qing Li, Ruiguo Cao, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396512258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Qin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, XIA LIU, Xian Liang, Linfeng Xie, Kuan Wang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yang Liu, Yawei Chen, Zhijun Lei, Pengfei Yan, Liang Wu, Shuhong Jiao, Qing Li, Ruiguo Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly selective electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to multi-carbon products at CuPd synergistic sites over OD-Cu based catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160189</link>
      <description>Jianguo Wen, Yue Gong, Ting Tan, Tao He, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396513970

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianguo Wen, Yue Gong, Ting Tan, Tao He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction of Pt&#8211;Co diatomic sites catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.254</link>
      <description>Bin Li, Rong Cao, Zhu Hai-yan, Ping Liu, Bingbing Suo, Yawei Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396515642

                Hydrolytic Hydrogen is a clean hydrogen production method. To mitigate the substantial costs associated with water electrolysis, electrocatalysts are crucial in decreasing the cathodic reaction involved in hydrogen hydrolysis, specifically, the overpotential for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Compared to traditional catalysts and single-atom catalysts, Pt&#8211;Co diatomic sites catalyst exhibit excellent hydrogen evolution reaction activity and stability. We have established eight different structures of dual-center metal catalysts based on graphene planes. A systematic study was conducted on the catalytic performance and mechanism of these configurations, among which the structure with the best hydrogen evolution reaction activity was CoN4/PtC2N2, with a Gibbs free energy (&#916;G) of 0.004 eV. Electronic structure analysis confirms that H follows the Sabatier mechanism on diatomic catalysts, and the catalyst exhibits excellent HER performance for moderate adsorption strength of H atoms. The d-band centers of Co and Pt atoms in the electrocatalyst CoN4&#8211;PtC2N2 are lower than those of a single system, indicating that the electronic effect between the CoN4 and PtC2N2 sites can enhance the inherent HER activity of the catalyst. This study expands the application scope of dual-site catalysts and provides new insights for the design and synthesis of dual-site hydrogen evolution catalysts.</description>
      <author>Bin Li, Rong Cao, Zhu Hai-yan, Ping Liu, Bingbing Suo, Yawei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights on 3D transition metal anchored poly[5,10,15,20-tetra(4-ethynylphenyl)porphyrin]diyne as highly efficient bifunctional catalyst toward ORR and OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114188</link>
      <description>Jian Gao, Ruiping Deng, Jing Wang, Ying Wang, Kai Li, Zhijian Wu, Molecular catalysis. 561(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396516874

                Searching for highly active oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is a challenging task in the development of clean energy devices. Herein, by using the poly[5,10,15,20-tetra(4-ethynyl-phenyl)porphyrin]diyne (TEPPD), we designed ORR and OER catalysts by anchoring 3d transition metal into TEPPD (TM@TEPPD, TM = Mn-Zn). Our study indicated that Fe@TEPPD is the best bifunctional catalyst for both ORR and OER. By proposing a proper descriptor, Ni-N3@TEPPD (Ni is only coordinated with three N atoms) is designed and also predicted to be a promising bifunctional catalyst. For Fe@TEPPD, ORR and OER become inactive when the acetylene bond in TEPPD is broken. The surface Pourbaix diagram indicated that on the surface of Fe@TEPPD, ORR and OER can be carried out at the whole pH region due to the high dissolution potential of Fe2+. For Ni-N3@TEPPD, however, the dissolution potential 0.71 V for Ni2+is low. Thus, for Ni-N3@TEPPD, ORR can be carried out only after pH&gt;2.54, while OER is not likely at the whole pH region. This suggested that the conclusions from the free energy changes at URHE=0 and pH=0 could be different when different potentials and pH values are considered.</description>
      <author>Jian Gao, Ruiping Deng, Jing Wang, Ying Wang, Kai Li, Zhijian Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding selective hydrogenation of phenylacetylene on PdAg single atom alloy: DFT insights on molecule size and surface ensemble effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115523</link>
      <description>Hossam Ibrahim, Timo Weckman, Dmitry Yu. Murzin, Karoliina Honkala, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396520431

                Single atom alloys (SAAs) have proven to be effective catalysts, offering customizable properties for diverse chemical processes. Various metal combinations are used in SAAs and Pd dispersed materials are frequently employed in catalyzing hydrogenation reactions. Herein, we explore the hydrogenation of phenylacetylene to styrene and ethylbenzene on PdAg SAA using density functional theory calculations. Our results show that while PdAg SAA does improve the activity of the host Ag towards hydrogenation, a dilute PdAg SAA surface with isolated Pd-atoms is not selective towards partial hydrogenation of phenylacetylene. Additionally, we investigate how the size of the reactant molecule, the size of the metal alloy ensemble, and a ligand effect impact the hydrogenation process. The SAA enhances the binding strengths of various organic adsorbates, although this effect diminishes as the adsorbate size increases. Our findings indicate the dilute PdAg exhibits selectivity towards hydrogenation of smaller molecules such acetylene due to its distinct adsorption geometry. The selective hydrogenation of phenylacetylene necessitates a surface Pd dimer ensemble. Our research highlights the importance of both reactant molecule size and surface configurations in SAA catalysts. This is particularly crucial when dealing with the adsorption of sizable organic molecules where the functional group can adopt different adsorption modes.</description>
      <author>Hossam Ibrahim, Timo Weckman, Dmitry Yu. Murzin, Karoliina Honkala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon electrodes for the electrocatalytic synthesis of hydrogen peroxide: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5805(24)60846-2</link>
      <description>Xianhuai Huang, Xueqing Yang, Ling Gui, Shiyong Liu, Kun Wang, Hongwei Rong, Wei Wei, New carbon materials. 39(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396520736

                Electrocatalytic oxygen reduction by a 2e&#8722; pathway enables the instantaneous synthesis of H2O2, a process that is far superior to the conventional anthraquinone process. In recent years, the electrocatalytic synthesis of H2O2 using carbon electrodes has attracted more and more attention because of its excellent catalytic performance and superior stability. The relationship between material modification, wettability and the rate of H2O2 synthesis and service life is considered together with the three-phase interface. The structure of the carbon electrodes and the principles of electrocatalytic H2O2 synthesis are first introduced, and four major catalysts are reviewed, namely, monolithic carbon materials, metal-free catalysts, noble metal catalysts and non-precious metal catalysts. The effects of the metal anode and the electrolyte on the three-phase interface are described. The relationship between carbon electrode wettability and the three-phase interface is described, pointing out that modification focusing on improving the selectivity of the 2e&#8722; pathway can also impact electrode wettability. In addition, the relationship between the design of the components in the electrochemical system and their effect on the efficiency of H2O2 synthesis is discussed for carbon electrodes. Finally, we present our analysis of the current problems in the electrocatalytic synthesis of H2O2 for carbon electrodes and future research directions.</description>
      <author>Xianhuai Huang, Xueqing Yang, Ling Gui, Shiyong Liu, Kun Wang, Hongwei Rong, Wei Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5805(24)60846-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic transition of 1D ferromagnetic catalysts during the NO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115524</link>
      <description>Zhan-peng Wang, Yi-jie Chen, Shui-yang Fang, Xianjie Zhang, Wei Zhang, Fu-li Sun, Wenxian Chen, Guilin Zhuang, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396520986

                Exploration of magnetic phase transitions during electrochemical processes is of great importance for rational design of supported magnetic-metal electrocatalysts. Herein, we systematically investigated the magnetic transition between ferromagnetism (FM) and anti-ferromagnetism (AFM) in one-dimensional ferromagnetic Co chain supported on graphene (Co4N8-gra) during NO electroreduction (NORR) process, focusing on the impact of potential and acidity on the catalytic property and magnetic transition. A combination of catalytic kinetics calculations and microkinetic simulations reveals that the Co4N8-gra exhibits excellent NH3 selectivity and thermal stability. In the implicit solvent model, the general reaction follows optimal pathway: *+NO(g) &#8594; *NO &#8594; *HNO &#8594; *H2NO &#8594; *H2NOH &#8594; *NH2 &#8594; *NH3 &#8594; *+NH3, with the potential-determining step (PDS) identified as *NO &#8594; *HNO. In acidic solvent, the magnetic transitions follow the pathway (FM &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; FM) under an applied potential of &#8722;0.20 V/RHE. In neutral solvent, the magnetic transitions occur according to this pathway (FM &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; FM &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; FM) under an applied potential of &#8722;0.14 V/RHE. In an alkaline solvent, the magnetic transitions proceed along this sequence (FM &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM2 &#8594; FM &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; AFM1 &#8594; FM) under an ultralow potential of &#8722;0.08 V/RHE. Essentially, the improvement of catalytic property is attributed to the synergistic influence of external potential and magnetic-state transition on the adsorption of reaction species (e.g., NO and NH3). Magnetic transitions are closely associated with ligand field effect of metal site with variable valence electron induced by applied potential. In general, this study provides valuable insights for the controllable design of magnetic metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhan-peng Wang, Yi-jie Chen, Shui-yang Fang, Xianjie Zhang, Wei Zhang, Fu-li Sun, Wenxian Chen, Guilin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory-guided construction of Cu-O-Ti-Ov active sites on Cu/TiO2 catalysts for efficient electrocatalytic nitrate reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64618-2</link>
      <description>Yuefeng Nie, H.F. Yan, Suwei Lu, Hongwei Zhang, Tingting Qi, Shijing Liang, Lilong Jiang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396521285

                Electrocatalytic nitrate reduction reaction (NO3RR) has been capturing immense interest in the industrial application of ammonia synthesis, and it involves complex reaction routes accompanied by multi-electron transfer, thus causing a challenge to achieve high efficiency for catalysts. Herein, we customized the Cu-O-Ti-Ov (oxygen vacancy) structure on the Cu/TiO2 catalyst, identified through density functional theory (DFT) calculations as the synergic active site for NO3RR. It is found that Cu-O-Ti-Ov site facilitates the adsorption/association of NOx&#8211; and promotes the hydrogenation of NO3&#8211; to NH3 via adsorbed *H species. This effectively suppresses the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and exhibits a lower reaction energy barrier for NO3RR, with the reaction pathways: NO3* &#8594; NO2* &#8594; HONO* &#8594; NO* &#8594; *NOH &#8594; *N &#8594; *NH &#8594; *NH2 &#8594; *NH3 &#8594; NH3. The optimized Cu/TiO2 catalyst with rich Cu-O-Ti-Ov sites achieves an NH3 yield rate of 3046.5 &#956;g h&#8211;1 mgcat&#8211;1 at &#8211;1.0 V vs. RHE, outperforming most of the reported activities. Furthermore, the construction of Cu-O-Ti-Ov sites significantly mitigates the leaching of Cu species, enhancing the stability of the Cu/TiO2 catalyst. Additionally, a mechanistic study, using in situ characterizations and various comparative experiments, further confirms the strong synergy between Cu, Ti, and Ov sites, which is consistent with previous DFT calculations. This study provides a new strategy for designing efficient and stable electrocatalysts in the field of ammonia synthesis.</description>
      <author>Yuefeng Nie, H.F. Yan, Suwei Lu, Hongwei Zhang, Tingting Qi, Shijing Liang, Lilong Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64618-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electrocatalytic Activity for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Alloys is Determined by Element-Specific Adsorption Sites rather than d-Band Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01084a</link>
      <description>Maximilian Schalenbach, Rebekka Tesch, Piotr M. Kowalski, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396525048

                Trends of the electrocatalytic activities across transition metals are typically explained by d-band properties such as center or upper edge positions in relation to Fermi levels. Here, the universality of...</description>
      <author>Maximilian Schalenbach, Rebekka Tesch, Piotr M. Kowalski, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01084a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photochemical hydrogen production using advanced semiconducting metal oxide nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-21456-1.00001-1</link>
      <description>Timur Sh. Atabaev, Kuralay Rustembekkyzy, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396530740

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timur Sh. Atabaev, Kuralay Rustembekkyzy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-21456-1.00001-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven physics-informed descriptors of cation ordering in multicomponent perovskite oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.101942</link>
      <description>Jiayu Peng, James Damewood, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Cell reports physical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396531391

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayu Peng, James Damewood, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.101942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergetic piezo-photocatalysis of g-C3N4/PCN-224 core-shell heterojunctions for ultrahigh H2O2 generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64629-7</link>
      <description>Lingyun Meng, Chen Zhao, Hong&#8208;Yu Chu, Yu-Hang Li, Huifen Fu, Peng Wang, Chong-Chen Wang, Hongwei Huang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396534062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingyun Meng, Chen Zhao, Hong&#8208;Yu Chu, Yu-Hang Li, Huifen Fu, Peng Wang, Chong-Chen Wang, Hongwei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64629-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourier-Transformed Alternating Current Voltammetry (FTacV) for Analysis of Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01526</link>
      <description>Rifael Z. Snitkoff-Sol, Alan M. Bond, Lior Elbaz, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396547671

                Electrocatalysts play a critical role in energy technologies, but the development of active, efficient, and durable catalysts is impeded by the lack of methodologies to deconvolute the complex interplay between various aspects influencing the activity of the catalysts, e.g., the number of active sites, turnover frequency, and the reaction pathways. Fourier-transformed alternating current voltammetry (FTacV) is an emerging tool for the analysis of electroactive species and has been successfully applied to a variety of reactions such as the oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, hydrogen evolution reaction, and hydrogen oxidation reaction. The harmonics generated from FTacV measurements neatly detect underlaying processes not visible by other, more commonly employed techniques for analysis of electrocatalysts, such as the rotating disc electrode and dc voltammetry. The harmonic components enable separating overlapping processes based on differences in kinetics or linearity of response. This paper presents a review of FTacV applied for the analysis of electrocatalysts. It highlights the importance of determining the electrochemically active site density (EASD) to decipher the intrinsic activity of a catalyst and discusses the use of FTacV in dynamic determination of the EASD over the course of a catalyst's working life, as well as the use of FTacV to understand intricate catalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Rifael Z. Snitkoff-Sol, Alan M. Bond, Lior Elbaz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the chemistry behind the electrolytic production of hydrogen peroxide by oxygenated carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.04.032</link>
      <description>Pan Xiang, Ke Yang, Qihao Yang, Yang Gao, Weiwei Xu, Zhiyi Lu, Liang Chen, Zhiming Wang, Ziqi Tian, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396554025

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pan Xiang, Ke Yang, Qihao Yang, Yang Gao, Weiwei Xu, Zhiyi Lu, Liang Chen, Zhiming Wang, Ziqi Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.04.032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy materials: Excellent energy-storage and conversion materials in the field of electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.partic.2024.04.010</link>
      <description>Jincan Li, Huiyu Duan, Long Qi, Zhang Bianjiang, Changyun Chen, Huan Pang, Particuology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396560051

                High-entropy materials (HEMs), a new type of materials, have attracted significant attention in the field of electrocatalytic reactions, batteries and energy-storage materials over the past few years owing to their unique structure, controllable elementary composition, and adjustable properties. These excellent characteristics result from four major factors: high entropy, sluggish-diffusion, severe lattice distortion, and cocktail effect, and are used widely in energy-energy applications. This review aims to summarize the recent progress of HEMs in electrochemical energy-storage. We begin with the concept, structure, and four core effects of HEMs that provide the basic information on HEMs. Next, we discuss the major properties of HEMs and analyze the relationship between their structures and properties. Furthermore, we highlight the outstanding performance of HEMs in hydrogen storage, electrode materials of batteries, catalysis, and supercapacitors, and briefly explain the mechanisms of these materials that are crucial in energy storage and conversion. This review will assist in understanding the excellent energy-storage properties, intricacies of the phase structures, elemental interactions, and reaction mechanisms associated with HEMs. Moreover, challenges and future development prospects are summarized. This work will provide insight into the factors that are crucial for designing HEMs with energy storage properties.</description>
      <author>Jincan Li, Huiyu Duan, Long Qi, Zhang Bianjiang, Changyun Chen, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.partic.2024.04.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the Cs/Cs-O adsorbed graphene/semiconductor heterojunction anode for thermionic converters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42768-024-00191-5</link>
      <description>Wei Sun, Haoran Xu, Hao Qiu, Gang Xiao, Waste Disposal &amp; Sustainable Energy/Waste disposal &amp; sustainable energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396217244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Sun, Haoran Xu, Hao Qiu, Gang Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42768-024-00191-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxyl-assisted globally spontaneous dynamic oxygen migration on biphenylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2024.115984</link>
      <description>Rubin Huo, Chuanjian Zhou, Boyi Situ, Zihan Yan, Hao Yang, Zhengyang Fei, Quan Jin, Ling Zhao, Z. Zhang, Yusong Tu, Physica. E, Low-dimensional systems and nanostructures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396521390

                Dynamic covalent interfaces (DCIs) can autonomously adjust their internal structures and dynamically respond to changes in the external environment, thus holding broad application prospects in drug delivery, molecular detection, and interface catalysis. However, the dynamic properties of such DCIs greatly rely on the localized exchanges or formations of chemical bonds, seriously constraining the adaptive response efficiency. To transcend the limitations of the dynamic two-dimensional (2D) scales, employing the experimentally synthesized biphenylene monolayer as a prototype, we systematically study the hydroxyl-assisted globally spontaneous dynamic oxygen migration on biphenylene interface based on the first-principles calculations and machine-learning-based molecular dynamics (MLMD) simulations. The calculated results indicate that the stable dangling oxygen atoms on the biphenylene monolayer can attract the proton in the interfacial water, which in turn undergoes a water dissociation process and produces hydroxyl groups on the biphenylene interface. Assisted by the hydroxyl groups, the dangling oxygen atoms can achieve long-range migration, exhibiting notably low energy barriers (0.09 eV, 0.04 eV) due to the reversible proton transfer reactions. Therefore, the local dynamic covalent behaviors of oxygen atoms on the biphenylene interface are broken with the oxygen atoms migrating between the adjacent C4 rings. More importantly, the charge density difference and Bader charge analysis demonstrate that the presence of hydroxyl groups significantly enhance the stability of the dangling oxygen, effectively reducing energy barriers of oxygen migration compared to epoxy on the biphenylene interface. Furthermore, the MLMD trajectories visually show the process of realizing large-area DCIs on the biphenylene monolayer. Our work not only clarifies the oxygen-related dynamic behavior of the biphenylene interface, but also provides new ideas for the realization of large-area dynamic covalent materials (DCMs) on other carbon-based or 2D materials.</description>
      <author>Rubin Huo, Chuanjian Zhou, Boyi Situ, Zihan Yan, Hao Yang, Zhengyang Fei, Quan Jin, Ling Zhao, Z. Zhang, Yusong Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2024.115984</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
