<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 01:25:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy Engineering in the First Coordination Shell of Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts for Enhanced Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412000</link>
      <description>Xinqi Chen, Tong Zhou, Tianwei He, Qingju Liu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408286006

                Abstract Modulating the coordination environment of active centers has been proven to be an effective strategy for tuning the activity and selectivity of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs). However, most current research primarily focuses on altering non&#8208;metallic elements coordinating with the single metal atom. In this study, a novel approach is presented by introducing various vacancies into the first coordination shell of single&#8208;atom doped boron&#8211;carbon&#8211;nitride (BCN) catalysts, systematically evaluating their hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions performances. Results indicate that the introduction of vacancy defects enhances the stability of M&#8208;B X C Y N Z structures. Furthermore, adjusting the coordinating atoms around metal sites modulates charge distribution, influencing the binding propensity of intermediates on the adsorption sites and promoting synergistic effects between metal and nonmetal, thereby altering catalytic activity. Specifically, among 147 M&#8208;B X C Y N Z and M&#8208;B X C Y N Z &#8208;vacancy structures, 17 catalysts with excellent HER performance have been identified. Notably, C&#8208;vacancy modulated Ni&#8208;BC 2 N exhibits an OER overpotential of only 0.36V, suggesting that Ni&#8208;BC 2 N&#8208;C1 may serve as an efficient multifunctional electrocatalyst for water&#8208;splitting reactions. This work employs vacancy engineering to precisely modulate the first coordination shell of single&#8208;atom catalysts, not only screening out efficient HER/OER electrocatalysts but also providing guidance for the development of potential BCN&#8208;based multifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xinqi Chen, Tong Zhou, Tianwei He, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed dual-active-site catalyst for enhanced oxygen reduction reaction: Synergistic effects of Fe and V in M&#8722;N&#8722;C structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161441</link>
      <description>Qi&#8208;Dong Ruan, Rui Feng, Lu Liu, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Ya-Cheng Shi, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408286463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi&#8208;Dong Ruan, Rui Feng, Lu Liu, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Ya-Cheng Shi, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Non&#8208;Resonant Infrared Optical Second Harmonic Generation in Bulk Crystals of Van der Waals Semiconductor, SnP&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202402649</link>
      <description>Jadupati Nag, Saugata Sarker, Safdar Imam, Abishek K. Iyer, Michael J. Waters, Albert Suceava, James M. Rondinelli, Mercouri G. Kanatzidis, Venkatraman Gopalan, Advanced Optical Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408287469

                Abstract 2D van der Waals (vdW) materials have emerged as a highly promising candidates for nonlinear optical (NLO) applications. This study presents the synthesis, comprehensive linear optical, and optical second harmonic generation (SHG) characterization of a novel 2D vdW semiconductor SnP 2 Se 6 in its bulk single crystal form. It exhibits an indirect bandgap of &#8776;1.47 eV and an exceptional non&#8208;resonant SHG coefficient of d 33 &#8764; &#8722;222 &#177; 30 pm V &#8722;1 at a fundamental wavelength of 2 &#181;m, which is &#8776;7 times larger than that of the commercial AgGaSe 2 with a comparable bandgap. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations of the linear and nonlinear optical properties exhibit reasonable agreement with the experimental measurements, revealing the chemical origin of the enhanced properties. Moreover, SnP 2 Se 6 can exhibit both type&#8208;I and type&#8208;II phase matching over a wide spectral range, fulfilling one of the key criteria for an ideal NLO crystal. These exceptional properties position SnP 2 Se 6 as a highly promising candidate for NLO applications.</description>
      <author>Jadupati Nag, Saugata Sarker, Safdar Imam, Abishek K. Iyer, Michael J. Waters, Albert Suceava, James M. Rondinelli, Mercouri G. Kanatzidis, Venkatraman Gopalan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202402649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Adsorption Isotherm That Includes the Interactions between Adsorbates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08754</link>
      <description>Simon I. Hansen, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Tejs Vegge, Anker Degn Jensen, Jakob Munkholt Christensen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408291776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simon I. Hansen, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Tejs Vegge, Anker Degn Jensen, Jakob Munkholt Christensen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size-effect induced controllable Cu0-Cu+ sites for ampere-level nitrate electroreduction coupled with biomass upgrading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57097-x</link>
      <description>Yuxuan Lu, Feng Yue, Tianyang Liu, Yucheng Huang, Feng Fu, Yu Jing, Hengquan Yang, Chunming Yang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408292176

                The synergistic Cu0-Cu+ sites is regarded as the active species towards NH3 synthesis from the nitrate electrochemical reduction reaction (NO3-RR) process. However, the mechanistic understanding and the roles of Cu0 and Cu+ remain exclusive. The big obstacle is that it is challenging to effectively regulate the interfacial motifs of Cu0-Cu+ sites. In this paper, we describe the tunable construction of Cu0-Cu+ interfacial structure by modulating the size-effect of Cu2O nanocube electrocatalysts to NO3-RR performance. We elucidate the formation mechanism of Cu0-Cu+ motifs by correlating the macroscopic particle size with the microscopic coordinated structure properties, and identify the synergistic effect of Cu0-Cu+ motifs on NO3-RR. Based on the rational design of Cu0-Cu+ interfacial electrocatalyst, we develop an efficient paired-electrolysis system to simultaneously achieve the efficient production of NH3 and 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid at an industrially relevant current densities (2 A cm&#8722;2), while maintaining high Faradaic efficiencies, high yield rates, and long-term operational stability in a 100 cm2 electrolyzers, indicating promising practical applications. It is challenging to regulate the interfacial motifs of Cu0-Cu+ sites to understand roles of Cu0 and Cu+ for nitrate electrochemical reduction reaction. Here, the authors report a tunable construction of Cu0-Cu+ interfacial structure by modulating the size-effect of Cu2O electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuxuan Lu, Feng Yue, Tianyang Liu, Yucheng Huang, Feng Fu, Yu Jing, Hengquan Yang, Chunming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57097-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom-Embedded Nitrogen-Doped Graphene as Efficient Electrocatalysts for the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00728</link>
      <description>Yinlong Tan, Y. Niu, Ji Xu, X.Y. Cui, Haiming Duan, Qun Jing, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408300849

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have displayed unprecedented activity and selectivity for electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Herein, a series of metal single atoms embedded on nitrogen-doped graphene (M&#8211;N4G, where M = In, Tl, Ge, Sn, Pb, Sb, and Bi) is systematically evaluated as CO2RR electrocatalysts by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The computational results show that most M&#8211;N4G exhibit better CO2RR selectivity over the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Ge/Pb&#8211;N4G exhibits excellent electrocatalytic performance in the generation of HCOOH from the CO2RR with low limiting potentials of &#8722;0.292 and &#8722;0.306 eV, which surpass the performance of the vast majority of electrocatalysts. Adsorption energy of the key intermediate *HCOO can be used as an effective reactivity reaction descriptor to screen promising CO2RR catalysts. The results of this work highlight M&#8211;N4G as an ideal electrochemical for the electrocatalytic CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Yinlong Tan, Y. Niu, Ji Xu, X.Y. Cui, Haiming Duan, Qun Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru&#8208;Doped Fe&#8322;TiO&#8325; as a High&#8208;Performance Electrocatalyst for Urea&#8208;Assisted Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412370</link>
      <description>Kassa Belay Ibrahim, Karim Harrath, Mohammad Hamrang, Matteo Bordin, St&#233;phanie Bruy&#232;re, David Horwat, Enrique Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Castell&#243;n, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Pratik V. Shinde, Danilo Oliveira de Souza, Luca Olivi, Alberto Vomiero, Elisa Moretti, Tofik Ahmed Shifa, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408301701

                The urea oxidation reaction (UOR), with its low thermodynamic potential, offers a promising alternative to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for efficient hydrogen production. However, its sluggish kinetics still demand the development of an efficient electrocatalyst. In this study, the critical role of Ru doping in Fe&#8322;TiO&#8325; is demonstrated to accelerate UOR kinetics. The computational finding confirmed the feasibility of this approach, guiding the experimental synthesis of Fe2-xRuxTiO5. Benefitting from surface properties and electronic structure, the synthesized material exhibits superior performance with a potential of 1.30 V at a current density of 10 mA cm-2 for UOR, compared to undoped Fe2TiO5 (1.40 V). Moreover, it demonstrates a favourable Tafel slope of 52 mV dec-1 and maintains robust durability for 72 h. As confirmed from experimental and computational findings, the enhanced activity can be attributed to the Ru doping resulting in structural distortion at the Fe site and creation of a favourable adsorption site thereby enhancing UOR via dual active center. This study not only broadens the potential applications of Fe2TiO5-based materials beyond their traditional role as photocatalysts but also establishes them as promising electrocatalysts underscoring the versatility and improved performance of Fe2-xRuxTiO5.</description>
      <author>Kassa Belay Ibrahim, Karim Harrath, Mohammad Hamrang, Matteo Bordin, St&#233;phanie Bruy&#232;re, David Horwat, Enrique Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Castell&#243;n, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Pratik V. Shinde, Danilo Oliveira de Souza, Luca Olivi, Alberto Vomiero, Elisa Moretti, Tofik Ahmed Shifa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412370</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering TM&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@C&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Covalent-Organic Frameworks for Enhanced Water-Splitting and Oxygen Reduction Reactions: A Constant Potential and Feature Coevaluation Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c05368</link>
      <description>Yajuan Feng, Xihang Zhang, Renxian Qin, Qingjun Zhou, Yu-Ling Song, Qiang Zhang, Chunping Hou, Zhenjin Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408301839

                The development of highly active metal-based single-atom catalysts (SACs) is crucial for energy conversion and storage, offering optimized atom utilization and high catalytic activity, with bifunctional SACs for hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution/reduction (OER/ORR) reactions providing greater efficiency and cost-effectiveness than monofunctional catalysts, making them scientifically and economically valuable. By integrating density functional theory and machine learning methods, we systematically evaluated the potential of TM&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 monolayers as efficient HER/OER/ORR catalysts, revealing that 27 TM atoms remain stable on N2@C15N5S3H5 with a TM&#8211;N2 coordination environment. Rh&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 outperforms Pt in HER, while Rh&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 drives both HER and OER, while Ni&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 catalyzes OER and ORR, making them bifunctional catalysts. Comparative activity analysis reveals that the Ni-d orbitals in Ni&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 interact with O-p orbitals, pairing up electrons from antibonding states into downward bonding orbitals, thus fitting OH* adsorption and enhancing catalytic performance. We further examined the pH and applied potential effects on OER/ORR performance of Ni&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 and Rh&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 monolayers, both show enhanced OER in acidic conditions, with Ni&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 excelling in ORR under alkaline conditions and Rh&#8211;N2@C15N5S3H5 in acidic conditions. Moreover, machine learning techniques were applied to explore the correlation between catalytic activity and a range of structural and atomic properties.</description>
      <author>Yajuan Feng, Xihang Zhang, Renxian Qin, Qingjun Zhou, Yu-Ling Song, Qiang Zhang, Chunping Hou, Zhenjin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c05368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of increasing bending rigidity of graphene with temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120150</link>
      <description>Martin T&#248;mterud, Simen K. Hellner, Sabrina D. Eder, Stiven Forti, Domenica Convertino, J. R. Manson, Camilla Coletti, Thomas Frederiksen, Bodil Holst, Carbon. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408304783

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Martin T&#248;mterud, Simen K. Hellner, Sabrina D. Eder, Stiven Forti, Domenica Convertino, J. R. Manson, Camilla Coletti, Thomas Frederiksen, Bodil Holst</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ adsorption-coupled-oxidation enabled mercury vapor capture over sp-hybridized graphdiyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57197-8</link>
      <description>Honghu Li, Chuanqi Pan, Xiyan Peng, Biluan Zhang, Siyi Song, Ze Xu, Xiaofeng Qiu, Yun-Long Liu, Jinlong Wang, Yanbing Guo, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408305564

                Abstract Developing efficient and sustainable carbon sorbent for mercury vapor (Hg 0 ) capture is significant to public health and ecosystem protection. Here we show a carbon material, namely graphdiyne with accessible sp -hybridized carbons (HsGDY), that can serve as an effective &#8220;trap&#8221; to anchor Hg atoms by strong electron-metal-support interaction, leading to the in-situ adsorption-coupled-oxidation of Hg. The adsorption process is benefited from the large hexagonal pore structure of HsGDY. The oxidation process is driven by the surface charge heterogeneity of HsGDY which can itself induce the adsorbed Hg atoms to lose electrons and present a partially oxidized state. Its good adaptability and excellent regeneration performance greatly broaden the applicability of HsGDY in diverse scenarios such as flue gas treatment and mercury-related personal protection. Our work demonstrates a sp -hybridized carbon material for mercury vapor capture which could contribute to sustainability of mercury pollution industries and provide guide for functional carbon material design.</description>
      <author>Honghu Li, Chuanqi Pan, Xiyan Peng, Biluan Zhang, Siyi Song, Ze Xu, Xiaofeng Qiu, Yun-Long Liu, Jinlong Wang, Yanbing Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57197-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoparticle-Driven cathode for hydrogen production in microbial electrolysis cell: Synergies and impact</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135020</link>
      <description>Pankaj Kumar, Suraj Prakash Singh Rana, Sakshi, Abdulaziz A.M. Abahussain, Lakhveer Singh, Fuel. 393(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408306343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pankaj Kumar, Suraj Prakash Singh Rana, Sakshi, Abdulaziz A.M. Abahussain, Lakhveer Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Regulation Strategies of Atomic Cobalt Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423552</link>
      <description>Mengyu Chen, Jingqi Guan, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408307736

                Abstract Oxygen electrocatalysis is a core reaction in renewable energy devices, greatly promoting the transformation and upgrading of the energy structure. Nonetheless, the performance of energy conversion devices is hindered by the large overpotential and slow kinetics of oxygen electrocatalytic reactions. Recently, single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as promising contenders in the field of oxygen electrocatalysis because of their exceptional metal atom utilization, distinctive coordination environment, and adjustable electronic properties. This review presents the latest advancements in the design of Co&#8208;based SACs for oxygen electrocatalysis. First, the OER and ORR mechanisms are introduced. Subsequently, the strategies for regulating the electronic structure of Co&#8208;based SACs are summarized in three aspects, including coordination environment, metal centers, and support carriers. A particular emphasis is given to the relationship between the structure and properties of catalysts. Afterward, the latest applications of Co&#8208;based SACs in energy conversion devices are explored. Ultimately, the challenges and prospects for Co&#8208;based SACs are prospected.</description>
      <author>Mengyu Chen, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Flexocatalytic Potential of Wide&#8208;Bandgap Spinel Oxides: Light&#8208;Free Hydrogen Evolution via Strain&#8208;Induced Polarization and Oxygen Vacancy Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424279</link>
      <description>K. Tu, Hsun&#8208;Yen Lin, Jyh&#8208;Pin Chou, Jyh Ming Wu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408307788

                Abstract Wide&#8208;bandgap spinel oxides, such as ZnAl 2 O 4 (ZAO) and ZnCr 2 O 4 (ZCO), are traditionally limited by poor electron activation under light irradiation, resulting in suboptimal photocatalytic performance. This study investigates a novel approach to overcoming these limitations by leveraging the flexoelectric effect in centrosymmetric porous nanoparticles with wrinkled surfaces. The inhomogeneous strain gradients generated under mechanical force induce flexoelectric polarization, offering a promising pathway to enhance photocatalytic activity. ZAO outperforms ZCO due to the smaller atomic radius of aluminum, allowing greater atomic displacement and higher polarization, which prolongs electron&#8208;hole recombination. Oxygen vacancies (O V ) further enhance ZAO performance, with ZAO&#8208;200 (annealed at 200 &#176;C) achieving the longest carrier lifetime (4.65 ns) and an exceptional hydrogen evolution rate of 3737 &#181;mol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 &#8212;206% higher than pristine ZAO&#8212;without light stimulation. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations confirm a lower hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) energy barrier for ZAO (&#916;G H = &#8722;0.13 eV) compared to ZCO (1.34 eV) and reveal spontaneous water splitting at O V sites without energy input. A unique butterfly curve validates flexoelectric potential generation from strain gradients. These findings establish a novel framework for eco&#8208;friendly hydrogen production, demonstrating that flexoelectric polarization and O V engineering can surpass traditional photocatalytic methods in sustainability and efficiency.</description>
      <author>K. Tu, Hsun&#8208;Yen Lin, Jyh&#8208;Pin Chou, Jyh Ming Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lighting the Path to Practical Applications of Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts in Photocatalysis: The Role of Platinum Group Single Atoms in Enhancing Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202400804</link>
      <description>Zi Qi Chen, Aldrich Ngan, Christopher T. Chan, Jaeha Lee, David Dwi Sanjaya, Frank Gu, Solar RRL. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408308385

                Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) show promise because of their efficient use of precious metals, unique coordination and electronic structures, and excellent tunability. Photocatalysis can harvest solar energy to drive energetically unfavorable reactions under mild conditions, offering a sustainable alternative to energy&#8208;intensive reactions. However, the efficiency of solar photocatalysis is limited by poor solar spectrum utilization and rapid charge recombination. Integrating single atoms into semiconductor photocatalysts is a promising route to address these limitations. Mechanistic understanding of single&#8208;atom photocatalysis is crucial for developing efficient catalysts as they guide effective material design. This work provides an overview of the current knowledge on platinum group SACs applied to photocatalytic applications with a focus on the role of single atoms in photocatalytic reactions. The review begins with a summary of the unique advantages of platinum group metal SACs as well as their common structures. A concise summary of synthesis methods is then provided, followed by a comprehensive review of characterization methods for SAC structure, photoelectronic properties, and mechanisms of action. Next, the role of single atoms in improving general photocatalytic processes as well as specific reactions are discussed. Finally, future outlooks for SAC development are included to guide further advancements in the field.</description>
      <author>Zi Qi Chen, Aldrich Ngan, Christopher T. Chan, Jaeha Lee, David Dwi Sanjaya, Frank Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/solr.202400804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Superatomic (Li/Na/K)-Al-Sc Cluster Catalysts for Selective Electrochemical HER and NRR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08178</link>
      <description>Ritika Saroha, Shweta Choudhary, R. Brahma, Swastika Banerjee, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408312144

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ritika Saroha, Shweta Choudhary, R. Brahma, Swastika Banerjee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B modulating MXene/Graphene heterojunction catalyst for highly efficient NO electrochemical synthesis of ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135055</link>
      <description>Fengjuan Guo, Junwei Ma, Xiaoyan Deng, Hongtao Gao, Fuel. 393(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408313118

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengjuan Guo, Junwei Ma, Xiaoyan Deng, Hongtao Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Pt/TiO2-Ov catalysts for enhanced electron transfer and CO tolerance in acidic HOR and ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-025-0990-8</link>
      <description>Bianyong Lian, Jinghong Chen, Lingfei Li, Shu&#8208;Qi Deng, Kaili Wang, Wei Yan, Jiujun Zhang, Frontiers in Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408315636

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bianyong Lian, Jinghong Chen, Lingfei Li, Shu&#8208;Qi Deng, Kaili Wang, Wei Yan, Jiujun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-025-0990-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface state of NiOOH under oxidative conditions: Can dopants induce surface oxidation?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.145960</link>
      <description>Laureline Treps, Tony Ermacora, A. Giacomelli, Carine Michel, Stephan N. Steinmann, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408318897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Laureline Treps, Tony Ermacora, A. Giacomelli, Carine Michel, Stephan N. Steinmann</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.145960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium-cobalt alloy nanoparticles uniformly dispersed on carbon nanotube films for high-performance electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137309</link>
      <description>Weixue Meng, Rui Pang, Ding Zhang, Junge Yuan, Lei Lu, Yuanyuan Shang, Yingjiu Zhang, Anyuan Cao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 690(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408318929

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weixue Meng, Rui Pang, Ding Zhang, Junge Yuan, Lei Lu, Yuanyuan Shang, Yingjiu Zhang, Anyuan Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Nitride Catalysts for Photoelectrochemical and Electrochemical Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20240013</link>
      <description>Hee Ryeong Kwon, Jin Wook Yang, Ho Won Jang, Exploration. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408321147

                ABSTRACT Metal nitrides have emerged as promising materials for photoelectrochemical and electrochemical catalysis due to their unique electronic properties and structural versatility, offering high electrical conductivity and abundant active sites for catalytic reactions. Herein, we comprehensively explore the characteristics, synthesis, and application of diverse metal nitride catalysts. Fundamental features and catalytic advantages of metal nitrides are presented in terms of electronic structure and surface chemistry. We deal with synthetic principles and parameters of metal nitride catalysts in terms of nitrogen source, introducing synthesis strategies of metal nitrides with various morphologies and phases. Recent progress of metal nitride catalysts in (photo)electrochemical reactions, such as hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, oxygen reduction, nitrogen reduction, carbon dioxide reduction, and biomass valorization reactions, is discussed with their tailored roles. By providing future direction for remaining challenges, this review aims to guide the design of metal nitride catalysts from a materials point of view, contributing to expanding into energy and environmental technologies.</description>
      <author>Hee Ryeong Kwon, Jin Wook Yang, Ho Won Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20240013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Cu&#8211;Ni/W&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;58&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for Hydrogenation of Nitriles to Secondary Amines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00668</link>
      <description>Jia&#8208;qi Bai, Mei Ma, Huangfei Liu, Zhangkai Qian, Da-Yan Liu, Yuncai Zhao, Yijing Gao, Jingshuai Chen, Mengdie Cai, Song Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408323578

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia&#8208;qi Bai, Mei Ma, Huangfei Liu, Zhangkai Qian, Da-Yan Liu, Yuncai Zhao, Yijing Gao, Jingshuai Chen, Mengdie Cai, Song Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkaline hydrogen oxidation reaction on nickel-based non-noble metal electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100400</link>
      <description>Lulu An, Tonghui Zhao, Wen Lei, Chang Yang, Junhao Yang, Deli Wang, eScience. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408326706

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lulu An, Tonghui Zhao, Wen Lei, Chang Yang, Junhao Yang, Deli Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2025.100400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ball milling-induced strain engineering in nanoporous catalysts for tailoring hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161491</link>
      <description>Qite Li, Wence Xu, Zhonghui Gao, Yanqin Liang, Hui Jiang, Zhaoyang Li, Zhenduo Cui, Heng Liu, Shengli Zhu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408328104

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qite Li, Wence Xu, Zhonghui Gao, Yanqin Liang, Hui Jiang, Zhaoyang Li, Zhenduo Cui, Heng Liu, Shengli Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Pt Carbon Aerogel Electrocatalysts with Multiscale Porosity Derived from Cellulose and Chitosan Biopolymer Aerogels via Supercritical Deposition for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400433</link>
      <description>Ala Abdulalem Abdo Moqbel Alsuhile, Philip Sidney Pein, &#350;ansim Bengisu Bar&#305;m, Selmi Erim Bozba&#287;, &#1048;&#1088;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072; &#1057;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Can Erkey, Baldur Schroeter, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408333127

                The aim of this study is to investigate the activity and stability of carbon aerogel&#8208;supported platinum electrocatalysts in the hydrogen evolution reaction, compared to current solutions based on carbon black. Self&#8208;synthesized carbon aerogels (pyrolyzed cellulose, and chitosan&#8208;based aerogels) with multiscale porosity and high overall specific surface area (up to &#8776;2500 m 2 g &#8722;1 ), as well as Vulcan XC&#8208;72R supports were loaded via supercritical deposition (SCD) with platinum nanoparticles (mean particle diameter &#8776;1.3&#8211;2.0 nm, 2.8&#8211;3.8 wt% Pt loading). Overpotentials ranged from 46.5 to 50.0 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , whereas self&#8208;synthesized electrocatalysts had similar overpotentials as compared to a commercial catalyst with &#8776;8&#8211;10 times higher Pt loading. In addition, Pt&#8208;carbon aerogel electrocatalysts had higher stability and durability as compared to Pt&#8208;Vulcan, most probably due to the high micro&#8208; to mesoporosity of carbon aerogels, which promotes nanoparticle stability. The current density at 40 mV for Pt&#8208;Vulcan decreased by 80% after 20 h, whereas an insignificant drop was observed for Pt&#8208;carbon aerogels. These results show that the applied combination of materials (biopolymer&#8208;based carbon aerogels) and loading method (SCD) are a promising approach for synthesizing stable electrocatalysts with reduced platinum content for green hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Ala Abdulalem Abdo Moqbel Alsuhile, Philip Sidney Pein, &#350;ansim Bengisu Bar&#305;m, Selmi Erim Bozba&#287;, &#1048;&#1088;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072; &#1057;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Can Erkey, Baldur Schroeter</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommendation System to Predict the d&#8208;band Center of Core&#8208;Shell Bimetallic Nanoparticles Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202401460</link>
      <description>Sakshi Agarwal, Abhishek K. Singh, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408343076

                Abstract Core&#8208;shell nanoparticles are an important class of catalytic materials due to the presence of unsaturated bonds, phase&#8208;separated metals, and synergistic effect of more than one elements. Exploring the electronic properties such as the &#8208;band center () and the related catalytic properties of these materials are quite challenging due to resource consuming experiments and computationally expensive modeling of the nanoparticles. Therefore, a density functional theory (DFT) coupled recommendation system based approach is developed to predict the of the core&#8208;shell nanoparticles. Here, the recommendation system involves completion of a core&#8208;shell interaction matrix, where each matrix element represents the of a unique core&#8208;shell pair. Matrix completion by predicting the interaction matrix elements is carried out using neural network. The neural network generated a low dimensional representations for each core and shell metals, which are learned iteratively to predict corresponding of the pair. The learned representations brilliantly captures the similarities and dissimilarities between metals present in shell or core. A very low train/test RMSE of 0.009/0.009 is obtained with elemental features based model. The same model is further employed to predict the &#8208;band width (), suggesting its transferability. This approach recommends the optimum range of / along with the combination of core&#8208;shell metals having most efficient adsorption of species for any reaction. The results presented in this study can help experimentally design the core&#8208;shell nanoparticles having a desired catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Agarwal, Abhishek K. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202401460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast and stable tight-binding framework for nonlocal kinetic energy density functional reconstruction in orbital-free density functional calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.125133</link>
      <description>Yun-Ting Chen, Cheng Ma, Bo Cui, Tian Cui, Wenhui Mi, Qiang Xu, Yanchao Wang, Yanming Ma, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408345037

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yun-Ting Chen, Cheng Ma, Bo Cui, Tian Cui, Wenhui Mi, Qiang Xu, Yanchao Wang, Yanming Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.125133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-demand heralded MIR single-photon source using a cascaded quantum system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adr9239</link>
      <description>Jake Iles-Smith, Mark Kamper Svendsen, &#193;ngel Rubio, Martijn Wubs, Nicolas Stenger, Science Advances. 11(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408345684

                We propose a mechanism for generating single photons in the mid-infrared (MIR) using a solid-state or molecular quantum emitter. The scheme uses cavity quantum electrodynamics (QED) effects to selectively enhance a Frank-Condon transition, deterministically preparing a single Fock state of a polar phonon mode. By coupling the phonon mode to an antenna, the resulting excitation is then radiated to the far field as a single photon with a frequency matching the phonon mode. By combining macroscopic QED calculations with methods from open quantum system theory, we show that optimal parameters to generate these MIR photons occur for modest light-matter coupling strengths, which are achievable with state-of-the-art technologies. Combined, the cascaded system we propose provides a quasi-deterministic source of heralded single photons in a regime of the electromagnetic spectrum where this previously was not possible.</description>
      <author>Jake Iles-Smith, Mark Kamper Svendsen, &#193;ngel Rubio, Martijn Wubs, Nicolas Stenger</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adr9239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic design of hierarchical and heterostructural P-NiMoO4@Net-like Ni2P for enhanced hydrogen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137313</link>
      <description>Jian Tang, Jun Fang, Haochen Yao, Jimeng Wei, Geng Gao, Yusong Yang, Bin Yang, Yaochun Yao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408348348

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Tang, Jun Fang, Haochen Yao, Jimeng Wei, Geng Gao, Yusong Yang, Bin Yang, Yaochun Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nanotube/metal organic framework hybrid scaffolds for scalable and self-structured OER catalyst coating: From rheology study to MEA fabrication</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161533</link>
      <description>Suhyeon Lee, Yunseong Ji, Gisu Doo, MinJoong Kim, J. Shin, Chansol Kim, Man Ho Han, Woong Hee Lee, Jong Hyup Lee, Yunsang Kwak, Eun&#8208;Ji Choi, Yonghwi Cho, Choong Hoo Lee, Minsu Kim, Jung Tae Park, Dae Woo Kim, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408350488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suhyeon Lee, Yunseong Ji, Gisu Doo, MinJoong Kim, J. Shin, Chansol Kim, Man Ho Han, Woong Hee Lee, Jong Hyup Lee, Yunsang Kwak, Eun&#8208;Ji Choi, Yonghwi Cho, Choong Hoo Lee, Minsu Kim, Jung Tae Park, Dae Woo Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon confined Mo doped CoP for alkali overall water splitting with enhanced catalytic activity and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161519</link>
      <description>Jiabing Luo, Yongxiao Tuo, Jianchao Zhang, Wenle Li, Shutao Wang, Yanpeng Li, Yuan Pan, Yan Zhou, Jun Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408359997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiabing Luo, Yongxiao Tuo, Jianchao Zhang, Wenle Li, Shutao Wang, Yanpeng Li, Yuan Pan, Yan Zhou, Jun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal Relationship between Electrochemical Symmetry and Thermodynamic Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07958</link>
      <description>Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408367828

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite Type ABO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Oxides in Photocatalysis, Electrocatalysis, and Solid Oxide Fuel Cells: State of the Art and Future Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00553</link>
      <description>Muhammad Humayun, Zhishan Li, Muhammad Israr, Abbas Khan, Wei Luo, Chundong Wang, Zongping Shao, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408370225

                Since photocatalytic and electrocatalytic technologies are crucial for tackling the energy and environmental challenges, significant efforts have been put into exploring advanced catalysts. Among them, perovskite type ABO3 oxides show great promising catalytic activities because of their flexible physical and chemical properties. In this review, the fundamentals and recent progress in the synthesis of perovskite type ABO3 oxides are considered. We describe the mechanisms for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions (OER), oxygen reduction reactions (ORR), hydrogen evolution reactions (HER), nitrogen reduction reactions (NRR), carbon dioxide reduction reactions (CO2RR), and metal-air batteries in details. Furthermore, the photocatalytic water splitting, CO2 conversion, pollutant degradation, and nitrogen fixation are reviewed as well. We also stress the applications of perovskite type ABO3 oxides in solid oxide fuel cells (SOFs). Finally, the optimization of perovskite type ABO3 oxides for applications in various fields and an outlook on the current and future challenges are depicted. The aim of this review is to present a broad overview of the recent advancements in the development of perovskite type ABO3 oxides-based catalysts and their applications in energy conversion and environmental remediation, as well as to present a roadmap for future development in these hot research areas.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Humayun, Zhishan Li, Muhammad Israr, Abbas Khan, Wei Luo, Chundong Wang, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-Surface Synthesis of 1D and 2D Porphyrin Metal&#8211;Organic Networks on Ag(100) Tuned by Substrate Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08308</link>
      <description>Nataly Herrera&#8208;Reinoza, D. J. Mowbray, Alejandro P&#233;rez Paz, Alisson Ceccatto dos Santos, Rodrigo Cezar de Campos Ferreira, Abner de Siervo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408370716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nataly Herrera&#8208;Reinoza, D. J. Mowbray, Alejandro P&#233;rez Paz, Alisson Ceccatto dos Santos, Rodrigo Cezar de Campos Ferreira, Abner de Siervo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms and Promising Cathode Catalysts for Metal&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527834815.ch2</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Zhiqian Hou, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408382619

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Zhiqian Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527834815.ch2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic performance of SrMn1-xCoxO3 perovskite metal oxides for oxygen reactions in Zn-air batteries: Influence of Mn/Co ratio</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsadv.2025.100725</link>
      <description>Paula Riquelme-Garc&#237;a, M. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Rodr&#237;guez, J.X. Flores-Lasluisa, Diego Cazorla&#8208;Amor&#243;s, Emilia Morall&#243;n, Applied Surface Science Advances. 27(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408386815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paula Riquelme-Garc&#237;a, M. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Rodr&#237;guez, J.X. Flores-Lasluisa, Diego Cazorla&#8208;Amor&#243;s, Emilia Morall&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsadv.2025.100725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyimide Modified with Different Types and Contents of Polar/Nonpolar Groups: Synthesis, Structure, and Dielectric Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/polym17060753</link>
      <description>Ting Li, Jie Liu, Shuhui Yu, Xiaojun Zhang, Zhiqiang Chen, Polymers. 17(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408387819

                Polyimide-based dielectric materials, as excellent high-temperature-resistant polymers, play a crucial role in advanced electronic devices and power systems. However, given the limitations of composite PI materials, it is a significant challenge to simultaneously improve the dielectric constant and breakdown strength of intrinsic polyimide dielectric materials to achieve high energy density. In this study, an indiscriminate copolymerization method was proposed, which utilizes two different diamine monomers with bulky side groups (-CF3) and high polarity (C-O-C), respectively, to copolymerize with the same dianhydride monomer and prepare a series of intrinsic PI films. Remarkably, PI films with a highly dipolar rigid backbone maintain excellent thermal and mechanical properties while enhancing dipole polarization. Meanwhile, a high breakdown strength of PI is shown, because the bulky side groups act as deep traps to capture and disperse charges during the charge transfer process. Under the optimal copolymer ratio, the dielectric constant and dielectric loss are 4.2 and 0.008, respectively. At room temperature, the highest breakdown strength reaches 493MV/m, and the energy storage density and charge&#8211;discharge efficiency are 5.07 J/cm3 and 82%, respectively. Finally, based on density functional theory calculations, the copolymerization tendencies of the three monomers are verified, and it is speculated that the copolymerization ratio of PI-60% is the most stable and exhibits the best overall performance, which perfectly aligns with the experimental results. These experimental results demonstrate the exciting potential of intrinsic polyimide in thin film capacitors.</description>
      <author>Ting Li, Jie Liu, Shuhui Yu, Xiaojun Zhang, Zhiqiang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/polym17060753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NaCl-Assisted electrospinning of bifunctional carbon fibers for High-Performance flexible zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137325</link>
      <description>Zhixin Wang, Chuanjun Fan, Yingjie Chen, Ye Yuan, J.J. Xue, Na Yu, Jianguang Feng, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408389293

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhixin Wang, Chuanjun Fan, Yingjie Chen, Ye Yuan, J.J. Xue, Na Yu, Jianguang Feng, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic catalysis of Fe-Co bimetallic sulfides for efficient water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162901</link>
      <description>H. Li, Jun Yao, Zhiqiang Peng, Mengyun Yang, Taotao Zhao, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408389491

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Li, Jun Yao, Zhiqiang Peng, Mengyun Yang, Taotao Zhao, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Beneficial Role of Transition-Metal Layer Na&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; Substitution on the Structure and Electrochemical Properties of the P2-Layered Cathode Na&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;/2&lt;/sub&gt;TeO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02798</link>
      <description>Nicholas S. Grundish, Graeme Henkelman, John B. Goodenough, Claude Delmas, Dany Carlier, Ieuan D. Seymour, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408391539

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicholas S. Grundish, Graeme Henkelman, John B. Goodenough, Claude Delmas, Dany Carlier, Ieuan D. Seymour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Se&#8208;Assisted Modulation of Electronic Structure of Ruthenium Phosphide Nanotubes for Efficient Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400610</link>
      <description>Yongju Hong, Eunsoo Lee, Jae Hun Seol, Tae Kyung Lee, Songa Choi, Seong Chan Cho, Taekyung Kim, Hionsuck Baik, Sangyeon Jeong, Sung Jong Yoo, Sang Uck Lee, Kwangyeol Lee, Small Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408404032

                Anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) holds immense promise for hydrogen (H 2 ) production yet faces challenges due to the sluggish kinetics of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Highly efficient and durable catalysts for HER are crucial for the successful implementation of AEMWE to produce hydrogen gas reliably. Ruthenium phosphides (Ru x P) have emerged as promising non&#8208;Pt catalysts for alkaline HER; however, they suffer from rapid degradation due to weak Ru&#63743;P bonding, which cannot protect the Ru center from further oxidation and subsequent dissolution. Herein, first&#8208;principles calculations indicate the enhanced stability of Ru&#63743;Se against oxidation compared to Ru&#63743;P, highlighting the importance of introducing Se into the Ru 2 P phase. Electrochemical studies using the selenium (Se)&#8208;doped Ru 2 P double&#8208;walled nanotubes (Ru 2 (P 0.9 Se 0.1 ) DWNTs) demonstrate significantly lower overpotentials (29 mV @ 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and robust stability (&gt;50 h) in 1.0 m KOH, surpassing those of Pt/C. In AEMWE, Ru 2 (P 0.9 Se 0.1 ) DWNTs exhibit an outstanding performance (10.31 A cm &#8722;2 @ 80 &#176;C, stable @ 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 for &#8776;200 h), surpassing state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art catalysts. The findings of this study highlight the pivotal role of anion modification in enhancing the catalytic stability and performance for efficient hydrogen production in AEMWE systems.</description>
      <author>Yongju Hong, Eunsoo Lee, Jae Hun Seol, Tae Kyung Lee, Songa Choi, Seong Chan Cho, Taekyung Kim, Hionsuck Baik, Sangyeon Jeong, Sung Jong Yoo, Sang Uck Lee, Kwangyeol Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Transition Metal 3d Spin state on Single&#8208;atom Catalysts for Selective Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417034</link>
      <description>Yipeng Zang, Yan Liu, Ruihu Lu, Qin Yang, B.X. Wang, Mingsheng Zhang, Yu Mao, Ziyun Wang, Yanwei Lum, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408416065

                Abstract Tuning transition metal spin states potentially offers a powerful means to control electrocatalyst activity. However, implementing such a strategy in electrochemical CO 2 reduction (CO 2 R) is challenging since rational design rules have yet to be elucidated. Here we show how the addition of P dopants to a ferromagnetic element (Fe, Co, and Ni) single&#8208;atom catalyst (SAC) can shift its spin state. For instance, with Fe SAC, P dopants enable a switch from low spin state ( d x2&#8208; y2 0 , d z2 0 , d xz 2 , d yz 1 , d xy 2 ) in Fe&#8208;N 4 to high spin state ( d x2&#8208;y2 0 , d xz 1 , d yz 1 , d z2 1 , d xy 2 ) in Fe&#8208;N 3 &#8208;P. This is studied using a suite of characterization efforts, including X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS), electron spin resonance (ESR) spectroscopy, and superconducting quantum interference device (SQUID) measurements. When used for CO 2 R, the SAC with Fe&#8208;N 3 &#8208;P active sites yields &gt; 90% Faradaic efficiency to CO over a wide potential window of &#8776;530 mV and a maximum CO partial current density of &#8776;600 mA cm &#8722;2 . Density functional theory calculations reveal that high spin state Fe 3+ exhibits enhanced electron back donation via the d xz / d yz &#8208;&#960;* bond, which enhances * COOH adsorption and promotes CO formation. Taken together, the results show how the SAC spin state can be intentionally tuned to boost CO 2 R performance.</description>
      <author>Yipeng Zang, Yan Liu, Ruihu Lu, Qin Yang, B.X. Wang, Mingsheng Zhang, Yu Mao, Ziyun Wang, Yanwei Lum</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-equilibrium Plasma Activated Ultradurable Molybdenum Oxycarbide Electrocatalysts for Acidic Hydrogen Evolution up to 10 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5954144/v1</link>
      <description>Guoping Xiong, Shiwen Wu, Taesoon Hwang, Amirarsalan Mashhadian, Tianyi Li, Yuzi Liu, Dewen Hou, Kyeongjae Cho, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408419335

                Abstract Electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution in acidic media at industrial-level current densities is limited by high overpotential, performance degradation, and thus low throughput. To address these issues, we developed a novel nanoedge-enriched molybdenum oxycarbide (MoOxCy) electrocatalysts with a uniform phase by non-equilibrium plasma-enhanced chemical vapor deposition. The vertically standing MoOxCy exhibits low overpotential of 415 mV and outstanding long-term operational stability (~ 0.11% performance degradation over 1,000 h) at high current densities up to 10 A cm&#8722; 2, corresponding to an ultrahigh hydrogen throughput of 4,477.4 L cm&#8722; 2 and a lifetime throughput of 407,033 L cm&#8722; 2 which exceed the department of energy (DOE) targets of 1,253.7 L cm&#8722; 2 and 100,503 L cm&#8722; 2, respectively. Molybdenum oxycarbide catalysts outperform state-of-the-art transition metal- and even noble metal-based catalysts (throughput of 9 ~ 269 L cm&#8722; 2 and lifetime throughput of 8 ~ 269 L cm&#8722; 2) by more than an order of magnitude for throughput and three orders of magnitude for lifetime throughput. The key mechanisms enabling high catalytic performance and stability are achieved by incorporating carbon into MoO2 lattices, which reduces the valence state of Mo, leading to weakened binding energy of Mo-H and thus improved hydrogen evolution performance. Density functional theory results suggest that the presence of carbon atoms in MoOxCy increases the binding energy between Mo and the adjacent atoms, improving the stability of MoOxCy operating under harsh conditions. This work paves the way for the development of new transition metal-based catalysts for practical industrial electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Guoping Xiong, Shiwen Wu, Taesoon Hwang, Amirarsalan Mashhadian, Tianyi Li, Yuzi Liu, Dewen Hou, Kyeongjae Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5954144/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing N- and F-Dual-Doped Pt-Based Heterojunction Catalysts via Synergistic Electronic Modulation for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Activity and CO Tolerance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c03350</link>
      <description>Yu Hao, Dongfang Chen, Dongyi Pu, Song Hu, Pavese Doague Nguela, Pucheng Pei, Xiaoguang Xu, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408421210

                The development of efficient and durable hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalysts is critical for sustainable energy conversion. Although platinum (Pt) serves as a benchmark HER catalyst, its practical application is hindered by the high cost, limited durability, and susceptibility to CO poisoning. In this work, we report a heterojunction Pt-based catalyst, Pt@NCL-MXene, synthesized by LiF etching of MXene and subsequent NH3 calcination. This process introduces dual nitrogen (N) and fluorine (F) doping and yields a nitrogen-doped carbon layer (NCL) coating on Pt nanoparticles with an average size of only 3.4 nm. Compared with conventional Pt&#8211;C catalysts, Pt@NCL-MXene exhibits a larger specific surface area, enhanced electron transfer efficiency, and an optimized d-band center, thereby facilitating both H* adsorption and desorption. As a result, Pt@NCL-MXene achieves a significantly lower overpotential of 73 mV at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2, alongside improved kinetics and stability under operational conditions. Furthermore, the 9 wt % F-rich MXene support effectively suppresses CO adsorption on Pt, reducing the CO uptake to 0.224 mmol g&#8211;1, which is purportedly lower than that of Pt&#8211;C (0.264 mmol g&#8211;1), thereby mitigating CO poisoning and prolonging the catalyst's service life. These findings offer insights into the rational design of advanced CO-resistant Pt-based HER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yu Hao, Dongfang Chen, Dongyi Pu, Song Hu, Pavese Doague Nguela, Pucheng Pei, Xiaoguang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c03350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Electrosynthesis of an Amino Acid from a Biomass Derivative</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00171</link>
      <description>Zamaan Mukadam, Sihang Liu, S&#248;ren B. Scott, Yuxiang Zhou, Georg Kastlunger, Mary P. Ryan, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Ifan E. L. Stephens, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408425966

                The electrochemical synthesis of nitrogen-containing molecules from biomass-derived compounds under ambient conditions is demonstrated, relying only on green sources of feedstock, renewable energy, and water. In this study, we report a two-step method of electrochemically synthesizing 5-(aminomethyl)furan-2-carboxylic acid (AFCA) from 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) using hydroxylamine (NH2OH) as the nitrogen source in an acidic electrolyte. In the first step, HMF was reductively aminated into (5-(aminomethyl)furan-2-yl)methanol (HMFA) using NH2OH as the source of nitrogen. This was followed by a second step, involving the oxidation of HMFA to AFCA on a manganese oxide (MnOx) anode at the same pH. MnOx was able to selectively oxidize the alcohol group on HMFA to produce AFCA with 35% Faradaic efficiency without affecting the amine group. As both of these reactions are completed in a pH 1 electrolyte, it eliminates the need to separate HMFA before proceeding with the second reaction. Among different metal electrodes (Ag, Au, Cu, Pb, Pt and Sn) tested for the electrochemical reductive amination reaction, Ag electrodes displayed the best performance to selectively aminate HMF to the intermediate species, HMFA, with up to 69% Faradaic efficiency at mild potentials of &#8722;0.50 VRHE. Density functional theory calculations were carried out to explore a possible reaction pathway for the reductive amination on Ag(111), which suggests a thermodynamically feasible reaction even at 0 VRHE. The cathodic experimental reaction parameters were optimized to reveal that an electrolyte pH of 1 is optimal for the electrochemical reductive amination reaction. Our work shapes the future possibility of an electrochemical synthesis to produce AFCA without the need for any product separation between steps by combining the Ag cathode reaction to the MnOx anode reaction sharing the same electrolyte. Since both the cathode and anode reactions both involve four electrons transferred, combining both half reactions in a single electrochemical reactor can eliminate the need for energy-wasting auxiliary counter reactions such as hydrogen evolution or water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Zamaan Mukadam, Sihang Liu, S&#248;ren B. Scott, Yuxiang Zhou, Georg Kastlunger, Mary P. Ryan, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Ifan E. L. Stephens</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active phase discovery in heterogeneous catalysis via topology-guided sampling and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57824-4</link>
      <description>Shisheng Zheng, Ximing Zhang, Heng-Su Liu, Ge-Hao Liang, S.J. Zhang, Wentao Zhang, Bingxu Wang, Jingling Yang, Xian&#8217;an Jin, Feng Pan, Jianfeng Li, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408444321

                Understanding active phases across interfaces, interphases, and even within the bulk under varying external conditions and environmental species is critical for advancing heterogeneous catalysis. Describing these phases through computational models faces the challenges in the generation and calculation of a vast array of atomic configurations. Here, we present a framework for the automatic and efficient exploration of active phases. This approach utilizes a topology-based algorithm leveraging persistent homology to systematically sample configurations across diverse coordination environments and material morphologies. Simultaneously, efficient machine learning force fields enable rapid computations. We demonstrate the effectiveness of this framework in two systems: hydrogen absorption in Pd, where hydrogen penetrates subsurface layers and the bulk, inducing a "hex" reconstruction critical for CO2 electroreduction, explored through 50,000 sampled configurations; and the oxidation dynamics of Pt clusters, where oxygen incorporation renders the clusters less active during oxygen reduction reactions, investigated through 100,000 sampled configurations. In both cases, the predicted active phases and their impacts on catalytic mechanisms closely align with previous experimental observations, indicating that the proposed strategy can model complex catalytic systems and discovery active phases under specific environmental conditions. Discovering active phases in heterocatalysis entails efficient configuration sampling and optimization. Here, the authors developed a framework based on topology and machine learning to effectively explore the active structures, applied in the CO2 electroreduction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction</description>
      <author>Shisheng Zheng, Ximing Zhang, Heng-Su Liu, Ge-Hao Liang, S.J. Zhang, Wentao Zhang, Bingxu Wang, Jingling Yang, Xian&#8217;an Jin, Feng Pan, Jianfeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57824-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CatTSunami: Accelerating Transition State Energy Calculations with Pretrained Graph Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04272</link>
      <description>Brook Wander, Muhammed Shuaibi, John R. Kitchin, Zachary W. Ulissi, C. Lawrence Zitnick, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408448357

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brook Wander, Muhammed Shuaibi, John R. Kitchin, Zachary W. Ulissi, C. Lawrence Zitnick</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning Graph Neural Networks via Active Learning: Unlocking the Potential of Graph Neural Networks Trained on Nonaqueous Systems for Aqueous CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00089</link>
      <description>Zihao Jiao, Yu Mao, Ruihu Lu, Ya Liu, Liejin Guo, Ziyun Wang, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408453275

                Graph neural networks (GNNs) have revolutionized catalysis research with their efficiency and accuracy in modeling complex chemical interactions. However, adapting GNNs trained on nonaqueous data sets to aqueous systems poses notable challenges due to intricate water interactions. In this study, we proposed an active learning-based fine-tuning approach to extend the applicability of GNNs to aqueous environments. The geometry optimization and transition state search workflows are designed to reduce computational costs while maintaining DFT-level accuracy. Applied to the CO2 reduction reaction, the workflow delivers a 2-3-fold acceleration in geometry optimization through a relaxed force threshold combined with DFT refinement. The versatility of the transition state search algorithm was demonstrated on key C-C coupling pathways, pinpointing *CO-*COH as the most energetically favorable pathway in aqueous systems of Cu and Cu-based Ag, Au, and Zn alloys. The Br&#248;nsted-Evans-Polanyi relationship remains robust under water-induced fluctuations, with alloyed metals such as Al, Ga, and Pd, along with Ag, Au, and Zn, exhibiting coupling efficiency comparable to that of Cu. Additionally, perturbation-based training on forces and energies extends the application of GNNs to aqueous ab initio molecular dynamics simulations, enabling efficient modeling of dynamical trajectories. This work presents novel approaches to adapting nonaqueous models for application in aqueous systems, highlighting GNNs' potential in solvated environments and laying a foundation for accelerating predictions of catalytic mechanisms under realistic conditions.</description>
      <author>Zihao Jiao, Yu Mao, Ruihu Lu, Ya Liu, Liejin Guo, Ziyun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ transformation and synergistic electrocatalysis of asymmetric threefold hollow sites in rosebud-like ternary metal diselenide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161585</link>
      <description>Shihao Wang, Lin Liao, Jinsong Wu, Haolin Tang, Haining Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408462171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shihao Wang, Lin Liao, Jinsong Wu, Haolin Tang, Haining Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-specific synergy in heterogeneous single atoms for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57864-w</link>
      <description>Peiyu Ma, Jiawei Xue, Jihong Li, Heng Cao, Ruyang Wang, Ming J. Zuo, Zhirong Zhang, Jun Bao, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408474317

                Abstract Heterogeneous single-atom systems demonstrate potential to break performance limitations of single-atom catalysts through synergy interactions. The synergy in heterogeneous single atoms strongly dependes on their anchoring sites. Herein, we reveal the site-specific synergy in heterogeneous single atoms for oxygen evolution. The Ru T Ir V /CoOOH is fabricated by anchoring Ru single atoms onto three-fold facial center cubic hollow sites and Ir single atoms onto oxygen vacancy sites on CoOOH. Moreover, Ir T Ru V /CoOOH is also prepared by switching the anchoring sites of single atoms. Electrochemical measurements demonstrate the Ru T Ir V /CoOOH exhibits enhanced OER performance compared to Ir T Ru V /CoOOH. In-situ spectroscopic and mechanistic studies indicate that Ru single atoms at three-fold facial center cubic hollow sites serve as adsorption sites for key reaction intermediates, while Ir single atoms at oxygen vacancy sites stabilize the *OOH intermediates via hydrogen bonding interactions. This work discloses the correlation between the synergy in heterogeneous single atoms and their anchoring sites.</description>
      <author>Peiyu Ma, Jiawei Xue, Jihong Li, Heng Cao, Ruyang Wang, Ming J. Zuo, Zhirong Zhang, Jun Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57864-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser-Induced Strong Metal-Lunar Basalt Interaction for Boosted Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110879</link>
      <description>Bing Wang, Gap Soo Chang, Yue Xu, Fengyu Zhou, Xin Liu, Yingfang Yao, Xi Zhu, Qingmei Su, Zhigang Zou, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408476239

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Wang, Gap Soo Chang, Yue Xu, Fengyu Zhou, Xin Liu, Yingfang Yao, Xi Zhu, Qingmei Su, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insight into defective molybdenum carbide as cathode catalyst in Li-CO2 battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fub.2025.100058</link>
      <description>Tingting Zhao, Lixiang Yan, Xueying Qiu, Liubin Song, Yanmei Nie, Yuhao Xiong, Ao Li, Yukang Su, Likai Yan, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408479150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Zhao, Lixiang Yan, Xueying Qiu, Liubin Song, Yanmei Nie, Yuhao Xiong, Ao Li, Yukang Su, Likai Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fub.2025.100058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the Ti:Al:Cr proportion on the structure and oxidation resistance of ternary intermetallic coatings produced by non-vacuum electron beam cladding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intermet.2025.108745</link>
      <description>Daria V. Lazurenko, Alexey A. Ruktuev, Yu. N. Malyutina, Gleb Dovzhenko, Lin Song, &#1053;. &#1057;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1072;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Elena Lozhkina, E. V. Domarov, Arina V. Ukhina, Intermetallics. 181(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408489714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daria V. Lazurenko, Alexey A. Ruktuev, Yu. N. Malyutina, Gleb Dovzhenko, Lin Song, &#1053;. &#1057;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1072;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Elena Lozhkina, E. V. Domarov, Arina V. Ukhina</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intermet.2025.108745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain engineering in gradient-structured metallic glasses for excellent overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.02.024</link>
      <description>Chaoqun Pei, Shuangqin Chen, Jiuyuan Xie, Shidong Feng, Mingyuan Yu, Cheng Zhan, Yuyang Qian, Guannan Yang, Yuxuan Chen, Si Lan, Erjun Kan, Yue Wang, Xiaoke Mu, Horst Hahn, Baoan Sun, Gerhard Wilde, Tao Feng, Materials Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408491533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoqun Pei, Shuangqin Chen, Jiuyuan Xie, Shidong Feng, Mingyuan Yu, Cheng Zhan, Yuyang Qian, Guannan Yang, Yuxuan Chen, Si Lan, Erjun Kan, Yue Wang, Xiaoke Mu, Horst Hahn, Baoan Sun, Gerhard Wilde, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.02.024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of novel Fe0.11V2O5.15/g-C3N4 for electrochemical paracetamol detection and electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109468</link>
      <description>Shakeel Ahmad, Iqra Fareed, Muhammad Danish Khan, Tahmina Maqsood, Muhammad Saeed Akhtar, Mashal Firdous, Zulfiqar Ali, Yahya Sandali, Muhammad Bilal Tahir, Faheem K. Butt, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 192(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408492629

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shakeel Ahmad, Iqra Fareed, Muhammad Danish Khan, Tahmina Maqsood, Muhammad Saeed Akhtar, Mashal Firdous, Zulfiqar Ali, Yahya Sandali, Muhammad Bilal Tahir, Faheem K. Butt</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable training of trustworthy and energy-efficient predictive graph foundation models for atomistic materials modeling: a case study with HydraGNN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11227-025-07029-9</link>
      <description>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, Jong Youl Choi, Kshitij Mehta, Pei Zhang, David W. Rogers, Jonghyun Bae, Khaled Z. Ibrahim, Ashwin M. Aji, Karl W. Schulz, Jord&#224; Polo, Prasanna Balaprakash, The Journal of Supercomputing. 81(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408430868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, Jong Youl Choi, Kshitij Mehta, Pei Zhang, David W. Rogers, Jonghyun Bae, Khaled Z. Ibrahim, Ashwin M. Aji, Karl W. Schulz, Jord&#224; Polo, Prasanna Balaprakash</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11227-025-07029-9</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
