<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 01:27:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study on single-atom catalysts of Fe-V2CS2 with low overpotential and high selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2025.138467</link>
      <description>Yibo Sun, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Zeliang Ju, Qingxin Kang, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409051811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yibo Sun, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Zeliang Ju, Qingxin Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2025.138467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Substituent Effects in CO to CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;OH Conversion on a Cobalt Phthalocyanine Catalyst Using DFT Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07097</link>
      <description>Prasenjit Das, Ilya Grinberg, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409052190

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Prasenjit Das, Ilya Grinberg</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchoring single iridium atoms on defective nickel&#8211;iron layered double hydroxides for promoting oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121606</link>
      <description>Jianguo Huang, Ruijie Gao, Baowei Wang, Xun Cui, Lun Pan, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409053420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianguo Huang, Ruijie Gao, Baowei Wang, Xun Cui, Lun Pan, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V activated electro-epoxidation catalyst in membrane electrode assembly system for the production of propylene oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58486-y</link>
      <description>Yan Lin, Hui Li, Xiaodong Miao, Yang Sun, Hao Ren, Xifeng Yu, Wangyang Cui, Mingbo Wu, Zhongtao Li, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409060602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Lin, Hui Li, Xiaodong Miao, Yang Sun, Hao Ren, Xifeng Yu, Wangyang Cui, Mingbo Wu, Zhongtao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58486-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials for Electrocatalysis: Future Prospects in Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400254</link>
      <description>John M. George, Susikumar Thangarasu, J. Archana, P. Justin Jesuraj, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409075137

                Abstract Electrocatalysts play a pivotal role in various energy conversion processes, such as water splitting, batteries, carbon dioxide reduction, and fuel cell reactions, by significantly reducing the energy barrier and enhancing reaction kinetics. This review highlights the potential of earth&#8208;abundant electrocatalysts, with a particular focus on their capabilities in critical electrochemical reactions, including oxygen evolution reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction. Emphasis is also placed on bifunctional, trifunctional, and tetrafunctional performance, showcasing their adaptability and effectiveness across diverse energy applications. Exploration is done on a range of promising materials, including transition metal chalcogenides, MXenes, metal&#8208;organic frameworks, covalent organic frameworks, and layered double hydroxides. By examining their intrinsic properties, structural versatility, and surface engineering strategies, this review sheds light on the factors that govern their catalytic efficiency and stability. The integration of experimental advancements with theoretical insights provides a deeper understanding of mechanisms driving their catalytic activity. Additionally, we address the scalability, cost&#8208;effectiveness, and environmental impact of these materials, underlining their potential for large&#8208;scale deployment. By synthesizing recent progress and identifying challenges, this work delivers a roadmap for the model and application of multifunctional electrocatalysts, fostering innovations that align with the goals of sustainable energy systems.</description>
      <author>John M. George, Susikumar Thangarasu, J. Archana, P. Justin Jesuraj</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Antimony Tin Oxide with a Particle Assembly Structure as an IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Support for an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Proton-Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00875</link>
      <description>Zuobo Yang, Xiaokuan Wu, Leilei Cai, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, Xin Liang, Hong Zhao, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409076512

                Proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) holds great promise for hydrogen production applications. However, the reliance of PEMWE membrane electrodes on high loadings of expensive iridium poses a significant barrier to their commercial viability. Therefore, the development of high-performance oxygen evolution catalysts with a low iridium content is of critical importance. In this research, a porous antimony tin oxide (ATO) conductive support with a particle assembly aggregate structure was fabricated by a carbon template removal method. ATO-supported IrO2 exhibits significantly improved oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, with a much lower overpotential compared to the unsupported IrO2 catalyst. Moreover, it achieves 1.8 V at 2 A cm-2 with an ultralow loading of iridium (0.3 mgIr cm-2) for the proton-exchange membrane electrolyzer. Characterization techniques and density functional theory calculations have elucidated that the enhanced performance is attributed to the porous morphology of ATO and the strong metal oxide-support interaction between IrO2 and the ATO support. These findings validate the practicality of conductive nanostructured antimony-tin-oxide-supported catalysts for PEMWE applications and offer a pathway for the design of low-Ir OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zuobo Yang, Xiaokuan Wu, Leilei Cai, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, Xin Liang, Hong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polydisperse Pt Deposits Over TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Nanotube&#8208;Array&#8208;Supported Ru Nanoparticles: Harnessing the Interfacial Synergy for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411870</link>
      <description>Mila N. Krstaji&#263; Paji&#263;, Ana S. Dobrota, Anca Mazare, Sladjana Djurdji&#263;, Xin Zhou, Nikita Denisov, Natalia V. Skorodumova, Dragan Manojlovi&#263;, Rastko Vasili&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, Patrik Schmuki, U.&#268;. La&#269;njevac, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409084727

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective precious metal electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is key to realizing the economic viability of acidic water electrolysis. Herein, galvanic displacement is employed for in situ formation of bimetallic Pt/Ru deposits on H&#8208;intercalated TiO 2 nanotube arrays. It is found that a two&#8208;step procedure yields polydisperse deposits with a dominant fraction of Ru nanoparticles coated with atomic and subnanometric Pt islands. These Pt|Ru nanointerfaces induce charge transfer from Pt to Ru, which modulates the electronic structure of Pt sites for accelerated HER kinetics. By varying the platinization time in the second step, a balance between the exposure of catalytically active Pt|Ru nanointerfaces and the total number of Pt surface sites is achieved. The optimized composite, termed Ru&#8208;30min@Pt&#8208;30min, requires an overpotential of 58 mV to deliver a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1.0 m HClO 4 and maintains performance stability and structure integrity under prolonged operation. Moreover, it presents a 3.5&#8208;fold increase in precious metal mass activity over Pt/C at &#951; = 80 mV. Theoretical calculations reveal that the electronic interactions generated by Pt&#8208;modification of Ru and hydrogenated TiO 2 surfaces provide multiple active sites with improved H ads energetics compared to pure Pt and Ru.</description>
      <author>Mila N. Krstaji&#263; Paji&#263;, Ana S. Dobrota, Anca Mazare, Sladjana Djurdji&#263;, Xin Zhou, Nikita Denisov, Natalia V. Skorodumova, Dragan Manojlovi&#263;, Rastko Vasili&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, Patrik Schmuki, U.&#268;. La&#269;njevac</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Rich Selenide Monolayers as Metal-Free Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reactions: A First-Principles Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7020055</link>
      <description>Yao Xu, Fengyu Li, Chemistry. 7(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409092115

                Carbon-based materials have garnered significant attention for electrocatalysis applications in fuel cells due to their unique structural and electronic properties, but rapid oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at the cathode of fuel cells is challenging. Dopants are typically used as active sites for ORR, and increasing the number of active sites for carbon-based catalysts remains a challenge. Here, we carried out first-principles calculations for the electrocatalytic ORR performance of the recently reported monolayer superconductors of carbon-rich selenides. Remarkably, the abundant C atoms serve as the active centers instead of the foreign atoms (Se). All the free energy changes during the ORR process are downhill, suggesting that these carbon-rich selenides hold promise as metal-free electrocatalysts for ORR. Note that the promising electrocatalytic performance of carbon-rich selenides is theoretically predicted; validation is encouraged for experimental efforts.</description>
      <author>Yao Xu, Fengyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7020055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Definition of Important Terms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527853205.ch4</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409187927

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527853205.ch4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Simulations of Skaergaardite (CuPd) with a Self-Consistent Hubbard U-Correction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7020056</link>
      <description>Martino Napoli, Assimo Maris, Chemistry. 7(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409091991

                The electronic and phonon bands of Skaergaardite are investigated using density functional theory (DFT) as implemented in Quantum ESPRESSO. Skaergaardite is a copper palladium mineral (CuPd) found in the Skaergaard intrusion with a CsCl-type (B2) structure. Due to its porous structure, it presents a large surface area available for interactions, which makes it a promising catalyst. The PBE-GGA functional with a Hubbard-like localized term (DFT+U) is combined with ultrasoft and norm-conserving pseudopotentials, and a conventional approach with a dense Monkhorst&#8211;Pack grid of k-points 12 &#215; 12 &#215; 12 is applied. The electronic valence bands are mainly constituted by 3d orbitals of Cu and 4d orbitals of Pd and a pseudo-gap can be recognized. With respect to DFT, DFT+U causes a general downward shift in the valence band. The acoustic and optical phonon branches are separated by a few cm&#8722;1 gap at about 150 cm&#8722;1 and show a density of state curve typical of ordered materials. These results highlight the reliability of DFT+U in studying bimetallic systems with scarce experimental benchmarks, offering insights into the behavior of Skaergaardite and its potential applications in material science such as reduction reactions and hydrogen storage.</description>
      <author>Martino Napoli, Assimo Maris</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7020056</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
