<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 01:20:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum-based catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction simulated with a quantum computer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01460-x</link>
      <description>Cono Di Paola, Evgeny Plekhanov, Micha&#322; Krompiec, Chandan Kumar, Emanuele Marsili, Fengmin Du, Daniel Weber, J. Krauser, Elvira Shishenina, David Mu&#241;oz Ramo, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405528122

                Hydrogen has emerged as a promising energy source for low-carbon and sustainable mobility purposes. However, its applications are still limited by modest conversion efficiency in the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) within fuel cells. The complex nature of the ORR and the presence of strong electronic correlations present challenges to atomistic modelling using classical computers. This scenario opens new avenues for the implementation of novel quantum computing workflows. Here, we present a state-of-the-art study that combines classical and quantum computational approaches to investigate ORR on platinum-based surfaces. Our research demonstrates, for the first time, the feasibility of implementing this workflow on the H1-series trapped-ion quantum computer and identify the challenges of the quantum chemistry modelling of this reaction. The results highlight the great potentiality of quantum computers in solving notoriously difficult systems with strongly correlated electronic structures and suggest platinum/cobalt as ideal candidate for showcasing quantum advantage in future applications.</description>
      <author>Cono Di Paola, Evgeny Plekhanov, Micha&#322; Krompiec, Chandan Kumar, Emanuele Marsili, Fengmin Du, Daniel Weber, J. Krauser, Elvira Shishenina, David Mu&#241;oz Ramo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01460-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizational and Mechanistic Modulation of ORR/OER Activity in M&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;N&#8211;C Bimetallic Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06280</link>
      <description>Xinge Wu, Zhaoying Yang, Decheng Li, Shuai Shao, Gaowu Qin, Xiangying Meng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405529735

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinge Wu, Zhaoying Yang, Decheng Li, Shuai Shao, Gaowu Qin, Xiangying Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of point defect properties near surfaces in metal halide perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.125402</link>
      <description>Bilal Ahmad, Md Salman Rabbi Limon, Zeeshan Ahmad, Physical Review Materials. 8(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405533719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bilal Ahmad, Md Salman Rabbi Limon, Zeeshan Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.125402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The V30 benchmark set for anharmonic vibrational frequencies of molecular dimers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0238491</link>
      <description>Johannes Hoja, A. Daniel Boese, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405541010

                Intermolecular vibrations are extremely challenging to describe but are the most crucial part for determining entropy and hence free energies and enable, for instance, the distinction between different crystal-packing arrangements of the same molecule via THz spectroscopy. Herein, we introduce a benchmark dataset&#8212;V30&#8212;containing 30 small molecular dimers with intermolecular interactions ranging from exclusively van der Waals dispersion to systems with hydrogen bonds. All the calculations are performed with the gold standard of quantum chemistry CCSD(T). We discuss vibrational frequencies obtained via different models starting with the harmonic approximation over independent Morse oscillators up to second-order vibrational perturbation theory (VPT2), which allows a proper anharmonic treatment including coupling of vibrational modes. However, large amplitude motions present in many low-frequency intermolecular modes are problematic for VPT2. In analogy to the often used treatment for internal rotations, we replace such problematic modes by a simple one-dimensional hindered rotor model. We compare selected dimers to the available experimental data or high-level calculations of potential energy surfaces and show that VPT2 in combination with hindered rotors can yield a very good description of fundamental frequencies for the discussed subset of dimers involving small and semi-rigid molecules.</description>
      <author>Johannes Hoja, A. Daniel Boese</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0238491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NMR Investigations of Host&#8211;Guest Interactions in MOFs and COFs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781839167287-00153</link>
      <description>Shoushun Chen, Xin Du, Yuzhen Liu, Jun Xu, Xingguo Han, Bryan E. G. Lucier, Yining Huang, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405551205

                Host&#8211;guest interactions in porous metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) and covalent-organic frameworks (COFs) play a key role in enhancing the performance of these materials for practical applications; however, it is often very challenging to investigate these interactions at the molecular level. In recent years, many solid-state NMR (SSNMR) approaches, including in situ variable temperature (VT), 2D correlation, and pulsed field gradient (PFG) experiments, have offered unique insights into the local structure and dynamics of adsorbed guest molecules in MOFs and COFs. Recent SSNMR studies of MOFs and COFs containing guest molecules are summarized in this chapter. These reports encompass a variety of gaseous and liquid guests such as hydrogen, carbon dioxide, water, and methanol. We also highlight studies involving larger guest molecules, drugs, and biomolecules. It is apparent that SSNMR spectroscopy can provide a wealth of data pertaining to host&#8211;guest interactions in these materials; the information available commonly includes the number and location of guest adsorption sites, guest binding strengths, guest dynamics and diffusion rates, and guest-induced structural changes in the host. The studies discussed in this chapter illustrate how SSNMR spectroscopy serves as a powerful tool to probe host&#8211;guest interactions in MOFs/COFs, especially given the variety of potential target nuclei and the numerous experimental strategies that are available.</description>
      <author>Shoushun Chen, Xin Du, Yuzhen Liu, Jun Xu, Xingguo Han, Bryan E. G. Lucier, Yining Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781839167287-00153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction on graphdiyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.169</link>
      <description>Lei Qin, Shitao Wang, Ju Rong, Yan Wei, Xiaohua Yu, Yudong Sui, Yongqiang Yang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 99(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405555100

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Qin, Shitao Wang, Ju Rong, Yan Wei, Xiaohua Yu, Yudong Sui, Yongqiang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Enhanced ORR Activity of FeN4-Embedded Graphene Through Interface Interactions with Metal Substrates: Electronic vs. Geometric Descriptors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101633</link>
      <description>Silu Li, Donghai Wu, Lulu Gao, Jiahang Li, Gang Tang, Zaiping Zeng, Dongwei Ma, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405565286

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silu Li, Donghai Wu, Lulu Gao, Jiahang Li, Gang Tang, Zaiping Zeng, Dongwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101633</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical interface modelling for electrocatalytic materials design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101638</link>
      <description>Lucas G. Verga, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Aron Walsh, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405585850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lucas G. Verga, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Aron Walsh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed iron &amp;amp; iron clusters synergistically accelerate electrocatalytic ammonia synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158785</link>
      <description>Haoran Zhang, Yuelong Liu, Sanshuang Gao, Haijian Wang, Rui Bai, Yan Zhao, Yingtang Zhou, Guangzhi Hu, Xue Zhao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405586089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoran Zhang, Yuelong Liu, Sanshuang Gao, Haijian Wang, Rui Bai, Yan Zhao, Yingtang Zhou, Guangzhi Hu, Xue Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Time Scale Molecular Dynamics Simulation of Magnesium Hydride Dehydrogenation Enabled by Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02627</link>
      <description>Oliver Morrison, Elena Uteva, Gavin S. Walker, David M. Grant, Sanliang Ling, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405591634

                Magnesium hydride (MgH2) is a promising material for solid-state hydrogen storage due to its high gravimetric hydrogen capacity as well as the abundance and low cost of magnesium. The material's limiting factor is the high dehydrogenation temperature (over 300 &#176;C) and sluggish (de)hydrogenation kinetics when no catalyst is present, making it impractical for onboard applications. Catalysts and physical restructuring (e.g., through ball milling) have both shown kinetic improvements, without full theoretical understanding as to why. In this work, we developed a machine learning interatomic potential (MLP) for the Mg&#8211;H system, which was used to run long time scale molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of a thick magnesium hydride surface slab for up to 1 ns. Our MLP-based MD simulations reveal previously unreported behavior of subsurface molecular H2 formation and subsequent trapping in the subsurface layer of MgH2. This hindered diffusion of subsurface H2 offers a partial explanation on the slow dehydrogenation kinetics of MgH2. The kinetics will be improved if a catalyst obstructs subsurface formation and trapping of H2 or if the diffusion of subsurface H2 is improved through defects created by physical restructuring.</description>
      <author>Oliver Morrison, Elena Uteva, Gavin S. Walker, David M. Grant, Sanliang Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding the Role of Adsorbates Entropy in the Reactivity of Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04472</link>
      <description>Elena Simone, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405592086

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) are rapidly gaining attention as a versatile class of materials that combine the advantages of both homogeneous and heterogeneous catalysis. A growing number of studies aim to identify potential new SACs or to describe their structure and reactivity through ab initio quantum chemical simulations. While many computational studies primarily address reactions involving small molecules, such as water splitting or CO2 reduction, the application scope of SACs is rapidly broadening to include the production of fine chemicals and the conversion of biomass-derived platform molecules, processes that involve larger, more complex reactants. Using density-functional theory (DFT) simulations, we demonstrate that, while an approximate treatment of entropy is acceptable for molecules with up to three atoms, it introduces substantial errors in reactions involving more complex molecules. Our results reveal a linear correlation between the entropy of adsorbed molecules and that of the corresponding isolated species, mirroring trends observed on extended catalytic surfaces. For the largest systems investigated in this study, the entropy of the free molecule is reduced by approximately 10&#8211;20% upon adsorption; for small molecules, this reduction can range from 50 to 70%. This disparity arises because, on SACs, the translational entropy is effectively zero, the rotational entropy is minimal, and the vibrational entropy increases with the size of the molecule. Moreover, the entropy of adsorbates scales linearly with the number of atoms in the molecule, allowing for the prediction of entropic contributions of adsorbates on SACs without additional computational cost. Using propyne hydrogenation as a test, we demonstrate that the reaction energy profile computed with current approximate approaches for estimating the entropy of adsorbates differs significantly from the profile where entropy is explicitly included. These findings highlight the importance of considering adsorbate entropy for accurately predicting the catalytic activity of SACs, particularly for reactions involving complex molecules.</description>
      <author>Elena Simone, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Co 3d/O 2p Orbital Hybridization in LaCoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; by Modulating the Co&#8211;O&#8211;Co Bond Angle for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05479</link>
      <description>Baoxin Ge, Pengyang Jiang, Biyi Chen, Caijin Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405601758

                The orbital hybridization between metal and oxygen of perovskite catalysts can lower the overpotential and enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. This study combines density functional theory with experiments to clarify how Sr/Fe codoping modulates orbital hybridization and enhances OER catalytic activity of LaCoO3. The as-prepared La0.50Sr0.50Co0.75Fe0.25O3 shows remarkable performance with a low overpotential of 310 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 current density and a 107.03 mV dec&#8211;1 Tafel slope, outperforming most state-of-the-art perovskite-based OER electrocatalysts. The experimental results confirm that Sr/Fe codoping enhances the expansion of Co&#8211;O&#8211;Co bond angles and strengthens the covalency of the Co&#8211;O bond in LaCoO3, leading to enhanced electrocatalytic activity. Moreover, increasing Sr doping reduces the distance between the Co 3d/O 2p center and the Fermi level, decreasing the energy difference between them and enhancing the degree of orbital hybridization between Co 3d and O 2p. As the degree of Co 3d/O 2p orbital hybridization increases, a higher charge transfer was found between the active center and intermediate product, OOH, reducing the energy barrier of the rate-determining step while lowering the overpotential. This study provides thorough insight into the rational design of OER catalysts based on orbital hybridization.</description>
      <author>Baoxin Ge, Pengyang Jiang, Biyi Chen, Caijin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultivating superior CO2 reduction performance via rationally engineered nitrogen-phosphorus co-doped graphene catalysts: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111895</link>
      <description>Ismail Shahid, Ruixin Zhang, Xiaoliang Zhang, Dawei Tang, Vineet Tirth, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405611556

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ismail Shahid, Ruixin Zhang, Xiaoliang Zhang, Dawei Tang, Vineet Tirth</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally Stimulated Spin Switching Accelerates Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.133.258001</link>
      <description>Mengfei Lu, Yu Du, Shicheng Yan, Tao Yu, Zhigang Zou, Physical Review Letters. 133(25)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405614811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengfei Lu, Yu Du, Shicheng Yan, Tao Yu, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.133.258001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Catalysts: Are You Really Single?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02844</link>
      <description>Ana S. Dobrota, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405615794

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted the attention of the scientific community due to a number of attractive properties allowing their application in different catalytic processes, including electrochemical ones. Due to the nature of the active site, consisting of only a few atoms, SACs are also very attractive for theoretical modeling as the active site can be directly translated into the computational model. However, as a rule, the possibility of the active site change induced by pH and electrode potential is disregarded in theoretical models. This Perspective emphasizes the need to address the actual state of SA electrocatalysts under operating conditions before considering their catalytic activity and selectivity. The concept of surface Pourbaix plot, well-known in electrochemistry, can be directly transferred to SACs, providing valuable insights and guidance for developing novel catalytic materials. We discuss recent approaches to designing Pourbaix plots for SACs and outline the importance of properly treating the actual state of SACs and other emerging types of catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ana S. Dobrota, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculation of Adsorbate Free Energy Using the Damping Function Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01079</link>
      <description>Yanhua Lei, Lei Liu, Erjun Zhang, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405615873

                Adsorbate free energies are important parameters in surface chemistry and catalysis. Because of its simplicity, the harmonic oscillator (HO) model remains the most widely used method for calculating adsorbate free energy in many fields, including microkinetic modeling. However, it is well-known that the HO method is ineffective for weak adsorption. In this study, we propose a translational model with a diffusion barrier to calculate the state functions of near free translation. Furthermore, an effective mass is introduced in this model. To address hindered translation uniformly, a diffusion barrier-based damping function (DF) is proposed that effectively links the harmonic vibration and translation limits. Adsorbates are divided into three categories according to their adsorption strength and diffusion barrier height. Adsorbed hydrogen atoms have a strong binding energy and relatively high vibrational frequency but a low diffusion barrier. The HT and our proposed DF methods predict that the adsorbed hydrogen atoms behave as translation above room temperature, while the previous DF method predicts that they behave as vibration at any temperature. At last, the dehydrogenation reaction of propane on the Pt(111) surface was taken as an example to illustrate the influence of different methods on the thermodynamic functions.</description>
      <author>Yanhua Lei, Lei Liu, Erjun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Library of Seed@High&#8208;Entropy&#8208;Alloy Core&#8211;shell Nanocrystals With Controlled Facets for Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411464</link>
      <description>Yueh&#8208;Chun Hsiao, Cheng&#8208;Yu Wu, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Wen&#8208;Yang Huang, Ho Viet Thang, Chong&#8208;Chi Chi, Wen&#8208;Jing Zeng, Jiaqi Gao, Chih&#8208;Yi Lin, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Adrian M. Gardner, Hansaem Jang, R.-C. Juang, Y.-C. Liu, Islam M. A. Mekhemer, Ming&#8208;Yen Lu, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ho&#8208;Hsiu Chou, Chun&#8208;Hong Kuo, Shan Zhou, Liang&#8208;Ching Hsu, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Alexander J. Cowan, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Jien&#8208;Wei Yeh, Tung&#8208;Han Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405616791

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy&#8208;alloy (HEA) nanocrystals hold immense potential for catalysis, offering virtually unlimited alloy combinations through the inclusion of at least five constituent elements in varying ratios. However, general and effective strategies for synthesizing libraries of HEA nanocrystals with controlled surface atomic structures remain scarce. In this study, a transferable strategy for developing a library of facet&#8208;controlled seed@HEA nanocrystals through seed&#8208;mediated growth is presented. The synthesis of seed@HEA core&#8211;shell nanocrystals incorporating up to ten different metallic elements, with control over the number of solid&#8208;solution HEA atomic layers is demonstrated. Epitaxial HEA growth on nanocrystal seeds with low&#8208;index and high&#8208;index facets leads to the formation of seed@HEA catalyst library with composition&#8208; and facet&#8208;dependent catalytic activities in both electrocatalysis and photocatalysis. In situ synchrotron X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy and density&#8208;functional theory calculations are employed to identify surface active sites of the HEA, rationalizing the high level of catalytic activities achieved. This work enables facet engineering in the multi&#8208;elemental chemical space and unveils the critical needs for their future development toward catalysis.</description>
      <author>Yueh&#8208;Chun Hsiao, Cheng&#8208;Yu Wu, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Wen&#8208;Yang Huang, Ho Viet Thang, Chong&#8208;Chi Chi, Wen&#8208;Jing Zeng, Jiaqi Gao, Chih&#8208;Yi Lin, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Adrian M. Gardner, Hansaem Jang, R.-C. Juang, Y.-C. Liu, Islam M. A. Mekhemer, Ming&#8208;Yen Lu, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ho&#8208;Hsiu Chou, Chun&#8208;Hong Kuo, Shan Zhou, Liang&#8208;Ching Hsu, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Alexander J. Cowan, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Jien&#8208;Wei Yeh, Tung&#8208;Han Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally stimulated chirp in a pulsed QCL: Microscopic origins behind Fabry-Perot pattern drift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2024.109618</link>
      <description>Evgeniia D. Cherotchenko, Ivan I. Vrubel, Alexander A. Pavlov, Anna S. Konanykhina, Ilya E. Rafailov, Roman G. Polozkov, V. V. Dudelev, G. S. Sokolovski&#301;, International Journal of Thermal Sciences. 210(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405632163

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Evgeniia D. Cherotchenko, Ivan I. Vrubel, Alexander A. Pavlov, Anna S. Konanykhina, Ilya E. Rafailov, Roman G. Polozkov, V. V. Dudelev, G. S. Sokolovski&#301;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2024.109618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e232" altimg="si37.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;X&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; reduction mechanism: Thermal vs electrochemical step</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145429</link>
      <description>Mohd Riyaz, Alexander Bagger, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405632928

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohd Riyaz, Alexander Bagger</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali metal cations act as homogeneous cocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction in aqueous electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01241-1</link>
      <description>Sang Gu Ji, Minho M. Kim, Man Ho Han, Junsic Cho, Yoosang Son, Young Yong Kim, Jaeyoung Jeong, Zee Hwan Kim, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, Nature Catalysis. 7(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405636810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sang Gu Ji, Minho M. Kim, Man Ho Han, Junsic Cho, Yoosang Son, Young Yong Kim, Jaeyoung Jeong, Zee Hwan Kim, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01241-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alternative Electrocatalysts: Exploring Quantum Dots and Transition Metal MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674664-00447</link>
      <description>Abid Ullah, Shahbaz Ahmad, Muhammad Arif, M. Egilmez, Basharat Hussain, Muhammad Raheel Khan, Amjad Hussain, Ayesha Samreen, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405647175

                Hydrogen emerges as a pivotal clean and versatile energy carrier amid global energy challenges, urging a shift towards renewable hydrogen production. The efficiency of the electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) hinges on catalyst choice, ambient conditions, and electrolyte pH. In transitioning away from costly and scarce catalysts like Pt or Ru, researchers explore Earth-abundant alternatives, notably transition metal-based quantum dots (QDs) and MXenes. QDs offer high surface area and customizable properties, while MXenes demonstrate exceptional conductivity and surface area. QDs, despite challenges such as agglomeration, prove effective when engineered into composites. MXenes, with their unique stacked structure and chemical robustness, hold promise for HER catalysis. As discussed, QDs and MXenes exhibit schematic HER representations, emphasizing their potential as catalysts for sustainable hydrogen production and their adaptability to span diverse fields, offering scalable solutions towards a renewable energy future.</description>
      <author>Abid Ullah, Shahbaz Ahmad, Muhammad Arif, M. Egilmez, Basharat Hussain, Muhammad Raheel Khan, Amjad Hussain, Ayesha Samreen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674664-00447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674664-00423</link>
      <description>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Subrata Kundu, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405647518

                Hydrogen is regarded as a vital resource for the advancement of renewable energy technologies. Electrocatalytic water splitting has emerged as a viable technique for producing ultra-pure hydrogen. The electrocatalyst, which can catalyze the electrochemical process to decrease the overpotential by increasing the current density, is critical to the effectiveness of this approach. Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) have become recognized as possible electrocatalysts in recent years due to their exposed surface active sites, evenly distributed interconnected pore structure, and adjustable shape. Thus, the significance of homogeneous and heterogeneous MOFs and their derivatives for the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution process (HER) is summarized in this chapter. The chapter begins with an overview of the fundamentals of the electrocatalytic HER, after which the importance of various transition metal-based pristine MOFs and their derivatives towards the HER is examined. However, there is still plenty of room for improvement given their sub-par intrinsic activity and weak conductivity. Various MOF-derived composites, as well as new methodologies and procedures, are given to solve intrinsic activity and conductivity issues, emphasizing progress in MOF-based materials for a more effective HER electrocatalyst in large-scale hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674664-00423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insight on the delicate regulation of coordination environments for carbon-nitrogen-supported single-atom metals for OER and ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114784</link>
      <description>Xiao-Kuan Wu, Junan Gao, Zhao Hong, Zhigang Lei, Jie Zhang, Molecular Catalysis. 572(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405660232

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao-Kuan Wu, Junan Gao, Zhao Hong, Zhigang Lei, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigations of hydroxyl-functionalized iron-doped phthalocyanine photocatalyst for efficient CO2 reduction to methanol and methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.121121</link>
      <description>Thangaraj Thiruppathiraja, Baker Rhimi, Na Zhang, Min Zhou, Weidong Shi, Zhifeng Jiang, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405662603

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thangaraj Thiruppathiraja, Baker Rhimi, Na Zhang, Min Zhou, Weidong Shi, Zhifeng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.121121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surficial Engineering of Cathodic Protection Strategy via P&#8208;Doped NiCuV Monolithic Electrode for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400815</link>
      <description>Huizhen Han, Shiyi Tao, Yu Sun, Yuxin Luo, Yulian Zhao, Somnath Mukherjee, Yi Ma, Xin Bo, Zenglin Wang, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405674677

                Abstract The concentrated alkaline passivates the monolithic electrode for electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in the alkaline water electrolysis (AWE) industry. Herein, a surface engineering of cathodic protection via one&#8208;step co&#8208;electrodeposition of P into NiCuV is presented and the achieved monolithic electrode exhibits an enhanced electrochemical catalytic behavior and constant durability with a feedback potential of &#8722;0.75 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) under an extremely high current density of 1A cm &#8722;2 for more than 270 h in alkaline media. The strategy of cathodic protection optimises the charge density redistribution by forming a phosphate surface layer. This preserves the particular metal (alloy) phase from oxidation while also modulating the heterarchical porous structure through P incorporation. Furthermore, an anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) with the NiCuVP serving as the HER catalyst and the NiFeCr LDH as the OER catalyst is constructed, which exhibits a current density of 912 mA cm &#8722;2 at 2 V at 80 &#176;C with 30 wt.% KOH electrolytes. The resultant factors for activity and durability such as the electrochemical specific area, redox behaviors and surface hydrophilicity are also systematically discussed. This research presents a practical protocol for the anticorrosion and active enhancement of AWE and AEMWE cathodes.</description>
      <author>Huizhen Han, Shiyi Tao, Yu Sun, Yuxin Luo, Yulian Zhao, Somnath Mukherjee, Yi Ma, Xin Bo, Zenglin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400815</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic role of nickel-chromium heterogeneous selenides in the efficient stabilisation of the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178250</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Ruixue Sun, Ting Li, Si Hui, Haoyu Luo, Gang Lv, Jifang Fu, Li Wang, Zhiqin Peng, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405679873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Ruixue Sun, Ting Li, Si Hui, Haoyu Luo, Gang Lv, Jifang Fu, Li Wang, Zhiqin Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing local CO2 availability via amorphous Bi2O3 enable efficient and stable photocatalytic C2H6 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158854</link>
      <description>Qingqing Chen, Jiaxin Jiang, Yan Wu, Jiaojiao Fang, Ning L&#252;, Gang Wang, Junjie Mao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405686146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingqing Chen, Jiaxin Jiang, Yan Wu, Jiaojiao Fang, Ning L&#252;, Gang Wang, Junjie Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Effective Catalysts for Hydrogen Production: A Performance Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.134257</link>
      <description>A. Ya&#287;mur G&#246;ren, Mert Temiz, Do&#287;an Erdemir, &#304;brahim Din&#231;er, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405686151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Ya&#287;mur G&#246;ren, Mert Temiz, Do&#287;an Erdemir, &#304;brahim Din&#231;er</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.134257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The influence of multiple factors on the PtCo3 catalyst characteristics during the ORR process in proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.122263</link>
      <description>Chuanqi Luo, Kechuang Wan, Jue Wang, Bing Li, Daijun Yang, Pingwen Ming, Cunman Zhang, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405695428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuanqi Luo, Kechuang Wan, Jue Wang, Bing Li, Daijun Yang, Pingwen Ming, Cunman Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.122263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wannier-function software ecosystem for materials simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/revmodphys.96.045008</link>
      <description>Antimo Marrazzo, Sophie Beck, Elena R. Margine, Nicola Marzari, Arash A. Mostofi, Junfeng Qiao, Ivo Souza, Stepan S. Tsirkin, Jonathan R. Yates, Giovanni Pizzi, Reviews of Modern Physics. 96(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405717922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Antimo Marrazzo, Sophie Beck, Elena R. Margine, Nicola Marzari, Arash A. Mostofi, Junfeng Qiao, Ivo Souza, Stepan S. Tsirkin, Jonathan R. Yates, Giovanni Pizzi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/revmodphys.96.045008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of electron&#8211;proton correlation functionals for vibrational spectra of shared-proton systems by constrained nuclear-electronic orbital density functional theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0243086</link>
      <description>Yuzhuo Yang, Yuzhe Zhang, Yang Yang, Xi Xu, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405725332

                Proton transfer plays a crucial role in various chemical and biological processes. A major theoretical challenge in simulating proton transfer arises from the quantum nature of the proton. The constrained nuclear-electronic orbital (CNEO) framework was recently developed to efficiently and accurately account for nuclear quantum effects, particularly quantum nuclear delocalization effects, in quantum chemistry calculations and molecular dynamics simulations. In this paper, we systematically investigate challenging proton transfer modes in a series of shared-proton systems using CNEO density functional theory (CNEO-DFT), focusing on evaluating existing electron&#8211;proton correlation functionals. Our results show that CNEO-DFT accurately describes proton transfer vibrational modes and significantly outperforms conventional DFT. The inclusion of the epc17-2 electron&#8211;proton correlation functional in CNEO-DFT produces similar performance to that without electron&#8211;proton correlations, while the epc17-1 functional yields less accurate results, comparable with conventional DFT. These findings hold true for both asymmetrical and symmetrical shared-proton systems. Therefore, until a more accurate electron&#8211;proton correlation functional is developed, we currently recommend performing vibrational spectrum calculations using CNEO-DFT without electron&#8211;proton correlation functionals.</description>
      <author>Yuzhuo Yang, Yuzhe Zhang, Yang Yang, Xi Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0243086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Coordination Environment of Cu-Embedded Mo&lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (&lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; = S, Se, and Te) Monolayers for Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;: Unveiling the Origin of Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03564</link>
      <description>Thamarainathan Doulassiramane, R. Padmanaban, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405735995

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is a promising approach to alleviating global warming and emerging energy crises. Yet, the CO2RR efficiency is impeded by the need for electrocatalysts with good selectivity and efficiency. Recently, single-atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted much attention in electrocatalysis and are more efficient than traditional metal-based catalysts. In this study, we modeled a Cu single atom embedded on MoX2 (X = Se and Te) monolayer with a single chalcogen (X) vacancy as SAC. Employing the dispersion-corrected density functional theory (DFT-D3) method, the electrocatalytic CO2RR activity of the Cu-MoX2 SACs is systematically investigated through significant descriptors, such as the Gibbs free energy change, charge density difference, and COHP analysis. The stability of SACs, CO2 adsorption configurations, and all possible reaction pathways for the formation of C1 products (HCOOH, CO, CH3OH, and CH4) were examined. All of the Cu-MoX2 SACs are stable and show high catalytic selectivity for the CO2RR by significantly suppressing the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). We found that the catalytic activity is mainly due to the level of antibonding states filling between the Cu atom and *OCHOH intermediate. Among the C1 products, CH4 is selectively produced in all three SACs. Notably, there is a decrease in the limiting potential (UL) when X changes from S to Te in Cu-MoX2. Among these three SACs, Cu-MoTe2 SAC is the most promising catalyst for reducing CO2 to CH4, with as low as UL of &#8722;0.34 V vs RHE. Our results demonstrate that the local coordination environment in SACs has a significant impact on the catalytic activity of CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Thamarainathan Doulassiramane, R. Padmanaban</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress on noble metal-transition metal carbide support catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118903</link>
      <description>Yang Yang, Huijuan Zhang, Miaomiao Yu, Jiangyu Luo, Yuhua Xue, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405738356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Yang, Huijuan Zhang, Miaomiao Yu, Jiangyu Luo, Yuhua Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual action of non-metal doped C2N and Ti3C2T2 heterojunction enhances the catalytic activity of electrochemical simultaneous oxidation of hydrogen peroxide and peroxymonosulfate:A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120698</link>
      <description>Yuxin Zhou, Yanru Huo, Yuhui Ma, Nuan Wen, Qingyuan Gu, Maoxia He, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405738889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Zhou, Yanru Huo, Yuhui Ma, Nuan Wen, Qingyuan Gu, Maoxia He</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive review on carbon capturing materials and processes for sustainable Development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101783</link>
      <description>Yatish Singla, Avinash Thakur, Dhiraj Sud, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405739733

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yatish Singla, Avinash Thakur, Dhiraj Sud</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A computational study on MNX3 transition metal dichalcogenides for the alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105704</link>
      <description>Y.C. Zhou, Chongchong Liu, Jiacheng Li, Fang Xue, Gang Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405741165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y.C. Zhou, Chongchong Liu, Jiacheng Li, Fang Xue, Gang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Assisted Screening of Hexagonal 2D van der Waals Bilayers for Photocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05495</link>
      <description>Arooba Kanwal, Abdul Jalil, Syed Raza Ali Raza, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405742458

                From the photoelectric effect to the development of contemporary photocatalysts, the hunt for efficient energy conversion has been a tale of invention and discovery. Since 1972, water-splitting photocatalysis has evolved as an effective strategy for advancing toward sustainable energy. The van der Waals (vdW) heterostructures, formed by the vertical stacking of two distinct 2D materials, exhibit unique electronic properties. The weak vdW interactions tend to provide the benefit of efficient carrier separation, thus making them promising candidates for photocatalysis. However, analyzing all possible combinations of 2D materials is impractical through traditional approaches, necessitating the development of predictive models to automate and accelerate the quest. Herein, we propose a hybrid approach using machine learning (ML) in conjugation with first-principles calculations to predict the properties of hexagonal vdW bilayers for application in photocatalysis. Our ML workflow comprises the following major steps: (1) constructing a vast material space of bilayers and their descriptors using a 2D material database, (2) labeling a diverse set of bilayers using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, (3) training the supervised ML models on a labeled data set for binding energy, interlayer distance, band gap, work function, and band edges of heterostructures, (4) evaluating the performance of models on the validation set, and (5) predicting the properties of the unlabeled data set and screening the bilayers feasible for overall water-splitting (OWS) photocatalysis. The computational framework presented here tends to establish the relationship between 2D monolayers and vdW bilayers. Our findings highlight the potential of this approach in accelerating the search for novel photocatalysts by efficiently and accurately predicting their properties, thereby contributing to the broader goal of sustainable energy production.</description>
      <author>Arooba Kanwal, Abdul Jalil, Syed Raza Ali Raza</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the critical roles of metal dissolution electrodeposition in enhancing oxygen evolution reaction activity of Fe&#8211;NiOOH electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.317</link>
      <description>Jaewon Lee, JeongEun Yoo, Kiyoung Lee, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 100(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405743617

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaewon Lee, JeongEun Yoo, Kiyoung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced efficiency and durability of nickel sulfide catalyst integrated with reduced graphene oxide: Exploring hierarchically porous structures for methanol oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.285</link>
      <description>Mehdi Salmi, Nabil Khossossi, Yousra Boudad, Charafeddine Jama, Fouad Bentiss, Zaina Zaroual, Sanae El Ghachtouli, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 100(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405743802

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mehdi Salmi, Nabil Khossossi, Yousra Boudad, Charafeddine Jama, Fouad Bentiss, Zaina Zaroual, Sanae El Ghachtouli</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous porosity bimetallic phosphide FeP/CoP/CP as an efficient electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.236092</link>
      <description>Meilian Gao, Siwen Tang, Pingping Gao, Ting Lei, Ren Zhong-ping, Geping Yin, Yong Du, Journal of Power Sources. 630(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405744150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meilian Gao, Siwen Tang, Pingping Gao, Ting Lei, Ren Zhong-ping, Geping Yin, Yong Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.236092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Criteria for Active and Selective Catalysts in the Nitrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00058</link>
      <description>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Kai S. Exner, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405746625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the production distribution in Ni-Cu nanoparticle mediated nitrile hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.179</link>
      <description>Zihan Lv, Zeng Hong, Da Ke, Chao Qian, Xinzhi Chen, Shaodong Zhou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405747184

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihan Lv, Zeng Hong, Da Ke, Chao Qian, Xinzhi Chen, Shaodong Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Melamine-Driven Solvation Effect Promotes Oxygen Reduction on a Platinum Catalyst: Machine Learning-Aided Free Energy Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03437</link>
      <description>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Saori Minami, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405749721

                The modification of Pt surfaces with organic compounds like melamine enhances oxygen reduction reaction activity and catalyst durability. Through first-principles free energy calculations utilizing thermodynamic integration and finite-temperature molecular dynamics, enhanced by machine learning force fields for efficient sampling of nanosecond-scale interfacial water fluctuations and incorporating corrections to accurately reproduce first-principles free energies, we demonstrate that melamine destabilizes OH adsorbates, facilitating their removal and enhancing catalytic activity. Unlike alloys, where OH destabilization is driven by changes in electronic structure and surface strain, melamine disrupts hydrogen bonding between OH and interfacial water. Structural and vibrational analyses reveal that melamine alters the water solvation structure, which is evident in modified radial distribution functions and a blue shift in the O&#8211;H stretching vibrations. These findings indicate that manipulating interfacial solvation with organic compounds could be a promising approach to enhance catalytic activity without compromising durability.</description>
      <author>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Saori Minami</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant-Tuned Restructuring Kinetic for the Formation of Heterophase-Confined Metal-Nonmetal Diatomic Sites for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03060</link>
      <description>Xinyi Li, Feiyan Liu, Wenting Lu, Huafeng Fan, Meiling Xiao, Xiaoqiang Cui, Lu Li, Xiaoxin Zou, Weitao Zheng, Xiao Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405751831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyi Li, Feiyan Liu, Wenting Lu, Huafeng Fan, Meiling Xiao, Xiaoqiang Cui, Lu Li, Xiaoxin Zou, Weitao Zheng, Xiao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The &lt;i&gt;On&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;Off&lt;/i&gt; pH-Dependent Electrocatalytic Activity of the Perfluorinated Iron Phthalocyanine for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Electrochemical Hardness as a Reactivity Descriptor: Experimental and Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06957</link>
      <description>Luis Acu&#241;a-Saavedra, Ana Mar&#237;a M&#233;ndez&#8208;Torres, Gloria C&#225;rdenas&#8208;Jir&#243;n, Rub&#233;n O&#241;ate, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Allende, Ricardo Venegas, Roberto Bernal, Francisco Melo, Elizabeth Imbarack, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Ingrid Ponce, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405755151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luis Acu&#241;a-Saavedra, Ana Mar&#237;a M&#233;ndez&#8208;Torres, Gloria C&#225;rdenas&#8208;Jir&#243;n, Rub&#233;n O&#241;ate, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Allende, Ricardo Venegas, Roberto Bernal, Francisco Melo, Elizabeth Imbarack, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Ingrid Ponce</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the influence of coexistence of Zn vacancies (VZn) and H interstices (Hi) on the photoelectrocatalytic performance of wurtzite ZnO (001) monolayer: Li/Na/K</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113981</link>
      <description>Gang Zhang, Qingyu Hou, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma, Riguleng Si, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405757090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Zhang, Qingyu Hou, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma, Riguleng Si</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating photocatalytic H2O2 rate over inter-molecular Z-scheme heterojunction via dual production paths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115192</link>
      <description>Yaodan Cao, Y. C. Zhai, Wenwen Lv, Hongyan Liu, J. Zhuo, Shouchun Ma, Maoquan Wu, Wanting Hui, Wenqi Ding, Tongjie Yao, Jiaxu Zhang, Jie Wu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405761097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaodan Cao, Y. C. Zhai, Wenwen Lv, Hongyan Liu, J. Zhuo, Shouchun Ma, Maoquan Wu, Wanting Hui, Wenqi Ding, Tongjie Yao, Jiaxu Zhang, Jie Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity-Drop of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in LiNO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Based &#8220;Hydronium-in-Salt&#8221; Acidic Electrolytes on Platinum Enables Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13117</link>
      <description>Cheolmin Park, Min Young Seo, Taesung Kwon, Ji-Yoon Kim, Ki Min Nam, YongJoo Kim, Jinho Chang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405741914

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheolmin Park, Min Young Seo, Taesung Kwon, Ji-Yoon Kim, Ki Min Nam, YongJoo Kim, Jinho Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of the DES-contained reduced graphene oxide system with efficient CO2 adsorption and photothermal desorption for pre-gas purification in AEMFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131193</link>
      <description>Yifan Li, Xianglin Kong, Dahai Zhu, Tianwen Guo, Xinfeng Wu, Wei Yu, Jinpeng Wang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405529564

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Li, Xianglin Kong, Dahai Zhu, Tianwen Guo, Xinfeng Wu, Wei Yu, Jinpeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131193</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
