<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 01:36:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal transport in amorphous carbon nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/klhj-x3f2</link>
      <description>Nianjie Liang, Alfredo Fiorentino, Bai Song, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 112(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414383199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nianjie Liang, Alfredo Fiorentino, Bai Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/klhj-x3f2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Structure Manipulation of Cobalt-Based Oxides for Catalytic Oxidation of Exhaust Gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.5c05635</link>
      <description>Kun Hou, Z. Zhao, Ganggang Li, Bingzhi Li, Ziyi Shui, Boyi Hao, Dong Sui, Xingyun Li, Jie Cheng, Zhengping Hao, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414383998

                Catalytic oxidation technologies for industrial exhaust emissions (e.g., VOCs, CO, and NOx) have gained significant attention due to the severe environmental and public health impacts. Recent advances highlight cobalt-based oxides as superior catalytic materials owing to excellent physicochemical properties, but the diverse compositions of industrial exhaust gases present significant obstacles in their practical applications. To develop rational design strategies for efficient cobalt-based oxides, exploring the structure&#8211;activity relationship (SAR) provides guidance for engineering structural properties to enhance performance. In this context, this review delves into how SAR impacts catalytic performance in exhaust gas purification through geometric structure modulation (size effects, morphology, and surface defect structures) and electronic structure modulation (Co&#8211;O bond strengths, d-band centers, coordination environments, and constrained structures). Furthermore, special attention is given to mechanistic studies combining reaction kinetic modeling, in situ spectroscopic characterization, and the effects of water vapor and SO2 on catalytic oxidation processes. We further outline emerging synthetic strategies and ongoing challenges for the design of next-generation cobalt-based catalysts. This review provides guidance and inspiration for the development of high-performance cobalt-based oxides for exhaust gas purification.</description>
      <author>Kun Hou, Z. Zhao, Ganggang Li, Bingzhi Li, Ziyi Shui, Boyi Hao, Dong Sui, Xingyun Li, Jie Cheng, Zhengping Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.5c05635</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Hollow Spherical Phosphide Catalysts with Industrial-Scale Potential for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c11704</link>
      <description>M. Stre&#269;kov&#225;, Alena Fedoro&#269;kov&#225;, A. Gub&#243;ov&#225;, Gabriel Su&#269;&#237;k, Vladim&#237;r Girman, Akbar Hussain, Michael Vorochta, Jozef Stre&#269;ka, Tom&#225;&#353; Bystro&#328;, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414384757

                The competitiveness of hydrogen as a fuel of the future relies on the development of low-cost, readily available, and efficient catalysts. Transition metal phosphides (TMP), mainly in multimetallic compositions, are recognized as an excellent alternative to platinum-based catalysts in electrolyzers and fuel cells. Herein, for the first time, the connection of the spray drying method as a user-friendly technique for the large-scale production of TMP as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalysts is presented. Three types of catalysts based on MoFeP modified with Co and Ni as third elements were compared by electrochemical methods in an alkaline medium of 1 M KOH. Among the studied materials, the as-prepared MoFeCoP electrocatalysts exhibited the lowest reaction overpotentials (&#951;10) of &#8722;285 mV, with Tafel slopes of 83 mV dec&#8211;1, low activation energy for the HER and sufficient durability in long-term stability tests. The high value of differential capacitance for both trimetallic materials MoFeNiP and MoFeCoP indicates a large surface area, resulting in excellent features for hydrogen production and application.</description>
      <author>M. Stre&#269;kov&#225;, Alena Fedoro&#269;kov&#225;, A. Gub&#243;ov&#225;, Gabriel Su&#269;&#237;k, Vladim&#237;r Girman, Akbar Hussain, Michael Vorochta, Jozef Stre&#269;ka, Tom&#225;&#353; Bystro&#328;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c11704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Configuration Modulation of 2D Pd&#8208;Pt Heterostructures for Boosting Electrochemical Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202522126</link>
      <description>Xinran Jiao, Chaoqun Ma, Biao Huang, Fukai Feng, Ning Li, Dengke Zhao, Sumei Han, Yiming Wang, Jinbo Kuang, Yixuan Gao, Xiaoxu Zhao, Qipeng Lu, Yiyao Ge, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414395092

                Abstract 2D metal heterostructures have shown great promise as highly efficient catalysts. However, how the spatial configuration of distinct components within 2D metal heterostructures affects their electrocatalytic performance still remains unclear. Herein, the controlled construction of Pd&#8208;Pt heterostructures with two distinct spatial configurations are reported, i.e., novel lateral heterostructure and conventional core&#8211;shell structure, through different epitaxial growth modes. Specifically, Pd&#8208;Pt mesoporous nanosheets (Pd&#8208;Pt MNSs) with abundant exposed Pd&#8208;Pt planar interfaces are prepared through the in&#8208;plane lateral epitaxial growth of Pt on Pd mesoporous nanosheets (Pd MNSs) by using carbon monoxide (CO) as a capping agent, which can selectively cover the (111) basal plane of Pd MNSs to inhibit the Pt growth on the basal planes, while Pd@Pt core&#8211;shell mesoporous nanosheets (Pd@Pt MNSs) are obtained without CO. Impressively, the obtained Pd&#8208;Pt MNSs exhibit excellent catalytic performance for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in alkaline media, outperforming the Pd@Pt MNSs and commercial Pd/C. Density functional theory calculations demonstrate that the exposed Pd&#8208;Pt planar interface in Pd&#8208;Pt MNSs possesses the preferential adsorption of reaction intermediates, demonstrating a reduced energy barrier in ORR compared to individual Pd and Pt sites. This work highlights the critical role of engineering the spatial configuration in metal heterostructures for efficient electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Xinran Jiao, Chaoqun Ma, Biao Huang, Fukai Feng, Ning Li, Dengke Zhao, Sumei Han, Yiming Wang, Jinbo Kuang, Yixuan Gao, Xiaoxu Zhao, Qipeng Lu, Yiyao Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202522126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective hydrogen detection at reduced temperatures using WO3 nanorods functionalized with Pd&#8211;Pt alloy nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151560</link>
      <description>Ashish Yadav, G.S. Pandey, Shiv Dutta Lawaniya, Kamlendra Awasthi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 177(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414396684

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashish Yadav, G.S. Pandey, Shiv Dutta Lawaniya, Kamlendra Awasthi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of asymmetric dual &#956;-O bridge structures for dynamic catalytic center modulation: Transition metal-substituted NiTiO3 for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151417</link>
      <description>Shaoxiong Zhu, Chen Hu, Haoyu Jiang, Yijun Wu, Yongmin Ying, Huanan Wang, Le Chen, Ping He, Chao&#8217;en Li, Jiang Wu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 177(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414396872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaoxiong Zhu, Chen Hu, Haoyu Jiang, Yijun Wu, Yongmin Ying, Huanan Wang, Le Chen, Ping He, Chao&#8217;en Li, Jiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of reactive elements on surface oxidation of a CoCrFeNi high-entropy alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0283981</link>
      <description>Dennis Boakye, Chuang Deng, Journal of Applied Physics. 138(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414410565

                Reactive element (RE) additions are widely known to improve the oxidation resistance of structural alloys in high-temperature applications, yet their atomistic role in oxide formation and adhesion remains unclear. Herein, first-principles calculations were employed to reveal the mechanistic influence of selected RE on the surface oxidation of a CoCrFeNi high-entropy alloy. REs were found to improve oxygen binding strength, facilitate charge transfer at the metal-oxide interface, reduce activation energy for oxygen diffusion, promote early-stage oxide nucleation, and improve scale adherence. Our findings bridge experimental observations with atomistic theory, offering insight for the design of oxidation-resistant materials capable of withstanding harsh environments.</description>
      <author>Dennis Boakye, Chuang Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0283981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and adsorption properties of Cu&#8211;Au nanoparticles in harsh reactive environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0288099</link>
      <description>Anastasiia A. Mikhailova, Alexey P. Maltsev, Paulo C. D. Mendes, Fernando Buend&#237;a, Artem R. Oganov, Sergey M. Kozlov, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414414442

                The reactivity of nanoparticles is governed by their surface composition, which tends to vary significantly under reactive conditions. In this study, the impacts of temperature and the presence of a CO or O2 atmosphere on the structures of Au79, Cu19Au60, Cu39Au40, Cu60Au19, and Cu79 nanoparticles were investigated using a combination of global optimization, machine learning interatomic potentials, and density functional theory. We find that increasing gold content weakens CO and O adsorption and limits oxygen-induced structural changes, while copper-rich particles undergo pronounced oxidation and reconstruction. Bader charge analysis shows that, in bare nanoalloys, Au withdraws electron density from Cu due to their electronegativity difference. In oxidized Cu&#8211;Au nanoalloys, the charge on Cu atoms depends on the number of O neighbors and can reach values typical of Cu2O (0.6 e) and CuO (1.1 e). On average, the Cu atoms exhibit positive effective Bader charges of &#8764;0.9 e in these nanoalloys. Our results indicate that models of Cu&#8211;Au catalysts under oxidizing conditions must incorporate the full ensemble of metallic and oxidized configurations rather than a single most probable structure to predict true catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Anastasiia A. Mikhailova, Alexey P. Maltsev, Paulo C. D. Mendes, Fernando Buend&#237;a, Artem R. Oganov, Sergey M. Kozlov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0288099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D&#8208;Band Width Rationally Broadened by Configuring Nearest Coordination of Metal Site for Enhanced Active Site&#8208;Intermediate Interaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202510760</link>
      <description>Jing Li, Xiaotao Zhang, Jinpeng Li, Xiaoyu Zheng, Minghui Li, Jiadong Zhou, Erhong Song, Yao Zhou, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414415777

                Abstract Metal&#8208;based site, as an important type of active site, plays the benchmarking role in the redox and charge transfer processes in the heterogeneous catalysis. Modulating the valence state of metal site as a promising and simple strategy theoretically enables control over the adsorption strength of reaction intermediates. However, this strategy is intrinsically limited by the local atomic configuration, often leading to unpredictable catalytic failures. Here, it is reported that the intermediate adsorption strength of platinum active site with different valence states exhibits a linear relationship with the d&#8208;band width of Pt (W d &#8208;Pt ). Adjusting the nearest&#8208;neighbor coordination environment of Pt sites by changing the transition metals bonded to Pt effectively modulates the W d &#8208;Pt , which offers a high activity (&#951; 10 = 14 mV) in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). W d &#8208;Pt broadening elevates the Pt&#9472;H anti&#8208;bonding states across the Fermi level, strengthening active site&#8208;absorbate interactions and thereby tuning HER catalytic activity. In addition, this d&#8208;band width engineering strategy can be expanded to other catalysts with the metal active site. The present study transcends limitations in valence state modulation and sheds light on deeper understanding of d&#8208;band structure of metal sites and a methodology to boost the activity of metal sites in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Jing Li, Xiaotao Zhang, Jinpeng Li, Xiaoyu Zheng, Minghui Li, Jiadong Zhou, Erhong Song, Yao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202510760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of Transition Metal (Sc to Zn) Decorated Mo&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; MXenes as a Catalyst Under Ambient Conditions for N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysis Using First Principles Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202500330</link>
      <description>Nandhini Panjulingam, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414419585

                In this study, 3d transition metal (TM) atom&#8208;decorated MXenes (TM@Mo 3 C 2 where TM = Sc&#63743;Zn) are used as potential catalysts for the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) using density functional theory&#8208;based screening. The favorable work function, strong N 2 activation, effective hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) suppression, and high current density collectively establish V@Mo 3 C 2 as a highly promising NRR catalyst, warranting in&#8208;depth exploration. Ab initio molecular dynamics simulations confirm the thermal stability of V@Mo 3 C 2 at 300 K. The side&#8208;on N 2 adsorption on V@Mo 3 C 2 favors enzymatic and consecutive reaction pathways. Notably, the reaction free&#8208;energy changes in the consecutive pathway are exothermic, contributing to an exceptionally low potential&#8208;determining step. Furthermore, V@Mo 3 C 2 demonstrates a Faradaic efficiency value of 99.9%. Overall, V@Mo 3 C 2 exhibits remarkable selectivity for the NRR compared to the HER, exhibiting a low current density, which inhibits the HER and high Faradaic efficiency. These findings demonstrate the potential of alternate TM&#8208;based MXenes surfaces, such as V@Mo 3 C 2 , for efficient ammonia synthesis.</description>
      <author>Nandhini Panjulingam, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202500330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory for Molecular and Periodic Systems in TURBOMOLE: Theory, Implementation, and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c02937</link>
      <description>Manas Sharma, Yannick J. Franzke, Christof Holzer, Fabian Pauly, Marek Sierka, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414419941

                This work provides a detailed overview of density functional theory (DFT) methods for treating molecular and periodic systems within the TURBOMOLE software package. The implementation employs Gaussian-type orbitals and is based on efficient real-space techniques and density-fitting approaches for Coulomb interactions. Recent developments are reviewed, including the treatment of relativistic effects with effective core potentials, the incorporation of spin&#8211;orbit coupling via two-component formalisms, and the extension to real-time time-dependent DFT (RT-TDDFT). Embedding schemes based on frozen-density and projection-based approaches are also discussed, enabling the combination of DFT with high-level correlated wave function methods and many-body perturbation theory for selected subsystems. Representative applications demonstrate the capabilities across bulk materials, surfaces, low-dimensional nanostructures, and adsorption processes. Additionally, a web-based graphical interface has been developed to support input generation, structure manipulation, and output analysis. By consolidating theoretical foundations, implementation strategies, and application examples, this work provides a reference for the use of periodic DFT methods in quantum chemical and materials science studies.</description>
      <author>Manas Sharma, Yannick J. Franzke, Christof Holzer, Fabian Pauly, Marek Sierka</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c02937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting photocatalytic hydrogen evolution via intrinsic electric fields in 2D Janus AlXY&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si81.svg" display="inline" id="d1e774"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; (X = Ga, In; Y = S, Se, Te) monolayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsadv.2025.100851</link>
      <description>Talha Zafer, Nabil Khossossi, Poulumi Dey, Applied Surface Science Advances. 30(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414420017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Talha Zafer, Nabil Khossossi, Poulumi Dey</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsadv.2025.100851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibrational recognition of local structures in hydrogen boride sheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0280856</link>
      <description>Kurt Irvin M. Rojas, Luong Thi Ta, Shuhei Naka, Yoshitada Morikawa, Ikutaro Hamada, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414423698

                We present a comprehensive vibrational analysis of hydrogen boride sheets through first-principles calculations, focusing on a variety of local structural configurations, including surfaces, edges, and bilayer models&#8212;some of which contain vacancy and substitutional defects. A database of vibrational modes and simulated infrared spectra was constructed, revealing distinct spectral features that serve as characteristic fingerprints for different bonding environments. By analyzing mode distributions with respect to coordination environments, we identify the distinct contributions of terminal and bridging hydrogen atoms to specific spectral regions. The results show that structural modifications, such as interlayer stacking and edge termination, have a significant influence on vibrational characteristics, particularly in the intermediate and high frequency regions. The vibrational database enables the precise interpretation of infrared spectra and offers a reliable reference for model selection and peak analysis in both experimental and theoretical studies on hydrogen boride sheets and related materials.</description>
      <author>Kurt Irvin M. Rojas, Luong Thi Ta, Shuhei Naka, Yoshitada Morikawa, Ikutaro Hamada</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0280856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General reactive element-based machine learning potentials for heterogeneous catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01398-3</link>
      <description>Changxi Yang, Chenyu Wu, Wenbo Xie, Daiqian Xie, P. Hu, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414424145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changxi Yang, Chenyu Wu, Wenbo Xie, Daiqian Xie, P. Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01398-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable GNN Framework Guided by Local Chemical Features to Predict Binding Energies in Bimetallic Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7566600/v1</link>
      <description>Andr&#233;s Felipe Usuga, C. S. Praveen, Aleix Comas&#8208;Vives, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414426653

                Abstract Adsorption energies are key catalytic descriptors that reveal adsorbate-site interactions on heterogeneous catalysts. However, their computation via DFT is time-consuming, limiting high-throughput screening. This work presents a machine learning (ML) methodology based on graph representations of local adsorption sites, using a Graph Neural Network (GNN) with per-atom local descriptors derived from accessible physicochemical properties. The approach is evaluated on two bimetallic datasets. The first includes AB-type bimetallic flat surfaces with varying A:B ratios, predicting binding energies for small monodentate adsorbates (C, N, O, S, H) with MSEs of 0.073/0.181 eV (train/test). The second dataset comprises reaction energies of key intermediates for CO2 hydrogenation on Ni-Ga-based surfaces. The GNN model achieves an impressive performance (MSE: 0.001/0.002 (train/test) eV) on complex atomic configurations, even bidentate ones. Beyond predictive performance, clustering analysis provides an explainable framework, showing how structural and electronic descriptors can rationally guide catalyst design and deepen understanding of adsorbate-metal interactions.</description>
      <author>Andr&#233;s Felipe Usuga, C. S. Praveen, Aleix Comas&#8208;Vives</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7566600/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growth Mechanism of Double-Walled Carbon Nanotubes: Insights from Density Functional Theory Computations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03332</link>
      <description>Bal&#225;zs Orb&#225;n, Tibor H&#246;ltzl, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414426702

                The growth mechanism of double- or multi-walled carbon nanotubes (DWCNTs or MWCNTs) via floating catalyst chemical vapor deposition (FCCVD) is still an uncharted territory, despite its significance in achieving controlled synthesis of carbon nanotubes (CNTs) with desired material properties. To address this knowledge gap, we employed Density Functional Theory (DFT) computations to investigate the stability and growth of DWCNT caps and shorter tubular segments on the surface of icosahedral Fe147 and Fe309 nanoparticles. Both zigzag and armchair CNTs with different diameters were considered as inner and outer tubes in our model systems. The tube growth was found to be mainly dependent on the diameter, while chirality plays a minor role. Furthermore, the results reveal that while the formation and growth of the outer tube are more favorable, its presence promotes the growth of the inner tube. Our findings suggest that the growth of inner and outer tubes in the FCCVD process occurs simultaneously rather than following a layer-by-layer mechanism. Overall, this study provides valuable insights into how nanoparticle and tube diameters influence the growth of DWCNTs.</description>
      <author>Bal&#225;zs Orb&#225;n, Tibor H&#246;ltzl</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illustrating Extreme Negative Linear Compressibility in Thermosalient Molecular Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c01043</link>
      <description>Bruno Mladineo, Teodoro Klaser, Martin Ende, Jasminka Popovi&#263;, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, &#381;eljko Skoko, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414429424

                We report a high-pressure single-crystal X-ray diffraction study of the thermosalient molecular crystal N'-2-propylidene-4hydroxybenzohydrazide. We find that it features one of the largest negative linear compressibilities recorded, with a coefficient of &#8722;39 TPa&#8211;1. With increasing pressure, it converts to a positive linear compressibility and at even higher pressures again to a negative linear compressibility. This switchable behavior arises from the pressure-induced straightening of the hydrogen-bonded zigzag chains, which is eventually counteracted by direct bond compression. To capture this mechanism, we trained a machine-learning interatomic potential and performed quasi-harmonic free-energy calculations, thereby obtaining atomistic insight across the whole pressure range. These findings broaden the still-scarce catalog of organic crystals that combine thermosalient activity with experimentally verified, pressure-tunable NLC.</description>
      <author>Bruno Mladineo, Teodoro Klaser, Martin Ende, Jasminka Popovi&#263;, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, &#381;eljko Skoko</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c01043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Spinel Oxides with Oxygen-Rich Vacancies Improve the Catalytic Performance for Low-Temperature Flexible Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c05910</link>
      <description>Wolong Li, Yong Wang, Xudong Sun, Hang Dong, Lili Sun, Xuyun Zhang, Yongcun Li, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414429710

                As a promising new energy storage device, low-temperature adaptability and slow reaction kinetics have become a restriction to flexible zinc-air batteries (FZABs) serviced in extreme environments. The research on electrocatalysts rich in oxygen vacancies (OV) to drive low-temperature FZAB performance still faces significant challenges. Developing high-entropy spinel oxides (HESOs) rich in OV is critical to improving the low-temperature FZAB performance. Herein, (FeCrCuNiMn)3O4 is synthesized using a five-metal element via a hydrothermal calcination method and loaded with three-dimensional graphene (3D-G), revealing the key role of OV in synergistically enhancing the performance of FZABs through dual active sites and interfacial charge transfer to drive electrocatalysis. The prepared electrocatalysts exhibit enhanced oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalytic activity, which drives FZABs at &#8722;25 &#176;C, with a peak power density of up to 60.1 mW cm&#8211;2, a stable voltage gap of 0.74 V, and remarkable low-temperature cycling stability. This work effectively solves the low-temperature limitations of the FZABs by using a high-entropy strategy to improve the ORR/OER, providing a new approach for advanced green and sustainable energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Wolong Li, Yong Wang, Xudong Sun, Hang Dong, Lili Sun, Xuyun Zhang, Yongcun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c05910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal atoms supported by Janus NbSSe monolayer for overall water splitting and oxygen reduction: A computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142432</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Jing Hu, Aiyu Yang, Caixia Zhong, Xingxing Yu, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414436057

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Jing Hu, Aiyu Yang, Caixia Zhong, Xingxing Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu dual-site doping: synergistic enhancement of OER activity through LDH and nickel foam interface engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5nj03068d</link>
      <description>Jinhui Li, Yuming Wei, Laixi Zou, Yaozong Liu, Shuaidong Li, Luo Yue, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414438157

                Novel Cu dual-site doping via the urea hydrothermal method: simultaneous incorporation into LDH lattice and NF substrate enhances OER activity through optimized NF electronic structure and facilitated intermediate adsorption.</description>
      <author>Jinhui Li, Yuming Wei, Laixi Zou, Yaozong Liu, Shuaidong Li, Luo Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5nj03068d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt oxide-based catalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1071/ch25104</link>
      <description>Huihui Li, Shuhao Wang, Chuan Zhao, Australian Journal of Chemistry. 78(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414443067

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) is a cornerstone technology for green hydrogen production, yet the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media remains a major bottleneck. Noble metal oxides such as IrO2 and RuO2 are effective but suffer from high cost and scarcity. As a non-precious alternative, spinel cobalt oxide (Co3O4) has attracted attention due to its promising performance results from its mixed-valence structure, tunable electronic properties and catalytic potential. However, its practical application is challenged by poor conductivity, moderate activity and instability under acidic conditions due to proton attack and lattice degradation. This review summarises recent advances in Co3O4-based electrocatalysts for acidic OER. We first introduce three key OER pathways: adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM), lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) and oxide path mechanism (OPM) and their relevance to Co3O4 performance. Then, we introduce the structural and electronic characteristics of Co3O4 that influence its catalytic behaviour. Next, we review a range of engineering strategies, including element doping, heterostructure construction, surface modification and defect engineering, all aimed at enhancing the activity and durability of Co3O4. Finally, we highlight critical challenges and offer perspectives for advancing Co3O4 as a viable acidic OER catalyst.</description>
      <author>Huihui Li, Shuhao Wang, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1071/ch25104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Plasma Reaction Conditions Affect the Optimal Catalyst: A Microkinetic Study of Plasma-catalytic CO2 Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11090-025-10599-4</link>
      <description>Bj&#246;rn Loenders, Roel Michiels, Annemie Bogaerts, Plasma Chemistry and Plasma Processing. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414447693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bj&#246;rn Loenders, Roel Michiels, Annemie Bogaerts</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11090-025-10599-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Engineering Induced Charge Accumulation for Enhanced Solar Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519825</link>
      <description>Xiu&#8208;Shuang Xing, Qianyu Gao, Chengyang Feng, Zhongyuan Zhou, Xiyang Liu, Yao Guo, Jingchao Zhang, Jimin Du, Huabin Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414451774

                Abstract Efficient separation and extraction of charge carriers at the surface of semiconductor photoanodes play a pivotal role in enhancing the performance of solar&#8208;driven photoelectrochemical (PEC) devices. Herein, a general strategy is presented to promote charge carrier migration by introducing a hole extraction layer, which enables dual&#8208;interface engineering between the photoanode and the catalytic sites. This design enhances the transfer and accumulation of photogenerated holes from the semiconductor to the oxygen evolution cocatalyst (OEC). Specifically, FeNi&#8208;LDH is inserted between &#945;&#8208;Fe 2 O 3 and a Ru&#8208;based OEC, forming a cascaded &#945;&#8208;Fe 2 O 3 /FeNi&#8208;LDH/Ru structure. This dual&#8208;interface configuration facilitates directional charge transport, accelerates hole accumulation at Ru active sites, and suppresses carrier recombination. The optimized photoanode achieves a photocurrent density of 2.51 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V versus RHE, which is 3.8 times higher than that of pristine &#945;&#8208;Fe 2 O 3 . This work highlights the crucial role of rational interface engineering in regulating carrier dynamics and provides a broadly applicable strategy for constructing high&#8208;efficiency PEC water&#8208;splitting systems.</description>
      <author>Xiu&#8208;Shuang Xing, Qianyu Gao, Chengyang Feng, Zhongyuan Zhou, Xiyang Liu, Yao Guo, Jingchao Zhang, Jimin Du, Huabin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Spin Polarization Facilitates the Urea Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501142</link>
      <description>Aravind Vadakkayil, Ulrich Pototschnig, Meera Joy, Elizabeth Shiby, Keerthana Govindaraj, Susheng Tan, Carmen Herrmann, Brian P. Bloom, David H. Waldeck, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414454311

                Abstract This work reports on the role of electron spin in the urea oxidation reaction (UOR), which is important for wastewater treatment and for hydrogen production in energy applications, as it possesses a lower thermodynamic equilibrium potential to produce hydrogen than does direct water splitting. We demonstrate that spin&#8208;polarized catalysts facilitate the UOR, leading to a decrease in reaction overpotential and an improved product distribution compared to analogous unpolarized catalysts. Computational studies attribute the improved performance to a stabilization of the desired reaction pathway upon spin polarization. This work underscores the importance of electron spin considerations for multistep, multielectron and multiproton, electrochemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Aravind Vadakkayil, Ulrich Pototschnig, Meera Joy, Elizabeth Shiby, Keerthana Govindaraj, Susheng Tan, Carmen Herrmann, Brian P. Bloom, David H. Waldeck</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing chemical engineering technology with artificial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ce/zkaf036</link>
      <description>Chao Ding, Xin Gui, Jun Jiang, Clean Energy. 9(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414458705

                Abstract Artificial intelligence is fundamentally transforming chemical engineering by redefining how materials are discovered, processes are optimized, and innovations are deployed at scale. This review provides a unique perspective on artificial intelligence&#8217;s role as a catalyst for chemical engineering&#8217;s evolution, emphasizing its ability to synergize computational intelligence with experimental workflows. Key contributions include artificial intelligence-enabled breakthroughs in structure&#8211;property relationship modeling, retrosynthetic analysis, and computational chemistry for rapid material optimization, followed by artificial intelligence&#8217;s impact on industrial translation through smart process control, digital twins, and automated laboratories, which facilitates seamless scaling from laboratory innovation to industrial production. Specific applications in energy, catalysis, batteries, and water treatment demonstrate artificial intelligence&#8217;s potential to address critical global challenges. By critically evaluating limitations and offering a roadmap for future advancements, this review highlights artificial intelligence not just as a tool but as a transformative force driving a more adaptive, intelligent, and sustainable chemical engineering paradigm.</description>
      <author>Chao Ding, Xin Gui, Jun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ce/zkaf036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Level Engineering of MOF-Derived Hierarchical Porous Carbon Nanofibers with Low-Coordinated Cobalt Single-Atom Catalysts for High-Performance Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42765-025-00614-w</link>
      <description>Jeong Ho Na, Seohyeon Jang, Hyun Jin Kim, Jin Koo Kim, Haeseong Jang, Inho Nam, Seung&#8208;Keun Park, Advanced Fiber Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414461060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jeong Ho Na, Seohyeon Jang, Hyun Jin Kim, Jin Koo Kim, Haeseong Jang, Inho Nam, Seung&#8208;Keun Park</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42765-025-00614-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Various Materials in the Introduction of Hydrogen Isotopes into Organic Compounds without Solvents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s2075113325701291</link>
      <description>&#1042;. &#1055;. &#1064;&#1077;&#1074;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, I. Yu. Nagaev, N. F. Myasoedov, Inorganic Materials Applied Research. 16(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414465202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1042;. &#1055;. &#1064;&#1077;&#1074;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, I. Yu. Nagaev, N. F. Myasoedov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s2075113325701291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acceleration of crystal structure relaxation with deep reinforcement learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01731-1</link>
      <description>Elena Trukhan, Efim Mazhnik, Artem R. Oganov, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414466390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elena Trukhan, Efim Mazhnik, Artem R. Oganov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01731-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Cobalt-Doped 2D Graphene: Electronic Design for Multifunctional Applications in Environmental Remediation and Energy Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics13100312</link>
      <description>Zhongkai Huang, Yue Zhang, Chunjiang Li, Liang Deng, Bo Song, Maolin Bo, Chuang Yao, Haolin Lu, Guankui Long, Inorganics. 13(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414472390

                Through atomic-scale characterization of a single cobalt atom anchored in a pyridinic N3 vacancy of graphene (Co-N3-gra), this study computationally explores three interconnected functionalities mediated by cobalt&#8217;s electronic configuration. Quantum-confined molecular prototypes extend prior bulk models, achieving a competitive catalytic activity for CO oxidation via Langmuir&#8211;Hinshelwood pathways with a 0.85 eV barrier. These molecular prototypes&#8217; discrete energy states facilitate single-electron transistor operation, enabling sensitive detection of NO, NO2, SO2, and CO2 through adsorption-induced conductance modulation. When applied to lithium&#8211;sulfur batteries using periodic Co-N3-gra, cobalt sites enhance polysulfide conversion kinetics and suppress the shuttle effect, with the Li2S2&#8594;Li2S step identified as the rate-limiting process. Density functional simulations provide atomic-scale physicochemical characterization of Co-N3-gra, revealing how defect engineering in 2D materials modulates electronic structures for multifunctional applications.</description>
      <author>Zhongkai Huang, Yue Zhang, Chunjiang Li, Liang Deng, Bo Song, Maolin Bo, Chuang Yao, Haolin Lu, Guankui Long</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics13100312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Site Cobalt-Doped RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst Enables Stable and Cost-Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution for PEM Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c14137</link>
      <description>Jing Liang, Yuanyuan Zhao, Chenyu Yang, Shu Zhu, Liang Wang, Ke Xu, Xueliang Mu, Yong Han, Zhi Liu, Zhiwei Zhao, Wei Liu, Fei Li, Zhangquan Peng, Edmund C. M. Tse, Qinghua Liu, Junfeng Gao, Qing Li, Jianfeng Li, Jinxuan Liu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414473639

                Developing efficient, cost-effective, and durable electrocatalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) remains a significant challenge, requiring the stabilization and enhancement of catalyst activity under harsh conditions. Here, we present cobalt-doped ruthenium dioxide (Co0.3Ru0.7O2) on TiO2 as an electrocatalyst toward an acidic oxygen evolution reaction. The Co0.3Ru0.7O2&#8211;TiO2 achieves an impressive overpotential of 322 mV at 1 A cm&#8211;2 and demonstrates stable operation for over 1000 h at 500 mA cm&#8211;2 in a PEMWE device. Comprehensive experimental and theoretical calculation results demonstrate that the doping of Co atoms into the rutile RuO2 lattice optimizes the geometric configuration. Moreover, the lattice-matched interface between Co0.3Ru0.7O2 and TiO2 promotes interfacial electron redistribution and stabilizes active centers under oxidative conditions. This facilitates a dual-site fully parallel oxidation (DFO) pathway in which intermediates are synchronously adsorbed and desorbed at Ru and Co sites, enabling direct O&#8211;O coupling. This work highlights the synergistic effect of the Ru&#8211;Co dual sites and TiO2 support in establishing a stable, self-regulating electronic environment that drives efficient intermediate transformation via the DFO mechanism.</description>
      <author>Jing Liang, Yuanyuan Zhao, Chenyu Yang, Shu Zhu, Liang Wang, Ke Xu, Xueliang Mu, Yong Han, Zhi Liu, Zhiwei Zhao, Wei Liu, Fei Li, Zhangquan Peng, Edmund C. M. Tse, Qinghua Liu, Junfeng Gao, Qing Li, Jianfeng Li, Jinxuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c14137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Role of Composition and Size Effects in the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Pd&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&#8211;&lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Clusters (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 13 and 27)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05544</link>
      <description>Tiago Marcolino de Souza, Henrique A. B. Fonseca, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414474004

                The low-cost generation of green hydrogen (H2) via water electrolysis depends on advances in catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Although palladium and nickel nanoparticles have demonstrated potential catalytic performance, the exact interplay between particle size and composition in their binary forms remains an unresolved issue. Here, we explore NimPdn&#8211;m nanoclusters consisting of 13 and 27 atoms to improve our atomistic understanding of the fundamental mechanisms of HER at a nanoscale regime. We used the putative global minimum structure of the bare clusters and employed data mining techniques to generate and select preferential hydrogen adsorption structures. The electronic and geometrical properties are predicted using a cost-effective calculation protocol, based on density functional theory calculations with the PBE functional including van der Waals corrections. The computational hydrogen electrode (CHE) model was employed to calculate Gibbs free energies. We found that atomic H adsorbs on bridge and hollow sites in the 13-atom clusters and only on hollow sites in the 27-atom clusters. The effects of size and composition on the adsorption energies are also calculated, and their relation to the bulk values is presented. Our results on the Gibbs free energy for the HER reaction suggest that, at the subnanometer scale, the most promising catalysts are obtained when earth-abundant nickel clusters are doped with a small percentage of palladium, which has potential application for cost reduction. For instance, Ni10Pd3 shows a &#916;G of &#8722;0.35 eV, while Ni13 and Pd13 unary counterparts present &#8722;0.51 and &#8722;0.47 eV, respectively. An analysis of electron density reveals that within these NimPdn&#8211;m nanoclusters, a substantial charge transfer from the cluster to the hydrogen atom is correlated with lower values of &#916;G. This observation implies that charge transfer is a significant factor in the HER.</description>
      <author>Tiago Marcolino de Souza, Henrique A. B. Fonseca, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of ligand field modulation in TM@N2C2 single-atom catalysts for boosting electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction activity and selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136929</link>
      <description>Siwen Kuai, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414474966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siwen Kuai, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium Cation&#8208;Induced Self&#8208;Reconstruction of a Stable and High Performance Boride&#8208;derived Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507475</link>
      <description>Charles Otieno Ogolla, M. Kasper, Muhammed Fasil Puthiyaparambath, Nastaran Farahbakhsh, Ranjit Thapa, T. Maiyalagan, Manuela S. Killian, Benjamin Butz, Jean Marie Vianney Nsanzimana, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414476352

                Abstract The rational design of efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), holds the key to advancing the overall electrolytic water splitting performance. Here, a scalable one&#8208;pot synthesis of a stable chromium&#9472;iron nickel boride (Cr&#9472;FeNiB) electrocatalyst is reported for OER in which nickel&#8208;boron sites are micro&#8208;environmentally modified through interactions with iron and chromium. Comprehensive, correlative electrochemical, structural, and chemical analyses reveal the formation of amorphous&#8208;crystalline core&#8208;shell structures that transform into nanosheets upon activation with enhanced water oxidation catalytic activity. The enhanced catalytic performance is attributed to the chromium&#8208;induced chemical self&#8208;reconstruction of the catalyst, which facilitates favorable OER kinetics, increased turnover frequency, and a synergistic effect between metal and boron constituents. Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculation showed that chromium incorporation effectively shifts the d &#8208;band centers ( &#603; d ) closer to the Fermi level and narrows the metal&#8208;d/boron&#8208;p band center gap (&#916; &#603; d&#8208;p ) (Ni 2 B 1.10 eV &#8594; FeNiB 0.71 eV &#8594; Cr&#9472;FeNiB 0.55 eV) ultimately enhancing OER activity. Accordingly, the &#916; &#603; d&#8208;p is established as a key electronic descriptor for predicting and optimizing OER performance. These findings pave the way for a better understanding of metal boride&#8208;derived electrocatalysts and also contribute to the development of efficient, stable, earth&#8208;abundant, non&#8208;noble metal catalysts for water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Charles Otieno Ogolla, M. Kasper, Muhammed Fasil Puthiyaparambath, Nastaran Farahbakhsh, Ranjit Thapa, T. Maiyalagan, Manuela S. Killian, Benjamin Butz, Jean Marie Vianney Nsanzimana</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507475</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sc/Mg Co&#8208;Doping in Na&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Zr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Si&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;PO&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; Solid&#8208;State Electrolytes Enables Outstanding Performance of Sodium Metal Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202515463</link>
      <description>Xin Wang, Jiayang Li, Zewei Hu, Xinghan Li, Liyang Liu, Jiazhao Wang, Jung Ho Kim, Weijie Li, Wei Kong Pang, Bernt Johannessen, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414478817

                Abstract All solid&#8208;state sodium metal batteries offer a transformative opportunity for more sustainable energy storage, with the potential to significantly improve both energy density and safety compared to conventional sodium&#8208;ion batteries. However, their practical application is hindered by challenges such as dendrite formation and limited ion conductivity. In this study, a novel strategy is proposed in which Sc 3+ and Mg 2+ dopants are directly introduced into the Na 3 Zr 2 Si 2 PO 12 solid&#8208;state electrolyte (NZSP SSE) to optimize composition and regulate interfacial chemistry. The resulting co&#8208;doped electrolyte, Na 3.7 Zr 1.45 Sc 0.4 Mg 0.15 Si 2 PO 12 (NSZSP&#8208;0.15Mg), exhibits a significantly enhanced ionic conductivity of 1.3 mS cm &#8722;1 at room temperature and improved interfacial compatibility. Moreover, symmetric Na//NSZSP&#8208;0.15Mg//Na cells demonstrate stable Na stripping/plating for over 400 h (0.5 mA cm &#8722;2 , 0.5 mAh cm &#8722;2 ), attributed to the formation of a dynamically stable ScPO 4 /Mg 3 (PO 4 ) 2 &#8208;rich interphase layer at the Na metal/SSE interface. Furthermore, Na//NSZSP&#8208;0.15Mg//Na 3 V 2 (PO 4 ) 3 full cell batteries exhibit excellent rate capability and long&#8208;term cycling stability, maintaining 75 mAh g &#8722;1 over 3000 cycles at 2 C at room temperature. This work presents a robust approach for enabling practical solid&#8208;state sodium metal batteries with high conductivity, enhanced interfacial stability, high energy density, and long&#8208;term cyclability, advancing the development of next&#8208;generation SSEs for high&#8208;performance sodium metal batteries.</description>
      <author>Xin Wang, Jiayang Li, Zewei Hu, Xinghan Li, Liyang Liu, Jiazhao Wang, Jung Ho Kim, Weijie Li, Wei Kong Pang, Bernt Johannessen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202515463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-sensitive electrochemical oxygen gas sensor with zero power consumption based on Pt/CMK-3-COOH modified ionic liquid as composite electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2025.138828</link>
      <description>Xingxing Yu, Faxun Wang, Huakang Zong, Yufei Gan, Guotao Duan, Yuanyuan Luo, Sensors and Actuators B Chemical. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414481357

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingxing Yu, Faxun Wang, Huakang Zong, Yufei Gan, Guotao Duan, Yuanyuan Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2025.138828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Mechanism for Hydrogen Production via Methane Pyrolysis on a Dynamic Liquid Ga&#8211;Fe&#8211;Ni Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501044</link>
      <description>Mohammad Zafari, Babu Ram, Rohit Anand, Yong Chul Kim, Geunsik Lee, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414487979

                Abstract Dynamic liquid metal alloys have been promising for catalytic green hydrogen (H 2 ) production through methane pyrolysis. Owing to their atomic mobility, liquid metal catalysts have a fluidic atomic structure in which obtaining reaction energies and kinetic barriers hinges on reliable geometrical descriptions of atomic arrangements. Here, the catalytic reaction mechanism for methane pyrolysis on the surface of molten Ga&#8211;Fe&#8211;Ni as the catalyst is investigated, using an approach based on fully dynamic sampling of ab initio molecular dynamic trajectories. The results reveal that the adsorption energy for the first C&#9472;H bond breaking in methane is notably enhanced from 2.2 eV on liquid Ga to 1.2 eV on molten Ga&#8211;Fe&#8211;Ni. The mobility of dissolved Fe and Ni atoms plays a critical role for activation of Ga atoms on the alloy surface, facilitating charge transferring from solvent atoms (electron donor) to solute atoms (electron acceptor), thereby modulating electronic structure. The dissociated hydrogen atoms, with a low kinetic barrier of approximately 0.6 eV computed via the blue moon ensemble method, can easily bond together, desorbing as H 2 molecules from the surface. Our findings highlight that mobile dissolved species in liquid metal matrix can bestow unique catalytic activity to solvent atoms by modifying electronic structure.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Zafari, Babu Ram, Rohit Anand, Yong Chul Kim, Geunsik Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Principles in Engineering of Multigrain Nanocatalysts via Multiscale Electronic Structure Characterization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c01154</link>
      <description>Min Gee Cho, Colin Ophus, Jung-Hoon Lee, Inchul Park, Dong Young Chung, Jeong Hyun Kim, Jaehyun Kim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Kisuk Kang, Mary Scott, A. Paul Alivisatos, Taeghwan Hyeon, Myoung Hwan Oh, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414489235

                Engineering grain boundary (GB) strain provides a promising pathway to tune the catalytic properties of nanocrystals. However, structural heterogeneity from random grain orientation and geometry has limited clear structure&#8211;property correlations. Here, we utilize a multigrain Co3O4/Mn3O4 core/shell nanocrystal platform as a model system to systematically investigate how geometric misfit strain at GBs serves as catalytically active sites for the oxygen reduction reaction. Through precise subnanometer-level control over grain morphology and by integrating multiscale electronic structure characterization, we identify the electronic structural signature of GB defects and establish a direct correlation between localized strain fields and modified electronic states. Strain modulation at GBs alters the eg orbital energy levels, with elongation along the z-axis combined with shear strain stabilizing the eg states, in contrast to the destabilization observed under pure shear strain. This stabilization mechanism enhances the electrocatalytic activity and selectivity of strained GBs compared with strain-relaxed grain surfaces. Furthermore, we reveal that GBs exhibit a radial strain gradient, producing a spatial energy shift that further modulates local electronic structures, as resolved through the classification of electron energy loss spectroscopy data. Together, these findings demonstrate that geometric misfit strain enables precise tuning of grain geometry and the resulting electronic structures, offering a robust strategy for engineering next-generation nanocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Min Gee Cho, Colin Ophus, Jung-Hoon Lee, Inchul Park, Dong Young Chung, Jeong Hyun Kim, Jaehyun Kim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Kisuk Kang, Mary Scott, A. Paul Alivisatos, Taeghwan Hyeon, Myoung Hwan Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c01154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Hemilabile Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks Overlooked as Promising Water-Stable Adsorbents? Elucidating Their Physical and Hydrolytic Properties Using Machine-Learned Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07377</link>
      <description>Yifei Yue, Athulya S. Palakkal, N. Duane Loh, Jianwen Jiang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414495489

                Poor water stability of many metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) is a persistent bottleneck toward their practical applications. Hemilabile STAMs (St. Andrews Materials) demonstrate greater water stability, as well as improved adsorption performance under humid conditions, compared to compositionally similar HKUST-1. Yet, the fundamental properties of STAMs remain largely unexplored. Herein, we leverage machine-learned potentials (MLPs) to simulate physical and hydrolytic properties, water stability and adsorption in STAMs functionalized with various hydrophobic/hydrophilic groups. Encouragingly, STAMs are predicted to exhibit high mechanical strength and low heat capacity, which are desirable attributes in adsorption processes. Moreover, defective STAMs are shown to possess greater mechanical robustness than defective HKUST-1. From MLP-based molecular dynamics simulations, we demonstrate that Cu-paddlewheels of STAMs are relatively stable even at high water loadings. The hydrolysis mechanism of Cu-paddlewheels is examined meticulously, and for the first time, we quantitatively reveal a higher energy barrier is required to hydrolyze Cu&#8211;O bonds in STAMs than in HKUST-1, unambiguously elucidating the crucial role of Cu&#183;&#183;&#183;OH2 interactions in water stability of hemilabile STAMs. From MLP-based Monte Carlo simulations, water adsorption isotherms predicted in STAMs match well with experimental data. Importantly, it is concretely demonstrated that water adsorption in the hexagonal pore can be tailored by modifying the hydrophobicity of functional groups, while adsorption in the triangular pore is affected marginally. Beyond showing that STAMs are promising adsorbents, we provide new microscopic insights into physical and hydrolytic properties in Cu paddlewheel-based MOFs. More generally, our findings suggest that incorporating hemilability is a promising but underexplored strategy for the development of new water-stable MOFs.</description>
      <author>Yifei Yue, Athulya S. Palakkal, N. Duane Loh, Jianwen Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-efficiency pHotocatalytic water splitting via direct Z-scheme charge transfer in GaN/ZrS2 van der Waals heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2025.116801</link>
      <description>Liqin Zhang, Qingquan Xiao, Sheng&#8208;Rui Jian, Jianfeng Ye, Fuqiang Ai, Li Sheng, Xiaoping Wu, Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology A Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414498294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liqin Zhang, Qingquan Xiao, Sheng&#8208;Rui Jian, Jianfeng Ye, Fuqiang Ai, Li Sheng, Xiaoping Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2025.116801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast and Fourier features for transfer learning of interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01779-z</link>
      <description>Pietro Novelli, Giacomo Meanti, Pedro J. Buigues, Lorenzo Rosasco, Michele Parrinello, Massimiliano Pontil, Leo H. Bonati, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414514094

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pietro Novelli, Giacomo Meanti, Pedro J. Buigues, Lorenzo Rosasco, Michele Parrinello, Massimiliano Pontil, Leo H. Bonati</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01779-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon confinement engineering of ultrafine Pt-based catalyst for robust electrochemical oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2025.09.006</link>
      <description>Dongping Xue, Yu Zhao, Huicong Xia, Jianliang Cao, Yan Wang, Nano Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414517484

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongping Xue, Yu Zhao, Huicong Xia, Jianliang Cao, Yan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2025.09.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Surface Degradation Pathways of Charged Nickel-Oxide Cathode Materials Using Machine-Learning Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c11818</link>
      <description>Svenja Both, Andrey D. Poletayev, Timo Danner, Arnulf Latz, M. Saiful Islam, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414517715

                While nickel-based layered oxide cathodes offer promising energy and power densities in lithium-ion batteries, they suffer from instability when fully delithiated upon charge. Ex situ studies often report a structural degradation of the charged cathode materials, but the precise mechanism is still poorly understood on the atomic scale. In this work, we combine high-level ab initio calculations with molecular dynamics using machine-learning interatomic potentials to study structural degradation of fully delithiated LiNiO2 surfaces at the top of charge. We find a previously unreported, stable reconstruction of the (012) facet with more facile oxygen loss compared to the pristine surfaces. The oxygen vacancy formation energy closely corresponds to the experimental decomposition temperatures of charged cathodes. Furthermore, we use molecular dynamics simulations to sample Ni ion migration into alkali-layer sites that is a kinetically plausible initiation step for surface degradation toward thermodynamically stable products.</description>
      <author>Svenja Both, Andrey D. Poletayev, Timo Danner, Arnulf Latz, M. Saiful Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c11818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconfiguration of the Fe N4 active site by S element and its effect on hydrogen evolution performance of Fe&#8209;carbon dots SACs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168904</link>
      <description>Chenfang Lou, Qinfen Tian, Jiaqi Liang, Tong Lin, Jiande Lin, Xinru Zheng, Xingyu Chen, Xin Li, Guofa Dong, Yuan Hu, Jiandong Zhuang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414520869

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenfang Lou, Qinfen Tian, Jiaqi Liang, Tong Lin, Jiande Lin, Xinru Zheng, Xingyu Chen, Xin Li, Guofa Dong, Yuan Hu, Jiandong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168904</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Electrochemical CO2 Reduction via Ionic Liquid Cation Enhanced Stabilization of CO2 Radical Anion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126006</link>
      <description>Hui Yu, Wenru Zhao, J. Wang, Wei Wang, Liu-Liu Shen, Guirong Zhang, Donghai Mei, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414521253

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Yu, Wenru Zhao, J. Wang, Wei Wang, Liu-Liu Shen, Guirong Zhang, Donghai Mei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo-enhanced passivity of stainless steels studied at metal/oxide interfaces by DFT atomistic modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164709</link>
      <description>Xian Huang, Dominique Costa, Vincent Maurice, Philippe Marcus, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414522781

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xian Huang, Dominique Costa, Vincent Maurice, Philippe Marcus</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy Governs the Structure and Reactivity of Water Dissociation Under Electric Fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12397</link>
      <description>Yair Litman, Angelos Michaelides, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414524000

                The response of water to electric fields is critical to the performance and stability of electrochemical devices, and the selectivity of enzymatic, atmospheric, and organic reactions. A key process in this context is the water (auto)dissociation reaction (WD), which governs acid&#8211;base aqueous chemistry and shapes reaction rates and mechanisms. Despite its significance, the thermodynamics of the WD reaction in electrified environments remains poorly understood. Here, we investigate the WD reaction under external electric fields using ab initio molecular dynamics simulations within the framework of the modern theory of polarization. Our results reveal that strong electric fields dramatically enhance the WD reaction, increasing the equilibrium constant by several orders of magnitude. Moreover, we show that the applied field transforms the WD reaction from an entropically hindered process to an entropy-driven one. Analysis shows that this is because the electric field alters the tendency of ions to be structure makers or structure breakers. By highlighting how strong electric fields reshape solvent organization and reactivity, this work opens new avenues for designing aqueous electro-catalysts that leverage solvent entropy to enhance their performance.</description>
      <author>Yair Litman, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of NH3 from low-concentration NO on cascade dual-site catalysts in neutral media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63365-7</link>
      <description>Xiaoxi Guo, Tongwei Wu, Hengfeng Li, Yanning Zhang, Chao Ma, Hongmei Li, Liyuan Chai, Haitao Zhao, Min Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414533656

                Electrosynthesis of NH3 from low-concentration NO (NORR) in neutral media offers a sustainable nitrogen fixation strategy but is hindered by weak NO adsorption, slow water dissociation, and sluggish hydrogenation kinetics. Herein, we propose an intriguing strategy that successfully overcomes these limitations through using an electron-donating motif to modulate NO-affinitive catalysts, thereby creating dual active site with synergistic functionality. Specifically, we integrate electron-donating nanoparticles into a Fe single-atom catalyst (FeSAC), where Fe sites ensure strong NO adsorption, while electron-donating motifs promote water dissociation and NO hydrogenation. In situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS), in situ attenuated total reflection-infrared spectroscopy (ATR-IR), and theoretical calculations reveal that electron-donating motifs increase Fe site electron density, strengthening NO adsorption. Additionally, these motifs also promote water dissociation, supplying protons to lower the NO hydrogenation barrier. This synergistic interplay enables a cascade reaction mechanism, delivering a remarkable Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 90.3% and a NH3 yield rate of 709.7 &#181;g h&#8722;1 mgcat.&#8722;1 under 1.0 vol% NO in neutral media, outperforming pure FeSAC (NH3 yield rate: 444.2 &#181;g h&#8722;1 mgcat.&#8722;1, FE: 56.6%) and prior to systems operating under high NO concentrations. Notably, the high NH3 yield of 3207.7 &#956;g h&#8722;1 mgcat.&#8722;1 is achieved in a membrane electrode assembly (MEA) electrolyzer under a 1.0 vol% NO. This work establishes an inspirational paradigm in NORR by simultaneously enhancing NO adsorption, water dissociation, and hydrogenation kinetics, providing a scalable route for efficient NH3 electrosynthesis from dilute NO sources. Weak NO adsorption, slow water dissociation, and sluggish hydrogenation hinder neutral-media NH3 electrosynthesis from low-concentration NO. Here, the authors report an electron-donating motif modulating a NO-affinitive catalyst to create dual active sites, thus facilitating NO-to-NH3 conversion.</description>
      <author>Xiaoxi Guo, Tongwei Wu, Hengfeng Li, Yanning Zhang, Chao Ma, Hongmei Li, Liyuan Chai, Haitao Zhao, Min Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63365-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoindentation simulations for copper and tungsten with adaptive-precision potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/2lkd-l6gt</link>
      <description>David Immel, Matous Mrovec, Ralf Drautz, Godehard Sutmann, Physical Review Materials. 9(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414534797

                We perform nanoindentation simulations for both the prototypical face-centered cubic metal copper and the body-centered cubic metal tungsten with an adaptive-precision description of interaction potentials including different accuracy and computational costs. We combine both a computationally efficient embedded atom method (EAM) potential and a precise but computationally less efficient machine learning potential based on the atomic cluster expansion (ACE) into an adaptive precision (AP) potential tailored for the nanoindentation. The numerically more expensive ACE potential is employed selectively only in regions of the computational cell where high precision is required. The comparison with pure EAM and pure ACE simulations shows that for Cu, all potentials yield similar dislocation morphologies under the indenter with only small quantitative differences. In contrast, markedly different plasticity mechanisms are observed for W in simulations performed with the central-force EAM potential compared to results obtained using the ACE potential. ACE is able to describe accurately the angular character of bonding, which is in W due to its half-filled d band. All ACE-specific mechanisms are reproduced in the AP nanoindentation simulations, however, with a significant speedup of 20&#8211;30 times compared to the pure ACE simulations. Hence, the AP potential overcomes the performance gap between the precise ACE and the fast EAM potential by combining the advantages of both potentials.</description>
      <author>David Immel, Matous Mrovec, Ralf Drautz, Godehard Sutmann</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/2lkd-l6gt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactions of Carbenes with Coinage Metal Surfaces: An Electrophilic Reactive Carbene vs. a Nucleophilic Stable Carbene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.joc.5c01313</link>
      <description>Yining Liu, Joel Mieres&#8208;P&#233;rez, Elsa S&#225;nchez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, The Journal of Organic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414535512

                Carbenes are key intermediates in many chemical applications. The properties of carbenes very much depend on substitution and on the chemical environment such as solvent or surface interactions. In this work, we computationally study cyclopentadienylidene (CP), as an archetypical electrophilic reactive carbene, on three metal surfaces: Cu(111), Ag(111), and Au(111). In addition, we investigate the stable nucleophilic N-heterocyclic carbene imidazolidene (IMI) as a structurally analogous counterpart of CP for comparing the behavior of these two drastically different types of carbene species in the presence of metal surfaces. Our study reveals different adsorption geometries: CP adsorbs tilted; IMI adsorbs perpendicularly on the three surfaces. CP has a much higher adsorption energy on metal surfaces compared to IMI. The adsorption energy of CP follows the tendency Ag &lt; Au &lt; Cu. All metal surfaces induced switching of the ground electronic state of CP from triplet to singlet. The nucleophilic IMI acts as electron donor when adsorbed, with net charge transferred from IMI to the metal surface. The electrophilic CP acts as an electron acceptor, withdrawing net charge from the metal surface. Our study can contribute to engineering new classes of on-surface catalytic systems, based on tailored reactivities of surface-bound carbenes.</description>
      <author>Yining Liu, Joel Mieres&#8208;P&#233;rez, Elsa S&#225;nchez&#8208;Garc&#237;a</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.joc.5c01313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pr-induced dual-site oxide pathway in BiFeO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; for enhanced alkaline water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5tc02862k</link>
      <description>Rongrong Jia, Y. H. Zheng, Zhe Su, Zhijie Yang, Guoli Chen, Wanting Yang, Xiaoxuan Ma, Yidan Liu, Shoushuang Huang, Lei Huang, Wei Ren, Shixun Cao, Rongrong Jia, Journal of Materials Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414541340

                Pr doping in BiFeO 3 induces lattice distortion, tunes electronic structure and the d-band center, boosting intermediate adsorption and OPM-driven *O&#8211;O* coupling. Bi 0.6 Pr 0.4 FeO 3 @NF shows &#951; 10 = 228 mV and stable 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for 100 h in 1 M KOH.</description>
      <author>Rongrong Jia, Y. H. Zheng, Zhe Su, Zhijie Yang, Guoli Chen, Wanting Yang, Xiaoxuan Ma, Yidan Liu, Shoushuang Huang, Lei Huang, Wei Ren, Shixun Cao, Rongrong Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5tc02862k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding pH-dependent electrocatalysis through electric field models and microkinetic volcanoes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta06105a</link>
      <description>Songbo Ye, Yuhang Wang, Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Xue Jia, Linda Zhang, Yizhou Zhang, Akichika Kumatani, Hitoshi Shiku, Hao Li, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414542010

                This perspective highlights advances in capturing pH-dependent surface structures, reactivity, and mechanisms via electric field-based methods.</description>
      <author>Songbo Ye, Yuhang Wang, Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Xue Jia, Linda Zhang, Yizhou Zhang, Akichika Kumatani, Hitoshi Shiku, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta06105a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Screening of 2D Photocatalyst Heterostructures with Suppressed Electron&#8211;Hole Recombination for Solar Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c02326</link>
      <description>Shalini S. Yadav, Jigisha Modi, Raihan Ahammed, B. S. Bhadoria, Yogesh Singh Chauhan, Amit Agarwal, Somnath Bhowmick, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414542604

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shalini S. Yadav, Jigisha Modi, Raihan Ahammed, B. S. Bhadoria, Yogesh Singh Chauhan, Amit Agarwal, Somnath Bhowmick</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c02326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Quantum Circuit Learning Models for Molecular Dynamics Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c03624</link>
      <description>Yasutaka Nishida, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414543782

                In the past decade, many hybrid quantum-classical algorithms have been applied to various industrial fields, reflecting the growing interest in NISQ devices. For example, in the field of chemistry, many studies were conducted to calculate the energies of eigenstates with high precision. However, there is still little research on molecular dynamics using quantum computers, because traditional approaches based on variational quantum algorithms are not suitable for the long-time steps of molecular dynamics. In this study, we propose a quantum circuit learning model that estimates the eigenvalues of a given molecular Hamiltonian for an arbitrary molecular configuration. Our model must first be costly to train; however, once trained, the resulting trained model can eliminate procedures that required variational optimization each time the molecular coordinates are updated in the previous variational approach. By using the proposed model, we demonstrate that the proposed model can be used to perform simple molecular dynamics simulations, such as Langevin dynamics and NVE simulation. We also show several applications of our model inspired by classical machine learning.</description>
      <author>Yasutaka Nishida</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c03624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Droplet Microfluidic Design Framework with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c06253</link>
      <description>Duc Minh Nguyen, Raymond Kai-YuTong, Ngoc&#8208;Duy Dinh, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414554088

                Droplet-based microfluidic devices have substantial promise as cost-effective alternatives to current assessment tools in biological research. Moreover, machine learning models that leverage tabular data, including input design parameters and their corresponding efficiency outputs, are increasingly utilized to automate the design process of these devices and to predict their performance. However, these models fail to fully leverage the data presented in the tables, neglecting crucial contextual information, including column headings and their associated descriptions. This study presents &#956;-Fluidic-LLMs, a framework designed for processing and feature extraction, which effectively captures contextual information from tabular data formats. &#956;-Fluidic-LLMs overcomes processing challenges by transforming the content into a linguistic format and leveraging pretrained large language models (LLMs) for analysis. We evaluate our &#956;-Fluidic-LLMs framework on prediction tasks utilizing publicly available data sets on droplet microfluidics. We demonstrate that our &#956;-Fluidic-LLMs framework can empower deep neural network models to be highly effective and straightforward while minimizing the need for extensive data preprocessing. When combined with LLMs like LLAMA3.1 and DEEPSEEK-R1, deep neural networks achieve marked improvements, lowering the mean absolute error in generation rate by nearly 40%, reducing the root mean squared error in droplet diameter by around 26%, and enhancing regime classification accuracy by over 3% in comparison with prior results. This study lays the foundation for the huge potential applications of LLMs and machine learning in a wider spectrum of microfluidic applications.</description>
      <author>Duc Minh Nguyen, Raymond Kai-YuTong, Ngoc&#8208;Duy Dinh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c06253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Mn-Doped ZnO Catalysts: Structural, Electronic, and Mechanistic Insights for Selective Peroxide Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7518552/v1</link>
      <description>Cristina Mart&#305;&#769;nez, Alannisse M. Santos-Rivera, N&#233;stor Pardo Garc&#237;a, Horacio Gonz&#225;lez, Joshua A. Ortiz-Fernandez, Joesene J. Soto, Anton&#237; Torres, Juan A. Santana, Christopher J. Pollock, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, M. Santiago-Berrios, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414556981

                Abstract In this work, we investigate manganese-doped ZnO catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in alkaline media, combining structural characterization, electrochemical analysis, and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. XRD confirms that Mn doping preserves the wurtzite ZnO structure while inducing lattice distortions and vibrational shifts indicative of manganese incorporation. XPS analysis reveals that Mn3&#8314; is the dominant surface species, which is confirmed by x-ray absorption and emission spectroscopic measurements. Electrochemically, Mn-doped ZnO exhibits enhanced catalytic performance, with increased limiting current density and slight improvements in onset potential compared to pure ZnO. DFT calculations indicate that, while the overall thermodynamics of peroxide formation remain similar, the incorporation of Mn significantly stabilizes the *&#8211;OOH intermediate, thereby reducing the energy requirement for this key step. Together, these findings demonstrate that manganese doping improves ORR activity by modifying the electronic structure and enhancing reaction kinetics, offering valuable insights for the design of efficient ZnO-based electrocatalysts for selective H&#8322;O&#8322; production.</description>
      <author>Cristina Mart&#305;&#769;nez, Alannisse M. Santos-Rivera, N&#233;stor Pardo Garc&#237;a, Horacio Gonz&#225;lez, Joshua A. Ortiz-Fernandez, Joesene J. Soto, Anton&#237; Torres, Juan A. Santana, Christopher J. Pollock, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, M. Santiago-Berrios</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7518552/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption Dynamics and Electric Double Layer Properties at Pt(100) Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500680</link>
      <description>Haiting Yu, Renata Sechi, Qingdian Liao, M.S. Nissen, Arghya Bhowmik, Elena L. Gubanova, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Heine Anton Hansen, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414560056

                Abstract The electrode&#8208;electrolyte interface governs many functional properties and processes, such as reaction rates, efficiency, and selectivity in electrochemical systems, with its structure and physicochemical phenomena being crucial for optimizing energy conversion and storage technologies. Platinum (Pt) is a state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art catalyst for numerous electrocatalytic reactions. While Pt(111) is extensively studied, atomic&#8208;level insights into interfacial properties of another basic surface, Pt(100), remain unresolved. Here, experimental techniques and first&#8208;principles calculations are utilized to investigate adsorption behavior and adsorbate coverage at varying potentials as well as interfacial entropy in acidic media. The results reveal four voltammetric peak features: below peak I, hydrogen is the predominant adsorbate; between peak II and peak III, a mixed adsorption region with 22% hydroxide and 44% hydrogen forms, while at higher potentials, hydroxide coverage increases. The double&#8208;layer structure is also explored, finding sensitivity of the double&#8208;layer capacitance to electrode surface structure. For the first time, by combining in situ laser&#8208;induced current transient and Raman spectroscopy, two potential values of maximum entropy are identified, indicating enhanced disorder and facilitated charge transfer, supported by disruption of the hydrogen&#8208;bond network due to increased dangling bonds. These insights guide the rational design of efficient electrode&#8208;electrolyte interfaces in Pt&#8208;based nanostructured materials.</description>
      <author>Haiting Yu, Renata Sechi, Qingdian Liao, M.S. Nissen, Arghya Bhowmik, Elena L. Gubanova, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Heine Anton Hansen, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500680</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Design of Pt&#63743;m (M = Au, Ir, Pd, Rh, and Ru) Binary Alloys for Enhanced Ammonia Oxidation Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500288</link>
      <description>Brendan J. R. Laframboise, Julia Coveny, Jingwen Zhou, Leanne D. Chen, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414565031

                The electrochemical ammonia oxidation reaction (AOR) shows considerable potential for its applications in waste removal and the production of clean energy. While Pt remains the most investigated catalyst for this reaction, its limitations have prompted research into Pt&#8208;based bimetallic alloys. This study investigates both uniform and mixed PtM (M = Au, Ir, Pd, Rh, and Ru) alloys as catalysts for the AOR using density functional theory (DFT). A systematic selection method is used to choose suitable surfaces for testing. The findings indicate that the Oswin&#8211;Salomon mechanism is preferred across all surfaces for N 2 (g) formation. Additionally, the results demonstrate that mixed alloys exhibit superior catalytic activity compared to uniform alloys for the AOR. It is found that the atoms in the topmost layer of the alloy are the most significant factor in influencing catalytic activity. Furthermore, the linear relationship between the &#8208;band center and adsorption energy of key intermediate *NH 2 is confirmed in this work, highlighting the effect of the secondary metal on the electronic structure of the catalyst. The findings provide theoretical insights for the design of high&#8208;performance Pt alloys for AOR and serve as a general guideline for modulating the reactivity of binary alloys for electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Brendan J. R. Laframboise, Julia Coveny, Jingwen Zhou, Leanne D. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layer-Dependent Nitrate Reduction on 2D Bismuth: p-Orbital Delocalization Breaks the &#8220;Thinner-is-Better&#8221; Paradigm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5536732</link>
      <description>Xiaorong Zhu, Jiayu Gu, Xiaolei Yuan, Ming Ge, Yanfeng Tang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414569322

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaorong Zhu, Jiayu Gu, Xiaolei Yuan, Ming Ge, Yanfeng Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5536732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STEMDiff: A Wavelet&#8208;Enhanced Diffusion Model for Physics&#8208;Informed STEM Image Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202508266</link>
      <description>Yihui Bao, Xinyi Lu, Yanyan Xia, Zhencheng Ye, Houyang Chen, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414570643

                Abstract Machine learning has emerged as a powerful tool for analyzing scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM) images, yet its widespread application remains constrained by the scarcity of annotated training data. While deep generative models offer a promising solution, they typically struggle to reproduce the complex high&#8208;frequency components that define experimental STEM images. Here, STEMDiff, a conditional diffusion model that transforms simple binary labels derived from crystal structures into realistic STEM images through a physical information embedding strategy, is proposed. By developing a novel Discrete Wavelet Transform&#8208;based skip&#8208;connection architecture, the high&#8208;frequency bias inherent in diffusion models are addressed, enabling the preservation of experimental noise characteristics. This approach generates images that are quantitatively nearly indistinguishable from experimental data (17 fold improvement over previous methods) while retaining ground truth structural information. Fully convolutional networks trained exclusively on these synthetic images achieve high&#8208;precision atomic column detection in experimental STEM images of WSe 2 and graphene, despite the presence of substantial background noise and contamination. This approach effectively eliminates the need for laborious manual annotation, providing a scalable solution to the data bottleneck in STEM image analysis. The principles underlying STEMDiff can extend to other scientific imaging modalities, accelerating advancements in materials design for water treatment.</description>
      <author>Yihui Bao, Xinyi Lu, Yanyan Xia, Zhencheng Ye, Houyang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202508266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic resonance theory for parametric uncertainty of programmable catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101523</link>
      <description>Sallye R. Gathmann, Seongjoo Jung, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414571673

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sallye R. Gathmann, Seongjoo Jung, Paul J. Dauenhauer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis, Alloying Process, and Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Activity of Highly Stable Ni&#8211;Fe&#8211;Mo Nanoparticles with a Face&#8208;Centered Cubic Phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202505716</link>
      <description>Yan Jia, Xiao Ma, Yibin Yang, Rui Chao, Ji&#8208;Kai Li, Pengfei Guo, Bing Zhu, Qian&#8208;Nan Yang, Weitao Wang, Lu Liu, Zhao&#8208;Tie Liu, Yang Yang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414575903

                Abstract Real&#8208;time visualization of alloying evolution is crucial yet challenging for designing and synthesizing face&#8208;centered cubic (fcc) nanoalloy catalysts for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, a trimetallic fcc NiFeMo nanoalloy is synthesized via topological reduction of NiFeMo layered double hydroxide (LDH) under an Ar/H 2 atmosphere. In situ heating transmission electron microscopy reveals the transforamtion of non&#8208;hexagonal NiFeMo LDH nanosheets into irregular inverse&#8208;spinel Ni 1&#8208;x Mo x Fe 2 O 4 nanoparticles, eventually forming spherical fcc NiFeMo nanoalloy particles. Furthermore, the NiFeMo nanoalloy demonstrates a Faradaic efficiency of 99.3% and superior intrinsic OER activity compared to NiFe and Ni nanoalloys at a consistent mass loading, due to synergistic metal interactions. The NiFeMo nanoalloy&#8208;modified nickel foam electrode exhibits excellent electrochemical stability, with structural and elemental analyses confirming that the original fcc structure remains intact after long&#8208;term OER testing. Operando differential electrochemical mass spectrometry coupled with isotope labelling experiment illustrates that the OER on NiFeMo nanoalloy proceeds via an adsorbate evolution mechanism pathway. Theoretical calculations suggest that Mo species reduce the potential barriers for *OH intermediate formation, thereby enhancing the inherent activity of Ni active sites in the NiFeMo nanoalloy. This work presents a novel approach for developing advanced trimetallic and high&#8208;entropy nanoalloy OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yan Jia, Xiao Ma, Yibin Yang, Rui Chao, Ji&#8208;Kai Li, Pengfei Guo, Bing Zhu, Qian&#8208;Nan Yang, Weitao Wang, Lu Liu, Zhao&#8208;Tie Liu, Yang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202505716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Nanoarchitectonics: DFT Calculation of the Adsorption Energy of Oxygen Atoms on Platinum Nanowires Formed on One-Dimensionally Polymerized Fullerene Molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02187-9</link>
      <description>Kun&#8217;ichi Miyazawa, Yumi Tanaka, Topics in Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414445371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kun&#8217;ichi Miyazawa, Yumi Tanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02187-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Dependent Interfacial Concentration of Oxygen Confined within Pd Interlayers: Molecular Dynamics with a Neural Network Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c15915</link>
      <description>Feicheng Huan, Feng Shi, Gaoyang Luo, Xiang Pan, Jingnan Zheng, Jianguo Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414542564

                Obtaining a detailed understanding of the interfacial dynamics of oxygen on palladium surfaces is crucial for industrial applications. However, it remains challenging to develop reaction&#8211;transport coupling mechanisms to enhance the activity and stability of Pd-based catalysts in confined environments. Herein, by integrating the established global neural network (G-NN) potential and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, the interfacial concentrations of confined O2 molecules within Pd interlayers were investigated systematically under various conditions. The developed reactive NN potential, rigorously validated against DFT benchmarks with an average error of 0.026 eV/atom, demonstrated precise structural discrimination capabilities among three Pd surfaces and subsequently produced reasonable catalytic structures. The Pd(100) surface exhibited the highest reactivity, followed by Pd(211), with the lowest on Pd(111). These differences show strong correlations with a reduced interlayer distance (approximately 1 nm) and the degree of surface reconstruction patterns through a comprehensive analysis of mean square displacement and reaction rate. Density distribution, in conjunction with radial distribution function analyses, further demonstrates how the interlayer confinement effect, as well as surface-specific atomic arrangements, remarkably regulate the interfacial concentration of oxygen. This work provides universal guidance for elucidating the macroscopic mechanism linking the bulk and interfacial concentrations in confined systems through large-scale simulations.</description>
      <author>Feicheng Huan, Feng Shi, Gaoyang Luo, Xiang Pan, Jingnan Zheng, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c15915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the HER performance of binary MnO2&#8211;CdSe heterostructure via interface engineering with g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151729</link>
      <description>Tauseef Munawar, Ambreen Bashir, Zhida Wang, Zhiming Tu, Lisha Shen, Muhammad Rafaqat, Jueshuo Fan, Muammer Ko&#231;&#8236;, Faisal Iqbal, Chang-Feng Yan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 179(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414567339

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tauseef Munawar, Ambreen Bashir, Zhida Wang, Zhiming Tu, Lisha Shen, Muhammad Rafaqat, Jueshuo Fan, Muammer Ko&#231;&#8236;, Faisal Iqbal, Chang-Feng Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schottky-Type Oxygen Defect and Orbital Engineering of Bismuth Oxide for Boosting Sulfur Redox Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104626</link>
      <description>Mingjie Yi, H.B. Zhang, Y Li, Shunyou Hu, Yang Yang, Run&#8208;Cang Sun, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414416807

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingjie Yi, H.B. Zhang, Y Li, Shunyou Hu, Yang Yang, Run&#8208;Cang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104626</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarifying the roles of surface structure and strain engineering in tuning the oxygen evolution reaction activity of La2/3Sr1/3MnO3 thin film</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164700</link>
      <description>Ji Qi, Kaixin Zhu, Weiguang Ma, Hefeng Zhang, Ming Feng, Xu Zong, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414482967

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ji Qi, Kaixin Zhu, Weiguang Ma, Hefeng Zhang, Ming Feng, Xu Zong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164700</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
