<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 01:58:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-Passivated germanium carbide nanomeshes as potential catalysts for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-11711-6</link>
      <description>Sarah Gamal, Ghada E. Khedr, M. Nashaat, L.M. Salah, Ahmed A. Maarouf, Nageh K. Allam, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412499951

                Nitrogen-passivated germanium carbide (GeC) nanomeshes have been systematically investigated as efficient photocatalysts for water splitting. The nanomesh, characterized by a lattice constant of 19.3 &#197; and a pore diameter of 7.3 &#197;, maintains a planar architecture with optimized N-Ge and N-C bond lengths of 1.8 &#197; and 1.3 &#197;, respectively. Partial density of states (PDOS) analysis indicates that the conduction band is predominantly governed by Ge states, while C states dominate the valence band. Nitrogen incorporation critically alters the electronic structure near the band edges, significantly influencing photocatalytic behavior. Notably, introducing porosity reduces the bandgap from 2.04 eV (pristine GeC) to 1.33 eV in the N-passivated configuration. The calculated band edge positions straddle the redox potentials of water, indicating thermodynamic feasibility for overall water splitting. Several favorable sites were identified for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), with nearly thermoneutral &#916;G values, suggesting high catalytic efficiency. For the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the formation of OH* was determined to be the rate-limiting step with a &#916;G1 = 1.84 eV. Bader charge analysis confirmed electron transfer from the OH* species to the adjacent Ge atom, resulting in a net gain of 0.39 |e| by Ge. These findings demonstrate that N-passivated GeC nanomeshes exhibit a favorable electronic structure and catalytic surface characteristics for photocatalytic water splitting.</description>
      <author>Sarah Gamal, Ghada E. Khedr, M. Nashaat, L.M. Salah, Ahmed A. Maarouf, Nageh K. Allam</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-11711-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph&#8208;Based High&#8208;Throughput Framework for Screening Selective Propane Dehydrogenation Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500803</link>
      <description>Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Siddharth Deshpande, David P. Dean, Jessica A. Muhlenkamp, Ryan Alcala, Aubrey L. Jeffries, Russell J. Clarke, Isha S. Chavan, Justin Senyk, Yinan Xu, Anne Esther Serban, Casey P. O apos Brien, Abhaya K. Datye, Jason C. Hicks, Jeffrey T. Miller, Jeffrey Greeley, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412501519

                Abstract High&#8208;throughput computational screening is a powerful approach in accelerating the identification of highly selective and stable catalysts. However, it is often hindered by lack of generalized descriptors and the complexity of handling numerous multidentate adsorption configurations. In this study, we propose a computational framework integrating graph theory and python&#8208;based databasing tools with robust catalytic descriptors to enable high&#8208;throughput screening of alloys for nonoxidative propane dehydrogenation. We derive mechanistic Br&#248;nsted&#8211;Evans&#8208;Polanyi (BEP) correlations for C&#9472;H and C&#9472;C bond breaking, highlighting the role of metastable binding configurations in transition states involving more than three surface atoms. Although activity and stability descriptors exhibit strong scaling, these descriptors are uncorrelated, enabling construction of a pareto&#8208;optimal line identifying alloys with the best balance between activity and selectivity. Known optimal catalysts, including PtZn, PdZn, PtSn, and PdIn, lie on this pareto&#8208;optimal line validating the framework. Furthermore, Ir and Rh, typically known for hydrogenolysis, can be engineered for high selectivity by site&#8208;isolating active ensembles with high promoter compositions. Experimental validation confirms that Ir 1 Sn 1 remains highly stable and selective over 15 h. Overall, our approach highlights the power of generalized descriptors combined with high&#8208;throughput screening and experimental benchmarking to extract key mechanistic insights and computationally design novel catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Siddharth Deshpande, David P. Dean, Jessica A. Muhlenkamp, Ryan Alcala, Aubrey L. Jeffries, Russell J. Clarke, Isha S. Chavan, Justin Senyk, Yinan Xu, Anne Esther Serban, Casey P. O apos Brien, Abhaya K. Datye, Jason C. Hicks, Jeffrey T. Miller, Jeffrey Greeley</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Behavior of Complex Aqueous Electrolytes Using Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials: The Case of Sodium Sulfate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.5c02306</link>
      <description>Ademola Soyemi, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, The Journal of Physical Chemistry B. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412506428

                Understanding the structure and thermodynamics of solvated ions is essential for advancing applications in electrochemistry, water treatment, and energy storage. While ab initio molecular dynamics methods are highly accurate, they are limited by short accessible time and length scales whereas classical force fields struggle with accuracy. Herein, we explore the structure and thermodynamics of complex monovalent-divalent ion pairs using Na2SO4(aq) as a case study by applying a machine learning interatomic potential (MLIP) trained on density functional theory (DFT) data. Our MLIP-based approach reproduces key bulk properties such as density and radial distribution functions of water. We provide the hydration structure of the sodium and sulfate ions in the 0.1-2 M concentration range and the one-dimensional and two-dimensional potentials of mean force for the sodium-sulfate ion pairing at the low concentration limit (0.1 M), which are inaccessible to DFT. At low concentrations, the sulfate ion is strongly solvated, leading to the stabilization of solvent-separated ion pairs over contact ion pairs. Minimum energy pathway analysis revealed that coordinating two sodium ions with a sulfate ion is a multistep process whereby the sodium ions coordinate to the sulfate ion sequentially. We demonstrate that MLIPs allow the study of solvated ions beyond simple monovalent pairs with DFT-level accuracy in their low concentration limit (0.1 M) via statistically converged properties from ns-long simulations.</description>
      <author>Ademola Soyemi, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.5c02306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia Performance on Metal Foam Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202516242</link>
      <description>Yongkang Li, Rundong Zhao, Qiuyu Yan, Ling Lu, Zhenhua Wu, Lihong Yu, Le Liu, Jingyu Xi, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412510389

                Abstract Electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) has emerged as a promising strategy for sustainable ammonia (NH 3 ) synthesis and the remediation of nitrate&#8208;contaminated wastewater. However, the catalytic pathways for NO 3 RR vary across different catalyst surfaces, which in turn affects the kinetics and selectivity of product formations. Therefore, it is necessary to establish a unified performance quantification for NO 3 RR among commonly used catalysts. In this work, transition metal&#8208;based foam electrodes&#8212;iron, cobalt, nickel, and copper, which are widely used as catalysts or substrates due to their excellent conductivity, high specific surface area and catalytic activity are systematically evaluated and compared to enable quantitative comparison of catalytic performance. Through comprehensive characterization of NO 3 RR performance metrics, a standardized evaluation framework is established. Furthermore, advanced in situ optical imaging reveals the dynamic evolution of NH 3 , intermediate nitrite, and hydrogen bubbles during NO 3 RR, uncovering critical mechanistic insights and guiding the subsequent targeted loading and modification of catalysts. In addition, the zinc&#8208;nitrate battery performance based on foam electrodes is also standardized and unified.</description>
      <author>Yongkang Li, Rundong Zhao, Qiuyu Yan, Ling Lu, Zhenhua Wu, Lihong Yu, Le Liu, Jingyu Xi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202516242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating and Enhancing Thermodynamic Simulations of Electrochemical Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c00547</link>
      <description>Xiaochen Du, M. Liu, Jiayu Peng, Hoje Chun, Alexander J. Hoffman, Bilge Yildiz, Lin Li, Martin Z. Bazant, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412512518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaochen Du, M. Liu, Jiayu Peng, Hoje Chun, Alexander J. Hoffman, Bilge Yildiz, Lin Li, Martin Z. Bazant, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c00547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Precise Silver Nanocluster Riveted by Uneven Charged Traps toward Enhancing Electrocatalytic Activity for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01922</link>
      <description>Zhaodi Wang, Wenyan Sun, Wenyan Li, Ya&#8208;Kun Lv, Yingying Wang, Peng Peng, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412524051

                Metal nanoclusters (MNCs) possessed promising potentials for catalytic applications but were hindered by the intrinsic charge-carrier mobility and the exposure of active sites. To this point, our work developed the uneven charged traps strategy to realize the homogeneous dispersion and immobilization of atomically precise silver nanoclusters (Ag6) and obtained an Ag cluster-based oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalyst with enhanced performance. As expected, the uneven charged traps derived by graphitized nitrogen-doped carbon (NDC) extended the effective catalytic active area, tuned the electrical environment, and facilitated the binding between ORR intermediates and the active sites. Compared with pure Ag6 nanoclusters, Ag6@NDC possessed nearly 160 times higher electrochemical surface area (ECSA) and dramatically decreased electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). In alkaline media, the overall catalytic performance of Ag6@NDC with only 3.64 wt % Ag was even superior to commercial 20 wt % Pt/C. This work not only offered a successful showcase to enhance the catalytic performance of atomically precise MNCs but also provided highly efficient alternatives for both electrocatalytic applications and mechanism studies.</description>
      <author>Zhaodi Wang, Wenyan Sun, Wenyan Li, Ya&#8208;Kun Lv, Yingying Wang, Peng Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Phase Stability and Transport Properties of Emerging Thermoelectric Materials: Machine Learning and Experimental Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01456</link>
      <description>Abhigyan Ojha, Ayush Tiwari, Sai Aditya Tagore Vambaravelli, &#922;. K. Sahu, Sivaiah Bathula, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412526042

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abhigyan Ojha, Ayush Tiwari, Sai Aditya Tagore Vambaravelli, &#922;. K. Sahu, Sivaiah Bathula</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the interfacial changes of PtCo3O4 catalysts during the dehydrogenation of ammonia borane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164116</link>
      <description>Silvio Bellomi, Daniel C. Cano-Blanco, Yaning Han, Juan J. Delgado, Xiaowei Chen, Kirill A. Lomachenko, Ilaria Barlocco, Davide Ferri, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Alberto Villa, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412529801

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silvio Bellomi, Daniel C. Cano-Blanco, Yaning Han, Juan J. Delgado, Xiaowei Chen, Kirill A. Lomachenko, Ilaria Barlocco, Davide Ferri, Alberto Rold&#225;n, Alberto Villa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification nonmetal doping induced S vacancy to active MoS2 for hydrogen evolution reaction via structural descriptor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150348</link>
      <description>Xiaopei Xu, Chia-Hung Chu, Zhiwei Hou, Zhipeng Peng, Juntao Wang, Xinyan Li, Xu Han, Haoxiang Xu, Daojian Cheng, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 158(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412531649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaopei Xu, Chia-Hung Chu, Zhiwei Hou, Zhipeng Peng, Juntao Wang, Xinyan Li, Xu Han, Haoxiang Xu, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclic liquid organic hydrogen carriers for efficient hydrogen storage using mesoporous catalytic systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43937-025-00082-8</link>
      <description>Leon Ndhlozi, Aisha Ayibongwe Khumalo, Austine Ofondu Chinomso Iroegbu, Orpah Zinyemba, Reinout Meijboom, Discover Energy. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412531697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leon Ndhlozi, Aisha Ayibongwe Khumalo, Austine Ofondu Chinomso Iroegbu, Orpah Zinyemba, Reinout Meijboom</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43937-025-00082-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical revealing the nitrogen reduction reaction on FeMo dual-atom catalysts and the role of sulfur modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115323</link>
      <description>Yuan&#8208;Hui Xiao, Ziwei Ma, Tai-Rui Wu, Xinwei Wu, Lai-Ke Chen, Jiande Lin, De&#8208;Yin Wu, Molecular Catalysis. 585(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412535954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan&#8208;Hui Xiao, Ziwei Ma, Tai-Rui Wu, Xinwei Wu, Lai-Ke Chen, Jiande Lin, De&#8208;Yin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Ru@Ir Core&#8211;Shell Nanoparticles on Titanium Oxynitride&#8211;Graphene Support for a Highly Active and Durable pH-Universal Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02831</link>
      <description>Aleksandra Popovi&#263;, Ivan Mari&#263;, Marjan Bele, Ervin Rems, Matej Hu&#353;, Luka Pavko, Francisco Ruiz&#8208;Zepeda, Lazar Bijeli&#263;, Branimir Grgur, Nejc Hodnik, Milutin Smiljani&#263;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412536451

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aleksandra Popovi&#263;, Ivan Mari&#263;, Marjan Bele, Ervin Rems, Matej Hu&#353;, Luka Pavko, Francisco Ruiz&#8208;Zepeda, Lazar Bijeli&#263;, Branimir Grgur, Nejc Hodnik, Milutin Smiljani&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-based dual-atom catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-methane conversion: thermodynamic and electronic insights into activity and selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02966j</link>
      <description>Yuxiang Jin, Zhengtong Ji, Xue Yao, Erhong Song, Yong Zhu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412552217

                The rational design of CO 2 electroreduction catalysts requires the establishment of robust structure&#8211;activity relationships through precise electronic descriptors.</description>
      <author>Yuxiang Jin, Zhengtong Ji, Xue Yao, Erhong Song, Yong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02966j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum carbide supported metal&#8211;organic framework-derived Ni, Co phosphosulphide heterostructures as efficient OER and HER catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5na00510h</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ahsan Naseeb, Maida Murtaza, Komal Farooq, Waqas Ali Shah, Amir Waseem, Nanoscale Advances. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412553928

                Designing porous Mo x C (Mo 2 C&#8211;MoC) heterostructures via confined carburization and phosphosulfurization</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ahsan Naseeb, Maida Murtaza, Komal Farooq, Waqas Ali Shah, Amir Waseem</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5na00510h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Charge in Electrical Double Layer as a Kinetic Descriptor of Electrocatalytic Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c01589</link>
      <description>Masao Shibata, Yu Morimoto, Adam Z. Weber, Iryna V. Zenyuk, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412557084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Masao Shibata, Yu Morimoto, Adam Z. Weber, Iryna V. Zenyuk</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c01589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ formed metal borates enable industrial-level seawater splitting via corrosion-resistant CoFe-boride nanocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138519</link>
      <description>Fakhr uz Zaman, Karim Harrath, Felix Ofori Boakye, Fuhai Zhang, Wenbin Zhang, Fekadu Tsegaye Dajan, Sikandar Iqbal, Fereja Shemsu Ligani, Wei Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412564521

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fakhr uz Zaman, Karim Harrath, Felix Ofori Boakye, Fuhai Zhang, Wenbin Zhang, Fekadu Tsegaye Dajan, Sikandar Iqbal, Fereja Shemsu Ligani, Wei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Reconstructing Amorphous High-Entropy Oxides for CO2-Free Methanol Electroreforming and Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125721</link>
      <description>Xi Liu, Xueting Zhao, Zhiwen Lu, Kai Chen, Jiyuan Gao, Huibing Wang, Junxiang Chen, Zhenhai Wen, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412564882

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xi Liu, Xueting Zhao, Zhiwen Lu, Kai Chen, Jiyuan Gao, Huibing Wang, Junxiang Chen, Zhenhai Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare earths evoked gradient orbital coupling in electrocatalysis: Recent advances and future perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2025.101539</link>
      <description>Xuan Wang, Meng Li, Yawen Tang, Hao Li, Gengtao Fu, Progress in Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412569579

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuan Wang, Meng Li, Yawen Tang, Hao Li, Gengtao Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2025.101539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Activity and Durability of Noble Metal Monolayer Catalysts on TiM3 Alloy Substrates: A Density Functional Theory Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107263</link>
      <description>Suihao Zhang, Zhixiao Liu, Guangdong Liu, Huiqiu Deng, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412569686

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suihao Zhang, Zhixiao Liu, Guangdong Liu, Huiqiu Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy&#8208;Efficient and Scalable Joule Heating Synthesis of Self&#8208;Standing Transition Metal Phosphide Electrodes for Full Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202502150</link>
      <description>Liel Abisdris, Muhammad Saad Naeem, Marco Bianchini, Isaac Herr&#227;iz&#8208;Cardona, Jonathan Tzadikov, Adi Azoulay, Rotem Geva, Michael Volokh, Joshua H. Baraban, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Menny Shalom, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412571001

                Abstract Transition metal phosphides (TMPs) show promise as low&#8208;cost (pre)electrocatalysts for water splitting and other energy&#8208;related applications. However, their traditional synthesis methods face challenges in energy consumption, stability, and reproducibility due to the reaction at high temperatures. Here, the Joule heating (JH) method for the scalable synthesis of TMPs (Ni, Cu, and In) as self&#8208;standing electrodes and powders is presented. The JH synthesis demonstrates substantial economic efficiency and significantly reduces energy consumption and environmental impacts while enhancing reproducibility due to fast processing times. Large&#8208;scale nickel phosphide&#8208;based electrodes are synthesized with various transition metal dopants and assembled into an anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer as anode and cathode, maintaining a cell potential of a maximum of 1.8 V at 200 mA cm&#8315; 2 under 55 &#176;C for 7 days. These results highlight the JH synthesis as a promising approach for the scalable production of high&#8208;performance self&#8208;standing electrodes for energy&#8208;related devices.</description>
      <author>Liel Abisdris, Muhammad Saad Naeem, Marco Bianchini, Isaac Herr&#227;iz&#8208;Cardona, Jonathan Tzadikov, Adi Azoulay, Rotem Geva, Michael Volokh, Joshua H. Baraban, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Menny Shalom</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202502150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoinduced dynamics of CO on Ru(0001): Understanding experiments by simulations with all degrees of freedom</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0278850</link>
      <description>Bruno Mladineo, J. I. Juaristi, M. Alducin, Peter Saalfrank, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412578065

                Real-time pump&#8211;probe experiments are powerful tools for monitoring chemical reactions but often need parallel theoretical modeling to disentangle different contributions. Monitoring x-ray spectra of photoinduced dynamics of CO on Ru(0001) provided a strong indication for a transient &#8220;precursor state&#8221; of unidentified nature to various subsequent outcomes. So far, the precise nature of the postulated precursor has also remained elusive in state-of-the-art ab initio molecular dynamics models, including single-moving CO molecules. In the present work, we have constructed a density functional theory-based machine learning interatomic potential energy surface that is valid for all ionic degrees of freedom of the system, comprising many molecules at various coverages and moving surface atoms. Our Langevin dynamics with electronic friction based on the new potential energy surface identified the precursor state as dynamically trapped molecules around 6 &#197; from the surface that arise from adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate interactions. We have compared our results to experimental observations and calculated the dependence of reaction probabilities on pump laser fluence and initial surface coverage.</description>
      <author>Bruno Mladineo, J. I. Juaristi, M. Alducin, Peter Saalfrank, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0278850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study of transition metal clusters TMn (n: 1&#8211;6) for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142299</link>
      <description>Yuan Yuan, Yujia Xie, Dengyang Guo, Yang Lv, Na Li, Yirong Zhu, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412585369

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan Yuan, Yujia Xie, Dengyang Guo, Yang Lv, Na Li, Yirong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High throughput screening of transition metal anchored C9N10 electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.112673</link>
      <description>Yuwen Xue, Keyuan Chen, Defa Hou, Fulin Yang, Yi Lu, Can Liu, Xu Lin, Hui Gao, Xiaohua Yu, Zhifeng Zheng, Hao Sun, Yunwu Zheng, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412599809

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuwen Xue, Keyuan Chen, Defa Hou, Fulin Yang, Yi Lu, Can Liu, Xu Lin, Hui Gao, Xiaohua Yu, Zhifeng Zheng, Hao Sun, Yunwu Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.112673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial Magnetic Fields Arising from Ballistic Ring Currents in Single-Molecule Junctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00735</link>
      <description>William Bro&#8208;J&#248;rgensen, Stephan P. A. Sauer, Gemma C. Solomon, Marc H. Garner, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412604296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>William Bro&#8208;J&#248;rgensen, Stephan P. A. Sauer, Gemma C. Solomon, Marc H. Garner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the local environment of Ni single-atom catalysts with heteroatoms for efficient CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64679-1</link>
      <description>Gang Wang, Imran Muhammad, Huimin Yan, Jun Li, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 74(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412621719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Wang, Imran Muhammad, Huimin Yan, Jun Li, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64679-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the couple-decouple spin state shifting of graphdiyne-supported d8 state Fe dual-atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64691-2</link>
      <description>Xinli Zhu, Haoran Xing, Guangyu He, Hai Xiao, Yinjuan Chen, Jun Li, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 74(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412621728

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinli Zhu, Haoran Xing, Guangyu He, Hai Xiao, Yinjuan Chen, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64691-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Adsorption States of OER Intermediates on Single-Atom Catalysts via a Spectral Machine Learning Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01212</link>
      <description>Fan Wu, Ke Ye, Jun Jiang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412626248

                Identifying the adsorption states of intermediates in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for revealing the potential-determining step and further optimizing catalytic systems. Infrared (IR) spectroscopy serves as an effective tool for probing oxygen-containing intermediates on electrode surfaces. However, extracting spectral characteristics and establishing a quantitative correlation between these features and the adsorption states of intermediates remains a significant challenge. In this letter, we present a machine learning framework tailored for single-atom catalysts to learn from the infrared spectra of OER intermediates and construct a "spectrum-property" relationship. This enables accurate prediction of the adsorption states, namely adsorption free energy and charge of key intermediates (*OH, *O, and *OOH). Notably, the pretrained model demonstrates efficient transferability across commonly reported single-atom OER systems and provides interpretable attention maps of infrared signals based on vibrational mode analysis. By quantitatively linking spectral features to the adsorption states of oxygen-containing intermediates via machine learning, our framework is expected to provide valuable insights for guiding the optimization of single-atom OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Fan Wu, Ke Ye, Jun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Insights into Two-Dimensional M&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(HHTP)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks as ORR/OER Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03531</link>
      <description>Victor Hoyos-Sinchi, Pedro H. Souza, Walter Orellana, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412638127

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Victor Hoyos-Sinchi, Pedro H. Souza, Walter Orellana</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Barriers in Electrochemical Toluene Hydrogenation for Efficient Hydrogen Storage by Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Au Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02493</link>
      <description>Chen&#8208;Hui Chan, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Nomin Tamir, Hyobin Nam, Sae Yane Paek, Jong Sung Lim, Bayasgalan Ulambayar, Keun Hwa Chae, Wenyu Sun, Sneha A. Akhade, Giovanna Bucci, Seung Yong Lee, Jong Min Kim, So&#8208;Hye Cho, Sang Soo Han, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412641719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen&#8208;Hui Chan, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Nomin Tamir, Hyobin Nam, Sae Yane Paek, Jong Sung Lim, Bayasgalan Ulambayar, Keun Hwa Chae, Wenyu Sun, Sneha A. Akhade, Giovanna Bucci, Seung Yong Lee, Jong Min Kim, So&#8208;Hye Cho, Sang Soo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Amorphous/Crystalline CoS/Co3B2 Heterostructure with Coupled Electronic Engineering Toward Efficient and Stable Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182443</link>
      <description>Yuxin Gao, Jing Zhao, Jiayu Xiao, Shuai Wan, Hao Wang, Xiaodong Lv, Lihong Bao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412644376

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Gao, Jing Zhao, Jiayu Xiao, Shuai Wan, Hao Wang, Xiaodong Lv, Lihong Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boronated aromatic ring-fused structure: An efficient electrocatalyst for sustainable ammonia synthesis from nitric oxide pollutant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136336</link>
      <description>Naga Venkateswara Rao Nulakani, Venkata Surya Kumar Choutipalli, Kevin L. Shuford, Mohamad Akbar Ali, Fuel. 404(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412646758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naga Venkateswara Rao Nulakani, Venkata Surya Kumar Choutipalli, Kevin L. Shuford, Mohamad Akbar Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynasor 2: From simulation to experiment through correlation functions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109759</link>
      <description>Esm&#233;e Berger, Erik Fransson, Fredrik Eriksson, Eric Lindgren, G&#1255;ran Wahnstr&#246;m, Thomas H. Rod, Paul Erhart, Computer Physics Communications. 316(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412651018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Esm&#233;e Berger, Erik Fransson, Fredrik Eriksson, Eric Lindgren, G&#1255;ran Wahnstr&#246;m, Thomas H. Rod, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling hydrocarbon chain growth and degree of branching in CO2 electroreduction on fluorine-doped nickel catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01370-1</link>
      <description>Yingqing Ou, Lu Liu, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Futian You, Haibin Ma, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Boon Siang Yeo, Nature Catalysis. 8(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412651021

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingqing Ou, Lu Liu, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Futian You, Haibin Ma, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Boon Siang Yeo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01370-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High entropy alloys as catalysts: A focused review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2025.139114</link>
      <description>Mark J. Mueller, Han K. Chau, Sarah Stofik, Matthew N. Gordon, Rebecca Fushimi, Jochen Lauterbach, Matthew Craps, Dylan D. Rodene, Dilpuneet S. Aidhy, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412651392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mark J. Mueller, Han K. Chau, Sarah Stofik, Matthew N. Gordon, Rebecca Fushimi, Jochen Lauterbach, Matthew Craps, Dylan D. Rodene, Dilpuneet S. Aidhy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2025.139114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory-guided Electron Delocalization Modulation at Cu&#8722;O&#8722;Ce Sites Boosts CO2 Electroreduction to Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125741</link>
      <description>Peng Wei, Shilun Wang, Yu&#8208;Kun Qian, Yongqing Fu, Yao Shen, Jingkai Zhao, Jiexu Ye, Qiaoli Wang, Pengfei Xie, Shihan Zhang, Xiang Gao, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412658024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Wei, Shilun Wang, Yu&#8208;Kun Qian, Yongqing Fu, Yao Shen, Jingkai Zhao, Jiexu Ye, Qiaoli Wang, Pengfei Xie, Shihan Zhang, Xiang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in metal-organic complexes for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions: Material design and mechanistic insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2025.122859</link>
      <description>Yingying Gu, Chuan Zhang, Minfeng Meng, Xianlong Ge, Shaohua Hu, Yankai Song, Inorganica Chimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412658222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingying Gu, Chuan Zhang, Minfeng Meng, Xianlong Ge, Shaohua Hu, Yankai Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2025.122859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topology-Driven Search for Molecular Links in Nanoclusters: Structure Prediction for Au&lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt;(SR)&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01668</link>
      <description>Jing Qian, Jingkuan Lyu, Zhucheng Yang, Jianping Xie, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412660378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Qian, Jingkuan Lyu, Zhucheng Yang, Jianping Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing machine learning for heterogeneous catalysis with experimental and computational data.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41570-025-00740-4</link>
      <description>Carlota Bozal&#8208;Ginesta, Sergio Pablo&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Changhyeok Choi, Albert Taranc&#243;n, Al&#225;n Aspuru-Guzik, PubMed. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412520561

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Carlota Bozal&#8208;Ginesta, Sergio Pablo&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Changhyeok Choi, Albert Taranc&#243;n, Al&#225;n Aspuru-Guzik</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41570-025-00740-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Strategies for Oxygen Evolution Reaction Using Layered Double Hydroxide&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202502680</link>
      <description>Zifeng Li, Honglin Gao, Li Che, Aiyi Dong, ChemistrySelect. 10(28)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412531105

                Abstract Layered double hydroxides (LDH) catalysts are widely used in oxygen evolution reaction (OER), but are limited by their low conductivity, few active sites, and poor stability. For this reason, various modification strategies have emerged. In this review, the mechanistic explanation direction of the OER performance enhancement of modified LDH was elaborated from a mechanistic point of view, which mainly includes the heterostructure&#8208;dominated synergistic effect, doping&#8208;induced lattice distortion and multi&#8208;element electronic interaction. The substantial improvements in OER performance achieved through LDH modification can be considered by focusing on the above three mechanisms. Subsequently, a detailed exploration of the existing shortcomings in the explanation of LDH modification mechanisms for OER was conducted. By addressing these gaps, we aim to offer more effective guidance for the rational design and broad application of LDH&#8208;based catalysts in OER processes in the future.</description>
      <author>Zifeng Li, Honglin Gao, Li Che, Aiyi Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202502680</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin State Differentiated [3Fe&#8211;4S] Cluster Electrocatalyzes Water Oxidation Efficiently</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202500812</link>
      <description>Rong Yan, Qian&#8208;Cheng Luo, Zi&#8208;Han Li, Nana Sun, Wei&#8208;Peng Chen, Yuan&#8208;Qi Zhai, H. Yin, Xiaotai Wang, Xin Tu, Yan&#8208;Zhen Zheng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412602809

                Though there are many synthetic iron&#8211;sulfur clusters that have been reported to show catalytic activity mimicking the natural cofactors in metalloenzymes, the influence of the spin state on the catalytic property is seldom touched. Here, a disulfide&#8208;bridged triiron(II) complex is shown, namely [Fe 3 (Sip) 4 ][CF 3 SO 3 ] 2 ( Fe 3 (Sip) 4 , HSip = sulfanylpropyliminomethyl&#8208;pyridine), can efficiently electrocatalyze water oxidation with a turnover frequency of 932 s &#8722;1 and Faraday efficiency of 86%, better than many iron&#8208;based catalysts. More importantly, the terminal low&#8208;spin ( S = 0) iron(II) sites possessing a N4S2 first coordination environment, along with the synergetic catalysis of ligands, play a crucial role in the catalytic process. This research highlights the unconventional applications of iron&#8211;sulfur clusters in electrocatalytic water oxidation and underlines a promising avenue for developing innovative catalysts.</description>
      <author>Rong Yan, Qian&#8208;Cheng Luo, Zi&#8208;Han Li, Nana Sun, Wei&#8208;Peng Chen, Yuan&#8208;Qi Zhai, H. Yin, Xiaotai Wang, Xin Tu, Yan&#8208;Zhen Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202500812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy RuO2 catalyst with dual-site oxide path for durable acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61763-5</link>
      <description>Fangren Qian, Dengfeng Cao, Shuangming Chen, Yalong Yuan, Kai Chen, Peter Joseph Chimtali, Hengjie Liu, Wei Jiang, Beibei Sheng, Luocai Yi, Jiabao Huang, Chengsi Hu, Huxu Lei, Xiaojun Wu, Zhenhai Wen, Qingjun Chen, Li Song, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412670086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangren Qian, Dengfeng Cao, Shuangming Chen, Yalong Yuan, Kai Chen, Peter Joseph Chimtali, Hengjie Liu, Wei Jiang, Beibei Sheng, Luocai Yi, Jiabao Huang, Chengsi Hu, Huxu Lei, Xiaojun Wu, Zhenhai Wen, Qingjun Chen, Li Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61763-5</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
