<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 01:20:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the phase transition and electrochemical application of MoSe2 material for energy conversion and storage devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160990</link>
      <description>Muthuraja Velpandian, Priyanka Gupta, Anshid Kuttasseri, Arup Mahata, Suddhasatwa Basu, Applied Surface Science. 677(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403410060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muthuraja Velpandian, Priyanka Gupta, Anshid Kuttasseri, Arup Mahata, Suddhasatwa Basu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of graphdiyne-supported single-cluster catalysts for electroreduction of nitric oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161522</link>
      <description>Ya Gao, Erpeng Wang, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403411757

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya Gao, Erpeng Wang, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effect of Cobalt/Ferrocene as a Catalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02039</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; M. Abad, Alba Duprat-Alvaro, Raquel Sainz, M.V. Mart&#305;&#769;nez-Huerta, Marcos Pita, Ant&#243;nio L. De Lacey, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403415342

                There is a great deal of interest in the development of electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) that are stable and have high activity because this anodic half-reaction is the main bottleneck in water splitting and other key technologies. Cobalt and iron oxide and oxyhydroxide electrocatalysts constitute a cheaper alternative to the highly active and commonly used Ir- and Ru-based catalysts. Most of the described electrocatalysts require tedious synthetic and expensive preparation procedures. We report here a facile and straightforward preparation of an electrocatalyst by a combination of commercial compounds, such as cobalt chloride and ferrocene. A highly active and stable OER electrocatalyst is obtained, which shows a low overpotential in the alkaline medium as a consequence of a synergistic effect between both compounds and is inexpensive.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; M. Abad, Alba Duprat-Alvaro, Raquel Sainz, M.V. Mart&#305;&#769;nez-Huerta, Marcos Pita, Ant&#243;nio L. De Lacey</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly asymmetrically configured single atoms anchored on flame-roasting deposited carbon black as cathode catalysts for ultrahigh power density Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100134</link>
      <description>Yu-Chieh Ting, Chih-Chieh Cheng, Fan-Yu Yen, Guan-Ru Li, Shao-I Chang, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403415418

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Chieh Ting, Chih-Chieh Cheng, Fan-Yu Yen, Guan-Ru Li, Shao-I Chang, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Simulations of Thermal Transport across Iron Oxide&#8211;Hydrocarbon Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09434</link>
      <description>F. H. Carman, James P. Ewen, Fernando Bresme, Billy Wu, Daniele Dini, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403416315

                The rational design of dielectric fluids for immersion cooling of batteries requires a molecular-level understanding of the heat flow across the battery casing/dielectric fluid interface. Here, we use nonequilibrium molecular dynamics (NEMD) simulations to quantify the interfacial thermal resistance (ITR) between hematite and poly-&#945;-olefin (PAO), which are representative of the outer surface of the steel battery casing and a synthetic hydrocarbon dielectric fluid, respectively. After identifying the most suitable force fields to model the thermal properties of the individual components, we then compared different solid&#8211;liquid interaction potentials for the calculation of the ITR. These potentials resulted in a wide range of ITR values (4&#8211;21 K m2 GW&#8211;1), with stronger solid&#8211;liquid interactions leading to lower ITR. The increase in ITR is correlated with an increase in density of the fluid layer closest to the surface. Since the ITR has not been experimentally measured for the hematite/PAO interface, we validate the solid&#8211;liquid interaction potential using the work of adhesion calculated using the dry-surface method. The work of adhesion calculations from the simulations were compared to those derived from experimental contact angle measurements for PAO on steel. We find that all of the solid&#8211;liquid potentials overestimate the experimental work of adhesion. The experiments and simulations can only be reconciled by further reducing the strength of the interfacial interactions. This suggests some screening of the solid&#8211;liquid interactions, which may be due to the presence of an interfacial water layer between PAO and steel in the contact angle experiments. Using the solid&#8211;liquid interaction potential that reproduces the experimental work of adhesion, we obtain a higher ITR (33 K m2 GW&#8211;1), suggesting inefficient thermal transport. The results of this study demonstrate the potential for NEMD simulations to improve understanding of the nanoscale thermal transport across industrially important interfaces. This study represents an important step toward the rational design of more effective fluids for immersion cooling systems for electric vehicles and other applications where thermal management is of high importance.</description>
      <author>F. H. Carman, James P. Ewen, Fernando Bresme, Billy Wu, Daniele Dini</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09434</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interaction of Nitric Oxide with Late 3d Transition Metals: Dissociation and Metal Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03048</link>
      <description>O. Quinn Carvalho, Hoan K. K. Nguyen, Sri Krishna Murthy Padavala, L&#237;ney &#193;rnad&#243;ttir, Ethan J. Crumlin, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403424207

                Heterogeneous interfaces influence chemical reactions by stabilizing the adsorption of reactive intermediates, lowering activation barriers of rate- and selectivity-determining steps. Here, we elucidate periodic trends in metal surface oxidation resulting from interaction with nitric oxide and subsequent adsorbate reaction chemistry across the late 3d transition-metal series with surface-sensitive ambient-pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (AP-XPS) and density functional theory calculations. Metals with open d-shell orbitals (e.g., Fe, Co) favor stabilization of nitric oxide dissociation products (nitrogen adatoms, N*), while metals having near (e.g., Ni) or completely (e.g., Cu) closed d shells promote nitric oxide oxidation toward nitrite and lower total nitrogen and N* coverage. Adsorbate core-level (O 1s and N 1s) binding energies capture electron localization around nitrogen, and eventually oxygen, as nitric oxide moves toward dissociation. Metal-nitride covalency increases with decreasing transition metal electronegativity, where nitrogen adatom binding energies decrease as the transition metal d-band is pushed toward the Fermi level. This work illustrates experimental and theoretical relationships between the nature of the d-band in facilitating nitric oxide adsorption and dissociation chemistry, furthering fundamental understanding of the role of metal electronic structure in determining catalytically relevant adsorption properties.</description>
      <author>O. Quinn Carvalho, Hoan K. K. Nguyen, Sri Krishna Murthy Padavala, L&#237;ney &#193;rnad&#243;ttir, Ethan J. Crumlin, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactive scattering of H2 on Cu(111) at 925 K: Effective Hartree potential vs sudden approximation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231559</link>
      <description>B. Smits, Mantu Kumar Sah, Koushik Naskar, Satrajit Adhikari, J&#246;rg Meyer, Mark F. Somers, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403430403

                We present new quantum dynamical results for the reactive scattering of hydrogen molecules from a Cu(111) surface at a surface temperature of 925 K. Reaction, scattering, and diffraction probabilities are compared for results obtained using both an effective Hartree potential (EfHP) and a sudden approximation approach, implemented through the static corrugation model (SCM), to include surface temperature effects. Toward this goal, we show how the SRP48 DFT-functional and an embedded atom potential perform when used to calculate copper lattice constants and thermal expansion coefficients based on lattice dynamics calculations within the quasi-harmonic approximation. The so-calculated phonons are then used in the EfHP approach to replace the normal modes of a fictitious copper cluster used in earlier work. We find that both the EfHP and SCM approaches correctly predict the reaction probability curve broadening effect when the surface temperature is increased. Similarly, results for rovibrationally elastic scattering appear to be improved, predominantly for the SCM model. The behavior of the EfHP results appears to remain much closer to that of a Born&#8211;Oppenheimer static surface approach, which excludes any surface temperature effects. Finally, for the diffraction, we show very clear attenuation effects for the SCM approach, significantly decreasing specular diffraction probabilities at 925 K surface temperature. These results demonstrate that state-of-the-art theoretical models are able to reproduce strictly quantum mechanical scattering effects with a sudden approximation model and open up interesting opportunities for further comparisons to experimental diffraction results.</description>
      <author>B. Smits, Mantu Kumar Sah, Koushik Naskar, Satrajit Adhikari, J&#246;rg Meyer, Mark F. Somers</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Capping Ligands on Metal-Nanoparticle-Driven Hydrogen Evolution and CO2 Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/3418_2024_116</link>
      <description>Gerard Mart&#237;, &#193;lvaro Lozano-Roche, Nuria Romero, Laia Franc&#224;s, Karine Philippot, Roger Bofill, Jordi Garc&#305;&#769;a-Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala, Topics in organometallic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403433128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gerard Mart&#237;, &#193;lvaro Lozano-Roche, Nuria Romero, Laia Franc&#224;s, Karine Philippot, Roger Bofill, Jordi Garc&#305;&#769;a-Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/3418_2024_116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Electrocatalysts with High Performance Based on Thermodynamics and Kinetics: Progress and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413826</link>
      <description>Minshu Du, Feihan Yu, Shumin Gong, Liu Feng, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403433257

                Abstract Efficient and robust electrocatalysts play a central role in clean energy conversion, enabling a number of sustainable processes for future technologies. The traditional explorations of electrocatalyst relying on the trial&#8208;and&#8208;error approaches are definitely tedious and inefficient. Theoretical progresses on reactive thermodynamics and kinetics in recent years have initiated a powerful theory&#8208;guided design strategy of electrocatalysts. Herein, this review first summarizes design principles for reactive activity and stability, presenting the thermodynamics, kinetics, and the synergistic thermokinetic correlation in electrocatalytic reaction. Second, the screening criterion, reasonable design, mechanistic understanding, and performance evaluation of the typical electrocatalysts as divided into the thermodynamics oriented&#8208;, kinetics oriented&#8208;, and thermokinetic correlation oriented&#8208;designs are discussed. The necessity of correlating thermodynamics and kinetics into the rational design and mechanism clarification is highlighted. Finally, the conclusions and perspectives of the development of highly efficient electrocatalysts are proposed.</description>
      <author>Minshu Du, Feihan Yu, Shumin Gong, Liu Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Libtool: Bridging Textual Analysis Gaps for Non&#8208;Programmers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.1072</link>
      <description>Faizhal Arif Santosa, Manika Lamba, Crissandra George, J. Stephen Downie, Proceedings of the Association for Information Science and Technology. 61(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403433714

                ABSTRACT In the era of big and ubiquitous data, professionals and students alike are finding themselves needing to perform a number of textual analysis tasks. Historically, the general lack of statistical expertise and programming skills has stopped many with humanities or social sciences backgrounds from performing and fully benefiting from such analyses. Thus, we introduce Coconut Libtool ( www.coconut-libtool.com/ ), an open&#8208;source, web&#8208;based application that utilizes state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art natural language processing (NLP) technologies. Coconut Libtool analyzes text data from customized files and bibliographic databases such as Web of Science, Scopus, and Lens. Users can verify which functions can be performed with the data they have. Coconut Libtool deploys multiple algorithmic NLP techniques at the backend, including topic modeling ( LDA, Biterm, and BERTopic algorithms), network graph visualization, keyword lemmatization, and sunburst visualization. Coconut Libtool is the people&#8208;first web application designed to be used by professionals, researchers, and students in the information sciences, digital humanities, and computational social sciences domains to promote transparency, reproducibility, accessibility, reciprocity, and responsibility in research practices.</description>
      <author>Faizhal Arif Santosa, Manika Lamba, Crissandra George, J. Stephen Downie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.1072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the ORR performance of PtMnM ternary intermetallics by tuning the surface strain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2312-x</link>
      <description>Min Young Song, Guanyu Luo, Qian Zhang, Hanyu Hu, Deli Wang, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403453751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Young Song, Guanyu Luo, Qian Zhang, Hanyu Hu, Deli Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2312-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chlorine vacancy&#8722;induced activation in two&#8722;dimensional transition metal dichlorides nanosheets for efficient CO electroreduction to C2+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.09.032</link>
      <description>Qiwen Su, L. Chen, Lichang Yin, Jingxiang Zhao, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiwen Su, L. Chen, Lichang Yin, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.09.032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn-doped Bi2O3 grown on PTFE-treated carbon paper for electrochemical CO2-to-formate production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115798</link>
      <description>Junjie Shi, Paulina Pr&#353;lja, Milla Suominen, Benjin Jin, Jouko Lahtinen, Lilian Moumaneix, Xiangze Kong, Tanja Kallio, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457987

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junjie Shi, Paulina Pr&#353;lja, Milla Suominen, Benjin Jin, Jouko Lahtinen, Lilian Moumaneix, Xiangze Kong, Tanja Kallio</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Integrated Approach Combining Experimental, Informatics and Energetic Methods for Solid Form Derisking of PF-06282999</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xphs.2024.10.013</link>
      <description>G. Sadiq, Shubham Sharma, Joanna S. Stevens, Pablo Mart&#237;nez-Bulit, Lily M. Hunnisett, Christopher P. Cameron, Brian Samas, Emma Hawking, Nicholas Francia, Jeff Lengyel, Elna Pidcock, Sadia Isfat Ara Rahman, Matthew L. Nisbet, Kevin Back, C.L. Doherty, Patricia Basford, Timothy G. Cooper, Garry O'Connor, Rajni M. Bhardwaj, Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403458371

                The landscapes of observed and predicted three-dimensional crystal packing arrangements of small-molecule drug candidates can be complex. The possible appearance of a more thermodynamically stable solid form during drug development has led to the digital workflow of informatics-based risk assessments, named a Solid Form Health Check. Herein, we describe the use of a combined approach consisting of experiments, informatics together with energetic calculations in analysis of four competing polymorphs of PF-06282999, a myeloperoxidase (MPO) inhibitor with conformational flexibility and multiple plausible hydrogen bond networks. This combined approach offered a comprehensive understanding of the solid form structure, properties, and performance, ensuring robust solid form derisking and selection.</description>
      <author>G. Sadiq, Shubham Sharma, Joanna S. Stevens, Pablo Mart&#237;nez-Bulit, Lily M. Hunnisett, Christopher P. Cameron, Brian Samas, Emma Hawking, Nicholas Francia, Jeff Lengyel, Elna Pidcock, Sadia Isfat Ara Rahman, Matthew L. Nisbet, Kevin Back, C.L. Doherty, Patricia Basford, Timothy G. Cooper, Garry O'Connor, Rajni M. Bhardwaj</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xphs.2024.10.013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Enhanced Screening of Single-Atom Alloy Clusters for Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12184</link>
      <description>Arunendu Das, Diptendu Roy, A. Das, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403462161

                The electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR) under ambient conditions is a promising method to generate ammonia (NH3), a crucial precursor for fertilizers and chemicals, without carbon emissions. Single-atom alloy catalysts (SAACs) have reinvigorated catalytic processes due to their high activity, selectivity, and efficient use of active atoms. Here, we employed density functional theory (DFT) calculations integrated with machine learning (ML) to investigate dodecahedral nanocluster-based SAACs for analyzing structure&#8211;activity relationships in eNRR. Over 300 nanocluster-based SAACs were screened with all the transition metals as dopants to develop an ML model predicting stability and catalytic performance. Facet sites were identified as optimal doping positions, particularly with late group transition metals showing superior stability and activity. Utilizing DFT+ML, we identified 8 highly suitable SAACs for eNRR. Interestingly, the number of valence d-electrons in dopants proved crucial in screening for eNRR activity. These catalysts exhibited low activity in hydrogen evolution reaction, further enhancing their suitability for eNRR. This successful ML-driven approach accelerates catalyst design and discovery, holding significant practical implications.</description>
      <author>Arunendu Das, Diptendu Roy, A. Das, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2-to-CH4 conversion via grain boundary oxidation effect in CuAg systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156728</link>
      <description>Lei Wang, Xue Yao, Yi Xiao, Cheng Du, Xiyang Wang, Dmitry Akhmetzyanov, Zuolong Chen, Youchao Teng, Tao Guo, Yongzan Zhou, Joel P. Mills, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Brant Billinghurst, Khaled M. Ibrahim, Jamie H. Warner, Chandra Veer Singh, Zhongchao Tan, Samira Siahrostami, Yimin A. Wu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403466206

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Wang, Xue Yao, Yi Xiao, Cheng Du, Xiyang Wang, Dmitry Akhmetzyanov, Zuolong Chen, Youchao Teng, Tao Guo, Yongzan Zhou, Joel P. Mills, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Brant Billinghurst, Khaled M. Ibrahim, Jamie H. Warner, Chandra Veer Singh, Zhongchao Tan, Samira Siahrostami, Yimin A. Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed ruthenium single-atom alloy catalysts enabling efficient iodide oxidation reaction electrolysis in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.155</link>
      <description>Dessalew Berihun Adam, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Meng&#8722;Che Tsai, Wei&#8208;Nien Su, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 91(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403468069

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dessalew Berihun Adam, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Meng&#8722;Che Tsai, Wei&#8208;Nien Su, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleeting-Active-Site-Thrust Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Iron Cations from the Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09585</link>
      <description>Zeyu Wang, Hai Xiao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403471736

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is key to sustainable energy and environmental engineering, thus necessitating rational design of high-performing electrocatalysts that requires understanding the structure-performance relationship with a possible dynamic nature under working conditions. Herein, we uncover a novel type of OER mechanisms thrust by the fleeting active sites (FASs) dynamically formed on Ni-based layered double hydroxides (Ni-LDHs) by Fe cations from the electrolyte under OER potentials. We employ grand-canonical ensemble methods and microkinetic modeling to elucidate the potential-dependent structures of FASs on Ni-LDHs and demonstrate that the fleeting-active-site-thrust (FAST) mechanism delivers superior OER activity via the FAST intramolecular oxygen coupling pathway, which also suppresses the lattice oxygen mechanism, leading to improved operando stability of Ni-LDHs. We further reveal that introducing only trace-level loadings (10-100 ppm) of FASs on Ni-LDHs can significantly boost and govern the catalytic performance for OER. This underscores the crucial importance of considering the novel FAST mechanism in OER and also suggests the electrolyte as a key part of the structure-performance relationship as well as an effective design strategy via engineering the electrolyte.</description>
      <author>Zeyu Wang, Hai Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational insight into the selectivity of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1392" altimg="si14.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;&#947;&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-valerolactone hydrodeoxygenation over Rh(111) and Ru(0001)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122624</link>
      <description>Minttu M. Kauppinen, Ewa N. Szlapa, Jos&#233; Luis Gonz&#225;lez Escobedo, Riikka L. Puurunen, Karoliina Honkala, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403472824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minttu M. Kauppinen, Ewa N. Szlapa, Jos&#233; Luis Gonz&#225;lez Escobedo, Riikka L. Puurunen, Karoliina Honkala</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst Screening and Mechanism Elucidation of Two-Dimensional Transition Metal Coordinated Porphyrin-Analogue Materials for Nitrogen Fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04313</link>
      <description>Wenfeng Hu, Bingyi Song, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403480668

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenfeng Hu, Bingyi Song, Li&#8208;Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress and prospects of unitized regenerative fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1360/tb-2024-0560</link>
      <description>Diankai Qiu, Yang Liu, Zhonghao Zhang, Mengdi Guo, Yang Miao, Linfa Peng, Chinese Science Bulletin (Chinese Version). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403482958

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Diankai Qiu, Yang Liu, Zhonghao Zhang, Mengdi Guo, Yang Miao, Linfa Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1360/tb-2024-0560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ synthesis of FeNi3/(Fe,Ni)9S8/Ni4S3/C nanorods and enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.2024.193.1333</link>
      <description>Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, S. J. Zhong, J. H. Chen, Mengyang Li, Yele Sun, Digest Journal of Nanomaterials and Biostructures. 19(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403515726

                NiFe-based nanomaterials have emerged as highly promising catalysts to replace platinum, ruthenium and iridium for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), in &#8220;green hydrogen&#8221; production process through water splitting. Using iron (2+) sulfate and nickel acetate as the raw materials, with the molar ratio of Ni acetate to iron (2+) sulfate controlled at 8:5, the concentration of metal-ion was 0.6 mol/L, and precursor fibers rich in Ni2+, Fe2+, and SO4 2&#8722; were prepared using electrospinning technology, with polyvinyl alcohol acting as the colloid. Subsequently, composite nanorods rich in the elements of Ni, Fe, S, and C were successfully obtained at a heat treatment temperature of 1000&#176;C in an Ar gas atmosphere. The results demonstrate that the nanorod samples possessed a surface diameter of ~200 nm, and the main phases of the nanorods after heat treatment at 1000&#176;C included FeNi3 alloy, (Fe,Ni)9S8, Ni4S3, and amorphous C. Electrochemical performance tests conducted in a 1.0 mol/L KOH solution exhibited excellent oxygen evolution reaction properties of the catalysts prepared using FeNi3/(Fe,Ni)9S8/Ni4S3/C nanorods as the materials. The overpotential was about 258.6 mV of the catalyst material at 10 mA&#61589;cm&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, S. J. Zhong, J. H. Chen, Mengyang Li, Yele Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.2024.193.1333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review of ordered PtCo3 catalyst with higher oxygen reduction reaction activity in proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.063</link>
      <description>Chuanqi Luo, Kechuang Wan, Jue Wang, Bing Li, Daijun Yang, Pingwen Ming, Cunman Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403524361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuanqi Luo, Kechuang Wan, Jue Wang, Bing Li, Daijun Yang, Pingwen Ming, Cunman Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TM@MoSSe (TM = Ni, Fe) as novel electrocatalysts for reduction of CO2to CO: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114929</link>
      <description>Yu-Pu He, Tian-Hao Guo, Shao-Yi Wu, Shungui Zuo, Jinming Fu, Xiaoyu Li, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403527857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Pu He, Tian-Hao Guo, Shao-Yi Wu, Shungui Zuo, Jinming Fu, Xiaoyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the overpotential of overall water spitting by micro-pump-like electrode engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156788</link>
      <description>Tianbiao Zeng, Jie Lin, Biao Wang, Binbin Guo, Yi&#8208;hong Ding, Chang Q. Sun, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403529736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianbiao Zeng, Jie Lin, Biao Wang, Binbin Guo, Yi&#8208;hong Ding, Chang Q. Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Different Morphologies on the Catalytic Activity of Pt-Pd Nanostructures for Methanol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145241</link>
      <description>Dara Silva Santos, Aline B. Trench, I. M. Costa, Mauro C. Santos, Katlin I.B. Eguiluz, Giancarlo R. Salazar&#8208;Banda, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403531691

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dara Silva Santos, Aline B. Trench, I. M. Costa, Mauro C. Santos, Katlin I.B. Eguiluz, Giancarlo R. Salazar&#8208;Banda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu surface plasmon resonance promoted charge transfer in S-scheme system enhanced visible light photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.087</link>
      <description>Xingyan Yang, Nan Yang, Zhishi Qiu, Guoyang Qiu, Tong Zhou, Weijie Zhan, Yuandong Shen, Ke Wang, Chunting Zhao, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Jianhong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Qingju Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403531720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingyan Yang, Nan Yang, Zhishi Qiu, Guoyang Qiu, Tong Zhou, Weijie Zhan, Yuandong Shen, Ke Wang, Chunting Zhao, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Jianhong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly stable and active catalyst in fuel cells through surface atomic ordering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado4935</link>
      <description>Ma Yanling, Jiaheng Peng, Jiakang Tian, Wenpei Gao, Jialiang Xu, Fan Li, Peter Tieu, Hao Hu, Yi Wu, Yuanlong Zhao, Lei Pan, Wen Shang, Peng Tao, Chengyi Song, Hong Zhu, Xiaoqing Pan, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu, Science Advances. 10(42)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533158

                Shape-controlled alloy nanoparticle catalysts have been shown to exhibit improved performance in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in liquid half-cells. However, translating the success to catalyst layers in fuel cells faces challenges due to the more demanding operation conditions in membrane electrode assembly (MEA). Balancing durability and activity is crucial. Here, we developed a strategy that limits the atomic diffusion within surface layers, fostering the phase transition and shape retention during thermal treatment. This enables selective transformation of platinum-iron nanowire surfaces into intermetallic structures via atomic ordering at a low temperature. The catalysts exhibit enhanced MEA stability with 50% less Fe loss while maintaining high catalytic activity comparable to that in half-cells. Density functional calculations suggest that the ordered intermetallic surface stabilizes morphology against rapid corrosion and improves the ORR activity. The surface engineering through atomic ordering presents potential for practical application in fuel cells with shape-controlled Pt-based alloy catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ma Yanling, Jiaheng Peng, Jiakang Tian, Wenpei Gao, Jialiang Xu, Fan Li, Peter Tieu, Hao Hu, Yi Wu, Yuanlong Zhao, Lei Pan, Wen Shang, Peng Tao, Chengyi Song, Hong Zhu, Xiaoqing Pan, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado4935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Van der Waals semiconductor InSe plastifies by martensitic transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado9593</link>
      <description>Yandong Sun, Yupeng Ma, Jinyu Zhang, Tian&#8208;Ran Wei, Xun Shi, David Rodney, Ben Xu, Science Advances. 10(42)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533295

                Inorganic semiconductor materials are crucial for modern technologies, but their brittleness and limited processability hinder the development of flexible, wearable, and miniaturized electronics. The recent discovery of room-temperature plasticity in some inorganic semiconductors offers a promising solution, but the deformation mechanisms remain controversial. Here, we investigate the deformation of indium selenide, a two-dimensional van der Waals semiconductor with substantial plasticity. By developing a machine-learned deep potential, we perform atomistic simulations that capture the deformation features of hexagonal indium selenide upon out-of-plane compression. Unexpectedly, we find that indium selenide plastifies through a martensitic transformation; that is, the layered hexagonal structure is converted to a tetragonal lattice with specific orientation relationship. This observation is corroborated by high-resolution experimental observations and theory. It suggests a change of paradigm, where the design of new plastically deformable inorganic semiconductors can focus on compositions and structures that facilitate phase transformations, going beyond the conventional dislocation slip.</description>
      <author>Yandong Sun, Yupeng Ma, Jinyu Zhang, Tian&#8208;Ran Wei, Xun Shi, David Rodney, Ben Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado9593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review for MXene-based Hybrid Nanocomposites toward Electro-/Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114483</link>
      <description>Latiful Kabir, Karna Wijaya, Jianjun Li, Junjuda Unruangsri, Won&#8208;Chun Oh, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403538511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Latiful Kabir, Karna Wijaya, Jianjun Li, Junjuda Unruangsri, Won&#8208;Chun Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Underpotential Deposition at Specific Sites of N-Doped Graphene for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205082</link>
      <description>Haofei Wu, Qiwen Zhang, Shufen Chu, Hao Du, Yanyue Wang, Pan Liu, Materials. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403545133

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have the advantages of good active site uniformity, high atom utilization, and high catalytic activity. However, the study of its controllable synthesis still needs to be thoroughly investigated. In this paper, we deposited Cu SAs on nanoporous N-doped graphene by underpotential deposition and further obtained a Pt SAC by a galvanic process. Electrochemical and spectroscopic analyses showed that the pyridine-like N defect sites are the specific sites for the underpotential-deposited SAs. The obtained Pt SAC exhibits a good activity in a hydrogen evolution reaction with a turnover frequency of 25.1 s&#8722;1. This work reveals the specific sites of UPD of SAs on N-doped graphene and their potential applications in HERs, which provides a new idea for the design and synthesis of SACs.</description>
      <author>Haofei Wu, Qiwen Zhang, Shufen Chu, Hao Du, Yanyue Wang, Pan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Potential of Bimetallic PtPd/C Cathode Catalysts to Enhance the Performance of PEM Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14201672</link>
      <description>&#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Vladislav Menshikov, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, Irina Gerasimova, Kirill Paperzh, Ilya Pankov, Nanomaterials. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403546602

                Bimetallic platinum-containing catalysts are deemed promising for electrolyzers and proton-exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). A significant number of laboratory studies and commercial offers are related to PtNi/C and PtCo/C electrocatalysts. The behavior of PtPd/C catalysts has been studied much less, although palladium itself is the metal closest to platinum in its properties. Using a series of characterization methods, this paper presents a comparative study of structural characteristics of the commercial PtPd/C catalysts containing 38% wt. of precious metals and the well-known HiSpec4000 Pt/C catalyst. The electrochemical behavior of the catalysts was studied both in a three-electrode electrochemical cell and in the membrane electrode assemblies (MEAs) of hydrogen&#8211;air PEMFCs. Both PtPd/C samples demonstrated higher values of the electrochemically active surface area, as well as greater specific and mass activity in the oxygen reduction reaction in comparison with conventional Pt/C, while not being inferior to the latter in durability. The MEA based on the best of the PtPd/C catalysts also exhibited higher performance in single tests and long-term durability testing. The results of this study conducted indicate the prospects of using bimetallic PtPd/C materials for cathode catalysts in PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>&#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Vladislav Menshikov, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, Irina Gerasimova, Kirill Paperzh, Ilya Pankov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14201672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass Transportation Facilitated Porous Fe/Co Dual&#8208;Site Catalytic Cathodes for Ultrahigh&#8208;Power&#8208;Density Al&#8211;Air Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404140</link>
      <description>Kai Chen, Yiqi Liang, Duo Pan, Junheng Huang, Jiyuan Gao, Zhiwen Lu, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Junxiang Chen, Hao Zhang, Xiang Hu, Zhenhai Wen, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403547980

                Abstract The development of oxygen&#8208;dependent fuel cells is frequently hindered by the high cost of cathode materials and the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). It is thus crucial to explore low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;activity catalysts with accelerated mass transport. Here, a high&#8208;throughput screening method is developed by integrating an explicit solvation model with machine learning potential&#8208;based molecular dynamics simulations, which enables the efficient evaluation of a vast array of diverse diatomic combinations and ultimately identifying Fe&#8211;Co dual&#8208;atomic sites as the optimal ORR electrocatalysts. The superior electrocatalytic performance of the diatomic Fe/Co sites loaded on 3D&#8208;interconnected ordered macroporous carbon (FeCo&#8208;3DMNC) is experimentally verified, achieving high ORR activity with half&#8208;wave potentials of 0.806 V in acidic and 0.905 V in alkaline environments. Additionally, innovative hybrid acid/alkali aluminum&#8211;air fuel cells (hA/A&#8208;AAFCs) incorporating FeCo&#8208;3DMNC as the cathode catalyst demonstrate a notably high open&#8208;circuit voltage of 2.72 V and a record&#8208;breaking power density of 827 mW cm &#8722;2 , significantly outperforming conventional alkaline aluminum&#8211;air fuel cells. This work marks a significant advancement by combining cutting&#8208;edge computational screening with rigorous experimental validation to develop promising electrocatalysts, potentially paving the way for the advanced energy storage and conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Kai Chen, Yiqi Liang, Duo Pan, Junheng Huang, Jiyuan Gao, Zhiwen Lu, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Junxiang Chen, Hao Zhang, Xiang Hu, Zhenhai Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active learning accelerated exploration of single-atom local environments in multimetallic systems for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01432-1</link>
      <description>Hoje Chun, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jeung Ku Kang, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Byungchan Han, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403560061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hoje Chun, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jeung Ku Kang, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Byungchan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01432-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing the Complexity of Endogenous Technological Learning for Energy System Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.adapen.2024.100192</link>
      <description>Johannes Behrens, Elisabeth Zeyen, Maximilian Hoffmann, Detlef Stolten, Jann Michael Weinand, Advances in Applied Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403561700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Johannes Behrens, Elisabeth Zeyen, Maximilian Hoffmann, Detlef Stolten, Jann Michael Weinand</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.adapen.2024.100192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the role of foreign atoms in &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e419" altimg="si139.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;CO&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; reduction on CuSn single-atom surface alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118718</link>
      <description>Vitaliy A. Kislenko, Sergey A. Kislenko, Victoria A. Nikitina, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403563779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vitaliy A. Kislenko, Sergey A. Kislenko, Victoria A. Nikitina</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial anchoring cobalt species mediated advanced oxidation: Degradation performance and mechanism of organic pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.097</link>
      <description>Z. Chen, Guanghao Meng, Zenghui Han, Hongjiang Li, Shao&#8208;Ming Chi, Guangzhi Hu, Xue Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403563889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Z. Chen, Guanghao Meng, Zenghui Han, Hongjiang Li, Shao&#8208;Ming Chi, Guangzhi Hu, Xue Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1-Dimensional metal Nitride-Supported platinum nanoclusters for Low-Temperature hydrogen production from formic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156940</link>
      <description>Liang Qiu, Bowen Sheng, Haotian Ye, Ping Wang, Jinglin Li, Ying Li, Yixin Li, Tianqi Yu, Muhammad Salman Nasir, Xinqiang Wang, Pan Hu, Zhen Huang, Baowen Zhou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403574280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Qiu, Bowen Sheng, Haotian Ye, Ping Wang, Jinglin Li, Ying Li, Yixin Li, Tianqi Yu, Muhammad Salman Nasir, Xinqiang Wang, Pan Hu, Zhen Huang, Baowen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonized-nitridated Mo2N-MoC heterostructures towards universal-medium hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156908</link>
      <description>Xiang Chen, Song Xie, Fang Zhou, Biao Gao, Xuming Zhang, Shuangjie Wu, Li Huang, Yun Li, Paul K. Chu, Xiang Peng, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403574389

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Chen, Song Xie, Fang Zhou, Biao Gao, Xuming Zhang, Shuangjie Wu, Li Huang, Yun Li, Paul K. Chu, Xiang Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure simulations in the cloud computing environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0226437</link>
      <description>Eric J. Bylaska, Ajay Panyala, Nicholas P. Bauman, Bo Peng, Himadri Pathak, Daniel Mej&#305;&#769;a-Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Niranjan Govind, David B. Williams&#8208;Young, Edoardo Apr&#224;, Abhishek Bagusetty, Erdal Mutlu, Koblar Alan Jackson, Tunna Baruah, Yoh Yamamoto, Mark R. Pederson, Kushantha P. K. Withanage, Jes&#250;s N. Pedroza-Montero, Jenna Pope, Sutanay Choudhury, Jesun Firoz, Kristina M. Herman, Sotiris S. Xantheas, Paul Rigor, Fernando D. Vila, J. J. Rehr, Mimi Fung, Adam Grofe, Conrad Johnston, Nathan Baker, K. Kaneko, Hongbin Liu, Karol Kowalski, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403585557

                The transformative impact of modern computational paradigms and technologies, such as high-performance computing (HPC), quantum computing, and cloud computing, has opened up profound new opportunities for scientific simulations. Scalable computational chemistry is one beneficiary of this technological progress. The main focus of this paper is on the performance of various quantum chemical formulations, ranging from low-order methods to high-accuracy approaches, implemented in different computational chemistry packages and libraries, such as NWChem, NWChemEx, Scalable Predictive Methods for Excitations and Correlated Phenomena, ExaChem, and Fermi&#8211;L&#246;wdin orbital self-interaction correction on Azure Quantum Elements, Microsoft's cloud services platform for scientific discovery. We pay particular attention to the intricate workflows for performing complex chemistry simulations, associated data curation, and mechanisms for accuracy assessment, which is demonstrated with the Arrows automated workflow for high throughput simulations. Finally, we provide a perspective on the role of cloud computing in supporting the mission of leadership computational facilities.</description>
      <author>Eric J. Bylaska, Ajay Panyala, Nicholas P. Bauman, Bo Peng, Himadri Pathak, Daniel Mej&#305;&#769;a-Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Niranjan Govind, David B. Williams&#8208;Young, Edoardo Apr&#224;, Abhishek Bagusetty, Erdal Mutlu, Koblar Alan Jackson, Tunna Baruah, Yoh Yamamoto, Mark R. Pederson, Kushantha P. K. Withanage, Jes&#250;s N. Pedroza-Montero, Jenna Pope, Sutanay Choudhury, Jesun Firoz, Kristina M. Herman, Sotiris S. Xantheas, Paul Rigor, Fernando D. Vila, J. J. Rehr, Mimi Fung, Adam Grofe, Conrad Johnston, Nathan Baker, K. Kaneko, Hongbin Liu, Karol Kowalski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0226437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ examination of oxygen vacancy dynamics in epitaxial LaCoO3 thin films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412922033</link>
      <description>Seung Jo Yoo, Jihyun Lee, Sang&#8208;Gil Lee, Hyung Joong Yun, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496353

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seung Jo Yoo, Jihyun Lee, Sang&#8208;Gil Lee, Hyung Joong Yun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412922033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Design of Catalysts with Experimental Validation: Recent Successes, Effective Strategies, and Pitfalls</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04949</link>
      <description>Hajar Hosseini, Connor J. Herring, Chukwudi F. Nwaokorie, Gloria A Sulley, M. M. Montemore, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403489277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hajar Hosseini, Connor J. Herring, Chukwudi F. Nwaokorie, Gloria A Sulley, M. M. Montemore</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04949</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption of CO2 on mechanochemically synthesized silicon oxycarbide composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112486</link>
      <description>S Grishin Il'Ya, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403533456

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S Grishin Il'Ya</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Crystalline Material Properties with AI: Bridging Molecular to Particle Scales</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03224</link>
      <description>Weiye Chen, Muyang Li, Tuo Yao, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Shengzhe Jia, Zhenguo Gao, Junbo Gong, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403423791

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiye Chen, Muyang Li, Tuo Yao, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Shengzhe Jia, Zhenguo Gao, Junbo Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porosity Prediction using Bagging Ensemble Machine Learning in CCUS Reservoirs. A Case Study: Darling Basin, Australia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4964600/v1</link>
      <description>Kushan Sandunil, Ziad Bennour, Saaveethya Sivakumar, Hisham Ben Mahmud, Ausama Giwelli, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496931

                Abstract Machine learning (ML), a subset of artificial intelligence, has been utilised in many engineering fields, such as computer engineering, electrical engineering, civil engineering petroleum engineering. Bagging ensemble algorithms have been employed for parameter prediction, as they theoretically outperform traditional ML algorithms. Carbon dioxide capture and storage (CCS) is a strategy implemented to mitigate carbon dioxide emissions. A vital aspect of CCS assessment is determining carbon storage capacity, which estimates the amount of CO2 that can be stored in the subsurface. Porosity is a critical parameter in calculating this capacity. In this study, the applicability of regression friendly bagging ensemble ML models; random forest regression (RFR) and extra tree regression (ETR) to estimate porosity of a sandstone layer as part of a CCS program was investigated. RFR models were developed considering caliper log (CAL), gamma ray log (GR), neutron log (NPHI), photoelectric factor log (PE) and deep laterolog (LLD) input features and calculated porosity as targets. Moreover, four traditional (classical) ML models, multilayer perceptron (MLP), support vector regression (SVR), k-nearest neighbor (KNN) and decision tree regression (DTR), were developed to compare them with the bagging ensemble models. The results showed that the RFR model achieved a testing model R2 value of 0.9668, while ETR model achieved a resting model R2 value of 0.9569. The higher R2 value of the RFR model makes it a better choice for predicting porosity in CCS assessment projects. However, if computational time is a critical factor, ETR could be preferable, as it required only1/3 of the computational time that of the RFR model. Furthermore, when the performance of these models was compared with the four traditional ML models the two bagging ensembles distinctly outperformed the traditional models.</description>
      <author>Kushan Sandunil, Ziad Bennour, Saaveethya Sivakumar, Hisham Ben Mahmud, Ausama Giwelli</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4964600/v1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
