<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 01:39:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Probing the NO electroreduction mechanism in single phosphorus atom decorated defective MXene: A first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142178</link>
      <description>Bin Huang, Guosheng Ren, Rong Chen, Neng Li, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410642625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Huang, Guosheng Ren, Rong Chen, Neng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling CoNi&#8208;LDH and Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N Nanoparticles on N&#8208;Doped Biomass&#8208;Derived Carbon as Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502145</link>
      <description>Guosheng Han, Ting Zhou, Yumeng Wu, Pengxiang Zhang, Yanyan Liu, Xianli Wu, Baojun Li, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410698547

                Abstract The engineering of structure and composition is crucial and challenging for modulating electrocatalytic activity. Herein, a bifunctional electrocatalyst, CoNi@Fe 2 N/C, is designed and prepared by coupling CoNi&#8208;layered double hydroxides (CoNi&#8208;LDH) nanosheets and Fe 2 N nanoparticles on 3D N&#8208;doped biomass&#8208;derived carbon through pyrolysis and electric field induction. CoNi@Fe 2 N/C delivers remarkable bifunctional electrocatalytic activity with a narrow overpotential gap (&#916; E ) of only 0.63 V for ORR and OER, surpassing commercial Pt/C+RuO 2 . Additionally, the aqueous rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries (RZABs) assembled with CoNi@Fe 2 N/C as a catalyst on the air electrode show a high peak power density (177.4 mW cm &#8722;2 ) and excellent durability (over 360 h). The high stability of 3D biomass&#8208;derived carbon assures the high durability of catalysts. Assistance of electric field induction ensures the uniform dispersion of CoNi&#8208;LDH nanosheets on 3D N&#8208;doped biomass&#8208;derived carbon. The interaction at the interface between two components appropriately modulates the electronic structure of hybrids via charge transfer to promote reaction kinetics. This work will provide a practical avenue to create ORR/ OER bifunctional biomass&#8208;derived catalytically active carbon hybrid catalysts for efficient RZABs.</description>
      <author>Guosheng Han, Ting Zhou, Yumeng Wu, Pengxiang Zhang, Yanyan Liu, Xianli Wu, Baojun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile co-precipitation synthesis of robust NiFe phosphate electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution in AEMWE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2025.207056</link>
      <description>Yu Yu, Jun Liu, Changhao Liang, Applied Catalysis O Open. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410701398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Yu, Jun Liu, Changhao Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2025.207056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverse design of catalytic active sites via interpretable topology-based deep generative models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01649-8</link>
      <description>Bingxu Wang, Shisheng Zheng, Jie Wu, Jingyan Li, Feng Pan, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410702307

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingxu Wang, Shisheng Zheng, Jie Wu, Jingyan Li, Feng Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01649-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt-CeO2/SDB ternary structure Achieved by Modulating Electronic interaction for high-efficiency Toluene Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117267</link>
      <description>Liu Zun, Guotan Liu, Xi Liu, Weihong Gao, Yudong Fu, Bin Sun, Yawei Shao, Guojun Dong, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410708258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liu Zun, Guotan Liu, Xi Liu, Weihong Gao, Yudong Fu, Bin Sun, Yawei Shao, Guojun Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zn-Co nanoferrite electrocatalysts for enhanced hydrogen and oxygen generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rechem.2025.102392</link>
      <description>Kiran Shahzadi, Muhammad Sarfraz, Muneerah Alomar, M.A. Mujtaba, Muhammad Nasir Bashir, Muhammad Mahmood Ali, Faisal Ali, Results in Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410708273

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kiran Shahzadi, Muhammad Sarfraz, Muneerah Alomar, M.A. Mujtaba, Muhammad Nasir Bashir, Muhammad Mahmood Ali, Faisal Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rechem.2025.102392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum Microalloying L1&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co Intermetallic Compounds via Bimodal Ordering Process by Mo Surface Termination and PDA&#8208;Coated Particle Confinement for Stable PEMFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503999</link>
      <description>Qiheng Wang, Jingkun Chen, Jingbo Fu, Ju Wang, Zhipeng Xing, Jingjun Liu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410709605

                Abstract Ordered platinum (Pt) intermetallic compounds with high performance expression under proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) operating conditions are a prerequisite for practical application. However, the heat treatment required for forming an ordered structure can lead to severe agglomeration and uneven distribution of nanoparticles, posing a significant challenge to efficient synthesis. Here, a molybdenum (Mo) assisted structural evolution strategy to controllably synthesize sub&#8208;4 nm Pt 3 Co intermetallic compounds is proposed. The results of experiments combined with density functional theory calculations demonstrate that the participation of trace Mo (0.2 wt.%) not only triggers the &#8220;growth site locking effect&#8221; and effectively suppresses the growth of nanoparticles, but also effectively adjusts the electronic structure, thereby optimizing the adsorption/desorption of oxygen intermediates. The preeminent intrinsic activity on an optimized catalyst reaches a mass activity as high as 1.22 A mg Pt &#8722;1 and has extraordinary stability with only a 5.7% decrease after 30 k cycles. This study paves a new path for the practical application of low Pt catalysts in PEMFCs in the future.</description>
      <author>Qiheng Wang, Jingkun Chen, Jingbo Fu, Ju Wang, Zhipeng Xing, Jingjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon&#8208;Based Flexible Electrode for Efficient Electrochemical Generation of Reactive Chlorine Species in Tumor Therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.202500369</link>
      <description>Cuinan Jiang, Zhaoyu Chen, Ruihao Yang, Ziga Luogu, Qian Ren, Hao Hu, Kaixin Wang, Senlin Li, Changlin Deng, Meng Li, Lu Zheng, Advanced Healthcare Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410709639

                Abstract Reactive chlorine species (RCS) are alternatives to reactive oxygen species (ROS) in tumor therapeutics. Unlike ROS, whose generation is limited by hypoxic conditions or insufficient H 2 O 2 levels in the tumor, RCS can be generated through the electrochemical oxidation of abundant Cl &#8722; present in body fluids. However, traditional electrochemical therapy modalities have shown suboptimal outcomes. Herein, a flexible anodic electrode is fabricated by growing a carbon nanowire network (C&#8208;NWN) onto carbon cloth (CC). Attributing to its excellent hydrophilicity, high specific surface area, and electrochemical surface area, CC@C&#8208;NWN demonstrates a superior capability for RCS generation. Additionally, the carbon vacancies in CC@C&#8208;NWN not only enhance Cl &#8722; adsorption but also reduce the reaction free energy of the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) more significantly compared to that of the oxygen evolution reaction, thereby promoting the CER process. RCS generated from the CC@C&#8208;NWN electrochemical system induces severe oxidative stress, disrupting the redox homeostasis in tumor cells and promoting the synergistic anti&#8208;tumor effect of apoptosis and ferroptosis. The pliability of CC@C&#8208;NWN enables it to conform closely to the tumor, and it has demonstrated remarkable tumor&#8208;suppressive efficacy under low&#8208;voltage (3 V) condition in in vivo experiments. Therefore, the work holds significant promise for the development of novel tumor treatment strategies.</description>
      <author>Cuinan Jiang, Zhaoyu Chen, Ruihao Yang, Ziga Luogu, Qian Ren, Hao Hu, Kaixin Wang, Senlin Li, Changlin Deng, Meng Li, Lu Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.202500369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of C1 and C2 Products Formation on (110) Facets of Carbides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106793</link>
      <description>Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410712051

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding magnesium dissolution through Machine learning molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163578</link>
      <description>Zhoulin Liu, Jianchun Sha, Guang&#8208;Ling Song, Ziliang Wang, Yinghe Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410714218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhoulin Liu, Jianchun Sha, Guang&#8208;Ling Song, Ziliang Wang, Yinghe Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Janus VSeTe monolayers for efficient HER by transition metal doping: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.292</link>
      <description>Lujing Zhao, W. L. Tan, Changmin Shi, D. Wang, Guangliang Cui, Hongmei Liu, Feifei Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 139(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410718270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lujing Zhao, W. L. Tan, Changmin Shi, D. Wang, Guangliang Cui, Hongmei Liu, Feifei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liquid&#8211;Liquid Interface-Based Thiocyanate Surface Treatment for Bright and Stable CsPbBr&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocrystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00803</link>
      <description>Rachel Lifer, Nathan Rafisiman, Saar Shaek, Arghyadeep Basu, Yaron Kauffmann, Nicholas G. Pavlopoulos, Ivano E. Castelli, Lev Chuntonov, Yehonadav Bekenstein, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410718339

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rachel Lifer, Nathan Rafisiman, Saar Shaek, Arghyadeep Basu, Yaron Kauffmann, Nicholas G. Pavlopoulos, Ivano E. Castelli, Lev Chuntonov, Yehonadav Bekenstein</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Loaded Catalyst Layers For Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell Dynamic Operation Part 2: Modeling Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146542</link>
      <description>Florent Vandenberghe, Fabrice Micoud, Pascal Schott, Marian Chatenet, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410733805

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Florent Vandenberghe, Fabrice Micoud, Pascal Schott, Marian Chatenet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain effects on catalytic activity and stability of PdM nanoalloys with grain boundaries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra02127h</link>
      <description>Junpeng Wang, Tao Jin, Longfei Guo, Zhen Li, Chongyang Wang, Shuang Shan, Quan Tang, Bowei Pan, Fuyi Chen, RSC Advances. 15(22)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410696812

                The PdIr nanoalloys with core&#8211;shell structure and Janus-structured PdAg nanoalloys exhibited the best FDR and FOR catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Junpeng Wang, Tao Jin, Longfei Guo, Zhen Li, Chongyang Wang, Shuang Shan, Quan Tang, Bowei Pan, Fuyi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra02127h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain in Core&#8211;Shell Spinel Nanocrystals Enhances ORR Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00896</link>
      <description>Jonathan L. Rowell, Aditya Joshi, H. S. Tan, Dasol Yoon, Jason Manassa, Alex Stangel, Colin R. Bundschu, Yafu Jia, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Robert Hovden, David A. Muller, Richard D. Robinson, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410714222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jonathan L. Rowell, Aditya Joshi, H. S. Tan, Dasol Yoon, Jason Manassa, Alex Stangel, Colin R. Bundschu, Yafu Jia, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Robert Hovden, David A. Muller, Richard D. Robinson</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00896</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group-VIII-metal-based electrocatalysts for acidic hydrogen evolution reaction: Recent progress and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.05.013</link>
      <description>Qingshui Xie, Linfeng Xiao, Xue Zhao, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Materials Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410737174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingshui Xie, Linfeng Xiao, Xue Zhao, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.05.013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parametrization of Zirconium for DFTB3/3OB: A Pathway to Study Complex Zr&#8208;Compounds for Biomedical and Material Science Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70140</link>
      <description>Andreas Penz, Jakob Gamper, Josef M. Gallmetzer, Felix R. S. Purtscher, Thomas S. Hofer, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410739168

                ABSTRACT This work presents the extension of the semi&#8208;empirical density functional tight binding method, DFTB3, to include zirconium for biomedical and material science applications. The parametrization of Zr has been carried out in consistency with already established 3OB parameters including the elements C, H, N, O, S, P, Mg, Zn, Na, K, Ca, F, Cl, Br, and I. Zirconium&#8208;ligand association and reaction energies have been compared with results from quantum chemical calculations obtained at MP2 and DFT (PBE and B3LYP) level of theory, as well as with those from the semi&#8208;empirical methods DFTB2/PTBP and GFN2&#8208;xTB. A structural validation has been carried out on 1,897 compounds reported in the Cambridge Structural Database, revealing an average root mean square deviation comparable to that obtained at semi&#8208;empirical (DFTB2/PTBP and GFN2&#8208;xTB) level of theory and via the novel neural network potential MACE&#8208;MP&#8208;0. To provide a critical validation of the newly derived parameters, the structure of the biomedically relevant Zr&#8208;DFO complex has been evaluated with respect to a DFT (B3LYP) reference calculation. In addition, extensive DFTB3 MD simulations of the two prominent metal&#8208;organic frameworks UiO&#8208;66 and UiO&#8208;67 have been performed. The results demonstrate the applicability of the newly developed parameters for the study of zirconium&#8208;containing metal&#8208;organic frameworks, when compared to experimental measurements, as well as computational approaches.</description>
      <author>Andreas Penz, Jakob Gamper, Josef M. Gallmetzer, Felix R. S. Purtscher, Thomas S. Hofer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Stability and Catalytic Performance of Iron&#8211;Manganese Dual-Atoms Supported on Graphene Edges for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02424</link>
      <description>Sasfan Arman Wella, Ahmad N. Hakim, Muhammad Luqman Hakim, Nadya Amalia, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410743503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sasfan Arman Wella, Ahmad N. Hakim, Muhammad Luqman Hakim, Nadya Amalia, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anharmonic effects control interaction of carbyne confined in carbon nanotubes shaping their vibrational properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59863-3</link>
      <description>Emil Parth, Andrea Corradini, Weili Cui, Davide Romanin, C. Schuster, Clara Freytag, Lei Shi, Kazuhiro Yanagi, Matteo Calandra, Thomas Pichler, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410754738

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Emil Parth, Andrea Corradini, Weili Cui, Davide Romanin, C. Schuster, Clara Freytag, Lei Shi, Kazuhiro Yanagi, Matteo Calandra, Thomas Pichler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59863-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling surplus acetone into long-chain chemicals using a tandem electro-biosystem</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01568-y</link>
      <description>Chunxiao Liu, Jiankang Zhao, Hongting Tang, Jing Xue, Weiqing Xue, Xu Li, Hongliang Li, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Tao Yu, Jie Zeng, Chuan Xia, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410755367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunxiao Liu, Jiankang Zhao, Hongting Tang, Jing Xue, Weiqing Xue, Xu Li, Hongliang Li, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Tao Yu, Jie Zeng, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01568-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ordered single active sites for cascade hydrogenation and hydroformylation reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01346-1</link>
      <description>Xiaojun Lu, Jiazhen Wu, Xinyi He, Zichuang Li, Yangfan Lu, Wenqian Li, Jiang Li, Miao Xu, Yanpeng Qi, Qing Zhang, Yijia Liu, Meng Du, Toshio Kamiya, Hideo Hosono, Fusheng Pan, Jie&#8208;Sheng Chen, Tian&#8208;Nan Ye, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410755960

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojun Lu, Jiazhen Wu, Xinyi He, Zichuang Li, Yangfan Lu, Wenqian Li, Jiang Li, Miao Xu, Yanpeng Qi, Qing Zhang, Yijia Liu, Meng Du, Toshio Kamiya, Hideo Hosono, Fusheng Pan, Jie&#8208;Sheng Chen, Tian&#8208;Nan Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01346-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials-discovery workflow guided by symbolic regression for identifying acid-stable oxides for electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01596-4</link>
      <description>Akhil S. Nair, Lucas Foppa, Matthias Scheffler, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410759542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akhil S. Nair, Lucas Foppa, Matthias Scheffler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01596-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C single atom/cluster catalyst on ORR of PEMFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.294</link>
      <description>Ruina Li, Xu&#8208;Wen Li, Qingcheng Liu, Hua Yue, Yang Meng, Yuanyuan Tian, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 139(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410760958

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruina Li, Xu&#8208;Wen Li, Qingcheng Liu, Hua Yue, Yang Meng, Yuanyuan Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclic Voltammetry&#8211;Synchronized Operando HERFD-XANES and RIXS Analyses of Adsorbed Structures and Bonding States of Active Oxygen Species on Pt Nanoparticle Electrocatalysts in PEFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01160</link>
      <description>Hiroko Ariga-Miwa, Takehiko Sasaki, Tomohiro Sakata, Kotaro Higashi, Takefumi Yoshida, Oki Sekizawa, Takuma Kaneko, Tomoya Uruga, Yasuhiro Iwasawa, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410762638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hiroko Ariga-Miwa, Takehiko Sasaki, Tomohiro Sakata, Kotaro Higashi, Takefumi Yoshida, Oki Sekizawa, Takuma Kaneko, Tomoya Uruga, Yasuhiro Iwasawa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning accelerated interfacial fluxionality in Ni-supported metal nitride ammonia synthesis catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116224</link>
      <description>Pranav Roy, Brandon C. Bukowski, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410769363

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pranav Roy, Brandon C. Bukowski</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mercapto-functionalized scaffold improves perovskite buried interfaces for tandem photovoltaics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59891-z</link>
      <description>Jianan Wang, Shuaifeng Hu, He Zhu, Sanwan Liu, Zhongyong Zhang, Rui Chen, Junke Wang, Chenyang Shi, Jiaqi Zhang, Wentao Liu, X. Lei, Bin Liu, Yongyan Pan, Fumeng Ren, Hasan Raza, Qisen Zhou, Sibo Li, Longbin Qiu, Guanhaojie Zheng, Xiaojun Qin, Zhiguo Zhao, Shuang Yang, Neng Li, Jingbai Li, Atsushi Wakamiya, Zonghao Liu, Henry J. Snaith, Wei Chen, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410770556

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianan Wang, Shuaifeng Hu, He Zhu, Sanwan Liu, Zhongyong Zhang, Rui Chen, Junke Wang, Chenyang Shi, Jiaqi Zhang, Wentao Liu, X. Lei, Bin Liu, Yongyan Pan, Fumeng Ren, Hasan Raza, Qisen Zhou, Sibo Li, Longbin Qiu, Guanhaojie Zheng, Xiaojun Qin, Zhiguo Zhao, Shuang Yang, Neng Li, Jingbai Li, Atsushi Wakamiya, Zonghao Liu, Henry J. Snaith, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59891-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sprynger: Scriptable bibliometrics using a Python interface to Springer Nature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.softx.2025.102186</link>
      <description>Nathan Herrmann, Michael E. Rose, SoftwareX. 31(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410775033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nathan Herrmann, Michael E. Rose</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.softx.2025.102186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT Study of Oxygen Adsorption by Single-Atom Catalysts on N-Doped Graphene: Implications for Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01990</link>
      <description>Luis Angel Alvarado-Leal, E. Per&#233;z&#8208;Tijerina, H. N. Fern&#225;ndez-Escamilla, J. M. Romo-Herrera, Noboru Takeuchi, Alejandro Toro&#8208;Labb&#233;, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410776741

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luis Angel Alvarado-Leal, E. Per&#233;z&#8208;Tijerina, H. N. Fern&#225;ndez-Escamilla, J. M. Romo-Herrera, Noboru Takeuchi, Alejandro Toro&#8208;Labb&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First&#8208;Principles Screening of 3d&#8208;Transition&#8208;Metal&#8208;Doped Hydrous Cobalt Phosphate Catalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500010</link>
      <description>Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Annop Ektarawong, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Rathawat Daengngern, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410780344

                Abstract Hydrous cobalt phosphate (CoPO) is a promising OER catalyst, but its activity is limited by poor electron transport and weak intermediate binding. This study reveals how 3d transition metal dopants can be used to tune these properties through first&#8208;principles calculations. Sc, Ti, V, and Cr improve catalytic activity by promoting electron transfer and stabilizing *O intermediates, while Mn, Fe, Cu, and Zn reduce performance. Among all candidates, Ni doping strikes the optimal balance, enhancing conductivity and providing moderate *O binding energy that minimizes overpotential. These trends follow electronic descriptors such as d&#8208;band center and electronegativity, and are validated by volcano plot analysis. Ni&#8208;CoPO emerges as the most effective design, offering a clear strategy for improving OER catalysts by controlling dopant identity and electronic structure.</description>
      <author>Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Annop Ektarawong, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Rathawat Daengngern, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient hydrogen evolution at Ni/CeO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; interfaces in anion-exchange membrane water electrolysers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee06113f</link>
      <description>Ibrahem O. Baibars, Haisen Huang, Yang Xiao, Shuhao Wang, Yan Nie, Chen Jia, Kamran Dastafkan, Chuan Zhao, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410781530

                Simultaneous reduction of concentration and activation overpotentials at hierarchically porous Ni/CeO x interfaces in anion-exchange membrane water electrolysers.</description>
      <author>Ibrahem O. Baibars, Haisen Huang, Yang Xiao, Shuhao Wang, Yan Nie, Chen Jia, Kamran Dastafkan, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee06113f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Controlled TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocrystals with Catalytically Active Single-Site Co Incorporation for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c05795</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, Soonho Kwon, Perrin Godbold, Grayson Johnson, Sooyeon Hwang, Cheng&#8208;Jun Sun, Hua Zhou, William A. Goddard, Sen Zhang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410788630

                The design of advanced electrocatalysts is often hindered by uncertainties in identifying and controlling the active surfaces and catalytic centers within heterogeneous materials. Here we present the synthesis of single-site Co catalysts, substitutionally doped into surface-controlled TiO2 anatase nanocrystals, aimed at enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Grand canonical quantum mechanics calculations reveal that the kinetics of the OER, following an adsorbate evolution mechanism, is markedly influenced by the coordination environment of Co. The simulations suggest significantly higher turnover frequencies when Co is doped into the (001) surface of TiO2 compared to the (101) surface. Consistent with the computational findings, experimental results show that Co-doped TiO2 (Co-TiO2) nanoplates with selectively exposed {001} surfaces exhibit enhanced current densities and turnover frequencies compared to Co-TiO2 nanobipyramids with {101} surfaces. This study highlights the synergy between theoretical calculations and precision synthesis in the development of more effective catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, Soonho Kwon, Perrin Godbold, Grayson Johnson, Sooyeon Hwang, Cheng&#8208;Jun Sun, Hua Zhou, William A. Goddard, Sen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c05795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synchronization of Emerging Materials and their Synthetic Strategies for Efficient Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500014</link>
      <description>Dun Chan, Chandan Kumar, Ashakiran Maibam, Sunghoon Yoo, Jaejun Park, Sumin Kim, Hayoung Kim, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Seunghyun Lee, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410789907

                Hydrogen is considered the &#8220;future fuel&#8221; due to its zero&#8208;carbon emissions, high gravimetric energy density, and sustainability. However, the generation of hydrogen through the splitting of water requires highly efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts to overcome the sluggish kinetics of each half&#8208;cell reaction, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode. Various emerging materials, including metal&#8208;organic frameworks, 2D materials, single&#8208;atom catalysts, high&#8208;entropy alloys, perovskites, and MXenes, have shown great potential for OER and HER. However, the synthesis strategies for these materials vary significantly based on their unique physicochemical properties. There has been no proper study on synthesis strategies for each class of the emerging materials or synchronization of the heterostructures formed. The variety in emerging materials and available synthesis routes presents ample opportunity for further exploration of target&#8208;oriented materials with unique properties. This review covers recent advancement of emerging materials and their synchronization with existing synthesis strategies for high electrocatalytic activities in water splitting. The review further discusses the challenges and future opportunities for utilizing such emerging materials in water splitting.</description>
      <author>Dun Chan, Chandan Kumar, Ashakiran Maibam, Sunghoon Yoo, Jaejun Park, Sumin Kim, Hayoung Kim, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Seunghyun Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic graphene vacancies: atomic-scale O2 scissors mediated by antiferromagnetic exchange interaction&#8211;spin-orbit selective coupling effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137998</link>
      <description>Gu Gaoyuan, Ge Ruijie, Yan Zhou, Jianing Zhang, Wenhui Li, Chong Peng, Bi Changlong, Shuyi Yang, E. Tao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410796023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gu Gaoyuan, Ge Ruijie, Yan Zhou, Jianing Zhang, Wenhui Li, Chong Peng, Bi Changlong, Shuyi Yang, E. Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137998</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Functional Properties of Ferroelectric Perovskite Thin Films: Mechanisms of Dielectric and Photoelectrochemical Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15060496</link>
      <description>Ioan Ghitiu, George Alexandru Nemne&#351;, N. Scarisoreanu, Crystals. 15(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410695650

                Various types of strain, as well as chemical pressure induced by dopants, can effectively tailor the performance of perovskite thin films, including their optical, electrical or photoelectrochemical properties. The control of these functional properties through such engineering techniques is key to fulfilling the application-specific requirements of ferroelectric devices in various fields. Numerous models and experimental data have been published on this subject, especially on ferrite-based ferroelectric materials. Within this paper, the mechanisms of tuning ferroelectric intrinsic properties, such as polarization and ferroelectric domain configurations, through epitaxial strain and doping, as well as the role of these techniques in influencing functional properties such as dielectric and photoelectrochemical ones, are presented. This review examines the significant improvements in dielectric properties and photoelectrochemical efficiency achieved by the strategical control of key functionalities including dielectric losses, domain structures, charge separation and surface reactions in strained/doped ferroelectric thin films, highlighting the advancements and research progress made in this field in recent years.</description>
      <author>Ioan Ghitiu, George Alexandru Nemne&#351;, N. Scarisoreanu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15060496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating ultrastable catalyst exploration for large-scale water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2025.47</link>
      <description>Ning Han, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Chemical Synthesis. 5(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410757743

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Han, Bao&#8208;Lian Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2025.47</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active and Stable Immobilized Iridium Complexes via Thermochemically Assisted Dangling Oxygen Participation for Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202500027</link>
      <description>Sang Youn Chae, Minee-Liane Choi, Si Young Lee, Jung Hyun Choi, Dae Won Kim, Je Seung Lee, Eun Duck Park, Jong Suk Yoo, Oh&#8208;Shim Joo, Small Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410778911

                This study investigates the immobilization of dinuclear iridium&#8208;imidazole complexes onto indium tin oxides for the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media. The immobilized iridium complexes show exceptional catalytic activity and stability, which are attributed to the facile cleavage of the elongated &#956; &#63743;O bonds between the two iridium metal centers. This cleavage leads to the formation of dangling oxygen, which plays a crucial role in facilitating thermochemical water dissociation. O 2 is released through a dangling oxygen&#8211;participated mechanism, accompanied by the regeneration of the &#956; &#63743;O bonds. This unique OER mechanism, possibly specific to immobilized (strained) molecular catalysts, resembles the lattice oxygen participation mechanism reported for unstable oxides, but with the advantage of high stability in acidic media. This study not only identifies a new mechanism but can also inform the design of immobilized molecular catalysts with enhanced performance.</description>
      <author>Sang Youn Chae, Minee-Liane Choi, Si Young Lee, Jung Hyun Choi, Dae Won Kim, Je Seung Lee, Eun Duck Park, Jong Suk Yoo, Oh&#8208;Shim Joo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202500027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transferable predictions of energetic and structural properties for refractory solid solution alloys across chemical compositions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113908</link>
      <description>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, Pei Zhang, Jong Youl Choi, German Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Ying Yang, Computational Materials Science. 257(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410708703

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, Pei Zhang, Jong Youl Choi, German Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Ying Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113908</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
