<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 01:47:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Materials design with target-oriented Bayesian optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01704-4</link>
      <description>Yuan Tian, Tongtong Li, Jianbo Pang, Yumei Zhou, Dezhen Xue, Xiangdong Ding, Turab Lookman, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411937000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan Tian, Tongtong Li, Jianbo Pang, Yumei Zhou, Dezhen Xue, Xiangdong Ding, Turab Lookman</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01704-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abridging the modelling of CO oxidation on single atom catalysts: From microkinetics to descriptor-based analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116308</link>
      <description>Hai&#8208;Yan Su, Keju Sun, Xiufang Ma, Xiangxuan Huang, Jie Feng, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411958542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hai&#8208;Yan Su, Keju Sun, Xiufang Ma, Xiangxuan Huang, Jie Feng, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Data Set Population for Training Machine Learning Potentials with Automated System Generation and Strategic Sampling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00616</link>
      <description>Alberto Pacini, Mauro Ferrario, Maria Clelia Righi, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411958907

                Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials (MLIPs) offer a powerful way to overcome the limitations of ab initio and classical molecular dynamics simulations. However, a major challenge is the generation of high-quality training data sets, which typically require extensive ab initio calculations and intensive user intervention. Here, we introduce Strategic Configuration Sampling (SCS), an active learning framework to construct compact and comprehensive data sets for MLIP training. SCS introduces the usage of workflows for the automated generation and exploration of systems, collections of MD simulations where geometries and run conditions are set up automatically based on high-level, user defined inputs. To explore nontrivial atomic environments, initial geometries can be assembled dynamically via collaging of structures harvested from preceding runs. Multiple automated exploration workflows can be run in parallel, each with its own resource budget according to the computational complexity of each system. Besides leveraging the MLIP models trained iteratively, SCS also incorporates pretrained models to steer the exploration MD, thereby eliminating the need for an initial data set. By integrating widely used software, SCS provides a fully open-source, automatic, active learning framework for the generation of data sets in a high-throughput fashion. Case studies demonstrate its versatility and effectiveness to accelerate the deployment of MLIP in diverse materials science applications.</description>
      <author>Alberto Pacini, Mauro Ferrario, Maria Clelia Righi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-selective reactivity modulation with intact reaction dynamics in H2 dissociation on single-atom alloy Au1/Ag(111) surface: Six dimensional quantum insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0278056</link>
      <description>Kaixin Meng, Haiming Huang, Tianhui Liu, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411961076

                The dissociative dynamics of molecular H2 on the Au1/Ag(111) single-atom alloy (SAA) surface was systematically investigated through full-dimensional quantum dynamical calculations. A neural network-derived potential energy surface with a 4.2 meV root-mean-square error was employed to ensure high-fidelity simulations. Density functional theory calculations identified a reduced static dissociation barrier of 1.08 eV for the SAA system, compared to the 1.22 and 1.25 eV values for pristine Ag(111) and Au(111) surfaces, respectively. Despite this energetic advantage, the six-dimensional quantum dynamical analysis revealed that the dissociation probabilities for H2 in the vibrational ground (v = 0) state exceeded those on Ag(111) only at kinetic energies below 1.33 eV. This reactivity suppression at elevated energies was attributed to the site-specific modulation induced by the Au dopant, which selectively enhanced reactivities at the top-Au, hcp, and fcc sites while inhibiting those at bridge and top-Ag sites. Furthermore, the vibrational excitation, rotational alignment, and rotational excitation effects were found to closely resemble those observed for H2 dissociation on pristine Ag(111), demonstrating that the fundamental dynamical characteristics of the reaction remain qualitatively preserved despite SAA modification. These findings provide critical insights into the interplay between local electronic structure modification and global reaction dynamics in SAA systems.</description>
      <author>Kaixin Meng, Haiming Huang, Tianhui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0278056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Charge Transfer and Delayed Recombination in a Type-II Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;TeO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;/MoSi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure: A Time-Domain Ab Initio Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01469</link>
      <description>Arooba Kanwal, Yixue Duan, Zhen&#8208;Chao Dong, Zirui Jiang, Hao Fan, Abdul Jalil, Syed Raza Ali Raza, M. Varma, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411965669

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arooba Kanwal, Yixue Duan, Zhen&#8208;Chao Dong, Zirui Jiang, Hao Fan, Abdul Jalil, Syed Raza Ali Raza, M. Varma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling electron storage at the interface between Au and anatase-TiO2 under ambient conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101430</link>
      <description>Yichen Li, Dongfang Cheng, Giyeong Son, Anna V. Shneidman, Kang Rui Garrick Lim, Joanna Aizenberg, Philippe Sautet, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411965739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yichen Li, Dongfang Cheng, Giyeong Son, Anna V. Shneidman, Kang Rui Garrick Lim, Joanna Aizenberg, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101430</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of H2 donation in heterogeneous Mo-based olefin metathesis site creation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2025.102670</link>
      <description>Dimitri Gatzios, Stephen Stockton, Avery F. Hill, Hannah Frankovic, M. M. Montemore, Lucas D. Ellis, Cell Reports Physical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411965856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dimitri Gatzios, Stephen Stockton, Avery F. Hill, Hannah Frankovic, M. M. Montemore, Lucas D. Ellis</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2025.102670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First principles investigation of zb-TiSn: A promising narrow bandgap semiconductor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417512</link>
      <description>R. Sudeep, M Sarojini, Uma Mahendra Kumar Koppolu, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411968216

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Sudeep, M Sarojini, Uma Mahendra Kumar Koppolu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Hybrid&#8208;phase IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts with Ti for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503601</link>
      <description>Young Hwa Yun, Jungwoo Choi, Young&#8208;Tae Park, Ho Bum Park, Gisu Doo, MinJoong Kim, Sang Soo Han, Jong Hyeok Park, Sechan Lee, Changsoo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411970770

                Abstract To realize a sustainable energy transition, water electrolysis&#8212;particularly proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE)&#8212;holds significant promise. However, practical deployment is hindered by the cost and instability of the anode catalyst, IrO 2 . Recent studies indicate that tuning the Ir&#9472;O bond distance, via doping or composite formation, is key to enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of IrO 2 &#8208;based electrocatalysts. Herein, a hybrid&#8208;phase Ti&#8208;incorporated IrO 2 electrocatalyst is developed, exhibiting outstanding OER activity (298.8 mV at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and stability over 25 h. This improvement originates from asymmetric interatomic interactions introduced by Ti, as revealed by combined experimental X&#8208;ray analyses and theoretical modeling. Ti incorporation induces tensile strain along the z&#8208;axis in IrO 2 motifs, effectively reducing the average Ir&#9472;O bond distance and thereby enhancing OER activity. In situ X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy further confirms that at 1.5 V (vs. RHE), the elongated Ir&#9472;O bond facilitates &#9472;OOH* intermediate formation while suppressing Ir dissolution, contributing to superior stability. These findings underscore the critical role of Ir&#9472;O bond engineering in balancing activity and durability, offering strategic insights for the rational design of high&#8208;performance OER catalysts for renewable energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Young Hwa Yun, Jungwoo Choi, Young&#8208;Tae Park, Ho Bum Park, Gisu Doo, MinJoong Kim, Sang Soo Han, Jong Hyeok Park, Sechan Lee, Changsoo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of graphdiyne-supported single- and dual-atom electrocatalysts for highly efficient hydrogen evolution reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150144</link>
      <description>Wangdi Zhang, Xiaojun Li, Junwei Lu, Shuna Li, Yunguang Zhang, Zhongkui Zhang, Mengqi Zhang, Wenyu Xi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 153(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411978826

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangdi Zhang, Xiaojun Li, Junwei Lu, Shuna Li, Yunguang Zhang, Zhongkui Zhang, Mengqi Zhang, Wenyu Xi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; Hydroxylation of the Sn&#8211;Co Diatomic Catalyst Boosting Ultrastable Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c02744</link>
      <description>Lulu Lyu, Hu Xu, Wenqi Fan, Bing Shao, Qichen Wang, Gilseob Kim, Jai Won Chung, Zhen Zhou, Yong&#8208;Mook Kang, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411980110

                Diatomic catalysts (DAs) exhibit superior catalytic activity for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) due to the synergistic interplay between dual metals. However, their dynamic evolution remains unexplored under the working conditions. Herein, Sn-Co diatomic pairs on N-doped carbon with an asymmetric N3Sn-CoN3 structure (SnCoN6 DA) are rationally designed for promoting ORR activity and durability. The operando hydroxylation of SnCoN6 DA regulates O2 adsorption on Co, allowing more d orbitals to hybridize with O2 s/p orbitals. Furthermore, the *OH-Sn moiety serves as an electron modulator that upshifts the d-band center of Co, enabling stronger binding with *OOH and expediting subsequent O-O cleavage. Accordingly, the operando hydroxylation of SnCoN6 DA positively shifts the half-wave potential by 54 mV and enhances the kinetic current density by 16.1 times compared to those of the Co single-atom catalyst. The constructed Zn-air battery shows an ultralong cycling life span (more than 3650 h at 5 and 10 mA cm-2).</description>
      <author>Lulu Lyu, Hu Xu, Wenqi Fan, Bing Shao, Qichen Wang, Gilseob Kim, Jai Won Chung, Zhen Zhou, Yong&#8208;Mook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c02744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction on IrO2(110) is governed by Walden-type mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61367-z</link>
      <description>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig, Stephan N. Steinmann, Kai S. Exner, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411983783

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key process for sustainable energy, although renewable sources require the use of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers, with IrO 2 -based materials being the gold standard under anodic polarization conditions. However, even for the (110) facet of a single-crystalline IrO 2 model electrode, the reaction mechanism is not settled yet due to contradictory reports in literature. In the present manuscript, we disentangle the conflicting results of previous theoretical studies in the density functional theory approximation. We demonstrate that dissimilar reaction mechanisms and limiting steps for the OER over IrO 2 (110) are obtained for different active surface configurations present on the IrO 2 electrode. In contrast to previous studies, we factor Walden-type mechanisms, in which the formation of the product O 2 and adsorption of the reactant H 2 O occur simultaneously, into the analysis of the elementary steps. Combining free-energy diagrams along the reaction coordinate and Bader charge analysis of the active site, we elucidate why mononuclear- or bifunctional-Walden pathways excel the traditional OER mechanisms for the OER over IrO 2 (110). Our computational methodology to identify the reaction mechanism and limiting step of proton-coupled electron transfer steps is widely applicable to electrochemical processes in the field of energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig, Stephan N. Steinmann, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61367-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical computational study of the effect of point defects and equivalent elemental doping on the photoelectrocatalytic properties of ZnO monolayers (0 0 1)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114061</link>
      <description>Hailan Li, Qingyu Hou, Yulan Gu, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma, Computational Materials Science. 258(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411983856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hailan Li, Qingyu Hou, Yulan Gu, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable synthesis of NiFe-layered double hydroxide for efficient anion exchange membrane electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61356-2</link>
      <description>&#193;lvaro Seijas&#8208;Da Silva, Adrian Hartert, V&#237;ctor Oestreicher, Jorge Romero, Camilo Jaramillo&#8208;Hern&#225;ndez, Luuk J J Muris, Gr&#233;goire Thorez, Bruno J. C. Vieira, Guillaume Ducourthial, Alice Fiocco, S&#233;bastien Legendre, Cristi&#225;n Huck&#8208;Iriart, Mart&#237;n Mizrahi, Diego L&#243;pez-Alcal&#225;, Anna T.S. Freiberg, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Jo&#227;o C. Waerenborgh, Jos&#233; J. Baldov&#237;, Serhiy Cherevko, M. Varela, Simon Thiele, Vicent Lloret, Gonzalo Abell&#225;n, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411983897

                The alkaline oxygen evolution reaction is a key step in producing green hydrogen through water electrolysis, but its large-scale industrial application remains limited due to challenges with current electrocatalysts-particularly in terms of scalability, efficiency, and long-term stability. Here we show an industrially scalable synthesis of an active NiFe layered double hydroxide (NiFe-LDH) catalyst using a room-temperature, atmospheric-pressure route. The process involves homogeneous alkalinization, where chloride ions nucleophilically attack an epoxide ring, producing a low-dimensional, defect-rich NiFe-LDH with pronounced iron clustering. In-situ spectroscopy and ab-initio calculations reveal that these structural features maximize the conversion of the NiFe-LDH to the catalytic active phase and minimize the energy barrier, improving catalytic efficiency. When used as the anode in an anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer operating at 70 &#176;C, our material delivers 1 A cm&#8315;&#178; at 1.69 V in a 5 cm2 full-cell setup, with notable durability compared to conventional NiFe-LDHs. This scalable approach could considerably lower the cost of green hydrogen production by enabling more efficient alkaline electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>&#193;lvaro Seijas&#8208;Da Silva, Adrian Hartert, V&#237;ctor Oestreicher, Jorge Romero, Camilo Jaramillo&#8208;Hern&#225;ndez, Luuk J J Muris, Gr&#233;goire Thorez, Bruno J. C. Vieira, Guillaume Ducourthial, Alice Fiocco, S&#233;bastien Legendre, Cristi&#225;n Huck&#8208;Iriart, Mart&#237;n Mizrahi, Diego L&#243;pez-Alcal&#225;, Anna T.S. Freiberg, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Jo&#227;o C. Waerenborgh, Jos&#233; J. Baldov&#237;, Serhiy Cherevko, M. Varela, Simon Thiele, Vicent Lloret, Gonzalo Abell&#225;n</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61356-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in IB-Group Metal Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Conversion and Utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100109</link>
      <description>Wenxuan Lv, Kailin Jiang, Y. Chen, Pengfei Yin, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411991137

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenxuan Lv, Kailin Jiang, Y. Chen, Pengfei Yin, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the photocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction, acetaminophen degradation, and energy recovery in fuel cells via the heterojunction of B-doped g-C3N4/BiOBr</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117848</link>
      <description>Esakkinaveen Dhanaraman, Antonysamy Soundarya Mary, Atul Verma, P. Murugan, Yen&#8208;Pei Fu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411991588

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Esakkinaveen Dhanaraman, Antonysamy Soundarya Mary, Atul Verma, P. Murugan, Yen&#8208;Pei Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput DFT Screening of Transition Metal-Graphyne Single-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113255</link>
      <description>Jueyi Ye, Zhijie He, Li Ma, Keyuan Chen, Yongzhi Wu, Hanqing Li, Ju Rong, Zhaohua Liu, Xiaohua Yu, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411991668

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jueyi Ye, Zhijie He, Li Ma, Keyuan Chen, Yongzhi Wu, Hanqing Li, Ju Rong, Zhaohua Liu, Xiaohua Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Segregation, ordering, and precipitation in WTaV-based concentrated refractory alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121276</link>
      <description>Jesper Byggm&#228;star, Damian Sobieraj, Jan Wr&#243;bel, Daniel K. Schreiber, Osman El&#8208;Atwani, Enrique Mart&#237;nez, D. Nguyen-Manh, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411992321

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jesper Byggm&#228;star, Damian Sobieraj, Jan Wr&#243;bel, Daniel K. Schreiber, Osman El&#8208;Atwani, Enrique Mart&#237;nez, D. Nguyen-Manh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study of the catalytic activity for oxygen reduction reaction in multi-N-doped graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107008</link>
      <description>W. Shao, Jinmin Guo, Xiaoliang Zhang, Bingling He, Wei Song, Yang&#8208;Yi Liu, Yu&#8208;Hao Li, Yilang Mai, Jinlong Wang, Xiao-Chun Li, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411992551

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W. Shao, Jinmin Guo, Xiaoliang Zhang, Bingling He, Wei Song, Yang&#8208;Yi Liu, Yu&#8208;Hao Li, Yilang Mai, Jinlong Wang, Xiao-Chun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of high C/N-ratio homonuclear dual-atom catalysts for electrochemical reduction of nitrate to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111536</link>
      <description>Yahui Li, Quanchen Feng, Krisztina L&#225;szl&#243;, Ying Wang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412002093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yahui Li, Quanchen Feng, Krisztina L&#225;szl&#243;, Ying Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Pt-based alloys for furfural electro-oxidation coupled with green hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138318</link>
      <description>Zehuai Mou, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412002506

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zehuai Mou, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic effect of hydroxyl modified PTI/LiCl supported monatomic and diatomic catalysts on oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138319</link>
      <description>Weichao Xue, Wei Lin, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412002508

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weichao Xue, Wei Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Guided Discovery of Alloy Nanoclusters: Steering Morphology-Based Activity and Selectivity Relationships in Bifunctional Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c07198</link>
      <description>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412004881

                Nanoclusters designed with atomic precision are poised to transform next-generation electrode materials for energy devices due to their exceptional performance. However, traditional computational studies often focus solely on individual nanoclusters, neglecting the impact of structurally diverse, low-energy isomers that coexist in a sample. Herein, we present a data-driven approach to screen late-transition metal-based core-shell nanoclusters for bifunctional electrocatalysis. Utilizing geometric and electronic properties, we establish morphology-based relationships for activity and selectivity, emphasizing the critical role of structural diversity in fuel cell applications. We identify the unique single-cluster catalyst identity of M55 nanoclusters, where intermediate adsorption is primarily governed by the constituent metals' electronic and elemental characteristics. Our findings identified the Au48W7 nanocluster as the most efficient electrocatalyst, exhibiting the lowest bifunctional overpotential of 0.76 V, with &#951;OER = 0.33 V and &#951;ORR = 0.43 V, highlighting its outstanding catalytic performance at the nano regime. Guided by the Sabatier principle, we highlight the limitations of conventional numerical methods and reshape the activity volcano, transitioning from RuO2 and Pt to Au/Ag-based nanoclusters. Furthermore, the trained ML model enables the screening of electrocatalysts for two- and four-electron pathways, steering selectivity between H2O2 and H2O formation. This study provides intuitive guidelines for designing efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts, redefining activity volcanoes, and modulates selectivity in nanocluster alloys.</description>
      <author>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c07198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Metal&#8208;Embedded Nitrogen Heterocycle Aromatic Catalysts for Efficient and Selective Two&#8208;Electron Water Electrolysis Toward Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.70042</link>
      <description>Pengting Sun, Jiaxiang Qiu, Jinlong Wu, Daoxiong Wu, Ruirui Wang, Xiaohong Yan, Yangyang Wan, Xiaojun Wu, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412014634

                ABSTRACT Hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) is an eco&#8208;friendly chemical with widespread industrial applications. However, the commercial anthraquinone process for H 2 O 2 production is energy&#8208;intensive and environmentally harmful, highlighting the need for more sustainable alternatives. The electrochemical production of H 2 O 2 via the two&#8208;electron water oxidation reaction (2e&#8315; WOR) presents a promising route but is often hindered by low efficiency and selectivity, due to the competition with the oxygen evolution reaction. In this study, we employed high&#8208;throughput computational screening and microkinetic modeling to design a series of efficient 2e&#8315; WOR electrocatalysts from a library of 240 single&#8208;metal&#8208;embedded nitrogen heterocycle aromatic molecules (M&#8208;NHAMs). These catalysts, primarily comprising post&#8208;transition metals, such as Cu, Ni, Zn, and Pd, exhibit high activity for H 2 O 2 conversion with a limiting potential approaching the optimal value of 1.76 V. Additionally, they exhibit excellent selectivity, with Faradaic efficiencies exceeding 80% at overpotentials below 300 mV. Structure&#8208;performance analysis reveals that the d &#8208;band center and magnetic moment of the metal center correlated strongly with the oxygen adsorption free energy (), suggesting these parameters as key catalytic descriptors for efficient screening and performance optimization. This study contributes to the rational design of highly efficient and selective electrocatalysts for electrochemical production of H 2 O 2 , offering a sustainable solution for green energy and industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Pengting Sun, Jiaxiang Qiu, Jinlong Wu, Daoxiong Wu, Ruirui Wang, Xiaohong Yan, Yangyang Wan, Xiaojun Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.70042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering artificial photosynthesis via photoinduced conversion of monometallic to bimetallic sites in FeCo nitroprussides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61129-x</link>
      <description>Hao Wang, Gui&#8208;Lin Zhuang, Yingjie Fan, Hua&#8208;Qing Yin, Wei Zhang, Zhe Wu, Shuang Yao, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Wenbin Lin, Zhiming Zhang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412018624

                Artificial photosynthesis provides an efficient strategy for solar energy storage via water splitting and CO2 reduction, but it remains a challenge in tuning artificial photosynthesis between these two competing reactions. Herein, we demonstrate photoinduced conversion of monometallic to bimetallic sites in a Fe-Co nitroprusside (FeCo-NP) to steer the reaction path from H2 evolution to CO2 reduction. Monometallic Co sites achieve efficient H2 production with 28.5 mmol g-1 activity and 85.4% selectivity. Photoinduced release of nitrosyl groups from Fe sites generates bimetallic Fe-Co sites, which suppress H2 evolution and enhance CO2 reduction, yielding 31.5 mmol g-1 activity and 87.3% selectivity for C1 products. Mechanistic investigations reveal that monometallic Co sites catalyze H2 evolution via H2O adsorption and O-H cleavage while bimetallic Fe-Co sites facilitate both H2O and CO2 adsorption and subsequent O and C hydrogenation for CO and HCOOH. This work uncovers a strategy to manipulate competing reaction pathways via photoinduced conversion of monometallic to bimetallic sites, which provides unique insights into addressing environmental issues and energy crises.</description>
      <author>Hao Wang, Gui&#8208;Lin Zhuang, Yingjie Fan, Hua&#8208;Qing Yin, Wei Zhang, Zhe Wu, Shuang Yao, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Wenbin Lin, Zhiming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61129-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Role of Transition-Metal Dopants in Ni(Oh)2/Niooh-Catalyzed Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5339125</link>
      <description>Qiu Jin, Matteo Xavier Garcia-Ortiz, L&#237;ney &#193;rnad&#243;ttir, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412018921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiu Jin, Matteo Xavier Garcia-Ortiz, L&#237;ney &#193;rnad&#243;ttir</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5339125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Densely Packed Hydrogen in Porous Hydridic Frameworks Simulated by Hybrid Grand Canonical Monte Carlo and Molecular Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c00761</link>
      <description>Jiewei Cheng, Peng&#8208;Hu Du, Qiang Sun, P. Jena, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412019591

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiewei Cheng, Peng&#8208;Hu Du, Qiang Sun, P. Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c00761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIGHT AS A SPATIAL AND SEMANTIC FACTOR IN ARCHITECTURE: A PHENOMENOLOGICAL APPROACH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33042/2311-7257.2025.112.1.15</link>
      <description>Oksana Fomenko, Serhii DANILOV, M. Blinova, No host. None(112)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412019802

                The article presents a concept that considers the prospects for the development of architecture as a significant part of an environmentally positive, sustainably functioning city integrated into the environment. At this stage of presenting the problem, such a city is the final stage of the implementation of the Sustainable Development Goals declared by the UN. The authors give an idea of three basic stages (periods) of urban development, from modernity to the achievement of the Goals, namely: industrial, post-industrial, sustainable. The concept of the principles of relations between cities and the ecological balance of adjacent regions corresponding to these stages is put forward. As a research method that formalizes the nature of the principles of ecological relations between the city and the surrounding region, the paradigm of biology as a science of living nature is taken. According to the chosen paradigm, the problems of integrating the city into the environment are considered from the standpoint of three possible types of symbiotic relationships: mutualism, parasitism, and commensalism. For each of the three types of symbiosis, examples of architectural and urban planning concepts are analyzed. A hypothesis is put forward about the current stage of the symbiotic relationship between architecture and the environment. A hypothesis is put forward about the beginning of the process of formation of architectural and urban planning approaches focused on an ecologically positive type of symbiosis of the city and the environment. The definition of a post-industrial city as a city of the transition period is given. A hypothesis is put forward about the basic principles of the formation of the architecture of a post-industrial city. The term "Compensatory-parasitic symbiosis" is proposed, which determines the principles of the functioning of the architecture of the transition period. The term "compensatory-parasitic type of architectural development" should be understood as such a formation of architectural and town-planning objects, in which the most effective compensation for damage caused by the city to the environment takes place.</description>
      <author>Oksana Fomenko, Serhii DANILOV, M. Blinova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33042/2311-7257.2025.112.1.15</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Step Microfluidic Synthesis of Active Nanostructured Pt/C Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5339540</link>
      <description>Irina O. Nechitailova, Yulia A. Pankova, Mahmoud Eid, Dmitrii Yu. Molodtsov, Andrei A. Tereshchenko, Ilya Pankov, Alexander Soldatov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Alexander A. Guda, Alexander D. Zagrebaev, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412023468

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Irina O. Nechitailova, Yulia A. Pankova, Mahmoud Eid, Dmitrii Yu. Molodtsov, Andrei A. Tereshchenko, Ilya Pankov, Alexander Soldatov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Alexander A. Guda, Alexander D. Zagrebaev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5339540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will It Blend? Mixing Numerical and Machine-Learned Physics Quantities for Accurate on-the-Fly Surrogate Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-97632-2_19</link>
      <description>Michael Tynes, Kyle Chard, Ian Foster, Logan Ward, Lecture notes in computer science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412042152

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Michael Tynes, Kyle Chard, Ian Foster, Logan Ward</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-97632-2_19</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Formation and Electrical Transformation in SiO2 Thin Films via Ti-Induced Interdiffusion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121313</link>
      <description>Soon Joo Yoon, Jeong Woo Jeon, Junho Lee, JungHun Park, Chan&#8208;Woo Lee, Ki Jun Yu, Hyeonhu Bae, Ki&#8208;Hyun Kim, Keun Heo, Cheol Seong Hwang, Deok&#8208;Yong Cho, Taehun Lee, Youn&#8208;Kyoung Lee, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412043550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soon Joo Yoon, Jeong Woo Jeon, Junho Lee, JungHun Park, Chan&#8208;Woo Lee, Ki Jun Yu, Hyeonhu Bae, Ki&#8208;Hyun Kim, Keun Heo, Cheol Seong Hwang, Deok&#8208;Yong Cho, Taehun Lee, Youn&#8208;Kyoung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Modeling of Solid&#8211;Liquid Interfaces: From Ab Initio Methods to Machine-Learning Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41745-025-00475-7</link>
      <description>Abhinav S. Raman, Journal of the Indian Institute of Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412046039

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abhinav S. Raman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41745-025-00475-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Compensation Challenges in Processing Antiferroelectric PbZrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Thin Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c04818</link>
      <description>Milan Haddad, &#1042;. &#1040;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1073;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1074;, Kristina M. Holsgrove, Sergio Rivera-Cruz, Sarah J. Stock, Nikhilesh Maity, S. Lisenkov, I. Ponomareva, Amit Kumar, Lewys Jones, Nazanin Bassiri&#8208;Gharb, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412047561

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Milan Haddad, &#1042;. &#1040;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1073;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1074;, Kristina M. Holsgrove, Sergio Rivera-Cruz, Sarah J. Stock, Nikhilesh Maity, S. Lisenkov, I. Ponomareva, Amit Kumar, Lewys Jones, Nazanin Bassiri&#8208;Gharb</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c04818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing a machine-learned potential to explore enhanced radiation tolerance in the MoNbTaVW high-entropy alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2025.156004</link>
      <description>Jiahui Liu, Jesper Byggm&#228;star, Zheyong Fan, Bing Bai, Ping Qian, Yanjing Su, Journal of Nuclear Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412048424

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahui Liu, Jesper Byggm&#228;star, Zheyong Fan, Bing Bai, Ping Qian, Yanjing Su</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2025.156004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Assisted Activation of Lattice Oxygen in Fe-Co3o4 Catalysts for Boosting Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5340410</link>
      <description>Yangshuo Liu, Yaotian Yan, Liang Qiao, Yao Meng, Jiehe Sui, Weimin Cai, Xiao Hang Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412049902

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yangshuo Liu, Yaotian Yan, Liang Qiao, Yao Meng, Jiehe Sui, Weimin Cai, Xiao Hang Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5340410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain heterogeneity in RuO2 for efficient acidic oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58570-3</link>
      <description>Xuejie Cao, Licheng Miao, Wenqi Jia, Hongye Qin, Guangliang Lin, Rongpeng Ma, Ting Jin, Lifang Jiao, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412050068

                Developing acid-stable and active ruthenium dioxide (RuO2) catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for facilitating the large-scale applications of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) for hydrogen production. Here, we propose a strain heterogeneity engineering strategy to simultaneously enhance the OER stability and activity of RuO2 electrocatalysts by introducing single-atom platinum (Pt). In a PEM water electrolyzer, the resultant Pt-RuO2 catalyst archives 3 A cm-2 at a low voltage of 1.791 V and maintains a stable performance for over 500 h at 500 mA cm-2. These performance metrics highlight its potential for practical applications. Experiments and calculations analyses confirm that the bulk tensile strain effectively stabilizes the entire structure of electrocatalysts, while the regions of compressive strain are identified as highly active catalytic sites, where the weakened binding energy of oxo-intermediates improves the catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Xuejie Cao, Licheng Miao, Wenqi Jia, Hongye Qin, Guangliang Lin, Rongpeng Ma, Ting Jin, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58570-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas-phase dispersion engineering of PtCo intermetallic catalysts with enhanced compressive strain for high-performance PEMFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116314</link>
      <description>Jun&#8208;Fei Shen, Guiming Wu, Na Tian, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang, Zhi&#8208;You Zhou, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412053494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun&#8208;Fei Shen, Guiming Wu, Na Tian, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang, Zhi&#8208;You Zhou, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How far are volcanologists from volcanoes?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00445-025-01849-6</link>
      <description>Gilles Seropian, Thomas J. Aubry, Jamie Farquharson, James Hickey, Bulletin of Volcanology. 87(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411951833

                Abstract Volcanoes are not randomly located on Earth, neither are volcanologists. We explored the physical distance between volcanologists and volcanoes by considering two categories of volcanoes: all volcanoes with a confirmed eruption in the Holocene and volcanoes that erupted in the past 50 years (1974&#8211;2024). We computed the distance between these volcanoes and the affiliation addresses from volcanologists, defined here as authors having published in the main volcanology journals. We then investigated the dependence of this distance on further bibliometric parameters, such as the journal published in or the author position. Affiliations were extracted from articles published since 1980 in four of the main English-speaking volcanology-focused journals in the Scopus database. Around 27% of volcanologists are based within 100 km of a Holocene volcano, compared to 14% of the world population. More than 85% of volcanologists are within 1000 km of a Holocene volcano, but 48% need to travel over 1000 km to visit a volcano that erupted in the past 50 years. We tested whether distance to the nearest volcano correlates with author position. We observed that researchers working nearer volcanoes tend to lead articles with more co-authors, which is robustly supported by statistical tests. We also found that authors in further positions tend to be based nearer recently active volcanoes, though this correlation is less significant. Using keywords to identify each article&#8217;s studied volcano, we performed single volcano analysis for the 25 most frequently studied volcanoes in the dataset. We observed significant differences in the distance from authors to the target volcano. For instance, we obtained median author-volcano distances of 9 km for Campi Flegrei and 11,735 km for Merapi. Our analyses also permitted a very simplistic estimate of the carbon footprint from fieldwork travel, yielding CO $$_{\varvec{2}}$$     2     equivalent emissions of about 1 ton per travelling author, with an order of magnitude uncertainty. The database presented is very rich and could serve future efforts in science strategy, equality, diversity and inclusivity, outreach, and sustainability.</description>
      <author>Gilles Seropian, Thomas J. Aubry, Jamie Farquharson, James Hickey</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00445-025-01849-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of electrochemical CO reduction on carbonitrides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2025.101970</link>
      <description>Muhammad Awais, Younes Abghoui, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412044301

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Awais, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2025.101970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping or loading: unraveling the optimal anchoring strategy of single metal atom on Co3O4 for electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.06.060</link>
      <description>Riming Hu, Haoyu Wang, Ruochen Zhu, Xinyuan Yang, Xiuxian Zhao, Fahao Ma, Jiayuan Yu, Xuchuan Jiang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412049091

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Riming Hu, Haoyu Wang, Ruochen Zhu, Xinyuan Yang, Xiuxian Zhao, Fahao Ma, Jiayuan Yu, Xuchuan Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.06.060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain Specific Language for Materials Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-97564-6_18</link>
      <description>Ivan Kondov, Rodrigo Cort&#233;s&#8208;Mej&#237;a, Marvin M&#252;ller, Nikolai Pfisterer, S Sreenivasan, Lecture notes in computer science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412055324

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ivan Kondov, Rodrigo Cort&#233;s&#8208;Mej&#237;a, Marvin M&#252;ller, Nikolai Pfisterer, S Sreenivasan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-97564-6_18</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partially reduced PdOx nanoparticles strongly interacting with defect-rich ceria via dynamic redox pulse for complete methane oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125672</link>
      <description>Seung-Hee Ryu, Seokhyun Choung, Yunji Choi, Hyunjoo Lee, Joon&#8208;Hwan Choi, Jeong Woo Han, Hojin Jeong, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412055487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seung-Hee Ryu, Seokhyun Choung, Yunji Choi, Hyunjoo Lee, Joon&#8208;Hwan Choi, Jeong Woo Han, Hojin Jeong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin-blockade effect of chiral multi-branch Au nanoparticles for mediating oxygen evolution reaction of electro-catalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165517</link>
      <description>Rui Tian, Lufei Huang, Ying Li, Dewei Zhang, Shenghong Ju, Baowen Zhou, Lin Yao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412055696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Tian, Lufei Huang, Ying Li, Dewei Zhang, Shenghong Ju, Baowen Zhou, Lin Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus&#8208;Doped Highly Crystalline Carbon for High Platinum Stability and Robust Support in Proton&#8208;Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500481</link>
      <description>Han Seul Kim, Seung Min Woo, Gi-Hwan Kang, Sang&#8208;Hoon You, Sang&#8208;Seok Lee, Su Bin Park, Jae Hyun Park, Y.&#8208;H. Cho, Kyung Rog Lee, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Seung&#8208;Ho Yu, Il&#8208;Kyu Park, Sung Jong Yoo, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412066895

                Abstract Proton&#8208;exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs) require durable and efficient catalyst supports to overcome the limitations of Pt&#8208;based catalysts and conventional low&#8208;crystalline carbon (LCC) supports, such as high cost, susceptibility to corrosion, and poor electrochemical durability. While highly crystalline carbon (HCC) offers improved stability, its intrinsic hydrophobicity and low defect density hinder Pt nanoparticles (NPs) nucleation and dispersion. In this study, a spin&#8208;on&#8208;dopant (SOD) approach is employed to synthesize phosphorus&#8208;incorporated HCC (HCC P ) providing stable anchoring sites that facilitate uniform Pt NPs distribution. Compared to commercial Pt/LCC, Pt/HCC P exhibits enhanced thermal stability and oxidation resistance, with an oxidation onset temperature &#8776;90 &#176;C higher. Accelerated durability tests reveal only a 2 mV half&#8208;wave potential shift and a minimal electrochemical surface area (ECSA) loss of 1.9% after 20 000 cycles, significantly lower than the 47.1% ECSA loss observed for Pt/LCC. Single&#8208;cell tests further confirm that Pt/HCC P retains 92.4% of its initial power density, outperforming Pt/LCC. The incorporation of phosphorus improves Pt NPs stabilization on the superhydrophobic HCC surface, enhancing Pt utilization and long&#8208;term durability. This study provides valuable insights into the development of high&#8208;performance carbon supports for PEMFC catalysts.</description>
      <author>Han Seul Kim, Seung Min Woo, Gi-Hwan Kang, Sang&#8208;Hoon You, Sang&#8208;Seok Lee, Su Bin Park, Jae Hyun Park, Y.&#8208;H. Cho, Kyung Rog Lee, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Seung&#8208;Ho Yu, Il&#8208;Kyu Park, Sung Jong Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curvature effect of TMN4 sites on carbon nanotube for electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide revealed by machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146862</link>
      <description>Aling Ma, YuShan Pang, Zongpeng Ding, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412071431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aling Ma, YuShan Pang, Zongpeng Ding, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-Equilibrium Reactivity of Boron-Enriched Metal Diboride Surfaces in Electroreduction Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04054</link>
      <description>Zisheng Zhang, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412073651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zisheng Zhang, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic reduction of CO2 over porous ultrathin NiO nanosheets with oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64687-0</link>
      <description>Rui Li, Pengfei Feng, Bonan Li, Jiayu Zhu, Yali Zhang, Ze Zhang, Jiangwei Zhang, Yong Ding, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 73(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412074891

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Li, Pengfei Feng, Bonan Li, Jiayu Zhu, Yali Zhang, Ze Zhang, Jiangwei Zhang, Yong Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64687-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planar [Cu&#8211;S]&#8211;Organic Framework for Selective and Low&#8208;Overpotential CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202500235</link>
      <description>Khatereh Roohi, Mohammad Soleimani, Nabil Khossossi, Stefano Canossa, Ali Kosari, Seyedamirhossein Mohseni Armaki, Majid Ahmadi, Ewout van der Veer, Mahinder Ramdin, Prasaanth Ravi Anusuyadevi, Prasad Gonugunta, J.M.C. Mol, Poulumi Dey, Peyman Taheri, Small Structures. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412075137

                The development of advanced catalysts with innovative nanoarchitectures is critical for addressing energy and environmental challenges such as the electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR). Herein, the synthesis of an innovative copper&#8211;sulfur planar structure, Cu&#8211;S&#8211;BDC, within a metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) catalyst is presented, which demonstrates 100% selectivity toward formate as the sole carbon product. Structural analysis and surface characterizations reveal that Cu&#8211;S&#8211;BDC exhibits quasi&#8208;2D inorganic building units, with Cu bonded to two S&#8208;CH groups and one BDC linker, while carboxylate groups adopt a bridging coordination mode. This unique arrangement not only imparts remarkable structural stability but also enhances the electronic properties of the MOF, as evidenced by a narrow bandgap of 1.203 eV that facilitates efficient charge transfer and increased electrochemical current density in CORR. Notably, it offers a Faradaic efficiency of 92% for formate at an overpotential as low as &#8722;0.4 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) in an aqueous electrolyte of 1 m KOH, as well as a current density of &#8722;25.8 mA cm 2 at &#8722;0.9 V versus RHE, averaged over 24 h of electrolysis. This study highlights a fresh perspective in the field of MOF electrocatalysts by demonstrating that engineering the metal coordination environment can significantly enhance the electronic properties and consequently improve the electrocatalytic performance of these materials.</description>
      <author>Khatereh Roohi, Mohammad Soleimani, Nabil Khossossi, Stefano Canossa, Ali Kosari, Seyedamirhossein Mohseni Armaki, Majid Ahmadi, Ewout van der Veer, Mahinder Ramdin, Prasaanth Ravi Anusuyadevi, Prasad Gonugunta, J.M.C. Mol, Poulumi Dey, Peyman Taheri</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202500235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure-activity relation of single-atom electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction to CH4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3460-4</link>
      <description>Changyan Zhu, Mengxue Wang, Ao Yang, Xiaohui Yao, Guangshan Zhu, Chongyi Ling, Zhongmin Su, Min Zhang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412077601

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changyan Zhu, Mengxue Wang, Ao Yang, Xiaohui Yao, Guangshan Zhu, Chongyi Ling, Zhongmin Su, Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3460-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure Engineering of Co-MOF Derived MoS2-CoS2/CoSO4 Composite: Synergistic Effects and Ionic Distribution Optimization for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146864</link>
      <description>Yingxuan Cao, Zhuoao Li, Pengbo Ding, Lixiu Guan, Zixiang Bai, Chaoping Yuan, Junguang Tao, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412077667

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingxuan Cao, Zhuoao Li, Pengbo Ding, Lixiu Guan, Zixiang Bai, Chaoping Yuan, Junguang Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal-centered boron clusters on graphene: Promising multifunctional catalysts for overall water splitting and oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164023</link>
      <description>Muhammad Bilal Ahmed Siddique, Jun Li, Shijun Wang, Yan-Zi Yu, Li Cao, Jing Chen, Lei Zhang, Shi&#8208;Bo Cheng, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412079763

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Bilal Ahmed Siddique, Jun Li, Shijun Wang, Yan-Zi Yu, Li Cao, Jing Chen, Lei Zhang, Shi&#8208;Bo Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Synthesis of Carbon-Supported Ir&#8211;Ni Bimetallic Nanoparticles for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03813</link>
      <description>Cunyuan Gao, Yutong Wang, Shiyu Zhen, Jinhua Zhan, Liang Zhang, Bin Cai, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412087737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cunyuan Gao, Yutong Wang, Shiyu Zhen, Jinhua Zhan, Liang Zhang, Bin Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cathode Materials for Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells: From Metal and Metal Composite Catalysts to Carbon&#8208;Supported Hybrids in Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500146</link>
      <description>Claudia Garc&#233;s&#8208;Barr&#237;a, Daniel C&#225;ceres&#8208;D&#237;az, Javiera Torres&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Tatiana M. Bustamante, Elizabeth Elgueta, Felipe Sanhueza, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412088039

                This review provides an overview of recent advancements in cathode materials for proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), focusing on their role in catalyzing the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). This begins with a fundamental discussion of the ORR mechanism, including two&#8208;electron and four&#8208;electron pathways. The review then explores a wide range of electrocatalyst materials, starting with precious metal catalysts, particularly platinum&#8208;based materials, along with alloying strategies and composite structures. This then delves into nonprecious metal catalysts, encompassing metal&#8208;free ORR electrocatalysts, carbon&#8208;supported composite materials (including heteroatom doping and metal&#8208;carbon composites), and transition metal oxides. The review further examines metal phthalocyanines, biomass&#8208;derived catalysts, bimetallic and trimetallic nanoparticles supported on carbon matrices, and chalcogenides (oxides, sulfides, and selenides) as ORR electrocatalysts. Advanced materials such as single&#8208; and dual&#8208;atom catalysts, high&#8208;entropy alloys, and metal organic frameworks derived electrocatalysts are also discussed. We analyze the identification of reaction sites and the effect of structure on catalytic activity. Furthermore, the review covers electrochemical measurements in PEMFCs and explores technological applications and industrial relevance, including products and patents. Finally, this review concludes by addressing future perspectives and challenges in the field of cathode materials for PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>Claudia Garc&#233;s&#8208;Barr&#237;a, Daniel C&#225;ceres&#8208;D&#237;az, Javiera Torres&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Tatiana M. Bustamante, Elizabeth Elgueta, Felipe Sanhueza</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modified Metal Hydride and Organometallic Composites as a Hydrogen Storage Material for Portable Storage System: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-3841-3_30</link>
      <description>Aditi Sinha, Avijit Ghosh, Sunil Baran Kuila, Lipika Das, Biswajit Mandal, Springer Proceedings in Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412088127

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aditi Sinha, Avijit Ghosh, Sunil Baran Kuila, Lipika Das, Biswajit Mandal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-3841-3_30</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2-to-CH4 Conversion via Grain Boundary Oxidation Effect in CuAg Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-98056-5_3</link>
      <description>Lei Wang, Zhongchao Tan, Yimin A. Wu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412094698

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Wang, Zhongchao Tan, Yimin A. Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-98056-5_3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certification of boroxol ring population in vitreous B&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e375" altimg="si133.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;O&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e383" altimg="si134.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; glass using theoretical simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtla.2025.102474</link>
      <description>Shingo Urata, Federica Lodesani, Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412096452

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shingo Urata, Federica Lodesani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtla.2025.102474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Selectivity Barrier of Single&#8208;Atom Nanozymes Through Out&#8208;of&#8208;Plane Ligand Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202506480</link>
      <description>Seonhye Park, Kyu In Shim, Phuong Thy Nguyen, Daeeun Choi, Seongbeen Kim, Seung Yeop Yi, Moon Il Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Jinwoo Lee, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412097680

                Abstract Peroxidase (POD)&#8208;like nanozymes have emerged as effective alternatives to natural enzymes owing to their stability and cost&#8208;effectiveness in biosensors. In particular, single&#8208;atom nanozymes (SAzymes) featuring Fe&#8211;N 4 active sites have attracted significant attention for their high catalytic performance. However, their 2D exposed active sites result in limited reaction selectivity and strong pH dependence, restricting their functionality under neutral conditions. This study introduces Ru&#8208;centered SAzymes coordinated out&#8208;of&#8208;plane with chlorine ligands (RuNC_Cl), achieving monofunctional POD&#8208;like activity. RuNC_Cl exhibited remarkable POD&#8208;like activity, which is 38&#8208;fold greater than its catalase (CAT)&#8208;like activity, indicating strong suppression of the competing CAT&#8208;like reaction. Density functional theory calculations and Bader charge analysis of RuNC_Cl reveal that repulsive forces preventing secondary H 2 O 2 adsorption contribute to an increased energy barrier for the CAT&#8208;like reaction. This selective POD&#8208;like activity enables the precise detection of multiple biomarkers through a one&#8208;pot cascade reaction under near&#8208;neutral conditions. This advancement paves the way for the precise regulation of reaction pathways, enhancing the practicality of nanozymes for biosensing and related applications.</description>
      <author>Seonhye Park, Kyu In Shim, Phuong Thy Nguyen, Daeeun Choi, Seongbeen Kim, Seung Yeop Yi, Moon Il Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Jinwoo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202506480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monolayer YTeI for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163928</link>
      <description>Dandan Mao, Rundong Wan, Shijie Wang, Zhengfu Zhang, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412097949

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dandan Mao, Rundong Wan, Shijie Wang, Zhengfu Zhang, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Janus Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts: Critical Role of Oxygen Coordination and an Effective Descriptor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202507849</link>
      <description>Hongling Liu, Zhichao Yu, Jia Zhao, Weng Fai Ip, S. Lin, Hui Pan, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412101020

                Abstract Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) embedded in nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene have been widely studied for electrochemical CO 2 reduction (CO 2 R), primarily yielding CO. However, achieving selectivity for C1 hydrocarbons remains challenging. Here, 32 Janus DACs (J&#8208;M'M) are designed and investigated for CO 2 R using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, identifying 13 capable of producing methanol and methane. Notably, J&#8208;FeCo and J&#8208;CoNi exhibit favorable limiting potentials (&#8722;0.38 and &#8722;0.45 V vs. RHE) for CH 3 OH and CH 4 production, respectively, based on constant&#8208;potential calculations. Compared to normal DACs (N&#8208;M'M), Janus DACs demonstrate enhanced initial CO 2 hydrogenation and stronger CO adsorption. Oxygen coordination in J&#8208;FeCo and J&#8208;CoNi induces a downshift/upshift of majority&#8208;/minority&#8208;spin energy levels of d z2 , d yz , and d xz orbitals toward the Fermi level relative to N&#8208;FeCo and N&#8208;CoNi, strengthening the bonding state and weakening the antibonding state, thereby improving CO adsorption. Furthermore, an effective descriptor based on atomic features is identified to evaluate *CO binding strength. This work highlights the critical role of partial oxygen coordination in DACs for C1 hydrocarbons production and proposes a robust descriptor to guide the design of related catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongling Liu, Zhichao Yu, Jia Zhao, Weng Fai Ip, S. Lin, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202507849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature effects on radiation damage in HCP-Zirconium: A molecular dynamics study using a fine-tuned machine-learned potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2025.156025</link>
      <description>J. Jia, Yu Bao, Shuo Cao, Ye Su, Ping Qian, Journal of Nuclear Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412105316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Jia, Yu Bao, Shuo Cao, Ye Su, Ping Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2025.156025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-Block Elements Adsorption Induced Shift of Potential of Zero Free Charge of Pt(111)/HClO4 Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146858</link>
      <description>Yu-Jun Xu, Shuo Zhang, Mengke Zhang, Tingting Mao, Jun Cai, Yanxia Chen, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412071761

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Jun Xu, Shuo Zhang, Mengke Zhang, Tingting Mao, Jun Cai, Yanxia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competitions between hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen reduction reaction on an Au surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64650-x</link>
      <description>Yao Yao, Juping Xu, Minhua Shao, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 73(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412073953

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Yao, Juping Xu, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64650-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of flow chemistry in self-driving labs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2025.102205</link>
      <description>Nikolai Mukhin, Pragyan Jha, Milad Abolhasani, Matter. 8(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411957801

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nikolai Mukhin, Pragyan Jha, Milad Abolhasani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2025.102205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Machine Learning Potentials through Transfer Learning across Chemical Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c00293</link>
      <description>Sebastien R&#246;cken, Julija Zavadlav, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412090803

                Machine learning potentials (MLPs) can enable simulations of ab initio accuracy at orders of magnitude lower computational cost. However, their effectiveness hinges on the availability of considerable data sets to ensure robust generalization across chemical space and thermodynamic conditions. The generation of such data sets can be labor-intensive, highlighting the need for innovative methods to train MLPs in data-scarce scenarios. Here, we introduce transfer learning of potential energy surfaces between chemically similar elements. Specifically, we leverage the trained MLP for silicon to initialize and expedite the training of an MLP for germanium. Utilizing classical force field and ab initio data sets, we demonstrate that transfer learning surpasses traditional training from scratch in force prediction, leading to more stable simulations and improved temperature transferability. These advantages become even more pronounced as the training data set size decreases. We also observe positive transfer learning effects for most out-of-target properties. Our findings demonstrate that transfer learning across chemical elements is a promising technique for developing accurate and numerically stable MLPs, particularly in a data-scarce regime.</description>
      <author>Sebastien R&#246;cken, Julija Zavadlav</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c00293</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
