<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 01:07:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation on the Structural Characteristics and Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction Mechanism of G-C3n4 Supported Ag/Au Single Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4865428</link>
      <description>Hui-Ling Shui, Xin Wei, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399657986

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui-Ling Shui, Xin Wei, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4865428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Mechanism and Activity of O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction of Co Nanocluster Encapsulated by Carbon Nanotube</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01355</link>
      <description>Ashok Singh, Srimanta Pakhira, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399661604

                Exploration of inexpensive electrocatalysts with excellent catalytic activity and chemical stability for the O2 reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for the widespread adoption of sustainable and renewable energy conversion technologies in practical applications. This study explored the potential of Co nanoparticle-encapsulated single-wall carbon nanotube (Co@SWCNT) as efficient electrocatalyst for ORR. We employed a quantum mechanical (QM) periodic hybrid B3LYP density functional theory (DFT) method with the dispersion corrections (-D3) (developed by Grimme and co-workers) to investigate the ORR mechanism. We examined the impact of Co nanoparticles on the electronic properties of the SWCNT and observed that Co@SWCNT has metallic characteristics in nature. The study focused on determining the adsorption energy (&#916;E) of ORR species on the Co@SWCNT surface to comprehend its electrocatalytic efficiency and performance toward ORR. Furthermore, we proposed two potential ORR mechanisms: a direct 4e&#8211; transfer reaction pathway and a series of 2e&#8211; transfer reaction pathways. The value of &#916;E of the 2O* ORR intermediate has been determined to be &#8722;0.35 eV, and for the OOH* ORR intermediate, the value of &#916;E is about &#8722;3.59 eV. This suggests that the 4e&#8211; dissociative pathway could be the thermodynamically favorable path for the O2 reduction reaction compared to the 4e&#8211; associative and 2e&#8211; pathways of ORR. This research not only paves the way for the development of cost-effective and highly durable nonmetal catalytic materials but also holds great promise for advancing future renewable energy and fuel cell applications.</description>
      <author>Ashok Singh, Srimanta Pakhira</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of single-atom catalysts on 1 T-TMD for highly active and selective CO2 reduction reaction: Computational and machine learning insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115610</link>
      <description>Xi Shen, Peng Zhao, Cheng He, W. Zhang, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399662000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xi Shen, Peng Zhao, Cheng He, W. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Transition Metals on CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Supported for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Adsorption by DFT and Machine Learning Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c01200</link>
      <description>Hossein Mashhadimoslem, Peyman Karimi, Mohammad Ali Abdol, Kourosh E. Zanganeh, Ahmed Shafeen, Ali A. AlHammadi, Ali Elkamel, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399667093

                Catalyst design is a field where machine learning (ML) algorithms have found many useful applications using atomistic simulation data sets. Atomistic simulation of CO2 adsorption energy using several transition metals on ceria oxide (CeO2) catalysts is the subject of our research. The density functional theory (DFT) calculation was used, and its results were applied as a data set to train several ML algorithms. Gibbs free energy (&#916;G) was simulated for all TMs such as Ni, Fe, Cu, Co, Mo, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ag, Pt, Zr, and Ti and used as the goal of CO2 adsorption prediction using ML algorithms. The XGBoost algorithm provided satisfactory predictions of &#916;G using different transition metals and bond energy at different adsorption temperatures on the catalysts. The effective role of Cu, Pt, Fe, and Ni in all temperature ranges regarding the increase of CO2 adsorption energy was evident. The best CO2 adsorption efficiency will be achieved by Ni at temperatures below 300 K and Cu at temperatures over 300 K. Evaluation of new catalysts using prediction findings and correlations between complex DFT simulation parameters demonstrates the potential of ML as a powerful tool for industry development.</description>
      <author>Hossein Mashhadimoslem, Peyman Karimi, Mohammad Ali Abdol, Kourosh E. Zanganeh, Ahmed Shafeen, Ali A. AlHammadi, Ali Elkamel</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c01200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Proximity to Energetics: Unveiling the Hidden Compass of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00761</link>
      <description>Arun Karmakar, Mahendiran Durairaj, Ragunath Madhu, Aditi De, Hariharan N. Dhandapani, Michelle J. S. Spencer, Subrata Kundu, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399667613

                The Volmer&#8211;Tafel (VT) and Volmer&#8211;Heyrovsky (VH) mechanisms were believed to be determined solely by the proximity of adsorbed hydrogen atoms on metallic surfaces for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, recent investigations challenge this notion, particularly with catalysts such as Au and Ag, where VH pathways are observed despite the close hydrogen atom distance. This study investigates the influence of free energy on hydrogen adsorption (&#916;GH*) and active site density on HER pathways, incorporating the consideration of the rate-determining step (RDS). Contrary to previous assumptions, it is found that &#916;GH* plays a pivotal role, with VT pathways favored when &#916;GH* approaches zero, and while VH pathways occurs in other cases, irrespective of active site density. This inclusive analysis, integrating both thermodynamic and energetic considerations with experimental and theoretical support, sheds new light on the mechanistic intricacies of the HER, challenging conventional paradigms and providing insights that are crucial for catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Arun Karmakar, Mahendiran Durairaj, Ragunath Madhu, Aditi De, Hariharan N. Dhandapani, Michelle J. S. Spencer, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium&#8208;Based Alkaline Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400838</link>
      <description>Qingqing Lv, Di Liu, Wei Zhu, Zhongbin Zhuang, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399678533

                Abstract The hydroxide exchange membrane fuel cells (HEMFCs) are promising but lack of high&#8208;performance anode hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) electrocatalysts. The platinum group metals (PGMs) have the HOR activity in alkaline medium two to three orders of magnitude lower than those in acid, leading to the high required PGMs amount on anode to achieve high HEMFC performance. The mechanism study demonstrates the hydrogen binding energy of the catalyst determines the alkaline HOR kinetics, and the adsorbed OH and water on the catalyst surface promotes HOR. Iridium (Ir) has a unique advantage for alkaline HOR due to its similar hydrogen binding energy to Pt and enhanced adsorption of OH. However, the HOR activity of Ir/C is still unsatisfied in practical HEMFC applications. Further fine tuning the adsorption of the intermediate on Ir&#8208;based catalysts is of great significance to improve their alkaline HOR activity, which can be reasonably realized by structure design and composition regulation. In this concept, we address the current understanding about the alkaline HOR mechanism and summarize recent advances of Ir&#8208;based electrocatalysts with enhanced alkaline HOR activity. We also discuss the perspectives and challenges on Ir&#8208;based electrocatalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Qingqing Lv, Di Liu, Wei Zhu, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combination of Co Single Atom and MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Antisite Defect for Efficient Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Methanation: A Rational Design at Electronic Scale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400328</link>
      <description>Xiangyu Gao, Tong&#8208;Hui Wang, Zi Wen, Q. Jiang, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399679298

                Abstract Methane, the simplest hydrocarbon, has a high energy density and is widely used as chemical feedstocks or fuels. Converting CO 2 to methane through electrochemical reduction offers a promising strategy for managing the global carbon balance, but is a challenge due to the lack of effective electrocatalysts. Herein, the Co single atom catalyst supported by MoS 2 antisite defect (Co&#8208;Mo S2 ) is designed from both the activity and selectivity aspects. By virtue of i) moderately electron&#8208;deficient state (Co &#948;+ ) ensuring efficient CO 2 activation and HER suppression; ii) the strong adsorption capability for intermediate enhancing selectivity; iii) the single atomic active site avoiding the formation of C 2 products, Co&#8208;Mo S2 could selectively convert CO 2 to CH 4 with a limiting potential of &#8722;0.45 V vs . RHE, which outperforms most of the present catalysts, and is expected to be a promising substitution for Cu&#8208;based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiangyu Gao, Tong&#8208;Hui Wang, Zi Wen, Q. Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring mesoscopic mass transport effects on electrocatalytic selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01177-6</link>
      <description>Hendrik H. Heenen, Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa Jane Bukas, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399679690

                Abstract Electrocatalytic selectivity is often discussed at the atomic level on the basis of the active site, while ignoring more subtle effects of mesoscopic mass transport. Here we show how transport controls selectivity through the exchange of surface-bound reaction intermediates between the electrode and bulk electrolyte. We argue that the arising kinetic competition changes with the catalyst&#8217;s surface area and can become relevant for technologically important reactions including, for example, different products during the electrochemical CO 2 reduction on Cu-based catalysts. Combining microkinetic and transport modelling in a multi-scale approach, we specifically explore and quantify this effect for various showcase examples in the experimental literature. Despite its simplicity, our model correctly reproduces selectivity trends with respect to catalyst roughness on all meso-, micro- and atomic scales. The resulting insight provides an alternative or, at least, complementary explanation to changes in electrocatalytic selectivity that have otherwise been attributed to nano-structuring of active sites or electronic effects due to doping or alloying.</description>
      <author>Hendrik H. Heenen, Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa Jane Bukas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01177-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab-Initio Simulation of Luminescence Spectra in Solids: Hylight, an Easy-to-Use Post-Processing Software</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4864809</link>
      <description>Th&#233;o Cavignac, St&#233;phane Jobic, Camille Latouche, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399679758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Th&#233;o Cavignac, St&#233;phane Jobic, Camille Latouche</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4864809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergetic Effects of Strain Engineering and Carbon Vacancy Modification on Ti&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;n&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;+1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;n&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; MXene for Promising Catalytic Activity of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00779</link>
      <description>C. L. Wang, Xiaodan Hai, Hao Wang, Yongshun Song, Zhang Wan, Yuqi Yang, Ping Huai, Yaru Yin, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399682489

                Developing efficient and low-cost catalysts is crucial to hydrogen generation through water electrolysis. Oxygen-functionalized titanium carbide MXene holds tremendous potential in catalyzing the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, appropriate modulation approaches aiming at optimizing the HER performance of these MXenes have not been systematically investigated. In this work, density functional theory was employed to screen the optimal HER operating conditions of Tin+1CnO2 (n = 1&#8211;3) by introducing carbon (C) vacancy modification coupled with strain engineering. Terminal oxygen atoms of pristine Ti2CO2 are identified as excellent reactive sites at relatively low hydrogen coverage, while those of Ti3C2O2 and Ti4C3O2 can reach an ideal catalytic state at high hydrogen coverage. An effective fine-tuning of reactive sites on these pristine MXenes can be achieved by exerting a biaxial strain. Besides, C vacancy can breed its nearest neighbor O atoms as active sites for Ti3C2O2 and Ti4C3O2, and their intrinsically excessive hydrogen adsorption would be weakened with the Gibbs free energies regulated extremely close to 0 eV. Detailed analyses indicate that more electrons are transferred to O atoms adjacent to the introduced C vacancy with the O-2p band center downshifting toward lower energy, thus weakening MXenes' capability in capturing hydrogen. Taken together, by collaborating biaxial strain with a C vacancy, Ti3C2O2 and Ti4C3O2 can perform with more outstanding reactive sites at a wider hydrogen coverage, while Ti2CO2 can perform only at low coverage. Our theoretical results point out reasonable regulation strategies for the desirable HER catalytic performance of Tin+1CnO2.</description>
      <author>C. L. Wang, Xiaodan Hai, Hao Wang, Yongshun Song, Zhang Wan, Yuqi Yang, Ping Huai, Yaru Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lithium-coupled electron transfer reactions of nano-confined WOx within Zr-based metal&#8211;organic framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1427536</link>
      <description>Hafsa Abdul Ghuffar, Hyunho Noh, Frontiers in chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399690487

                Interfacial charge transfer reactions involving cations and electrons are fundamental to (photo/electro) catalysis, energy storage, and beyond. Lithium-coupled electron transfer (LCET) at the electrode-electrolyte interfaces of lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) is a preeminent example to highlight the importance of charge transfer in modern-day society. The thermodynamics of LCET reactions define the minimal energy for charge/discharge of LIBs, and yet, these parameters are rarely available in the literature. Here, we demonstrate the successful incorporation of tungsten oxides (WO x ) within a chemically stable Zr-based metal&#8722;organic framework (MOF), MOF-808. Cyclic voltammograms (CVs) of the composite, WO x @MOF-808, in Li + -containing acetonitrile (MeCN)-based electrolytes showed an irreversible, cathodic Faradaic feature that shifted in a Nernstian fashion with respect to the Li + concentration, i.e., &#8764;59 mV/log [(Li + )]. The Nernstian dependence established 1:1 stoichiometry of Li + and e &#8722; . Using the standard redox potential of Li +/0 , the apparent free energy of lithiation of WO x @MOF-808 (&#916;G app,Li ) was calculated to be &#8722;36 &#177; 1 kcal mol &#8722;1 . &#916;G app,Li is an intrinsic parameter of WO x @MOF-808, and thus by deriving the similar reaction free energies of other metal oxides, their direct comparisons can be achieved. Implications of the reported measurements will be further contrasted to proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) reactions on metal oxides.</description>
      <author>Hafsa Abdul Ghuffar, Hyunho Noh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1427536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering single-atom catalysts on triazine-based covalent organic frameworks for enhanced photocatalytic performance in N2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153133</link>
      <description>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Xinyue Xu, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanxia Li, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Qiang Chen, Rongjian Sa, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399693195

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Xinyue Xu, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanxia Li, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Qiang Chen, Rongjian Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density functional theory study of transition metal dual-atom anchored phthalocyanine as high-performance electrocatalysts for carbon dioxide reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160532</link>
      <description>Zhenzhen Wang, Aling Ma, Zhiyi Liu, Zongpeng Ding, Yushan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399697037

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenzhen Wang, Aling Ma, Zhiyi Liu, Zongpeng Ding, Yushan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on fundamentals for designing hydrogen evolution electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234856</link>
      <description>M. A. Qadeer, Xiaoxue Zhang, Muhammad Asim Farid, Muhammad Tanveer, Yue Yan, Shangfeng Du, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, M.N. Tahir, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Journal of power sources. 613(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399699147

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. A. Qadeer, Xiaoxue Zhang, Muhammad Asim Farid, Muhammad Tanveer, Yue Yan, Shangfeng Du, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, M.N. Tahir, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Nickel on Iridium&#8211;Ruthenium Structure and Activity for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction under Acidic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.4c00025</link>
      <description>Erlend Bertheussen, Simon Pitscheider, Susan Cooper, Rebecca Pittkowski, Katrine L. Svane, Aline Bornet, Erik Wisaeus, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz, Christian Kalles&#248;e, Christoffer M&#248;lleskov Pedersen, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399699268

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) is a promising technology to produce hydrogen directly from renewable electricity sources due to its high power density and potential for dynamic operation. Widespread application of PEMWE is, however, currently limited due to high cost and low efficiency, for which high loading of expensive iridium catalyst and high OER overpotential, respectively, are important reasons. In this study, we synthesize highly dispersed IrRu nanoparticles (NPs) supported on antimony-doped tin oxide (ATO) to maximize catalyst utilization. Furthermore, we study the effect of adding various amounts of Ni to the synthesis, both in terms of catalyst structure and OER activity. Through characterization using various X-ray techniques, we determine that the presence of Ni during synthesis yields significant changes in the structure of the IrRu NPs. With no Ni present, metallic IrRu NPs were synthesized with Ir-like structure, while the presence of Ni leads to the formation of IrRu oxide particles with rutile/hollandite structure. There are also clear indications that the presence of Ni yields smaller particles, which can result in better catalyst dispersion. The effect of these differences on OER activity was also studied through rotating disc electrode measurements. The IrRu-supported catalyst synthesized with Ni exhibited OER activity of up to 360 mA mgPGM&#8211;1 at 1.5 V vs RHE. This is &#8764;7 times higher OER activity than the best-performing IrOx benchmark reported in the literature and more than twice the activity of IrRu-supported catalyst synthesized without Ni. Finally, density functional theory (DFT) calculations were performed to further elucidate the origin of the observed activity enhancement, showing no improvement in intrinsic OER activity for hollandite Ir and Ru compared to the rutile structures. We, therefore, hypothesize that the increased activity measured for the IrRu supported catalyst synthesized with Ni present is instead due to increased electrochemical surface area.</description>
      <author>Erlend Bertheussen, Simon Pitscheider, Susan Cooper, Rebecca Pittkowski, Katrine L. Svane, Aline Bornet, Erik Wisaeus, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz, Christian Kalles&#248;e, Christoffer M&#248;lleskov Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.4c00025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study of the electrochemical CO2 reduction by Sc to Ni single atom catalysts implanted on the pristine and N-doped-H4,4,4-graphyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132225</link>
      <description>Azadeh Masiha, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani, Fuel. 372(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399702713

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Azadeh Masiha, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanotubes and other nanostructures of VS2, WS2, and MoS2: Structural effects on the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmt.2024.102288</link>
      <description>Sunil R. Kadam, K. Manjunath, Saptarshi Ghosh, M. B. Sreedhara, Alevtina Neyman, Alexander Upcher, E. Roth, Lothar Houben, Alla Zak, Andrey N. Enyashin, Ronen Bar&#8208;Ziv, Maya Bar&#8208;Sadan, Applied materials today. 39(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399703633

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sunil R. Kadam, K. Manjunath, Saptarshi Ghosh, M. B. Sreedhara, Alevtina Neyman, Alexander Upcher, E. Roth, Lothar Houben, Alla Zak, Andrey N. Enyashin, Ronen Bar&#8208;Ziv, Maya Bar&#8208;Sadan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmt.2024.102288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into efficient oxygen evolution reaction using non-noble metal single-atom catalysts on W2CO2 MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02838-y</link>
      <description>Jing Zhou, Zhen Han, Shu Zhao, Tao Yang, De-Zhen Yan, Haijun Yu, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399707735

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhou, Zhen Han, Shu Zhao, Tao Yang, De-Zhen Yan, Haijun Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02838-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customized Electronic Modulations of Transition Metal Chalcogenide Electrodes Via Heterointerfacing/High&#8208;Valence Doping Toward High&#8208;Performance Water Electrolysis with Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405262</link>
      <description>Xinyu Qin, Bingyi Yan, Tianyu Chen, Zixuan Teng, Deok Ki Cho, Andi Haryanto, Heon Kil Lim, Chan Woo Lee, Yuanzhe Piao, Lin Xu, Jin Young Kim, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399708438

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting offers an advancing approach to producing highly pure hydrogen and oxygen, motivated by the prevalence of a low&#8208;carbon economy and the goal of a sustainable future. The customized modulation of electronic structures enables the electrocatalyst to directionally promote hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is a promising shortcut to overall water splitting (OWS). Herein, 3D homologous WSeS/CoSeS heterojunction nanoarrays (WSeS/CoSeS NAs) and W&#8208;doped CoSeS nanoarrays (W&#8208;CoSeS NAs) are investigated. Abundant heterointerfaces within WSeS/CoSeS NAs facilitate HER kinetics, boosting mass diffusivity, and increasing carrier separation and transfer process. High&#8208;valence W 6+ doping into CoSeS prevents phase separation and stabilizes Co sites by charge offset effect, leading to enhanced OER. Consequently, the WSeS/CoSeS NAs and W&#8208;CoSeS NAs reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at an overpotential of 43.8 and 233.3 mV in 1.0 m KOH electrolyte for HER and OER, respectively. Moreover, when asymmetrically engaged as an electrolyzer, this configuration exhibits extraordinary electrocatalytic performances (cell voltage of 1.51 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) with satisfying stability and mechanical robustness (over 1000 h at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 ). The modulation and manufacture of reaction&#8208;property&#8208;oriented materials are experimentally and theoretically validated potential, illuminating the light of inspiration for multiple applications.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Qin, Bingyi Yan, Tianyu Chen, Zixuan Teng, Deok Ki Cho, Andi Haryanto, Heon Kil Lim, Chan Woo Lee, Yuanzhe Piao, Lin Xu, Jin Young Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homogeneous In&#8208;Plane Lattice Strain Enabling d&#8208;Band Center Modulation and Efficient d&#8211;&#960; Interaction for an Ag&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; Cathode Catalyst With Ultralong Cycle Life in Li&#8208;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401509</link>
      <description>Han Yu, Guoliang Zhang, Dongmei Zhang, Ruonan Yang, Xia Li, Xiuqi Zhang, Gang Lian, Hua Hou, Zhanhu Guo, Chuanxin Hou, Xiaoyang Yang, Feng Dang, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399708604

                Abstract Although lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries (LOBs) hold great promise as future energy storage systems, they are impeded by insulated discharge product Li 2 O 2 and sluggish oxygen reduction reaction/oxygen evolution revolution (ORR/OER) kinetics. The application of a highly efficient cathode catalyst determines the LOBs performance. The d&#8208;band modulation and catalytic kinetics promotion are important concept guidelines for the performance enhancement of cathode catalysts. In this work, the homogeneous in&#8208;plane distortion&#8208;derived synergistic catalytic capability of an Ag 2 Mo 2 O 7 catalyst with modulated d&#8208;band centers and promoted ORR/OER kinetics is demontrated. The uniform elongation of Ag&#9472;O bonds and compression of Mo&#9472;O bonds in (020) plane leads to d&#8208;band splitting and d&#8208;band center optimization and delivers improved adsorption behavior for high ORR/OER capability. Furthermore, the spatial and energy overlap of Ag d xz and O 2 anti&#8208;bonding &#960; * orbitals facilitate electron injection during ORR process and reduce the energy barrier for charge transfer and O 2 desorption during OER process, accelerating the ORR/OER kinetics. As a result, the (020) plane&#8208;exposed Ag 2 Mo 2 O 7 cathode exhibits ultralong cycle stability of 817 cycles at 500 mA g &#8722;1 and large specific discharge/charge capacities of 15898/15180 mAh g &#8722;1 . This work provides facile concept guidance for optimizing catalytic capability through controlled lattice distortion in cathode catalysts for LOBs.</description>
      <author>Han Yu, Guoliang Zhang, Dongmei Zhang, Ruonan Yang, Xia Li, Xiuqi Zhang, Gang Lian, Hua Hou, Zhanhu Guo, Chuanxin Hou, Xiaoyang Yang, Feng Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficient photocatalytic performance of Z-scheme BTe/HfS2 heterostructure for H2O splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115606</link>
      <description>Lan He, Xing Long, Liyan Wang, Cheng Mi, Chaopeng Zhang, Keping Ma, Liang She, Ming Yu, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399710354

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lan He, Xing Long, Liyan Wang, Cheng Mi, Chaopeng Zhang, Keping Ma, Liang She, Ming Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid photothermal reduction-derived Pt1.6Ni nanoalloys embedded in laser-induced graphene for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.063</link>
      <description>Seung Geun Jo, Yoo-Kyum Shin, Min&#8208;Ho Seo, Jung Woo Lee, International journal of hydrogen energy. 77(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399712029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seung Geun Jo, Yoo-Kyum Shin, Min&#8208;Ho Seo, Jung Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure evolution of Cu3Pd single-particles under CO2 hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153208</link>
      <description>Changcheng Xu, Shaobo Han, Qiao Zhao, Shuang Liu, Wei Liu, Yong Li, Wenjie Shen, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399715717

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changcheng Xu, Shaobo Han, Qiao Zhao, Shuang Liu, Wei Liu, Yong Li, Wenjie Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic Molecular Volcano Plots for Enhanced Catalyst Selectivity and Activity Predictions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01175</link>
      <description>Thanapat Worakul, Rub&#233;n Laplaza, Shubhajit Das, Matthew D. Wodrich, Cl&#233;mence Corminb&#339;uf, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399722609

                Molecular volcano plots, which facilitate the rapid prediction of the activity and selectivity of prospective catalysts, have emerged as powerful tools for computational catalysis. Here, we integrate microkinetic modeling into the volcano plot framework to develop "microkinetic molecular volcano plots". The resulting unified computational framework allows the influence of important reaction parameters, including temperature, reaction time, and concentration, to be quickly incorporated and more complex situations, such as off-cycle resting states and coupled catalytic cycles, to be tackled. Compared to previous generations of molecular volcanoes, these microkinetic counterparts offer a more comprehensive understanding of catalytic behavior, in which selectivity and product ratios can be explicitly determined by tracking the evolution of each product concentration over time. This is demonstrated by examining two case studies, rhodium-catalyzed hydroformylation and metal-catalyzed hydrosilylation, in which the unique insights provided by microkinetic modeling, as well as the ability to simultaneously screen catalysts and reaction conditions, are highlighted. To facilitate the construction of these plots/maps, we introduce mikimo, a Python program that seamlessly integrates with our previously developed automated volcano builder, volcanic.</description>
      <author>Thanapat Worakul, Rub&#233;n Laplaza, Shubhajit Das, Matthew D. Wodrich, Cl&#233;mence Corminb&#339;uf</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrocatalytic Urea Formation from Gas Pollutants on Heteronuclear Dual-Metal Atom Anchored N-Doped Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01378</link>
      <description>Lu Song, Jiadi Ying, Tiancun Liu, Xu Jian, Qianqian Wang, Min Guo, Qi Shen, Yong Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399725574

                The electrochemical synthesis of urea under mild conditions is considered a promising alternative to the harsh industrial Haber-Bosch process. However, the development of highly active and selective electrocatalysts remains a formidable challenge. In this study, a novel mechanism for urea synthesis on dual-atom catalysts (DACs) using two gas pollutants (NO and CO) is proposed based on density functional theory (DFT) calculations. It is found that urea can be synthesized through consecutive C&#8211;N coupling and hydrogenation steps on heteronuclear DACs, in which the stable adsorption of NO and CO on DACs significantly contributes to the excellent performance for urea formation. Notably, only CoZn, CoCu, and FeZn@N6/C can continuously accept proton&#8211;electron and ultimately achieve urea formation, exhibiting low limiting potentials of &#8722;0.27, &#8722;0.30, and &#8722;0.60 V, respectively. Furthermore, it is also determined that an alternative mechanism is preferable on three DACs. Moreover, competitive hydrogen evolution reaction, as well as reductions of CO and NO reductions, can be effectively suppressed, thereby endowing high selectivity for urea generation. Importantly, this study not only advances a novel mechanism for urea production utilizing gas pollutants but also broadens the applicability of DACs in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Lu Song, Jiadi Ying, Tiancun Liu, Xu Jian, Qianqian Wang, Min Guo, Qi Shen, Yong Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conjugated Microporous Polymer Derived Hierarchically Porous N-Rich Nanocarbon as a Durable Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Zn-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4868072</link>
      <description>Lunjie Liu, Zian Xu, Yu Xia, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Qiong&#8208;Hua Jin, Baobing Zheng, Chongxuan Liu, Shaoqing Chen, Z. Zhang, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399729859

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lunjie Liu, Zian Xu, Yu Xia, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Qiong&#8208;Hua Jin, Baobing Zheng, Chongxuan Liu, Shaoqing Chen, Z. Zhang, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4868072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-based materials for electrocatalytic CO2 to alcohols: Reaction mechanism, catalyst categories, and regulation strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.06.008</link>
      <description>Yaru Lei, Yue Niu, Xiaolong Tang, Xiangtao Yu, Xiubing Huang, Xiaoxi Lin, Honghong Yi, Shunzheng Zhao, Jingjing Jiang, Jiyue Zhang, Feifei Gao, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399730927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaru Lei, Yue Niu, Xiaolong Tang, Xiangtao Yu, Xiubing Huang, Xiaoxi Lin, Honghong Yi, Shunzheng Zhao, Jingjing Jiang, Jiyue Zhang, Feifei Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.06.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Principles Energetic Span Analysis of the Activity of Transition Metal Catalysts for N2O Decomposition: The Reversal of Descriptor Roles in the Presence of NO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114892</link>
      <description>Gunjana Yadav, Abhishek Khetan, Catalysis today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399732840

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gunjana Yadav, Abhishek Khetan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Supported Metal Dual-Atom Site Catalyst for Oxygen Reduction: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700022</link>
      <description>Xianjun Chen, C. F. Xu, Feng He, Minggang Huang, Hua Ji, Russian journal of electrochemistry. 60(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399739457

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianjun Chen, C. F. Xu, Feng He, Minggang Huang, Hua Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-block germanenes as a promising electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211907</link>
      <description>Pengju Wang, Weiyi Xia, Nanshu Liu, Wei Pei, Si Zhou, Yusong Tu, Jijun Zhao, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399740280

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), a pivotal process in hydrogen fuel cells crucial for enhancing fuel cell performance through suitable catalysts, remains a challenging aspect of development. This study explores the catalytic potential of germanene on Al (111), taking advantage of the successful preparation of stable reconstructed germanene layers on Al (111) and the excellent catalytic performance exhibited by germanium-based nanomaterials. Through first-principles calculations, we demonstrate that the O2 molecule can be effectively activated on both freestanding and supported germanene nanosheets, featuring kinetic barriers of 0.40 and 0.04 eV, respectively. The presence of the Al substrate not only significantly enhances the stability of the reconstructed germanene but also preserves its exceptional ORR catalytic performance. These theoretical findings offer crucial insights into the substrate-mediated modulation of germanene stability and catalytic efficiency, paving the way for the design of stable and efficient ORR catalysts for future applications.</description>
      <author>Pengju Wang, Weiyi Xia, Nanshu Liu, Wei Pei, Si Zhou, Yusong Tu, Jijun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes as Electrocatalysts for Energy Conversion Applications: Advances and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400033</link>
      <description>Mohamed El Ouardi, Omar Ait Layachi, Badr&#8208;Eddine Channab, Ayoub El Idrissi, Amal BaQais, Madjid Arab, Mohamed Zbair, Mohamed Saadi, Hassan Ait Ahsaine, Advanced energy and sustainability research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399756246

                Hydrogen as a potential future energy source provides a number of benefits in terms of sustainability, high energy density, and zero emissions. The production of hydrogen via water splitting is regarded as the cleanest and sustainable process. In contrast, fossil fuel combustion causes significant environmental problems through the production and release of secondary gases such as NO x , SO 2 , and CO 2 . It is vital to focus on reducing these harmful gases. CO 2 , a major pollutant produced by the combustion of fossil fuels and various human activities, plays a central role in the greenhouse effect and contributes to global warming. It is therefore imperative to actively eliminate and mitigate CO 2 levels to preserve the global environment. MXenes and MXene&#8208;based catalysts exhibit both outstanding hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance and CO 2 reduction. In this review, recent progress is systematically examined and discussed in the preparation and utilization of MXenes as catalysts for HER and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR). The discussion begins with a concise overview of the fabrication and characteristics of MXenes, followed by a comprehensive exploration of their efficacy as catalysts for HER and CO 2 RR.</description>
      <author>Mohamed El Ouardi, Omar Ait Layachi, Badr&#8208;Eddine Channab, Ayoub El Idrissi, Amal BaQais, Madjid Arab, Mohamed Zbair, Mohamed Saadi, Hassan Ait Ahsaine</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Amorphous Molybdenum Sulfide Thin Film Electrocatalysts: Trade-Off between Specific Activity and Microscopic Porosity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06308</link>
      <description>Thom R. Harris-Lee, Tom Turvey, Gunani Jayamaha, Myunghee Kang, Frank Marken, Andrew L. Johnson, Jie Zhang, Cameron L. Bentley, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399758517

                Amorphous molybdenum sulfide (a-MoSx) is a promising candidate to replace noble metals as electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in electrochemical water splitting. So far, understanding of the activity of a-MoSx in relation to its physical (e.g., porosity) and chemical (e.g., Mo/S bonding environments) properties has mostly been derived from bulk electrochemical measurements, which provide limited information about electrode materials that possess microscopic structural heterogeneities. To overcome this limitation, herein, scanning electrochemical cell microscopy (SECCM) has been deployed to characterize the microscopic electrochemical activity of a-MoSx thin films (ca. 200 nm thickness), which possess a significant three-dimensional structure (i.e., intrinsic porosity) when produced by electrodeposition. A novel two-step SECCM protocol is designed to quantitatively determine spatially resolved electrochemical activity and electrochemical surface area (ECSA) within a single, high-throughput measurement. It is shown for the first time that although the highest surface area (e.g., most porous) regions of the a-MoSx film possess the highest total activity (measured by the electrochemical current), they do not possess the highest specific activity (measured by the ECSA-normalized current density). Instead, the areas of highest specific activity are localized at/around circular structures, coined "pockmarks", which are tens to hundreds of micrometers in size and ubiquitous to a-MoSx films produced by electrodeposition. By coupling this technique with structural and elemental composition analysis techniques (scanning electron microscopy, energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy) and correlating ECSA with activity and specific activity across SECCM scans, this work furthers the understanding of structure&#8211;activity relations in a-MoSx and highlights the importance of local measurements for the systematic and rational design of thin film catalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Thom R. Harris-Lee, Tom Turvey, Gunani Jayamaha, Myunghee Kang, Frank Marken, Andrew L. Johnson, Jie Zhang, Cameron L. Bentley</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Exploration of the Origin of Alkaline Dependence in the Oxidation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural Catalyzed by NiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00940</link>
      <description>Si Wang, Haisong Feng, Tianyong Liu, Yuan Deng, Meng Zhang, Sylvia Zhao, Juan Han, Xin Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399760359

                Alkaline dependence is a common phenomenon in the electrochemical oxidation of biomass, and investigating the influence of alkalinity on the oxidation mechanisms is crucial for enhancing both the activity and the selectivity of biomass oxidation. Herein, we constructed five NiO2Hx catalysts under different alkaline environments (pH &#8776; 9&#8211;13) and employed density functional theory methods to investigate the reaction mechanisms of the selective oxidation of the biomass platform molecule 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF). The origin of alkaline dependence in HMF electrochemical oxidation was analyzed, and the results indicate that the catalyst alkalinity determines the oxidation pathway of HMF to 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid: under weak alkalinity (pH &#8776; 9&#8211;11), the adsorption and activation of the alcohol group in HMF are more favorable, resulting in preferential oxidation of the alcohol group; under strong alkalinity (pH &#8776; 11&#8211;13), the aldehyde group of HMF is more prone to adsorb and activate on the catalyst surface, resulting in a predominant aldehyde oxidation. With the increase in the alkalinity of NiO2Hx, there is a decrease of H atom coverage and an increase in the valence state of Ni, resulting in a transformation in the preferential oxidation pathway of HMF from the alcohol group to the aldehyde group as well as a transition in the oxidation mechanism from direct oxidation to indirect oxidation. NiOOH under moderately alkaline environment effectively reduces the Gibbs free energy change for C&#8211;H/O&#8211;H bonds cleavage, lowering the reaction energy. It significantly enhances the oxidation ability of alcohol and aldehyde groups, exhibiting the highest catalytic performance in the conversion of HMF to FDCA. The study not only provide a comprehensive explanation for the alkaline dependence of HMF oxidation but also offer guidance on how to rationally design catalysts for improving oxidative performance through alkalinity adjustments.</description>
      <author>Si Wang, Haisong Feng, Tianyong Liu, Yuan Deng, Meng Zhang, Sylvia Zhao, Juan Han, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening transition metal and nonmetal atoms co-doped graphyne as efficient single-atom catalysts for nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153275</link>
      <description>Shulong Li, Ming Peng, Yu Song, Yutao Chen, Liang Qiao, Bo Wang, Yong Zhao, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399761233

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shulong Li, Ming Peng, Yu Song, Yutao Chen, Liang Qiao, Bo Wang, Yong Zhao, Li&#8208;Yong Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Ions Synergistic Bilayer H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Pillared MXene Directing In Situ Ordered Embedding Growth of Highly Efficient NiFe Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408303</link>
      <description>Zhongjie Qiu, Jiayan Wu, Baolin Zhang, Hui&#8208;Hua Song, Zhiming Cui, Zhenxing Liang, Li Du, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399764220

                Abstract Efficient, stable, and inexpensive electrocatalysts are essential to overcome the high overpotential and slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process during water electrolysis applications. 2D transition metal carbides (MXene) show great potential in functional heterogeneous interface engineering for electrocatalytic OER. However, it is still a challenge to regulate the interlayer space and realize the heterogeneous layer&#8208;by&#8208;layer ordered embedding for MXene. Herein, a simple hydrothermal&#8208;assisted strategy is proposed to prepare highly conductive Ti 3 C 2 T x MXene supported by synergized Ni 2+ , Co 2+ , and Fe 3+ with bilayer H 2 O, which significantly enlarges the interlayer distances and improves the interlayer ion concentrations. Benefiting from modulated interface chemistry, embedded metal ions undergo multi&#8208;directional in situ growth on the MXene substrate, thereby forming a stable 0D/2D@2D nano&#8208;hybrid material (NiFe/MX&#8208;HT). Combining density functional theory calculations with experiments demonstrates that MXene offers a framework for electron transfer, enhances the exposure of active sites, modulates the electronic structure, and greatly reduces the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step in the process of OER. Thus, NiFe/MX&#8208;HT requires only 230 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and maintains stability even after operating at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for 150 h. This work offers new insights into exploring various functional MXene&#8208;based heterogeneous materials.</description>
      <author>Zhongjie Qiu, Jiayan Wu, Baolin Zhang, Hui&#8208;Hua Song, Zhiming Cui, Zhenxing Liang, Li Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Hydrogen Evolution Reaction with single-atom catalysts on Ti&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si101.svg" display="inline" id="d1e214"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;B MBenes: Insights from computational screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.141</link>
      <description>Aarti Shukla, International journal of hydrogen energy. 77(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399765830

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aarti Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Electronic and Vibrational Spectroscopy of Electrochemical Transformations on a Metal-Oxide Surface during Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05931</link>
      <description>Tanja Cuk, Michael Paolino, Suryansh Singh, James J. P. Stewart, Xihan Chen, Ilya Vinogradov, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399767385

                Oxygen evolution catalysis fuels the planet through photosynthesis and is a primary means for hydrogen storage in energy technologies. Yet the detection of intermediates of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) central to the catalytic mechanism has been an ongoing challenge. This tutorial and minireview covers the relevance of ultrafast electronic and vibrational spectroscopy of the electrochemical transformations of a metal-oxide surface undergoing OER. Here, we highlight the ultrafast trigger and probes of the electron-doped SrTiO3/electrolyte as the primary example in which light probes across the electromagnetic spectrum have detected intermediate forms. We compare the results to other early transition-metal-oxide surfaces when they exist for select probes and longer timescales. The first part covers how the catalytic reaction is triggered by ultrafast light pulses, describing the semiconducting depletion and electrolyte Helmholtz layers. The second part covers the detection of the intermediates that occur upon electron and proton transfer from an adsorbed water species by transient spectroscopy. Their detection by a broadband visible probe, a mid-infrared evanescent wave, and a coherent acoustic wave respectively targets electronic states, vibrational levels, and lattice strain respectively. One of the aims is a tutorial on how these measurements are made and to what extent they allow for the interpretation of experimental spectra by intermediate configurations predicted by theory. Another aim is to describe what these experiments directly recommend in terms of future efforts to visualize the OER intermediates and their dynamics.</description>
      <author>Tanja Cuk, Michael Paolino, Suryansh Singh, James J. P. Stewart, Xihan Chen, Ilya Vinogradov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review on Highly Efficient Ru-Based Electrocatalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02080</link>
      <description>Jiayi Li, Zeng Ju, Fangchen Zhao, Xinran Sun, Sibo Wang, Xingwen Lu, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399772787

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) technology is seen as the most compatible hydrogen production technology with renewable energy generation. However, the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the scarcity of acid-resistant, high-activity, and low-cost catalysts have seriously hindered the overall efficiency and manufacturing costs of PEMWE. Recently, ruthenium (Ru)-based materials have gradually attracted attention due to their suitable binding strength toward oxygen intermediates and lowest price in the noble metal family. Herein, the great achievements and progress of Ru-based acidic OER electrocatalysts are comprehensively reviewed, which started with a general description of reaction mechanisms and in situ characterization techniques to understand the structure&#8211;activity relationships. Subsequently, some typical strategies to enhance the activity and stability of Ru-based electrocatalysts are highlighted. Insights from synthesis methods, advanced characterizations, intermediate evolution, and theoretical calculations are provided, together with our viewpoints on the daunting challenges and future endeavors of Ru-based OER electrocatalysts for their practical employment.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Li, Zeng Ju, Fangchen Zhao, Xinran Sun, Sibo Wang, Xingwen Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Screening of Tm1tm2/N6-1 (Tm = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Mo) as Effective Electrocatalysts for Nitrogen Fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4868581</link>
      <description>Shujie Yao, Xinlu Cheng, Hong Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399790307

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shujie Yao, Xinlu Cheng, Hong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4868581</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient screening and catalytic mechanism of TM@&#946;-Te for nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115611</link>
      <description>Jiang Ma, Yuhong Huang, Haili Zhao, Fang Ma, Haiping Lin, Xiumei Wei, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399796264

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiang Ma, Yuhong Huang, Haili Zhao, Fang Ma, Haiping Lin, Xiumei Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115611</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation into the performance of tremella-like LaNiO3-NiO composite as an electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05614-1</link>
      <description>Wangran Li, Hui Xu, Yaru Pei, Haibo Lin, Zhong Yang, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399799370

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangran Li, Hui Xu, Yaru Pei, Haibo Lin, Zhong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05614-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Electrocatalytic Performance of Silicene and Single Atom Doped Silicene for HER, OER and ORR Activity Using Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphi.2024.100664</link>
      <description>Deepak Arumugam, J. Sivakumar, Akilesh Muralidharan, Ravi Shankar, Chemical physics impact. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399801984

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deepak Arumugam, J. Sivakumar, Akilesh Muralidharan, Ravi Shankar</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphi.2024.100664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-free Advanced Energy Materials for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Anion-Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124319</link>
      <description>Ramesh K. Singh, John C. Douglin, Vipin Kumar, Polina Tereshchuk, Pietro Giovanni Santori, Eduardo B. Ferreira, Gregory Jerkiewicz, Paulo J. Ferreira, Amir Natan, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Dario R. Dekel, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399802761

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ramesh K. Singh, John C. Douglin, Vipin Kumar, Polina Tereshchuk, Pietro Giovanni Santori, Eduardo B. Ferreira, Gregory Jerkiewicz, Paulo J. Ferreira, Amir Natan, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Dario R. Dekel</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Surface Oxygen Coverage on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction over a CoFeNiCr High-Entropy Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14121058</link>
      <description>Geng Yuan, Luis Ruiz Pestana, Nanomaterials. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399803259

                Developing cost-effective and highly active electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for advancing sustainable energy applications. High-entropy alloys (HEAs) made from earth-abundant transition metals, thanks to their remarkable stability and electrocatalytic performance, provide a promising alternative to expensive electrocatalysts typically derived from noble metals. While pristine HEA surfaces have been theoretically investigated, and the effect of oxygen coverage on conventional metal electrocatalysts has been examined, the impact of surface oxygen coverage on the electrocatalytic performance of HEAs remains poorly understood. To bridge this gap, we employ density functional theory (DFT) calculations to reconstruct the free energy diagram of OER intermediates on CoFeNiCr HEA surfaces with varying oxygen coverages, evaluating their impact on the rate-limiting step and theoretical overpotential. Our findings reveal that increased oxygen coverage weakens the adsorption of HO* and O*, but not HOO*. As a result, the theoretical overpotential for the OER decreases with higher oxygen coverage, and the rate-limiting step shifts from the third oxidation step (HOO* formation) at low coverage to the first oxidation step (HO* formation) at higher coverage.</description>
      <author>Geng Yuan, Luis Ruiz Pestana</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14121058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Electronic Properties and Stability of Rh3 Clusters on Rutile TiO2 for Potential Photocatalytic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14121051</link>
      <description>Moteb Alotaibi, Nanomaterials. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399806083

                Addressing the pressing needs for alternatives to fossil fuel-based energy sources, this research explores the intricate interplay between Rhodium (Rh3) clusters and titanium dioxide (TiO2) to improve photocatalytic water splitting for the generation of eco-friendly hydrogen. This research applies the density functional theory (DFT) coupled with the Hartree&#8211;Fock theory to meticulously examine the structural and electronic structures of Rh3 clusters on TiO2 (110) interfaces. Considering the photocatalytic capabilities of TiO2 and its inherent limitations in harnessing visible light, the potential for metals such as Rh3 clusters to act as co-catalysts is assessed. The results show that triangular Rh3 clusters demonstrate remarkable stability and efficacy in charge transfer when integrated into rutile TiO2 (110), undergoing oxidation in optimal adsorption conditions and altering the electronic structures of TiO2. The subsequent analysis of TiO2 surfaces exhibiting defects indicates that Rh3 clusters elevate the energy necessary for the formation of an oxygen vacancy, thereby enhancing the stability of the metal oxide. Additionally, the combination of Rh3-cluster adsorption and oxygen-vacancy formation generates polaronic and localized states, crucial for enhancing the photocatalytic activity of metal oxide in the visible light range. Through the DFT analysis, this study elucidates the importance of Rh3 clusters as co-catalysts in TiO2-based photocatalytic frameworks, paving the way for empirical testing and the fabrication of effective photocatalysts for hydrogen production. The elucidated impact on oxygen vacancy formation and electronic structures highlights the complex interplay between Rh3 clusters and TiO2 surfaces, providing insightful guidance for subsequent studies aimed at achieving clean and sustainable energy solutions.</description>
      <author>Moteb Alotaibi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14121051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double&#8208;Hollow Au@CdS Yolk@Shell Nanostructures as Superior Plasmonic Photocatalysts for Solar Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402392</link>
      <description>Y.-W. Chen, Yuhi Nakayasu, Yongcheng Lin, Jui&#8208;Cheng Kao, Kai&#8208;Chi Hsiao, Quang Tuyen Le, Keh&#8208;Minn Chang, Ming&#8208;Chung Wu, Jyh&#8208;Pin Chou, Chun&#8208;Wei Pao, Tso&#8208;Fu Mark Chang, Masato Sone, Chun&#8208;Yi Chen, Yu&#8208;Chieh Lo, Yan&#8208;Gu Lin, Akira Yamakata, Yung&#8208;Jung Hsu, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399808555

                Abstract Structural engineering has proven effective in tailoring the photocatalytic properties of semiconductor nanostructures. In this work, a sophisticated double&#8208;hollow yolk@shell nanostructure composed of a plasmonic, mobile, hollow Au nanosphere (HGN) yolk and a permeable, hollow CdS shell is proposed to achieve remarkable solar hydrogen production. The shell thickness of HGN@CdS is finely adjusted from 7.7, 18.4 to 24.5 nm to investigate its influence on the photocatalytic performance. Compared with pure HGN, pure CdS, a physical mixture of HGN and CdS, and a counterpart single&#8208;hollow cit&#8208;Au@CdS yolk@shell nanostructure, HGN@CdS exhibits superior hydrogen production under visible light illumination (&#955; = 400&#8211;700 nm). The apparent quantum yield of hydrogen production reaches 8.2% at 320 nm, 6.2% at 420 nm, and 4.4% at 660 nm. The plasmon&#8208;enhanced activity at 660 nm is exceptional, surpassing the plasmon&#8208;induced photoactivities of the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art plasmonic photocatalysts ever reported. The superiority of HGN@CdS originates from the creation of charge separation state at HGN/CdS heterojunction, the considerably long&#8208;lived hot electrons of plasmonic HGN, the magnified electric field, and the advantageous features of double&#8208;hollow yolk@shell nanostructures. The findings can provide a guideline for the rational design of versatile double&#8208;hollow yolk@shell nanostructures for widespread photocatalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Y.-W. Chen, Yuhi Nakayasu, Yongcheng Lin, Jui&#8208;Cheng Kao, Kai&#8208;Chi Hsiao, Quang Tuyen Le, Keh&#8208;Minn Chang, Ming&#8208;Chung Wu, Jyh&#8208;Pin Chou, Chun&#8208;Wei Pao, Tso&#8208;Fu Mark Chang, Masato Sone, Chun&#8208;Yi Chen, Yu&#8208;Chieh Lo, Yan&#8208;Gu Lin, Akira Yamakata, Yung&#8208;Jung Hsu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Activity of Nitrogen-Deficient hg-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Quantum Dot</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01461</link>
      <description>Khushboo Dange, Vaishali Roondhe, Alok Shukla, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399808778

                The present study investigates the catalytic performance of a hg-C3N4 quantum dot aimed at enhancing electrochemical water splitting using first-principles density functional theory. The size of the considered quantum dot lies within the range reported experimentally (2&#8211;4 nm) [Zhou et al. ACS Nano 2015, 9, 12480]. The nitrogen vacancies are created in the considered hg-C3N4 structure to simulate the realistic scenario as the presence of nitrogen and carbon defects is reported in the synthesized hg-C3N4 quantum dots. First, the structural and vibrational properties are computed to ensure the stability of the nitrogen-deficient hg-C3N4 quantum dots, and subsequently, their electronic and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) properties are investigated. The calculated HER parameters, i.e., adsorption energies, Gibbs free energies, and overpotentials, demonstrate that the considered hg-C3N4 quantum dot with nitrogen vacancies can be used as a moderately effective electrocatalyst for HER performance. We also considered the quantum dot to be dissolved in water and ethanol and find that the overpotential gets drastically reduced to 16 mV for the alcohol-dissolved quantum dot, while some significant reduction is seen for the aqueous solution also. As a result, this study suggests that the nitrogen-deficient hg-C3N4 quantum dots dissolved in ethanol are excellent candidates for catalysis aimed at sustainable hydrogen production via electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Khushboo Dange, Vaishali Roondhe, Alok Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Durable Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers through Suppressed Electrochemical Corrosion of a NiFe&#8211;Graphitic Carbon Shell Anode Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02696</link>
      <description>Young Sang Park, Gwan Hyun Choi, Jiyoon Jung, Cheol&#8208;Hee Ahn, Seung Sang Hwang, Myeong Gyun Nam, Pil J. Yoo, Albert S. Lee, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399812294

                Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) shows potential for hydrogen production using cost-effective nonplatinum group metal (non-PGM) catalysts, achieving high current density performance. However, challenges remain in developing materials, including stable membranes and ionomers under alkaline conditions and non-PGM catalysts that are both high-performing and durable for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This study presents an approach for synthesizing highly crystalline carbon-encapsulated metal nanoparticle networks using a polyphenolic tannic acid precursor and non-PGM NiFe metal cores, creating a durable OER catalyst. The simplified synthetic process introduces graphitic carbon layers (GCLs) to encompass the NiFe catalytic nanoparticles. Rigorous testing over 1100 h of continuous current operation demonstrates the stability of the catalysts, which is attributed to the robust interaction between the catalyst and the carbon support. The enhanced durability is further confirmed through theoretical calculations, showing greater resistance to corrosion in graphitic carbon compared to defective carbon. This study highlights the importance of highly crystalline carbon structures for achieving both high performance and durability in OER catalysts, which are vital for cost-effective AEMWE technologies. The findings contribute significantly to understanding the role of regulating carbon crystalline properties in developing efficient and durable non-PGM OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Young Sang Park, Gwan Hyun Choi, Jiyoon Jung, Cheol&#8208;Hee Ahn, Seung Sang Hwang, Myeong Gyun Nam, Pil J. Yoo, Albert S. Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing electrocatalytic reactions through mapping key intermediates to active sites &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; descriptors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01130e</link>
      <description>Xiaowen Sun, Rafael B. Araujo, Egon Campos dos Santos, Yuanhua Sang, Hong Liu, Xiaowen Yu, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399813249

                This review provides a systematic and comprehensive summary of the relevance of physical and chemical features mapping key reaction intermediates and their applications as descriptors in critical electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Xiaowen Sun, Rafael B. Araujo, Egon Campos dos Santos, Yuanhua Sang, Hong Liu, Xiaowen Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01130e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Searching Materials Space for Hydride Superconductors at Ambient Pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404043</link>
      <description>Tiago F. T. Cerqueira, Yue&#8208;Wen Fang, Ion Errea, Antonio Sanna, Miguel A. L. Marques, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399813464

                Abstract A machine&#8208;learning&#8208;assisted approach is employed to search for superconducting hydrides under ambient pressure within an extensive dataset comprising over 150 000 compounds. The investigation yields &#8776;50 systems with transition temperatures surpassing 20 K, and some even reaching above 70 K. These compounds have very different crystal structures, with different dimensionality, chemical composition, stoichiometry, and arrangement of the hydrogens. Interestingly, most of these systems display slight thermodynamic instability, implying that their synthesis will re quire conditions beyond ambient equilibrium. Moreover, a consistent chemical composition is found in the majority of these systems, which combines alkali or alkali&#8208;earth elements with noble metals. This observation suggests a promising avenue for future experimental investigations into high&#8208;temperature superconductivity within hydrides at ambient pressure.</description>
      <author>Tiago F. T. Cerqueira, Yue&#8208;Wen Fang, Ion Errea, Antonio Sanna, Miguel A. L. Marques</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment regulation breaks the Faradaic efficiency-current density trade-off for electrocatalytic deuteration using D2O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49544-y</link>
      <description>Meng He, Rui Li, Chuanqi Cheng, Cuibo Liu, Bin Zhang, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399814416

                Abstract The high Faradaic efficiency (FE) of the electrocatalytic deuteration of organics with D 2 O at a large current density is significant for deuterated electrosynthesis. However, the FE and current density are the two ends of a seesaw because of the severe D 2 evolution side reaction at nearly industrial current densities. Herein, we report a combined scenario of a nanotip-enhanced electric field and surfactant-modified interface microenvironment to enable the electrocatalytic deuteration of arylacetonitrile in D 2 O with an 80% FE at &#8722;100 mA cm &#8722;2 . The increased concentration with low activation energy of arylacetonitrile due to the large electric field along the tips and the accelerated arylacetonitrile transfer and suppressed D 2 evolution by the surfactant-created deuterophobic microenvironment contribute to breaking the trade-off between a high FE and large current density. Furthermore, the application of our strategy in other deuteration reactions with improved Faradaic efficiencies at &#8722;100 mA cm &#8722;2 rationalizes the design concept.</description>
      <author>Meng He, Rui Li, Chuanqi Cheng, Cuibo Liu, Bin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49544-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;Ab Initio&lt;/i&gt; Studies of Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction for Small Cu Cluster Supported on Polar Substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07445</link>
      <description>Huiru Yang, Wenli Zou, Chunmei Zhang, Aijun Du, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399847413

                Small Cu clusters are excellent candidates for the electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR), and their catalytic performance is expected to be significantly influenced by the interaction between the substrate and cluster. In this study, we systematically investigate the CO2RR for a Cu3 cluster anchored on Janus MoSX (X = Se, Te) substrates using density functional theory calculations. These substrates feature a broken vertical mirror symmetry, which generates spontaneous out-of-plane polarization and offers two distinct polar surfaces to support the Cu3 cluster. Our findings reveal that the CO2RR performance on the Cu3 cluster is strongly influenced by the polarization direction and strength of the MoSX (X = Se, Te) substrates. Notably, the Cu3 cluster supported on the S-terminated MoSTe surface (Cu3(S)@MoSTe) demonstrates the highest CO2RR activity, producing methane. These results underscore the pivotal role of substrate polarization in modulating the binding strength of reactants and reaction intermediates, thereby enhancing the CO2RR efficiency.</description>
      <author>Huiru Yang, Wenli Zou, Chunmei Zhang, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water-hydroxide trapping in cobalt tungstate for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adk9849</link>
      <description>R.A. Mohan Ram, Lu Xia, H. Benzidi, Anku Guha, Viktoria Golovanova, Alba Garz&#243;n Manj&#243;n, David Llorens Rauret, Pol Sanz Berman, Marinos Dimitropoulos, Bernat Mundet, Ernest Pastor, Ver&#243;nica Celorrio, Camilo A. Mesa, Anita Das, Adri&#225;n Pinilla-S&#225;nchez, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jordi Arbiol, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer, Science. 384(6702)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399848834

                The oxygen evolution reaction is the bottleneck to energy-efficient water-based electrolysis for the production of hydrogen and other solar fuels. In proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE), precious metals have generally been necessary for the stable catalysis of this reaction. In this work, we report that delamination of cobalt tungstate enables high activity and durability through the stabilization of oxide and water-hydroxide networks of the lattice defects in acid. The resulting catalysts achieve lower overpotentials, a current density of 1.8 amperes per square centimeter at 2 volts, and stable operation up to 1 ampere per square centimeter in a PEMWE system at industrial conditions (80&#176;C) at 1.77 volts; a threefold improvement in activity; and stable operation at 1 ampere per square centimeter over the course of 600 hours.</description>
      <author>R.A. Mohan Ram, Lu Xia, H. Benzidi, Anku Guha, Viktoria Golovanova, Alba Garz&#243;n Manj&#243;n, David Llorens Rauret, Pol Sanz Berman, Marinos Dimitropoulos, Bernat Mundet, Ernest Pastor, Ver&#243;nica Celorrio, Camilo A. Mesa, Anita Das, Adri&#225;n Pinilla-S&#225;nchez, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jordi Arbiol, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adk9849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Insight into Transition Metal Atoms Anchored on B2c3p As Single-Atom Electrocatalysts for Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4871205</link>
      <description>Pengfei Ma, Fu Zhe, Chaozheng He, Wei Song, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399854237

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Ma, Fu Zhe, Chaozheng He, Wei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4871205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building adaptive active sites in doped-RuO2 to boost acidic water oxidation performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101035</link>
      <description>Susanta Bera, Chem catalysis. 4(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399855134

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Susanta Bera</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient ethylene electrosynthesis through C&#8211;O cleavage promoted by water dissociation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00568-8</link>
      <description>Yongxiang Liang, Anna Klinkova, Rui Kai Miao, Sunpei Hu, Weiyan Ni, Shuzhen Zhang, Yanjiang Liu, Yang Bai, Haoyue Wan, Pengfei Ou, Xiao-Yan Li, Ning Wang, Sungjin Park, Fengwang Li, Jie Zeng, David Sinton, Edward H. Sargent, Nature synthesis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399860902

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongxiang Liang, Anna Klinkova, Rui Kai Miao, Sunpei Hu, Weiyan Ni, Shuzhen Zhang, Yanjiang Liu, Yang Bai, Haoyue Wan, Pengfei Ou, Xiao-Yan Li, Ning Wang, Sungjin Park, Fengwang Li, Jie Zeng, David Sinton, Edward H. Sargent</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00568-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali-assisted polymeric carbon nitride effectively improves the visible-light-driven intrinsic reactivity for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution: A first-principles analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214552</link>
      <description>Huimin Gao, Anqi Shi, Ruilin Guan, Zhang Xin, Xiuyun Zhang, Wang Bing, Yong Pu, Xianghong Niu, Applied physics letters. 124(25)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399861792

                Two-dimensional (2D) polymeric carbon nitride (PCN) materials have drawn broad attention as promising candidates for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution. However, it remains a significant challenge to simultaneously improve the visible light absorption, separation of photogenerated carriers, and activity. Herein, alkali metals doping PCN (e.g., C6N6 and C2N) are systematically investigated based on density functional theory. Different from the conventional notion of doping atoms as active sites, the actual active site is the intrinsic pyridine nitrogen surrounding the alkali metal. Compared to the change of Gibbs free energy value of &#8722;0.45 eV (&#8722;0.60 eV) for pristine C6N6 (C2N), Li or Cs doped PCN decreases to &#8722;0.03 eV (&#8722;0.10 eV) or 0.06 eV (&#8722;0.11 eV), respectively, benefitting from the adjustment of the 3p electronic state occupation for N atoms by charges transfer from alkali metal. Meanwhile, Li or Cs doping not only broadens the absorption of visible light by narrowing the band edge position but also promotes the separation of photogenerated electrons and holes by regulating their spatial separation, which is further confirmed by significant photocurrents for Li or Cs doped PCN based on nonequilibrium Green's function simulation. Our work could provide interesting insights into the mechanistic understanding and the highly efficient design of PCN materials in photocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Huimin Gao, Anqi Shi, Ruilin Guan, Zhang Xin, Xiuyun Zhang, Wang Bing, Yong Pu, Xianghong Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of electrocatalytic activity of Pt-free dual atom-doped graphene for O2 reduction in an alkaline solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-61223-y</link>
      <description>Tahereh Jangjooye Shaldehi, Soosan Rowshanzamir, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399862452

                Abstract Non-precious electrocatalysts as the alternative to Pt have become a hot research area in the last decade due to the suitable catalytic activity in Oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in electrochemical systems. In this work, the density functional theory calculations were investigated to explore the activity of Fe, Cu, and Fe-Cu atoms supported by N-doped graphene as the ORR electrocatalyst for Oxygen-depolarized cathodes (ODCs). To this end, the ORR mechanism was surveyed in detail in the gas and solvent phases. The results show that the solvent phase leads to a higher overpotential and thermodynamic limiting potential. According to the density of states curves, there are strong interactions between metal atom and substrate that can effectively tune the electronics of catalysts. Bader's analysis confirms that, in addition to the single metal atoms, nitrogen atoms have also played a critical role in charge transfer between substrates and oxygen molecules in ORR. It is also predicted that Fe-Cu@NC SAC exhibits the highest catalytic activity which is consistent with thermodynamic limiting potential and theoretical overpotential of &#8722; 0.26 and 0.66 (V vs. SHE), respectively, indicating that this type of catalyst may be a suitable candidate instead of precious metals in oxygen-depolarized cathodes in electrochemical devices.</description>
      <author>Tahereh Jangjooye Shaldehi, Soosan Rowshanzamir</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-61223-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mno2 Nanozyme@Persistent Luminescent Nanoparticles for Dual-Modality Glucose Detection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4856887</link>
      <description>Yue Zhang, Renagul Abdurahman, Yugui Han, Shiji Liu, Rui Zhang, Xue&#8208;Bo Yin, Jie Gao, Shuqi Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399875215

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue Zhang, Renagul Abdurahman, Yugui Han, Shiji Liu, Rui Zhang, Xue&#8208;Bo Yin, Jie Gao, Shuqi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4856887</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
