<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 01:40:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Prospects, Costs, and Risks of Carbon Capture and Storage Implementation in Germany</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100418</link>
      <description>Nicol&#225;s Malz, Pao-Yu Oei, Philipp Herpich, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408733460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicol&#225;s Malz, Pao-Yu Oei, Philipp Herpich</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing CoNiRuIrMn High-entropy Alloy Network for Boosting Electrocatalytic Activity toward Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.120964</link>
      <description>Yan Su, Linfeng Zhang, Weimo Li, Ruikai Qi, Mengxiao Zhong, Meijiao Xu, Wei Song, Xiaofeng Lu, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408735398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Su, Linfeng Zhang, Weimo Li, Ruikai Qi, Mengxiao Zhong, Meijiao Xu, Wei Song, Xiaofeng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.120964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different capture methods for various feed CO2 concentrations and flow rates from flue gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-025-03152-6</link>
      <description>Ph&#7841;m Th&#7883; Lan H&#432;&#417;ng, Y. B. N. Tran, Tuan B.H. Nguyen, Clean Technologies and Environmental Policy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408746088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ph&#7841;m Th&#7883; Lan H&#432;&#417;ng, Y. B. N. Tran, Tuan B.H. Nguyen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10098-025-03152-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D Borophene Nanostructures: Recent Advances in Synthesis, Characterization, and Emerging Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106296</link>
      <description>Maria Batool, Jahangir Ahmad Rather, Akhtar Hussain Malik, Waheed Ahmad Khanday, Waseem Ahmad Wani, Abdul Haleem Wani, Rakesh Bhaskar, Palanisamy Kannan, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408746543

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maria Batool, Jahangir Ahmad Rather, Akhtar Hussain Malik, Waheed Ahmad Khanday, Waseem Ahmad Wani, Abdul Haleem Wani, Rakesh Bhaskar, Palanisamy Kannan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel two-dimensional ZnO materials for enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163068</link>
      <description>Peixian Wang, Bin Song, Gaoling Zhao, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408755952

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peixian Wang, Bin Song, Gaoling Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Supported Annealing for Prediction of Grand Canonical Crystal Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7566/jpsj.94.044802</link>
      <description>Yannick Couzini&#233;, Yuya Seki, Yusuke Nishiya, Hirofumi Nishi, Taichi Kosugi, Shu Tanaka, Yu&#8208;ichiro Matsushita, Journal of the Physical Society of Japan. 94(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408757120

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yannick Couzini&#233;, Yuya Seki, Yusuke Nishiya, Hirofumi Nishi, Taichi Kosugi, Shu Tanaka, Yu&#8208;ichiro Matsushita</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7566/jpsj.94.044802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical Significance of Descriptors to Predict the Band Center of High&#8208;Entropy Nanoalloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70086</link>
      <description>Y&#363;suke Nanba, Michihisa Koyama, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408748740

                ABSTRACT The band center of d orbitals ( d &#8208;band center) has been widely used as an effective descriptor for analyzing material properties. However, in high&#8208;entropy nanoalloys, the diverse atomic environments present challenges in systematically exploring all possible combinations. Due to computational resource limitations, generating a sufficient number of samples is infeasible. Consequently, the d &#8208;band center should be treated as a response variable in machine&#8208;learning models. We calculated the d &#8208;band center for individual atoms and applied supervised learning techniques to identify key factors influencing its behavior. While several factors were identified, their physical significance in predicting d &#8208;band centers remained unclear. To address this issue, we incorporated various interatomic distance terms as descriptors, along with element&#8208;based coordination numbers (ECN). The resulting model closely resembled the overlap integral of the Slater&#8208;type orbital, and the regression coefficients of the ECN exhibited sensitivity to the effective principal quantum number and nuclear charge. Understanding the physical significance of these descriptors is crucial for improving property predictions and facilitating data collection on novel materials.</description>
      <author>Y&#363;suke Nanba, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic transition metal dichalcogenides NixMo1-xSSe as efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction in protic electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135035</link>
      <description>R. Shwetharani, Samriti Mehta, Bhuneshwar Paswan, Itika Kainthla, Sumanth Dongre S, Amitava Banerjee, R. Geetha Balakrishna, Fuel. 394(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408751279

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Shwetharani, Samriti Mehta, Bhuneshwar Paswan, Itika Kainthla, Sumanth Dongre S, Amitava Banerjee, R. Geetha Balakrishna</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-activated oxophilic surface of porous molybdenum carbide nanosheets promotes hydrogen evolution activity in alkaline environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137423</link>
      <description>Yong Li, Weining Song, Teng Gai, Lipeng Wang, Zhen Li, Peng He, Qi Liu, Lawrence Yoon Suk Lee, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408756062

                Molybdenum carbides are promising alternatives to Pt-based catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to their similar d-band electronic configuration. Notably, MoxC exhibits superior HER kinetics in alkaline media compared to acidic conditions, contrasting with Pt-based catalysts. Herein, we present 3D porous &#946;-Mo2C nanosheets, achieving an overpotential of 111 mV at 10 mA cm-2 in 1 M KOH, significantly lower than in acidic environments. Simulations on pristine Mo2C surface reveal that water dissociation poses a higher energy barrier in alkaline media, suggesting that crystal structure alone does not dictate kinetics. Operando attenuated total reflection surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy shows that Mo2C activates interfacial water, generating liquid-like and free water, and facilitates hydroxyl species adsorption, reducing activation energy to below 38.43 &#177; 0.19 kJ/mol. Our findings on the self-activation effect offer insights into the HER mechanism of Mo-based electrocatalysts and guide the design of highly active HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yong Li, Weining Song, Teng Gai, Lipeng Wang, Zhen Li, Peng He, Qi Liu, Lawrence Yoon Suk Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying &#960;-electron delocalization as a universal descriptor for ORR activity in MN4 catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116093</link>
      <description>Miao&#8208;Ying Chen, Jiabo Le, Haoran Wu, Weidong Li, Jianan Zhang, Bang&#8208;An Lu, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408768117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miao&#8208;Ying Chen, Jiabo Le, Haoran Wu, Weidong Li, Jianan Zhang, Bang&#8208;An Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur doping activated metal&#8211;support interaction drives Pt nanoparticles to achieve acid&#8211;base hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08499c</link>
      <description>Yagang Li, Jiaqing Luo, Peilin Liu, Liangkun Zhang, Weiyu Song, Yuechang Wei, Zhen Zhao, Xiao Zhang, Jian Liu, Yuanqing Sun, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408769162

                The sulfur doping strategy activates the interfacial effect, thereby promoting Pt NPs to attain efficient acid&#8211;base hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Yagang Li, Jiaqing Luo, Peilin Liu, Liangkun Zhang, Weiyu Song, Yuechang Wei, Zhen Zhao, Xiao Zhang, Jian Liu, Yuanqing Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08499c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice thermal conductivity in the anharmonic overdamped regime</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.104314</link>
      <description>&#272;or&#273;e Dangi&#263;, Giovanni Caldarelli, Raffaello Bianco, Ivana Savi&#263;, Ion Errea, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408776904

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#272;or&#273;e Dangi&#263;, Giovanni Caldarelli, Raffaello Bianco, Ivana Savi&#263;, Ion Errea</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.104314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spillover Dynamics in Heterogeneous Catalysis on Singe&#8208;Atom Alloys: A Theoretical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.70011</link>
      <description>Shuyu Lin, Rui Xiong, Jun Chen, Sen Lin, Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews Computational Molecular Science. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408778659

                ABSTRACT Recent advances in single&#8208;atom alloy ( SAA ) catalysts provide a unique platform for understanding spillover, due to the well&#8208;defined nature of the active site for dissociative chemisorption. In particular, the use of spilled adsorbates following molecular dissociation on the host metal surface facilitates the generation of high&#8208;value chemicals in subsequent catalytic reactions. Nevertheless, the factors that control the spillover process remain to be fully elucidated. This perspective discusses recent theoretical advances in the spillover dynamics on SAAs , with a particular focus on the dissociation and spillover processes of H 2 and CH 4 . It provides valuable insights into how various factors, such as energy transfer, nuclear quantum effects, gas&#8208;adsorbate interactions, and adsorbate size, impact the diffusion behavior of hydrogen and methyl species on SAA surfaces. The article concludes with a discussion of future prospects. This perspective underscores the significance of spillover dynamics in heterogeneous catalysis, with important implications for improving catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Shuyu Lin, Rui Xiong, Jun Chen, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.70011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Catalytic Selectivity of Reverse Water&#8211;Gas Shift Reaction Catalyzed by Ru/CeO2 Through the Addition of Yttrium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040301</link>
      <description>Alfredo Sol&#237;s-Garc&#237;a, Karina Portillo-Cortez, D. Dom&#237;nguez, S. Fuentes, J.N. D&#237;az de Le&#243;n, T.A. Zepeda, Uriel Caudillo&#8208;Flores, Catalysts. 15(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408778954

                This study reports the synthesis, characterization, and catalytic performance of a series of catalysts of Ru supported on CeO2-Y2O3 composites (Ru/CeYX; X = 0, 33, 66, and 100 wt.% Y2O3) for CO2 hydrogenation. Supported material modification (Y2O3-CeO2), by the Y2O3 incorporation, allowed a change in selectivity from methane to RWGS of the CO2 hydrogenation reaction. This change in selectivity is correlated with the variation in the physicochemical properties caused by Y2O3 addition. X-ray diffraction (XRD) analysis confirmed the formation of crystalline fluorite-phase CeO2 and &#945;-Y2O3. High-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM) and energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS) elemental mapping revealed the formation of a homogeneous CeO2-Y2O3 nanocomposite. As the Y2O3 content increased, the specific surface area, measured by BET, showed a decreasing trend from 106.3 to 51.7 m2 g&#8722;1. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) of Ce3d indicated a similar Ce3+/Ce4+ ratio across all CeO2-containing materials, while the O1s spectra showed a reduction in oxygen vacancies with increasing Y2O3 content, which is attributed to the decreased surface area upon composite formation. Catalytically, the addition of Y2O3 influenced both conversion and selectivity. CO2 conversion decreased with increasing Y2O3 content, with the lowest conversion observed for Ru/CeY100. Regarding selectivity, methane was the dominant product for Ru/CeY0 (pure CeO2), while CO was the main product for Ru/CeY33, Ru/CeY66, and Ru/CeY100, indicating a shift towards the reverse water&#8211;gas shift (RWGS) reaction. The highest RWGS reaction rate was observed with the Ru/CeY33 catalyst under all tested conditions. The observed differences in conversion and selectivity are attributed to a reduction in active sites due to the decrease in surface area and oxygen vacancies, both of which are important for CO2 adsorption. In order to verify the surface species catalytically active for RWGS, the samples were characterized by FTIR spectroscopy under reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Alfredo Sol&#237;s-Garc&#237;a, Karina Portillo-Cortez, D. Dom&#237;nguez, S. Fuentes, J.N. D&#237;az de Le&#243;n, T.A. Zepeda, Uriel Caudillo&#8208;Flores</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Promoting NO electrochemical reduction via N-N coupling by Surface-Adsorbed *NH intermediates on Mo2C nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116097</link>
      <description>Xiang Huang, Xiangting Hu, Jiong Wang, Hu Xu, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408782209

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Huang, Xiangting Hu, Jiong Wang, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedding transition metal atoms in S- modified porphyrin-expanded porphyrin tandem carbon-rich conjugated frameworks for efficient synthesis of C3 sugars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.112333</link>
      <description>Huan Xing, Ling Guo, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408783757

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Xing, Ling Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.112333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sol&#8211;Gel-Synthesized Pt, Ni and Co-Based Electrocatalyst Effects of the Support Type, Characterization, and Possible Application in AEM-URFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/gels11040229</link>
      <description>Elitsa Petkucheva, Borislava Mladenova, Mohsin Muhyuddin, Mariela Dimitrova, G. Borisov, Carlo Santoro, E. Slavcheva, Gels. 11(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408793889

                This study explores the synthesis and characterization of platinum (Pt), nickel (Ni), and cobalt (Co)-based electrocatalysts using the sol&#8211;gel method. The focus is on the effect of different support materials on the catalytic performance in alkaline media. The sol&#8211;gel technique enables the production of highly uniform electrocatalysts, supported on carbon-based substrates, metal oxides, and conductive polymers. Various characterization techniques, including X-ray diffraction (XRD) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM), were used to analyze the structure of the synthesized materials, while their electrochemical properties, which are relevant to their application in unitized regenerative fuel cells (URFCs), were investigated using cyclic voltammetry (CV) and linear sweep voltammetry (LSV). This hydrogen energy-converting device integrates water electrolyzers and fuel cells into a single system, reducing weight, volume, and cost. However, their performance is constrained by the electrocatalyst&#8217;s oxygen bifunctional activity. To improve URFC efficiency, an ideal electrocatalyst should exhibit high oxygen evolution (OER) and oxygen reduction (ORR) activity with a low bifunctionality index (BI). The present study evaluated the prepared electrocatalysts in an alkaline medium, finding that Pt25-Co75/XC72R and Pt75-Co25/N82 demonstrated promising bifunctional activity. The results suggest that these electrocatalysts are well-suited for both electrolysis and fuel cell operation in anion exchange membrane-unitized regenerative fuel cells (AEM-URFCs), contributing to improved round-trip efficiency.</description>
      <author>Elitsa Petkucheva, Borislava Mladenova, Mohsin Muhyuddin, Mariela Dimitrova, G. Borisov, Carlo Santoro, E. Slavcheva</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/gels11040229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy Engineering Activates Cu&#8208;Fe Inertia Center From Prussian Blue Analogs With Micro&#8208;Strains for Oxygen Electrocatalysis in Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.693</link>
      <description>Han Man, Guanyu Chen, Fengmei Wang, Jiafeng Ruan, Yihao Liu, Yang Liu, Fang Fang, Renchao Che, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408806535

                ABSTRACT By the random distribution of metals in a single phase, entropy engineering is applied to construct dense neighboring active centers with diverse electronic and geometric structures, realizing the continuous optimization of multiple primary reactions for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Many catalysts developed through entropy engineering have been built in nearly equimolar ratios to pursue high entropy, hindering the identification of the active sites and potentially diluting the concentration of real active sites while weakening their electronic interactions with reaction intermediates. Herein, this work proposes an entropy&#8208;engineering strategy in metal nanoparticle&#8208;embedded nitrogen carbon electrocatalysts, implemented by entropy&#8208;engineered Prussian blue analogs (PBA) as precursors to enhance the catalytic activity of primary Cu&#8208;Fe active sites. Through the introduction of the micro&#8208;strains driven by entropy engineering, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and geometric phase analysis (GPA) using Lorentz electron microscopy further elucidate the optimization of the adsorption/desorption of intermediates. Furthermore, the multi&#8208;dimensional morphology and the size diminishment of the nanocrystals serve to expand the electrochemical area, maximizing the catalytic activity for both ORR and OER. Notably, the Zn&#8208;air battery assembled with CuFeCoNiZn&#8208;NC operated for over 1300 h with negligible decay. This work presents a paradigm for the design of low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts with entropy engineering for multi&#8208;step reactions.</description>
      <author>Han Man, Guanyu Chen, Fengmei Wang, Jiafeng Ruan, Yihao Liu, Yang Liu, Fang Fang, Renchao Che</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Methanol Oxidation Catalysis by PtNi Nanowires with Controllable Element Distribution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c03303</link>
      <description>Xiaojie Jiang, Zhenyu Zhang, Xing Hu, Xu Zhen, Pei Zhang, Shan Zhu, Feng Liu, Kezhu Jiang, Shijian Zheng, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408810241

                Pt-based alloys with precisely controllable element distribution are highly sought after in catalysis. This study focuses on optimizing elemental distribution and alloying in PtNi alloy nanowires (NWs) through high-temperature heat treatment. The resulting PtNi alloy NWs with uniform elemental distribution (U-PtNi NWs) demonstrate exceptional stability, attributed to facilitated electron transfer and a denser Pt shell, in stark contrast to untreated NWs that suffer from elemental segregation and subsequent performance degradation during electrochemical testing. In methanol oxidation reaction tests, U-PtNi NWs demonstrated exceptional mass activity (1562.0 mA mg&#8211;1) and specific activity (5.38 mA cm&#8211;2), with minimal activity loss after 1000 cycles. This work emphasizes the significance of precise component control in developing high-performance catalysts and presents a strategy to enhance fuel cell performance through one-dimensional nanocomponent adjustment.</description>
      <author>Xiaojie Jiang, Zhenyu Zhang, Xing Hu, Xu Zhen, Pei Zhang, Shan Zhu, Feng Liu, Kezhu Jiang, Shijian Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c03303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystallization Instead of Amorphization in Collision Cascades in Gallium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.126101</link>
      <description>J. Zhao, Javier Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Alexander Azarov, Ru He, &#216;ystein Prytz, K. Nordlund, Mengyuan Hua, Flyura Djurabekova, Andrej Kuznetsov, Physical Review Letters. 134(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408815345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Zhao, Javier Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Alexander Azarov, Ru He, &#216;ystein Prytz, K. Nordlund, Mengyuan Hua, Flyura Djurabekova, Andrej Kuznetsov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.126101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor-Driven Prediction of Adsorption Energy of Oxygenates on Metal Dioxide Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00005</link>
      <description>Chen Chen, Zhihui Li, Jia Yang, Haifeng Wang, De Chen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408820301

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Chen, Zhihui Li, Jia Yang, Haifeng Wang, De Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving pH-universal oxygen electrolysis via synergistic density and coordination tuning over biomass-derived Fe single-atom catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58297-1</link>
      <description>Wei Guo, Meiling Pan, Qianjie Xie, Hua Fan, Laihao Luo, Qun Jing, Yehua Shen, Yan Yan, Mingkai Liu, Zheng Wang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408824299

                Renewable biomass serves as a cost-effective source of carbon matrix to carry single-atom catalysts (SACs). However, the natural abundant oxygen in these materials hinders the sufficient dispersion of element with high oxygen affinity such iron (Fe). The lowered-density and oxidized SACs greatly limits their catalytic applications. Here we develop a facile continuous activation (CA) approach for synthesizing robust biomass-derived Fe-SACs. Comparing to the traditional pyrolysis method, the CA approach significantly increases the Fe loading density from 1.13 atoms nm&#8722;2 to 4.70 atoms nm&#8722;2. Simultaneously, the CA approach induces a distinct coordination tuning from dominated Fe-O to Fe-N moieties. We observe a pH-universal oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance over the CA-derived Fe-SACs with a half-wave potential of 0.93 V and 0.78 V vs. RHE in alkaline and acidic electrolyte, respectively. Density functional theory calculations further reveal that the increased Fe-N coordination effectively reduces the energy barriers for the ORR, thus enhancing the catalytic activity. The Fe-SACs-based zinc-air batteries show a specific capacity of 792 mA&#183;h&#183;gZn&#8722;1 and ultra-long life span of over 650 h at 5 mA cm&#8722;2. Developing efficient single-atom catalysts for clean energy technologies is still challenging. Here, the authors report a facile method to increase the density and tune the coordination of iron atom loaded in single-atom catalysts that boosts the activity for pH-universal oxygen electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Wei Guo, Meiling Pan, Qianjie Xie, Hua Fan, Laihao Luo, Qun Jing, Yehua Shen, Yan Yan, Mingkai Liu, Zheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58297-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 reduction catalysis on Mo and Nb single atoms anchored to g-C3N4: A DFT investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.127451</link>
      <description>Asad Mahmood, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408826432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asad Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.127451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Density Functional Theory Calculations and Machine Learning to Identify Conduction Band Minimum as a Descriptor for High-Efficiency Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Catalysts in Transition Metal Dichalcogenides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040309</link>
      <description>Xiaolin Jiang, G.H. Liu, L. Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Catalysts. 15(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408829497

                Identifying efficient and physically meaningful descriptors is crucial for the rational design of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalysts. In this study, we systematically investigate the HER activity of transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) monolayers by combining density functional theory (DFT) calculations and machine learning techniques. By exploring the relationship between key electronic properties, including the conduction band minimum (CBM), pz band center, and hydrogen adsorption free energy (&#916;G*H), we establish a strong linear correlation between the CBM and &#916;G*H, identifying the CBM as a reliable and physically meaningful descriptor for HER activity. Furthermore, this correlation is validated in vacancy-defected TMD systems, demonstrating that the CBM remains an effective descriptor even in the presence of structural defects. To enable the rapid and accurate prediction of the CBM, we develop an interpretable three-dimensional model using the Sure Independence Screening and Sparsifying Operator (SISSO) algorithm. The SISSO model achieves a high predictive accuracy, with correlation coefficients (r) and coefficients of determination (R2) reaching 0.98 and 0.97 in the training and 0.99 and 0.99 in the validation tests, respectively. This study provides an efficient computational framework that combines first-principles calculations and machine learning to accelerate the screening and design of high-performance TMD-based HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaolin Jiang, G.H. Liu, L. Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single transition metal atom catalysts on defective VSeTe monolayer for efficient ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112715</link>
      <description>Lujing Zhao, Changmin Shi, Guangliang Cui, Hongmei Liu, Feifei Li, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408837809

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lujing Zhao, Changmin Shi, Guangliang Cui, Hongmei Liu, Feifei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous CoO/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanostructures as Efficient Anodes for Hydrogen Generation via Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00422</link>
      <description>Dafeng Zhang, Dongliang Zhang, Yage Cao, Yumei Chen, Baozhong Liu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408840745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dafeng Zhang, Dongliang Zhang, Yage Cao, Yumei Chen, Baozhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling active ensembles consisting of clusters and single atoms for oxygen reduction: a synergy of machine learning and DFT calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5qi00219b</link>
      <description>Xinyi Li, Dongxu Jiao, Jingxiang Zhao, Xiao Zhao, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408844613

                Combining ML and DFT, we screened 1521 candidates to identify 24 active ORR catalysts. Key metal features correlate with &#951; ORR , enabling efficient optimization. Pt 3 Ni-CoNC, Pt 3 Ni-ZnNC, Pt 3 V-ZnNC, and Pt 3 Mo-CoNC show high activity and durability.</description>
      <author>Xinyi Li, Dongxu Jiao, Jingxiang Zhao, Xiao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5qi00219b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in theory and computational methods for next-generation thermoelectric materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241645</link>
      <description>Junsoo Park, Alex M. Ganose, Yi Xia, Applied Physics Reviews. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408848753

                This is a review of theoretical and methodological development over the past decade pertaining to computational characterization of thermoelectric materials from first principles. Primary focus is on electronic and thermal transport in solids. Particular attention is given to the relationships between the various methods in terms of the theoretical hierarchy as well as the tradeoff of physical accuracy and computational efficiency of each. Further covered are up-and-coming methods for modeling defect formation and dopability, keys to realizing a material's thermoelectric potential. We present and discuss all these methods in close connection with parallel developments in high-throughput infrastructure and code implementation that enable large-scale computing and materials screening. In all, it is demonstrated that advances in computational tools are now ripe for efficient and accurate targeting of the needles in the haystack, which are &#8220;next-generation&#8221; thermoelectric materials.</description>
      <author>Junsoo Park, Alex M. Ganose, Yi Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative Dehydrogenation of Ethane Combined with CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Splitting via Chemical Looping on In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Modified with Ni&#8211;Cu Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07737</link>
      <description>Kosuke Watanabe, Takuma Higo, Koki Saegusa, Shigemi Matsumoto, Hiroshi Sampei, Yuki Isono, Akira Shimojuku, Hideki Furusawa, Yasushi Sekine, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408849089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kosuke Watanabe, Takuma Higo, Koki Saegusa, Shigemi Matsumoto, Hiroshi Sampei, Yuki Isono, Akira Shimojuku, Hideki Furusawa, Yasushi Sekine</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of C(1s) binding energy shifts in amorphous carbon materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.035601</link>
      <description>Michael Walter, Filippo Mangolini, J. Brandon McClimon, Robert W. Carpick, Michael Moseler, Physical Review Materials. 9(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408851648

                The quantitative evaluation of the carbon hybridization state by x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) has been a surface-analysis problem for the last three decades due to the challenges associated with the unambiguous identification of the characteristic binding energy values for sp2- and sp3-bonded carbon. Here, we computed the binding energy values of C(1s) core electrons on the absolute energy scale for model structures of amorphous carbon (a-C) using density functional theory (DFT). The DFT calculations show that in the case of hydrogen-free a-C, the C(1s) binding energy for sp3 carbon atoms is a distribution found approximately 1 eV higher than the binding energy distribution of sp2-hybridized carbons. However, the introduction of hydrogen in the a-C network reduces the distance between the characteristic signals of sp3- and sp2-bonded carbon due to the increased ability to screen the core hole by neighboring hydrogen atoms as compared to carbon atoms. This effect hinders the unambiguous quantification of the carbon hybridization state on the basis of C(1s) XPS data alone. This work can assist surface scientists in the use of XPS for the accurate characterization of carbon-based materials. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>Michael Walter, Filippo Mangolini, J. Brandon McClimon, Robert W. Carpick, Michael Moseler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.035601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilot&#8208;Scale Photoreforming of Hydrolyzed Polylactic Acid Waste to High&#8208;Value Chemicals and H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Atomic Ru Integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202500015</link>
      <description>Feng Liu, Chun&#8208;yang Zhang, Kejian Lu, Xueli Yan, Yi Wang, Dengwei Jing, Liejin Guo, Maochang Liu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408854007

                Abstract Photoreforming of polylactic acid (PLA) waste into valuable chemicals offers a promising approach for environmental protection and waste valorization, yet faces challenges of low yields and harsh conditions. Herein, a Cd 0.5 Zn 0.5 S nanotwin catalyst decorated with Ru single atoms and clusters is reported, enabling selective photoreforming of PLA into pyruvic acid (PA) and H 2 . It is demonstrated that Ru single atoms favor PA formation via hydroxyl dissociation, while the further incorporation of Ru clusters serve as active sites for H 2 production. This synergistic effect significantly enhances photocatalytic performance, achieving 96.8% PA selectivity and efficient H 2 production with a record&#8208;breaking apparent quantum efficiency of 83.7% at 400 nm. This approach is scalable for outdoor processes, utilizing direct 1 m 2 sunlight irradiation to deliver &#8776;1191 mL h &#8722;1 of H 2 and 47.27 mmol h &#8722;1 of PA from PLA waste, paving a viable pathway for large&#8208;scale simultaneous production of high&#8208;value chemicals and H 2 .</description>
      <author>Feng Liu, Chun&#8208;yang Zhang, Kejian Lu, Xueli Yan, Yi Wang, Dengwei Jing, Liejin Guo, Maochang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202500015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lanthanide single-atom catalysts for efficient CO2-to-CO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57464-8</link>
      <description>Qiyou Wang, Tao Luo, Xueying Cao, Yujie Gong, Yuxiang Liu, Y. L. Xiao, Hongmei Li, Franz Gr&#246;bmeyer, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chao Ma, Kang Liu, Junwei Fu, Shiguo Zhang, Changxu Liu, Lin Zhang, Liyuan Chai, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Min Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408857437

                Abstract Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have received increasing attention due to their 100% atomic utilization efficiency. The electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) to CO using SAC offers a promising approach for CO 2 utilization, but achieving facile CO 2 adsorption and CO desorption remains challenging for traditional SACs. Instead of singling out specific atoms, we propose a strategy utilizing atoms from the entire lanthanide (Ln) group to facilitate the CO 2 RR. Density functional theory calculations, operando spectroscopy, and X-ray absorption spectroscopy elucidate the bridging adsorption mechanism for a representative erbium (Er) single-atom catalyst. As a result, we realize a series of Ln SACs spanning 14 elements that exhibit CO Faradaic efficiencies exceeding 90%. The Er catalyst achieves a high turnover frequency of ~130,000 h &#8722; 1 at 500 mA cm &#8722; 2 . Moreover, 34.7% full-cell energy efficiency and 70.4% single-pass CO 2 conversion efficiency are obtained at 200 mA cm &#8722; 2 with acidic electrolyte. This catalytic platform leverages the collective potential of the lanthanide group, introducing new possibilities for efficient CO 2 -to-CO conversion and beyond through the exploration of unique bonding motifs in single-atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qiyou Wang, Tao Luo, Xueying Cao, Yujie Gong, Yuxiang Liu, Y. L. Xiao, Hongmei Li, Franz Gr&#246;bmeyer, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chao Ma, Kang Liu, Junwei Fu, Shiguo Zhang, Changxu Liu, Lin Zhang, Liyuan Chai, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Min Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57464-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-Dependent Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction Catalysis on Ni-Anchored &#947;-Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(110) Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08378</link>
      <description>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408869529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the activity origin and mechanisms of the oxygen reduction reaction on the tetramethyl metalloporphyrin/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra00814j</link>
      <description>Tran Phuong Dung, Pham Tran Nguyen Nguyen, Viorel Chihaia, Do Ngoc Son, RSC Advances. 15(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408873061

                This study elucidated the impact of metal substitutions in MeTMP/MoS 2 on the mechanisms and activity of the ORR. The Co atom is the best substitution in MeTMP/MoS 2 catalysts, while the MoS 2 support favours the dissociative ORR mechanism.</description>
      <author>Tran Phuong Dung, Pham Tran Nguyen Nguyen, Viorel Chihaia, Do Ngoc Son</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra00814j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Dynamics Simulation of Polymer Electrolyte Membrane for Understanding Structure and Proton Conductivity at Various Hydration Levels Using Neural Network Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.macromol.4c02607</link>
      <description>Attila T&#225;borosi, Kentaro Aoki, Nobuyuki Zettsu, Michihisa Koyama, Yuki Nagao, Macromolecules. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408888610

                Alkyl sulfonated polyimides (ASPIs), as alternative polymer electrolytes for fuel cells, are known to exhibit lyotropic liquid crystalline behavior upon water uptake, forming organized lamellar structures and achieving high proton conductivity. Previous experimental studies have shown that ASPIs with planar backbones exhibit enhanced proton conductivity (0.2 S/cm) compared to those with bent backbones (0.03 S/cm). To explain this difference at the atomistic level, molecular dynamics simulations were conducted using a universal neural network potential. The appearance of monomer unit length in planar ASPIs, indicating higher molecular order, was found to correlate with higher proton conductivity compared to that of bent ASPIs. Despite the similar deprotonation and solvation of sulfonic acid groups in both planar and bent ASPIs, the proton conductivity was independent of these factors. Directional mean square displacement analysis provided further insights into the differences in proton conductivity between planar and bent types.</description>
      <author>Attila T&#225;borosi, Kentaro Aoki, Nobuyuki Zettsu, Michihisa Koyama, Yuki Nagao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.macromol.4c02607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The advantages of reheated and intercooled gas turbines for combined cycles with post-combustion CO2 capture and storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2025.104345</link>
      <description>Andrea Zelaschi, Davide Bonalumi, Paolo Chiesa, Emanuele Martelli, International journal of greenhouse gas control. 144(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408899645

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrea Zelaschi, Davide Bonalumi, Paolo Chiesa, Emanuele Martelli</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2025.104345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCoP-stabilized single atoms for efficient hydrogen evolution: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.323</link>
      <description>Yihong Sun, Jianfeng Wan, Wenyan Bi, Shizheng Xie, Menglin Yu, Yikai Hou, Tianen Li, Dongkui Zhou, Lebin Li, Baozhong Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 120(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408903140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yihong Sun, Jianfeng Wan, Wenyan Bi, Shizheng Xie, Menglin Yu, Yikai Hou, Tianen Li, Dongkui Zhou, Lebin Li, Baozhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia using &#947;-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/BCN in a Neutral Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00936</link>
      <description>Soniya Mariya Varghese, Anju Vakakuzhiyil Gopinathan, Sudhin Rathnakumaran, S. Sasikumar, Sooraj Kunnikuruvan, G. Ranga Rao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408903528

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soniya Mariya Varghese, Anju Vakakuzhiyil Gopinathan, Sudhin Rathnakumaran, S. Sasikumar, Sooraj Kunnikuruvan, G. Ranga Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Investigation of Monolayer Sc&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;X&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (X = Cl, Br) as a High-Performance Photocatalyst for Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00155</link>
      <description>Dandan Mao, Rundong Wan, Zhengfu Zhang, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408905661

                Two-dimensional materials hold substantial promise for photocatalytic water splitting, primarily due to their unique structural properties and high-efficiency light absorption. However, finding such applicable materials poses a huge challenge because there are many strict requirements to meet. In this study, we employ first-principles calculations to design and evaluate two monolayers, Sc2Se2X2 (X = Cl, Br), highlighting their potential as high-performance photocatalysts. these materials exhibit low activation energy barriers for water-splitting redox reactions, which facilitate high catalytic performance. The photogenerated electric field promotes oxygen adsorption, accelerating the overall reaction. The structural, mechanical, dynamical, and thermodynamic stabilities of these materials are confirmed through comprehensive analyses. With band gaps of 2.65 and 2.40 eV, respectively, these materials meet the band gap requirements for photocatalytic water splitting. Furthermore, a prominent characteristic of these materials is their significantly high electron mobility along the y-axis, reaching 26,560.74 and 17,634.01 cm2 V-1 s-1, which far surpasses the hole mobility. This characteristic effectively reduces electron-hole recombination and enhances photocatalytic performance. With solar-to-hydrogen efficiencies of 13.60% and 20.58%, respectively, these materials surpass the 10% threshold required for commercial photocatalytic applications. These findings indicate that monolayer Sc2Se2X2 (X = Cl, Br) has great theoretical potential for photocatalytic water splitting.</description>
      <author>Dandan Mao, Rundong Wan, Zhengfu Zhang, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiMo LDH-Derived Mo@NiSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as Advanced Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution in Acidic and Alkaline Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c06371</link>
      <description>M Pratheeksha, Hemavathi NJ, Sumanth Dongre S, Suman Kalyan Sahoo, R. Geetha Balakrishna, R. Shwetharani, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408914637

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M Pratheeksha, Hemavathi NJ, Sumanth Dongre S, Suman Kalyan Sahoo, R. Geetha Balakrishna, R. Shwetharani</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c06371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeePMD-GNN: A DeePMD-kit Plugin for External Graph Neural Network Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c02441</link>
      <description>Jinzhe Zeng, Timothy J. Giese, Duo Zhang, Han Wang, Darrin M. York, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408914802

                Machine learning potentials (MLPs) have revolutionized molecular simulation by providing efficient and accurate models for predicting atomic interactions. MLPs continue to advance and have had profound impact in applications that include drug discovery, enzyme catalysis, and materials design. The current landscape of MLP software presents challenges due to the limited interoperability between packages, which can lead to inconsistent benchmarking practices and necessitates separate interfaces with molecular dynamics (MD) software. To address these issues, we present DeePMD-GNN, a plugin for the DeePMD-kit framework that extends its capabilities to support external graph neural network (GNN) potentials.DeePMD-GNN enables the seamless integration of popular GNN-based models, such as NequIP and MACE, within the DeePMD-kit ecosystem. Furthermore, the new software infrastructure allows GNN models to be used within combined quantum mechanical/molecular mechanical (QM/MM) applications using the range corrected &#916;MLP formalism.We demonstrate the application of DeePMD-GNN by performing benchmark calculations of NequIP, MACE, and DPA-2 models developed under consistent training conditions to ensure fair comparison.</description>
      <author>Jinzhe Zeng, Timothy J. Giese, Duo Zhang, Han Wang, Darrin M. York</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c02441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal nitrides vs. metal carbides: a comparative analysis of catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43153-025-00552-5</link>
      <description>Yuping Yang, Abdulrahman T. Ahmed, Pinank Patel, Hussein Riyadh Abdul Kareem Al&#8208;Hetty, Thiagarajan Ramachandran, Aman Shankhyan, Vikasdeep Singh Mann, Deepak K. Gupta, Muthena Kariem, Marwa Akram Nafea, Brazilian Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408916889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuping Yang, Abdulrahman T. Ahmed, Pinank Patel, Hussein Riyadh Abdul Kareem Al&#8208;Hetty, Thiagarajan Ramachandran, Aman Shankhyan, Vikasdeep Singh Mann, Deepak K. Gupta, Muthena Kariem, Marwa Akram Nafea</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43153-025-00552-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity in LiMgFe&#8322;O&#8324;: structural, morphological, and magnetic insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06229-w</link>
      <description>Nilesh N. Kengar, Atul D. Teli, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, C.M. Kanamadi, Ionics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408920725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nilesh N. Kengar, Atul D. Teli, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, C.M. Kanamadi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06229-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Oxygen Octahedra Regulation of Iridium&#8208;Based Perovskites for Efficient and Durable Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202506467</link>
      <description>Yang Yang, Yu&#8208;Ting Chen, Yueying Yan, Bohan Yao, Huanhuan Xing, Dongxu Jiao, Zhicai Xing, Dewen Wang, Xiurong Yang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934016

                Abstract The dissolution and inactivation of anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts remain significant barriers to the development of acidic water electrolysis. Here, the activity and stability of BaIrO 3 (BIO) perovskite are enhanced through the controlled regulation of metal&#8208;oxygen octahedra via B&#8208;site substitution with Co (BICO). During OER process, the dissolution of Ba and Co leads to the formation of highly active IrCoO x nanoparticles on the amorphous surface layers of BICO. The introduction of Co not only increases the concentration of high&#8208;valence Ir species with high activity but also prevents the excessive oxidation and dissolution of Ir by taking over its oxidation role during the reaction. Theoretical calculations reveal a substantial reduction in the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) after Co doping. BICO&#8208;2 electrocatalyst demonstrates exceptional OER performance, requiring an overpotential of 216 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , while maintaining continuous operation for over 140 h without significant degradation, and boasting a stability number (S&#8208;number) of 4.3 &#215; 10 5 . Additionally, BICO&#8208;2 exhibits excellent activity and durability in proton exchange membranes (PEM) water electrolysis. This work introduces a novel approach for designing and fabricating efficient, long&#8208;lasting electrocatalysts, offering significant insights for advancing acidic water electrolysis technologies.</description>
      <author>Yang Yang, Yu&#8208;Ting Chen, Yueying Yan, Bohan Yao, Huanhuan Xing, Dongxu Jiao, Zhicai Xing, Dewen Wang, Xiurong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202506467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of a 2D tungsten MXene for electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00773-z</link>
      <description>Anupma Thakur, Wyatt J. Highland, Brian C. Wyatt, Jiayi Xu, Nithin Chandran, Bowen Zhang, Zachary D. Hood, Shiba P. Adhikari, Emad Oveisi, Barbara Pac&#225;kov&#225;, Fernando Vega, Jeffrey Simon, Colton Fruhling, Benjamin Reigle, Mohammad Asadi, Pawe&#322; Piotr Micha&#322;owski, Vladimir M. Shalaev, Alexandra Boltasseva, Thomas E. Beechem, Cong Liu, Babak Anasori, Nature Synthesis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934620

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anupma Thakur, Wyatt J. Highland, Brian C. Wyatt, Jiayi Xu, Nithin Chandran, Bowen Zhang, Zachary D. Hood, Shiba P. Adhikari, Emad Oveisi, Barbara Pac&#225;kov&#225;, Fernando Vega, Jeffrey Simon, Colton Fruhling, Benjamin Reigle, Mohammad Asadi, Pawe&#322; Piotr Micha&#322;owski, Vladimir M. Shalaev, Alexandra Boltasseva, Thomas E. Beechem, Cong Liu, Babak Anasori</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00773-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidation of interfacial cobalt controls the pH dependence of the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01784-1</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Kenneth Crossley, Julie Guehl, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Nature Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Kenneth Crossley, Julie Guehl, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01784-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a unified benchmark and framework for deep learning-based prediction of nuclear magnetic resonance chemical shifts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00783-z</link>
      <description>Fanjie Xu, Wentao Guo, Feng Wang, Lin Yao, Hongshuai Wang, Fujie Tang, Zhifeng Gao, Linfeng Zhang, E Weinan, Zhong&#8208;Qun Tian, Jun Cheng, Nature Computational Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934721

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fanjie Xu, Wentao Guo, Feng Wang, Lin Yao, Hongshuai Wang, Fujie Tang, Zhifeng Gao, Linfeng Zhang, E Weinan, Zhong&#8208;Qun Tian, Jun Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00783-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical production of disinfectants from seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01530-y</link>
      <description>Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Zehua Gao, Nhat Truong Nguyen, Junxiang Chen, Xianhu Liu, Lei Wang, Limin Wu, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Zehua Gao, Nhat Truong Nguyen, Junxiang Chen, Xianhu Liu, Lei Wang, Limin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01530-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Catalysis: Applying Graph Neural Networks for Intelligent Catalyst Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.70010</link>
      <description>Zhihao Wang, Wentao Li, Siying Wang, Xiaonan Wang, Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews Computational Molecular Science. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408782647

                ABSTRACT With the increasing global demand for energy transition and environmental sustainability, catalysts play a vital role in mitigating global climate change, as they facilitate over 90% of chemical and material conversions. It is important to investigate the complex structures and properties of catalysts for enhanced performance, for which artificial intelligence (AI) methods, especially graph neural networks (GNNs) could be useful. In this article, we explore the cutting&#8208;edge applications and future potential of GNNs in intelligent catalyst design. The fundamental theories of GNNs and their practical applications in catalytic material simulation and inverse design are first reviewed. We analyze the critical roles of GNNs in accelerating material screening, performance prediction, reaction pathway analysis, and mechanism modeling. By leveraging graph convolution techniques to accurately represent molecular structures, integrating symmetry constraints to ensure physical consistency, and applying generative models to efficiently explore the design space, these approaches work synergistically to enhance the efficiency and accuracy of catalyst design. Furthermore, we highlight high&#8208;quality databases crucial for catalysis research and explore the innovative application of GNNs in thermocatalysis, electrocatalysis, photocatalysis, and biocatalysis. In the end, we highlight key directions for advancing GNNs in catalysis: dynamic frameworks for real&#8208;time conditions, hierarchical models linking atomic details to catalyst features, multi&#8208;task networks for performance prediction, and interpretability mechanisms to reveal critical reaction pathways. We believe these advancements will significantly broaden the role of GNNs in catalysis science, paving the way for more efficient, accurate, and sustainable catalyst design methodologies.</description>
      <author>Zhihao Wang, Wentao Li, Siying Wang, Xiaonan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.70010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iterative charge equilibration for fourth-generation high-dimensional neural network potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0252566</link>
      <description>Emir Kocer, Andreas Singraber, Jonas A. Finkler, Philipp Misof, Tsz Wai Ko, Christoph Dellago, J&#246;rg Behler, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408831566

                Machine learning potentials allow performing large-scale molecular dynamics simulations with about the same accuracy as electronic structure calculations, provided that the selected model is able to capture the relevant physics of the system. For systems exhibiting long-range charge transfer, fourth-generation machine learning potentials need to be used, which take global information about the system and electrostatic interactions into account. This can be achieved in a charge equilibration step, but the direct solution of the set of linear equations results in an unfavorable cubic scaling with system size, making this step computationally demanding for large systems. In this work, we propose an alternative approach that is based on the iterative solution of the charge equilibration problem (iQEq) to determine the atomic partial charges. We have implemented the iQEq method, which scales quadratically with system size, in the parallel molecular dynamics software LAMMPS for the example of a fourth-generation high-dimensional neural network potential (4G-HDNNP) intended to be used in combination with the n2p2 library. The method itself is general and applicable to many different types of fourth-generation MLPs. An assessment of the accuracy and the efficiency is presented for a benchmark system of FeCl3 in water.</description>
      <author>Emir Kocer, Andreas Singraber, Jonas A. Finkler, Philipp Misof, Tsz Wai Ko, Christoph Dellago, J&#246;rg Behler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0252566</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
