<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 01:54:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical and Electrocatalytic Behavior of Platinum&#8211;Palladium Bulk Alloy Single Crystal Electrodes in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02416</link>
      <description>Gabriel Melle, Juan M. Feli&#250;, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais, Enrique Herrero, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411515934

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gabriel Melle, Juan M. Feli&#250;, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais, Enrique Herrero</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence-Driven Catalyst Design for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Production: Paradigm Innovation and Challenges in Material Discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scenem.2025.100010</link>
      <description>Zhaoyong Jin, Dongxu Gu, Panpan Li, Guilin Ye, Haiou Zhu, Kailun Wei, Chunxiang Li, Wenhui Zhong, Wenjie Du, Qing Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411516850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaoyong Jin, Dongxu Gu, Panpan Li, Guilin Ye, Haiou Zhu, Kailun Wei, Chunxiang Li, Wenhui Zhong, Wenjie Du, Qing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scenem.2025.100010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Synthesis to Functionality: Borophene's Transformative Potential in Next&#8208;Generation Electrocatalysis and Battery Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202500186</link>
      <description>Ozden Gunes Yildiz, Asli Ceren Can, Naeimeh Sadat Peighambardoust, Umut Aydemir, Small Structures. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411530039

                Borophene, a novel two&#8208;dimensional boron allotrope, has rapidly emerged as a transformative material due to its unique atomic configurations and tunable properties. Its intrinsic electron deficiency gives rise to a diverse range of structural motifs from atomically thin flat sheets to corrugated and striped architectures that underpin remarkable mechanical strength, high electrical conductivity, and superior ion transport. This review comprehensively examines recent advances in borophene synthesis, stabilization, and functionalization. Special emphasis is placed on understanding how defect engineering, heteroatom doping, and the formation of heterostructures can mitigate borophene's inherent instability while enhancing its catalytic and electrochemical performance. In particular, borophene's potential in electrocatalytic water splitting is highlighted, where its abundant active sites facilitate efficient hydrogen evolution and oxygen evolution reactions as well as for high&#8208;capacity anodes in lithium&#8208;ion batteries, where storage capacities far exceed those of conventional materials. Though targeting distinct functions, both of these applications rely on shared electrochemical fundamentals and structural design strategies, supporting a unified treatment of borophene's energy applications. Despite promising theoretical and experimental results, challenges in scalable synthesis, stability, and integration persist, highlighting the need for advanced interdisciplinary strategies to fully harness borophene's potential in next&#8208;generation energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Ozden Gunes Yildiz, Asli Ceren Can, Naeimeh Sadat Peighambardoust, Umut Aydemir</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202500186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Reduction of Nitric Oxide to Ammonia on Defective ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202500152</link>
      <description>M. T. Nasir, Qingchao Fang, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Xiuwen Zhou, Aijun Du, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411531005

                The electrocatalytic nitric oxide reduction reaction (NORR) is a sustainable approach for converting the gas pollutant nitric oxide (NO) into value&#8208;added ammonia (NH 3 ). Currently, electrocatalytic synthesis remains a significant challenge due to the limited understanding of theoretical principles for designing highly active and selective catalysts. Herein, for the first time, hexagonal ZnIn 2 S 4 with a sulfur vacancy (V S ) as a potential NORR catalyst is systematically investigated using first&#8208;principles calculations. The hybridization between 5 p orbital of the indium (In) atom and absorbed NO leads to a strong interaction between the substrate and the adsorbate. The catalyst demonstrates excellent performance with a low limiting potential and prevents the formation of byproducts. Additionally, the hydrogen evolution reaction can be completely inhibited due to the deviation of the proton adsorption from the optimal zero value. Different from conventional d &#8208;block transitional metal catalysts, here, the exposed p &#8208;block indium acts catalytically active center for NORR. This work not only highlights a new sustainable catalyst for NORR but also offers an effective strategy for designing novel catalysts.</description>
      <author>M. T. Nasir, Qingchao Fang, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Xiuwen Zhou, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202500152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feature-Driven Prediction of HOMO&#8211;LUMO Gaps in Transition-Metal Complexes Using the SLEET Model: A SMILES-Based Transformer Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00085</link>
      <description>Sheng-Hsuan Hung, Zong-Rong Ye, Chi&#8208;Feng Cheng, An-Cheng Yang, Berlin Chen, Ming&#8208;Kang Tsai, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411531753

                A feature-driven model, SLEET, built upon the early reported SchNet-bs-RAN framework, that combines the approaches of SchNet and the bond-step representation weighted by the reduced atom number, is reported for evaluating the molecular electronic structure properties of transition-metal complexes (TMCs). Ligands were derived by segmenting purely two-dimensional SMILES representations, and metal-ligand interactions were modeled by using a Transformer-like architecture to construct a property prediction framework that aligns closely with chemical knowledge. This approach effectively captures the characteristics of the ligand field within TMCs. Consequently, the SLEET model delivers precise HOMO-LUMO gap predictions comparable to those achieved by three-dimensional information-based models while also demonstrating strong performance in predicting the molecular-weight-independent electronic properties.</description>
      <author>Sheng-Hsuan Hung, Zong-Rong Ye, Chi&#8208;Feng Cheng, An-Cheng Yang, Berlin Chen, Ming&#8208;Kang Tsai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhibiting overoxidation of an &#945;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrocatalyst by the lattice strain effect for efficient water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ey00106d</link>
      <description>Fangyi Li, Shan Guan, Jianming Liu, Changhao Liu, Junfeng Zhang, Ju Gu, Zhaosheng Li, Zhigang Zou, Zhen&#8208;Tao Yu, EES Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411536551

                The development of low-cost transition metal catalysts for use in alkaline water electrolysis (AWE) at high current densities is essential for achieving high-performance water splitting.</description>
      <author>Fangyi Li, Shan Guan, Jianming Liu, Changhao Liu, Junfeng Zhang, Ju Gu, Zhaosheng Li, Zhigang Zou, Zhen&#8208;Tao Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ey00106d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Manganese Oxide Nanosheets in Pyrolyzed Carbonaceous Supports for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00212</link>
      <description>Andr&#233; Wark, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Richard W. Haid, Regina M. Kluge, Shinya Suzuki, Zyun Siroma, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Jun Maruyama, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411538125

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andr&#233; Wark, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Richard W. Haid, Regina M. Kluge, Shinya Suzuki, Zyun Siroma, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Jun Maruyama</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning high-throughput screening of double perovskites for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165258</link>
      <description>Dong Hyeon Mok, Jaehyoung Lim, Hyunju Chang, Jungho Shin, Jiwoo Jang, Uk Sim, Geun Ho Gu, Seoin Back, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411541201

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dong Hyeon Mok, Jaehyoung Lim, Hyunju Chang, Jungho Shin, Jiwoo Jang, Uk Sim, Geun Ho Gu, Seoin Back</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diverse MOFs-derived carbon-based materials for advanced electrochemical energy applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2025.100163</link>
      <description>Chunyan Yang, Jian&#8208;Ping Lang, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411545479

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunyan Yang, Jian&#8208;Ping Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2025.100163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Engineering Modulates Spin-Polarization in Ruthenium Oxide to Enhance Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125630</link>
      <description>Lei Tan, Huilin Fan, Siyi Ding, Zian Zhao, Xiaotong Wu, Faiza Meharban, Yonghui Zhao, Qian Xu, Haojie Zhang, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Ralf B. Wehrspohn, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411545654

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Tan, Huilin Fan, Siyi Ding, Zian Zhao, Xiaotong Wu, Faiza Meharban, Yonghui Zhao, Qian Xu, Haojie Zhang, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Ralf B. Wehrspohn</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triggering Exothermic Water Dissociation on Copper via Rhenium Implantation for Enhanced Alkaline Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202504300</link>
      <description>Bhargav Rajbongshi, Pragyan Tripathi, Abhishek Kumar Singh, Manikoth M. Shaijumon, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411571727

                Abstract Implantation of foreign elements into a host lattice can enhance catalytic activity by modulating electronic properties. Copper (Cu), a low&#8208;cost and abundant material, shows great potential in energy conversion applications. However, its high water dissociation energy barrier limits its catalytic performance in alkaline hydrogen evolution reactions (HER). Herein, a highly scalable co&#8208;electrodeposition method is presented to enhance the electrocatalytic performance of copper for alkaline HER by incorporating rhenium (Re) into the copper lattice. The incorporated Re improves electrocatalytic activity by promoting exothermic water dissociation and enhancing water adsorption. The optimized catalyst, CuRe&#8208;10/CP, achieves an overpotential of 46 mV to drive a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , demonstrating excellent electrochemical stability for 450 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 in an alkaline medium (1.0 m KOH). Additionally, the electrochemical activity of the CuRe&#8208;10/CP is evaluated in simulated seawater and alkaline seawater, where it exhibited exceptional activity and stability. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), electrochemical surface area measurement (ECSA), and turnover frequency (TOF) analyses confirm the significant enhancement in catalytic performance following Re incorporation. Furthermore, in situ Raman spectroscopy, EIS, and density functional theory (DFT) studies reveal that the Re incorporation into the copper lattice significantly improves the water dissociation and intermediate adsorption. This study gives a scalable strategy for designing platinum group element free electrocatalysts for alkaline hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Bhargav Rajbongshi, Pragyan Tripathi, Abhishek Kumar Singh, Manikoth M. Shaijumon</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202504300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prospects of precious metal based single-atom catalysts in selective hydrogenation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135998</link>
      <description>Xiuli Dong, Xiaowen Meng, Fengping Jiao, Shuohui Li, Ting Liang, Cuiyuan Liang, Huan Wang, Fuel. 403(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411574011

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiuli Dong, Xiaowen Meng, Fengping Jiao, Shuohui Li, Ting Liang, Cuiyuan Liang, Huan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135998</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential&#8208;Dependent Kinetics and Reaction Pathways of Low&#8208;Potential Furfural Electrooxidation with Anodic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202500132</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Wu, Guihao Liu, Ziheng Song, Yihang Hu, Tianqi Nie, Yu&#8208;Fei Song, Small Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411575159

                The low&#8208;potential furfural electrooxidation reaction (FFOR) on copper&#8208;based catalysts provides a novel pathway to upgrade biomass and produce H 2 simultaneously on anode. Herein, a series of oxide&#8208;derived copper catalysts (OD&#8208;Cu&#8208;x, x represents electroreduction time) with distinct Cu 0 /Cu + ratios and residual content of lattice oxygen are successfully constructed by tuning in&#8208;situ electroreduction time. When applied for FFOR, the OD&#8208;Cu&#8208;600 with a Cu 0 /Cu + ratio of 83.3% shows the Faradaic efficiency of 96.1% for furoic acid (FA) and 97.4% for H 2 , which can be achieved at a lowest potential of 0.081 V versus RHE at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in continuous 10 cycles, outperforming the state&#8208;of&#8208;art Cu&#8208;based catalysts reported so far. Detailed characterization and density functional theory (DFT) calculations prove that the moderate coverage (25% based on DFT models) of Cu(OH) ads surface species generated by Cu + during the electrooxidation process endows the optimal furfural molecule adsorption and activation. Moreover, this potential&#8208;dependent coverage of surface OH can promote the kinetics of *H transfer to the Cu surface, allowing the H 2 evolution from the anode. The Cu 0 /Cu + ratio (83.8%) and suitable applied potential windows (0 to 0.4 V vs RHE) are both responsible for the co&#8208;production of FA and H 2 with high intrinsic activity and efficient H atom utilization.</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Wu, Guihao Liu, Ziheng Song, Yihang Hu, Tianqi Nie, Yu&#8208;Fei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202500132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the morphology of cobalt, copper, and ruthenium on TaN for interconnect metal deposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0256958</link>
      <description>Karl R&#246;nnby, Michael Nolan, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(24)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411577203

                Downscaling of metal interconnects has become a bottleneck in the back-end-of-line processing of CMOS semiconductor devices. The conductivity of the commonly used Cu metal drastically reduces at nanoscale, limiting its use as the devices shrink, as the metal starts forming non-conductive islands. This has led to the requirement for new interconnect metals such as Co and Ru, as they have a much higher tendency to form conductive films with horizontal growth at nanoscale. Understanding how the morphology of interconnects depends on the metals' atomistic properties and their interactions at diffusion barrier layers is necessary to continue the rapid development of interconnects. In this study, we have used first-principles density functional theory (DFT) relaxations, ab initio molecular dynamics, and neural network machine learning potentials (MLPs) to investigate how the morphology of Cu, Co, and Ru differs on TaN substrates. We investigate the binding of single metal atoms and four atom clusters to obtain the metals' substrate binding energy and metal-metal interaction energies. The morphology of the metals was then investigated by 15 ps molecular dynamics simulations with DFT and 5 ns with MLPs using larger metal structures that can display 2D and 3D morphologies. Comparing the binding energies with the obtained morphology allows us to demonstrate how the balance of metal-substrate and metal-metal interactions determines the morphology, while the MLP simulations allow longer timescale processes to be included. These insights help in the development of morphology predictors, allowing a rapid method for screening new interconnect materials with targeted horizontal growth on substrates used in semiconductors.</description>
      <author>Karl R&#246;nnby, Michael Nolan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0256958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT investigation on bi-functional {1 2 1} faceted orthorhombic &#946;&#8722;Sb2O3 for water splitting application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100862</link>
      <description>Harshada A. Barve, Ravindra R. Deshmukh, Zeenat A. Shaikh, Balaji G. Ghule, Shoyebmohamad F. Shaikh, Ji&#8208;Hyun Jang, Rajaram S. Mane, Krishna Chaitanya Gunturu, Next Materials. 8(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411579520

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harshada A. Barve, Ravindra R. Deshmukh, Zeenat A. Shaikh, Balaji G. Ghule, Shoyebmohamad F. Shaikh, Ji&#8208;Hyun Jang, Rajaram S. Mane, Krishna Chaitanya Gunturu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.100862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Behavior of Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;TM&lt;/i&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (&lt;i&gt;TM&lt;/i&gt; = Fe, Co, Ni) upon the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.5c00035</link>
      <description>Fatma Aras, Ulrich Burkhardt, Alim Ormeci, Horst Borrmann, S. G. Altendorf, Yuri Grin, Iryna Antonyshyn, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411583072

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fatma Aras, Ulrich Burkhardt, Alim Ormeci, Horst Borrmann, S. G. Altendorf, Yuri Grin, Iryna Antonyshyn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.5c00035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct N2 to NH3 conversion on diamond-supported Ni4 cluster catalysts: A first-principle study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107043</link>
      <description>Ziwei Zhao, Kesheng Guo, Yongbing Zhao, Xiaowu Gao, Hansong Zhang, Yumin Zhang, Yannick J. Dappe, Xiaobin Chen, Yongjie Wang, Jiaqi Zhu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411589936

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziwei Zhao, Kesheng Guo, Yongbing Zhao, Xiaowu Gao, Hansong Zhang, Yumin Zhang, Yannick J. Dappe, Xiaobin Chen, Yongjie Wang, Jiaqi Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali Cation Interactions with Superoxide Intermediates during the Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Ni&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;OOH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c01481</link>
      <description>Sarmad Iqbal, Pradipkumar Leuaa, Fabian Luca Buchauer, Umer Javed, Mike Tebyetekerwa, Laurence J. Hardwick, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411592694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarmad Iqbal, Pradipkumar Leuaa, Fabian Luca Buchauer, Umer Javed, Mike Tebyetekerwa, Laurence J. Hardwick, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c01481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of iron-nickel metal-organic framework anchored on reduced graphene oxide for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237555</link>
      <description>Mehran Nozari-Asbemarz, Hamideh Imanzadeh, Leila Hazraty, Behnam Babaei, Amirali Abbasi, Seyedsaeed Mehrabi-Kalajahi, Mikhail A. Vafolomeev, James J. Leahy, Mandana Amiri, Journal of Power Sources. 652(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411593445

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mehran Nozari-Asbemarz, Hamideh Imanzadeh, Leila Hazraty, Behnam Babaei, Amirali Abbasi, Seyedsaeed Mehrabi-Kalajahi, Mikhail A. Vafolomeev, James J. Leahy, Mandana Amiri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoluminescence and Stability of 2D Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper Halide Perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30132716</link>
      <description>Zhilin Ren, Zhengtian Yuan, Aleksandr A. Sergeev, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, Muhammad Umair Ali, Atta Ur Rehman, Kam Sing Wong, Yanling He, Juraj Ov&#269;ar, Jasminka Popovi&#263;, Aleksandra B. Djuri&#353;i&#263;, Molecules. 30(13)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411607447

                Two-dimensional lead halide perovskites are of significant interest for a variety of practical applications. However, the relationships between their composition and properties are not fully clear. Here we investigated photoluminescence from 2D Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper perovskites with different bulky spacer cations. Significant differences in their optical properties and stability are observed, and perovskites with benzylammonium (BZA) and phenethylammonium (PEA) were selected for more detailed investigation of the observed stability differences due to their similar structure. We find that PEA2PbI4 exhibits more narrow emission and increased stability compared to BZA2PbI4. In addition, PEA2PbI4 exhibits self-healing of defects evident from PL enhancement, which is absent for BZA2PbI4. The observed differences between perovskites with BZA and PEA spacer cations can be attributed to differences in the formation of spacer cation vacancies.</description>
      <author>Zhilin Ren, Zhengtian Yuan, Aleksandr A. Sergeev, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, Muhammad Umair Ali, Atta Ur Rehman, Kam Sing Wong, Yanling He, Juraj Ov&#269;ar, Jasminka Popovi&#263;, Aleksandra B. Djuri&#353;i&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30132716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Computational Modeling of Reactant Adsorption through a Combined MACE+DFT Approach: Furfural on Cu Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01790</link>
      <description>Steffen Jeschke, Karen Wilson, Adam F. Lee, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411608989

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Steffen Jeschke, Karen Wilson, Adam F. Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01790</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A &lt;scp&gt;DFT&lt;/scp&gt; Study on the Activity of &lt;scp&gt;FeMN&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;&#63743;C Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70075</link>
      <description>Jice Li, Zhizhao Zhang, Jiaxing Wang, Hui Liu, Limin Liang, Ying Li, International Journal of Quantum Chemistry. 125(13)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411616107

                ABSTRACT The low&#8208;cost and highly active FeN 4 &#63743;C single&#8208;atom catalyst is currently one of the most promising oxygen reduction catalysts for replacing the precious metal catalysts in fuel cells. The electron occupation states of Fe 3d orbitals have been proved to play a determining role in the catalytic activity of FeN 4 &#63743;C. Herein, by adding the second transition&#8208;metal atom M to form FeMN 6 &#63743;C, we modulate the 3d&#8208;orbital splitting and spin states of Fe to uncover the spin effects on the adsorption energies of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and catalytic activity. The results reveal that the introduction of M gives rise to various electron occupation states and magnetic moments of the Fe atom, tuning the catalytic activity of FeN 4 &#63743;C. Among them, FeRhN 6 &#63743;C and FePdN 6 &#63743;C have low theoretical ORR overpotentials of 0.41 and 0.42 V. It is found that there is a volcano relation between the spin moments of Fe and the adsorption energies rather than the linear relation reported in other work.</description>
      <author>Jice Li, Zhizhao Zhang, Jiaxing Wang, Hui Liu, Limin Liang, Ying Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the Structural and Compositional Space of Two-Dimensional M&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;X&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Materials via Simulated Etching of Layered YM&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;X&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Phases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00079</link>
      <description>Pernilla Helmer, Rodrigo Mantovani Ronchi, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411616956

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pernilla Helmer, Rodrigo Mantovani Ronchi, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Johanna Ros&#233;n</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light field&#8211;controlled PHz currents in intrinsic metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adv5406</link>
      <description>Beatrix Feh&#233;r, V. Hanu&#353;, Weiwei Li, Zsuzsanna P&#225;pa, Judit Budai, Pallabi Paul, Adriana Szeghalmi, Zilong Wang, Matthias F. Kling, P&#233;ter Dombi, Science Advances. 11(26)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411629456

                Oriented electric currents in metals are routinely driven by applying an external electric potential. Although the response of electrons to the external electric fields occurs within attoseconds, conventional electronics do not use this speed potential. Ultrashort laser pulses with controlled shapes of electric fields that switch direction at petahertz frequencies open perspectives for driving currents in metals. Light field-driven currents were demonstrated in various media including dielectrics, semiconductors, and topological insulators. Now, our research question is whether we can drive and control orders of magnitude more charge carriers in metals enabling ultrafast switching with practically low-energy, picojoule-level pulses. Here, we demonstrate the interaction of light with nanometer-thick metallic layers, which leads to a generation of light field-controlled electric currents. We show that the implantation of metallic layers into a dielectric matrix leads to up to 40 times increase of the sensitivity in contrast to a bare dielectric, decreasing the intensity threshold for lightwave electronics.</description>
      <author>Beatrix Feh&#233;r, V. Hanu&#353;, Weiwei Li, Zsuzsanna P&#225;pa, Judit Budai, Pallabi Paul, Adriana Szeghalmi, Zilong Wang, Matthias F. Kling, P&#233;ter Dombi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adv5406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Problems Got You in a Twist? Try StrainRelief: A Quantum-Accurate Tool for Ligand Strain Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c00586</link>
      <description>Ewan R. S. Wallace, Nathan C. Frey, Joshua A. Rackers, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411630021

                Ligand strain energy, the energy difference between the bound and unbound conformations of a ligand, is an important component of structure-based small molecule drug design. A large majority of observed ligands in protein-small molecule cocrystal structures bind in low-strain conformations, making strain energy a useful filter for structure-based drug design. In this work we present a tool for calculating ligand strain with a high accuracy. StrainRelief uses a MACE neural network potential (NNP), trained on a large database of density functional theory (DFT) calculations to estimate ligand strain of neutral molecules with quantum accuracy. We show that this tool estimates strain energy differences relative to DFT to within 1.4 kcal/mol, more accurately than alternative NNPs. These results highlight the utility of NNPs in drug discovery, and provide a useful tool for drug discovery teams.</description>
      <author>Ewan R. S. Wallace, Nathan C. Frey, Joshua A. Rackers</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c00586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn&#8211;Ce modified NiP electrocatalysts for HER: A combined computational and electrochemical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150068</link>
      <description>T. L. Remadevi, Anju Rajan, Akhila Muhammed, Sumi Vijayakumari Sasidharan Nair, Raghu Chatanathodi, S. Rijith, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 148(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411632753

                No abstract</description>
      <author>T. L. Remadevi, Anju Rajan, Akhila Muhammed, Sumi Vijayakumari Sasidharan Nair, Raghu Chatanathodi, S. Rijith</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical investigation of transition metal-based MOF with different halogen coordination environments for CO2 reduction to C1 and C2 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115311</link>
      <description>Z CHEN, Qiang Luo, Y.&#8208;L. QIU, Yang Liu, Xin Chen, Molecular Catalysis. 584(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411633063

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Z CHEN, Qiang Luo, Y.&#8208;L. QIU, Yang Liu, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115311</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of NiZr oxide amorphous/crystalline heterojunction for boosting hydrogen evolution reaction in alkaline by magnetron co-sputtering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150107</link>
      <description>Jinsen Tian, Mingwei Tang, Junhao Qin, Hao Zhang, Jun Shen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 148(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411634584

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinsen Tian, Mingwei Tang, Junhao Qin, Hao Zhang, Jun Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid flame induced dual-metal doping on WO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; electrode for boosting photo-electrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2025.59</link>
      <description>Seung Hun Roh, Jaekyum Kim, Won So, Yuankai Li, Won Tae Hong, Hyun Min Kwon, Sae Byeok Jo, Wooseok Yang, Byung&#8208;Keun Oh, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Jongwook Park, Chisung Ahn, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Jung Kyu Kim, Energy Materials. 5(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411653809

                A bidirectional co-doping of transition metal Fe and post-transition metal Sn on WO3 photoanode via a facile one step flame-doping process demonstrates the challenging amelioration of both thermodynamic charge migration and surface catalytic kinetics, achieving high-efficient photoelectrochemical (PEC) water oxidation reaction in a neutral pH. The direct flamethrower with rapid thermal flux effectively induces the bidirectional doping of Fe3+ and Sn4+ into WO3 without damaging its nanostructure and fluorine-doped tin oxide glass substrate. From the synergetic effect of the dual-metal doping, the photoinduced charge migration and the surface water oxidation kinetics are effectively ameliorated. As a result, the Fe/Sn co-doped WO3 photoanode shows significantly enhanced PEC response with 6.16-fold higher photocurrent density performance at 1.23 VRHE than bare WO3. This work highlights the facile metal atom co-doping method without affecting intrinsic properties of photoanode and substrate for boosting the PEC water splitting performance and solar fuel production.</description>
      <author>Seung Hun Roh, Jaekyum Kim, Won So, Yuankai Li, Won Tae Hong, Hyun Min Kwon, Sae Byeok Jo, Wooseok Yang, Byung&#8208;Keun Oh, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Jongwook Park, Chisung Ahn, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2025.59</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric field induced soft breakdown of Ni81Fe19/&#945;-Fe2O3 photoanodes for efficient photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237768</link>
      <description>Junming Li, Dongxue Liu, Ke Wang, Lei Xu, Shi&#8208;Jun Luo, Dunhui Wang, Journal of Power Sources. 653(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411657884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junming Li, Dongxue Liu, Ke Wang, Lei Xu, Shi&#8208;Jun Luo, Dunhui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237768</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor-Based Screening of Dual-Atom Photocatalysts for Efficient Urea Synthesis from CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01152</link>
      <description>Guang&#8208;Hui Chen, Chao Peng, Bing-Hao Wang, Biao Hu, Xiong Wang, Tian Sheng, Xing-Sheng Hu, Huijuan Wang, Wei Shao, Yang Li, Jinxin Li, Lang Chen, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411667610

                The development of efficient photocatalysts with high activity and selectivity for coreduction of N2 and CO2 under ambient conditions represents a highly promising but still challenging strategy for sustainable urea synthesis. In this study, using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we present a comprehensive descriptor strategy integrating geometric, electronic, and energetic factors to screen Cu-metal dual-atom photocatalysts (CuM/CeO2, where M = 27 transition metals) for urea synthesis. According to the screening of the catalyst stability, coadsorption capability of N2 and CO2, energy barriers of the rate-determining step (RDS), and urea desorption energies, CuMn/CeO2 emerged as the most promising candidate photocatalyst. Through comprehensive analysis of the effects of the Cu-Mn interatomic distance on catalytic performance, a robust volcano-type relationship was established between the energy barrier for the RDS and the formation free energy of the key intermediate NCON (&#916;GNCON). This relationship was found to be independent of the support examined in this study.</description>
      <author>Guang&#8208;Hui Chen, Chao Peng, Bing-Hao Wang, Biao Hu, Xiong Wang, Tian Sheng, Xing-Sheng Hu, Huijuan Wang, Wei Shao, Yang Li, Jinxin Li, Lang Chen, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pre-treated carbon additive enables reduction of metal loading in CoNiFe oxide-based OER electrocatalysts while maintaining performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116299</link>
      <description>Trang Minh Pham, Na Liu, Stephan Bartling, Nils Rockstroh, Reinhard Eckelt, Ju Wen, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411678934

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Trang Minh Pham, Na Liu, Stephan Bartling, Nils Rockstroh, Reinhard Eckelt, Ju Wen, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjacent boron-modified TiSiGeN4 for efficient photocatalytic nitrogen reduction: A comparison of doping and loading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114969</link>
      <description>Shilong Feng, Zhe Sun, Hengrui Jian, Kun&#65533; Shi, Qianqian Shen, Jinbo Xue, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411679579

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shilong Feng, Zhe Sun, Hengrui Jian, Kun&#65533; Shi, Qianqian Shen, Jinbo Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafine PdMo alloy nanowires mitigate excessive oxygen adsorption to enhance oxygen reduction in Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138273</link>
      <description>Huaifang Teng, Songliang Liu, Donghang Xu, Cong Zhang, G.H Li, Ming-Ying Zheng, Xuejing Cui, Xin Chen, Luhua Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411679767

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaifang Teng, Songliang Liu, Donghang Xu, Cong Zhang, G.H Li, Ming-Ying Zheng, Xuejing Cui, Xin Chen, Luhua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138273</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing SrCo0.8Fe0.2O3&#8722;&#948;-Fe3O4 nanocomposite heterostructure enabling high proton conduction for low temperature fuel cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.06.406</link>
      <description>Nabeela Akbar, M.A.K. Yousaf Shah, Naveed Mushtaq, Bin Zhu, Muhammad Imran Asghar, Sara Paydar, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411682518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nabeela Akbar, M.A.K. Yousaf Shah, Naveed Mushtaq, Bin Zhu, Muhammad Imran Asghar, Sara Paydar</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.06.406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing MoS2-based hierarchical heterostructure for synergistic optimization of water dissociation and adsorption enhancement in alkaline hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237770</link>
      <description>You Jia, Zhaoping Zhong, Renzhi Qi, Yuxuan Yang, Wei Wang, Qihang Ye, Huanqi Chen, Zekun Yun, Xiaokun Fan, Journal of Power Sources. 653(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411683446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>You Jia, Zhaoping Zhong, Renzhi Qi, Yuxuan Yang, Wei Wang, Qihang Ye, Huanqi Chen, Zekun Yun, Xiaokun Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photocatalytic overall water splitting through polarity reversal in direct Z-scheme g-SiC/SMoSiN2 heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237758</link>
      <description>Xin Huang, Zhenxing Yang, Kaining Ding, Nianqiao Gong, Ning Ding, Zhaoshun Meng, Yi Xu, Yakui Weng, Zhihong Yang, Yunhui Wang, Journal of Power Sources. 653(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411698238

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Huang, Zhenxing Yang, Kaining Ding, Nianqiao Gong, Ning Ding, Zhaoshun Meng, Yi Xu, Yakui Weng, Zhihong Yang, Yunhui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Activity-Durability Trade-Off of Anode Catalysts for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c01602</link>
      <description>Xiaozhong Zheng, Lin Jiang, Hongge Pan, Wenping Sun, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411708478

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaozhong Zheng, Lin Jiang, Hongge Pan, Wenping Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c01602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energies Exploration for Glycine Molecule Supported on Zinc Oxide Clusters: Computational and Experimental Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.5c01286</link>
      <description>L. C. Duque-Ossa, Jos&#233; Ram&#237;rez, Brenda Garc&#237;a-Farrera, J.A. Reyes-Retana, The Journal of Physical Chemistry B. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411709731

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. C. Duque-Ossa, Jos&#233; Ram&#237;rez, Brenda Garc&#237;a-Farrera, J.A. Reyes-Retana</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.5c01286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Band-bending-engineered S-scheme MXene-Sc2CF2/2D-PbI2 heterojunctions for concurrent photocatalytic water splitting and CO2+H2-to-methanol conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150039</link>
      <description>Jianfeng Ye, Xinhai Wang, Dehai Yu, Songguo Yu, Fuqiang Ai, Lu Shen, Qingquan Xiao, Jin Huang, Xie Quan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 148(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411712789

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianfeng Ye, Xinhai Wang, Dehai Yu, Songguo Yu, Fuqiang Ai, Lu Shen, Qingquan Xiao, Jin Huang, Xie Quan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ring Contraction of Cyclooctatetraenes toward Non&#8208;Benzenoid Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbons by Au(111)&#8208;Catalysis and Bulk Pyrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202501101</link>
      <description>Svenja Weigold, Ye Liu, Hailong Li, Qiang Chen, Xuechao Li, Haiming Zhang, Miao Xie, Frank R&#246;minger, Jan Freudenberg, Uwe H. F. Bunz, Kl&#228;us M&#252;llen, Lifeng Chi, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411713438

                Abstract The Au(111)&#8208;catalyzed cyclodehydrogenation of tetraphenylated diacenaphtho&#8208;cyclooctatetraene ( DA&#8208;COT ) and tetraacenaphtho&#8208;cyclooctatetraene ( TA&#8208;COT ) was investigated and compared with their uncatalyzed bulk pyrolysis. On Au(111), a strain&#8208;induced contraction of the central COT unit toward six&#8208;membered rings upon extrusion of alkynes occurred. For TA&#8208;COT , an alternative reaction pathway opened up due to the increased ring strain of the eliminated alkyne product. This pathway involved a rearrangement toward a non&#8208;benzenoid polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon containing a sesquifulvalene core. Intermediates and (by&#8208;)products were observed by high&#8208;resolution scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) and non&#8208;contact atomic force microscopy (nc&#8208;AFM), verifying the predicted reaction mechanism. Formation of [8]circulene derivatives was not observed. Uncatalyzed bulk pyrolysis only gave one ring contraction product, respectively, for both COT derivatives.</description>
      <author>Svenja Weigold, Ye Liu, Hailong Li, Qiang Chen, Xuechao Li, Haiming Zhang, Miao Xie, Frank R&#246;minger, Jan Freudenberg, Uwe H. F. Bunz, Kl&#228;us M&#252;llen, Lifeng Chi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202501101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NanoVer Server: A Python Package for Serving Real-Time Multi-User Interactive Molecular Dynamics in Virtual Reality</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.08118</link>
      <description>Harry J. Stroud, Mark Wonnacott, Jonathan Barnoud, Rhoslyn Roebuck Williams, Mohamed Dhouioui, Adam McSloy, Ludovica Aisa, Luis Toledo, P. J. Bates, Adrian J. Mulholland, David R. Glowacki, The Journal of Open Source Software. 10(110)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411715493

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harry J. Stroud, Mark Wonnacott, Jonathan Barnoud, Rhoslyn Roebuck Williams, Mohamed Dhouioui, Adam McSloy, Ludovica Aisa, Luis Toledo, P. J. Bates, Adrian J. Mulholland, David R. Glowacki</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.08118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the effect of interlayer metal materials on Li deposition in zero-excess Lithium batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237567</link>
      <description>Neubi Francisco Xavier, Qiong Cai, Journal of Power Sources. 653(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411717088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Neubi Francisco Xavier, Qiong Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus-Driven Dual d-Band Harmonization for Reversible Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03061</link>
      <description>Yiming Zhang, Lanling Zhao, Jun Wang, Yao Liu, Zidong Zhang, Wenwen Cai, Jizhen Ma, Jintao Zhang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411718410

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiming Zhang, Lanling Zhao, Jun Wang, Yao Liu, Zidong Zhang, Wenwen Cai, Jizhen Ma, Jintao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distance-Aware Molecular Property Prediction in Nonlinear Structure&#8211;Property Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01037</link>
      <description>Jae Young Kim, Dionisios G. Vlachos, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411549233

                Molecular property prediction with limited data in novel chemical domains remains challenging. We introduce an approach based on the hypothesis that prediction difficulty increases systematically with distance from well-characterized regions in an appropriately defined structure-property space. Our framework combines nonlinear structure-property space embedding with distance-aware domain classification and uncertainty quantification. We create a structure-property embedding connecting molecular similarity with prediction difficulty, implement distance-aware classification balancing precision and true positive rate, and provide distance-based uncertainty estimates scaled by molecular similarity. Across four ecotoxicity data sets, our local models reduced root mean squared error by 28-48% for truly in-domain molecules compared to global models, with strong correlations (r = 0.40-0.62) between distance and prediction error. In a biolubricant base oil property application, our approach reduced prediction error by 29% compared to a global model and outperformed transfer learning and standard machine learning approaches. This framework's focus on relevant domains and distance-calibrated uncertainty estimates for limited, heterogeneous chemical data makes it broadly applicable across applications, such as toxicity prediction, drug discovery, and materials design.</description>
      <author>Jae Young Kim, Dionisios G. Vlachos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Methylcellulose Chain Design on Gelation and Fibril Structure Using Coarse-Grained Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00862</link>
      <description>Stephen Kronenberger, Arthi Jayaraman, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4411531326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stephen Kronenberger, Arthi Jayaraman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00862</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
