<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 02:04:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the local environment of Ni single-atom catalysts with heteroatoms for efficient CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64679-1</link>
      <description>Gang Wang, Imran Muhammad, Huimin Yan, Jun Li, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 74(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412621719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Wang, Imran Muhammad, Huimin Yan, Jun Li, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64679-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the couple-decouple spin state shifting of graphdiyne-supported d8 state Fe dual-atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64691-2</link>
      <description>Xinli Zhu, Haoran Xing, Guangyu He, Hai Xiao, Yinjuan Chen, Jun Li, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 74(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412621728

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinli Zhu, Haoran Xing, Guangyu He, Hai Xiao, Yinjuan Chen, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64691-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Adsorption States of OER Intermediates on Single-Atom Catalysts via a Spectral Machine Learning Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01212</link>
      <description>Fan Wu, Ke Ye, Jun Jiang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412626248

                Identifying the adsorption states of intermediates in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for revealing the potential-determining step and further optimizing catalytic systems. Infrared (IR) spectroscopy serves as an effective tool for probing oxygen-containing intermediates on electrode surfaces. However, extracting spectral characteristics and establishing a quantitative correlation between these features and the adsorption states of intermediates remains a significant challenge. In this letter, we present a machine learning framework tailored for single-atom catalysts to learn from the infrared spectra of OER intermediates and construct a "spectrum-property" relationship. This enables accurate prediction of the adsorption states, namely adsorption free energy and charge of key intermediates (*OH, *O, and *OOH). Notably, the pretrained model demonstrates efficient transferability across commonly reported single-atom OER systems and provides interpretable attention maps of infrared signals based on vibrational mode analysis. By quantitatively linking spectral features to the adsorption states of oxygen-containing intermediates via machine learning, our framework is expected to provide valuable insights for guiding the optimization of single-atom OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Fan Wu, Ke Ye, Jun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Insights into Two-Dimensional M&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(HHTP)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks as ORR/OER Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03531</link>
      <description>Victor Hoyos-Sinchi, Pedro H. Souza, Walter Orellana, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412638127

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Victor Hoyos-Sinchi, Pedro H. Souza, Walter Orellana</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Barriers in Electrochemical Toluene Hydrogenation for Efficient Hydrogen Storage by Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Au Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02493</link>
      <description>Chen&#8208;Hui Chan, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Nomin Tamir, Hyobin Nam, Sae Yane Paek, Jong Sung Lim, Bayasgalan Ulambayar, Keun Hwa Chae, Wenyu Sun, Sneha A. Akhade, Giovanna Bucci, Seung Yong Lee, Jong Min Kim, So&#8208;Hye Cho, Sang Soo Han, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412641719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen&#8208;Hui Chan, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Nomin Tamir, Hyobin Nam, Sae Yane Paek, Jong Sung Lim, Bayasgalan Ulambayar, Keun Hwa Chae, Wenyu Sun, Sneha A. Akhade, Giovanna Bucci, Seung Yong Lee, Jong Min Kim, So&#8208;Hye Cho, Sang Soo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Amorphous/Crystalline CoS/Co3B2 Heterostructure with Coupled Electronic Engineering Toward Efficient and Stable Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182443</link>
      <description>Yuxin Gao, Jing Zhao, Jiayu Xiao, Shuai Wan, Hao Wang, Xiaodong Lv, Lihong Bao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412644376

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Gao, Jing Zhao, Jiayu Xiao, Shuai Wan, Hao Wang, Xiaodong Lv, Lihong Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boronated aromatic ring-fused structure: An efficient electrocatalyst for sustainable ammonia synthesis from nitric oxide pollutant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136336</link>
      <description>Naga Venkateswara Rao Nulakani, Venkata Surya Kumar Choutipalli, Kevin L. Shuford, Mohamad Akbar Ali, Fuel. 404(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412646758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naga Venkateswara Rao Nulakani, Venkata Surya Kumar Choutipalli, Kevin L. Shuford, Mohamad Akbar Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynasor 2: From simulation to experiment through correlation functions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109759</link>
      <description>Esm&#233;e Berger, Erik Fransson, Fredrik Eriksson, Eric Lindgren, G&#1255;ran Wahnstr&#246;m, Thomas H. Rod, Paul Erhart, Computer Physics Communications. 316(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412651018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Esm&#233;e Berger, Erik Fransson, Fredrik Eriksson, Eric Lindgren, G&#1255;ran Wahnstr&#246;m, Thomas H. Rod, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling hydrocarbon chain growth and degree of branching in CO2 electroreduction on fluorine-doped nickel catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01370-1</link>
      <description>Yingqing Ou, Lu Liu, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Futian You, Haibin Ma, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Boon Siang Yeo, Nature Catalysis. 8(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412651021

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingqing Ou, Lu Liu, Ranga Rohit Seemakurthi, Futian You, Haibin Ma, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Boon Siang Yeo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01370-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High entropy alloys as catalysts: A focused review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2025.139114</link>
      <description>Mark J. Mueller, Han K. Chau, Sarah Stofik, Matthew N. Gordon, Rebecca Fushimi, Jochen Lauterbach, Matthew Craps, Dylan D. Rodene, Dilpuneet S. Aidhy, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412651392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mark J. Mueller, Han K. Chau, Sarah Stofik, Matthew N. Gordon, Rebecca Fushimi, Jochen Lauterbach, Matthew Craps, Dylan D. Rodene, Dilpuneet S. Aidhy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2025.139114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory-guided Electron Delocalization Modulation at Cu&#8722;O&#8722;Ce Sites Boosts CO2 Electroreduction to Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125741</link>
      <description>Peng Wei, Shilun Wang, Yu&#8208;Kun Qian, Yongqing Fu, Yao Shen, Jingkai Zhao, Jiexu Ye, Qiaoli Wang, Pengfei Xie, Shihan Zhang, Xiang Gao, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412658024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Wei, Shilun Wang, Yu&#8208;Kun Qian, Yongqing Fu, Yao Shen, Jingkai Zhao, Jiexu Ye, Qiaoli Wang, Pengfei Xie, Shihan Zhang, Xiang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in metal-organic complexes for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions: Material design and mechanistic insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2025.122859</link>
      <description>Yingying Gu, Chuan Zhang, Minfeng Meng, Xianlong Ge, Shaohua Hu, Yankai Song, Inorganica Chimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412658222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingying Gu, Chuan Zhang, Minfeng Meng, Xianlong Ge, Shaohua Hu, Yankai Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2025.122859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topology-Driven Search for Molecular Links in Nanoclusters: Structure Prediction for Au&lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt;(SR)&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01668</link>
      <description>Jing Qian, Jingkuan Lyu, Zhucheng Yang, Jianping Xie, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412660378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Qian, Jingkuan Lyu, Zhucheng Yang, Jianping Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy RuO2 catalyst with dual-site oxide path for durable acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61763-5</link>
      <description>Fangren Qian, Dengfeng Cao, Shuangming Chen, Yalong Yuan, Kai Chen, Peter Joseph Chimtali, Hengjie Liu, Wei Jiang, Beibei Sheng, Luocai Yi, Jiabao Huang, Chengsi Hu, Huxu Lei, Xiaojun Wu, Zhenhai Wen, Qingjun Chen, Li Song, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412670086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangren Qian, Dengfeng Cao, Shuangming Chen, Yalong Yuan, Kai Chen, Peter Joseph Chimtali, Hengjie Liu, Wei Jiang, Beibei Sheng, Luocai Yi, Jiabao Huang, Chengsi Hu, Huxu Lei, Xiaojun Wu, Zhenhai Wen, Qingjun Chen, Li Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-61763-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Transition Metal-Intercalated Ti-Doped WS2 Bilayers for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Catalysis: A Synergistic DFT-Machine Learning Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147011</link>
      <description>Yingchao Wang, Yi Wang, Teng&#8208;Teng Chen, Lei Li, Guang Wang, Zhengli Zhang, Zhao Ding, Xiang Guo, Zijiang Luo, Xuefei Liu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412676134

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingchao Wang, Yi Wang, Teng&#8208;Teng Chen, Lei Li, Guang Wang, Zhengli Zhang, Zhao Ding, Xiang Guo, Zijiang Luo, Xuefei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric charge polarized heteronuclear nonmetal dual-atom catalysts for efficient electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138564</link>
      <description>Yafei Zhao, Liang He, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412678170

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yafei Zhao, Liang He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput ab initio study of elemental segregation and cohesion at ferritic-iron grain boundaries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121288</link>
      <description>Lin Han, Xiangyuan Cui, Tilmann Hickel, J&#246;rg Neugebauer, Simon P. Ringer, Acta Materialia. 297(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412687026

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lin Han, Xiangyuan Cui, Tilmann Hickel, J&#246;rg Neugebauer, Simon P. Ringer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constant-Potential Machine Learning Force Field for the Electrochemical Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00784</link>
      <description>Ruoyu Wang, Shaoheng Fang, Qixing Huang, Yuanyue Liu, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412687597

                Better understanding and prediction of the electrochemical interface require large-scale atomistic simulations. Machine learning force fields (MLFFs) have proven to be an effective approach. However, current MLFFs typically do not account for the effect of electrode potential, which requires treating interface electrons with a grand canonical ensemble. Here, we develop a constant potential MLFF (CP-MLFF) based on an equivariant graph neural network and implement it into MACE. Specifically, we design an architecture that can take the number of electrons as the input and accurately predict the Fermi level. The CP-MLFF allows us to examine the convergency of the electrochemical barrier with respect to sampling, which we demonstrate through the example of CO2 reduction on the Ni-N-C catalyst. Our work provides a useful method and tool enabling accurate and efficient large-scale simulation of the electrochemical interface.</description>
      <author>Ruoyu Wang, Shaoheng Fang, Qixing Huang, Yuanyue Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Activation and Electrochemical Reduction to CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;OH via Charge Modulation on Defect-Induced Free-Standing Bilayer Borophene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02237</link>
      <description>Upasana Nath, Manabendra Sarma, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412687898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Upasana Nath, Manabendra Sarma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: machine learning in high-entropy alloys-transformative potential and innovative application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-11232-7</link>
      <description>Xudong Hu, Journal of Materials Science. 60(29)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412688189

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xudong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-11232-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precipitation synthesis and characterization of SnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; heterojunctions for enhanced photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra03721b</link>
      <description>Rizwan Hasan Khan, S. Ahmad, Haikal Muhammad Ihsan, S. Nadeem, Syed Zulfiqar, Ferry Anggoro Ardy Nugroho, RSC Advances. 15(33)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412694186

                Fabrication of SnO 2 @g-C 3 N 4 heterojunctions via a simple precipitation route, for enhanced photocatalytic H 2 production.</description>
      <author>Rizwan Hasan Khan, S. Ahmad, Haikal Muhammad Ihsan, S. Nadeem, Syed Zulfiqar, Ferry Anggoro Ardy Nugroho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra03721b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ammonia Evolution in Glycine Pyrolysis via Ionic-Pair Reaction Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08868</link>
      <description>Jacopo Lupi, Thantip Roongcharoen, Luca Sementa, Francesca Cicogna, Alessandro Nanni, Alessandro Fortunelli, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412694448

                Amino acids are key contributors to nitrogenous emissions during biomass pyrolysis, yet the underlying reaction mechanisms governing their thermal degradation remain only partially understood. In this study, we combine systematic reaction path search algorithms with chemical insight and density functional theory (DFT) simulations to investigate the thermal decomposition of glycine (Gly), the simplest amino acid, with a focus on the formation of ammonia (NH3), a major precursor of environmentally harmful NOx species. We derive a comprehensive reaction network for the thermal decomposition of Gly. Notably, we show that, at variance with water (H2O) that can be generated via simple dimerization in the gas phase, NH3 evolution is kinetically unfavorable at moderate temperatures and low-pressure conditions, while it can proceed with much smaller barriers in the condensed phase via many-body mechanisms involving ionic-pair proton-exchange-driven polymerization pathways. Under such conditions, we predict that NH3 evolution competes with H2O formation, reconciling theoretical predictions with experimental observations.</description>
      <author>Jacopo Lupi, Thantip Roongcharoen, Luca Sementa, Francesca Cicogna, Alessandro Nanni, Alessandro Fortunelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Stabilizing Spinel Cobalt Oxide&#8208;Based Catalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202509415</link>
      <description>Chengli Rong, Qian Sun, Jiexin Zhu, Hamidreza Arandiyan, Zongping Shao, Yuan Wang, Yuan Chen, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412697337

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is pivotal to sustainable energy storage and conversion technologies. Yet, its sluggish kinetics in acidic media and reliance on expensive noble metal catalysts limit its efficiency in these applications. Spinel cobalt(II, III) oxide (Co 3 O 4 )&#8208;based catalysts are cost&#8208;effective alternatives with high theoretical catalytic activity. However, their practical deployment is hindered by their poor stability in acidic electrolytes. This review critically examines recent advances in enhancing the stability of spinel Co 3 O 4 &#8208;based catalysts for acidic OER. The fundamental reaction mechanisms of acidic OER are first analyzed to illustrate how different catalyst design strategies can be used to improve their stability. Next, five key catalyst design strategies reported in recent studies are summarized: 1) constructing protective surface layers, 2) modulating reaction pathways, 3) controlling cobalt redox dynamics, 4) tuning cobalt&#8208;oxygen covalency, and 5) stabilizing lattice oxygen. Further, recent research progress in understanding the structure&#8208;activity&#8208;stability relationship of spinel Co 3 O 4 &#8208;based catalysts is summarized, with a focus on identifying their catalytically active sites, tracking surface reconstruction, and elucidating degradation mechanisms. This review ends with a discussion of future research directions for addressing key challenges in realizing durable, high&#8208;performance Co 3 O 4 &#8208;based catalysts for acidic OER applications.</description>
      <author>Chengli Rong, Qian Sun, Jiexin Zhu, Hamidreza Arandiyan, Zongping Shao, Yuan Wang, Yuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202509415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convergence of Body-Orders in Linear Atomic Cluster Expansions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c01335</link>
      <description>Apolinario Miguel Tan, Franco Pellegrini, Stefano de Gironcoli, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412699201

                We study the convergence of a linear atomic cluster expansion (ACE) potential with respect to its basis functions, in terms of the effective two-body interactions of elemental carbon and silicon systems. We build ACE potentials with descriptor sets truncated at body-orders K = 2 to K = 5 trained on a diverse carbon data set and on silicon dimers to pentamers. The potentials trained on diverse structures with standard ACE bases are not able to recover the correct dimer curves, much less produce stable curves or solutions. While employing ACE bases removed of self-interactions still does not generalize to the DFT-expected results, properly tailored data sets and basis sets are able to show signs of convergence and stability in the curves and expansions, suggesting a method to build potentials with interpretable bases with respect to the cluster expansion.</description>
      <author>Apolinario Miguel Tan, Franco Pellegrini, Stefano de Gironcoli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c01335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible Structural Oscillation Mediates Stable Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202509915</link>
      <description>Qunlei Wen, Tianyang Liu, Danji Huang, Yu Lin, Zhenhong Yang, Ruoou Yang, Youwen Liu, Xiaomeng Ai, Jiakun Fang, Yafei Li, Bao Yu Xia, Shijie Cheng, Tianyou Zhai, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412702121

                Abstract The dynamic dissolution of active species of electrocatalysts suffers severe durability issues, thus limiting practical sustainable electrochemical application despite the enormous strides in the activity. An atomistic understanding of the dynamic pattern is a fundamental prerequisite for realizing prolonged stability. Herein, modeling on NiFe LDHs, multiple operando spectroscopies revealed the structural oscillation of the local [Ni&#8211;O 2 &#8211;Fe] unit identified a strong dependence on the alternant Fe dissolution and redeposition during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process, thus mediating the dynamic stability. At this point, a proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept strategy with S, Co co&#8208;doping was demonstrated to tune structural oscillations. In situ S leaching that alleviates the lattice mismatch suppresses Fe dissolution, while the electron&#8208;withdrawing Co as a deposition site promotes Fe redeposition, thus achieving the reversible oscillation of local [Ni/Co&#8211;O 2 &#8211;Fe] units and dynamic stability. The implementation of the modified NiFe LDH in industrial water electrolysis equipment operated steadily over 800 h (5000&#8208;h lifetime obtained by epitaxial method with 10% attenuation) with an energy consumption of 4.05 kWh Nm &#8722;3 H 2 @ 4000 A m &#8722;2 . The levelized cost of hydrogen of US$ 2.315 per kg H2 overmatches the European Commission's target for the coming decade (&lt;US$ 2.5 per kg H2 ).</description>
      <author>Qunlei Wen, Tianyang Liu, Danji Huang, Yu Lin, Zhenhong Yang, Ruoou Yang, Youwen Liu, Xiaomeng Ai, Jiakun Fang, Yafei Li, Bao Yu Xia, Shijie Cheng, Tianyou Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202509915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Acidity of Oxygen Evolution Intermediates by Excited State Optical Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c10001</link>
      <description>Michael Paolino, Suryansh Singh, C. M. Boyd, Moritz Lang, Tanja Cuk, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412703094

                While the protonation of homogeneous metal-oxide catalysts is quite relevant for mechanisms in aqueous solution, the relevance of surface acidity to catalytic mechanisms of heterogeneous metal oxides is far less understood. Without a distinguishing metric ascribed to transient intermediates, invoking surface acidity is limited to rationalizing pH-dependent product evolution. Recently, the emissive population associated with intermediates of electron and proton transfer at a titanium oxide surface demonstrated an isotherm with pH whose half-rise occurred at pH = 11.8. As detected by a time-resolved visible broadband probe, the intermediates formed within &lt;2 ps upon photoexcitation of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at an electron-doped (0.1% Nb) SrTiO3/aqueous interface. Here, we demonstrate how the pH dependence of the &lt;2 ps population is preserved such that when the intermediate population finally decays with a time constant of 10 &#956;s, it does so with a pH onset at 11.4. The distinctive pH associated with a metastable population ascribes a surface acidity to the first intermediate of water oxidation, interpreted as favoring Ti-OH&#8226; below and Ti-O&#8226;- above an acid dissociation constant (i.e., pKa). The work shows that the excited state optical spectroscopy is sensitive to protonation over the lifetime of metastable intermediates. Further, it shows that the details of the hydration layer prior to excitation are important for stabilizing intermediate populations of different acidities that then affect the chemical steps of water oxidation catalysis at longer time scales, e.g., bond formation.</description>
      <author>Michael Paolino, Suryansh Singh, C. M. Boyd, Moritz Lang, Tanja Cuk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c10001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learned bond-order potential for exploring the configuration space of carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/73gp-bm46</link>
      <description>Ikuma Kohata, Kaoru Hisama, Keigo Otsuka, Shigeo Maruyama, Physical Review Materials. 9(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412703107

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ikuma Kohata, Kaoru Hisama, Keigo Otsuka, Shigeo Maruyama</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/73gp-bm46</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A density functional theory study on transition metals loaded on antimonene as effective electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138577</link>
      <description>Zhujun Li, Ting Yao, Yang Cai, Xin Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412703399

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhujun Li, Ting Yao, Yang Cai, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138577</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tepkit: A toolkit for measuring and visualizing interatomic force constants and accelerating transport-property calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114151</link>
      <description>Shu-Hao Cao, Xiang-Rong Chen, Zhao-Yi Zeng, Hua-Yun Geng, Computational Materials Science. 259(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412705306

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shu-Hao Cao, Xiang-Rong Chen, Zhao-Yi Zeng, Hua-Yun Geng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transferring Knowledge from MM to QM: A Graph Neural Network-Based Implicit Solvent Model for Small Organic Molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00728</link>
      <description>Paul Katzberger, Felix Pultar, Sereina Riniker, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412705605

                The conformational ensemble of a molecule is strongly influenced by the surrounding environment. Correctly modeling the effect of any given environment is, hence, of pivotal importance in computational studies. Machine learning (ML) has been shown to be able to model these interactions probabilistically, with successful applications demonstrated for classical molecular dynamics. While first instances of ML implicit solvents for quantum-mechanical (QM) calculations exist, the high computational cost of QM reference calculations hinders the development of a generally applicable ML implicit solvent model for QM calculations. Here, we present a novel way of developing such a general machine-learned QM implicit solvent model by transferring knowledge obtained from classical interactions to QM, emulating a QM/MM setup with electrostatic embedding and a nonpolarizable MM solvent. This has the profound advantages that neither QM/MM reference calculations nor experimental data are required for training and that the obtained graph neural network (GNN)-based implicit solvent model (termed QM-GNNIS) is compatible with any functional and basis set. QM-GNNIS is currently applicable to small organic molecules and describes 39 different organic solvents. The performance of QM-GNNIS is validated on NMR and IR experiments, demonstrating that the approach can reproduce experimentally observed trends unattainable by state-of-the-art implicit-solvent models paired with static QM calculations.</description>
      <author>Paul Katzberger, Felix Pultar, Sereina Riniker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in computational design of van der Waals heterostructures for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02722e</link>
      <description>Ramandeep Singh, Pooja Jamdagni, Ashok Kumar, K. Tankeshwar, Ravindra Pandey, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412706704

                Light-driven photocatalytic water splitting is a promising approach to renewable hydrogen production, driven by the increasing global energy demand.</description>
      <author>Ramandeep Singh, Pooja Jamdagni, Ashok Kumar, K. Tankeshwar, Ravindra Pandey</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02722e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering 3D-printed molybdenum carbide catalysts for selective CO2 reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166134</link>
      <description>Arturo Pajares, Mehmet Tanr&#305;verdi, Eduardo Couti&#241;o&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Jacob Andrade&#8208;Arvizu, Maxim Guc, Pablo Guardia, H&#232;ctor Prats, Bart Michielsen, Chemical Engineering Journal. 520(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412711710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arturo Pajares, Mehmet Tanr&#305;verdi, Eduardo Couti&#241;o&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Jacob Andrade&#8208;Arvizu, Maxim Guc, Pablo Guardia, H&#232;ctor Prats, Bart Michielsen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid carbothermic shock synthesis of high-entropy oxides as highly stable oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237967</link>
      <description>Changyu Hu, Huidong Xie, Cheng Chen, Xiaoyu Liu, Hao Chen, Lingyi Meng, Hu Liu, Journal of Power Sources. 655(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412711831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changyu Hu, Huidong Xie, Cheng Chen, Xiaoyu Liu, Hao Chen, Lingyi Meng, Hu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening and mechanistic study of transition metal and non-metal mono-/co-doped WS2 with anti-site defects as nitrogen reduction electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136349</link>
      <description>Huaping Xiong, Yue Meng, Bo Xie, Zheming Ni, Shengjie Xia, Fuel. 404(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412715582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaping Xiong, Yue Meng, Bo Xie, Zheming Ni, Shengjie Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient Surface Degradation of LSCO and LSFO during OER in Alkaline Electrolyte under Dynamic Cycling Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02273</link>
      <description>Anton Kaus, Bixian Ying, Zhenjie Teng, Muzaffar Maksumov, Lisa Heymann, Michael Merz, S. Schuppler, Peter Nagel, Florian Hausen, Karin Kleiner, Felix Gunkel, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412716932

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anton Kaus, Bixian Ying, Zhenjie Teng, Muzaffar Maksumov, Lisa Heymann, Michael Merz, S. Schuppler, Peter Nagel, Florian Hausen, Karin Kleiner, Felix Gunkel</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02273</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Estimation of Inter-atomic Potentials in Plasma Material Interaction Molecular Dynamic Modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-97992-7_13</link>
      <description>Alper Pahsa, Lecture notes in networks and systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412719240

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alper Pahsa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-97992-7_13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: beyond the surface&#8212;exploring the complexities of 2D materials with density functional theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-11190-0</link>
      <description>Mehedi Hasan, Heider A. Abdulhussein, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412722169

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mehedi Hasan, Heider A. Abdulhussein</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-11190-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promising two-dimensional Janus &#946;-PdXO (X = S/Se) for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150617</link>
      <description>Yue Hao, Shuo Jiang, Xi Sun, Zihan Qu, Zuyu Xu, Yunlai Zhu, Yihong Dai, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 161(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412730454

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue Hao, Shuo Jiang, Xi Sun, Zihan Qu, Zuyu Xu, Yunlai Zhu, Yihong Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A state-of-the-art review of digital twin-enabled human-robot collaboration in smart energy management systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2025.106524</link>
      <description>S. Q. Fu, Maxwell Fordjour Antwi&#8208;Afari, Shahnawaz Anwer, Zhiqiang Chen, Heng Li, Results in Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412739116

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Q. Fu, Maxwell Fordjour Antwi&#8208;Afari, Shahnawaz Anwer, Zhiqiang Chen, Heng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2025.106524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface structural engineering of self-supported HER electrodes: Multiscale micro/nanostructure regulation and their roles in HER process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01570</link>
      <description>Yaxin Wen, Zhaoyang Zhang, Hao Zhu, Yang Liu, Tian Wen, Lizhuo Ma, Jingtao Wang, Kun Xu, Sustainable materials and technologies. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412739183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaxin Wen, Zhaoyang Zhang, Hao Zhu, Yang Liu, Tian Wen, Lizhuo Ma, Jingtao Wang, Kun Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen evolution reaction by goldene/Janus-MSSe (M=Mo, W) heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150744</link>
      <description>Kourosh Rahimi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 161(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412740343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kourosh Rahimi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectro-Microscopy of Individual Pt&#8211;Rh Core&#8211;Shell Nanoparticles during Competing Oxidation and Alloying</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c07668</link>
      <description>Jagrati Dwivedi, Lydia J. Bachmann, Arno Jeromin, Satishkumar Kulkarni, Heshmat Noei, Liviu C. T&#259;nase, Aarti Tiwari, Lucas de Souza Caldas, Thomas Schmidt, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Andreas Stierle, Thomas F. Keller, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412741690

                The surface chemical composition of supported single Pt-Rh core-shell nanoparticles was studied to understand the Rh behavior in oxidizing and reducing gas environments using spectro-microscopy with high spatial resolution. We combined in situ X-ray photoemission electron microscopy with ex situ scanning electron-, atomic force-, and scanning Auger-microscopy to distinguish Rh oxidation-reduction, dewetting-sintering, and alloying-segregation during the course of the experiment. A more than 20% higher Rh 3d5/2 oxide to metal photoemission intensity ratio for the Rh layer on top of the Pt-core was found as compared to the bare strontium titanate (STO) oxide catalyst support in close vicinity, where Rh/RhOx nanoparticles are forming. At elevated temperatures, Rh diffuses into the Pt particle, and this alloying at the Pt metal surface competes with Rh oxidation, whereas the Rh/RhOx nanoparticles on the STO support are observed to sinter under identical oxidizing and temperature environments. A nanoparticle facet-dependent analysis of selected Pt-core nanoparticles suggests that Rh oxidation is most advanced on a small nanoparticle with a low coordination top facet that we indexed by electron backscatter diffraction, demonstrating the strength of our correlative approach.</description>
      <author>Jagrati Dwivedi, Lydia J. Bachmann, Arno Jeromin, Satishkumar Kulkarni, Heshmat Noei, Liviu C. T&#259;nase, Aarti Tiwari, Lucas de Souza Caldas, Thomas Schmidt, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Andreas Stierle, Thomas F. Keller</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c07668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carburization-Assisted Conversion of N-Doped Mo to N-Doped Mo2c for Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5372834</link>
      <description>Stefanos Chaitoglou, Subrata Ghosh, Shubhadeep Majumdar, Roger Amade, E. Bertr&#225;n, Carlo S. Casari, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412743023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefanos Chaitoglou, Subrata Ghosh, Shubhadeep Majumdar, Roger Amade, E. Bertr&#225;n, Carlo S. Casari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5372834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stereochemical Control of Cocrystal and Hybrid Salt&#8211;Cocrystal Formation in the Baclofen&#8211;Mandelic Acid System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00779</link>
      <description>Sarita Songsermsawad, Kajjana Boonpalit, Oleksii Shemchuk, Koen Robeyns, Tom Leyssens, Adrian E. Flood, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412743394

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarita Songsermsawad, Kajjana Boonpalit, Oleksii Shemchuk, Koen Robeyns, Tom Leyssens, Adrian E. Flood</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-engineered molybdenum Diboride and tungsten Diboride monolayers as efficient catalysts for sustainable ammonia production via nitric oxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138597</link>
      <description>Rongjian Sa, Qingyu Li, Weiguo Li, Helong Wu, De&#8208;Jing Li, Zuju Ma, Diwen Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412746358

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rongjian Sa, Qingyu Li, Weiguo Li, Helong Wu, De&#8208;Jing Li, Zuju Ma, Diwen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138597</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Accelerated Computational Screening of Pt-Modified Cantor Alloys as High-Entropy Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00063-5</link>
      <description>Wiljar Lobjakas, Christian M. Clausen, Jaak Nerut, Jan Rossmeisl, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412746629

                Abstract High-entropy alloys are increasingly recognised as promising catalyst materials due to their highly tunable compositions. In particular, the Cantor alloy, CrCoFeMnNi, has attracted significant interest as a low-cost, earth-abundant alternative to Pt-group catalysts. However, the Cantor alloy is susceptible to degradation in acidic environments. To address this, Pt has been proposed as an addition to the Cantor alloy to leverage the high catalytic activity and surface stability of Pt. In this study, we identify and elucidate the catalytic activity trend for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) by screening CrCoFeMnNiPt alloys containing 50&#8211;100 at.% Pt and up to 50 at.% of each 3d element at 10 at.% resolution using a purely computational, machine learning-accelerated density-functional-theory workflow. Assuming the formation of a Pt skin through surface reconfiguration, a machine learning-accelerated simulation protocol infers the strain-corrected adsorption strengths of key reaction intermediates and uses them as descriptors for kinetic modelling. Our results show that Pt-modification of the Cantor alloy is a potentially viable strategy towards active and durable ORR catalysts. However, the simulations also predict binary Pt-rich alloys with approximately 80 at.% Pt to exhibit the highest ORR activity due to synergistic ligand and strain effects. As this model identifies known alloys with high ORR performance, we suggest that this framework contributes to a clear understanding of how bulk composition affects the reaction kinetics of complex surface alloys.</description>
      <author>Wiljar Lobjakas, Christian M. Clausen, Jaak Nerut, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00063-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Templated Engineering of W&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Active Sites on CTF-Derived Tungsten Catalysts: Synergistic Regulation of Mass Transfer, Reaction Pathway, and Oxygen Reduction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c08970</link>
      <description>Huan Ye, Yuanzhi Zhu, Qicheng Zhang, Jiawen Wu, Xiaobin Fan, Wenchao Peng, Xiaoxia Chang, Yang Li, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412754301

                The urgent demand for Pt-free oxygen reduction catalysts drives exploration of tungsten-based alternatives, motivated by its Pt-mimetic valence electron configuration and optimal oxygen binding energy (&#916;EO &#8776; - 2.05 eV) revealed in oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) volcano plots. Herein, a hierarchical W3N4-doped catalyst has been engineered through dual-stage thermal activation of covalent triazine framework (CTF)-tungstate complexes, where W precursors serve dual roles as self-sacrificing templates and active site generators. In-depth discussions via distribution of relaxation time (DRT) analysis elucidates that the hierarchical pore structure and active sites of WNNP-C demonstrate &#8764;90% reduction in relaxation time (&#964; = 0.18 vs 1.6 s of WNOSAC-C) at half potential and achieve a 0.83 V half-wave potential (E1/2) approaching Pt/C (0.865 V) in 0.1 M KOH coupled with exceptional methanol tolerance. The mechanistic analysis demonstrates that the enhanced electrical conductivity of the catalyst support facilitates the desorption of *OH intermediates by overcoming their elevated energy barrier, which preferentially promotes the 4e- ORR pathway and consequently improves the overall ORR performance. Moreover, the WNNP-C assembled zinc-air battery delivers 839 mAh gZn-1 specific capacity and over 140 h of stability at a discharge current density of 5 mA/cm2, validating the strategy's effectiveness in synchronizing porous architectures with W3N4 active centers. This work provides a paradigm for unlocking catalytic potential in traditionally inert transition metals through synergistic coordination pyrolysis engineering.</description>
      <author>Huan Ye, Yuanzhi Zhu, Qicheng Zhang, Jiawen Wu, Xiaobin Fan, Wenchao Peng, Xiaoxia Chang, Yang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c08970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xtalopt Version 14: Variable-Composition Crystal Structure Search for Functional Materials Through Pareto Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5372187</link>
      <description>Samad Hajinazar, Eva Zurek, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412754436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samad Hajinazar, Eva Zurek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5372187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable machine learned predictions of adsorption energies at the metal&#8211;oxide interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0282674</link>
      <description>Michael S. Nielsen, L. Kempen, J&#244;rgen Ravn, Raffaele Cheula, Mie Andersen, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412757774

                The conversion of CO2 to value-added compounds is an important part of the effort to store and reuse atmospheric CO2 emissions. Here, we focus on CO2 hydrogenation over so-called inverse catalysts: transition metal oxide clusters supported on metal surfaces. The conventional approach for computational screening of such candidate catalyst materials involves a reliance on density functional theory (DFT) to obtain accurate adsorption energies at a significant computational cost. Here, we present a machine learning (ML)-accelerated workflow for obtaining adsorption energies at the metal&#8211;oxide interface. We enumerate possible binding sites at the clusters and use DFT to sample a subset of these with diverse local adsorbate environments. The dataset is used to explore interpretable and black-box ML models with the aim of revealing the electronic and structural factors controlling adsorption at metal&#8211;oxide interfaces. Furthermore, the explored ML models can be used for low-cost prediction of adsorption energies on structures outside of the original training dataset. The workflow presented here, along with the insights into trends in adsorption energies at metal&#8211;oxide interfaces, will be useful for identifying active sites, predicting parameters required for microkinetic modeling of reactions on complex catalyst materials, and accelerating data-driven catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Michael S. Nielsen, L. Kempen, J&#244;rgen Ravn, Raffaele Cheula, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0282674</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Stabilization Mechanism of Electron-Enriched PtNiCo Catalysts in Practical Direct Methanol Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c01144</link>
      <description>Min Chen, Yichi Guan, Zhengpei Miao, Shuo Zhang, Chunxia Wu, Yu Zhou, Hongxian Luo, Daoxiong Wu, Ruisong Li, Junming Luo, Xinlong Tian, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412761595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Chen, Yichi Guan, Zhengpei Miao, Shuo Zhang, Chunxia Wu, Yu Zhou, Hongxian Luo, Daoxiong Wu, Ruisong Li, Junming Luo, Xinlong Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c01144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Efficiency Electrochemical Nitrogen Fixation by Noble&#8208;Metal&#8208;Free Metallic Glasses</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503400</link>
      <description>Xue Chen, Xin&#8208;Jie Peng, Dongdong Xiao, Y. T. Sun, Kailing Zhou, Xiaoyong Yang, Yong&#8208;Zheng Zhang, Weihua Wang, Zhen Lu, Hong-Yang Bai, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412765121

                Abstract The electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) represents an energy&#8208;efficient alternative to the traditional Haber&#8208;Bosch process for industrial ammonia synthesis. However, the cleavage of the strong N&#8801;N bond hinders the practical application of NRR. Herein, an innovative design strategy is proposed based on a Fe 76 Si 8 B 13 Nb 3 metallic glass (MG&#8208;FeSiBNb) catalyst, featuring a unique amorphous structure with endogenous nanoscale compositional heterogeneity. This catalyst achieves an impressive ammonia yield rate of 92.1 &#181;g h &#8722;1 mg &#8722;1 cat. in 0.1 m Na 2 SO 4 solution, surpassing most state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art NRR electrocatalysts. Extended X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure analysis reveals that MG&#8208;FeSiBNb provides abundant unsaturated coordination sites, essential for effective N 2 adsorption. Furthermore, electronic structural characterizations and density functional theory calculations demonstrate that the incorporation of Si, B, and Nb atoms into the Fe&#8208;based matrix precisely tailors the local electronic environment, effectively shifting the Fe d&#8208;band center toward the Fermi level. This electronic modulation enhances electron transfer efficiency, thus promoting the hydrogenation of * NH 2 to * NH 3 . Additionally, the amorphous nature of MG&#8208;FeSiBNb suppresses hydrogen adsorption by eliminating well&#8208;defined crystal facets, thereby selectively mitigating the hydrogen evolution reaction and enhancing NRR selectivity. This work offers not only a high&#8208;performing NRR catalyst but also a generalizable strategy for sustainable electrocatalysis beyond conventional crystalline systems.</description>
      <author>Xue Chen, Xin&#8208;Jie Peng, Dongdong Xiao, Y. T. Sun, Kailing Zhou, Xiaoyong Yang, Yong&#8208;Zheng Zhang, Weihua Wang, Zhen Lu, Hong-Yang Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structurally Ordered High&#8208;Entropy Intermetallics for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503306</link>
      <description>Lu Fan, Guang Feng, Huimin Qi, Qichang Li, Lina Su, Z X Kang, Yuying Hou, Zhiqi Huang, Dingguo Xia, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412765439

                Abstract Structurally ordered high&#8208;entropy intermetallics (HEIs) have garnered increased attention due to their unique physicochemical properties. The ordered atomic configuration and compositional diversity of HEIs contribute to optimal active&#8208;site isolation, broad tunability of catalytic activity, and remarkable electrochemical stability. These advantages have enabled HEIs to achieve exceptional catalytic performance in various energy&#8208;related applications, positioning them as promising candidates for next&#8208;generation catalytic materials. However, comprehensive reviews on HEIs are scarce. This work provides a systematic overview of recent advances in HEIs research, encompassing innovative synthesis strategies, advanced characterization techniques, and catalytic applications such as the oxygen reduction reaction, hydrogen evolution reaction, electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction, and small&#8208;molecule oxidation reactions. Furthermore, the unique catalytic properties of HEIs are thoroughly elucidated, while discussing the challenges and future research opportunities for HEI&#8208;based catalysts. This work highlights the transformative potential of HEIs in driving the development of energy&#8208;related catalytic technologies and provides valuable insights for designing next&#8208;generation high&#8208;performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Lu Fan, Guang Feng, Huimin Qi, Qichang Li, Lina Su, Z X Kang, Yuying Hou, Zhiqi Huang, Dingguo Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma-synthesized NiFe-layered double hydroxides/amorphous MoWSx featuring synergistic effect of hydrogen spillover and vacancy engineering for highly efficient high-current-density overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtadv.2025.100601</link>
      <description>Dai Zhang, Feilong Wang, Shiting Ou, Ying Guo, Rongqing Liang, Shuyu Zhang, Xijiang Chang, Materials Today Advances. 27(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412772329

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dai Zhang, Feilong Wang, Shiting Ou, Ying Guo, Rongqing Liang, Shuyu Zhang, Xijiang Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtadv.2025.100601</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
