<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 01:08:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Heterogeneous Catalysis and Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400507</link>
      <description>Shaama Mallikarjun Sharada, Joseph A. Gauthier, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399039549

                With this special collection of articles with contributions from friends, former colleagues, collaborators, students, and postdocs, we celebrate Jens K. N&#248;rskov&#8242;s belated 70 th birthday. The studies reported here highlight just a small portion of the breadth and depth of Jens N&#248;rskov's 40 years of influence in modeling heterogeneous catalysis and electrocatalysis. Many challenges remain in enabling in silico catalyst design, and the contributions in this special collection highlight the growing importance of machine learning approaches towards solving these challenges.</description>
      <author>Shaama Mallikarjun Sharada, Joseph A. Gauthier</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400507</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of polar bridging molecules on the photoelectrocatalytic hydrogen production from perylene diimide network structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124242</link>
      <description>Weixing Nie, Mengnan Ruan, Ying Zhang, Yuxin Sun, Ke Ruan, Xiaowei Liu, Zhifeng Liu, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399040937

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weixing Nie, Mengnan Ruan, Ying Zhang, Yuxin Sun, Ke Ruan, Xiaowei Liu, Zhifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissociative Adsorption of O2 on Ag3Au(111) Surface: A Density Functional Theory Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14060504</link>
      <description>Yanlin Yu, Ming-An Fu, Huaizhang Gu, Lei Wang, W. Q. Liu, Qianqian Xie, Guojiang Wu, Crystals. 14(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399043021

                The catalytic efficiency of oxygen reduction catalysts is notably influenced by the dissociative adsorption of O2. We conducted a systematic investigation into the dissociative adsorption of O2 on the Ag3Au(111) surface using ab initio density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Our computational findings indicate that adsorption the configuration designated t-b-t exhibits favorable energetics on the Ag3Au(111) surface. Regarding the dissociation of O2, we identified a reasonable dissociation pathway, which proceeds from the initial t-b-t state to the creation of two oxygen atoms that occupy a set of neighboring fcc sites. Furthermore, our analysis indicates that the adsorption of O2 on the Ag3Au(111) surface is less favored thermodynamically and more difficult to dissociate than that on the Ag(111) surface. This study furnishes a theoretical framework elucidating the prospective utilization of Ag-Au alloy in the capacity of oxygen reduction catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yanlin Yu, Ming-An Fu, Huaizhang Gu, Lei Wang, W. Q. Liu, Qianqian Xie, Guojiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14060504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic antibacterial and anticancer activity in gadolinium&#8211;chitosan nanocomposite films: A novel approach for biomedical applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7531</link>
      <description>Khaled D. Khalil, Ali H. Bashal, Talaat H. Habeeb, Ahmed M. Abu&#8208;Dief, Applied organometallic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399051200

                Driven by the continuous search for materials with antibacterial and anticancer applications, this study focuses on the fabrication of nanocomposite films using chitosan as the basis material, with the addition of gadolinium oxide nanoparticles at varying weight percentages (5 and 10 wt.% Gd 2 O 3 /CS). The films were made using the coprecipitation&#8208;solution cast approach. The structural characteristics of the Gd 2 O 3 /CS films that were formed were investigated and confirmed using a range of analytical techniques, including Fourier transform infrared, X&#8208;ray diffraction, and scanning electron microscopy&#8211;energy&#8208;dispersive X&#8208;ray spectroscopy. The X&#8208;ray diffraction study provided unambiguous evidence of an increased degree of crystallinity in chitosan with the inclusion of gadolinia. The particle size was determined using the Debye&#8211;Scherrer formula, resulting in an estimated value of 36 nm. Following this, a thorough examination was undertaken to evaluate the antibacterial effectiveness against one strain of Gram&#8208;positive bacteria and two strains of Gram&#8208;negative bacteria. Our research has revealed that the efficacy of the inspected Gd 2 O 3 /CS as bactericides is superior to that of CS alone. Furthermore, the MCF&#8208;7, HCT&#8208;116, and HepG&#8208;2 cell lines exhibited anticancer activity when exposed to the Gd 2 O 3 /CS nanocomposites. In addition, nanocomposites exhibit significant antioxidant activity in comparison with the conventional vitamin C. These findings provide evidence for the viability of our nanocomposites in combating breast cancer.</description>
      <author>Khaled D. Khalil, Ali H. Bashal, Talaat H. Habeeb, Ahmed M. Abu&#8208;Dief</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interplay between alloying and tramp element effects on temper embrittlement in bcc iron: DFT and thermodynamic insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120044</link>
      <description>Amin Sakic, Ronald Schnitzer, David Holec, Acta materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399051276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amin Sakic, Ronald Schnitzer, David Holec</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXene-Based Catalysts: a Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2024.100054</link>
      <description>Ali Hamzehlouy, Masoud Soroush, Materials today catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399051757

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ali Hamzehlouy, Masoud Soroush</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2024.100054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coverage, repulsion, and reactivity of hydrogen on High-Entropy alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115570</link>
      <description>Frederik C. &#216;stergaard, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Jan Rossmeisl, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399056816

                Modeling hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity probability on IrPdPtRhRu(1 1 1) high-entropy alloys. Determining hydrogen coverages based on ligand effects and generalized hydrogen&#8211;hydrogen repulsion. The rate of H2 formation is highly impacted by the level of hydrogen coverage on the catalyst surface. In search of optimal catalytic properties high-entropy alloys (HEA) are promising candidates that utilize the compositional space of multiple elements. Based on simulations of HEA model (1 1 1) surfaces with a range of hydrogen coverages, distributions of binding energies are used to construct a framework that approximates the probability that adsorbed hydrogen may lead to the formation of H2 as a function of applied potential. By optimizing the alloy compositions for the highest activity probability at given potentials the best and most efficient catalyst candidates for HER can be identified. Treating hydrogen&#8211;hydrogen repulsion effects and binding energy separately, we find that the repulsion is larger for HEAs than for pure metals. Differing isotherm slopes in the mean adsorption and desorption energies demonstrate a possible hysteresis for hydrogen adsorption on HEAs.</description>
      <author>Frederik C. &#216;stergaard, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous&#8208;Spin&#8208;Polarized 2D &#960;&#8208;d Conjugated Frameworks Towards Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401987</link>
      <description>Won Seok Lee, Hiroaki Maeda, Yen&#8208;Ting Kuo, Koki Muraoka, Naoya Fukui, Kenji Takada, Sono Sasaki, Hiroshi Nishihara, Akira Nakayama, Hong&#8208;Kang Tian, Hiroshi Nishihara, Ken Sakaushi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399070034

                Abstract Alternative strategies to design sustainable&#8208;element&#8208;based electrocatalysts enhancing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics are demanded to develop affordable yet high&#8208;performance water&#8208;electrolyzers for green hydrogen production. Here, it is demonstrated that the spontaneous&#8208;spin&#8208;polarized 2D &#960;&#8208;d conjugated framework comprising abundant elements of nickel and iron with a ratio of Ni:Fe = 1:4 with benzenehexathiol linker (BHT) can improve OER kinetics by its unique electronic property. Among the bimetallic NiFe x:y &#8208;BHTs with various ratios with Ni:Fe = x:y, the NiFe 1:4 &#8208;BHT exhibits the highest OER activity. The NiFe 1:4 &#8208;BHT shows a specific current density of 140 A g &#8722;1 at the overpotential of 350 mV. This performance is one of the best activities among state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art non&#8208;precious OER electrocatalysts and even comparable to that of the platinum&#8208;group&#8208;metals of RuO 2 and IrO 2 . The density functional theory calculations uncover that introducing Ni into the homometallic Fe&#8208;BHT (e.g., Ni:Fe = 0:1) can emerge a spontaneous&#8208;spin&#8208;polarized state. Thus, this material can achieve improved OER kinetics with spin&#8208;polarization which previously required external magnetic fields. This work shows that a rational design of 2D &#960;&#8208;d conjugated frameworks can be a powerful strategy to synthesize promising electrocatalysts with abundant elements for a wide spectrum of next&#8208;generation energy devices.</description>
      <author>Won Seok Lee, Hiroaki Maeda, Yen&#8208;Ting Kuo, Koki Muraoka, Naoya Fukui, Kenji Takada, Sono Sasaki, Hiroshi Nishihara, Akira Nakayama, Hong&#8208;Kang Tian, Hiroshi Nishihara, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401987</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the Atomic Local Environment on the ORR Activity of Single-Atom Catalysts in N-Doped Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00518</link>
      <description>L.A. Alvarado-Leal, J.I. Paez-Ornelas, H. N. Fern&#225;ndez-Escamilla, E. Per&#233;z&#8208;Tijerina, J. Guerrero-S&#225;nchez, J. M. Romo-Herrera, Noboru Takeuchi, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399085331

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L.A. Alvarado-Leal, J.I. Paez-Ornelas, H. N. Fern&#225;ndez-Escamilla, E. Per&#233;z&#8208;Tijerina, J. Guerrero-S&#225;nchez, J. M. Romo-Herrera, Noboru Takeuchi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;emle-engine&lt;/i&gt;: A Flexible Electrostatic Machine Learning Embedding Package for Multiscale Molecular Dynamics Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00248</link>
      <description>Kirill Zinovjev, Lester O. Hedges, Rub&#233;n Montagud Andreu, Christopher Woods, I&#241;aki Tu&#241;&#243;n, Marc W. van der Kamp, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399091017

                We present in this work the emle-engine package (https://github.com/chemle/emle-engine)&#9472;the implementation of a new machine learning embedding scheme for hybrid machine learning potential/molecular-mechanics (ML/MM) dynamics simulations. The package is based on an embedding scheme that uses a physics-based model of the electronic density and induction with a handful of tunable parameters derived from in vacuo properties of the subsystem to be embedded. This scheme is completely independent of the in vacuo potential and requires only the positions of the atoms of the machine learning subsystem and the positions and partial charges of the molecular mechanics environment. These characteristics allow emle-engine to be employed in existing QM/MM software. We demonstrate that the implemented electrostatic machine learning embedding scheme (named EMLE) is stable in enhanced sampling molecular dynamics simulations. Through the calculation of free energy surfaces of alanine dipeptide in water with two different ML options for the in vacuo potential and three embedding models, we test the performance of EMLE. When compared to the reference DFT/MM surface, the EMLE embedding is clearly superior to the MM one based on fixed partial charges. The configurational dependence of the electronic density and the inclusion of the induction energy introduced by the EMLE model leads to a systematic reduction in the average error of the free energy surface when compared to MM embedding. By enabling the usage of EMLE embedding in practical ML/MM simulations, emle-engine will make it possible to accurately model systems and processes that feature significant variations in the charge distribution of the ML subsystem and/or the interacting environment.</description>
      <author>Kirill Zinovjev, Lester O. Hedges, Rub&#233;n Montagud Andreu, Christopher Woods, I&#241;aki Tu&#241;&#243;n, Marc W. van der Kamp</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis of Tunable Ultra-Thin Anodes for Long-Lasting and High-Energy-Density Lithium Metal Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4844308</link>
      <description>Tao Du, Weimin Chen, Yue Shen, Wenzhu Cao, Wenwen Miao, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Shanshan Yang, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399097595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Du, Weimin Chen, Yue Shen, Wenzhu Cao, Wenwen Miao, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Shanshan Yang, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4844308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable layered Mn oxides for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01144-1</link>
      <description>E Liu, Drew Higgins, Nature Catalysis. 7(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399121605

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E Liu, Drew Higgins</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01144-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Synthesis of Transition Metal Carbide via Thermochemical Oxocarbon Equilibrium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03820</link>
      <description>Seo Jin Oh, Dohun Kim, Ji-Yong Kim, Geosan Kang, Junho Jeon, Miyoung Kim, Young&#8208;Chang Joo, Dae&#8208;Hyun Nam, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399123083

                Fabricating nanoscale metal carbides is a great challenge due to them having higher Gibbs free energy of formation (&#916;G&#176;) values than other metal compounds; additionally, these carbides have harsh calcination conditions, in which metal oxidation is preferred in the atmosphere. Herein, we report oxocarbon-mediated calcination for the predictive synthesis of nanoscale metal carbides. The thermochemical oxocarbon equilibrium of CO&#8211;CO2 reactions was utilized to control the selective redox reactions in multiatomic systems of Mo&#8211;C&#8211;O, contributing to the phase-forming and structuring of Mo compounds. By harnessing the thermodynamically predicted processing window, we controlled a wide range of Mo phases (MoO2, &#945;-MoC1&#8211;x, and &#946;-Mo2C) and nanostructures (nanoparticle, spike, stain, and core/shell) in the Mo compounds/C nanofibers. By inducing simultaneous reactions of C&#8211;O (selective C combustion) and Mo&#8211;C (Mo carbide formation) in the nanofibers, Mo diffusion was controlled in C nanofibers, acting as a template for the nucleation and growth of Mo carbides and resulting in precise control of the phases and structures of Mo compounds. The formation mechanism of nanostructured Mo carbides was elucidated according to the CO fractions of CO&#8211;CO2 calcination. Moreover, tungsten (W) and niobium (Nb) carbides/C nanofibers have been successfully synthesized by CO&#8211;CO2 calcination. We constructed the thermodynamic map for the predictive synthesis of transition metal carbides to provide universal guideline via thermochemical oxocarbon equilibrium. We revealed that our thermochemical oxocarbon-mediated gas&#8211;solid reaction enabled the structure and phase control of nanoscale transition metal compounds to optimize the material&#8211;property relationship accordingly.</description>
      <author>Seo Jin Oh, Dohun Kim, Ji-Yong Kim, Geosan Kang, Junho Jeon, Miyoung Kim, Young&#8208;Chang Joo, Dae&#8208;Hyun Nam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03820</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The NOMAD mini-apps: A suite of kernels from ab initio electronic structure codes enabling co-design in high-performance computing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.2</link>
      <description>Isidre Mas Magre, Rogeli Grima Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a, Jos&#233; Julio Guti&#233;rrez Moreno, Open research Europe. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399124316

                This article introduces a suite of mini-applications (mini-apps) designed to optimise computational kernels in ab initio electronic structure codes. The suite is developed from flagship applications participating in the NOMAD Center of Excellence, such as the ELPA eigensolver library and the GW implementations of the exciting, Abinit, and FHI-aims codes. The mini-apps were identified by targeting functions that significantly contribute to the total execution time in the parent applications. This strategic selection allows for concentrated optimisation efforts. The suite is designed for easy deployment on various High-Performance Computing (HPC) systems, supported by an integrated CMake build system for straightforward compilation and execution. The aim is to harness the capabilities of emerging (post)exascale systems, which necessitate concurrent hardware and software development &#8212; a concept known as co-design. The mini-app suite serves as a tool for profiling and benchmarking, providing insights that can guide both software optimisation and hardware design. Ultimately, these developments will enable more accurate and efficient simulations of novel materials, leveraging the full potential of exascale computing in material science research.</description>
      <author>Isidre Mas Magre, Rogeli Grima Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a, Jos&#233; Julio Guti&#233;rrez Moreno</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Heating-Induced Suppression of &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;-Band Dominance in the Electronic Excitation Spectrum of Cuprum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c02920</link>
      <description>Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Thomas Gawne, Sebastian Schwalbe, Thomas R. Preston, Jan Vorberger, Tobias Dornheim, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399129821

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Thomas Gawne, Sebastian Schwalbe, Thomas R. Preston, Jan Vorberger, Tobias Dornheim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c02920</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Multifunctional Electrocatalysts for ORR/OER/HER/HOR: Janus Makes Difference</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404000</link>
      <description>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399140360

                Abstract Multifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) have broad application prospects; However, realization of such kinds of materials remain difficulties because it requires the materials to have not only unique electronic properties, but multiple active centers to deal with different reactions. Here, employing density functional theory (DFT) computations, it is demonstrated that by decorating the Janus&#8208;type 2D transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) of TaSSe with the single atoms, the materials can achieve multifunctionality to catalyze the ORR/OER/HER/HOR. Out of sixteen catalytic systems, Pt&#8208;V S (i.e., Pt atom embedded in the sulfur vacancy), Pd&#8208;V Se , and Pt&#8208;V Se @TaSSe are promising multifunctional catalysts with superior stability. Among them, the Pt&#8208;V S @TaSSe catalyst exhibits the highest activity with theoretical overpotentials &#951; ORR = 0.40 V, &#951; OER = 0.39 V, and &#951; HER/HOR = 0.07 V, respectively, better than the traditional Pt (111), IrO 2 (110). The interplays between the catalyst and the reaction intermediate over the course of the reaction are then systematically investigated. Generally, this study presents a viable approach for the design and development of advanced multifunctional electrocatalysts. It enriches the application of Janus, a new 2D material, in electrochemical energy storage and conversion technology.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is no escape: How insertion of a single Fe, Co, Ni or Cu atom into lattice of &#946;-molybdenum carbide affects its fundamental properties and catalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104533</link>
      <description>Andrey A. Koverga, Elizabeth Fl&#243;rez, Edson A. Ticianelli, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399142810

                Impact of insertion of a single Fe, Co, Ni or Cu atom into crystalline lattice of orthorhombic Mo2C(001) surface on fundamental properties of the surface atoms has been investigated by means of density functional theory. Polar C- and Mo-terminated surfaces were used as model systems and two modes of the foreign atom insertion were considered: into the topmost Mo layer of the surface and into metal layer deeper in the structure of the host system. Calculations revealed that TM-modified Mo2C compounds were less stable than the pristine carbide with no significant changes in work function of the carbide surface, regardless of its termination, foreign atom nature, and its position in the host system. Furthermore, presence of either Fe, Co, Ni or Cu atom in subsurface or in the topmost metal layer of the terminations did not impact noticeably electronic structure of either C or Mo atoms closest to the modification site as evidenced from analysis of their density of states. Consequentially, insertion of foreign atoms into the lattice of molybdenum carbide results in atomic hydrogen stability close to that on the corresponding unmodified polar termination of the Mo2C(001) surface. In the context of experimentally observed changes in catalytic activity of molybdenum carbide toward hydrogen evolution reaction upon doping it with transition metals, the obtained data evidence that the major effect comes from the foreign atoms being adsorbed on molybdenum carbide surface, while insertion into the lattice bears no significant impact. This suggests that coating Mo2C surface with transition metals can be promising strategy to modify and tailor its catalytic properties for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Andrey A. Koverga, Elizabeth Fl&#243;rez, Edson A. Ticianelli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and theoretical studies of WO3/Vulcan XC-72 electrocatalyst enhanced H2O2 yield ORR performed in acid and alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113182</link>
      <description>Jo&#227;o Paulo Moura, Lanna E.B. Luchetti, Caio Machado Fernandes, Aline B. Trench, Camila Neves Lange, Bruno Lemos Batista, J. Almeida, Mauro C. Santos, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399142859

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) plays a pivotal role in clean energy generation and sustainable chemical production, particularly in the synthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2). In this study, WO3/Vulcan-XC72 electrocatalysts have been synthesized and characterized for ORR applications. We assessed the ratio of WO3 to Vulcan-XC72 and investigated the impact of electrolytes pH (covering acidic and alkaline media) on the ORR process. The results revealed that WO3 with a monoclinic crystalline phase and nanoflower-like morphology was successfully synthesized, and confirmed an improvement in surface properties, with an increase in hydrophilicity and superficial oxygenated species. Electrochemical studies showed that WO3/C was the most selective for H2O2 electrogeneration, compared to pure Vulcan-XC72, in both acidic and alkaline media. These results indicate that the ORR on the WO3/C electrocatalyst surface has a pH-dependent mechanism. Using WO3/C GDEs, an accumulation of 862 mg L-1 of H2O2 was achieved after 120 min of electrolysis at 100 mA cm-2. The higher selectivity of WO3/C could be related to the presence of more oxygen functional acid species on the catalyst surface and increased hydrophilicity compared to pure Vulcan, as well as a synergistic effect of the WO3 nanoflowers in ORR, confirmed by theoretical calculations. The results reveal that WO3/Vulcan is a promising catalyst for H2O2 electrogeneration via the ORR.</description>
      <author>Jo&#227;o Paulo Moura, Lanna E.B. Luchetti, Caio Machado Fernandes, Aline B. Trench, Camila Neves Lange, Bruno Lemos Batista, J. Almeida, Mauro C. Santos</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113182</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do we achieve &#8220;1 + 1 &amp;gt; 2&#8221; in dual-atom or dual-single-atom catalysts?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215961</link>
      <description>Yifeng Xue, Li&#8208;Li Xu, Yuxin Li, Coordination chemistry reviews. 516(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399150954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifeng Xue, Li&#8208;Li Xu, Yuxin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Exploration of Subnano Zn and Cu Species on Cu/ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Implications for Methanol Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01300</link>
      <description>Aku Lempelto, Minttu M. Kauppinen, Karoliina Honkala, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399155399

                Ternary Cu/Zn/ZrO2 catalysts prepared recently using atomic layer deposition (ALD) have shown increased performance toward methanol synthesis. In the present computational study, we have investigated the structure, composition, and stability of various zinc- and copper-containing subnano size species on a zirconia support. Density functional theory calculations with minima hopping were used to sample the positioning and geometry of supported ZnxCuyOz structures up to 8 metal atoms in total. ZnO monomeric species were found to be energetically more favorable than small clusters, which could suggest a resistance to initial stage agglomeration. Ab-initio thermodynamics revealed that under typical methanol synthesis conditions, the complete reduction of ZnO and mixed ZnO/Cu clusters is unfavorable. The investigated ZnO monomers and clusters are able to provide CO2 activation sites, with the Cu/ZnO/ZrO2 triple interface offering the best stabilization for the adsorbed CO2. All in all, the findings suggest that small ZnO species generated by ALD could be stabilized by the zirconia component, while contact with copper species at the interface benefits CO2 activation.</description>
      <author>Aku Lempelto, Minttu M. Kauppinen, Karoliina Honkala</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-volt conversion of activated biochar and water for H2 production near equilibrium via biochar-assisted water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102013</link>
      <description>Nishithan C. Kani, Rohit Chauhan, Samuel Olusegun, Ishwar Sharan, Amit Katiyar, David House, Sang-Won Lee, Alena Jairamsingh, Rajan Bhawnani, Dongjin Choi, Adam C. Nielander, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Hae&#8208;Seok Lee, Anil R. Oroskar, Vimal Chandra Srivastava, Shishir Sinha, Joseph A. Gauthier, Meenesh R. Singh, Cell reports physical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399155404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nishithan C. Kani, Rohit Chauhan, Samuel Olusegun, Ishwar Sharan, Amit Katiyar, David House, Sang-Won Lee, Alena Jairamsingh, Rajan Bhawnani, Dongjin Choi, Adam C. Nielander, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Hae&#8208;Seok Lee, Anil R. Oroskar, Vimal Chandra Srivastava, Shishir Sinha, Joseph A. Gauthier, Meenesh R. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin Porous Pd Metallene with Amorphous/Crystalline Phase Coexitence as Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01808</link>
      <description>Hua Cui, Hongpeng Chen, Xixi Wang, Yiquan Jiang, Yimin Zhang, Danfeng Sun, Zanyu Chen, Ying Li, Junwei Sha, Biao Chen, Chunsheng Shi, Jin&#8208;Kyu Kang, Enzuo Liu, Liying Ma, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399155700

                The development of efficient nonplatinum electrocatalysts with enhanced oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity and stability is of crucial importance for the commercial application of fuel cells and metal&#8211;air batteries. Metallenes exhibit excellent performance in energy and catalysis due to their unique physicochemical and electronic properties. In particular, the ultrahigh proportion of under-coordinated metal atomic sites in metallenes enhances the atom utilization and intrinsic activity, which endows them with considerable potential for catalytic applications. Herein, the synthesized two-dimensional (2D) ultrathin porous Pd metallene with amorphous/crystalline phase coexistence exhibits enhanced alkaline oxygen reduction properties, as evidenced by four-electron selectivity, lower overpotential (E1/2 = 0.944 V), high mass activity (MA = 1.44 mA/&#956;gPd), and solid stability (only loss of 7 mV in half-wave potential after 10,000 potential cycles). Such high performance of Pd metallene is attributed to amorphous/crystalline heterophases, 2D morphology, and porous structure. DFT calculations demonstrate that the ORR catalytic performance can be effectively promoted by the amorphous structure with a modulated electronic structure. The amorphous/crystalline coexisting porous Pd metallene with excellent catalytic performance can provide the reference for metallene materials design in various fields. This study presents a scientific basis to understand the mechanism of 2D amorphous phase nanostructures for boosting the electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Hua Cui, Hongpeng Chen, Xixi Wang, Yiquan Jiang, Yimin Zhang, Danfeng Sun, Zanyu Chen, Ying Li, Junwei Sha, Biao Chen, Chunsheng Shi, Jin&#8208;Kyu Kang, Enzuo Liu, Liying Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01808</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen reduction reaction enhanced by single-atom transition metal catalysts on functionalized graphene: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.408</link>
      <description>Thillai Govindaraja Senthamaraikannan, Dong&#8208;Hee Lim, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399158115

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thillai Govindaraja Senthamaraikannan, Dong&#8208;Hee Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the mathematic equations behind the materials science data using interpretable symbolic regression</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/idm2.12180</link>
      <description>Guanjie Wang, Erpeng Wang, Zefeng Li, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun, Interdisciplinary materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399161945

                Abstract Symbolic regression (SR), exploring mathematical expressions from a given data set to construct an interpretable model, emerges as a powerful computational technique with the potential to transform the &#8220;black box&#8221; machining learning methods into physical and chemistry interpretable expressions in material science research. In this review, the current advancements in SR are investigated, focusing on the underlying theories, fundamental flowcharts, various techniques, implemented codes, and application fields. More predominantly, the challenging issues and future opportunities in SR that should be overcome to unlock the full potential of SR in material design and research, including graphics processing unit acceleration and transfer learning algorithms, the trade&#8208;off between expression accuracy and complexity, physical or chemistry interpretable SR with generative large language models, and multimodal SR methods, are discussed.</description>
      <author>Guanjie Wang, Erpeng Wang, Zefeng Li, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/idm2.12180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of machine learning techniques for the analysis of wave energy conversion systems: a comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40722-024-00330-4</link>
      <description>Masoud Masoumi, Bahareh Estejab, Florence Henry, Journal of ocean engineering and marine energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399165142

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Masoud Masoumi, Bahareh Estejab, Florence Henry</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40722-024-00330-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Performance Pd&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Cluster Supported on CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110) for the Electroreduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01686</link>
      <description>Ping Liu, Haoguo Zhu, Baiyue Li, Chen Wu, Jia Shi, Bingbing Suo, Wenli Zou, Yawei Li, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399167912

                Copper and palladium exhibit excellent catalytic performance for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR). Here, a PdxCu4&#8211;x (x = 2, 3) cluster was supported on CeO2 with different sites to form three kinds of novel nanocatalysts, namely, Pd2Cu2/CeO2, Pd3Cu/CeO2 (Pd&#8211;Pd), and Pd3Cu/CeO2 (Pd&#8211;Cu). Based on density functional theory, the catalytic performance and selective mechanisms were studied systematically. During the process of CO2RR, *CO was hydrogenated to produce deeply reduced products such as CH4 or CH3OH due to its strong adsorption energies on all three catalysts (Pd3Cu/CeO2(Pd&#8211;Pd) for 0.95 eV, Pd3Cu/CeO2(Pd&#8211;Cu) for 0.89 eV, and Pd2Cu2/CeO2 for 1.22 eV). The overpotential to form the CH4 or CH3OH product can be changed by varying the atomic ratio or anchoring sites of PdxCu4&#8211;x clusters on CeO2. In particular, the CO2RR on Pd2Cu2/CeO2 showed the lowest overpotentiontial (&#8722;0.60 eV) compared to the other two Pd3Cu/CeO2 catalysts. This study extends the family of CO2RR catalysts and the application scenarios of bimetallic catalysts, which provides new insights into the design and preparation of composite nanocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Ping Liu, Haoguo Zhu, Baiyue Li, Chen Wu, Jia Shi, Bingbing Suo, Wenli Zou, Yawei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Searching COVID-19 Clinical Research Using Graph Queries: Algorithm Development and Validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2196/52655</link>
      <description>Francesco Invernici, Francesco Invernici, Francesco Invernici, JMIR. Journal of medical internet research/Journal of medical internet research. 26(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399173448

                Since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, &gt;1 million studies have been collected within the COVID-19 Open Research Dataset, a corpus of manuscripts created to accelerate research against the disease. Their related abstracts hold a wealth of information that remains largely unexplored and difficult to search due to its unstructured nature. Keyword-based search is the standard approach, which allows users to retrieve the documents of a corpus that contain (all or some of) the words in a target list. This type of search, however, does not provide visual support to the task and is not suited to expressing complex queries or compensating for missing specifications.</description>
      <author>Francesco Invernici, Francesco Invernici, Francesco Invernici</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2196/52655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur Recovery Assisted Electrochemical Water Splitting for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production Using CoMo-Based Nanorod Arrays Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00695</link>
      <description>Jichuan Huo, Qing Liu, Xiaofang Liu, Xue&#8208;Feng Cheng, Dongyun Chen, Najun Li, Kin Liao, Qingfeng Xu, Jianmei Lu, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399175366

                Swapping the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for the thermodynamically advantageous sulfur ion oxidation reaction (SOR) makes it possible to produce low-energy hydrogen. We report here on an electrocatalytic SOR-coupled HER system that allows for the joint production of sulfur and hydrogen. We prepare a CoMoO4 nanoarray on nickel foam (NF) for anodic SOR and N-doped CoMoO4/NF, CoMoN/NF, for cathodic HER. The current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2 was obtained at 0.29 V (vs RHE) in the SOR process. After nitridation, the electrode can achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in HER at a voltage of only 32 mV (vs RHE). The coupling system (SOR//HER) can run steadily for 150 h. Detailed exploration and discussion were conducted on the pathways of SOR. This work develops an energy-efficient mixed water electrolysis system for H2, providing a viable option for toxic waste treatment.</description>
      <author>Jichuan Huo, Qing Liu, Xiaofang Liu, Xue&#8208;Feng Cheng, Dongyun Chen, Najun Li, Kin Liao, Qingfeng Xu, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active learning of ternary alloy structures and energies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01256-z</link>
      <description>Gaurav Deshmukh, Noah J. Wichrowski, Nikolaos Evangelou, Pushkar Ghanekar, Siddharth Deshpande, Ioannis G. Kevrekidis, Jeffrey Greeley, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399176479

                Abstract Machine learning models with uncertainty quantification have recently emerged as attractive tools to accelerate the navigation of catalyst design spaces in a data-efficient manner. Here, we combine active learning with a dropout graph convolutional network (dGCN) as a surrogate model to explore the complex materials space of high-entropy alloys (HEAs). We train the dGCN on the formation energies of disordered binary alloy structures in the Pd-Pt-Sn ternary alloy system and improve predictions on ternary structures by performing reduced optimization of the formation free energy, the target property that determines HEA stability, over ensembles of ternary structures constructed based on two coordinate systems: (a) a physics-informed ternary composition space, and (b) data-driven coordinates discovered by the Diffusion Maps manifold learning scheme. Both reduced optimization techniques improve predictions of the formation free energy in the ternary alloy space with a significantly reduced number of DFT calculations compared to a high-fidelity model. The physics-based scheme converges to the target property in a manner akin to a depth-first strategy, whereas the data-driven scheme appears more akin to a breadth-first approach. Both sampling schemes, coupled with our acquisition function, successfully exploit a database of DFT-calculated binary alloy structures and energies, augmented with a relatively small number of ternary alloy calculations, to identify stable ternary HEA compositions and structures. This generalized framework can be extended to incorporate more complex bulk and surface structural motifs, and the results demonstrate that significant dimensionality reduction is possible in thermodynamic sampling problems when suitable active learning schemes are employed.</description>
      <author>Gaurav Deshmukh, Noah J. Wichrowski, Nikolaos Evangelou, Pushkar Ghanekar, Siddharth Deshpande, Ioannis G. Kevrekidis, Jeffrey Greeley</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01256-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distribution Tendencies of Noble Metals on Fe(100) Using Lattice Gas Cluster Expansions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01402</link>
      <description>Isaac G. Onyango, Greg Collinge, Yong Wang, Jean&#8208;Sabin McEwen, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399176575

                Fe-based catalysts are highly selective for the hydrodeoxygenation of biomass-derived oxygenates but are prone to oxidative deactivation. Promotion with a noble metal has been shown to improve oxidative resistance. The chemical properties of such bimetallic systems depend critically on the surface geometry and spatial configuration of surface atoms in addition to their coverage (i.e., noble metal loading), so these aspects must be taken into account in order to develop reliable models for such complex systems. This requires sampling a vast configurational space, which is rather impractical using density functional theory (DFT) calculations alone. Moreover, "DFT-based" models are limited to length scales that are often too small for experimental relevance. Here, we circumvent this challenge by constructing DFT-parametrized lattice gas cluster expansions (LG CEs), which can describe these types of systems at significantly larger length scales. Here, we apply this strategy to Fe(100) promoted with four technologically relevant precious metals: Pd, Pt, Rh, and Ru. The resultant LG CEs have remarkable predictive accuracy, with predictive errors below 10 meV/site over a coverage range of 0 to 2 monolayers. The ground state configurations for each noble metal were identified, and the analysis of the cluster energies reveals a significant disparity in their dispersion tendency.</description>
      <author>Isaac G. Onyango, Greg Collinge, Yong Wang, Jean&#8208;Sabin McEwen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noble metal-free CZTS electrocatalysis: synergetic characteristics and emerging applications towards water splitting reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1394191</link>
      <description>Somnath C. Dhawale, Renuka V. Digraskar, Anil V. Ghule, Bhaskar R. Sathe, Frontiers in chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399177549

                This review provides a comprehensive overview of the production and modification of CZTS nanoparticles (NPs) and their application in electrocatalysis for water splitting. Various aspects, including surface modification, heterostructure design with carbon nanostructured materials, and tunable electrocatalytic studies, are discussed. A key focus is the synthesis of small CZTS nanoparticles with tunable reactivity, emphasizing the sonochemical method&#8217;s role in their formation. Despite CZTS&#8217;s affordability, it often exhibits poor hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) behavior. Carbon materials like graphene, carbon nanotubes, and C 60 are highlighted for their ability to enhance electrocatalytic activity due to their unique properties. The review also discusses the amine functionalization of graphene oxide/CZTS composites, which enhances overall water splitting performance. Doping with non-noble metals such as Fe, Co., and Ni is presented as an effective strategy to improve catalytic activity. Additionally, the synthesis of heterostructures consisting of CZTS nanoparticles attached to MoS 2 -reduced graphene oxide (rGO) hybrids is explored, showing enhanced HER activity compared to pure CZTS and MoS 2 . The growing demand for energy and the need for efficient renewable energy sources, particularly hydrogen generation, are driving research in this field. The review aims to demonstrate the potential of CZTS-based electrocatalysts for high-performance and cost-effective hydrogen generation with low environmental impact. Vacuum-based and non-vacuum-based methods for fabricating CZTS are discussed, with a focus on simplicity and efficiency. Future developments in CZTS-based electrocatalysts include enhancing activity and stability, improving charge transfer mechanisms, ensuring cost-effectiveness and scalability, increasing durability, integrating with renewable energy sources, and gaining deeper insight into reaction processes. Overall, CZTS-based electrocatalysts show great promise for sustainable hydrogen generation, with ongoing research focused on improving performance and advancing their practical applications.</description>
      <author>Somnath C. Dhawale, Renuka V. Digraskar, Anil V. Ghule, Bhaskar R. Sathe</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1394191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Parallel Algorithm for Graph Neural Network Interatomic Potentials in Molecular Dynamics Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00190</link>
      <description>Yutack Park, Jaesun Kim, Seungwoo Hwang, Seungwu Han, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399178686

                Message-passing graph neural network interatomic potentials (GNN-IPs), particularly those with equivariant representations such as NequIP, are attracting significant attention due to their data efficiency and high accuracy. However, parallelizing GNN-IPs poses challenges because multiple message-passing layers complicate data communication within the spatial decomposition method, which is preferred by many molecular dynamics (MD) packages. In this article, we propose an efficient parallelization scheme compatible with GNN-IPs and develop a package, SevenNet (Scalable EquiVariance-Enabled Neural NETwork), based on the NequIP architecture. For MD simulations, SevenNet interfaces with the LAMMPS package. Through benchmark tests on a 32-GPU cluster with examples of SiO2, SevenNet achieves over 80% parallel efficiency in weak-scaling scenarios and exhibits nearly ideal strong-scaling performance as long as GPUs are fully utilized. However, the strong-scaling performance significantly declines with suboptimal GPU utilization, particularly affecting parallel efficiency in cases involving lightweight models or simulations with small numbers of atoms. We also pretrain SevenNet with a vast data set from the Materials Project (dubbed "SevenNet-0") and assess its performance on generating amorphous Si3N4 containing more than 100,000 atoms. By developing scalable GNN-IPs, this work aims to bridge the gap between advanced machine-learning models and large-scale MD simulations, offering researchers a powerful tool to explore complex material systems with high accuracy and efficiency.</description>
      <author>Yutack Park, Jaesun Kim, Seungwoo Hwang, Seungwu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoinduced dynamics during electronic transfer from narrow to wide bandgap layers in one-dimensional heterostructured materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48880-3</link>
      <description>Yuri Saida, Thomas Gauthier, Hiroo Suzuki, Satoshi Ohmura, Ryo Shikata, Y. Iwasaki, Godai Noyama, Misaki Kishibuchi, Yuichiro Tanaka, Wataru Yajima, Nicolas Godin, Ga&#235;l Privault, Tomoharu Tokunaga, Shota Ono, Shin&#8208;ya Koshihara, Kenji Tsuruta, Y&#251;ji Hayashi, Roman Bertoni, Masaki Hada, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399179133

                Abstract Electron transfer is a fundamental energy conversion process widely present in synthetic, industrial, and natural systems. Understanding the electron transfer process is important to exploit the uniqueness of the low-dimensional van der Waals (vdW) heterostructures because interlayer electron transfer produces the function of this class of material. Here, we show the occurrence of an electron transfer process in one-dimensional layer-stacking of carbon nanotubes (CNTs) and boron nitride nanotubes (BNNTs). This observation makes use of femtosecond broadband optical spectroscopy, ultrafast time-resolved electron diffraction, and first-principles theoretical calculations. These results reveal that near-ultraviolet photoexcitation induces an electron transfer from the conduction bands of CNT to BNNT layers via electronic decay channels. This physical process subsequently generates radial phonons in the one-dimensional vdW heterostructure material. The gathered insights unveil the fundamentals physics of interfacial interactions in low dimensional vdW heterostructures and their photoinduced dynamics, pushing their limits for photoactive multifunctional applications.</description>
      <author>Yuri Saida, Thomas Gauthier, Hiroo Suzuki, Satoshi Ohmura, Ryo Shikata, Y. Iwasaki, Godai Noyama, Misaki Kishibuchi, Yuichiro Tanaka, Wataru Yajima, Nicolas Godin, Ga&#235;l Privault, Tomoharu Tokunaga, Shota Ono, Shin&#8208;ya Koshihara, Kenji Tsuruta, Y&#251;ji Hayashi, Roman Bertoni, Masaki Hada</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48880-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-Scheme Boron Phosphide/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure with Excellent Light Conversion Ability for Solar Cells and Water Splitting Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03567</link>
      <description>Yuncai Jiang, Shuangying Lei, Mingyuan Wang, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399180955

                Monolayer molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) with a suitable direct band gap and strong optical absorption is very attractive for utilization in solar cells and photocatalytic water splitting. Nevertheless, the broader utilization of MoS2 is impeded by its low carrier mobility and limited responsiveness to infrared light. To overcome these challenges, we constructed a variety of stackings for the boron phosphide (BP)/MoS2 van der Waals heterostructure (vdWH), all of which display S-scheme band alignments except for the AC&#8242; stacking. The constituent BP monolayer has superior carrier mobility and strong infrared and visible light response, which makes up for the shortcomings of MoS2. The study revealed that the AB stacking exhibits a remarkable power conversion efficiency of 22.27%, indicating its significant application prospect in solar cells. Additionally, the AB stacking also exhibits a promising application prospect in photocatalytic water splitting due to its suitable band structure, S-scheme band alignment, strong optical adsorption characteristic, high solar-to-hydrogen efficiency, and robust built-in electric field. Meanwhile, applying uniaxial tensile strains along the x-axis direction is more beneficial for photocatalytic water splitting. Hence, the AB-stacked BP/MoS2 vdWH shows significant potential for use in both solar cells and photocatalytic water splitting. This work paves the way for exploring the application of S-scheme heterostructures in solar energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Yuncai Jiang, Shuangying Lei, Mingyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Double Layer Effect on the Outer-Sphere Benzyl Halides Electro-Reduction Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08224</link>
      <description>Aleksandr S. Kramarenko, Ivan Yu. Chernyshov, Evgeny A. Pidko, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399181814

                Electrocatalytic reduction of organic halides and subsequent carboxylation are promising methods for the valorization of CO2 as a C1 source in synthetic organic chemistry. The reaction mechanism underlying the selectivity and reduction mechanism of benzyl halides is highly dependent on the nature of the electrode material as well as the processes, composition, and structure of the liquid phase at the electrode&#8211;solution interface. Herein, we present a computational study on the influence of the electric double layer (EDL) on the activation of benzyl halides at different applied potentials over the Au (111) cathode. Using a multiscale modeling approach, we demonstrate that, under realistic electrocatalytic conditions, the formation of a dense EDL over the cathode hampers the diffusion of benzyl halides toward the electrode surface. A combination of classical molecular dynamics simulations and density functional theory calculations reveals the most favorable benzyl halide electro-carboxylation pathway over the EDL that does not require direct substrate adsorption to the cathode surface. The dense EDL promotes the dissociative reduction of the benzyl halides via the outer-sphere electron transfer from the cathode surface to the electrolyte. Such a reduction mechanism results in a benzyl radical intermediate, which is then converted to benzyl anions in the EDL via an additional electron transfer step.</description>
      <author>Aleksandr S. Kramarenko, Ivan Yu. Chernyshov, Evgeny A. Pidko</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small amount but big impact: Trace oxygen interstitially inserted PtCu alloys by microalloying for efficient oxygen reduction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6730-2</link>
      <description>Qiheng Wang, Zhiguo Chen, Jingyan Zhang, Jingjun Liu, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399194593

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiheng Wang, Zhiguo Chen, Jingyan Zhang, Jingjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6730-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing the ethanol pathway during the competitive photocatalytic CO2 reduction in a defective transition metal dichalcogenide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124260</link>
      <description>Hongyu Chen, Linghui Wang, Deng Long, Yibo Zeng, Shigui Jiang, Weijia Chen, Caiyuan Zhao, Chu Cheng, Yan&#8208;Xin Chen, Miao L&#252;, Shuang Li, X. Y. Chen, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399209149

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongyu Chen, Linghui Wang, Deng Long, Yibo Zeng, Shigui Jiang, Weijia Chen, Caiyuan Zhao, Chu Cheng, Yan&#8208;Xin Chen, Miao L&#252;, Shuang Li, X. Y. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Ni-doped Co3O4 oxygen evolution catalysts for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.365</link>
      <description>Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, N. Krishna Chandar, Nisha Devi, Hai Lin, Cheng-Che Huang, Xin-Yu Jiang, Yuan-Yao Li, G. Arthanareeswaran, Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, Neeraj K. Jaiswal, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399212076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, N. Krishna Chandar, Nisha Devi, Hai Lin, Cheng-Che Huang, Xin-Yu Jiang, Yuan-Yao Li, G. Arthanareeswaran, Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, Neeraj K. Jaiswal, Yong&#8208;Song Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excitation signatures of isochorically heated electrons in solids at finite wave number explored from first principles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevresearch.6.023219</link>
      <description>Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Thomas Gawne, Sebastian Schwalbe, Thomas R. Preston, Jan Vorberger, Tobias Dornheim, Physical review research. 6(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399212971

                Ultrafast heating of solids with modern x-ray free electron lasers (XFELs) leads to a unique set of conditions characterized by the simultaneous presence of heated electrons in a cold ionic lattice. In this work, we analyze the effect of electronic heating on the dynamic structure factor (DSF) in bulk aluminum (Al) with a face-centered cubic lattice and in silicon (Si) with a crystal diamond structure using first-principles linear-response time-dependent density functional theory simulations. We find a thermally induced red shift of the collective plasmon excitation in both materials. In addition, we show that the heating of the electrons in Al can lead to the formation of a double-plasmon peak due to the extension of the Landau damping region to smaller wave numbers. Finally, we demonstrate that thermal effects generate a measurable and distinct signature (peak-valley structure) in the DSF of Si at small frequencies. Our simulations indicate a variety of new features in the spectrum of x-ray-driven solids, specifically at finite momentum transfer, which can be probed in upcoming x-ray Thomson scattering experiments at various XFEL facilities. Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Thomas Gawne, Sebastian Schwalbe, Thomas R. Preston, Jan Vorberger, Tobias Dornheim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevresearch.6.023219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Degradation of Iron&#8211;Nitrogen&#8211;Carbon Heterogeneous Molecular Catalysts with Electron-Donating/Withdrawing Substituents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01752</link>
      <description>Fangzhou Liu, Di Zhang, Fangxin She, Zixun Yu, Leo Lai, Hao Li, Wei Li, Yuan Chen, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399213497

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangzhou Liu, Di Zhang, Fangxin She, Zixun Yu, Leo Lai, Hao Li, Wei Li, Yuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Pentagonal Layered Palladium Diselenide Enables Rapid Electrosynthesis of Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c00875</link>
      <description>R. Dominic Ross, Kwanpyung Lee, Gerardo J. Quintana Cintr&#243;n, Kaylin Xu, Hongyuan Sheng, J. R. Schmidt, Song Jin, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399229319

                Electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H</description>
      <author>R. Dominic Ross, Kwanpyung Lee, Gerardo J. Quintana Cintr&#243;n, Kaylin Xu, Hongyuan Sheng, J. R. Schmidt, Song Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c00875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-Derived LDHs: Unveiling Their Potential in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100128</link>
      <description>Mohammad Etesami, Shiva Rezaei Motlagh, Ramin Khezri, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Myong Yong Choi, Kasidit Nootong, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Soorathep Kheawhom, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammad Etesami, Shiva Rezaei Motlagh, Ramin Khezri, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Myong Yong Choi, Kasidit Nootong, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disordering of Rh(111) Single Crystalline Electrode Surface in O2 Saturated Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144524</link>
      <description>Da Zhou, Dan Zhao, Yao Yao, Yan&#8208;Xia Chen, Shen Ye, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399242942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Da Zhou, Dan Zhao, Yao Yao, Yan&#8208;Xia Chen, Shen Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy&#8208;Driven Ostwald Ripening Reversal Promotes the Formation of Low&#8208;Platinum Intermetallic Fuel Cell Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401134</link>
      <description>S. F. Li, Peng Yin, Cong Xu, Kun&#8208;Ze Xue, Yuan Kong, Ming J. Zuo, Wan&#8208;Qun Zhang, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399247819

                Abstract Strain engineering has been widely used to optimize platinum&#8208;based oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts for proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). PtM 3 (M is base metals), a well&#8208;known high&#8208;compressive&#8208;strain intermetallic alloy, shows promise as a low platinum ORR catalyst due to high intrinsic activity. However, during the alloying of Pt with a threefold amount of M, a notable phase separation between Pt and M may occur, with M particles rapidly sintering while Pt particles grow slowly, posing a challenge in achieving a well&#8208;defined PtM 3 intermetallic alloy. Here, an entropy&#8208;driven Ostwald ripening reversal phenomenon is discovered that enables the synthesis of small&#8208;sized Pt(FeCoNiCu) 3 intermetallic ORR catalysts. High entropy promotes the thermodynamic driving force for the alloying Pt with M, which triggers the Ostwald ripening reversal of sintered FeCoNiCu particles and facilitates the formation of uniform Pt(FeCoNiCu) 3 intermetallic catalysts. The prepared Pt(FeCoNiCu) 3 catalysts exhibit a high specific activity of 3.82 mA cm &#8722;2 , along with a power density of &#8776;1.3 W cm &#8722;2 at 0.67 V and 94 &#176;C with a cathode Pt loading of 0.1 mg cm &#8722;2 in H 2 &#8211;air fuel cell.</description>
      <author>S. F. Li, Peng Yin, Cong Xu, Kun&#8208;Ze Xue, Yuan Kong, Ming J. Zuo, Wan&#8208;Qun Zhang, Hai&#8208;Wei Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly active Mn2O3-Fe3O4 catalyst with abundant metal-oxygen bonds for real time sensing of carbendazim in environmental samples</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2024.06.001</link>
      <description>Saravana Pandi Sivaji, Subramaniyan Pulikkutty, Shen&#8208;Ming Chen, Shen&#8208;Ming Chen, Wedad A. Al-onazi, Tahani Saad Algarni, Mohamed S. Elshikh, Process safety and environmental protection/Transactions of the Institution of Chemical Engineers. Part B, Process safety and environmental protection/Chemical engineering research and design/Chemical engineering research &amp; design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399255455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saravana Pandi Sivaji, Subramaniyan Pulikkutty, Shen&#8208;Ming Chen, Shen&#8208;Ming Chen, Wedad A. Al-onazi, Tahani Saad Algarni, Mohamed S. Elshikh</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2024.06.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Atom Binding Energy of Structurally Well-Defined Cerium Oxide Nodes at the Metal&#8211;Organic Framework&#8211;Liquid Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02409</link>
      <description>Zachary Ingram, Chance Lander, Madeleine C. Oliver, Nazmiye G&#246;k&#231;e Alt&#305;n&#231;eki&#231;, Liangliang Huang, Yihan Shao, Hyunho Noh, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399256990

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zachary Ingram, Chance Lander, Madeleine C. Oliver, Nazmiye G&#246;k&#231;e Alt&#305;n&#231;eki&#231;, Liangliang Huang, Yihan Shao, Hyunho Noh</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantification of alloy atomic composition sites in 2D ternary MoS2(1-x)Se2x and their role in persistent photoconductivity, enhanced photoresponse and photo-electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtadv.2024.100504</link>
      <description>Ravi K. Biroju, Dipak Maity, Viliam Vreten&#225;r, &#317;ubom&#237;r Van&#269;o, Rahul Sharma, Madhusmita Sahoo, Jitendra Kumar, G. Gayathri, Tharangattu N. Narayanan, Saroj K. Nayak, Materials today advances. 22(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399257409

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ravi K. Biroju, Dipak Maity, Viliam Vreten&#225;r, &#317;ubom&#237;r Van&#269;o, Rahul Sharma, Madhusmita Sahoo, Jitendra Kumar, G. Gayathri, Tharangattu N. Narayanan, Saroj K. Nayak</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtadv.2024.100504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into the activity of the N doped graphene quantum dots for oxygen reduction reaction as a function of the shape and edge terminations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114243</link>
      <description>Raluca-Ioana Jalb&#259;, Drago&#537; Lucian Isac, &#536;tefan Gabriel Soriga, Isabela C. Man, Molecular catalysis. 563(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399262784

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Raluca-Ioana Jalb&#259;, Drago&#537; Lucian Isac, &#536;tefan Gabriel Soriga, Isabela C. Man</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Searching COVID-19 Clinical Research Using Graph Queries: Algorithm Development and Validation (Preprint)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2196/preprints.52655</link>
      <description>Francesco Invernici, Anna Bernasconi, Stefano Ceri, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4399173353

                 BACKGROUND Since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, &amp;gt;1 million studies have been collected within the COVID-19 Open Research Dataset, a corpus of manuscripts created to accelerate research against the disease. Their related abstracts hold a wealth of information that remains largely unexplored and difficult to search due to its unstructured nature. Keyword-based search is the standard approach, which allows users to retrieve the documents of a corpus that contain (all or some of) the words in a target list. This type of search, however, does not provide visual support to the task and is not suited to expressing complex queries or compensating for missing specifications.   OBJECTIVE This study aims to consider small graphs of concepts and exploit them for expressing graph searches over existing COVID-19&#8211;related literature, leveraging the increasing use of graphs to represent and query scientific knowledge and providing a user-friendly search and exploration experience.   METHODS We considered the COVID-19 Open Research Dataset corpus and summarized its content by annotating the publications&#8217; abstracts using terms selected from the Unified Medical Language System and the Ontology of Coronavirus Infectious Disease. Then, we built a co-occurrence network that includes all relevant concepts mentioned in the corpus, establishing connections when their mutual information is relevant. A sophisticated graph query engine was built to allow the identification of the best matches of graph queries on the network. It also supports partial matches and suggests potential query completions using shortest paths.   RESULTS We built a large co-occurrence network, consisting of 128,249 entities and 47,198,965 relationships; the GRAPH-SEARCH interface allows users to explore the network by formulating or adapting graph queries; it produces a bibliography of publications, which are globally ranked; and each publication is further associated with the specific parts of the query that it explains, thereby allowing the user to understand each aspect of the matching.   CONCLUSIONS Our approach supports the process of query formulation and evidence search upon a large text corpus; it can be reapplied to any scientific domain where documents corpora and curated ontologies are made available. </description>
      <author>Francesco Invernici, Anna Bernasconi, Stefano Ceri</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2196/preprints.52655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin 2D Alloyed Cu&#8722;Ga&#8722;Zn&#8722;S Curved Nanobelts for Boosting Visible&#8208;Light Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407271</link>
      <description>Yu Liu, Mengmeng Ma, Yi Ding, Qi Zhou, Jie Chen, Yangyang Bian, Wentao Niu, Chunhe Yang, Zhe Yin, Zhijie Wang, Aiwei Tang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399079659

                Abstract 2D semiconductor nanomaterials have received significant attention as photocatalysts for solar&#8208;to&#8208;hydrogen conversion due to their robust light absorption capacity, large specific surface area, and superior electron transport characteristics. Nevertheless, it is challenging to develop 2D quaternary copper&#8208;based sulfides (QCSs) with functional integration of conducive structural features for photocatalysis from multiple elements and intricate control conditions. Herein, ultrathin 2D alloyed Cu&#8722;Ga&#8722;Zn&#8722;S (CGZS) curved nanobelts (NBs) are fabricated by using a facile one&#8208;pot colloidal method. Subsequently, the derived Cu 31 S 16 &#8208;CGZS Janus heterostructures are designed by increasing Cu concentrations. The formation mechanism of 2D curved alloys and Janus heterostructures is systematically investigated. Without cocatalysts, curved alloyed CGZS NBs demonstrated superior photocatalytic activities of 1264.2 &#181;mol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 compared to Janus heterostructured Cu 31 S 16 &#8722;CGZS (463.1 &#181;mol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 ) under visible light (&gt; 400 nm). Experimental and theoretical results unveiled that the improved photocatalytic activities of curved CGZS NBs can be attributed to enhanced charge&#8211;carrier separation efficiency resulting from high crystallinity and ultrathin 2D structure, abundant active sites from curved structure, high&#8208;active (0001) crystal facet with the lowest reaction Gibbs energy, work function, and metal&#8208;like properties. This work offers new insights into functional integration into ultrathin 2D QCSs with enhanced visible&#8208;light photocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Yu Liu, Mengmeng Ma, Yi Ding, Qi Zhou, Jie Chen, Yangyang Bian, Wentao Niu, Chunhe Yang, Zhe Yin, Zhijie Wang, Aiwei Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational exploration of two-dimensional vacancy-free boridene sheet and its derivatives: high stabilities and the promise for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.80</link>
      <description>Yixin Zhao, Jincan Zhang, Fengxian Ma, Hongbo Wu, Weizhen Meng, Ying Liu, Yalong Jiao, Aijun Du, Microstructures. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399090575

                The recent synthesis of a two-dimensional (2D) MBene sheet, referred to as the boridene sheet (Mo4B6Tz), has ignited considerable interest in exploring 2D transition metal borides. Boridene has an ordered arrangement of metal vacancies, which are pivotal to its stability. Employing first-principles calculations, we explored the stable phases, electronic properties and catalytic abilities of boridene with different vacancy concentrations (Vm). Our results demonstrate that Vm significantly influences the cohesive energies of boridene sheets. Phonon spectrum and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations reveal the high stability of the vacancy-free boridene Mo6B6T6 (T = O, -OH), underscoring their potential for experimental realization. Substituting Mo atoms with Nb, Ta, or W enhances the structural stability of boridene sheets, leading to the identification of four stable variants: Nb6B6F6, Ta6B6F6, Ta6B6O6, and W6B6O6. These boridene sheets exhibit metallic behavior, with five structures displaying near-zero Gibbs free energy for hydrogen atom adsorption, indicating their potential as catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction. The uncovering of vacancy-free boridenes and their 2D derivatives greatly broadens the scope of the MBene family.</description>
      <author>Yixin Zhao, Jincan Zhang, Fengxian Ma, Hongbo Wu, Weizhen Meng, Ying Liu, Yalong Jiao, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.80</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PACMAN: A Robust Partial Atomic Charge Predicter for Nanoporous Materials Based on Crystal Graph Convolution Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00434</link>
      <description>Guobin Zhao, Yongchul G. Chung, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399259267

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guobin Zhao, Yongchul G. Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00434</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
