<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 01:18:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening of transition metal atom doped ZnS and ZnSe nanostructures as promising bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04011b</link>
      <description>Feifei Xia, Shu Li, Fengli Yang, Yingpin Wen, Chunzhi Zheng, RSC Advances. 14(40)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402491900

                The design of bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts showing high catalytic performance for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is of great significance for developing new renewable energy storage and conversion technologies. Herein, based on the first principles calculations, we systematically explored the electrocatalytic activity of a series of transition metal atom (Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Pd and Pt)-doped ZnS and ZnSe nanostructures for OER and ORR. The calculated results revealed that Ni- and Pt-doped ZnS and ZnSe nanostructures exhibit promising electrocatalytic performance for both OER and ORR in comparison to the pristine ZnS and ZnSe nanostructures. Especially, the OER/ORR overpotentials of Ni-doped ZnS and ZnSe nanostructures are estimated to be 0.28/0.30 and 0.31/0.31 V, respectively, disclosing their great potential as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts. Moreover, it is found that Ni-doped ZnS and ZnSe nanostructures for OER and ORR are on the top of the volcano plots, evincing promising catalytic performance. Our results provide theoretical insights into a feasible strategy to synthesize highly efficient ZnS- and ZnSe-based bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Feifei Xia, Shu Li, Fengli Yang, Yingpin Wen, Chunzhi Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04011b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Direct Methane to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15740-0.00130-0</link>
      <description>Ebrahim Ghanbari, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402559239

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ebrahim Ghanbari, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15740-0.00130-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equivariance is essential, local representation is a need: A comprehensive and critical study of machine learning potentials for tobermorite phases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113363</link>
      <description>Keming Zhu, Zhibin Zhang, Computational Materials Science. 246(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402565410

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Keming Zhu, Zhibin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Reliable Conformational Energies of Amino Acids and Dipeptides&#9472;The DipCONFS Benchmark and DipCONL Datasets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00801</link>
      <description>Christoph Plett, Stefan Grimme, Andreas Hansen, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402435288

                Simulating peptides and proteins is becoming increasingly important, leading to a growing need for efficient computational methods. These are typically semiempirical quantum mechanical (SQM) methods, force fields (FFs), or machine-learned interatomic potentials (MLIPs), all of which require a large amount of accurate data for robust training and evaluation. To assess potential reference methods and complement the available data, we introduce two sets, DipCONFL and DipCONFS, which cover large parts of the conformational space of 17 amino acids and their 289 possible dipeptides in aqueous solution. The conformers were selected from the exhaustive PeptideCS dataset by Andris et al. [</description>
      <author>Christoph Plett, Stefan Grimme, Andreas Hansen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Machine Learning Potentials for In-Situ Searching of Active sites in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00051</link>
      <description>Xiran Cheng, Cheng-Yen Wu, Jiayan Xu, Yulan Han, Wenping Xie, P. Hu, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402438846

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiran Cheng, Cheng-Yen Wu, Jiayan Xu, Yulan Han, Wenping Xie, P. Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core structure of dislocations in ordered ferromagnetic FeCo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.093604</link>
      <description>A. D. Egorov, Antoine Kraych, Matous Mrovec, Ralf Drautz, Thomas Hammerschmidt, Physical Review Materials. 8(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402440524

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. D. Egorov, Antoine Kraych, Matous Mrovec, Ralf Drautz, Thomas Hammerschmidt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.093604</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ surface activation of polycrystalline LaNiO3 electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.038</link>
      <description>Giuditta De Amicis, Anna Testolin, Cristina Cazzaniga, F. D&#8217;Acapito, Alessandro Minguzzi, Paolo Ghigna, Alberto Vertova, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 87(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402440638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Giuditta De Amicis, Anna Testolin, Cristina Cazzaniga, F. D&#8217;Acapito, Alessandro Minguzzi, Paolo Ghigna, Alberto Vertova</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable long-lived exciton lifetime and high carrier mobilities in Group III A elements doped two-dimensional blue phosphorene: A time domain &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219326</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, Yulong Qiu, Caifeng Zhou, Hao Dong, Applied Physics Letters. 125(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402443529

                In this Letter, we combine first-principles calculations with the non-adiabatic molecular dynamics (NAMD) method to investigate the photocatalytic and excited-state properties of blue phosphorene (BlueP). Doping with Group III A elements not only maintains an appropriate bandgap and band edge positions for photocatalytic water splitting but also converts the indirect bandgap of BlueP to a direct bandgap, significantly enhancing photon absorption efficiency. The dopants effectively improve optical absorption in the visible and ultraviolet light regions, potentially enabling a solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency of 22.3% in the photocatalytic water splitting process. In NAMD calculations, we consider the dynamics of the electron&#8211;hole pair recombination process between the valence band maximum and conduction band minimum. We demonstrate the regulatory impact of dopant elements, temperature, and non-adiabatic coupling strength on the exciton lifetime of doped BlueP through ab initio molecular dynamics and NAMD methods. This study reveals the relationship between the charge transfer mechanism and non-adiabatic coupling in low-dimensional materials, offering valuable insights into the excited-state properties of optoelectronic materials. Ultimately, our findings contribute to the development of tunable, long-lived exciton lifetimes and high carrier mobilities in doped BlueP, which hold significant potential for photocatalytic water splitting to generate hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, Yulong Qiu, Caifeng Zhou, Hao Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles investigation of H2O2 electrosynthesis on Cu-C24N24 single-atom catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114520</link>
      <description>Junkai Wang, Yifei Wang, Zhenxia Huang, Qianku Hu, Aiguo Zhou, Shaowei Zhang, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402467532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junkai Wang, Yifei Wang, Zhenxia Huang, Qianku Hu, Aiguo Zhou, Shaowei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114520</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Composition-Dependent Catalytic Mechanism of Pt&#8211;Ni Alloys for Oxygen Reduction: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02164</link>
      <description>Zhiyuan Xia, Xiangyu Zhu, Xing Chen, Yanan Zhou, Qiquan Luo, Jinlong Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402469323

                Unveiling the composition-dependent catalytic mechanism of Pt-based alloy cathodes for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) helps improve the proton exchange membrane fuel cells. Using density functional theory calculations, this study investigates the ORR catalytic performance of the Pt-Ni system with various compositions (1.00, &#8764;0.99, 0.75, 0.50, 0.25, &#8764;0.01, and 0.00). The ordered solid solution PtNi</description>
      <author>Zhiyuan Xia, Xiangyu Zhu, Xing Chen, Yanan Zhou, Qiquan Luo, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvent-mediated oxide hydrogenation in layered cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adg4687</link>
      <description>Gang Wan, Travis P. Pollard, Lin Ma, Marshall A. Schroeder, Chia&#8208;Chin Chen, Zihua Zhu, Zhan Zhang, Cheng Sun, Jiyu Cai, Harry L. Thaman, Art&#363;ras Vailionis, Haoyuan Li, Shelly D. Kelly, Zhenxing Feng, Joseph B. Franklin, Steven P. Harvey, Ye Zhang, Yingge Du, Zonghai Chen, Christopher J. Tassone, Hans&#8208;Georg Steinr&#252;ck, Quanquan Pang, Oleg Borodin, Michael F. Toney, Science. 385(6714)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402475620

                Self-discharge and chemically induced mechanical effects degrade calendar and cycle life in intercalation-based electrochromic and electrochemical energy storage devices. In rechargeable lithium-ion batteries, self-discharge in cathodes causes voltage and capacity loss over time. The prevailing self-discharge model centers on the diffusion of lithium ions from the electrolyte into the cathode. We demonstrate an alternative pathway, where hydrogenation of layered transition metal oxide cathodes induces self-discharge through hydrogen transfer from carbonate solvents to delithiated oxides. In self-discharged cathodes, we further observe opposing proton and lithium ion concentration gradients, which contribute to chemical and structural heterogeneities within delithiated cathodes, accelerating degradation. Hydrogenation occurring in delithiated cathodes may affect the chemo-mechanical coupling of layered cathodes as well as the calendar life of lithium-ion batteries.</description>
      <author>Gang Wan, Travis P. Pollard, Lin Ma, Marshall A. Schroeder, Chia&#8208;Chin Chen, Zihua Zhu, Zhan Zhang, Cheng Sun, Jiyu Cai, Harry L. Thaman, Art&#363;ras Vailionis, Haoyuan Li, Shelly D. Kelly, Zhenxing Feng, Joseph B. Franklin, Steven P. Harvey, Ye Zhang, Yingge Du, Zonghai Chen, Christopher J. Tassone, Hans&#8208;Georg Steinr&#252;ck, Quanquan Pang, Oleg Borodin, Michael F. Toney</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adg4687</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physics-Informed Active Learning for Accelerating Quantum Chemical Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00821</link>
      <description>Yi-Fan Hou, Lina Zhang, Quanhao Zhang, Fuchun Ge, Pavlo O. Dral, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402477242

                Quantum chemical simulations can be greatly accelerated by constructing machine learning potentials, which is often done using active learning (AL). The usefulness of the constructed potentials is often limited by the high effort required and their insufficient robustness in the simulations. Here, we introduce the end-to-end AL for constructing robust data-efficient potentials with affordable investment of time and resources and minimum human interference. Our AL protocol is based on the physics-informed sampling of training points, automatic selection of initial data, uncertainty quantification, and convergence monitoring. The versatility of this protocol is shown in our implementation of quasi-classical molecular dynamics for simulating vibrational spectra, conformer search of a key biochemical molecule, and time-resolved mechanism of the Diels-Alder reaction. These investigations took us days instead of weeks of pure quantum chemical calculations on a high-performance computing cluster.</description>
      <author>Yi-Fan Hou, Lina Zhang, Quanhao Zhang, Fuchun Ge, Pavlo O. Dral</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure, Bonding, and Vibrational Dynamics of a Triamine High Energy Density Material under Pressure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03637</link>
      <description>Zachary L. Whipple, Roma R. Ripani, Janki Brahmbhatt, Muhtar Ahart, Nilesh P. Salke, Yue Meng, Zhenxian Liu, Stella Chariton, Stephen A. Gramsch, Santanu Chaudhuri, Emmanuele Parisi, Roberto Centore, Russell J. Hemley, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402477400

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zachary L. Whipple, Roma R. Ripani, Janki Brahmbhatt, Muhtar Ahart, Nilesh P. Salke, Yue Meng, Zhenxian Liu, Stella Chariton, Stephen A. Gramsch, Santanu Chaudhuri, Emmanuele Parisi, Roberto Centore, Russell J. Hemley</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Plasmonic Catalysis via Strong Coupling with Electromagnetic Resonators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03153</link>
      <description>Jakub Fojt, Paul Erhart, C. Sch&#228;fer, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402477650

                Plasmonic excitations decay within femtoseconds, leaving nonthermal (often referred to as "hot") charge carriers behind that can be injected into molecular structures to trigger chemical reactions that are otherwise out of reach&#9472;a process known as plasmonic catalysis. In this Letter, we demonstrate that strong coupling between resonator structures and plasmonic nanoparticles can be used to control the spectral overlap between the plasmonic excitation energy and the charge injection energy into nearby molecules. Our atomistic description couples real-time density-functional theory self-consistently to an electromagnetic resonator structure via the radiation-reaction potential. Control over the resonator provides then an additional knob for nonintrusively enhancing plasmonic catalysis, here more than 6-fold, and dynamically reacting to deterioration of the catalyst&#9472;a new facet of modern catalysis.</description>
      <author>Jakub Fojt, Paul Erhart, C. Sch&#228;fer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Polymer End Groups on the Formation of Solid Electrolyte Interphase at the Lithium Metal Interface: A First-Principles Calculations Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03261</link>
      <description>Kazem Zhour, Andreas Heuer, Diddo Diddens, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402480543

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kazem Zhour, Andreas Heuer, Diddo Diddens</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneity in Point Defect Distribution and Mobility in Solid Ion Conductors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12128</link>
      <description>Md Salman Rabbi Limon, Zeeshan Ahmad, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402482224

                Alkali metal anodes paired with solid ion conductors offer promising avenues for enhancing battery energy density and safety. To facilitate rapid ion transport crucial for fast charging and discharging of batteries, it is essential to understand the behavior of point defects in these conductors. In this study, we investigate the heterogeneity of defect distribution in two prototypical solid ion conductors, Li</description>
      <author>Md Salman Rabbi Limon, Zeeshan Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling O2 adsorption on non-metallic active site for selective photocatalytic H2O2 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124586</link>
      <description>Jindi Yang, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du, Mike Tebyetekerwa, Chuanbiao Bie, Xiaoyi Hu, Zhimeng Sun, Zhongguo Zhang, Xiangkang Zeng, Xiwang Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. 361(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402482477

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jindi Yang, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du, Mike Tebyetekerwa, Chuanbiao Bie, Xiaoyi Hu, Zhimeng Sun, Zhongguo Zhang, Xiangkang Zeng, Xiwang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen evolution reaction on Ag12M icosahedrons: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141588</link>
      <description>Peter L. Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Kessler, Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402488700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peter L. Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Kessler, Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic studies on defective hBN-supported metal-nonmetal synergistic catalysis for urea electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161230</link>
      <description>Zi-Yang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402495689

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zi-Yang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal doped into layered double hydroxide as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161233</link>
      <description>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402495714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the role of Zn and Fe doping in nitrogen-carbon electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6962-1</link>
      <description>Yanan Zou, Yuanyuan Su, Yongchao Yu, Jinliang Luo, Xiaomin Kang, Jun Zhang, Linghan Lan, Tianshi Wang, Jun Li, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402500287

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Zou, Yuanyuan Su, Yongchao Yu, Jinliang Luo, Xiaomin Kang, Jun Zhang, Linghan Lan, Tianshi Wang, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6962-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supported Metallic Glass as a Highly Durable HER Electrode under Fluctuating Renewable Power</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c04017</link>
      <description>Liandong Li, Bing Lin, Hailong Zhang, J.C. Qiao, Takeshi Wada, Hidemi Kato, Junlei Tang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402503906

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liandong Li, Bing Lin, Hailong Zhang, J.C. Qiao, Takeshi Wada, Hidemi Kato, Junlei Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c04017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Role of Density Functional Approximation in Predicting M&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalyst Activities for Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03322</link>
      <description>Brett Henderson, Sofia Donnecke, Scott N. Genin, Ilya G. Ryabinkin, Irina Paci, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402504253

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brett Henderson, Sofia Donnecke, Scott N. Genin, Ilya G. Ryabinkin, Irina Paci</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119744856.ref</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402504857

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119744856.ref</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovations in Catalytic Understanding: A Journey through Advanced Characterization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2024.100061</link>
      <description>Ifeanyi Michael Smarte Anekwe, Stephen Okiemute Akpasi, Emeka Michael Enemuo, Darlington C. Ashiegbu, Sherif Ishola Mustapha, Yusuf Makarfi Isa, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402511815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ifeanyi Michael Smarte Anekwe, Stephen Okiemute Akpasi, Emeka Michael Enemuo, Darlington C. Ashiegbu, Sherif Ishola Mustapha, Yusuf Makarfi Isa</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2024.100061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the stability of binary copper oxide photocathodes and augmenting CuO water reduction performance: Comprehensive experimental and theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155692</link>
      <description>Angelina Mary, C. Murugan, K. Karthick, P. Murugan, Alagarsamy Pandikumar, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402519312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angelina Mary, C. Murugan, K. Karthick, P. Murugan, Alagarsamy Pandikumar</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earth-Abundant Electrocatalytic Material for Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-65902-7_8</link>
      <description>Sharadchandra S. Patil, Jyotiprakash B. Yadav, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402524041

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sharadchandra S. Patil, Jyotiprakash B. Yadav</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-65902-7_8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A cation exchange strategy to construct highly dispersed copper-doped CdS nanoparticles for photocatalytic hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.116</link>
      <description>Mingzhu Xue, Yuchen Dong, Xiaoyuan Ye, Xiangjiu Guan, Liejin Guo, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 87(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402530202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingzhu Xue, Yuchen Dong, Xiaoyuan Ye, Xiangjiu Guan, Liejin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Optimization of a Spin-Crossover Molecule on Monolayer MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Spin Transition-Induced Band Edge Shift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02110</link>
      <description>Yachao Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402534544

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yachao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of dual sites on FeS2 surface for enhanced electrocatalytic reduction of nitrite to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.120</link>
      <description>Heying Li, Xinyue Song, Nana Zhang, Ke Chu, Jingxiang Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402535516

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Heying Li, Xinyue Song, Nana Zhang, Ke Chu, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic synergies of melt-quenched Ni-Sn-Se-Te nanoalloy for direct seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155775</link>
      <description>John D. Rodney, Sindhur Joshi, Subhasmita Ray, L. Vaikunta Rao, S. Deepapriya, Karel Carva, Badekai Ramachandra Bhat, N.K. Udayashankar, Suresh Perumal, Sadhana Katlakunta, C. Justin Raj, Byung Chul Kim, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402538290

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John D. Rodney, Sindhur Joshi, Subhasmita Ray, L. Vaikunta Rao, S. Deepapriya, Karel Carva, Badekai Ramachandra Bhat, N.K. Udayashankar, Suresh Perumal, Sadhana Katlakunta, C. Justin Raj, Byung Chul Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the evolution of molybdenum-nitrogen doped carbon with long-term durability for efficient oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155778</link>
      <description>Xingyu Luo, Bingbao Mei, Ru Feng, Xiaofeng Xu, Zhongyan Zhang, Mingyu Ou, Fanfei Sun, Huajun Zheng, Meiqin Shi, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402546983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingyu Luo, Bingbao Mei, Ru Feng, Xiaofeng Xu, Zhongyan Zhang, Mingyu Ou, Fanfei Sun, Huajun Zheng, Meiqin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen spillover enhances the selective hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes on the Cu-O-Ce interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100438</link>
      <description>Jinyun Cui, Jing Wang, Teng Xu, Jiabao Lin, Kunlong Liu, Pengxin Liu, Chinese Journal of Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402557608

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinyun Cui, Jing Wang, Teng Xu, Jiabao Lin, Kunlong Liu, Pengxin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Selective Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Formic Acid Conversion: A First-Principles Study of Single-Atom and Dual-Atom Catalysts on Tin Disulfide Monolayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02283</link>
      <description>Guan-Ming Chen, Margherita Buraschi, Rashid Al-Heidous, Satyanarayana Bonakala, Fedwa El&#8208;Mellouhi, Clotilde S. Cucinotta, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402573649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guan-Ming Chen, Margherita Buraschi, Rashid Al-Heidous, Satyanarayana Bonakala, Fedwa El&#8208;Mellouhi, Clotilde S. Cucinotta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast joule-heating synthesis of FeCoMnCuAl high-entropy-alloy nanoparticles as efficient OER electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.08.005</link>
      <description>Xindong Zhu, Wen Huang, Yu Lou, Zhongzheng Yao, Huiqiang Ying, Min Dong, Lan Tan, Jianrong Zeng, Hua Ji, He Zhu, Si Lan, Progress in Natural Science Materials International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402472017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xindong Zhu, Wen Huang, Yu Lou, Zhongzheng Yao, Huiqiang Ying, Min Dong, Lan Tan, Jianrong Zeng, Hua Ji, He Zhu, Si Lan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.08.005</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
