<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 01:23:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>The Integration of Magnetic Fields and Catalysts for Clean Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501973</link>
      <description>Ziyong Zhang, Bo Feng, Junting Sun, Guowei Li, Zunming Lu, Junqiang Wang, Juntao Huo, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414793182

                Abstract Electrocatalysis is a crucial approach for achieving clean energy transitions, requiring highly efficient catalytic materials to expedite this process. However, overcoming the thermodynamic and kinetic constraints is key to discovering next&#8208;generation materials that are both cost&#8208;effective and efficient. The introduction of magnetic fields offers new opportunities for modulating the electronic structures of catalytic materials, optimizing the adsorption/desorption behavior of key intermediates, and enhancing catalytic efficiency. This review starts with the fundamental principles of classical electrocatalytic reactions, and revisits the main mechanisms by which magnetic fields affect magnetic catalytic materials and electrocatalytic systems, including magneto&#8208;thermal effects, magnetohydrodynamic effects, and spin&#8208;selective effects. Focusing on amorphous materials, topological materials, and metal oxides, the review highlights the design of magnetic catalytic materials, the control of magnetic structures, and their response behaviors to external fields. Finally, it discusses the major bottlenecks facing magnetic catalysis and its potential applications in other important small molecule catalytic transformations. This review provides a new perspective for understanding the essence of magnetic field chemistry and accelerating the development of catalytic materials aimed at applications.</description>
      <author>Ziyong Zhang, Bo Feng, Junting Sun, Guowei Li, Zunming Lu, Junqiang Wang, Juntao Huo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface microenvironment regulation of nitrogen-doped carbon via deep eutectic solvent for enhanced oxygen reaction kinetics in zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.122738</link>
      <description>Guowei Hao, Peng Wang, D. Yuhui Deng, Wei Zhang, Suqin Wu, Wenhao Zhang, Henan Li, Li Xu, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414797360

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guowei Hao, Peng Wang, D. Yuhui Deng, Wei Zhang, Suqin Wu, Wenhao Zhang, Henan Li, Li Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.122738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing How Acid Sites Enhance the Electrocatalytic Glycerol Oxidation Performance on Pt Loaded Zeolite&#8208;Carbon Composite Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202511220</link>
      <description>Ju Ye Kim, S.Y. No, Jinwoo Hwang, M.H. Yoo, Hak&#8208;Ju Lee, Youngbi Kim, Youngmin Kim, Yong Tae Kim, Jeong&#8208;Chul Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Kyoungsoo Kim, Hyung Ju Kim, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414812358

                Abstract The catalytic role and function of acid sites in solid acid catalysts, such as zeolites, are well understood in the context of heterogeneous catalytic reactions. But although many studies have highlighted the importance of acid sites, their catalytic effects in electrocatalytic reactions have rarely been investigated. In this work, a novel catalyst synthesis strategy is developed, integrating metal sites with acid sites for application in the electrocatalytic glycerol oxidation reaction (EGOR). Specifically, an ordered microporous carbon support containing acidic aluminum sites (AlYTC) is prepared through a nanocasting approach using a sacrificial zeolite template. Platinum (Pt) nanoclusters are then deposited onto the AlYTC support, forming a structure that exposes both acid sites and Pt nanoclusters on a zeolite&#8208;templated 3D carbon framework (PtAlYTC). The prepared PtAlYTC catalyst demonstrates a turnover frequency (TOF, s &#8722;1 ) 30 times higher and a reaction rate () 17 times greater than those of a Pt catalyst lacking acid sites (PtYTC) in the EGOR. First&#8208;principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that the combination of Pt sites and acidic Al sites lowers the Gibbs free energy of key reaction steps, improves charge transfer, and strengthens hydrogen adsorption, thereby significantly enhancing the catalytic performance in EGOR.</description>
      <author>Ju Ye Kim, S.Y. No, Jinwoo Hwang, M.H. Yoo, Hak&#8208;Ju Lee, Youngbi Kim, Youngmin Kim, Yong Tae Kim, Jeong&#8208;Chul Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Kyoungsoo Kim, Hyung Ju Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202511220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Carbon Dioxide-to-Formic Acid Conversion via Composition and Vacancy Engineering of MoxNbyV1-(x+y)Se2 Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-025-00555-5</link>
      <description>Getasew Mulualem Zewdie, Hong Seok Kang, Hyeyoung Shin, Korean Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414827683

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Getasew Mulualem Zewdie, Hong Seok Kang, Hyeyoung Shin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-025-00555-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strained-Induced Morphological Reconstruction of RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110) Thin-Film Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08607</link>
      <description>Jacob Som, Austin Jerad Reese, Luka Mitrovic, R. Soyoung Kim, Shay McBride, Swapnil Nalawade, Shyam Aravamudhan, Geoffroy Hautier, Junko Yano, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414843702

                Strain is a widely used strategy for electrocatalyst engineering. Overstraining, however, can lead to unintentional materials transformation. We investigate the impact of strain on the surface morphology of a rutile RuO2(110) film grown on a symmetry-matching rutile TiO2(110) substrate. When the film thickness exceeds 9 nm, the RuO2 surface relaxes by forming step edges that expose the {011} plane. Density functional theory (DFT) calculation shows that the (011) facet is among the lower energy surfaces of rutile RuO2, suggesting that this formation incurs minimal energetic penalties. In situ atomic force microscopy (AFM) shows that the film maintains the (110) structure of the terrace during electrochemistry. Inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) further reveals the insensitivity of the Ru dissolution to strain. Our findings show a strain-relieving pathway via surface reconstruction in RuO2(110) and provide an example of a strain-relieving mechanism that does not affect dissolution.</description>
      <author>Jacob Som, Austin Jerad Reese, Luka Mitrovic, R. Soyoung Kim, Shay McBride, Swapnil Nalawade, Shyam Aravamudhan, Geoffroy Hautier, Junko Yano, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin&#8208;State Reconfiguration and Lattice Oxygen Activation Co&#8208;Mediated Oxygen Evolution Catalysis Pathway via Artificial Hetero&#8208;Sites for Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202514933</link>
      <description>Hongmei Tang, Maohong Fan, Lin Lv, Gang Cheng, Fei Han, Junhua Zou, Qing Gong, Zhenxiong Huang, Xiaoping Chen, Bohong Chen, Houzhao Wan, Hao Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414845333

                Abstract It is desirable but challenging to develop low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) applications. In this work, a series of cerium oxide&#8208;coated cobalt vanadium oxide nanoplates (denoted as CVO@CeO 2 ) are prepared using different CeO 2 loadings through a facile two&#8208;step method. Compared to bare CVO, CeO 2, and commercial RuO 2 , the CVO@CeO 2 &#8208;0.20 catalyst presents much higher activity toward OER in alkaline solutions. Moreover, the CVO@CeO 2 &#8208;0.20 also exhibits superior open&#8208;circuit voltage and durability when utilized as the cathode in ZABs. Both theoretical calculations and experimental results disclose that the decoration of CeO 2 on CVO not only regulates the formation of high&#8208;spin state Co 3+ , optimizing the absorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) pathway, but also activates lattice oxygen, enhancing the lattice oxide oxidation mechanism (LOM) pathway. This research presents the CVO@CeO 2 heterojunction as an excellent catalyst for the OER and proposes a promising interface&#8208;regulated strategy for developing catalysts based on the reinforcement of AEM and LOM mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Hongmei Tang, Maohong Fan, Lin Lv, Gang Cheng, Fei Han, Junhua Zou, Qing Gong, Zhenxiong Huang, Xiaoping Chen, Bohong Chen, Houzhao Wan, Hao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202514933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing hydrogen evolution reaction performance of ZnIn2S4-Based single atom catalysts via surface vacancies and interlayer charge transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151790</link>
      <description>Wenli Xie, Bin Cui, Desheng Liu, Haicai Huang, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 183(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414860439

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenli Xie, Bin Cui, Desheng Liu, Haicai Huang, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151790</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Understanding of Laser&#8208;Induced Defect Engineering of Anisotropic Cobalt Oxide Spinel Platelets in Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501054</link>
      <description>Dana Schellenburg, Thomas Bihnam, Carsten Placke&#8208;Yan, Georg Bendt, Oleg Prymak, Takuma Sato, Dylan Jennings, Catalina Leiva&#8208;Leroy, Dongsheng Zhang, Milen Nachev, Kapil Dhaka, F.B.S. Nkou, Ulrich Hagemann, Markus Heidelmann, St&#233;phane Kenmoe, Kai S. Exner, Bernd Sures, Martin Muhler, Christian H. Liebscher, Alexander Schnegg, Stephan Schulz, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414866193

                Abstract In this study, we employ the pulsed laser defect engineering in liquid (PUDEL) to tailor the surface properties of cobalt (II, III) oxide (Co 3 O 4 ) platelets grown in the &lt; 111 &gt; direction. By varying the laser intensity and pulse number, we systematically investigate the relationship between defect formation and catalytic performance in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and selective oxidation of two alcohols. Our results reveal that the PUDEL processing leads to the formation of lattice distortions, the gradual alteration of three different paramagnetic defect sites, a partial reduction of Co 3 O 4 , and enrichment of the Co 3 O 4 (111) surface with hydroxyl groups (*OH), which significantly enhances OER activity. Theoretical investigations confirm that optimized hydroxyl coverage is critical for determining OER activity. The observed trends in selectivity and conversion efficiency for the selective oxidation of cinnamyl alcohol (CA) and ethylene glycol (EG) suggest different reaction mechanisms. The activity trend of the selective oxidation of CA appears to follow the trend of a defect&#8208;attributed paramagnetic species that was assigned to a surface&#8208;near, distorted high&#8208;spin (S = 3/2) Co 2+ . In turn, the catalytic activity and OER activity trends for the EG oxidation showed similar trends, which followed the density of a paramagnetic CoO x species observed during EPR spectroscopy. In particular, the highest OER activity and EG conversion were both found for moderate (2 PPV, ), yet not too intense PUDEL processing. Our findings establish PUDEL as a precise method for catalyst optimization, both for thermal and electro&#8208;catalytic oxidation over defect&#8208;enriched cobalt oxides, which enables the correlation of specific laser&#8208;induced defects with catalytic activity trends.</description>
      <author>Dana Schellenburg, Thomas Bihnam, Carsten Placke&#8208;Yan, Georg Bendt, Oleg Prymak, Takuma Sato, Dylan Jennings, Catalina Leiva&#8208;Leroy, Dongsheng Zhang, Milen Nachev, Kapil Dhaka, F.B.S. Nkou, Ulrich Hagemann, Markus Heidelmann, St&#233;phane Kenmoe, Kai S. Exner, Bernd Sures, Martin Muhler, Christian H. Liebscher, Alexander Schnegg, Stephan Schulz, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Specific Nitrogen Vacancy Engineering in BaMO2N (M = Ta, Nb) for Enhanced Electrochemical Ammonia Production: Insights from First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100125</link>
      <description>Santhanamoorthi Nachimuthu, Chenglin Chu, Zhong-Lun Li, Kenta Hongo, Ryo Maezono, Yuji Masubuchi, Jyh&#8208;Chiang Jiang, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414871685

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Santhanamoorthi Nachimuthu, Chenglin Chu, Zhong-Lun Li, Kenta Hongo, Ryo Maezono, Yuji Masubuchi, Jyh&#8208;Chiang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superparamagnetic Fe&#8211;Ni mixed oxides-based electrocatalysts for enhanced alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151026</link>
      <description>Tabassum Taspya, Tanvir Ahmed, Md. Mominul Islam, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414872926

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tabassum Taspya, Tanvir Ahmed, Md. Mominul Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determining the Potential of Maximum Entropy from Ab Initio Molecular Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500958</link>
      <description>Amanda Schramm Petersen, T. Madsen, Theophilus Kobina Sarpey, Christian M. Schott, Elena L. Gubanova, Adrian V. Himmelreich, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Jan Rossmeisl, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414874714

                Abstract Understanding electrochemical interfaces at the atomic level is essential for optimizing catalytic performance in energy conversion and storage technologies. This study introduces a computational framework based on ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations to predict the potential of maximum entropy (PME) a descriptor of electric double layer disorder and charge transfer efficiency. By integrating AIMD with the generalized computational hydrogen electrode, it is systematically investigated how electrolyte composition, cation identity, and pH effect the position of PME. The approach reproduces experimental shifts in PME for Au and Pt electrodes and provides unprecedented insights into the emergence of multiple PME values in mixed&#8208;cation systems. The findings challenge conventional models of electrolyte structuring by revealing the presence of multiple PME values within mixed&#8208;cation systems. This suggests a more complex interplay between cations, adsorbates, and interfacial disorder than previously assumed. The computational framework developed in this study provides a predictive tool for understanding these interactions, offering new strategies for tuning electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Amanda Schramm Petersen, T. Madsen, Theophilus Kobina Sarpey, Christian M. Schott, Elena L. Gubanova, Adrian V. Himmelreich, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electrostatic Engineering for Chlorine Ions Blocking Toward Long&#8208;Lasting Alkaline Seawater Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202509149</link>
      <description>Yafeng Guan, Haolin Lu, Lipeng Zhao, Shengli Zhu, Zhenduo Cui, Zhaoyang Li, Wence Xu, Zhonghui Gao, Te Ba, Yanqin Liang, Guankui Long, Hui Jiang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414885363

                Abstract The existence of Cl &#8722; in seawater electrolysis weakens the selectivity of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) via the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) and causes material failure by chlorine pitting. Introducing anion layers not only repels the transition of Cl &#8722; without retarding the diffusion of oxygen&#8208;containing anions but also can be generated in situ on the outer surface. Here, a hierarchical catalyst consisting of a MnO 2 layer formed on a Ni foam substrate covered uniformly by a nickel&#8208;iron layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH) active layer is developed through interfacial electrostatic engineering. It was found that the introduced Lewis acid layer (MnO 2 ) can spontaneously generate OH &#8722; groups on the outer surface in situ to repel Cl &#8722; by electrostatic repulsion force. Meanwhile, Ni&#8208;active sites anchored inside the MnO 2 matrix can improve the low activity of MnO 2 . The multilayer NiFe&#8208;LDH@MnO 2 /NF anode can operate steadily at the current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at 70 &#176;C for 100 h and maintain 97.9% OER selectivity. Furthermore, the OER overpotential was reduced by 136 mV, superior to the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art commercial Ni mesh in industrial environments, especially the device can be powered by wind energy. The work offers an efficient strategy for designing high&#8208;performance seawater electrolysis with low cost and high stability.</description>
      <author>Yafeng Guan, Haolin Lu, Lipeng Zhao, Shengli Zhu, Zhenduo Cui, Zhaoyang Li, Wence Xu, Zhonghui Gao, Te Ba, Yanqin Liang, Guankui Long, Hui Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202509149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating C&#8211;C Coupling on Copper during CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;RR: Charge-Controlled Design of Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.5c00297</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Mattia Salomone, Michele Re Fiorentin, Francesca Risplendi, Giancarlo Cicero, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414901745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Mattia Salomone, Michele Re Fiorentin, Francesca Risplendi, Giancarlo Cicero</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.5c00297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effects in FeP4-NPC-CP Nanocomposites electrocatalysts for Boosted nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137067</link>
      <description>Yafei Guo, Sajid Mahmood, Anum Bilal, Ali Bahadur, Shahid Iqbal, Ali Hussain, Muhammad T. Sajjad, Syed Kashif Ali, Salah Knani, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414903045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yafei Guo, Sajid Mahmood, Anum Bilal, Ali Bahadur, Shahid Iqbal, Ali Hussain, Muhammad T. Sajjad, Syed Kashif Ali, Salah Knani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning electrical conductivity in lithium-doped sodium titanate via sonochemical synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118836</link>
      <description>J. Silva, Juliana Pereira da Silva, Rita Santos, Salom&#227;o dos Santos Costa, Francisco Xavier Nobre, M&#243;nica Tirado, Angsula Ghosh, Lianet Aguilera Dom&#237;nguez, Y. Leyet, Materials Science and Engineering B. 323(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414904817

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Silva, Juliana Pereira da Silva, Rita Santos, Salom&#227;o dos Santos Costa, Francisco Xavier Nobre, M&#243;nica Tirado, Angsula Ghosh, Lianet Aguilera Dom&#237;nguez, Y. Leyet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of surface phonons on the thermal conductivity of triply periodic minimal surface silicon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/ctfs-fx4m</link>
      <description>Peng Bi, Yakun Wan, Yong Yi, Songhu Bi, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 112(15)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414912749

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Bi, Yakun Wan, Yong Yi, Songhu Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/ctfs-fx4m</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Powering the Future: A Cobalt&#8208;Based Catalyst for Longer&#8208;Lasting Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519329</link>
      <description>Manami Banerjee, Peng Ren, Greesh Kumar, Lucie M. Lindenbeck, Byoung Joon Park, Anna Rokici&#324;ska, Piotr Ku&#347;trowski, Adam Slabon, Francesco Ciucci, Ramendra Sundar Dey, Shoubhik Das, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414914133

                Abstract The development of cost&#8208;effective catalysts for zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) remain challenging due to the sluggish kinetics of oxygen reduction (ORR) and evolution (OER) at the cathode. In this context, a novel N&#8208;doped graphitic shell&#8208;encapsulated cobalt catalyst is presented as an air electrode with exceptional bifunctional activity, achieving an ORR half&#8208;wave potential ( E 1/2 ) of 0.81 V and an OER overpotential of 349 mV in an alkaline medium. The catalyst demonstrated excellent cycling durability and delivered superior power density in both liquid and solid&#8208;state ZABs. Furthermore, a quasi&#8208;solid&#8208;state ZAB is assembled with the catalyst, and it maintained a stable open&#8208;circuit voltage (OCV) of 1.360 V for &gt;10 000 s. The catalyst achieved a peak power density of 127 mW cm &#8722;2 &#8212;significantly outperforming the benchmark Pt/C + RuO 2 system (74 mW cm &#8722;2 ). When two tandem&#8208;junction ZABs are connected in series, they achieved an OCV of 2.75 V and powering a &#8220;ZAB&#8221; LED strip and a mini fan. Furthermore, Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations revealed that the enhanced performance resulted from optimized binding energies between the Co@N(py) active sites and reaction intermediates. An in situ Raman study is carried out to understand the catalytic mechanism through transient intermediate detection.</description>
      <author>Manami Banerjee, Peng Ren, Greesh Kumar, Lucie M. Lindenbeck, Byoung Joon Park, Anna Rokici&#324;ska, Piotr Ku&#347;trowski, Adam Slabon, Francesco Ciucci, Ramendra Sundar Dey, Shoubhik Das</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Library for Monte Carlo Simulations with Ab Initio and Machine-Learned Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01148</link>
      <description>Woodrow N. Wilson, Vivek S. Bharadwaj, Neeraj Rai, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414914434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Woodrow N. Wilson, Vivek S. Bharadwaj, Neeraj Rai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Bifunctional Electrocatalysts Through p&#8208;Block Metal Incorporation in Transition Metal Doped N&#8208;Graphene for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507111</link>
      <description>Sougata Saha, K. Vipin Raj, Swapan K. Pati, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414917841

                Abstract Development of efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is essential for renewable energy storage and conversion technologies. While transition metal (TM) co&#8208;doped N&#8208;doped graphene systems (TM&#8208;N&#8208;G) are well&#8208;known for their electrocatalytic performance, their bifunctional activity for both OER and ORR remains limited and inefficient. In this work, bifunctional electrocatalytic performance of TM&#8208;N 6 &#8208;G systems (TM = Fe, Co, and Ni) is investigated by incorporating p&#8208;block metals (PM = Al, Ga, In, Sn, and Bi) into an N 4 cavity, resulting in TM&#8208;PM&#8208;N 6 &#8208;G structures. Systematic DFT calculations reveal that among all the system configurations, Co&#8208;Ga&#8208;N 6 &#8208;G and Co&#8208;Sn&#8208;N 6 &#8208;G emerge as highly efficient bifunctional catalysts. The enhanced catalytic activity of Co centres is attributed to optimal interactions with reaction intermediates, as elucidated by scaling relations, volcano plots, and contour maps. These optimal interactions are explained by changes in electronic structure of catalysts and charge redistribution at the TM sites, induced by incorporated PMs. A new descriptor &#978; is proposed to describe the catalytic activity, performing better than conventional d&#8208;band center. Additionally, several unifunctional catalysts are identified. This detailed analysis provides key insights and design strategies for developing high&#8208;performance bifunctional catalysts via PM doping in TM&#8208;N&#8208;G systems.</description>
      <author>Sougata Saha, K. Vipin Raj, Swapan K. Pati</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting paint resistance to pull-off by first principles calculations: The case of acrylic acid on (oxidised) metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2025.114898</link>
      <description>Manuel Montebelli, Paolo Restuccia, Maria Clelia Righi, Materials &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414926842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manuel Montebelli, Paolo Restuccia, Maria Clelia Righi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2025.114898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low&#8208;Voltage Driven Co&#8208;Production of Ammonia, Formate, and Hydrogen From Nitrite Reduction Coupled Formaldehyde Oxidation System on Ultra&#8208;Stable AuCuRh Nanowires under Illumination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202513320</link>
      <description>Ze&#8208;Nong Zhang, Xiaohui Wang, Wei Zhong, Xuan Ai, Xin Wang, Shu&#8208;Ni Li, Bao Yu Xia, Yu Chen, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414930241

                The nitrite electroreduction reaction (NO2RR) offers a green and sustainable pathway for environmental wastewater treatment and ammonia (NH3) generation. Herein, defect-rich trimetallic AuCuRh nanowires (AuCuRh NWs) with a large number of grain boundaries, twin boundaries, and atomic steps are successfully synthesized by galvanic replacement reaction. Due to its self-stability and high activity, AuCuRh NWs can efficiently drive the stable NO2RR at 0 V potential (Faradaic efficiency: 98.32%, NH3 yield rate: 20.49 mg h-1 mgcat -1). Moreover, AuCuRh NWs also reveal excellent electrocatalytic activity for the formaldehyde electrooxidation reaction (FOR), which can reach 10 mA cm-2 at only 0.35 V potential. The NO2RR||FOR electrolysis system assembled with AuCuRh NWs requires only the electrolysis voltage of 0.38 V to achieve the co-production of NH3, formate, and hydrogen and ultra-stable continuous electrolysis for 300 hours. The NO2RR||FOR electrolysis system can be further decreased to only 0.29 V under illumination due to plasmon-enhanced activity. This study provides an energy-efficient coupling strategy for the stable co-production of value-added chemicals.</description>
      <author>Ze&#8208;Nong Zhang, Xiaohui Wang, Wei Zhong, Xuan Ai, Xin Wang, Shu&#8208;Ni Li, Bao Yu Xia, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202513320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of the electrocatalytic activity of nonlinear optically active CuWO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanocomposites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5dt01694k</link>
      <description>Bankim J. Sanghavi, K. Aravinth, Manikandan Kandasamy, P. Balaji Bhargav, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414936464

                This research focused on successfully synthesizing CuWO4/g-C3N4 nanocomposites using microwave assistance, and their potential as electrochemical supercapacitors and electrocatalysts for the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions was thoroughly investigated. Structural studies demonstrated the anchoring of the spherical CuWO4 nanoparticles with a triclinic structure on the g-C3N4 surface. The CuWO4/g-C3N4 system showed an impressive specific capacitance of 111 F g-1 and excellent stability (85%) in supercapacitor applications. It also exhibited remarkable bifunctional electrocatalytic performance, efficiently facilitating both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in distinct electrolytes. Notably, it achieved a standard current density of 10 mA cm-2 with significantly lower Tafel slopes (46 mV dec-1 (HER) and 104 mV dec-1 (OER)) compared to pristine CuWO4. The nanocomposite's superior electrochemical performance was attributed to the synergistic effect of g-C3N4 and CuWO4, leading to high capacitance and excellent catalytic activity. Additionally, the nanocomposite exhibited enhanced nonlinear absorption and refraction upon He-Ne laser excitation, suggesting potential applications in optical devices. These findings highlight the promising prospects of CuWO4/g-C3N4 nanocomposites as multifunctional materials for energy storage and catalysis. DFT calculations further validate the experimental findings by providing insights into the electronic structures, quantum capacitance, adsorption geometries, and overpotentials of the hybrid systems. The calculated overpotential trend of CuW/gCN &lt; CuW agrees with the experimental data.</description>
      <author>Bankim J. Sanghavi, K. Aravinth, Manikandan Kandasamy, P. Balaji Bhargav, Brahmananda Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5dt01694k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning axial ligand coordination for enhanced activity and selectivity in metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon single-atom catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0288918</link>
      <description>H.T. Wang, Mingjie Liu, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414966260

                Axial ligand coordination plays a critical role in modulating the catalytic activity and selectivity of metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) single-atom catalysts (SACs) for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we systematically investigate FeN4, CoN4, and NiN4 active sites coordinated with a broad range of axial ligands to elucidate how ligand environments influence reaction energetics across different metal centers. Free energy analyses reveal that axial ligands can substantially modify key steps in the ORR pathway, including *OOH formation and *OH desorption, with distinct effects observed for each metal. FeN4 exhibits tunable activity and selectivity depending on the ligand, balancing between 4e&#8722; and 2e&#8722; pathways. CoN4 shows a pronounced preference toward the 2e&#8722; pathway under specific ligand environments, highlighting its potential for selective H2O2 production. In contrast, NiN4 displays generally high energy barriers and limited ORR activity across all axial ligands. These results establish a comparative framework for understanding how axial ligand coordination governs ORR performance and provide guidance for the rational design of M&#8211;N&#8211;C SACs with tailored activity and selectivity.</description>
      <author>H.T. Wang, Mingjie Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0288918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the electrocatalytic activity of Fe/co-8-16-4 graphyne through sulfur or phosphorus doping for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238579</link>
      <description>Ghazaleh Jafari, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani, Journal of Power Sources. 660(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414967546

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ghazaleh Jafari, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partitioning adsorption energy: An electronegativity-based descriptor for hydrogen adsorption on group IV and III&#8211;V 2D honeycombs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0295089</link>
      <description>Yi Sheng Ng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414969325

                Understanding and predicting hydrogen adsorption energy is key to designing effective electrocatalysts. In this study, we develop a physically interpretable descriptor within a framework that decomposes atomic hydrogen adsorption energy into intuitive contributions, applied to 22 group IV and III&#8211;V 2D honeycomb materials. The density functional theory (DFT) calculated adsorption energy is decomposed into two components: bond energy, approximated by the integrated crystal orbital Hamilton population (ICOHP), and the energy cost of forming the additional bond, termed distortion energy Ed. This decomposition facilitates analysis of adsorption trends beyond treating adsorption energy as a single quantity. We find that ICOHP correlates strongly with the adsorption site electronegativity (R2 = 0.86), improving to R2 = 0.91 when electronegativity differences and structural parameters are included. Ed shows moderate correlation with the unrelaxed vacancy energy Evac (R2 = 0.60) and can be accurately modeled (R2 = 0.92) using similar dependences on electronegativity and structural parameters. Notably, Evac can be expressed in terms of the sum of electronegativities, enabling a DFT-free formulation. Combining both components into an Eads descriptor, we achieve an R2 score of 0.82 across both group IV and III&#8211;V systems. Further analysis reveals that increasing the adsorption site electronegativity weakens adsorption unless the lattice constant is sufficiently large. In addition, we identify a linear relationship between ICOHP and the zero-point energy change, allowing the descriptor to be extended to the free energy of hydrogen adsorption, a key indicator of hydrogen evolution reaction activity.</description>
      <author>Yi Sheng Ng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0295089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand-Canonical Equivariant Neural Potentials for Electrochemical Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01381</link>
      <description>Jia-Lan Chen, Xin&#8208;Rui Qi, Jinze Zhu, Jin Li, Xuechun Jiang, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Jin&#8208;Xun Liu, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414970226

                Electrochemical reactions under constant potential underpin critical processes in energy storage, catalysis, and corrosion but remain challenging to model owing to the voltage insensitivity of conventional machine learning potentials. The lack of a unified framework incorporating grand-canonical constraints into machine-learned models fundamentally limits accurate, scalable simulations of potential-dependent interfacial phenomena. Here, we present a constant-potential, E(3)-equivariant message-passing neural network (CPMPNN) that integrates grand-canonical electronic structure principles with a global excess-charge parameter that is dynamically redistributed via a multihead attention mechanism. The atomic geometry is encoded through a graph neural network that preserves the full symmetry of the Euclidean group in three dimensions (E(3))&#9472;including translations, rotations, and reflections. Benchmarking against the grand-canonical DFT confirms that the CPMPNN retains first-principles accuracy while achieving a three-orders-of-magnitude computational speedup. Applied to key electrocatalytic processes&#9472;CO dimerization in CO2 reduction and the Volmer step in hydrogen evolution on Cu(100)&#9472;CPMPNN captures how the applied potential modulates the reaction thermodynamics, charge distribution, and transition-state structures, providing mechanistic insight into potential-dependent kinetics. By bridging first-principle accuracy with molecular dynamics scalability, CPMPNN provides a transferable framework for operando modeling of electrified interfaces, enabling new mechanistic insights into potential-controlled electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Jia-Lan Chen, Xin&#8208;Rui Qi, Jinze Zhu, Jin Li, Xuechun Jiang, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Jin&#8208;Xun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Cr-Ru Oxide Catalysts on TiO2 Support for High-Efficiency Proton Exchange towards Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2025.107988</link>
      <description>Bohan Zhang, Chang Wen, Mingtao Xu, Zhilin Ye, Wenshang Chen, Ben Chen, Qingsong Hua, Ke Liu, Zhengkai Tu, Process Safety and Environmental Protection. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414974313

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bohan Zhang, Chang Wen, Mingtao Xu, Zhilin Ye, Wenshang Chen, Ben Chen, Qingsong Hua, Ke Liu, Zhengkai Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2025.107988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annihilation process of a diagonally arranged dislocation pair in graphene: density-functional tight-binding molecular dynamics and first-principles studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114301</link>
      <description>Yasuhito Ohta, Computational Materials Science. 261(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414974369

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yasuhito Ohta</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.114301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the efficiency and stability of cerium-doped trimetallic phosphides for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169404</link>
      <description>Mai Mai, Sampath Prabhakaran, Huyen Thi Dao, Lan Nguyen, Hyunseok Ko, Young Sun Mok, Van Hien Hoa, Do Hwan Kim, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414974776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mai Mai, Sampath Prabhakaran, Huyen Thi Dao, Lan Nguyen, Hyunseok Ko, Young Sun Mok, Van Hien Hoa, Do Hwan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the Code of RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Corrosion: A Theoretical Exploration of Potential&#8208;Driven Switches Between Oxidative and Reductive Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500341</link>
      <description>Badr Elkamash, Franziska He&#223;, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414979225

                Ruthenium dioxide (RuO 2 ) is a benchmark catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media but suffers from slow dissolution under operating conditions, limiting its long&#8208;term durability. Here, density functional theory combined with the computational hydrogen electrode model is employed to elucidate the atomistic mechanisms governing RuO 2 surface corrosion across a relevant potential window from 0 to 1.5 V standard hydrogen electrode (SHE) . The study reveals a potential&#8208;dependent switch in dissolution pathways: at anodic potentials above 1.21 V SHE , direct oxidative dissolution leads to soluble RuO 4 , whereas at lower potentials, coupled proton&#8211;electron transfer reactions drive the formation of soluble hydroxylated species, specifically Ru(OH) 4 and RuO 2 (OH) 2 . Key surface intermediates act as energetic basins, regulating transient dissolution during potential cycling and shutdown. Furthermore, it is shown that doping RuO 2 with W, Ti, or Ir shifts the onset potentials for these corrosion pathways, enhancing surface stability by widening the potential window where the materials are stable. These insights advance the mechanistic understanding of RuO 2 degradation and support rational strategies for designing durable OER catalysts in acidic water&#8208;splitting technologies.</description>
      <author>Badr Elkamash, Franziska He&#223;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tetragonal transition metal sulfides for hydrogen evolution: a density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107819</link>
      <description>Fei Yang, Yuan Yao, Chao Su, Beibei Xiao, Daifen Chen, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414979727

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Yang, Yuan Yao, Chao Su, Beibei Xiao, Daifen Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ParametrizANI: Fast and Accessible Dihedral Parametrization for Small Molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01957</link>
      <description>Pablo R. Arantes, Souvik Sinha, Giulia Palermo, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414982114

                In molecular studies, the accurate parametrization of small molecules stands as an essential yet growing demand. Addressing this, we introduce ParametrizANI, a tool crafted explicitly for establishing detailed protocols for dihedral parametrization using GAFF and OpenFF force fields. The robust PyTorch-based program, TorchANI, forms the backbone of ParametrizANI, functioning as a benchmark to uphold precision in parametrization tasks. TorchANI plays a pivotal role in enabling ANI (ANAKIN-ME) deep learning models, which are trained to predict potential energy surfaces and related molecular properties with high accuracy. Our work on ParametrizANI goes beyond just creating a tool; it is about building a research-friendly environment, free from the constraints of limited resources. We are committed to democratizing research, enabling teams of all sizes to perform dihedral parametrization with DFT-level accuracy. This tool opens up new possibilities in molecular dynamics and related fields. It marks a significant step forward in improving the scientific community's ability to parametrize small molecules. For a detailed look at its features, we invite you to check out ParametrizANI on GitHub (https://github.com/palermolab/ParametrizANI).</description>
      <author>Pablo R. Arantes, Souvik Sinha, Giulia Palermo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning oxygen evolution activity via transition metal doping in bimetallic nickel phosphates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164846</link>
      <description>Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Rizky Dio Idhola, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Hamad AlMohamadi, Shashikant P. Patole, Sasfan Arman Wella, Fiki T. Akbar, Jenny Rizkiana, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414991420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Rizky Dio Idhola, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Hamad AlMohamadi, Shashikant P. Patole, Sasfan Arman Wella, Fiki T. Akbar, Jenny Rizkiana, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Exploration of High-Dimensional Configuration Spaces for the Generation of Chemical Datasets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01286</link>
      <description>Xuewen Xiao, A. Allouche, E. Dartois, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Magoul&#232;s, Daniel Pel&#225;ez, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414992617

                In this work, we introduce an automated methodology for the efficient and relatively inexpensive exploration of large high-dimensional chemical spaces, with particular focus on number-of-atoms-conserving processes, such as in mechanochemical reactions. Our approach combines: (1) a physically motivated stochastic global-landscape exploration phase (mechanochemical distortion), which efficiently overcomes entropic barriers, and (2) a local exploration phase in which the previously determined local basins are sampled with molecular dynamics and graph theory. Specifically, this last phase makes use of the (vdW-) transition state search using a chemical dynamical simulations algorithm. Our methodology requires minimal input from the user. As a case study, we have explored the conformational landscape, including transition states and minimum energy paths, of the C60H10 hydrogen-carbon clusters owing to their astrochemical relevance as potential carriers of the aromatic infrared bands. From a single initial seed (geometry), we have obtained a series of 212 mechanochemically relevant conformers, and from just 3 of them, we have obtained a set of &gt;13 000 minima spanning the domain of our interest. The underlying chemical network has been fully characterized and rationalized using statistical analysis tools. Our case study perfectly illustrates the potential of our approach in the automatic generation of chemical databases, in other words, annotated data for the training of data-hungry deep learning models in chemistry.</description>
      <author>Xuewen Xiao, A. Allouche, E. Dartois, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Magoul&#232;s, Daniel Pel&#225;ez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prussian blue analogues and their derivatives for electrochemical energy conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.217215</link>
      <description>Jun Xiang, Shu Jiang, Guangxun Zhang, Shuaining Gao, Ke Wu, Mohsen Shakouri, Huan Pang, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 548(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414995718

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Xiang, Shu Jiang, Guangxun Zhang, Shuaining Gao, Ke Wu, Mohsen Shakouri, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.217215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Strain and Electronic Effects in AuCu@CuFePd Core&#8211;Shell Nanocatalysts for Acidic Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c03515</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Ma, Zhong Zheng, Hui Liu, Shaonan Tian, Dong Chen, Jun Yang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414998512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Ma, Zhong Zheng, Hui Liu, Shaonan Tian, Dong Chen, Jun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c03515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Mechanisms and Catalysis in Solar Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-5914-2_9</link>
      <description>Esdras J. Canto&#8208;Aguilar, Elena Puentes-Prado, Alice Kuzhikandathil, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino, Progress in optical science and photonics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415002587

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Esdras J. Canto&#8208;Aguilar, Elena Puentes-Prado, Alice Kuzhikandathil, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-5914-2_9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Analysis of the Energetic Stability of High-Entropy Structures of a Prototypical Lanthanide-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04892</link>
      <description>S. D. Madhu Kumar, Dorina F. Sava Gallis, David S. Sholl, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415008276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. D. Madhu Kumar, Dorina F. Sava Gallis, David S. Sholl</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles discovery of stable two-dimensional AlInX2 (X=N, P, As) with high carrier mobility for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417905</link>
      <description>Chunying Pu, Yuqing Kang, Xinfu Pan, Dawei Zhou, Physica B Condensed Matter. 718(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415011781

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunying Pu, Yuqing Kang, Xinfu Pan, Dawei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial assembly and electrolytic water mechanism of PW11M, PW11M@ZIF-67, and PW11M@FeCoNi-LDH: Insights from DFT and experimental characterizations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169358</link>
      <description>B. T. Dai, Liang Chen, Xiaolong Bao, Qin Zhong, Hongxia Qu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415013417

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. T. Dai, Liang Chen, Xiaolong Bao, Qin Zhong, Hongxia Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Supercooled Liquid Sulfur for Enhanced Electrochemical Performance in Nanoporous Metal-Based Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c01173</link>
      <description>Cong Xi, Shuo Hao, Xiaotong Wang, Lei Bi, Zejing Lin, Chunchen Zhang, Jiuhui Han, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414857526

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cong Xi, Shuo Hao, Xiaotong Wang, Lei Bi, Zejing Lin, Chunchen Zhang, Jiuhui Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c01173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are we there yet? Adventures on a road trip through machine learning as a computational chemist</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0297853</link>
      <description>Heather J. Kulik, No host. 1(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414936445

                Over the past two decades, the integration of machine learning (ML) into theoretical and computational chemistry has transformed the scale and scope of discovery that is possible on a computer. In this Perspective, I share my personal journey from early density functional theory method development for small transition metal complexes to the building of automated workflows and ML models for catalysis, redox chemistry, and materials design. I will describe my unlikely path toward machine learning starting from minimal models of catalysts and the use of structural databases to gain data-driven insights. I will then describe our experiences in training machine learning models for discovery, including active learning and descriptor-based approaches that enabled data-driven exploration despite limited experimental reference data for open-shell transition metal complexes. As an example of overcoming these limitations, I will describe our more recent efforts that culminated in experimental validation of our computational predictions. Along the way, challenges in data curation, DFT method sensitivity, and synthetic realism have shaped the trajectory of the field. I conclude with reflections on the rapid rise of generative AI, agentic workflows, and the enduring need to ask questions that truly advance molecular discovery.</description>
      <author>Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0297853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring beyond experiment: generating high-quality datasets of transition metal complexes with quantum chemistry and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101189</link>
      <description>Jacob Toney, Aaron Garrison, Weiliang Luo, R. Michel, Sukrit Mukhopadhyay, Heather J. Kulik, Current Opinion in Chemical Engineering. 50(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414826559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jacob Toney, Aaron Garrison, Weiliang Luo, R. Michel, Sukrit Mukhopadhyay, Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph neural networks for predicting metal&#8211;ligand coordination of transition metal complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2415658122</link>
      <description>Jacob Toney, R. Michel, Aaron Garrison, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(41)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414857994

                High-throughput virtual screening campaigns are invaluable for surveying the combinatorial space of possible transition metal complexes (TMCs), but they rely on accurate metal&#8211;ligand connectivity for meaningful results. Here, we curate a dataset of 70,069 unique ligands of known coordination from experimental structures of TMCs deposited in the Cambridge Structural Database. Using this dataset, we train separate graph neural network models to predict the total number and individual identities of ligand coordinating atoms with high accuracy and precision. Interpreting each model in terms of the learned molecular representations uncovers trends aligned with our understanding of coordination chemistry as well as chemical insights. Next, we integrate the trained models with the high-throughput screening software molSimplify and illustrate their utility by generating 1,175 TMCs and validating their geometries with density functional theory calculations. We anticipate these models will accelerate computational screening of TMCs with de novo combinations of metals and ligands in physically realistic coordination.</description>
      <author>Jacob Toney, R. Michel, Aaron Garrison, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2415658122</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
