<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:46:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen generation via water splitting with hexagonal silicon monolayers as (photo)catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114081</link>
      <description>Riri Jonuarti, Wilson Agerico Di&#241;o, Hikaru Kobayashi, Suprijadi, - Ratnawulan, Rahmat Hidayat, Molecular catalysis (Online). 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393216663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Riri Jonuarti, Wilson Agerico Di&#241;o, Hikaru Kobayashi, Suprijadi, - Ratnawulan, Rahmat Hidayat</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated atomistic simulations of dissociated dislocations with &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; accuracy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.094120</link>
      <description>Laura Mismetti, Max Hodapp, Physical review. B. 109(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393222082

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Laura Mismetti, Max Hodapp</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.094120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Cooperative Mechanisms in Ultralow Copper-Loaded WC@NGC for Enhanced CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to Acetic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c00405</link>
      <description>Debabrata Bagchi, Mohd Riyaz, Jithu Raj, Soumyabrata Roy, Ashutosh Kumar Singh, Arjun Cherevotan, C. P. Vinod, Sebastian C. Peter, Chemistry of materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393225487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Debabrata Bagchi, Mohd Riyaz, Jithu Raj, Soumyabrata Roy, Ashutosh Kumar Singh, Arjun Cherevotan, C. P. Vinod, Sebastian C. Peter</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c00405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable electronic coupling of Fe-doped CoS2/reduced graphene oxide composites for boosting bifunctional water splitting activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174281</link>
      <description>Bo Fang, Yue Li, Jiaqi Yang, Ting L&#252;, Xinjuan Liu, Xiaohong Chen, Likun Pan, Zhenjie Zhao, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393227029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Fang, Yue Li, Jiaqi Yang, Ting L&#252;, Xinjuan Liu, Xiaohong Chen, Likun Pan, Zhenjie Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical regulating the M-site composition of Janus MXenes enables the tailoring design for highly active bifunctional ORR/OER catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.093</link>
      <description>Shuang Luo, Ninggui Ma, Jun Zhao, Yuhang Wang, Yaqin Zhang, Yan Xiong, Jun Fan, Journal of Materials Science and Technology (Shenyang). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393227083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuang Luo, Ninggui Ma, Jun Zhao, Yuhang Wang, Yaqin Zhang, Yan Xiong, Jun Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly area-selective atomic layer deposition of device-quality Hf1-xZrxO2 thin films through catalytic local activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150760</link>
      <description>Hyo&#8208;Bae Kim, Jeong&#8208;Min Lee, Dong Jun Sung, Ji&#8208;Hoon Ahn, Woo&#8208;Hee Kim, Chemical engineering journal (1996. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393227170

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyo&#8208;Bae Kim, Jeong&#8208;Min Lee, Dong Jun Sung, Ji&#8208;Hoon Ahn, Woo&#8208;Hee Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced manufacturing in heterogeneous catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837672035-00001</link>
      <description>Swarom Kanitkar, Biswanath Dutta, Ashraf Abedin, Xue Bai, Daniel Haynes, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393232922

                Heterogeneous catalysis is one of the major pillars of the chemical and refining industry that has evolved significantly from the need for more efficient and sustainable industrial processes. Advanced manufacturing will play an important role in driving this evolution through its ability to create or design more favourable interactions with catalytic components that can result in more active and stable catalysts, efficient catalytic processes, and sustainable reaction systems. This chapter provides an overview of recent progress that covers various catalyst coating methods, application of 3D printing in catalytic supports and reactor components, and process intensification through additive manufacturing. The work also provides a brief overview on artificial intelligence/machine learning in heterogeneous catalysis that is helping to make/screen catalysts more efficiently. The work further highlights the impacts and challenges of implementing advanced manufacturing methods.</description>
      <author>Swarom Kanitkar, Biswanath Dutta, Ashraf Abedin, Xue Bai, Daniel Haynes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837672035-00001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding pH-Dependent Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Metal Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00461</link>
      <description>Xinnan Mao, Lu Wang, Youyong Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393234212

                Exploring low-cost and high-efficiency catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) kinetics in both acidic and alkaline environments could dramatically improve the efficiency of hydrogen fuel cells and their industrial applications. During the electrochemical process, the effect of pH is a complicating factor and is of great importance in identifying high-efficiency electrocatalysts. In this work, we conducted systematic computations to gain a deep understanding of the pH-dependent ORR activity on Pt, Pd, and their near-surface alloys (NSAs). The effects of pH were calculated by employing the double-reference method, and our calculated pH-dependent current densities are in good agreement with the experimental results. High-throughput calculations identified a series of NSA catalysts with superior ORR performance under acidic or alkaline conditions, and we have developed a pH-corrected theoretical model to efficiently estimate the ORR activity on metal catalysts. This work underscores the importance of considering pH effects when evaluating ORR activity from calculations and provides a strategy for designing superior ORR electrocatalysts in acidic and alkaline solutions.</description>
      <author>Xinnan Mao, Lu Wang, Youyong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cr dopants and S vacancies in ZnS to trigger efficient photocatalytic H2 evolution and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.094</link>
      <description>Linping Bao, Yushuai Jia, Xiaohui Ren, Xin Liu, Chunhui Dai, Sajjad Ali, M. Bououdina, Zhang&#8208;Hui Lu, Chao Zeng, Journal of Materials Science and Technology (Shenyang). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393238252

                Driven by endless solar energy, photocatalytic H2 evolution from water splitting and CO2 conversion to hydrocarbon fuels over semiconductor photocatalysts are of great potential to simultaneously settle the greenhouse effect and energy shortage. Herein, Cr-doped zinc sulfide (ZnS) with accompanying sulphur vacancies (Vs) photocatalytic materials is developed by a facile hydrothermal method. The Cr dopants centralize photoinduced holes and Vs trap electrons, forming a synergistic effect for accelerating charge separation and transfer. The reaction energy barrier for both H2 evolution and CO2 reduction has been optimized. Therefore, in the absence of a cocatalyst, the optimal catalyst (Zn0.94Cr0.06S) achieves an outstanding H2 evolution activity of 20.3 mmol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1, which is approximately 2.9 times higher than 6.9 mmol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 for pristine ZnS. In addition, in the gas-solid reaction system without co-catalysts or sacrificial agents, the Zn0.94Cr0.06S exhibits a considerable CO evolution rate of 19.56 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1, about 10.1 times higher than ZnS (1.94 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1). Both the performances for H2 evolution and CO2 reduction of Zn0.94Cr0.06S outperform most of the previously reported photocatalysts. Particularly, the Zn0.94Cr0.06S possesses superior stability, the photoactivity of which exhibits no noticeable deactivation after six cycles' reactions. This work may shed light on the rational design and fabrication of highly efficient materials via combining individual element doping and defect engineering.</description>
      <author>Linping Bao, Yushuai Jia, Xiaohui Ren, Xin Liu, Chunhui Dai, Sajjad Ali, M. Bououdina, Zhang&#8208;Hui Lu, Chao Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SMATool: Strength of Materials Analysis Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109189</link>
      <description>Chinedu Ekuma, Computer physics communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393254202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chinedu Ekuma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances on Computational Modeling of Supported Single-Atom and Cluster Catalysts: Characterization, Catalyst&#8211;Support Interaction, and Active Site Heterogeneity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14040224</link>
      <description>Jiayi Xu, Colton J. Lund, Prajay Patel, Yu Lim Kim, Cong Liu, Catalysts. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393254287

                To satisfy the need for catalyst materials with high activity, selectivity, and stability for energy conversion, material design and discovery guided by theoretical insights are a necessity. In the past decades, the rise in theoretical investigations into the properties of catalyst materials, reaction mechanisms, and catalyst design principles has shed light on the catalysis field. Quantitative structure&#8211;activity relationships have been developed through incorporating spectroscopic simulations, electronic structure calculations, and reaction mechanistic studies. In this review, we report the state-of-the-art computational approaches to catalyst materials characterization for supported single-atom and cluster catalysts utilizing spectroscopic simulations, i.e., XANES simulation, and material properties investigation via electronic-structure calculations. Furthermore, approaches regarding reaction mechanisms, focusing on active site heterogeneity, are also discussed.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Xu, Colton J. Lund, Prajay Patel, Yu Lim Kim, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14040224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Electrocatalytic Activity in HMF Oxidation to FDCA by Fine&#8208;Tuning the Degree of NiOOH Phase Over Ni Nanoparticles Supported on Graphene Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400779</link>
      <description>Sorasak Klinyod, Nuttapon Yodsin, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Zikkawas Pasom, Sunpet Assavapanumat, Marisa Ketkaew, Pinit Kidkhunthod, Tetsu Yonezawa, Supawadee Namuangruk, Chularat Wattanakit, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393259803

                Abstract The development of an efficient electrocatalyst for HMF oxidation to FDCA has been in the early stages. Herein, the NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam is fabricated as an electrocatalyst for FDCA production. However, the electrocatalytic performance of the untreated NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam is observed with moderate Faradaic efficiency (FE) (73.0%) and FDCA yield (80.2%). By electrochemically treating the NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam in an alkaline solution with positive potential at different treatment durations, the degree of NiOOH on metal surfaces is changed. The distinctive electrocatalytic activity obtained when using the different NiOOH degrees allows to understand the crucial impact of NiOOH species in HMF electrooxidation. Enhancing the portion of the NiOOH phase on the electrocatalyst surface improves electrocatalytic activity in terms of FE and FDCA yield up to 94.8&#177;4.8% and 86.9&#177;4.1%, respectively. Interestingly, as long as the NiOOH portion on the electrocatalyst surface is preserved or regenerated, the electrocatalyst performance can be intact even after several catalytic cycles. The theoretical study via density functional theory (DFT) also agrees with the experimental observations and confirms that the NiOOH phase facilitates the electrochemical transformation of HMF to FDCA through the HMFCA pathway, and the potential limiting step of the overall reaction is the oxidation of FFCA to FDCA.</description>
      <author>Sorasak Klinyod, Nuttapon Yodsin, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Zikkawas Pasom, Sunpet Assavapanumat, Marisa Ketkaew, Pinit Kidkhunthod, Tetsu Yonezawa, Supawadee Namuangruk, Chularat Wattanakit</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultralow charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap of 0.05 V in sunlight&#8208;responsive neutral aqueous Zn&#8211;air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.535</link>
      <description>Zhimin Niu, Yan Gao, Tianhui Wu, Fei Zhang, Ran Zhao, Zijia Chen, Yiming Yuan, Tifeng Jiao, Jianmin Gu, L&#252; Li, Desong Wang, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393260047

                Abstract Rechargeable neutral aqueous zinc&#8722;air batteries (ZABs) are a promising type of energy storage device with longer operating life and less corrosiveness compared with conventional alkaline ZABs. However, the neutral ZABs normally possess poor oxygen evolution reactions (OERs) and oxygen reduction reactions performance, resulting in a large charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap and low round&#8208;trip efficiency. Herein, we demonstrate a sunlight&#8208;assisted strategy for achieving an ultralow voltage gap of 0.05 V in neutral ZABs by using the FeOOH&#8208;decorated BiVO 4 (Fe&#8208;BiVO 4 ) as an oxygen catalyst. Under sunlight, the electrons move from the valence band (VB) of Fe&#8208;BiVO 4 to the conduction band producing holes in VB to promote the OER process and hence reduce the overpotential. Meanwhile, the photopotential generated by the Fe&#8208;BiVO 4 compensates a part of the charging potential of neutral ZABs. Accordingly, the energy loss of the battery could be compensated via solar energy, leading to a record&#8208;low gap of 0.05 V between the charge and discharge voltage with a high round&#8208;trip efficiency of 94%. This work offers a simple but efficient pathway for solar&#8208;energy utilization in storage devices, further guiding the design of high energy efficiency of neutral aqueous ZABs.</description>
      <author>Zhimin Niu, Yan Gao, Tianhui Wu, Fei Zhang, Ran Zhao, Zijia Chen, Yiming Yuan, Tifeng Jiao, Jianmin Gu, L&#252; Li, Desong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Valence W&lt;sup&gt;6+&lt;/sup&gt; Ions Boost Cr&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; Activity in CrWO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Ideal Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400114</link>
      <description>C. Kim, Dasom Jeon, Nayeong Kim, Jungki Ryu, JunHee Lee, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393261486

                Abstract Electrocatalytic activity of multi&#8208;valence metal oxides for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) arises from various interactions among the constituent metal elements. Although the high&#8208;valence metal ions attract recent attentions due to the interactions with their neighboring 3 d transition metal catalytic center, atomic&#8208;scale explanations for the catalytic efficiencies are still lacking. Here, by employing density functional theory predictions and experimental verifications, unprecedented electronic isolation of the catalytic 3 d center ( M 2+ ) induced by the surrounding high&#8208;valence ions such as W 6+ is discovered in multivalent oxides M WO 4 ( M = Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, and Zn). Due to W 6+ &#8217;s extremely high oxidation state with the minimum electron occupations (d 0 ), the surrounding W 6+ blocks electron transfer toward the catalytic M 2+ ions and completely isolates the ions electronically. Now, the isolated M 2+ ions solely perform OER without any assistant electron flow from the adjacent metal ions, and thus the original strong binding energies of Cr with OER intermediates are effectively moderated. Through exploiting &#8220;electron isolators&#8221; such as W 6+ surrounding the catalytic ion, exploring can be done beyond the conventional materials such as Ni&#8208; or Co&#8208;oxides into new candidate groups such as Cr and Mn on the left side of the periodic table for ideal OER.</description>
      <author>C. Kim, Dasom Jeon, Nayeong Kim, Jungki Ryu, JunHee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Design of Transition Metal-Based Catalysts for Electrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01456</link>
      <description>Liang Guo, Jingwen Zhou, Fu Liu, Xiangchuan Meng, Yangbo Ma, Fengkun Hao, Yi Xiong, Zhanxi Fan, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Guo, Jingwen Zhou, Fu Liu, Xiangchuan Meng, Yangbo Ma, Fengkun Hao, Yi Xiong, Zhanxi Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Interlayer Bonding on Superlubric Sliding of Graphene Contacts: A Machine-Learning Potential Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c13099</link>
      <description>Penghua Ying, Amir Natan, Oded Hod, Michael Urbakh, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277820

                Surface defects and their mutual interactions are anticipated to affect the superlubric sliding of incommensurate layered material interfaces. Atomistic understanding of this phenomenon is limited due to the high computational cost of ab initio simulations and the absence of reliable classical force-fields for molecular dynamics simulations of defected systems. To address this, we present a machine-learning potential (MLP) for bilayer defected graphene, utilizing state-of-the-art graph neural networks trained against many-body dispersion corrected density functional theory calculations under iterative configuration space exploration. The developed MLP is utilized to study the impact of interlayer bonding on the friction of bilayer defected graphene interfaces. While a mild effect on the sliding dynamics of aligned graphene interfaces is observed, the friction coefficients of incommensurate graphene interfaces are found to significantly increase due to interlayer bonding, nearly pushing the system out of the superlubric regime. The methodology utilized herein is of general nature and can be adapted to describe other homogeneous and heterogeneous defected layered material interfaces.</description>
      <author>Penghua Ying, Amir Natan, Oded Hod, Michael Urbakh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c13099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transferable Water Potentials Using Equivariant Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00605</link>
      <description>Tristan Maxson, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393280718

                Machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) have emerged as a technique that promises quantum theory accuracy for reduced cost. It has been proposed [J. Chem. Phys. 2023, 158, 084111] that MLIPs trained on solely liquid water data cannot accurately transfer to the vapor&#8211;liquid equilibrium while recovering the many-body decomposition (MBD) analysis of gas-phase water clusters. This suggests that MLIPs do not directly learn the physically correct interactions of water molecules, limiting transferability. In this work, we show that MLIPs using equivariant architecture and trained on 3200 liquid water structures reproduces liquid-phase water properties (e.g., density within 0.003 g/cm3 between 230 and 365 K), vapor&#8211;liquid equilibrium properties up to 550 K, the MBD analysis of gas-phase water cluster up to six-body interactions, and the relative energy and the vibrational density of states of ice phases. We show that potentials developed using equivariant MLIPs allow transferability for arbitrary phases of water that remain stable in nanosecond long simulations.</description>
      <author>Tristan Maxson, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvement of manganese electrolytic process and secondary resources recovery of manganese&#65306;a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2024.03.097</link>
      <description>Tianyi Wu, Baozhong Ma, Yarui An, Yongqiang Chen, Chengyan Wang, Process Safety and Environmental Protection. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393282254

                The mainstream process for the production of electrolytic manganese metal is hydrometallurgy, which includes leaching, purification and electrolysis. The electrolytic process consumes the most energy in the whole production. With the development of manganese mineral resources, the recovery of manganese from secondary sources plays an important role. Therefore, the majorization of the manganese electrolytic process and the recovery of manganese from secondary resources are very important. This article introduces the process flow of manganese metallurgy and provides a systematic overview of the optimisation of various aspects of the manganese electrolytic process, including the improvement of the electrolytic cell, the development of the electrodes, the innovation of current applying methods and the exploration of additives. At the same time, this review also summarizes the recovery methods of valuable elements from secondary resources in recent years. Finally, the challenges and future prospects of electrolytic manganese metal are discussed.</description>
      <author>Tianyi Wu, Baozhong Ma, Yarui An, Yongqiang Chen, Chengyan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psep.2024.03.097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical fundamentals | Mixed potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00187-0</link>
      <description>&#193;ngel Cuesta, Alan J. Gibson, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393286278

                In this chapter we first explain the concept of mixed potentials by comparison with equilibrium potentials and then expand briefly on the relevance of mixed potentials in corrosion, where the concept was used first. The relevance of mixed potentials to understanding electrocatalytic reactions follows then, using the peroxide oxidation and reduction reactions and their connection with the oxygen reduction reaction as an example. This then allows us to explain the effect of mixed potentials on the performance of electrochemical energy conversion and storage. The chapter also includes some practical applications of the measurement of mixed potentials, such as the detection of modern forgeries of archeological objects or the determination of kinetic parameters of electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>&#193;ngel Cuesta, Alan J. Gibson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00187-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical fundamentals | Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00188-2</link>
      <description>Enrique Herrero, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393286318

                In this chapter, the basic principles of electrocatalysis will be presented. A general description of the electrocatalytic phenomena will be given, emphasizing the necessity of a specific interaction between the electrode surface, which acts as the electrocatalyst, and some of the species (reactants or intermediates) participating in the electrochemical reaction. A model that justifies the appearance of volcano curves when the electrochemical reaction rates are plotted vs. the electrode adsorption properties will be described. The implications of this model for some of the most important electrochemical reactions will be discussed as well as the limits in its application. Finally, the effects of the interfacial properties in the electrocatalysis, such as surface charge, pH, and electrolyte composition (anions and cations) will be described providing examples of their effects.</description>
      <author>Enrique Herrero, Rosa M. Ar&#225;n&#8208;Ais</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00188-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water-regulated 2D Ni-MOF-derived heat-sheared Nano-Ni@TC for efficient hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.312</link>
      <description>Qianwei Chen, Lianghuo Fan, Wenqian Liu, Ruilin He, Jieyu Zhang, Yangyang Tan, Wei Sun, Shu&#8208;Juan Bao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393295238

                Hydrogen energy has garnered significant attention due to its high calorific value and minimal environmental impact. However, the high-current electrolysis of water encounters challenges such as insufficient active sites and the disruptive effects from rapidly generated bubbles. In this paper, a small amount of water was introduced to modify the strong coordination ability of metal ions with organic ligands, and prepared 2D Ni MOFs. Subsequently, thin carbon-armed Ni-based catalysts (Ni@TC NPs) were prepared through nickel-assisted low-temperature pyrolysis. Unlike other 3D MOFs, the 2D MOF thin sheets prepared in this work can decompose at low temperatures due to its thin thickness, and the exposed Ni will accelerate the carbonization of surrounding organic groups, resulting in the formation of smaller and uniformly distributed thin carbon-armored Ni@TC NPs at lower temperature. Serving as a Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) electrocatalyst, Ni@TC NPs demonstrate exceptional electrocatalytic performance (low overpotential of 36.6 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and low Tafel slope of 91.06 mV dec&#8722;1), and long-term stability (over 50 h at 440 mA cm&#8722;2). The electronic modulation between the thin carbon armor and the metal center endows Ni@TC NPs with excellent kinetic performance, while the carbon armor provides protection in alkaline environments. In addition, the small and dense bubbles that quickly escape greatly reduce the bubble shielding and oscillation effects on the electrode surface, enabling Ni@TC NPs to work stably under high currents.</description>
      <author>Qianwei Chen, Lianghuo Fan, Wenqian Liu, Ruilin He, Jieyu Zhang, Yangyang Tan, Wei Sun, Shu&#8208;Juan Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal single-atoms supported on hexagonal ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; monolayers for the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00107a</link>
      <description>Xinlu Cheng, Kui Cheng, Xiaowang Zhou, Mingyang Shi, Gang Jiang, Jiguang Du, PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393299658

                The 2D h-ZnIn 2 S 4 monolayers are used as substrate materials to investigate the HER catalytic activity of single TM atoms supported on the surface, and the mechanism of the high catalytic activity of SAC is also discussed.</description>
      <author>Xinlu Cheng, Kui Cheng, Xiaowang Zhou, Mingyang Shi, Gang Jiang, Jiguang Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00107a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible Hydrogen Electrode (RHE) Scale Dependent Surface Pourbaix Diagram at Different pH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00298</link>
      <description>Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Wang Yuan, Hao Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393301713

                In the analysis of electrocatalysis mechanisms and the design of catalysts, the effect of electrochemistry-induced surface coverage is a critical consideration that should not be overlooked. The surface Pourbaix diagram emerges as a fundamental tool in this context, providing essential insights into the surface coverage of adsorbates generated via electrochemical potential-driven water activation. A classic surface Pourbaix diagram considers the pH effects by correcting the free energy of H+ ions by the concentration-dependent term: &#8722;kBT ln(10) &#215; pH, which is independent of the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) scale. However, this is sometimes inconsistent with the experimentally observed potential-dependent surface coverage at an RHE scale, especially under high-pH conditions. Here, we derived the pH-dependent surface Pourbaix diagram at an RHE scale by considering the energetics computed by density functional theory with the Bayesian Error Estimation Functional with van der Waals corrections (BEEF-vdW), the electric field effects, the derived adsorption-induced dipole moment and polarizability, and the potential of zero-charge. Using Pt(111) as the typical example, we found that the surface coverage predicted by the proposed RHE-dependent surface Pourbaix diagram can significantly minimize the discrepancy between theory and experimental observations, especially under neutral-alkaline, moderate-potential conditions. This work provides a new methodology and establishes guidelines for the precise analysis of the surface coverage prior to the evaluation of the activity of an electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Wang Yuan, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid Electrolyte Anions Adsorption Effects on IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08103</link>
      <description>S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393302584

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis is a promising technology merging the usage of intermittent renewable energy sources with the production of green hydrogen. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction remains the bottleneck of the efficiency of these devices due to sluggish reaction kinetics, high cost, and the scarcity of state-of-the-art catalytic materials. Though most research is focused on the discovery of new catalytic materials, understanding the effects of acid electrolyte anions is crucial to designing and optimizing existing electrocatalysts in diverse electrochemical microenvironments. Herein, we systematically study the effects of acid electrolytes on the IrO2(110) surface under OER reaction conditions using density functional theory. The potential-dependent anion adsorption results show that HPO42&#8211; adsorbs the strongest, followed by SO42&#8211;, NO3&#8211;, and ClO4&#8211; respectively at 1.6 V (vs RHE). HPO42&#8211; and SO42&#8211; block the Ir-active sites by competitively adsorbing with the OER intermediates while ClO4&#8211; does not interfere with OER performance. By evaluating dipole-field interactions, surface work function changes, Bader charges of adsorbed anions, and the effects of adsorbed electrolyte anions on the adsorption of the OER intermediates, we provide further insights into acid anion electrolyte effects under the OER conditions. This expansion of fundamental understanding of the effects of acid electrolyte anion adsorption on IrO2 assists in engineering better-performing catalysts with integrated electrolyte microenvironment for OER.</description>
      <author>S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The reduction mechanism of C1 product from carbon dioxide catalyzed by Ni-doped g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Molecular catalysis (Online). 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393305887

                This work employs density functional theory (DFT) to scrutinize the catalytic efficacy of nano nickel (Ni) clusters supported by graphitic carbon nitride (Nin@g-C3N4, where n ranges from 1 to 6) in the context of the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Structural examination revealed that Nin@g-C3N4 possesses a substantial binding energy (-1.63 eV to -7.72 eV), confirming the structural stability of the catalyst in the CO2RR. Electronic structure analysis revealed a pronounced orbital overlap near the Fermi level between the 3d orbital of Ni atoms and the 2p orbital of adjacent cavity nitrogen atoms in Nin@g-C3N4. Further insights are gleaned from the calculations of the Bader charge and energy band, indicating significant charge transfer and band gap alteration, suggesting enhanced conductivity due to Ni doping on g-C3N4. The catalytic performance in the CO2RR is predominantly influenced by the size of the doped Ni clusters. The Ni4@g-C3N4 cluster demonstrated optimal efficiency in producing formic acid (HCOOH) with a limiting potential of -0.12 V. In contrast, the Ni5@g-C3N4 cluster excels in methane (CH4) formation, with a limiting potential of -0.35 V. Additionally, these catalysts exhibit marked inhibition of the hydrogen evolution reaction, further underscoring their potential in CO2RR applications.</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validation workflow for machine learning interatomic potentials for complex ceramics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</link>
      <description>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash, Computational materials science. 239(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393373529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process Operability Analysis of Membrane-Based Direct Air Capture for Low-Purity CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsengineeringau.3c00069</link>
      <description>Vitor V. Gama, Beatriz Dantas, Oishi Sanyal, Fernando V. Lima, ACS Engineering Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277124

                Addressing climate change constitutes one of the major scientific challenges of this century, and it is widely acknowledged that anthropogenic CO2 emissions largely contribute to this issue. To achieve the "net-zero" target and keep the rise in global average temperature below 1.5 &#176;C, negative emission technologies must be developed and deployed at a large scale. This study investigates the feasibility of using membranes as direct air capture (DAC) technology to extract CO2 from atmospheric air to produce low-purity CO2. In this work, a two-stage hollow fiber membrane module process is designed and modeled using the AVEVA Process Simulation platform to produce a low-purity (&#8776;5%) CO2 permeate stream. Such low-purity CO2 streams could have several possible applications such as algae growth, catalytic oxidation, and enhanced oil recovery. An operability analysis is performed by mapping a feasible range of input parameters, which include membrane surface area and membrane performance metrics, to an output set, which consists of CO2 purity, recovery, and net energy consumption. The base case for this simulation study is generated considering a facilitated transport membrane with high CO2/N2 separation performance (CO2 permeance = 2100 GPU and CO2/N2 selectivity = 1100), when tested under DAC conditions. With a constant membrane area, both membranes' intrinsic performances are found to have a considerable impact on the purity, recovery, and energy consumption. The area of the first module plays a dominant role in determining the recovery, purity, and energy demands, and in fact, increasing the area of the second membrane has a negative impact on the overall energy consumption, without improving the overall purities. The CO2 capture capacity of DAC units is important for implementation and scale-up. In this context, the performed analysis showed that the m-DAC process could be appropriate as a small-capacity system (0.1&#8211;1 Mt/year of air), with reasonable recoveries and overall purity. Finally, a preliminary CO2 emissions analysis is carried out for the membrane-based DAC process, which leads to the conclusion that the overall energy grid must be powered by renewable sources for the technology to qualify within the negative emissions category.</description>
      <author>Vitor V. Gama, Beatriz Dantas, Oishi Sanyal, Fernando V. Lima</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsengineeringau.3c00069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenges of hydrogen production from biomass gasification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13613-9.00005-2</link>
      <description>Jingwei Chen, Yilin Guo, Xiaomin Wu, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393323912

                With the development of alternative energy sources, biomass gasification for hydrogen production technology has attracted high attentions from researchers. This chapter introduces three main aspects: biomass gasification for hydrogen production technology, enhancement strategies for hydrogen production from biomass gasification, and hydrogen purification technology. The physical and chemical processes of hydrogen production from traditional biomass gasification, the effects of various key parameters on the performance of hydrogen production from biomass gasification, and the advantages and disadvantages of existing hydrogen purification technologies are introduced in details. Although the technology of hydrogen production from biomass gasification has been studied for many years, there are still challenges that hinder the commercialization and industrialization of hydrogen production technology from biomass gasification. The challenges including the detailed gasification evolution mechanisms of biomass, the gasification interactions between biomass components, the development of new catalysts and purification technologies, and the antiaging of catalytic and purification materials have been proposed in this chapter. In particular, there is a lack of precise and detailed descriptions of the gasification evolution mechanism of biomass macromolecules, catalytic and deactivation mechanisms of catalysts, which provide a theoretical basis for precise manipulation of the direction of hydrogen production reactions from biomass gasification. Finally, it is hoped that by overcoming the challenges presented, the technical barriers of hydrogen production from biomass gasification can be broken through, and the hydrogen production technology from biomass gasification can be commercialized and industrialized.</description>
      <author>Jingwei Chen, Yilin Guo, Xiaomin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13613-9.00005-2</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
