<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 01:04:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>The role of chalcogen doping in Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts for hydrogen-air polymer electrolyte fuel cells: Selenium doped Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234612</link>
      <description>S&#322;awomir Dyjak, Wojciech Tokarz, A. B&#322;achowski, Mateusz Gratzke, Barbara Szcz&#281;&#347;niak, Kamil Sobczak, Wojciech Kici&#324;ski, Journal of power sources. 609(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396791589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S&#322;awomir Dyjak, Wojciech Tokarz, A. B&#322;achowski, Mateusz Gratzke, Barbara Szcz&#281;&#347;niak, Kamil Sobczak, Wojciech Kici&#324;ski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ion solvation free energy calculations based on first-principles molecular dynamics thermodynamic integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0191068</link>
      <description>Chao Lin, Xiaojun He, Cong Xi, Qianfan Zhang, Lin&#8208;Wang Wang, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803459

                Numerous electrochemistry reactions require the precise calculation of the ion solvation energy. Despite the significant progress in the first-principles calculations for crystals and defect formation energies for solids, the liquid system free energy calculations still face many challenges. Ion solvation free energies can be calculated via different semiempirical ways, e.g., using implicit solvent models or cluster of explicit molecule models; however, systematically improving these models is difficult due to their lack of a solid theoretical base. A theoretically sound approach for calculating the free energy is to use thermodynamic integration. Nevertheless, owing to the difficulties of self-consistent convergence in first-principles calculations for unphysical atomic configurations, the computational alchemy approach has not been widely used for first-principles calculations. This study proposes a general approach to use first-principles computational alchemy for calculating the ion solvation energy. This approach is also applicable for other small molecules. The calculated ion solvation free energies for Li+, Na+, K+, Be2+, Mg2+, and Ca2+ are close to the experimental results, and the standard deviation due to molecular dynamics fluctuations is within 0.06 eV.</description>
      <author>Chao Lin, Xiaojun He, Cong Xi, Qianfan Zhang, Lin&#8208;Wang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0191068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe Based Mof Encapsulating [Co(En)3]3+ to Prepare Fen3-Con3 Dual-Atom Catalyst for Efficient Orr in Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823403</link>
      <description>Xiaopeng Zhang, Cheng Gao, Longzhu Li, Xiaoming Yan, Ning Zhang, Junjiang Bao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaopeng Zhang, Cheng Gao, Longzhu Li, Xiaoming Yan, Ning Zhang, Junjiang Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Via Partial Oxidation of Re Through Co Modification in Nanoalloy Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823406</link>
      <description>An Jiang, Chao Chen, Jiwen Feng, Qiang Li, Wei Liu, Mingdong Dong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396804020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>An Jiang, Chao Chen, Jiwen Feng, Qiang Li, Wei Liu, Mingdong Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic exploration of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</link>
      <description>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng, Computational and theoretical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396807019

                The reaction rate of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an important factor restricting its application. In this work, we have systematic explorated of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for ORR and OER. Firstly, a variety of stability analysis methods show that most of the catalysts have excellent stability. Secondly, a series of excellent bifunctional catalysts are screened by volcanic maps, ORR overpotential (&#951;ORR), OER overpotential (&#951;OER), and bifunctional index (BI), such as, RhN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.28 V, &#951;OER = 0.34 V, BI = 0.62 V) and CoN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.33 V, &#951;OER = 0.37 V, BI = 0.70 V). In particular, RhN3O1-1 has the smallest BI value, indicating that it has the best bifunctional catalytic activity. This study offers insights into how the coordination environment affects the activity of OER/ORR.</description>
      <author>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Nanoparticles Supported on P-Doped Tungsten Nitride Nanosheets as Catalysts for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01135</link>
      <description>Shuqin Liang, Pengyuan Wang, Meizan Jing, Huashuai Hu, Shaohong Zhang, Zifan Cang, Youpeng Zhao, H. Gong, Jian Liu, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396829656

                Electrochemical water decomposition is a promising alternative to hydrogen production (HER), but it is significantly limited by the scarcity of precious metals. Here, we propose a highly efficient yet low-cost phosphorus-modified nickel/tungsten nitride (P-Ni/WN) electrocatalyst, which exhibits excellent HER performance with a low overpotential (45 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2) and a high exchange current density (2.02 mA cm&#8211;2). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations and experiments reveal that the introduction of P and Ni attracts electrons from W species, making WN more conducive to the HER reaction. Moreover, the P doping contributes to the dispersion of Ni nanoparticles on the WN support, thereby enhancing the HER performance of the P-Ni/WN catalyst. This work provides a facile approach to improve the electrocatalytic activity of nickel-based catalysts in the context of the HER.</description>
      <author>Shuqin Liang, Pengyuan Wang, Meizan Jing, Huashuai Hu, Shaohong Zhang, Zifan Cang, Youpeng Zhao, H. Gong, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the pH-Dependent Catalytic Activity for the Layered Li&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;CoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00413</link>
      <description>Huiyan Zeng, Jiajun Chen, Chao Wang, Jun Qi, Zhongfei Liu, Mengxian Li, Long Gu, Jian Wen Wang, Enna Hong, Yan Zhang, Jin Xu, Chunzhen Yang, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830301

                Many highly active catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) demonstrate strong pH-dependent catalytic activities. However, the exact mechanism behind this phenomenon is still a subject of debate. In this study, delithiated Li0.5CoO2 is utilized as a model catalyst due to its tunable chemical states and layered structure that can facilitate reversible intercalation and deintercalation of cations. By increasing the pH to 14 using a 1.0 M CsOH solution, rapid intercalation of Cs+ cations and water molecules induce notable lattice expansion up to 9.9 &#197;, resulting in an order of magnitude higher OER intrinsic activity comparing to that in 0.1 M CsOH. It is hypothesized that lattice water in layered structure facilitates the dynamic intercalation and deintercalation of Cs+ cations, promoting the so-called "electrochemical-chemical" reaction mechanism. These findings provide valuable insights into the intricate nature of surface dynamics and the redox chemistry on the catalyst/electrolyte interface during the OER.</description>
      <author>Huiyan Zeng, Jiajun Chen, Chao Wang, Jun Qi, Zhongfei Liu, Mengxian Li, Long Gu, Jian Wen Wang, Enna Hong, Yan Zhang, Jin Xu, Chunzhen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time&#8208;Resolved Oxidation State Changes Are Key to Elucidating the Bifunctionality of Perovskite Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12737</link>
      <description>Casey E. Beall, Emiliana Fabbri, Adam H. Clark, Vivian Meier, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Dino Aegerter, Thomas Graule, Thomas J. Schmidt, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831905

                In a unified regenerative fuel cell (URFC) or reversible fuel cell, the oxygen bifunctional catalyst must switch reversibly between the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), fuel cell mode, and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), electrolyzer mode. However, it is often unclear what effect alternating between ORR and OER has on the electrochemical behavior and physiochemical properties of the catalyst. Herein, operando X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) is utilized to monitor the continuous and dynamic evolution of the Co, Mn, and Fe oxidation states of perovskite catalysts Ba 0.5 Sr 0.5 Co 0.8 Fe 0.2 O 3&#8208;&#948; (BSCF) and La 0.4 Sr 0.6 MnO 3&#8208;&#948; (LSM), while the potential is oscillated between reducing and oxidizing potentials with cyclic voltammetry. The results reveal the importance of investigating bifunctional catalysts by alternating between fuel cell and electrolyzer operation and highlight the limitations and challenges of bifunctional catalysts. It is shown that the requirements for ORR and OER performance are divergent and that the oxidative potentials of OER are detrimental to ORR activity. These findings are used to give guidelines for future bifunctional catalyst design. Additionally, it is demonstrated how sunlight can be used to reactivate the ORR activity of LSM after rigorous cycling.</description>
      <author>Casey E. Beall, Emiliana Fabbri, Adam H. Clark, Vivian Meier, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Dino Aegerter, Thomas Graule, Thomas J. Schmidt</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#28023;&#32966;&#29366;CoTe-CoP&#24322;&#36136;&#32467;&#26500;&#20652;&#21270;&#21058;&#22312;&#20840;pH&#33539;&#22260;&#20869;&#39640;&#25928;&#26512;&#27682;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2820-0</link>
      <description>Shengli Zhu, Minghui Xing, Zhe L&#252;, Zelong Qiao, Shitao Wang, Qianchuan Zhao, Yu Zhang, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao, Science China. Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834143

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengli Zhu, Minghui Xing, Zhe L&#252;, Zelong Qiao, Shitao Wang, Qianchuan Zhao, Yu Zhang, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2820-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous enhanced photocatalytic overall water splitting on AlO/WSi2N4 vdW heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160247</link>
      <description>C. H. Li, Liang Xu, Zehua Jin, Qiongchao Wang, Bin Xiao, Zhengquan Li, Lingling Wang, Kun Dong, Tong Chen, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834524

                Completely achieving spontaneous water splitting without sacrificing co-catalysts poses a significant challenge, as factors such as electrical, optical, and catalytic activity can limit the conversion efficiency of solar energy to hydrogen. Herein, we propose a type-II van der Waals heterostructure composed of vertically stacked AlO and WSi2N4, and systematically investigate its mechanism and potential for catalyzing water splitting. Photon-induced photocatalytic water splitting takes advantage of the staggered energy bands of the heterojunction, effectively promoting the separation of photogenerated carriers and thus enhancing catalytic efficiency. In neutral water environment, the band edge position of AlO/WSi2N4 aligns with the redox potential required for water decomposition. Thermodynamic analysis of the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions indicates that the external potential provided by photogenerated carriers is expected to trigger spontaneous water decomposition. Moreover, with its high electron mobility (4800.62 cm2/Vs) and a solar-to-hydrogen energy conversion efficiency of up to 19.98 %, the AlO/WSi2N4 heterojunction demonstrates substantial potential as a photoelectric catalyst. This research introduces a promising avenue for efficient photocatalytic production of clean energy.</description>
      <author>C. H. Li, Liang Xu, Zehua Jin, Qiongchao Wang, Bin Xiao, Zhengquan Li, Lingling Wang, Kun Dong, Tong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of transition metal atom-doped NiSe2 electrocatalysts for efficient alkaline hydrogen precipitation using first principles screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141324</link>
      <description>Yangyang Xu, Yiwei Zhao, Yuanjiang Lv, Xinmeng Er, Mingxia Liu, Fei Ma, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834534

                Transition metal (TM) doping exhibits great potential in designing high-performance two-dimensional (2D) NiSe2-based catalysts for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). 22 TM atom-doped 2D-NiSe2 catalysts are screened, and the effects of TM doping on the thermal stability and HER catalytic activity are investigated by first-principles calculations. Among them, Cu doped 2D-NiSe2 might exhibit remarkable HER properties with the water dissociation energy of 1.03 eV and H adsorption Gibbs free energy of &#8722;0.05 eV. Furthermore, we elucidate the reasons behind the different HER activities. These findings suggest new possibilities for the application of Cu doped 2D-NiSe2 for alkaline HER, offering new perspectives for future research.</description>
      <author>Yangyang Xu, Yiwei Zhao, Yuanjiang Lv, Xinmeng Er, Mingxia Liu, Fei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Hydrogen Passivation Effects in TiC-Based Single-Atom Catalysts for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00550</link>
      <description>Seong Chan Cho, Chi Ho Lee, Sang Uck Lee, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834660

                The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is crucial for producing hydrogen gas via electrochemical water splitting. Among diverse strategies to activate the HER, single-atom catalysts (SACs) are efficient alternatives to conventional platinum catalysts, focusing on titanium carbide (TiC) as a support material with good redox and electronic stability. Using this, we conducted a comprehensive investigation of various SAC candidates, screening their thermodynamic stabilities and HER activities. These calculations revealed four possible transition metal (TM) (Pt, Pd, Au, and Ag)-embedded TiC candidates (TM@TiC) that are thermodynamically stable and further suggested that they exhibit an intriguing H*-passivated surface state, significantly improving HER activities. Notably, the Pt@TiC demonstrates superior activity, promoting H2 gas generation due to its unique H*-passivated surface, which enables a sustainable HER. Therefore, this work introduces a new SAC paradigm centered around the H*-passivated surface, expanding the conventional focus on a single TM site.</description>
      <author>Seong Chan Cho, Chi Ho Lee, Sang Uck Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperation between single atom catalyst and support to promote nitrogen electroreduction to ammonia: A theoretical insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.002</link>
      <description>Wei Guo, Siyao Wang, Hongxia Wang, Qinghai Cai, Jingxiang Zhao, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835133

                The co-catalysis between single atom catalyst (SAC) and its support has recently emerged as a promising strategy to synergistically boost the catalytic activity of some complex electrochemical reactions, encompassing multiple intermediates and pathways. Herein, we utilized defective BC3 monolayer-supported SACs as a prototype to investigate the cooperative effects of SACs and their support on the catalytic performance of the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) for ammonia (NH3) production. The results showed that these SACs can be firmly stabilized on these defective BC3 supports with high stability against aggregation. Furthermore, co-activation of the inert N2 reactant was observed in certain embedded SACs and their neighboring B atoms on the certain BC3 sheets due to the noticeable charge transfer and significant N&#8211;N bond elongation. Our high-throughput screening revealed that the Mo/DVCC and W/DVCC exhibit superior NRR catalytic performance, characterized by a low limiting potential of &#8722;0.33 and &#8722;0.43V, respectively, which can be further increased under acid conditions based on the constant potential method. Moreover, varying NRR catalytic activities can be attributed to the differences in the valence state of active sites. Remarkably, further microkinetic modeling analysis displayed that the turnover frequency of N2&#8211;to&#8211;NH3 conversion on Mo/DVCC is as large as 1.20 &#215; 10&#8722;3 s&#8722;1 site&#8722;1 at 700 K and 100 bar, thus guaranteeing its ultra-fast reaction rate. Our results not only suggest promising advanced electrocatalysts for NRR, but also offered an effective avenue to regulate the electrocatalytic performance via the co-catalytic metal&#8211;support interactions.</description>
      <author>Wei Guo, Siyao Wang, Hongxia Wang, Qinghai Cai, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretical Benchmark of the Geometric and Optical Properties for 3d Transition Metal Nanoclusters via Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00408</link>
      <description>Shana Havenridge, Cong Liu, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A/&#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835391

                Understanding structure&#8211;property relationships in atomically precise metal nanoclusters is vital in finding selective and tunable catalysts. In this study, density functional theory (DFT) was used to benchmark seven exchange correlation functionals at different basis sets for 17 atomically precise nanoclusters against experimentally determined geometries, band gaps, and optical gaps. The set contains both monometallic and bimetallic clusters that possess at least two types of 3d transition metals (specifically, Cu, Ni, Fe, or Co). The benchmark highlights that PBE0 is a good functional to use regardless of the basis set, and Minnesota functionals do well with respect to specific metals. Further, while long-range corrected functionals overestimate band and optical gaps, they model absorption features better than the other considered functionals. The study additionally looks at the photoinduced hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the CO2 reduction mechanism on nanoclusters reported from the literature.</description>
      <author>Shana Havenridge, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Capture With Mixed-Matrix Membrane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-93940-9.00269-3</link>
      <description>Hojatollah Vali, Arash Sadeghi, Mohammad Javad Shafiee, M Barzegar, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396838798

                One promising technology for carbon capture is mixed-matrix membrane (MMM) technology. MMMs are composite materials that combine a polymer matrix with inorganic fillers or nanoparticles to enhance the separation performance of the membrane. These membranes offer several advantages, including high selectivity, tunable permeability, and resistance to harsh operating conditions. The incorporation of inorganic fillers or nanoparticles into the polymer matrix improves the separation properties of the membrane by creating a tortuous path for gas molecules, increasing the surface area, and enhancing the interaction between the membrane and the gas molecules. This results in improved carbon dioxide capture efficiency and selectivity. MMM technology offers potential advantages over other carbon capture technologies. It has the potential for lower energy consumption compared to solvent-based absorption processes and can be easily integrated into existing gas separation systems. MMMs also have the advantage of being scalable and cost-effective, making them suitable for large-scale industrial applications. This chapter will delve deeper into the principles of carbon capture technologies, mixed-matrix membranes (MMMs), the materials used in MMMs, the strategies for improving MMMs, and the challenges associated with them.</description>
      <author>Hojatollah Vali, Arash Sadeghi, Mohammad Javad Shafiee, M Barzegar, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-93940-9.00269-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Electrocatalysts Anchored on Phosphoniobic Acid (M&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;/PNb&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;40&lt;/sub&gt;) Cluster for Water Splitting (HER/OER) and Metal-Air Batteries (ORR)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00349</link>
      <description>Sajjad Hussain, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li, Zhansheng Lu, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396844986

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajjad Hussain, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li, Zhansheng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the First Activation Step of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction over Ag and Ni-N-C Active Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109728</link>
      <description>Yujie Wang, Jungho Kim, Hyun Dong Jung, Jun Liu, Ke Yao, Chuan Xia, Seoin Back, Kun Jiang, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396846502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Wang, Jungho Kim, Hyun Dong Jung, Jun Liu, Ke Yao, Chuan Xia, Seoin Back, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Hydrogenation of Carbon Dioxide as a Method to Produce Valuable Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s2070050424010045</link>
      <description>I. A. Makaryan, &#1048;. &#1042;. &#1057;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1057;&#1072;&#1074;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Catalysis in industry. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396852768

                No abstract</description>
      <author>I. A. Makaryan, &#1048;. &#1042;. &#1057;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1057;&#1072;&#1074;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s2070050424010045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peierls-like distortion drives anion ordering in rutile TiOF</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.054602</link>
      <description>S. Senthil Nathan, Danilo Puggioni, James M. Rondinelli, Physical review materials. 8(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Senthil Nathan, Danilo Puggioni, James M. Rondinelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.054602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu Atomic Subnanoclusters on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01277</link>
      <description>Hanjun Zou, Yan Tong, Yajie Feng, Yongfeng Zhou, Jiaxun Xiao, Xia Lu, Anku Guha, B&#225;rbara B. Polesso, Bin Zhang, Juanli Liu, Kaiwen Wang, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857555

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hanjun Zou, Yan Tong, Yajie Feng, Yongfeng Zhou, Jiaxun Xiao, Xia Lu, Anku Guha, B&#225;rbara B. Polesso, Bin Zhang, Juanli Liu, Kaiwen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dewetting of Pt Nanoparticles Boosts Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Due to Electronic Metal&#8208;Support Interaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403628</link>
      <description>Shreyas Harsha, Rakesh Kumar Sharma, Martin Dierner, Christoph Baeumer, Igor A. Makhotkin, Guido Mul, Paolo Ghigna, Erdmann Spiecker, Johannes Will, Marco Altomare, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396860609

                Abstract Solid&#8208;state dewetting is the heat&#8208;induced agglomeration of thin metal films into defined nanoparticles (NPs). Dewetted Pt nanoparticles are investigated on F&#8208;doped SnO 2 (FTO) substrates as model binder&#8208;free electrodes for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Dewetting of Pt films into particles exposes the FTO substrate and the metal/support (Pt&#8208;FTO) contact line. Despite the decrease in Pt electrochemical surface area (ECSA) upon dewetting, dewetted NPs show a &gt;3&#8208;fold increase in ECSA&#8208;normalized HER activity compared to as&#8208;deposited nanocrystalline Pt films. Electrodes designed with dewetted Pt NPs of different sizes show that the HER activity does not only correlate with the ECSA but also increases with increasing the Pt&#8208;FTO contact line length. The smaller the NPs, the larger the Pt&#8208;FTO contact line, and the higher the activity. This effect is ascribed to electronic metal&#8208;support interaction (EMSI), due to electron transfer from FTO to Pt. It is proposed that EMSI effects alter the electronic structure of Pt sites near the Pt&#8208;FTO contact line, facilitating the H 2 evolution kinetics. When NPs are a few nm&#8208;sized, a large mass fraction of Pt is affected by EMSI, resulting in a further increase of HER activity compared to NPs &#8805;10 nm despite the lower ECSA.</description>
      <author>Shreyas Harsha, Rakesh Kumar Sharma, Martin Dierner, Christoph Baeumer, Igor A. Makhotkin, Guido Mul, Paolo Ghigna, Erdmann Spiecker, Johannes Will, Marco Altomare</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase segregation and nanoconfined fluid O2 in a lithium-rich oxide cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-024-01873-5</link>
      <description>Kit McColl, Samuel W. Coles, Pezhman Zarabadi&#8211;Poor, Benjamin J. Morgan, M. Sa&#239;ful Islam, Nature materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396862249

                Abstract Lithium-rich oxide cathodes lose energy density during cycling due to atomic disordering and nanoscale structural rearrangements, which are both challenging to characterize. Here we resolve the kinetics and thermodynamics of these processes in an exemplar layered Li-rich (Li 1.2&#8211; x Mn 0.8 O 2 ) cathode using a combined approach of ab initio molecular dynamics and cluster expansion-based Monte Carlo simulations. We identify a kinetically accessible and thermodynamically favourable mechanism to form O 2 molecules in the bulk, involving Mn migration and driven by interlayer oxygen dimerization. At the top of charge, the bulk structure locally phase segregates into MnO 2 -rich regions and Mn-deficient nanovoids, which contain O 2 molecules as a nanoconfined fluid. These nanovoids are connected in a percolating network, potentially allowing long-range oxygen transport and linking bulk O 2 formation to surface O 2 loss. These insights highlight the importance of developing strategies to kinetically stabilize the bulk structure of Li-rich O-redox cathodes to maintain their high energy densities.</description>
      <author>Kit McColl, Samuel W. Coles, Pezhman Zarabadi&#8211;Poor, Benjamin J. Morgan, M. Sa&#239;ful Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-024-01873-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of copper as a unique catalyst for C&#8211;C coupling in electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02056a</link>
      <description>Jie Chen, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Jia Zhang, Wei Chen, Yi&#8208;Yang Sun, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396863962

                Evolution of the molecular orbitals during CO&#8211;CO coupling on the Cu(100) surface and identification of the corresponding frontier molecular orbitals.</description>
      <author>Jie Chen, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Jia Zhang, Wei Chen, Yi&#8208;Yang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02056a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveil the Triple Roles of Water Molecule on Power Generation of MXene Derived TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; based Moisture Electric Generator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400590</link>
      <description>Chao Liu, Tao Wan, Peiyuan Guan, Mengyao Li, Shuo Zhang, Long Hu, Yu&#8208;Chieh Kuo, Ziheng Feng, Fandi Chen, Yuqing Zhu, Haowei Jia, Tao Cao, Tianyue Liang, Tushar Kumeria, Dawei Su, Dewei Chu, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396883693

                Abstract Evaporation&#8208;driven electricity generators have been proposed to generate electricity by water interacting with nanostructured materials. However, several proposed mechanisms, such as intrinsic gradient of polar functional groups principle and electrokinetic effect perspective, are in wide discrepancy. Here, through the combination of theoretical calculations involving time dimension on material's moisturizing process and experimental analyses, it is revealed the working principle through the water molecule triple roles in driving moisture electric generators (MEGs): 1) intrinsic H 2 O absorption on the material surface and splitting into hydroxy group and proton due to the polarizability of the material surface determined by the static electric potential of the materials. This process induces the electrochemical potential difference of the materials via the work function changes; 2) freely diffused protons derived from the H 2 O splitting work as the ions charge carriers; 3) via the hydrogen bond of the water molecules to drive charge carriers diffuse between opposite electrodes, maintaining the internal circuit current flow. It is successfully unveiled that anatase TiO 2 based materials for output voltage changes correlated to the domains&#8217; work function's difference, tuning by the surface adsorption species (H, Cl, OH) and anisotropic exposed crystal facets of the material. This work unveils MEG's general working principle.</description>
      <author>Chao Liu, Tao Wan, Peiyuan Guan, Mengyao Li, Shuo Zhang, Long Hu, Yu&#8208;Chieh Kuo, Ziheng Feng, Fandi Chen, Yuqing Zhu, Haowei Jia, Tao Cao, Tianyue Liang, Tushar Kumeria, Dawei Su, Dewei Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed asymmetric cobalt electrocatalyst for efficient hydrogen peroxide production in neutral media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48209-0</link>
      <description>Longxiang Liu, Liqun Kang, Jianrui Feng, David G. Hopkinson, Christopher S. Allen, Yeshu Tan, Hao Gu, Iuliia Mikulska, Ver&#243;nica Celorrio, Diego Gianolio, Tianlei Wang, Liquan Zhang, Kaiqi Li, Jichao Zhang, Jiexin Zhu, Georg Held, Pilar Ferrer, David C. Grinter, June Callison, Martin C. Wilding, Sining Chen, Ivan P. Parkin, Guanjie He, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396887199

                Abstract Electrochemical hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) production (EHPP) via a two-electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e - ORR) provides a promising alternative to replace the energy-intensive anthraquinone process. M-N-C electrocatalysts, which consist of atomically dispersed transition metals and nitrogen-doped carbon, have demonstrated considerable EHPP efficiency. However, their full potential, particularly regarding the correlation between structural configurations and performances in neutral media, remains underexplored. Herein, a series of ultralow metal-loading M-N-C electrocatalysts are synthesized and investigated for the EHPP process in the neutral electrolyte. CoNCB material with the asymmetric Co-C/N/O configuration exhibits the highest EHPP activity and selectivity among various as-prepared M-N-C electrocatalyst, with an outstanding mass activity (6.1 &#215; 10 5 A g Co &#8722;1 at 0.5 V vs. RHE), and a high practical H 2 O 2 production rate (4.72 mol g catalyst &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 ). Compared with the popularly recognized square-planar symmetric Co-N 4 configuration, the superiority of asymmetric Co-C/N/O configurations is elucidated by X-ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy analysis and computational studies.</description>
      <author>Longxiang Liu, Liqun Kang, Jianrui Feng, David G. Hopkinson, Christopher S. Allen, Yeshu Tan, Hao Gu, Iuliia Mikulska, Ver&#243;nica Celorrio, Diego Gianolio, Tianlei Wang, Liquan Zhang, Kaiqi Li, Jichao Zhang, Jiexin Zhu, Georg Held, Pilar Ferrer, David C. Grinter, June Callison, Martin C. Wilding, Sining Chen, Ivan P. Parkin, Guanjie He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48209-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput screening of metal nitrides for electrochemical nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160289</link>
      <description>Zhenxin Lou, Shuhao Zhou, Yu Hou, Hua Gui Yang, Hai Yang Yuan, Hai Feng Wang, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396888736

                Metal nitrides have garnered considerable attention in the context of nitrogen reduction reactions (NRR) due to their rich lattice nitrogen and abundant nitrogen vacancies to activate N2. However, the identification of suitable metal nitrides with superior stability, activity, and selectivity (vs. hydrogen evolution reaction, HER) for electrochemical NRR under rigorous isotope labeling experiments remains a perplexing challenge in experiments. In this study, we implemented a systematic screening protocol to assess the electrochemical stability and efficiency of various metal nitrides for NRR by high-throughput density functional theory calculations, aiming to search out promising metal nitride catalysts. Through a set of predetermined criteria, a subset of 6 candidates emerges as the most promising metal nitrides for NRR from a pool of 668 metal nitrides sourced from the Materials Project Database, all of which catalyze NRR following the Mars-van Krevelen pathway. Importantly, based on the analysis of these candidates, the unique structural property (i.e., four(or three)-coordinate lattice nitrogen) and energy descriptor (i.e., the formation energy of the lattice nitrogen vacancy is around 2.1 eV) of potential metal nitrides for electrochemical NRR were extracted, which could be used as the direction to rationally design metal nitride catalyst. This research not only serves as a valuable guide for experimental investigations into potential metal nitrides for NRR, but also provides an efficient method for high-throughput screening of potential catalysts for other electrochemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Zhenxin Lou, Shuhao Zhou, Yu Hou, Hua Gui Yang, Hai Yang Yuan, Hai Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Metallic and Oxidized Tin Using Grand-Canonical DFT and In Situ ATR-SEIRA Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01290</link>
      <description>Todd N. Whittaker, Yuval Fishler, Jacob M. Clary, Paige Brimley, Adam Holewinski, Charles B. Musgrave, Carrie A. Farberow, Wilson A. Smith, Derek Vigil&#8208;Fowler, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396889493

                Electrochemical CO2 reduction (CO2R) to formate is an attractive carbon emissions mitigation strategy due to the existing market and attractive price for formic acid. Tin is an effective electrocatalyst for CO2R to formate, but the underlying reaction mechanism and whether the active phase of tin is metallic or oxidized during reduction is openly debated. In this report, we used grand-canonical density functional theory and attenuated total reflection surface-enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy to identify differences in the vibrational signatures of surface species during CO2R on fully metallic and oxidized tin surfaces. Our results show that CO2R is feasible on both metallic and oxidized tin. We propose that the key difference between each surface termination is that CO2R catalyzed by metallic tin surfaces is limited by the electrochemical activation of CO2, whereas CO2R catalyzed by oxidized tin surfaces is limited by the slow reductive desorption of formate. While the exact degree of oxidation of tin surfaces during CO2R is unlikely to be either fully metallic or fully oxidized, this study highlights the limiting behavior of these two surfaces and lays out the key features of each that our results predict will promote rapid CO2R catalysis. Additionally, we highlight the power of integrating high-fidelity quantum mechanical modeling and spectroscopic measurements to elucidate intricate electrocatalytic reaction pathways.</description>
      <author>Todd N. Whittaker, Yuval Fishler, Jacob M. Clary, Paige Brimley, Adam Holewinski, Charles B. Musgrave, Carrie A. Farberow, Wilson A. Smith, Derek Vigil&#8208;Fowler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of atomic substitution in first coordination shell of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C single atom catalyst towards oxygen reduction reaction: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.124</link>
      <description>Monika Singh, Dipak K. Das, Anuj Kumar, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396890883

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Monika Singh, Dipak K. Das, Anuj Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Engineering in Zirconium&#8211;Nitrogen-Functionalized Materials for N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction: A First-Principles Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00781</link>
      <description>Jianpeng Guo, Hao Luo, Qingzhong Zhao, Bingbing Suo, Bo Zhou, Haoguo Zhu, Zhiyong Zhang, Qi Song, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396894429

                Coordination engineering was employed to optimize the coordination environment of the zirconium (Zr) atom anchored on the porphyrins (PP), serving as single-atom catalysts (SACs). Five promising ZrPP-A (A = C3O, N4, N2C2-o, C2O2-o, and C2O2-n) candidates as electrocatalysts for nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) were identified through a "four-step" screening strategy, from a pool of 15 designed models. Performance evaluation of these candidates for NRR was conducted using first-principles calculations. A comprehensive examination of reaction pathways unveiled a predilection for a hybrid pathway when employing the selected catalysts for the NRR. The stability and notable catalytic activity of ZrPP-A stemmed from orbital hybridization and charge transfer mechanisms, occurring both between Zr and its coordinated atoms, as well as between ZrPP-A and the adsorbed N2 molecule. Zr played a pivotal role in orchestrating charge transfer during the NRR process. Simultaneously, coordinating atoms and the PP moiety collectively facilitated supplementary charge transfers to or from the adsorbate. Because of the robust coupling between O and its neighboring carbon atoms, no significant bonds were detected between the central Zr and the coordinating O atoms. An asymmetric coordination environment results in an uneven charge distribution within the substrate, inducing polarization of N2 molecules and their migration toward regions of asymmetric charge aggregation. This study underscores the significance of not only focusing on the single-atom catalyst itself but also its coordination environment when designing catalysts for enhanced efficiency.</description>
      <author>Jianpeng Guo, Hao Luo, Qingzhong Zhao, Bingbing Suo, Bo Zhou, Haoguo Zhu, Zhiyong Zhang, Qi Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Evaluation and Durability Analysis of NiFeCoOx Catalysts for Alkaline Water Electrolysis in Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14050322</link>
      <description>Khaja Wahab Ahmed, Michael Fowler, Catalysts. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396897620

                This study examines the catalytic activity of NiFeCoOx catalysts for anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolysis. The catalysts were synthesized with a Ni to Co ratio of 2:1 and Fe content ranges from 2.5 to 12.5 wt%. The catalysts were characterized using scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and X-ray diffraction (XRD) techniques. The catalytic activity of the NiFeCoOx catalysts was evaluated through linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) and chronoamperometry (CA) experiments for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The catalyst with 5% Fe content exhibited the highest catalytic activity, achieving an overpotential of 228 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Long-term catalyst testing for the OER at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 showed stable electrolysis operation for 100 h. The catalyst was further analyzed in an AEM water electrolyzer in a single-cell test, and the NiFeCoOx catalyst with 5% Fe at the anode demonstrated the highest current densities of 1516 mA cm&#8722;2 and 1620 mA cm&#8722;2 at 55 &#176;C and 70 &#176;C at 2.1 V. The maximum current density of 1880 mA cm&#8722;2 was achieved at 2.2 V and 70 &#176;C. The Nyquist plot analysis of electrolysis at 55 &#176;C showed that the NiFeCoOx catalyst with 5% Fe had lower activation resistance compared with the other Fe loadings, indicating enhanced performance. The durability test was performed for 8 h, showing stable AEM water electrolysis with minimum degradation. An overall cell efficiency of 70.5% was achieved for the operation carried out at a higher current density of 0.8 A cm&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Khaja Wahab Ahmed, Michael Fowler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14050322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene-Supported Mn4 Single-Atom Catalysts for Multifunctional Electrocatalysis Enabled by Axial Fe Tetramer Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4827186</link>
      <description>Lian&#8208;Ming Gao, Donghai Wu, Silu Li, Haobo Li, Dongwei Ma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396899562

                Multifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are crucial for development of the key electrochemical energy storage and conversion devices, for which single-atom catalyst (SAC) has present great promises. Very recently, some experimental works showed that structurally well-defined ultra-small transition-metal clusters (such as Fe and Co tetramers, denoted as Fe4 and Co4, respectively), can efficiently modulate the catalytic behavior of SACs by axial coordination. Herein, taking the graphene-supported MN4 SACs as representatives, we theoretically explored the feasibility of realizing multifunctional SACs for ORR, OER, and HER by this novel axial coordination engineering. Through extensive first-principles calculations, from 23 candidates, IrN4 decorated with Fe4 (IrN4/Fe4) is identified as the promising trifunctional catalyst with the theoretical overpotential of 0.43, 0.51, and 0.30 V for OER, ORR, and HER, respectively. RhN4/Fe4 and CoN4/Fe4 are recognized as potential OER and ORR bifunctional catalysts. In addition, NiN4/Fe4 exhibits the best ORR activity with an overpotential of 0.30 V, far superior to the pristine NiN4 SAC (0.88 V). Electronic structure analyses reveal that the significantly enhanced ORR activity can be ascribed to the orbital and charge redistribution of Ni active center, resulting from its electronic interaction with Fe4 cluster. This work could stimulate and guide the rational design of graphene-based multifunctional SACs realized by axial coordination of small TM clusters, and provide insights into the modulation mechanism.</description>
      <author>Lian&#8208;Ming Gao, Donghai Wu, Silu Li, Haobo Li, Dongwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4827186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrochemical nitrate reduction on copper nitride with moderate intermediates adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.084</link>
      <description>Jinshan Wei, Gan Ye, Hui Ju Lin, Zhiming Li, Ji Zhou, Yayun Li, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396907384

                Nitrate in surface and underground water caused systematic risk to the ecological environment. The electrochemically reduction of nitrate into ammonia (NO3RR), offering a sustainable route for nitrate containing wastewater treatment and ammonia fertilizer conversion. Exploration of improved catalysts activity with lower energy barriers is still challenging. Herein, we present a copper nitride (Cu3N) catalyst with moderate *NOx and&#183;H2O intermediates adsorptions showed enhanced NO3RR performance. Density functional theory calculations reveals that the unique electronic structure of Cu3N provides efficient active sites for NO3RR, and enables balanced adsorption of *NO3 and&#183;H2O (&#916;E descriptor) and moderate intermediate (*NO3 &#8594; HNO3, *NH2&#8594;*NH3) adsorption energy. Interestingly, in-situ analysis proved the potential-driven reconstruction and rehabilitation of Cu3N, thus implied for better mechanism understanding. The NO3RR activity of Cu3N surpasses that of most recent catalysts and demonstrates superior stability and implies the application for NH4+ fertilizer recovery, which maintaining an NH3 Faradaic efficiency of 93.1 % and high yield rate of 2.9 mg cm2h&#8722;1 at &#8722;0.6 V versus RHE.</description>
      <author>Jinshan Wei, Gan Ye, Hui Ju Lin, Zhiming Li, Ji Zhou, Yayun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchoring Ordered Ptzn Nanoparticles on Mof-Derived Carbon Support: Towards Highly Active and Durable Catalysts for Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4828082</link>
      <description>KwangHo Lee, Eoyoon Lee, Ho&#8208;Nam Chang, JeongHan Roh, SangJae Lee, Junu Bak, YongKeun Kwon, Hyung Chul Ham, EunAe Cho, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396910558

                Despite the superior catalytic activity of ordered Pt-M nanoparticles for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), challenges such as particle growth during the ordering transformation and insufficient durability over extended operation hinder their application in polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). In this study, a zeolitic imidazolate framework-8 (ZIF-8) is pyrolyzed into zinc and nitrogen-doped carbon (ZnNC). Pt nanoparticles are synthesized on the ZnNC and underwent heat treatment, transforming into ordered PtZn nanoparticles (O-PtZn). Through this simple process, well distributed O-PtZn nanoparticles are obtained with an average particle size of approximately 4.5 nm. The O-PtZn/ZnNC achieves outstanding ORR mass activity and durability compared to the corresponding value of Pt/C both in a half-cell and in a single-cell configuration. Density functional theory calculations illustrate that ZnNC has a strong binding energy with O-PtZn and a minimum distance, resulting in exceptional electrochemical active surface area retention of O-PtZn/ZnNC.</description>
      <author>KwangHo Lee, Eoyoon Lee, Ho&#8208;Nam Chang, JeongHan Roh, SangJae Lee, Junu Bak, YongKeun Kwon, Hyung Chul Ham, EunAe Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4828082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiment-Driven Atomistic Materials Modeling: A Case Study Combining X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy and Machine Learning Potentials to Infer the Structure of Oxygen-Rich Amorphous Carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01897</link>
      <description>Tigany Zarrouk, R. I. Ibragimova, Albert P. Bart&#243;k, A. Miguel, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396914550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tigany Zarrouk, R. I. Ibragimova, Albert P. Bart&#243;k, A. Miguel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;Capture-activation-recapture&#8221; mechanism-guided design of double-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.04.047</link>
      <description>Cheng He, Shiqi Yan, W. X. Zhang, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396919593

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng He, Shiqi Yan, W. X. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.04.047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of Single-Atom Catalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Based on BiTeBr Monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102377</link>
      <description>Tao Yang, Qiquan Luo, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396920569

                Developing an inexpensive and efficient catalyst for a hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is an effective measure to alleviate the energy crisis. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) based on Janus materials demonstrated promising prospects for the HER. Herein, density functional theory calculations were conducted to systematically investigate the performance of SACs based on the BiTeBr monolayer. Among the one hundred and forty models that were constructed, fourteen SACs with potential HER activity were selected. Significantly, the SAC, in which a single Ru atom is anchored on a BiTeBr monolayer with a Bi vacancy (RuS2/VBi-BiTeBr), exhibits excellent HER activity with an ultra-low |&#916;GH*| value. A further investigation revealed that RuS2/VBi-BiTeBr tends to react through the Volmer&#8211;Heyrovsky mechanism. An electronic structure analysis provided deeper insights into this phenomenon. This is because the Tafel pathway requires overcoming steric hindrance and disrupting stable electron filling states, making it challenging to proceed. This study finally employed constant potential calculations, which approximate experimental situations. The results indicated that the &#916;GH* value at pH = 0 is 0.056 eV for RuS2/VBi-BiTeBr, validating the rationality of the traditional Computational Hydrogen Electrode (CHE) method for performance evaluation in this system. This work provides a reference for the research of new HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Yang, Qiquan Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective CO2 to Proportionally Tunable Syngas at Lower Onset Potential Enabled by Bimetallic Chalcogenides in Polyoxometalate Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124206</link>
      <description>Wencong Sun, Guoyan Zou, Wenxue Tian, Shumiao Li, Min Yang, Chunxiang Li, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396920571

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wencong Sun, Guoyan Zou, Wenxue Tian, Shumiao Li, Min Yang, Chunxiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vesicle-Shaped Co-Ni-S Designed by First Principles Screening and D-Band Center Control for Active Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4828724</link>
      <description>Youbin Zheng, Ze Li, Huajun Guo, Cong-Cong Liu, Yuefeng Chen, Xiuli Han, Dong Liang, Jianbing Zang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396921028

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youbin Zheng, Ze Li, Huajun Guo, Cong-Cong Liu, Yuefeng Chen, Xiuli Han, Dong Liang, Jianbing Zang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4828724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Potential Model of Two-Dimensional Imine Covalent Organic Frameworks with Enhanced Quantum Efficiency for Photocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00980</link>
      <description>Xiao Luo, Yunlei Wang, Haifeng Lv, Xiaojun Wu, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396921458

                Two-dimensional (2D) covalent organic frameworks (COFs) assembled using building blocks have been widely employed in photocatalysis due to their customizable optoelectronic characteristics and porous structure, which facilitate charge carrier and mass movement. Nevertheless, the development of COF photocatalysts encounters a continuous obstacle in enhancing the efficiency of photocatalysis, impeded by a limited comprehension of the orbital interaction between molecular fragments and linkers. In this study, we present a model that examines the interaction between molecular fragments in an imine-based COF at the frontier molecular orbital level, enabling us to comprehend the impact of manipulating linkers on light adsorption, exciton efficiency, and catalytic activity. Our findings demonstrate that altering the connecting orientation of 14 R&#8211;C=N&#8211;R imine linkers in 2D COFs can enhance solar-to-hydrogen (STH) efficiency under visible light from 2.76% to 4.24%. This research has the potential to provide a valuable model for refining photocatalysts with enhanced photocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Xiao Luo, Yunlei Wang, Haifeng Lv, Xiaojun Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of graphene doping and gas adsorption on the peak positions of graphene plasmon resonance and adsorbate infrared absorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0003588</link>
      <description>Jongpil Ye, Journal of vacuum science and technology. B, Nanotechnology &amp; microelectronics. 42(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396924530

                The peak positions of graphene plasmon resonance can be controlled to overlap with those of the infrared absorption spectra of gas molecules, allowing highly sensitive detection and identification by graphene nanoribbons. In this study, we investigate the adsorption of gas molecules, including SO2, SO3, H2S, and NH3, on graphene and characterize its effects on the relative positions of the two peaks using density functional theory and the finite difference time domain method. It is demonstrated that the binding energies are stronger, and the amounts of charge transfer are greater in the case of SO2 and SO3 adsorbed on n-doped graphene than in other cases. Electron acceptance by SO2 and SO3 adsorbates on n-doped graphene redshifts the graphene plasmon resonance peaks and their stretching and wagging infrared absorption peaks. However, the former is significantly further redshifted, leading to narrower peak-position-matching ribbon widths in n-doped graphene than in p-doped graphene. The amounts of charge transfer are relatively small regardless of the doping type in the case of NH3 and H2S, mitigating the doping-type dependence compared to SO2 and SO3. The wagging peaks of NH3 on n-doped graphene are shown to be further blueshifted than on p-doped graphene, rendering their peak-position-matching ribbon widths further closer to each other. These results suggest that the effects of doping and adsorption on the two types of peaks should be considered to optimize the performance of graphene plasmon-based gas sensing and identification.</description>
      <author>Jongpil Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0003588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Approach to Synthesizing Cathode PtCo/C Catalysts for Low-Temperature Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14100856</link>
      <description>&#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1044;. &#1050;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1091;&#1101;&#1088;, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1043;&#1072;&#1074;&#1088;&#1080;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, A. K. Nevelskaya, E. R. Beskopylny, Ilya Pankov, &#1040;. &#1053;. &#1053;&#1080;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Nanomaterials. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396926010

                The presented study is concerned with a new multi-step method to synthesize PtCo/C materials based on composite CoxOy/C that combines the advantages of different liquid-phase synthesis methods. Based on the results of studying the materials at each stage of synthesis with the TG, XRD, TEM, SEI, TXRF, CV and LSV methods, a detailed overview of the sequential changes in catalyst composition and structure at each stage of the synthesis is presented. The PtCo/C catalyst synthesized with the multi-step method is characterized by a uniform distribution of bimetallic nanoparticles of about 3 nm in size over the surface of the support, which result in its high ESA and ORR activity. The activity study for the synthesized PtCo/C catalyst in an MEA showed better current&#8211;voltage characteristics and a higher maximum specific power compared with an MEA based on a commercial Pt/C catalyst. Therefore, the results of the presented study demonstrate high prospects for the developed approach to the multi-step synthesis of PtM/C catalysts, which may enhance the characteristics of proton-exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs).</description>
      <author>&#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1044;. &#1050;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1091;&#1101;&#1088;, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1043;&#1072;&#1074;&#1088;&#1080;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, A. K. Nevelskaya, E. R. Beskopylny, Ilya Pankov, &#1040;. &#1053;. &#1053;&#1080;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14100856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Study of Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction in Fourth-Period Transition Metal&#8211;Tetrahydroxyquinone Organic Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29102320</link>
      <description>Yufeng Wen, Xianshi Zeng, Yanan Xiao, Rong Wen, Kai Xiong, Zhangli Lai, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396928519

                This study investigates the utilisation of organometallic network frameworks composed of fourth-period transition metals and tetrahydroxyquinone (THQ) in electrocatalytic CO2 reduction. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations were employed in analysing binding energies, as well as the stabilities of metal atoms within the THQ frameworks, for transition metal TM-THQs ranging from Y to Cd. The findings demonstrate how metal atoms could be effectively dispersed and held within the THQ frameworks due to sufficiently high binding energies. Most TM-THQ frameworks exhibited favourable selectivity towards CO2 reduction, except for Tc and Ru, which experienced competition from hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and required solution environments with pH values greater than 5.716 and 8.819, respectively, to exhibit CO2RR selectivity. Notably, the primary product of Y, Ag, and Cd was HCOOH; Mo produced HCHO; Pd yielded CO; and Zr, Nb, Tc, Ru, and Rh predominantly generated CH4. Among the studied frameworks, Zr-THQ displayed values of 1.212 V and 1.043 V, corresponding to the highest limiting potential and overpotential, respectively, while other metal&#8211;organic frameworks displayed relatively low ranges of overpotentials from 0.179 V to 0.949 V. Consequently, it is predicted that the TM-THQ framework constructed using a fourth-period transition metal and tetrahydroxyquinone exhibits robust electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Yufeng Wen, Xianshi Zeng, Yanan Xiao, Rong Wen, Kai Xiong, Zhangli Lai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29102320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regioselective hydroformylation with subnanometre Rh clusters in MFI zeolite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01155-y</link>
      <description>Xiaomeng Dou, Zhiguo Pei, Lixiang Qian, Haiyun Hou, Miguel L&#243;pez&#8208;Haro, Carlo Marini, Giovanni Agostini, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Xiangjie Zhang, Liang Zhang, Zhi Cao, Lichen Liu, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396929114

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaomeng Dou, Zhiguo Pei, Lixiang Qian, Haiyun Hou, Miguel L&#243;pez&#8208;Haro, Carlo Marini, Giovanni Agostini, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Xiangjie Zhang, Liang Zhang, Zhi Cao, Lichen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01155-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface&#8208;Enriched Room&#8208;Temperature Liquid Bismuth for Catalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401777</link>
      <description>Jing&#8208;Dong Guo, Zhi Xing, Dingqi Wang, Longbing Qu, Ali Zavabeti, Qining Fan, Yuecheng Zhang, Joshua D. Butson, Jianing Yang, Chao Wu, Jefferson Zhe Liu, Masood S. Alivand, Xiaolei Fan, Gang Kevin Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396932166

                Abstract Bismuth&#8208;based electrocatalysts are effective for carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) reduction to formate. However, at room temperature, these materials are only available in solid state, which inevitably suffers from surface deactivation, declining current densities, and Faradaic efficiencies. Here, the formation of a liquid bismuth catalyst on the liquid gallium surface at ambient conditions is shown as its exceptional performance in the electrochemical reduction of CO 2 (i.e., CO 2 RR). By doping a trace amount of bismuth (740 ppm atomic) in gallium liquid metal, a surface enrichment of bismuth by over 400 times (30 at%) in liquid state is obtained without atomic aggregation, achieving 98% Faradic efficiency for CO 2 conversion to formate over 80 h. Ab initio molecular simulations and density functional theory calculations reveal that bismuth atoms in the liquid state are the most energetically favorable sites for the CO 2 RR intermediates, superior to solid Bi&#8208;sites, as well as joint GaBi&#8208;sites. This study opens an avenue for fabricating high&#8208;performing liquid&#8208;state metallic catalysts that cannot be reached by elementary metals under electrocatalytic conditions.</description>
      <author>Jing&#8208;Dong Guo, Zhi Xing, Dingqi Wang, Longbing Qu, Ali Zavabeti, Qining Fan, Yuecheng Zhang, Joshua D. Butson, Jianing Yang, Chao Wu, Jefferson Zhe Liu, Masood S. Alivand, Xiaolei Fan, Gang Kevin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Semi-Automated Solution Approach Recommender for a Given Use Case: a Case Study for AI/ML in Oncology via Scopus and OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44230-024-00070-6</link>
      <description>Deniz Kenan K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, Alex Elkj&#230;r Vasegaard, Aur&#233;lien Desoeuvres, Peter Nielsen, Human-centric intelligent systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396935000

                Abstract Nowadays, literature review is a necessary task when trying to solve a given problem. However, an exhaustive literature review is very time-consuming in today&#8217;s vast literature landscape. It can take weeks, even if looking only for abstracts or surveys. Moreover, choosing a method among others, and targeting searches within relevant problem and solution domains, are not easy tasks. These are especially true for young researchers or engineers starting to work in their field. Even if surveys that provide methods used to solve a specific problem already exist, an automatic way to do it for any use case is missing, especially for those who don&#8217;t know the existing literature. Our proposed tool, SARBOLD-LLM, allows discovering and choosing among methods related to a given problem, providing additional information about their uses in the literature to derive decision-making insights, in only a few hours. The SARBOLD-LLM comprises three modules: (1: Scopus search) paper selection using a keyword selection scheme to query Scopus API; (2: Scoring and method extraction) relevancy and popularity scores calculation and solution method extraction in papers utilizing OpenAI API (GPT 3.5); (3: Analyzes) sensitivity analysis and post-analyzes which reveals trends, relevant papers and methods. Comparing the SARBOLD-LLM to manual ground truth using precision, recall, and F1-score metrics, the performance results of AI in the oncology case study are 0.68, 0.9, and 0.77, respectively. SARBOLD-LLM demonstrates successful outcomes across various domains, showcasing its robustness and effectiveness. The SARBOLD-LLM addresses engineers more than researchers, as it proposes methods and trends without adding pros and cons. It is a useful tool to select which methods to investigate first and comes as a complement to surveys. This can limit the global search and accumulation of knowledge for the end user. However, it can be used as a director or recommender for future implementation to solve a problem.</description>
      <author>Deniz Kenan K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, Alex Elkj&#230;r Vasegaard, Aur&#233;lien Desoeuvres, Peter Nielsen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44230-024-00070-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergetic effect of vacancy and dual-metals on defective V2CO2 MXene as efficient catalysts for nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160295</link>
      <description>Cuiping Shao, Wenjie Wang, Yuwen Cheng, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396936483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cuiping Shao, Wenjie Wang, Yuwen Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of surface stoichiometry on initial oxidation of intermetallic alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160288</link>
      <description>Wei Xie, Chaoyue Cai, Guangwen Zhou, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396936695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Xie, Chaoyue Cai, Guangwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material Engineering Strategies for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400158</link>
      <description>Yongli Luo, Yulong Zhang, Jiayi Zhu, Tian Xia, Gang Liu, Zhiming Feng, Liwen Pan, Xinhua Liu, Ning Han, Ruiqin Tan, Small methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396944351

                Abstract Water electrolysis, a key enabler of hydrogen energy production, presents significant potential as a strategy for achieving net&#8208;zero emissions. However, the widespread deployment of water electrolysis is currently limited by the high&#8208;cost and scarce noble metal electrocatalysts in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Given this challenge, design and synthesis of cost&#8208;effective and high&#8208;performance alternative catalysts have become a research focus, which necessitates insightful understandings of HER fundamentals and material engineering strategies. Distinct from typical reviews that concentrate only on the summary of recent catalyst materials, this review article shifts focus to material engineering strategies for developing efficient HER catalysts. In&#8208;depth analysis of key material design approaches for HER catalysts, such as doping, vacancy defect creation, phase engineering, and metal&#8208;support engineering, are illustrated along with typical research cases. A special emphasis is placed on designing noble metal&#8208;free catalysts with a brief discussion on recent advancements in electrocatalytic water&#8208;splitting technology. The article also delves into important descriptors, reliable evaluation parameters and characterization techniques, aiming to link the fundamental mechanisms of HER with its catalytic performance. In conclusion, it explores future trends in HER catalysts by integrating theoretical, experimental and industrial perspectives, while acknowledging the challenges that remain.</description>
      <author>Yongli Luo, Yulong Zhang, Jiayi Zhu, Tian Xia, Gang Liu, Zhiming Feng, Liwen Pan, Xinhua Liu, Ning Han, Ruiqin Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kirkendall effect induced the formation of hollow Co2P in Co-N-C for ORR, OER, HER and flexible Zn&#8211;Air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152301</link>
      <description>Xue Li, Yan Wei, Jie Song, Hao Song, Wenmiao Chen, Yuexing Zhang, Yanli Chen, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396951253

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Li, Yan Wei, Jie Song, Hao Song, Wenmiao Chen, Yuexing Zhang, Yanli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#946;-Mo2C nanoparticles/carbon nanotubes Mott-Schottky nanoarray on carbon cloth as freestanding cathodes for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174868</link>
      <description>Shengwei Zeng, Xiangqun Zeng, Lan Jiang, Ding Zhao, Jiao&#8208;Jing Shao, Jie Zhao, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396951983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengwei Zeng, Xiangqun Zeng, Lan Jiang, Ding Zhao, Jiao&#8208;Jing Shao, Jie Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Limits Conquest of Stability Descriptors? &#8211; Intriguing Aspects of Dissolution of Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300832</link>
      <description>Aleksandar R. &#381;eradjanin, Ahyoun Lim, Ioannis Spanos, Justus Masa, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396956238

                Abstract Design of active and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) requires in&#8208;depth understanding of the electrocatalyst properties and interfacial structural dynamics during OER. One of the essential insights for advanced electrocatalyst design is vivid understanding of the drivers and mechanisms of dissolution of electrocatalysts. In this work we analyze some important aspects of electrocatalyst dissolution during OER, to deepen and advance our understanding of activity&#8208;stability relations and relevant stability descriptors.</description>
      <author>Aleksandar R. &#381;eradjanin, Ahyoun Lim, Ioannis Spanos, Justus Masa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the origin of single&#8208;atom W activity in H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrocatalytic production: Charge symmetry&#8208;breaking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.581</link>
      <description>Changfei Jing, Tianran Wei, Peipei Jia, Mengmeng Jin, Lihui Zhou, Xijun Liu, Jun Luo, Sheng Dai, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396972617

                Abstract The low&#8208;energy electrochemical production of hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) has garnered significant attention as a viable alternative to traditional industrial routes, with the goal of achieving carbon neutrality. For their H 2 O 2 selectivity in the two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), the coordination environment of tungsten (W)&#8208;based materials is critical. In this study, atomically dispersed W single atoms were immobilized on N&#8208;doped carbon substrates by a facile pyrolysis method to obtain a W single&#8208;atom catalyst (W&#8208;SAC). The coordination environment of an isolated W single atom with a tetra&#8208;coordinated porphyrin&#8208;like structure in W&#8208;SAC was determined by X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy analysis. Notably, the as&#8208;prepared W&#8208;SAC showed superior two&#8208;electron ORR activity in 0.1 M KOH solution, including high onset potential (0.89 V), high H 2 O 2 selectivity (82.5%), and excellent stability. By using differential phase contrast&#8208;scanning transmission electron microscopy and density functional theory calculations, it is revealed that the charge symmetry&#8208;breaking of W atoms changes the adsorption behavior of the intermediates, leading to enhanced reactivity and selectivity for two&#8208;electron ORR. This work broadens the avenue for understanding the charge transfer of W&#8208;based electrocatalytic materials and the in&#8208;depth reaction mechanism of SACs in two&#8208;electron ORR.</description>
      <author>Changfei Jing, Tianran Wei, Peipei Jia, Mengmeng Jin, Lihui Zhou, Xijun Liu, Jun Luo, Sheng Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.581</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Limited Experimental Data with Machine Learning: Differentiating a Methyl from an Ethyl Group in the Corey&#8211;Bakshi&#8211;Shibata Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01286</link>
      <description>Osvaldo Jos&#233; Ribeiro Pereira, Marcel Ruth, Dennis Gerbig, Raffael C. Wende, Peter R. Schreiner, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396976914

                We present a case study on how to improve an existing metal-free catalyst for a particularly difficult reaction, namely, the Corey&#8211;Bakshi&#8211;Shibata (CBS) reduction of butanone, which constitutes the classic and prototypical challenge of being able to differentiate a methyl from an ethyl group. As there are no known strategies on how to address this challenge, we leveraged the power of machine learning by constructing a realistic (for a typical laboratory) small, albeit high-quality, data set of about 100 reactions (run in triplicate) that we used to train a model in combination with a key-intermediate graph (of substrate and catalyst) to predict the differences in Gibbs activation energies &#916;&#916;G&#8225; of the enantiomeric reaction paths. With the help of this model, we were able to select and subsequently screen a small selection of catalysts and increase the selectivity for the CBS reduction of butanone to 80% enantiomeric excess (ee), the highest possible value achieved to date for this substrate with a metal-free catalyst, thereby also exceeding the best available enzymatic systems (64% ee) and the selectivity with Corey's original catalyst (60% ee). This translates into a &gt;50% improvement in relative &#916;G&#8225; from 0.9 to 1.4 kcal mol&#8211;1. We underscore the transformative potential of machine learning in accelerating catalyst design because we rely on a manageable small data set and a key-intermediate graph representing a combination of catalyst and substrate graphs in lieu of a transition-state model. Our results highlight the synergy of synthetic chemistry and data-centric approaches and provide a blueprint for future catalyst optimization.</description>
      <author>Osvaldo Jos&#233; Ribeiro Pereira, Marcel Ruth, Dennis Gerbig, Raffael C. Wende, Peter R. Schreiner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical challenges and enhancement strategies for transitioning PEMFCs from H2-air to H2-O2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118525</link>
      <description>Ming Cheng, Mengjie Liu, Yang Feng, Yangge Guo, Huahui Xu, Junliang Zhang, Jiewei Yin, Xiaohui Yan, Shuiyun Shen, Junliang Zhang, Energy conversion and management. 311(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396986069

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ming Cheng, Mengjie Liu, Yang Feng, Yangge Guo, Huahui Xu, Junliang Zhang, Jiewei Yin, Xiaohui Yan, Shuiyun Shen, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into effect of dopant site and dopant concentration on structural, electronic and optical properties of GaNbO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1237" altimg="si56.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; and its implications on visible light photocatalytic behavior: An ab-initio study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cocom.2024.e00916</link>
      <description>Bhakti Kshirsagar, Ankosh D. Deshmukh, David Mascarenhas, Vaishali Shah, Computational condensed matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bhakti Kshirsagar, Ankosh D. Deshmukh, David Mascarenhas, Vaishali Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cocom.2024.e00916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and Catalytic Performance of Mo2C/MoS2 Composite Heterojunction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102355</link>
      <description>Congyi Zhang, Zhigang Pan, Yaqiu Tao, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396920466

                Hydrogen, as a clean, safe, and efficient energy carrier, is one of the hot energy sources that have attracted much attention. Mo2C, due to the introduction of C atoms, makes the atomic spacing of the Mo lattice decrease and changes the width of the d-band, which makes the electronic properties of Mo2C similar to that of Pt noble metals, exhibiting excellent electrochemical hydrogen precipitation performance. MoS2, due to its special crystal structure and tunable electronic structure, has been widely studied. In this paper, Mo2C nanoparticles were prepared by high-temperature carbonization, and then two-dimensional layered MoS2 were be loaded on Mo2C nanoparticles by the hydrothermal method to synthesize Mo2C/MoS2 composite catalysts. Their electrochemical hydrogen precipitation (HER) performance under acidic conditions was tested. The above catalysts were also characterized by modern material testing methods such as XRD, SEM, TEM, and XPS. The results showed that the composite catalysts exhibited the most excellent electrochemical hydrogen precipitation performance at Mo2C/MoS2-3, with the lowest overpotential at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, Tafel slope, and electrochemical impedance. At the same time, the electrochemically active area was dramatically enhanced, with good stability under prolonged testing. The catalytic activity was significantly improved compared with that of Mo2C and MoS2. The characterization and experimental results indicate that the heterogeneous structure of Mo2C and MoS2 formed a built-in electric field between the two, which accelerated the electron transfer efficiency and provided more active sites. The Mo2C/MoS2 composite catalyst is a low-cost, easy-to-prepare, and high-efficiency electrochemical hydrogen precipitation catalyst, providing a new idea for developing green and clean energy.</description>
      <author>Congyi Zhang, Zhigang Pan, Yaqiu Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering of polydisperse porous media for enhanced fluid flows through systematic topology tuning via differentiable direct numerical simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevfluids.9.054103</link>
      <description>Mohammed Alhashim, Michael P. Brenner, Physical review fluids. 9(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396813474

                Recent advancements in automatic differentiation, which played a pivotal role in deep learning, offer a promising approach to addressing challenges in controlling fluid flow behavior. We demonstrate the power of the method by optimizing the packing of a polydisperse system of periodically arranged circular rods to minimize the pressure drop across the media. We show how the optimum topology of the porous media changes with changing the packing fraction.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Alhashim, Michael P. Brenner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevfluids.9.054103</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
