<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 01:05:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of amorphous subnanometric palladium nanostructures on metallic transition metal dichalcogenides for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00622d</link>
      <description>Liang Mei, Yuefeng Zhang, Zimeng Ye, Ting Han, Honglu Hu, Ruijie Yang, Ting Ying, W. Zheng, Ruixin Yan, Yue Zhang, Zhenbin Wang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581113

                Metallic transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets decorated with amorphous subnanometric Pd nanoparticles exhibit comparable HER performance to that of commercial Pt&#8211;C.</description>
      <author>Liang Mei, Yuefeng Zhang, Zimeng Ye, Ting Han, Honglu Hu, Ruijie Yang, Ting Ying, W. Zheng, Ruixin Yan, Yue Zhang, Zhenbin Wang, Zhiyuan Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00622d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Accelerated High-Throughput Computational Screening: Unveiling Bimetallic Nanoparticles with Peroxidase-Like Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01473</link>
      <description>Kaiwei Wan, Hui Wang, Xinghua Shi, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581121

                Bimetallic nanoparticles (NPs) with peroxidase-like (POD-like) activity play a crucial role in biosensing, disease treatment, environmental management, and other fields. However, their development is impeded by a vast range of tunable properties in components and structures, making the establishment of structure&#8211;effect relationships and the discovery of active materials challenging. Addressing this, we established robust scaling relationships by meticulously analyzing the catalytic reaction networks of pure metal NPs, which laid the volcano-shaped correlation between the activity and O* adsorption energy. Utilizing these relationships, we introduced an innovative and versatile descriptor of the NPs, which was then integrated into a machine learning-accelerated high-throughput computational workflow, significantly boosting the predictive accuracy for the POD-like activity of bimetallic NPs. Our methodological approach enabled the successful prediction of activities for 1260 bimetallic NPs, leading to the identification of several highly effective catalysts. Furthermore, we distilled several strategies for designing efficient bimetallic NPs based on our screening results.</description>
      <author>Kaiwei Wan, Hui Wang, Xinghua Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biphenylene nanoribbon as a promising electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.054007</link>
      <description>Radha N Somaiya, Aftab Alam, Zicong Marvin Wong, Teck Leong Tan, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Physical review applied. 21(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396609366

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Radha N Somaiya, Aftab Alam, Zicong Marvin Wong, Teck Leong Tan, Brahmananda Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.21.054007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study on Mo-stabilized passive films: Hydroxylation effects on chromium and iron oxide surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112105</link>
      <description>Xintang Huang, Dominique Costa, Boubakar Diawara, Vincent Maurice, Philippe Marcus, Corrosion science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396609725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xintang Huang, Dominique Costa, Boubakar Diawara, Vincent Maurice, Philippe Marcus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Si12C12 nanocluster with late first-row transition metals: A promising approach during single-atom catalysis toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.368</link>
      <description>Naveen Kosar, Saira Rafiq, Khurshid Ayub, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396615899

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naveen Kosar, Saira Rafiq, Khurshid Ayub, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applied electric field induced the change of spin-electron of the Fe3GeTe2 to improve its oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118310</link>
      <description>Liwei Guo, Rui Wang, Qiuhong Li, Jingguo Hu, Jing Pan, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396621839

                Utilizing density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we investigate the influence of the external electric field on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of monolayer Fe3GeTe2. Monolayer Fe3GeTe2 has ferromagnetic metal properties and displays excellent electrocatalytic activity. The magnetism mainly comes from FeI atoms, owing to the strong Fe-Te orbitals hybridization, and FeI atoms have great effect on the active site Te atoms. The electric field induces the change of spin-electron and promotes charge redistribution in the Fe3GeTe2, resulting in the changes of the magnetic moment and magnetic anisotropic energy (MAE). Simultaneously, the applied electric field shifts the energy band and decreases the work function which facilitates carrier migration to the surface. Therefore, the OER overpotential is reduced and the catalytic performance is improved. These valuable findings can serve as vital references for the design of 2D magnetic electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Liwei Guo, Rui Wang, Qiuhong Li, Jingguo Hu, Jing Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intercalated and Surface-Adsorbed Phosphate Anions in NiFe Layered Double-Hydroxide Catalysts Synergistically Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01200</link>
      <description>Shiqing Ding, Zheng Bo, Xiao&#8208;Feng Wang, Yue Zhou, Zhongben Pan, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Guangxiang Liu, Leiming Lang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396633214

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER), a crucial semireaction in water electrolysis and rechargeable metal-air batteries, is vital for carbon neutrality. Hindered by a slow proton-coupled electron transfer, an efficient catalyst activating the formation of an O-H bond is essential. Here, we proposed a straightforward one-step hydrothermal procedure for fabricating PO</description>
      <author>Shiqing Ding, Zheng Bo, Xiao&#8208;Feng Wang, Yue Zhou, Zhongben Pan, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Guangxiang Liu, Leiming Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial synthesis of polyesters at ambient condition via consecutive CO2 electrolysis and fermentation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6658-6</link>
      <description>Guiru Zhang, Jianguo Ning, Seung Chul Lyu, Baoxin Ni, Ping Shen, Ke Yao, Yuting Wang, Xuheng Jiang, Hai Zhang, Xi Ling, Yongcheng Wang, Kun Jiang, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396585498

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guiru Zhang, Jianguo Ning, Seung Chul Lyu, Baoxin Ni, Ping Shen, Ke Yao, Yuting Wang, Xuheng Jiang, Hai Zhang, Xi Ling, Yongcheng Wang, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6658-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ exploration of oxygen electrocatalysis using core-shell nanostructure-enhanced Raman spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.03.006</link>
      <description>Zhengxin Qian, Ji&#8208;Shuang Zeng, Shuang Zhao, Qing&#8208;Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Qingchi Xu, Hua Zhang, Jian-Feng Li, Nano materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396589595

                Advancements in fuel cells and water electrolyzers have significantly bolstered the utilization of hydrogen energy. Notably, the oxidation and reduction processes of oxygen at the electrode&#8212;termed oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR)&#8212;manifest sluggish reaction kinetics, thus requiring noble metals as catalysts, which considerably impedes system efficiency and cost. The imperative for enhancing reaction rates and diminishing overpotential necessitates the development of effective catalysts, which strongly depends on the mechanistic understanding of these reactions at the molecular level. Therefore, this review summarizes our recent efforts in utilizing in situ enhanced Raman spectroscopy, especially the borrowing surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) strategy, shell-isolated nanoparticle-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SHINERS), and the SHINERS-satellite strategy, to capture oxygen intermediate species as a bridge to investigate the molecular mechanisms of OER and ORR. Combining in situ SERS with other characterization techniques and theoretical simulation, the structural evolution of active sites and intermediates, including &#8727;OOH, &#8727;OH, &#8727;OO, etc., during OER/ORR has been monitored under reaction conditions, and the reaction mechanisms together with structure-activity correlations have been identified at the molecular level. These findings may provide a pivotal scientific foundation towards the discovery of better materials for electrochemical hydrogen energy.</description>
      <author>Zhengxin Qian, Ji&#8208;Shuang Zeng, Shuang Zhao, Qing&#8208;Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Qingchi Xu, Hua Zhang, Jian-Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.03.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Computational Screening of Novel Two-Dimensional Covalent Organic Frameworks for Efficient Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00818</link>
      <description>Li Sheng, Weiyi Wang, Jiajun Wang, Wenhua Zhang, Qunxiang Li, Jinlong Yang, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396596848

                The pursuit of efficient photocatalysts toward photocatalytic water splitting has attracted wide attention. However, the low efficiency of photocatalytic reactions due to the rapid electron-hole recombination and the time-consuming searching process hinder the development of high-performance photocatalysts. Here, we proposed a data-driven screening procedure for covalent organic frameworks (COFs) as overall solar water-splitting photocatalysts. Based on a COF database through assembling different</description>
      <author>Li Sheng, Weiyi Wang, Jiajun Wang, Wenhua Zhang, Qunxiang Li, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Corrosion Induced by Surface Defects Accelerates Degradation of Platinum/Graphene Catalysts in Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310940</link>
      <description>X.L. Li, Fangyuan Su, Lingling Xie, Yan&#8208;Ru Tian, Zonglin Yi, Jie&#8208;Fei Cheng, Cheng&#8208;Meng Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396614089

                Abstract Graphene supported electrocatalysts have demonstrated remarkable catalytic performance for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). However, their durability and cycling performance are greatly limited by Oswald ripening of platinum (Pt) and graphene support corrosion. Moreover, comprehensive studies on the mechanisms of catalysts degradation under 0.6&#8211;1.6 V versus RHE (Reversible Hydrogen Electrode) is still lacking. Herein, degradation mechanisms triggered by different defects on graphene supports are investigated by two cycling protocols. In the start&#8211;up/shutdown cycling (1.0&#8211;1.6 V vs. RHE), carbon oxidation reaction (COR) leads to shedding or swarm&#8211;like aggregation of Pt nanoparticles (NPs). Theoretical simulation results show that the expansion of vacancy defects promotes reaction kinetics of the decisive step in COR, reducing its reaction overpotential. While under the load cycling (0.6&#8211;1.0 V vs. RHE), oxygen containing defects lead to an elevated content of Pt in its oxidation state which intensifies Oswald ripening of Pt. The presence of vacancy defects can enhance the transfer of electrons from graphene to the Pt surface, reducing the d&#8722;band center of Pt and making it more difficult for the oxidation state of platinum to form in the cycling. This work will provide comprehensive understanding on Pt/Graphene catalysts degradation mechanisms.</description>
      <author>X.L. Li, Fangyuan Su, Lingling Xie, Yan&#8208;Ru Tian, Zonglin Yi, Jie&#8208;Fei Cheng, Cheng&#8208;Meng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on carbon dioxide capture materials used for carbon dioxide capture, utilization, and storage technology: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-33370-2</link>
      <description>Hongtao Dang, Bin Guan, Junyan Chen, Zeren Ma, Yujun Chen, Jinhe Zhang, Zelong Guo, Lei Chen, Jingqiu Hu, Yi Chao, Shunyu Yao, Zhen Huang, Environmental science and pollution research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396620328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongtao Dang, Bin Guan, Junyan Chen, Zeren Ma, Yujun Chen, Jinhe Zhang, Zelong Guo, Lei Chen, Jingqiu Hu, Yi Chao, Shunyu Yao, Zhen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-33370-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Hydrothermally Synthesized NiFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1166/sam.2024.4691</link>
      <description>S. M. Bodhale, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, Abhijit Gurav, A.D. Teli, N.N. Kengar, A. R. Vedante, Pravin Jadhav, M.M. Abdullah, Hasan B. Albargi, Jari S. Algethami, Preeti Singh, C.M. Kanamadi, Science of advanced materials. 16(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396631293

                In this study, nickel ferrite (NiFe 2 O 4 ) nanoparticles were synthesized using the hydrothermal method at various pH values. The objective was to investigate the influence of pH variation on particle size and electrocatalytic activity. The formation of cubic phase nanoparticles was confirmed through X-ray diffraction (XRD) analysis. To characterize the electrochemical properties, the nickel ferrite nanoparticles were coated onto a stainless steel substrate using the doctor blade technique. The microstructural analysis was conducted using scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The samples were further analyzed using linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The average crystallite size, determined from the XRD pattern, was approximately 40 nm. SEM images revealed a conversion from nanoplates to a granular morphology. The synthesized electrode exhibited an overpotential of 392 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 and demonstrated good stability for 5 hours. These findings highlight the excellent electrocatalytic activity of nickel ferrite nanoparticles for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>S. M. Bodhale, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, Abhijit Gurav, A.D. Teli, N.N. Kengar, A. R. Vedante, Pravin Jadhav, M.M. Abdullah, Hasan B. Albargi, Jari S. Algethami, Preeti Singh, C.M. Kanamadi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1166/sam.2024.4691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting oxygen reduction electrocatalytic performance of Cu-Nx by modulating electron structure via construction of Cu-Nx and Cu nanocluster coupling catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.362</link>
      <description>Kaixin Liang, Yongfeng Liang, Hui Zhang, Feiying Tang, Shun&#8208;Li Shang, Zhe Liu, Yongfeng Liang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396637528

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaixin Liang, Yongfeng Liang, Hui Zhang, Feiying Tang, Shun&#8208;Li Shang, Zhe Liu, Yongfeng Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering benzyl alcohol electrooxidation coupled with hydrogen evolution via hetero&#8208;interface construction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18469</link>
      <description>Xiaohui Du, Wenfu Xie, Yanfei Wang, Hao Li, Jinze Li, Yang Li, Yiheng Song, Zhenhua Li, Jin Yong Lee, Mingfei Shao, AIChE journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396639735

                Abstract It is still a challenge to develop electrocatalyst for the efficient adsorption and conversion of organic molecule in aqueous media. Herein, a hetero&#8208;interface structure based on CuO@Ni(OH) 2 is rationally designed to enhance the performance of benzyl alcohol oxidation to benzoic acid. A high Faradaic efficiency of 99% and the yield of 3.09 mmol cm &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 are achieved at 1.70 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode, outperforming the previously reported electrocatalysts. Furthermore, a membrane&#8208;free flow electrolyzer was assembled based on CuO@Ni(OH) 2 hetero&#8208;interface, exhibiting a much high yielding of benzoic acid (6.73 mmol cm &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 ) and hydrogen (0.35 L cm &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 ) with excellent stability. Both experimental data and density functional theory calculations verify that the electron is tend to accumulate at the hetero&#8208;interface, thus accelerating the adsorption of reactant and intermediate and reducing the energy barrier of the conversion of benzyl alcohol to benzoic acid.</description>
      <author>Xiaohui Du, Wenfu Xie, Yanfei Wang, Hao Li, Jinze Li, Yang Li, Yiheng Song, Zhenhua Li, Jin Yong Lee, Mingfei Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructured Catalytic Materials as Advanced Electrocatalysts: Classification, Synthesis, Characterization, and Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404535</link>
      <description>Weiqi Xu, Qing Yan, Hao Wang, Dongping Wu, Haijun Zhou, Hui Li, Song Yang, Tianyi Ma, Heng Zhang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396659441

                Abstract The proactive exploration of electrocatalytic conversion for renewable energy valorization is of tremendous significance in addressing the issues of fossil energy exhaustion, among which the critical challenge of electrocatalysis lies in the rational design of efficient electrocatalysts that are rich in the earth. Among electrocatalysts, the design of heterostructured materials exhibits immense potential for the optimization of noble metals and elaboration of non&#8208;precious metal electrocatalysts with durability. In this review, a systematic overview of modern advances in heterostructured electrocatalysts for a range of energy conversion reactions is described, and special interfacial design brings additional functional effects. Subsequently, various synthesis methods and characterization techniques for heterostructured electrocatalysts are also summarized. The innovative classification of heterostructures in methods of interfacial junction, crystal structure, structural morphology, and properties of the components is presented in this review. Finally, the possible challenges and outlooks of heterostructured electrocatalysts in the future are further discussed, including how to develop more sophisticated synthesis, characterization, and theoretical calculation methods, which will serve as the guiding direction for a more rational interface design. This review aims to set the trajectory for providing meaningful inspiration and references in energy conversion by heterostructured electrocatalysts, advancing the process of carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Weiqi Xu, Qing Yan, Hao Wang, Dongping Wu, Haijun Zhou, Hui Li, Song Yang, Tianyi Ma, Heng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Assessment of Current Hydrogen Supply Chains in the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131576</link>
      <description>Valentina Olabi, Hussam Jouhara, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396665250

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Valentina Olabi, Hussam Jouhara</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Two-Dimensional Phthalocyanine Dual Site Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02229</link>
      <description>Lingze Wei, Delowar Hossain, Chunfang Gan, Gaurav A. Kamat, Melissa E. Kreider, Junjie Chen, Keping Yan, Zhenan Bao, Michal Bajdich, Michaela Burke Stevens, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396668652

                Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) offer an interesting opportunity for catalysis, particularly for metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) motifs by providing an organized porous structural pattern and well-defined active sites for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), a key need for hydrogen fuel cells and related sustainable energy technologies. In this work, we leverage electrochemical testing with computational models to study the electronic and structural properties in the MOF systems and their relationship to ORR activity and stability based on dual transitional metal centers. The MOFs consist of two M1 metals with amine nodes coordinated to a single M2 metal with a phthalocyanine linker, where M1/M2 = Co, Ni, or Cu. Co-based metal centers, in particular Ni&#8211;Co, demonstrate the highest overall activity of all nine tested MOFs. Computationally, we identify the dominance of Co sites, relative higher importance of the M2 site, and the role of layer M1 interactions on the ORR activity. Selectivity measurements indicate that M1 sites of MOFs, particularly Co, exhibit the lowest (&lt;4%), and Ni demonstrates the highest (&gt;46%) two-electron selectivity, in good agreement with computational studies. Direct in situ stability characterization, measuring dissolved metal ions, and calculations, using an alkaline stability metric, confirm that Co is the most stable metal in the MOF, while Cu exhibits notable instability at the M1. Overall, this study reveals how atomistic coupling of electronic and structural properties affects the ORR performance of dual site MOF catalysts and opens new avenues for the tunable design and future development of these systems for practical electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Lingze Wei, Delowar Hossain, Chunfang Gan, Gaurav A. Kamat, Melissa E. Kreider, Junjie Chen, Keping Yan, Zhenan Bao, Michal Bajdich, Michaela Burke Stevens, Thomas F. Jaramillo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption model for atoms and molecules on doped semiconducting oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.195416</link>
      <description>Abhinav S. Raman, Colin Lehman-Chong, Aleksandra Vojvodi&#263;, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 109(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396670358

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abhinav S. Raman, Colin Lehman-Chong, Aleksandra Vojvodi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.195416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic role of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;&#8722;&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; hybridization and magnetism in enhanced water splitting on ferromagnetic &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;T&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; transition metal dichalcogenides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.195414</link>
      <description>Y.-C. T. Huang, Shunfang Li, Zhen Yu Zhang, Ping Cui, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 109(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396670694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y.-C. T. Huang, Shunfang Li, Zhen Yu Zhang, Ping Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.195414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving NiFe Electrocatalysts through Fluorination&#8208;Driven Rearrangements for Neutral Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310642</link>
      <description>Jiang Yu, Jiamin Li, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Yang Yang, Lei Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396671335

                Abstract Neutral electrolysis to produce hydrogen is prime challenging owing to the sluggish kinetics of water dissociation for the electrochemical reduction of water to molecular hydrogen. An ion&#8208;enriched electrode/electrolyte interface for electrocatalytic reactions can efficiently obtain a stable electrolysis system. Herein, we found that interfacial accumulated fluoride ions and the anchored Pt single atoms/nanoparticles in catalysts can improve hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity of NiFe&#8208;based hydroxide catalysts, prolonging the operating stability at high current density in neutral conditions. NiFe hydroxide electrode obtains an outstanding performance of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 at low overpotential of 218 mV with 1000 h operation at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Electrochemical experiments and theoretical calculations have demonstrated that the interfacial fluoride contributes to promote the adsorption of Pt to proton for sustaining a large current density at low potential, while the Pt single atoms/nanoparticles provide H adsorption sites. The synergy effect of F and Pt species promotes the formation of Pt&#9472;H and F&#9472;H bonds, which accelerate the adsorption and dissociation process of H 2 O and promote the HER reaction with a long&#8208;term durability in neutral conditions.</description>
      <author>Jiang Yu, Jiamin Li, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Yang Yang, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Binary Covalent Alloy Space to Pursue Superior Nitrogen Reduction Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304559</link>
      <description>Cooper R. Tezak, Sophie Gerits, Brent D. Rich, Christopher Sutton, Nicholas R. Singstock, Charles B. Musgrave, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396672290

                Abstract The electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) has the potential to decarbonize industrial ammonia production. However, NRR has poor activity and selectivity versus the competing hydrogen evolution reaction for catalysts that adhere to scaling relations. Overcoming the limitations imposed by scaling relations requires more complex catalyst materials, however, evaluating materials beyond simple metal systems is a large combinatorial problem that requires an improved understanding of the electrocatalyst surface to rationally guide the discovery of superior catalysts. The study uses grand canonical density functional theory to uncover NRR trends on a large and disparate set of binary covalent alloys (BCA) with variable compositions and active&#8208;site geometries. The studied BCAs generally follow scaling relations, albeit with larger variance and several systems that significantly break scaling. BCAs with early&#8208; to mid&#8208;transition metals tend to lie near the volcano peak and activate the N 2 triple bond via a side&#8208;on binding configuration. Trends in the BCA space cannot be readily predicted using simple electronic descriptors, which is ascribed to the large geometric variability of the BCA surfaces. It is anticipated that these findings will provide a foundation for the rational design of superior NRR electrocatalysts with increasing material complexity.</description>
      <author>Cooper R. Tezak, Sophie Gerits, Brent D. Rich, Christopher Sutton, Nicholas R. Singstock, Charles B. Musgrave</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in electrocatalysts for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02649-1</link>
      <description>Hongbin He, D. John, Kunsong Hu, Hanqing Yu, Zhen-Guo Zhang, Feng Zhao, Xinhua Liu, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396672638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongbin He, D. John, Kunsong Hu, Hanqing Yu, Zhen-Guo Zhang, Feng Zhao, Xinhua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02649-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learned Material Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-44622-1_13</link>
      <description>N. M. Anoop Krishnan, Hariprasad Kodamana, Ravinder Bhattoo, Springer eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396680946

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. M. Anoop Krishnan, Hariprasad Kodamana, Ravinder Bhattoo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-44622-1_13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrocatalytic hydrogen generation from water splitting with heterostructured MoS2/NiFe2O4 composite in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.042</link>
      <description>Noureen Amir Khan, Gul Rahman, Sang Youn Chae, Anwar ul Haq Ali Shah, Oh&#8208;Shim Joo, Shabeer Ahmad Mian, Akhtar Hussain, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396685920

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Noureen Amir Khan, Gul Rahman, Sang Youn Chae, Anwar ul Haq Ali Shah, Oh&#8208;Shim Joo, Shabeer Ahmad Mian, Akhtar Hussain</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant Induced Hollow Ni2P Nanocrystals Regulate Dehydrogenation Kinetics for Highly Efficient Solar-Driven Hydrazine Assisted H2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124165</link>
      <description>Umesh P. Suryawanshi, Uma V. Ghorpade, Priyank V. Kumar, Jun Sung Jang, Mingrui He, Hong Jae Shim, Hyo Rim Jung, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, Jihun Kim, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396690843

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Umesh P. Suryawanshi, Uma V. Ghorpade, Priyank V. Kumar, Jun Sung Jang, Mingrui He, Hong Jae Shim, Hyo Rim Jung, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, Jihun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moir&#233; fractional Chern insulators. I. First-principles calculations and continuum models of twisted bilayer &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;MoTe&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.205121</link>
      <description>Yujin Jia, Jong W. Yu, J. D. Liu, Jonah Herzog-Arbeitman, Ziyue Qi, Hanqi Pi, Nicolas Regnault, Hongming Weng, B. Andrei Bernevig, Quansheng Wu, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 109(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396692690

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujin Jia, Jong W. Yu, J. D. Liu, Jonah Herzog-Arbeitman, Ziyue Qi, Hanqi Pi, Nicolas Regnault, Hongming Weng, B. Andrei Bernevig, Quansheng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.205121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Stable Lithium Deposition Via Li3n-Enriched Inorganic Sei Induced by a Polycationic Polymer Layer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4819228</link>
      <description>Wenzhu Cao, Weimin Chen, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Tao Du, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396694075

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenzhu Cao, Weimin Chen, Zonghe Lai, Hong Chen, Tao Du, Liang Wang, Faquan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4819228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of transition metal-doped &#946;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; borophene as a new single-atom catalyst for carbon dioxide electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00601a</link>
      <description>Hongjie Huang, Ming&#8208;Yao Chen, Rongxin Zhang, Yuxuan Ding, Hong Huang, Zhangfeng Shen, Lingchang Jiang, Ge Zhang, Hongtao Jiang, Minhong Xu, Yangang Wang, Yongyong Cao, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396694578

                Among the 19 catalysts, Sc@&#946; 12 -BM and Y@&#946; 12 -BM were screened and easily reduced to C 1 products (CH 4 and CH 3 OH) and C 2 products (CH 3 CH 2 OH).</description>
      <author>Hongjie Huang, Ming&#8208;Yao Chen, Rongxin Zhang, Yuxuan Ding, Hong Huang, Zhangfeng Shen, Lingchang Jiang, Ge Zhang, Hongtao Jiang, Minhong Xu, Yangang Wang, Yongyong Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00601a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy Effects on Reactive Processes at Metal-Solvent Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06816</link>
      <description>Oskar Cheong, Fabian P. Tipp, Michael Eikerling, Piotr M. Kowalski, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396697785

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oskar Cheong, Fabian P. Tipp, Michael Eikerling, Piotr M. Kowalski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c06816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the heat treatment on structural and functional characteristics of the PtCu/C electrocatalysts on various carbon supports</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05920-8</link>
      <description>A. K. Nevelskaya, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Angelina Pavlets, V. S. Menshchikov, Ilya Pankov, A. V. Nikolskiy, A. T. Kozakov, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Journal of solid state electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396699496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. K. Nevelskaya, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Angelina Pavlets, V. S. Menshchikov, Ilya Pankov, A. V. Nikolskiy, A. T. Kozakov, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05920-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards non-blinking perovskite quantum dots</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4214840/v1</link>
      <description>Yitong Dong, Chenjia Mi, Gavin Gee, Chance Lander, Matthew Atteberry, Novruz G. Akhmedov, Lamia Hidayatova, Jesse DiCenso, Wai Tak Yip, Yihan Shao, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396699669

                Abstract Surface defect-induced photoluminescence blinking is ubiquitous in lead halide perovskite quantum dots (QDs). Despite efforts to passivate the defects on perovskite QDs by chemically engineering ligand binding moieties, blinking accompanied by photodegradation still poses barriers to studying and implementing quantum-confined perovskite QDs in quantum emitters. We posited that the intermolecular interaction between ligands can affect the QD surface passivation. In the solid state, steric repulsions among bulky ligand tails prevent adequate QD surface ligand coverage. Alternatively, attractive &#960;-&#960; stacking between low-steric phenethylammonium (PEA) ligands promotes the formation of a nearly epitaxial surface ligand layer. Here, we demonstrate that single CsPbBr3 QDs covered by these PEA ligands are nearly non-blinking, with single photon purity reaching 98%. Moreover, these QDs exhibited no spectral shifting and photodegradations, and they remained blinking-free after 12 hours of continuous operation. Free of interferences from blinking and photodegradation, we present size-dependent exciton radiative rates and emission line widths of single CsPbBr3 QDs ranging from strongly to weakly confined regimes.</description>
      <author>Yitong Dong, Chenjia Mi, Gavin Gee, Chance Lander, Matthew Atteberry, Novruz G. Akhmedov, Lamia Hidayatova, Jesse DiCenso, Wai Tak Yip, Yihan Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4214840/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-cluster anchored on PC6 monolayer as high-performance electrocatalyst for carbon dioxide reduction reaction: First principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.022</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Chenyin Li, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396702194

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Chenyin Li, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the effect of solvent for hydrogen evolution in Pt-doped MXenes and corresponding high-entropy phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100808</link>
      <description>Zheng Shu, Zhangsheng Shi, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Teck Leong Tan, Yongqing Cai, Materials today sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396703787

                Effect of solvent at the water/solid interface plays a non-negligible role in chemical reactions. Explicit solvation has been proved for its important effect on thermodynamics and kinetics of catalytic reactions. However, systematic studies about this perspective are still absence. In this work, using the model of single platinum atom immobilized on the metal vacancies of a series of MXenes, we systematically investigate the implicit/explicit solvent effect on their catalytic performance of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). We find that the solvent effect plays a significant role in affecting the calculation results for some systems. For TiNbC-PtNb, the value of &#916;GH* decreases from -0.121 to -0.511 (-0.583) eV when considering implicit (explicit) correction, implying the decisive role of solvent effect for calculating HER in this system. Bader charge analysis and AIMD simulations reveal that TiNbC-PtNb surface is sensitive to H2O, thus causing this abnormal case. Surprisingly high-entropy phases of MXene overall are less sensitive to solvent compared to the pure phases, which could be due to their alloyed lattice with a strong ability against electronic and lattice fluctuations induced by solvent. Several systems like V2C-PtV, TiMoC-PtMo, and VNbC-PtV are predicted to be excellent electrocatalysts for alkaline HER with the appropriate Gibbs free energy of hydrogen adsorption and kinetic barrier of water. The perspective exemplified in this work highlights that more feasible operando should be considered, e.g., influence of water, to better simulate the reaction process. Our work suggests that Pt-doped MXenes are perfect systems for hosting atomic catalyst as well.</description>
      <author>Zheng Shu, Zhangsheng Shi, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Teck Leong Tan, Yongqing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100808</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascading symmetry constraint during machine learning-enabled structural search for sulfur-induced Cu(111)-(43&#215;43) surface reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0201421</link>
      <description>Florian Brix, Mads-Peter Verner Christiansen, Bj&#248;rk Hammer, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396709157

                In this work, we investigate how exploiting symmetry when creating and modifying structural models may speed up global atomistic structure optimization. We propose a search strategy in which models start from high symmetry configurations and then gradually evolve into lower symmetry models. The algorithm is named cascading symmetry search and is shown to be highly efficient for a number of known surface reconstructions. We use our method for the sulfur-induced Cu (111) (43&#215;43) surface reconstruction for which we identify a new highly stable structure that conforms with the experimental evidence.</description>
      <author>Florian Brix, Mads-Peter Verner Christiansen, Bj&#248;rk Hammer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0201421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolysis &#8211; Alkaline electrolyzer with anion-exchange membrane | Alkaline anion exchange membrane electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00241-3</link>
      <description>S. Ramakrishnan, Mohamed Mamlouk, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713567

                This chapter examines alkaline anion exchange membrane (AAEM) electrolysis, exploring both its advantages and challenges. A comprehensive overview of the fundamentals of water electrolyzers is provided. This is followed by a detailed discussion on the advantages and challenges faced by AEM electrolyzers in comparison to alkaline water electrolyzers (AWE) and proton exchange membrane electrolyzers (PEMWE). AEM chemistry and degradation mechanism was reviewed. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysis is discussed in terms of the activity descriptors, mechanism, and performance across a wide range of pH levels. Conclusion and recommendation were made on the advancement required in AEM water electrolyzers performance, durability and scale up challenges to enable rapid deployment and competitive green hydrogen production to meet global NetZero hydrogen ambitions.</description>
      <author>S. Ramakrishnan, Mohamed Mamlouk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00241-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Combined Density Functional Theory and Microkinetics Simulations Study of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction on Cu8/SnO2(110): The Crucial Role of Hydrogen Coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144409</link>
      <description>Zhaochun Liu, Roos Krosschell, Ivo A. W. Filot, Emiel J. M. Hensen, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396716198

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (eCO2R) is a promising approach for converting CO2 into valuable chemicals and fuels using renewable energy sources. We investigated the mechanism of eCO2R for a small Cu8 cluster placed on SnO2 containing O vacancies using density functional theory and predicted current density and selectivity by microkinetics simulations within the computational hydrogen electrode model. Low and high H coverages were modeled by Cu8/SnO2-x and Cu8H6/SnO2-x models, using statistical methods to identify their most stable structures. Different CO2 adsorption modes on Cu8/SnO2-x and Cu8H6/SnO2-x surface models, all containing an O vacancy, resulted in distinct reaction pathways, leading to either HCOOH or CO. The preferred formation of HCOOH occurred upon CO2 adsorption on an O vacancy on the Cu8H6/SnO2-x surface, followed by sequential hydrogenation to HCOO and HCOOH. Adsorption of CO2 on Cu8/SnO2-x opened a facile pathway to CO. Electronic structure analysis revealed that differences in charge donation of Cu to the antibonding orbitals of CO2 can explain the predicted selectivity differences. The preferred adsorption mode of CO2 is bidentate at the Cu-SnO2-x interface. Our findings emphasize the role of H coverage on Cu on the selectivity of eCO2R for Cu/SnOx catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhaochun Liu, Roos Krosschell, Ivo A. W. Filot, Emiel J. M. Hensen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Polar Bridging Molecules on the Photoelectrocatalytic Hydrogen Production from Perylene Diimide Network Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821599</link>
      <description>Weixing Nie, Mengnan Ruan, Ying Zhang, Yuxin Sun, Ke Ruan, Xiaowei Liu, Zhifeng Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396718887

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weixing Nie, Mengnan Ruan, Ying Zhang, Yuxin Sun, Ke Ruan, Xiaowei Liu, Zhifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First-Principles and Machine Learning Study on Design of Graphitic Carbon Nitride-Based Single-Atom Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01412</link>
      <description>F.-Q. Chen, Yongan Yang, Xing Chen, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720626

                Photocatalytic nitrogen fixation offers an efficient, environmentally friendly, and energy-saving approach for ammonia synthesis. In this study, semiconductor materials, particularly graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) combined with single metal atoms, were theoretically investigated to identify promising candidates as nitrogen fixation photocatalysts. Initially, six different single 3d transition-metal atoms, i.e., V, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, and Cu, were loaded onto g-C3N4, and the optimal single-atom catalyst, Fe@g-C3N4, was selected through reaction energy calculations. This catalyst demonstrated excellent performance in terms of the electronic structure and light absorption properties. Furthermore, machine learning methods were applied to a limited sample set to predict a catalyst with a superior performance beyond the computational samples. Utilizing a backward elimination method and sure independence screening and sparsifying operator (SISSO) training, the key descriptors correlated with the target properties of the catalysts were identified. The SISSO descriptors, consisting of structural and electronic characteristic parameters, are interpretable and provide meaningful insights. Importantly, a catalyst, Ru@g-C3N4, with outstanding performance was predicted and verified by density functional theory calculations. This catalyst design strategy demonstrates promising results with limited computational data, highlighting the potential of combining theoretical simulations with machine learning methods for catalyst design.</description>
      <author>F.-Q. Chen, Yongan Yang, Xing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics for Catalysis Predictions: Are We Ready Yet?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05285</link>
      <description>Difan Zhang, Brett Smith, Haiyi Wu, Manh&#8208;Thuong Nguyen, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki Alexandra Glezakou, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396729186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Difan Zhang, Brett Smith, Haiyi Wu, Manh&#8208;Thuong Nguyen, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki Alexandra Glezakou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Fabrication and Characterization of Amine-Functional Silica Coated Magnetic Iron Oxide Nanoparticles for Aqueous Carbon Dioxide Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10082</link>
      <description>Md. Muhyminul Islam, Md. Abdur Rahman, M. A. Alam, Md. Mahbubor Rahman, O. Thompson Mefford, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Jalil Miah, Hasan Ahmad, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581384

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Md. Muhyminul Islam, Md. Abdur Rahman, M. A. Alam, Md. Mahbubor Rahman, O. Thompson Mefford, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Jalil Miah, Hasan Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating material property prediction using generically complete isometry invariants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59938-z</link>
      <description>Jonathan Balasingham, Viktor Zamaraev, Vitaliy Kurlin, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592660

                Abstract Periodic material or crystal property prediction using machine learning has grown popular in recent years as it provides a computationally efficient replacement for classical simulation methods. A crucial first step for any of these algorithms is the representation used for a periodic crystal. While similar objects like molecules and proteins have a finite number of atoms and their representation can be built based upon a finite point cloud interpretation, periodic crystals are unbounded in size, making their representation more challenging. In the present work, we adapt the Pointwise Distance Distribution (PDD), a continuous and generically complete isometry invariant for periodic point sets, as a representation for our learning algorithm. The PDD distinguished all (more than 660 thousand) periodic crystals in the Cambridge Structural Database as purely periodic sets of points without atomic types. We develop a transformer model with a modified self-attention mechanism that combines PDD with compositional information via a spatial encoding method. This model is tested on the crystals of the Materials Project and Jarvis-DFT databases and shown to produce accuracy on par with state-of-the-art methods while being several times faster in both training and prediction time.</description>
      <author>Jonathan Balasingham, Viktor Zamaraev, Vitaliy Kurlin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59938-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An overview of technologies for Capturing, Storing, and utilizing carbon Dioxide: Technology Readiness, large-scale Demonstration, and cost</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151998</link>
      <description>Divya Baskaran, P. Saravanan, Loganathan Nagarajan, Hun&#8208;Soo Byun, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396690643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Divya Baskaran, P. Saravanan, Loganathan Nagarajan, Hun&#8208;Soo Byun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151998</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
