<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 01:10:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a DFT-driven thermodynamic framework for ferrous alloy electrochemistry in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113216</link>
      <description>Pragyandipta Mishra, Lakshman Neelakantan, I. Adlakha, Computational materials science. 244(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400481617

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pragyandipta Mishra, Lakshman Neelakantan, I. Adlakha</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acetylene and Ethylene Adsorption during Floating Fe Catalyst Formation at the Onset of Carbon Nanotube Growth and the Effect of Sulfur Poisoning: a DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01830</link>
      <description>Bal&#225;zs Orb&#225;n, Tibor H&#246;ltzl, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400483060

                Here, we investigated the adsorption of acetylene and ethylene on iron clusters and nanoparticles, which is a crucial aspect in the nascent phase of carbon nanotube growth by floating catalyst chemical vapor deposition (FCCVD). The effect of sulfur on adsorption was also studied due to its indispensable role in the process and its commonly known impact on metal catalyst poisoning. We performed systematic density functional theory (DFT) computations, considering numerous adsorption configurations and iron particles of various sizes (Fe</description>
      <author>Bal&#225;zs Orb&#225;n, Tibor H&#246;ltzl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold&#8211;Thiolate Nanocluster Dynamics and Intercluster Reactions Enabled by a Machine Learned Interatomic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03094</link>
      <description>Caitlin A. McCandler, Antti Pihlajam&#228;ki, Sami Malola, Hannu H&#228;kkinen, Kristin A. Persson, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400484860

                Monolayer protected metal clusters comprise a rich class of molecular systems and are promising candidate materials for a variety of applications. While a growing number of protected nanoclusters have been synthesized and characterized in crystalline forms, their dynamical behavior in solution, including prenucleation cluster formation, is not well understood due to limitations both in characterization and first-principles modeling techniques. Recent advancements in machine-learned interatomic potentials are rapidly enabling the study of complex interactions such as dynamical behavior and reactivity on the nanoscale. Here, we develop an Au-S-C-H atomic cluster expansion (ACE) interatomic potential for efficient and accurate molecular dynamics simulations of thiolate-protected gold nanoclusters (Au</description>
      <author>Caitlin A. McCandler, Antti Pihlajam&#228;ki, Sami Malola, Hannu H&#228;kkinen, Kristin A. Persson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic doping of Iron and selenium on nickel hydroxide nitrate nanoarrays-derived as an efficient electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160657</link>
      <description>Huu Tuan Le, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Yong Jung Kwon, Min Ji Ham, Seok Ki Kim, Yong Jung Kwon, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400487044

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huu Tuan Le, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Yong Jung Kwon, Min Ji Ham, Seok Ki Kim, Yong Jung Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoscale molecular assembly is favored by the active, crowded cytoplasm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/prxlife.2.033001</link>
      <description>Tong Shu, Gaurav Mitra, Jonathan Alberts, Matheus P. Viana, Emmanuel D. Levy, Glen M. Hocky, Liam J. Holt, PRX life. 2(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400495089

                The mesoscale organization of molecules into membraneless biomolecular condensates is emerging as a key mechanism of rapid spatiotemporal control in cells. Principles of biomolecular condensation have been revealed through reconstitution. However, intracellular environments are much more complex than test-tube environments: they are viscoelastic, highly crowded at the mesoscale, and are far from thermodynamic equilibrium due to the constant action of energy-consuming processes. We developed synDrops, a synthetic phase separation system, to study how the cellular environment affects condensate formation. Three key features enable physical analysis: synDrops are inducible, bioorthogonal, and have well-defined geometry. This design allows kinetic analysis of synDrop assembly and facilitates computational simulation of the process. We compared experiments and simulations to determine that macromolecular crowding promotes condensate nucleation but inhibits droplet growth through coalescence. ATP-dependent cellular activities help overcome the frustration of growth. In particular, stirring of the cytoplasm by actomyosin dynamics is the dominant mechanism that potentiates droplet growth in the mammalian cytoplasm by reducing confinement and elasticity. Our results demonstrate that mesoscale molecular assembly is favored by the combined effects of crowding and active matter in the cytoplasm. These results move toward a better predictive understanding of condensate formation . Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Tong Shu, Gaurav Mitra, Jonathan Alberts, Matheus P. Viana, Emmanuel D. Levy, Glen M. Hocky, Liam J. Holt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/prxlife.2.033001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The defect chemistry and machine learning study 5d transition metal doped on graphitic carbon nitride for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst with low overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.034</link>
      <description>Wentao Wang, Y. C. Qu, Dongying Li, Aodi Zhang, Hongxia Yan, Zhenzhen Feng, Wenzhi Yao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 79(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400498275

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wentao Wang, Y. C. Qu, Dongying Li, Aodi Zhang, Hongxia Yan, Zhenzhen Feng, Wenzhi Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key role of paracrystalline motifs on iridium oxide surfaces for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01187-4</link>
      <description>Bingzhang Lu, Carolin B. Wahl, Roberto dos Reis, Jane Edgington, Xiao Kun Lu, Ruihan Li, Matthew E. Sweers, Brianna N. Ruggiero, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Vinayak P. Dravid, Linsey C. Seitz, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400503861

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingzhang Lu, Carolin B. Wahl, Roberto dos Reis, Jane Edgington, Xiao Kun Lu, Ruihan Li, Matthew E. Sweers, Brianna N. Ruggiero, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Vinayak P. Dravid, Linsey C. Seitz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01187-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multi&#8208;Active Site Subnano Heterostructures Catalyst Grown In situ POM and Fe&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; onto Nickel Foam Toward Efficient Electrocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408968</link>
      <description>Liping Cui, Yu&#8208;wen Wang, Kai Yu, Yajie Ma, Baibin Zhou, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400504070

                Abstract Designing efficient, durable, and cheap bifunctional electrocatalysts is a challenging goal in water splitting. Herein, trivanadium&#8208;substituted Keggin&#8208;type polyoxometalate H 6 PV 3 Mo 9 O 40 (POM) and Fe 0.2 Ni 0.8 Co 2 O 4 (FNCO) are in situ grown onto nickel foam (NF) yielding a self&#8208;supporting nanoflower&#8208;like heterojunction via convenient hydrothermal reaction. The POM&#8208;Fe 0.2 Ni 0.8 Co 2 O 4 /NF as HER and OER electrocatalyst, displays low overpotential (89 and 259 mV) and high electrode stability at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . POM&#8208;FNCO/NF as the cathode and anode requires a lower voltage (1.58 V) to provide 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for overall water splitting (OWS), which is better than that of commercial catalysts. The electronic sponge characteristics of POM provide more active sites and fast reaction kinetics for HER and OER. The synergy of POM and FNCO optimizes the electron distribution at the interface and enhances the intrinsic activity of HER/OER. Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations show that water molecules preferentially bind to Co sites on POM&#8208;FNCO. Additionally, POM has proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer properties and its modified FNCO exhibits thermodynamic advantages. The synergistic effect of these two factors enables the efficient overall water splitting of POM&#8208;FNCO. This study offers a novel pathway for the construction of self&#8208;supporting efficient catalysts by in situ growth of POM nanoclusters and spinel oxide sub&#8208;nanometer heterojunctions on NF.</description>
      <author>Liping Cui, Yu&#8208;wen Wang, Kai Yu, Yajie Ma, Baibin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fractal Characterization of Simulated Metal Nanocatalysts in 3D</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400123</link>
      <description>Jonathan Y. C. Ting, George Opletal, Amanda S. Barnard, Small science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400510966

                The surface roughness of metal nanoparticles is known to be influential toward their properties, but the quantification of surface roughness is challenging. Given the recent availability of large&#8208;scale simulated data and tools for the computation of the box&#8208;counting dimension of simulated atomistic objects, researchers are now enabled to study the connections between the surface roughness of metal nanoparticles and their properties. Herein, the relationships between the fractal box&#8208;counting dimension of metal nanoparticle surfaces and structural features relevant to experimental and computational studies are investigated, providing actionable insights for the manufacturing of rough nanoparticles. This approach differs from conventional concepts of roughness, but introduces a possible indicator for their functionalities such as catalytic performance that was not previously accessible. It is found that, while it remains difficult to consistently correlate the dimension with the catalytic activity of surface facets, matching trends with their surface energy, thermodynamic stability, and number of bond vacancy are observed. This highlights the potential of fractal box&#8208;counting dimensions to rationalize catalytic activity trends among metal nanoparticles, and opens up opportunities for the design of nanocatalysts with better performance via surface engineering.</description>
      <author>Jonathan Y. C. Ting, George Opletal, Amanda S. Barnard</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles modeling of Corrosion current for Passive Magnesium alloys and its application in Mg-RE Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109823</link>
      <description>Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, Xuming Zhang, Xi Zhang, Yuhao Huang, Yi Luo, Lan Luo, Yong Liu, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400519776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, Xuming Zhang, Xi Zhang, Yuhao Huang, Yi Luo, Lan Luo, Yong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of Photocatalytic CO2 Reduction by n&#8211;p Codoping Engineering of Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14141183</link>
      <description>Guowei Yin, Chunxiao Zhang, Yundan Liu, Yuping Sun, Xiang Qi, Nanomaterials. 14(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400521100

                Transition metal (TM) single-atom catalysts (SACs) have been widely applied in photocatalytic CO2 reduction. In this work, n&#8211;p codoping engineering is introduced to account for the modulation of photocatalytic CO2 reduction on a two-dimensional (2D) bismuth-oxyhalide-based cathode by using first-principles calculation. n&#8211;p codoping is established via the Coulomb interactions between the negatively charged TM SACs and the positively charged Cl vacancy (VCl) in the dopant&#8211;defect pairs. Based on the formation energy of charged defects, neutral dopant&#8211;defect pairs for the Fe, Co, and Ni SACs (PTM0) and the &#8722;1e charge state of the Cu SAC-based pair (PCu&#8722;1) are stable. The electrostatic attraction of the n&#8211;p codoping strengthens the stability and solubility of TM SACs by neutralizing the oppositely charged VCl defect and TM dopant. The n&#8211;p codoping stabilizes the electron accumulation around the TM SACs. Accumulated electrons modify the d-orbital alignment and shift the d-band center toward the Fermi level, enhancing the reducing capacity of TM SACs based on the d-band theory. Besides the electrostatic attraction of the n&#8211;p codoping, the PCu&#8722;1 also accumulates additional electrons surrounding Cu SACs and forms a half-occupied dx2&#8722;y2 state, which further upshifts the d-band center and improves photocatalytic CO2 reduction. The metastability of Cl multivacancies limits the concentration of the n&#8211;p pairs with Cl multivacancies (PTM@nCl (n &gt; 1)). Positively charged centers around the PTM@nCl (n &gt; 1) hinders the CO2 reduction by shielding the charge transfer to the CO2 molecule.</description>
      <author>Guowei Yin, Chunxiao Zhang, Yundan Liu, Yuping Sun, Xiang Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14141183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of porous vanadium-based alloys modified with a Ni-Cu-Mo coating for alkaline water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144676</link>
      <description>Jinjing Du, Yu Zhou, Xinhai Liu, Xinxin Cui, Xuan Zhang, Bin Wang, Xiao Feng, Jun Zhu, Heng Zuo, Qian Li, Xihong He, PingAn Hu, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400521102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinjing Du, Yu Zhou, Xinhai Liu, Xinxin Cui, Xuan Zhang, Bin Wang, Xiao Feng, Jun Zhu, Heng Zuo, Qian Li, Xihong He, PingAn Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical regulating the T-site composition of Janus MXenes achieving efficient bifunctional ORR/OER catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144712</link>
      <description>Shuang Luo, Ninggui Ma, Jun Zhao, Yaqin Zhang, Yuhang Wang, Yu Xiong, Jun Fan, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400521612

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuang Luo, Ninggui Ma, Jun Zhao, Yaqin Zhang, Yuhang Wang, Yu Xiong, Jun Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active learning streamlines development of high performance catalysts for higher alcohol synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50215-1</link>
      <description>Manu Suvarna, Tangsheng Zou, Sok Ho Chong, Yuzhen Ge, Antonio J. Mart&#237;n, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400522717

                Abstract Developing efficient catalysts for syngas-based higher alcohol synthesis (HAS) remains a formidable research challenge. The chain growth and CO insertion requirements demand multicomponent materials, whose complex reaction dynamics and extensive chemical space defy catalyst design norms. We present an alternative strategy by integrating active learning into experimental workflows, exemplified via the FeCoCuZr catalyst family. Our data-aided framework streamlines navigation of the extensive composition and reaction condition space in 86 experiments, offering &gt;90% reduction in environmental footprint and costs over traditional programs. It identifies the Fe 65 Co 19 Cu 5 Zr 11 catalyst with optimized reaction conditions to attain higher alcohol productivities of 1.1 g HA h &#8722;1 g cat &#8722;1 under stable operation for 150 h on stream, a 5-fold improvement over typically reported yields. Characterization reveals catalytic properties linked to superior activities despite moderate higher alcohol selectivities. To better reflect catalyst demands, we devise multi-objective optimization to maximize higher alcohol productivity while minimizing undesired CO 2 and CH 4 selectivities. An intrinsic trade-off between these metrics is uncovered, identifying Pareto-optimal catalysts not readily discernible by human experts. Finally, based on feature-importance analysis, we formulate data-informed guidelines to develop performance-specific FeCoCuZr systems. This approach goes beyond existing HAS catalyst design strategies, is adaptable to broader catalytic transformations, and fosters laboratory sustainability.</description>
      <author>Manu Suvarna, Tangsheng Zou, Sok Ho Chong, Yuzhen Ge, Antonio J. Mart&#237;n, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50215-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Parameterization of Density Functional Tight-Binding for 5&lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;-Elements: A Th&#8211;O Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00145</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, N&#233;stor F. Aguirre, M. J. Cawkwell, Enrique R. Batista, Ping Yang, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400531195

                Density functional tight binding (DFTB) models for</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, N&#233;stor F. Aguirre, M. J. Cawkwell, Enrique R. Batista, Ping Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Atomistic Modeling Methods for Heterogeneous Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00735</link>
      <description>Zachary Levell, Jia&#8208;Bo Le, Saerom Yu, Ruoyu Wang, Sudheesh Kumar Ethirajan, Rachita Rana, Ambarish Kulkarni, Joaquin Resasco, Deyu Lu, Jun Cheng, Yuanyue Liu, Chemical reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400533521

                Heterogeneous electrocatalysis lies at the center of various technologies that could help enable a sustainable future. However, its complexity makes it challenging to accurately and efficiently model at an atomic level. Here, we review emerging atomistic methods to simulate the electrocatalytic interface with special attention devoted to the components/effects that have been challenging to model, such as solvation, electrolyte ions, electrode potential, reaction kinetics, and pH. Additionally, we review relevant computational spectroscopy methods. Then, we showcase several examples of applying these methods to understand and design catalysts relevant to green hydrogen. We also offer experimental views on how to bridge the gap between theory and experiments. Finally, we provide some perspectives on opportunities to advance the field.</description>
      <author>Zachary Levell, Jia&#8208;Bo Le, Saerom Yu, Ruoyu Wang, Sudheesh Kumar Ethirajan, Rachita Rana, Ambarish Kulkarni, Joaquin Resasco, Deyu Lu, Jun Cheng, Yuanyue Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MiMiC: A high-performance framework for multiscale molecular dynamics simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211053</link>
      <description>Andrej Antal&#237;k, Andrea Levy, Sonata Kvedaravi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Sophia K. Johnson, David Carrasco&#8208;Busturia, Bharath Raghavan, Fran&#231;ois Mouvet, Angela Acocella, Sambit Das, Vikram Gavini, Davide Mandelli, Emiliano Ippoliti, Simone Meloni, Paolo Carloni, Ursula R&#246;thlisberger, J&#243;gvan Magnus Haugaard Olsen, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 161(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400542470

                MiMiC is a framework for performing multiscale simulations in which loosely coupled external programs describe individual subsystems at different resolutions and levels of theory. To make it highly efficient and flexible, we adopt an interoperable approach based on a multiple-program multiple-data (MPMD) paradigm, serving as an intermediary responsible for fast data exchange and interactions between the subsystems. The main goal of MiMiC is to avoid interfering with the underlying parallelization of the external programs, including the operability on hybrid architectures (e.g., CPU/GPU), and keep their setup and execution as close as possible to the original. At the moment, MiMiC offers an efficient implementation of electrostatic embedding quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) that has demonstrated unprecedented parallel scaling in simulations of large biomolecules using CPMD and GROMACS as QM and MM engines, respectively. However, as it is designed for high flexibility with general multiscale models in mind, it can be straightforwardly extended beyond QM/MM. In this article, we illustrate the software design and the features of the framework, which make it a compelling choice for multiscale simulations in the upcoming era of exascale high-performance computing.</description>
      <author>Andrej Antal&#237;k, Andrea Levy, Sonata Kvedaravi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Sophia K. Johnson, David Carrasco&#8208;Busturia, Bharath Raghavan, Fran&#231;ois Mouvet, Angela Acocella, Sambit Das, Vikram Gavini, Davide Mandelli, Emiliano Ippoliti, Simone Meloni, Paolo Carloni, Ursula R&#246;thlisberger, J&#243;gvan Magnus Haugaard Olsen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal and ligand modification modulates the electrocatalytic HER, OER, and ORR activity of 2D conductive metal-organic frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6813-0</link>
      <description>Yanan Zhou, L. Sheng, Lanlan Chen, Wenhui Zhao, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400559456

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Zhou, L. Sheng, Lanlan Chen, Wenhui Zhao, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6813-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High selectivity and abundant active sites in atomically dispersed TM2C12 monolayer for CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2024.108106</link>
      <description>Shulong Li, Song Yu, Tian Guo, Qiaoling Liu, Liang Qiao, Yong Zhao, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Fuel processing technology. 261(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400576723

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shulong Li, Song Yu, Tian Guo, Qiaoling Liu, Liang Qiao, Yong Zhao, Li&#8208;Yong Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2024.108106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atomic Catalyst of Hydrogen Evolution Supported by Semimetallic &#947;-GeSe</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02261</link>
      <description>Dan Liang, Hejin Yan, Yongqing Cai, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400576867

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Liang, Hejin Yan, Yongqing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-Triggered Distinct Oxygen Evolution Reaction Pathway in Two-Dimensional Metastable Phase IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Loading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05204</link>
      <description>Hao Yu, Yujin Ji, Chenchen Li, Wenxiang Zhu, Yue Wang, Zhiwei Hu, Jing Zhou, C. W. Pao, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Youyong Li, Xiaoqing Huang, Qi Shao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400577623

                A strain engineering strategy is crucial for designing a high-performance catalyst. However, how to control the strain in metastable phase two-dimensional (2D) materials is technically challenging due to their nanoscale sizes. Here, we report that cerium dioxide (CeO</description>
      <author>Hao Yu, Yujin Ji, Chenchen Li, Wenxiang Zhu, Yue Wang, Zhiwei Hu, Jing Zhou, C. W. Pao, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Youyong Li, Xiaoqing Huang, Qi Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Excitonic Properties of Monochalcogenides via Design of Janus Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01813</link>
      <description>Mateus B. P. Querne, A. C. Dias, Anderson Janotti, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Matheus P. Lima, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400581365

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mateus B. P. Querne, A. C. Dias, Anderson Janotti, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Matheus P. Lima</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feni Nanoparticle-Modified Reduced Graphene Oxide as a Durable Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4892968</link>
      <description>Inna Yusnila Khairani, Jin Benjin, Sidney M. Palardonio, Ulrich Hagemann, Beatriz Alonso, Amaya Ortega, Carlos Do&#241;ate&#8208;Buend&#237;a, Jordi Martorell, Carles Ros, Tanja Kallio, Bilal G&#246;kce, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400582061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Inna Yusnila Khairani, Jin Benjin, Sidney M. Palardonio, Ulrich Hagemann, Beatriz Alonso, Amaya Ortega, Carlos Do&#241;ate&#8208;Buend&#237;a, Jordi Martorell, Carles Ros, Tanja Kallio, Bilal G&#246;kce</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4892968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular modeling applied to corrosion inhibition: a critical review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41529-024-00478-2</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; M. Castillo-Robles, Ernane de Freitas Martins, Pablo Ordej&#243;n, Ivan Cole, npj materials degradation. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400583285

                Abstract In the last few years, organic corrosion inhibitors have been used as a green alternative to toxic inorganic compounds to prevent corrosion in materials. Nonetheless, the fundamental mechanisms determining their inhibition performance are still far from understood. Molecular modeling can provide important insights into those mechanisms, allowing for a detailed analysis of the corrosion inhibition (CI) process. However, CI modeling is frequently underexplored and commonly used in a standardized way following a pre-determined recipe to support experimental data. We highlight six fundamental aspects (A) that one should consider when modeling CI: (A1) the electronic properties of isolated inhibitors, (A2) the interaction of the inhibitor with the surface, (A3) the surface model, (A4) the effect of the anodic and cathodic zones on the surface, (A5) the solvent effects, and (A6) the electrodes&#8217; potential effects. While A1-A3 are more frequently investigated, A4-A6 and some more complex surface models from A3 are usually not considered and represent gaps in the CI modeling literature. In this review, we discuss the main features of molecular modeling applied to CI, considering the aforementioned key aspects and focusing on the gaps that the emerging approaches aim to fill. Filling these gaps will allow performing more detailed simulations of the CI process, which, coupled with artificial intelligence (AI) methods and multiscale approaches, might construct the bridge between the nanoscale CI modeling and the continuum scale of the CI processes.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; M. Castillo-Robles, Ernane de Freitas Martins, Pablo Ordej&#243;n, Ivan Cole</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41529-024-00478-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadening the Realm of Nanoporous Gold Catalysts: Preparation and Properties When Emanating from AuCu as Parent Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400280</link>
      <description>Jorge Adrian Tapia Burgos, Christoph Mahr, Alex Ricardo Silva Olaya, Lars Robben, Marco Schowalter, Thorsten M. Gesing, Andreas Rosenauer, G&#252;nther Wittstock, Arne Wittstock, Marcus B&#228;umer, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400584052

                Abstract Nanoporous gold (npAu) attracted increasing attention over the last 20 years as a highly active and selective oxidation catalyst in particular at low temperatures. Previous research mainly focused on npAu that was fabricated by corrosive dealloying of AuAg parent alloys. Yet, the use of other binary alloys, such as AuCu, promises interesting variations of the catalytic properties, when considering that residual amounts of the less noble metal were shown to be co&#8208;catalytically involved. Aiming at providing a platform for systematic studies in this direction for Cu, we not only dealt with strategies for a reliable and reproducible preparation of npAu(Cu) catalysts from AuCu, but also with their potential for CO oxidation in comparison to npAu(Ag). We were able to develop an approach based on thermally quenched Au 0.3 Cu 0.7 alloys, providing distinct synthetic advantages as a starting material for the catalyst fabrication versus the thermodynamically more stable AuCu 3 intermetallic compound. Using PCD (potentiostatically controlled dealloying), well&#8208;defined pore structures with ligament diameters of &#8764;40 nm and variable residual Cu concentrations in the range between &#8764;0.6 at % and &#8764;1.2 at % could be straightforwardly obtained. After activating such catalysts at 150 &#176;C, they reproducibly showed catalytic activity for aerobic CO oxidation in a broad temperature window between 40 &#176;C and 250 &#176;C. As opposed to npAu(Ag), the activity increased with decreasing residual Cu content, outperforming the former at temperatures above &#8764;60 &#176;C not only with respect to CO 2 formation rates but also with respect to thermal stability. Based on X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopic and transmission electron microscopic results, it was possible to conclude that Cu segregates to the surface and, with rising Cu bulk content, increasingly occurs in form of Cu 2+ species at the surface. While the latter are expected to be catalytically inactive, Cu and Cu + species are likely candidates for the activation of oxygen being not possible on pure Au.</description>
      <author>Jorge Adrian Tapia Burgos, Christoph Mahr, Alex Ricardo Silva Olaya, Lars Robben, Marco Schowalter, Thorsten M. Gesing, Andreas Rosenauer, G&#252;nther Wittstock, Arne Wittstock, Marcus B&#228;umer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual node graph neural network for full phonon prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00661-0</link>
      <description>Ryotaro Okabe, Abhijatmedhi Chotrattanapituk, Artittaya Boonkird, Nina Andrejevic, Xiang Fu, Tommi Jaakkola, Qichen Song, Thanh B&#236;nh Nguy&#7877;n, Nathan C. Drucker, Sai Mu, Yao Wang, Bolin Liao, Yongqiang Cheng, Mingda Li, Nature computational science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400588429

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ryotaro Okabe, Abhijatmedhi Chotrattanapituk, Artittaya Boonkird, Nina Andrejevic, Xiang Fu, Tommi Jaakkola, Qichen Song, Thanh B&#236;nh Nguy&#7877;n, Nathan C. Drucker, Sai Mu, Yao Wang, Bolin Liao, Yongqiang Cheng, Mingda Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00661-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General applications of density functional theory in photocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60006-9</link>
      <description>Shiwen Du, Fuxiang Zhang, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 61(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400603432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiwen Du, Fuxiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60006-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlating Nitrate Adsorption with the Local Environments of FeCoNiCuZn High-Entropy Alloy Catalysts Using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01071</link>
      <description>Xiang He, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400603905

                The electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia holds significant values for water remediations and energy applications, which quests for the development of highly effective catalysts with considerable stability and selectivity. Recently, high-entropy alloys (HEAs) are attracting growing attention for electrocatalytic processes. Nonetheless, studies of HEA-based nitrate reduction to ammonia are still at the early stage, and it remains unclear how the HEA compositions affect the adsorption and activation of the reaction intermediates. Herein, high-throughput density functional theory (DFT) calculations were integrated with machine learning to investigate the dependence of nitrate adsorption on the FeCoNiCuZn HEA structures. In particular, a total of 1268 different structures were sampled and constructed from the multidimensional configuration space, followed by the DFT calculations to investigate the Gibbs free energy of nitrate adsorption (i.e., &#916;</description>
      <author>Xiang He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the multiple effects of MOF-derived TiO2 on Ti-Fe2O3 photoanodes for efficient and stable photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60005-7</link>
      <description>Kaikai Ba, Yunan Liu, Kai Zhang, Ping Wang, Yanhong Lin, Sheng Wang, Ziheng Li, Tengfeng Xie, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 61(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400603959

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaikai Ba, Yunan Liu, Kai Zhang, Ping Wang, Yanhong Lin, Sheng Wang, Ziheng Li, Tengfeng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60005-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Mechanistic Landscape and Advantages of Two-Dimensional Phthalocyanine in Sustainable Urea Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4893780</link>
      <description>Xiaorong Zhu, Ming Ge, Xiaolei Yuan, Yijin Wang, Yanfeng Tang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400604092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaorong Zhu, Ming Ge, Xiaolei Yuan, Yijin Wang, Yanfeng Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4893780</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferromagnetic-Interaction-Induced Spin Symmetry Broken in Ruthenium Oxide for Enhanced Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02736</link>
      <description>Lei Tan, Xiaotong Wu, Haifeng Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Bingbao Mei, Xiangxiang Pan, Weibo Hu, Faiza Meharban, Qi Xiao, Yonghui Zhao, Chao Fu, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Wei Luo, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400604797

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Tan, Xiaotong Wu, Haifeng Wang, Jianrong Zeng, Bingbao Mei, Xiangxiang Pan, Weibo Hu, Faiza Meharban, Qi Xiao, Yonghui Zhao, Chao Fu, Chao Lin, Xiaopeng Li, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Ag12m Icosahedrons: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4893394</link>
      <description>Pilar Rodriguez Rodr&#237;&#173;guez, Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400611077

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pilar Rodriguez Rodr&#237;&#173;guez, Salom&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez-Carrera, Alvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Castro</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4893394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and robust single-layer IrO cluster electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120508</link>
      <description>Wenbo Liu, Zhicheng Hu, Tong Ren, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang, Chemical engineering science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400614572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenbo Liu, Zhicheng Hu, Tong Ren, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120508</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relaxor Unveils Geometrical Frustration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120172</link>
      <description>&#1052;. &#1042;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, L. A. Avakyan, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1079;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1057;. &#1040;. &#1048;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, A.I. Stash, &#1045;. &#1057;. &#1046;&#1091;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, B. P. Gorshunov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1096;, Acta materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400615552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1052;. &#1042;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, L. A. Avakyan, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1079;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1057;. &#1040;. &#1048;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, A.I. Stash, &#1045;. &#1057;. &#1046;&#1091;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, B. P. Gorshunov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1096;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined Cu&#8544; sites in partially electro-reduced 2D conductive Cu-MOF film for boosting CO2 electrocatalysis to C2 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153993</link>
      <description>Bing Chang, Fengtao Zhang, Zhaojun Min, Sheng Wang, Qingchun Xia, Jing Fan, Maohong Fan, Jianji Wang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400618342

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Chang, Fengtao Zhang, Zhaojun Min, Sheng Wang, Qingchun Xia, Jing Fan, Maohong Fan, Jianji Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum-level machine learning calculations of Levodopa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compbiolchem.2024.108146</link>
      <description>Hossein Shirani, Seyed Majid Hashemianzadeh, Computational biology and chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400618468

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hossein Shirani, Seyed Majid Hashemianzadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compbiolchem.2024.108146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of the catalytic mechanism of hydrogen evolution reaction enhanced by surface oxidation on FCC_CoCrFeNi and Co0.35Cr0.15Fe0.2Mo0.1Ni0.2 multi-principal element alloys based on site preference</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160730</link>
      <description>Liangji Weng, Xiaoqiong Zhang, Longju Su, Cheng Qian, Qi Cai, Tianliang Xie, Rong Chen, Hui Guo, Bo Wu, Baisheng Sa, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400618572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liangji Weng, Xiaoqiong Zhang, Longju Su, Cheng Qian, Qi Cai, Tianliang Xie, Rong Chen, Hui Guo, Bo Wu, Baisheng Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of noble metal-free electrocatalysts towards acidic water oxidation: From fundamental understanding to state-of-the-art catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100295</link>
      <description>Jing Ni, Zhaoping Shi, Yibo Wang, Jiahao Yang, Hongxiang Wu, Pengbo Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400618967

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Ni, Zhaoping Shi, Yibo Wang, Jiahao Yang, Hongxiang Wu, Pengbo Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative neural networks-accelerated prediction of transition state energy barriers for CO catalytic oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175546</link>
      <description>Tian Tang, Jingyu Xue, Xiaoqiang Shen, Jinfei Chen, Vladislav Rac, Vesna Raki&#263;, Xinbao Li, Bo Zhou, Yanrong Chen, Hao Song, Xuesen Du, Journal of alloys and compounds. 1002(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400621470

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tian Tang, Jingyu Xue, Xiaoqiang Shen, Jinfei Chen, Vladislav Rac, Vesna Raki&#263;, Xinbao Li, Bo Zhou, Yanrong Chen, Hao Song, Xuesen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D materials for enabling hydrogen as an energy vector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109997</link>
      <description>Johnson Kehinde Abifarin, Juan F. Torres, Yuerui Lu, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400623392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Johnson Kehinde Abifarin, Juan F. Torres, Yuerui Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109997</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering electronic structures and oxygen vacancies of manganese-doped nickel molybdate porous nanosheets for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.118</link>
      <description>Fang Miao, Peng Cui, Tiantian Gu, Bo Sun, Zhijie Yan, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400648309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fang Miao, Peng Cui, Tiantian Gu, Bo Sun, Zhijie Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 Electroreduction on Single Atom Catalysts: Role of the Local Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144714</link>
      <description>Gianfranco Pacchioni, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400650185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gianfranco Pacchioni, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Modified Nickel Phosphides Electrocatalyst for Stable Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Neutral Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409365</link>
      <description>P. Zhang, Han Man, Yao Huo, Fei Zhang, Yang Liu, Renbing Wu, Fei Wang, Dalin Sun, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400658006

                Abstract The development of efficient and long&#8208;term stable electrodes for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in seawater is highly desirable for hydrogen generation but remains challenging. In this work, a highly active CrO x @Ni 2 P&#8208;Ni 5 P 4 /NF electrode is developed and investigated its dynamic reconstruction for HER in neutral electrolytes. The combination of in situ Raman spectra and electrochemical measurements revealed the dynamic surface reconstruction of the catalyst during HER. The CrO x modification not only effectively facilitates water dissociation but also stabilizes the structure post&#8208;reconstruction, enabling rapid and stable hydrogen generation in neutral media. Remarkably, CrO x @Ni 2 P&#8208;Ni 5 P 4 /NF exhibits overpotentials of 109 and 263 mV at current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m PBS, respectively. Concurrently, it exhibits stable operation for 500 h in 1 m PBS and 140 h in natural seawater at current densities of 50 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The proposed catalytic electrode and the mechanistic insights present a significant stride toward the realization of metal phosphides for direct seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>P. Zhang, Han Man, Yao Huo, Fei Zhang, Yang Liu, Renbing Wu, Fei Wang, Dalin Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening of single transition-metal atoms anchored Janus MoSSe monolayers as efficient electrocatalysts for nitrogen fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132474</link>
      <description>Jia-Xing Guo, Shao-Yi Wu, Chunyu Yao, Rong-Gang Tian, Shunping Shi, Fuel. 374(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400601712

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia-Xing Guo, Shao-Yi Wu, Chunyu Yao, Rong-Gang Tian, Shunping Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Post-combustion Capture: A Critical Review of Current Technologies and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02513</link>
      <description>Federica Raganati, Paola Ammendola, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400646404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Federica Raganati, Paola Ammendola</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on Cu-Based Monatomic Alloys: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01246</link>
      <description>Xiaojiao Li, Liyun Jiang, Yong Zhou, Qi Yu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400651340

                In recent years, single-atom alloy catalysts (SAAs) have received much attention due to the combination of structural features of both single-atom and alloy catalysts, as well as their efficient catalytic activity, high selectivity, and high stability in various chemical reactions. In this work, we designed a series of Cu-based SAAs by doping isolated 3d transition metal (TM1) atoms on the surface of Cu(111) (TM1 = Fe, Co, Ru, Rh, Os and Ir), in which Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs are considered to be the most stable among 3d-series SAAs due to their optimal binding energy (Eb). The density of states of SAAs have been systematically investigated to further discuss structural properties. Based on density functional theory calculations, the activity and selectivity of Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs are investigated for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). The initial hydrogenation of CO2 on Ir1/Cu(111) SAAs can form *CO intermediates, which will be further to CH4 production by the pathway of *CO &#8594; *CHO &#8594; *CHOH &#8594; *CH2OH &#8594; *CH2 &#8594; *CH3 &#8594; CH4. This study provides theoretical insights for the rational design of selective Cu-based monatomic alloy catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaojiao Li, Liyun Jiang, Yong Zhou, Qi Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure to Property: Chemical Element Embeddings for Predicting Electronic Properties of Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01990</link>
      <description>Shokirbek Shermukhamedov, Dilorom Mamurjonova, Thana Maihom, Michael Probst, Journal of chemical information and modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400653212

                We present a new general-purpose machine learning model that is able to predict a variety of crystal properties, including Fermi level energy and band gap, as well as spectral ones such as electronic densities of states. The model is based on atomic representations that enable it to effectively capture complex information about each atom and its surrounding environment in a crystal. The accuracy achieved for band gaps exceeds results previously published. By design, our model is not restricted to the electronic properties discussed here but can be extended to fit diverse chemical descriptors. Its advantages are (a) its low computational requirements, making it an efficient tool for high-throughput screening of materials; and (b) the simplicity and flexibility of its architecture, facilitating implementation and interpretation, especially for researchers in the field of computational chemistry.</description>
      <author>Shokirbek Shermukhamedov, Dilorom Mamurjonova, Thana Maihom, Michael Probst</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating digital chemistry within the broader chemistry community</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trechm.2024.06.008</link>
      <description>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena, Trends in chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400642443

                No abstract</description>
      <author>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trechm.2024.06.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sampling rare events using nanostructures for universal Pt neural network potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cap.2024.07.005</link>
      <description>Joonhee Kang, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Min Ho Seo, Jehyun Lee, Current applied physics. 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400621569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joonhee Kang, Byung&#8208;Hyun Kim, Min Ho Seo, Jehyun Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cap.2024.07.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strained heterojunction enables high-performance, fully textured perovskite/silicon tandem solar cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.015</link>
      <description>Zhiliang Liu, Zhijun Xiong, Shaofei Yang, Ke Fan, Jiang Long, Yuliang Mao, Chaochao Qin, Sibo Li, Longbin Qiu, Jie Zhang, Francis Lin, Linfeng Fei, Yong Hua, Jia Yao, Yu Cao, Jian Zhou, Yimu Chen, Hong Zhang, Haitao Huang, Alex K.&#8208;Y. Jen, Kai Yao, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400651877

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiliang Liu, Zhijun Xiong, Shaofei Yang, Ke Fan, Jiang Long, Yuliang Mao, Chaochao Qin, Sibo Li, Longbin Qiu, Jie Zhang, Francis Lin, Linfeng Fei, Yong Hua, Jia Yao, Yu Cao, Jian Zhou, Yimu Chen, Hong Zhang, Haitao Huang, Alex K.&#8208;Y. Jen, Kai Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Special Issue on Machine Learning in Physical Chemistry Volume 2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c03822</link>
      <description>Andrew L. Ferguson, Jim Pfaendtner, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A/&#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A.. 128(27)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400558935

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrew L. Ferguson, Jim Pfaendtner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c03822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Special Issue on Machine Learning in Physical Chemistry Volume 2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03824</link>
      <description>Andrew L. Ferguson, Jim Pfaendtner, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. 128(27)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400560685

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrew L. Ferguson, Jim Pfaendtner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Special Issue on Machine Learning in Physical Chemistry Volume 2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.4c03823</link>
      <description>Andrew L. Ferguson, Jim Pfaendtner, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. B. 128(27)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400560775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrew L. Ferguson, Jim Pfaendtner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.4c03823</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
