<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 01:18:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening and an interpretable machine learning model of single-atom hydrogen evolution catalysts with an asymmetric coordination environment constructed from heteroatom-doped graphdiyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08095e</link>
      <description>Ying Zhao, Shuaishuai Gao, Penghui Ren, Lishuang Ma, Xuebo Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406314790

                Exploring high-activity and low-cost electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction is the key to developing new energy sources, but it faces major challenges.</description>
      <author>Ying Zhao, Shuaishuai Gao, Penghui Ren, Lishuang Ma, Xuebo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08095e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced delocalization and separation of charge carriers of D-&#960;-A type conjugated porous polymers by inserting fused thiophene derivative as &#960; bridge for improved photocatalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134347</link>
      <description>Xin Liu, Weiqiang Zhang, Fanpeng Meng, Jinsheng Zhao, Yuchang Du, Fei Zhao, Fuel. 387(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406316797

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Liu, Weiqiang Zhang, Fanpeng Meng, Jinsheng Zhao, Yuchang Du, Fei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in improving utilization efficiency of precious metal catalysts for hydrogen generation from hydrolysis of ammonia borane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216445</link>
      <description>Wenjing Xu, Mei Liu, Kexin Xu, Baojun Li, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 529(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406325967

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjing Xu, Mei Liu, Kexin Xu, Baojun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated and Efficient Sampling of Chemical Reaction Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409009</link>
      <description>Minhyeok Lee, Umit Volkan Ucak, Jinyoung Jeong, Islambek Ashyrmamatov, Juyong Lee, Eunji Sim, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406330162

                Machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) promise quantum-level accuracy at classical force field speeds, but their performance hinges on the quality and diversity of training data. An efficient and fully automated approach to sample chemical reaction space without relying on human intuition, addressing a critical gap in MLIP development is presented. The method combines the speed of tight-binding calculations with selective high-level refinement, generating diverse datasets that capture both equilibrium and reactive regions of potential energy surfaces. By employing single-ended growing string and nudged elastic band methods, reaction pathways previously underrepresented in MLIP training sets, particularly near transition states are systematically explored. This approach yields datasets with rich structural and chemical diversity, essential for robust MLIP development. Open-source code is provided for the entire workflow, facilitating the integration of the approach into existing MLIP development pipelines.</description>
      <author>Minhyeok Lee, Umit Volkan Ucak, Jinyoung Jeong, Islambek Ashyrmamatov, Juyong Lee, Eunji Sim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dry Reforming of Methane Over Ru&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Dynamic Behavior of Lattice Oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06174</link>
      <description>Pengfei Qu, Dong Fu, Gui&#8208;Chang Wang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406335145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Qu, Dong Fu, Gui&#8208;Chang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Amino Acid Synthesis with WO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Sub&#8208;Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418233</link>
      <description>Guanzheng Wu, Zengying Ma, Tobias Heil, Leting Zhang, Wangcheng Hu, Guoqing Wu, Wenhui He, Lei Dai, Yucheng Huang, Qing Qin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406336851

                Abstract The conversion of nitrate&#8208;rich wastewater and biomass&#8208;derived blocks into high&#8208;value products using renewably generated electricity is a promising approach to modulate the artificial carbon and nitrogen cycle. Here, a new synthetic strategy of WO x sub&#8208;nanoclusters is reported and supported on carbon materials as novel efficient electrocatalysts for nitrate reduction and its coupling with &#945;&#8208;keto acids. In acidic solutions, the NH 3 &#8208;NH 2 OH selectivity can also optimized by adjusting the potential, with the total FE exceeding 80% over a wide potential range. After introducing &#945;&#8208;keto acids, the WO x /D&#8208;CB electrode achieves remarkable activity and selectivity toward C 2 &#8208;C 6 amino acids. For glycine and alanine, impressive FEs of 49.34% and 38.22% based on transitional metal oxides can be obtained, surpassing those of WO x nanoclusters with larger size. In situ analysis and mechanistic studies reveal the critical role of WO x sub&#8208;nanoclusters in reducing the energy barriers of key steps in alanine synthesis. This work opens up new insights into the rational design of cluster catalysts to promote electrochemical amino acid synthesis.</description>
      <author>Guanzheng Wu, Zengying Ma, Tobias Heil, Leting Zhang, Wangcheng Hu, Guoqing Wu, Wenhui He, Lei Dai, Yucheng Huang, Qing Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Oxidative Desorption of Adsorbed Sulfur Species on (111) Surfaces of Single Crystals of Pure Pt and Pt-Based Bimetallic Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06652</link>
      <description>Makoto Aoki, Tamao Shishido, Tetsuro Morooka, Takuya Nakanishi, Takuya Masuda, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406351662

                The adsorption/desorption behavior of sulfur species at the (111) surfaces of pure Pt and various Pt-based bimetallic alloys, denoted as Pt3M (M = Co, Cu, Fe, Pd), was investigated by electrochemical measurements and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). After the adsorption of elemental sulfur, the current responses characteristic of the adsorption/desorption of hydrogen and hydroxyl species at the sulfur-free bare (111) surfaces completely disappeared, and a doublet peak corresponding to the elemental sulfur appeared in the S 2p region of XPS spectra. The characteristic current responses gradually recovered, simultaneously with the decrease of the S 2p peak, by repeating the potential cycling between &#8722;0.2 and 0.8 V vs Ag/AgCl, indicating the oxidative desorption of S species. Except for the Pt3Pd(111) surface, in which Pd has a similar atomic radius to Pt and fully occupied 4d orbitals, the Pt3M(111) surfaces showed higher oxidative desorption capability than those of the pure Pt(111) surface; electrochemically active surface area recovered at the Pt3M(111) surfaces by fewer potential cycles than at the Pt(111) surface. Among the various factors, the downshift of the d-band center due to the ligand effect of foreign metal and the electronic interaction between adsorbed S and Pt are the dominant factors promoting the oxidative desorption of sulfur as well as the strain effect of foreign metal with an atomic radius smaller than Pt.</description>
      <author>Makoto Aoki, Tamao Shishido, Tetsuro Morooka, Takuya Nakanishi, Takuya Masuda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06652</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Potential-Dependent Rate-Determining Step of Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16098</link>
      <description>Huimin Yan, Gang Wang, X. C. Lv, Hao Cao, Gangqiang Qin, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406357472

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted widespread attention due to their potential to replace platinum-based catalysts in achieving efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), yet the rational optimization of SACs remains challenging due to their elusive reaction mechanisms. Herein, by employing ab initio molecular dynamics simulations and a thermodynamic integration method, we have constructed the potential-dependent free energetics of ORR on a single iron atom catalyst dispersed on nitrogen-doped graphene (Fe-N4/C) and further integrated these parameters into a microkinetic model. We demonstrate that the rate-determining step (RDS) of the ORR on SACs is potential-dependent rather than invariant within the operative potential range. Specifically, under the charge-neutral condition, the RDS is calculated to be water desorption with the highest barrier, while as the potential increases, it gradually transitions to the protonation of *OH species, O2* species, and O* species, regardless of the protonation of *OH species as the potential-determining step. Moreover, we reveal the critical role of the dynamic adsorption of axially adsorbed water in facilitating the release of the single-atom site, thus enhancing the ORR rate. Our work has resolved the long-standing controversies over the RDS of ORR on SACs and implies that the step with the lowest exothermicity is not always synonymous with the RDS, highlighting the importance of examining the kinetic barriers under realistic potential conditions for understanding the electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Huimin Yan, Gang Wang, X. C. Lv, Hao Cao, Gangqiang Qin, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation of Piezoelectricity in Quadruple Perovskite Oxides by Harnessing Cation Defects and Their Application in Piezo-Photocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14974</link>
      <description>Kai Wang, Xiangyu Guo, Han Chen, Lihong Liu, Zhiliang Wang, Lars Thomsen, Peng Chen, Zongping Shao, Xudong Wang, Fang Xie, Gang Liu, Lianzhou Wang, Shaomin Liu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406359043

                Quadruple perovskite oxides have received extensive attention in electronics and catalysis, owing to their cation-ordering structure and intriguing physical properties. However, their repertoires still remain limited. In particular, piezoelectricity from quadruple perovskites has been rarely reported due to the frustrated symmetry-breaking transition in A-site-ordered perovskite structures, disabling their piezoelectric applications. Herein, we report a feasible strategy to achieve piezoelectricity in CaCu3Ti4O12 (CCTO) quadruple perovskite via cation defect engineering, specifically through a thermal-driven selective cation exsolution strategy to introduce Cu vacancies. The introduction of Cu point defects in CCTO locally destabilizes the constrained tilted TiO6 octahedra framework, relaxing the octahedral tilting and inducing structural heterogeneity which, in turn, disrupts the high symmetry of the pristine cubic phase. As a result, the defective CCTO with localized asymmetry exhibits intense polarization and a robust piezoelectricity of 7 pC N-1. The created piezoelectricity is further validated by its application as a piezo-photocatalyst, enabling efficient charge separation and transfer with a 2.5-times increment in the lifetime of photoexcitations. This enhancement leads to a 3.86- and 31-fold increase in the production of hydrogen peroxide and reactive oxygen species compared with individual piezocatalysis and photocatalysis, respectively. This study establishes a pathway to engineer piezoelectricity in quadruple perovskites, potentially unlocking a wide range of applications in modern microelectronics beyond the demonstrated piezo-photocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Kai Wang, Xiangyu Guo, Han Chen, Lihong Liu, Zhiliang Wang, Lars Thomsen, Peng Chen, Zongping Shao, Xudong Wang, Fang Xie, Gang Liu, Lianzhou Wang, Shaomin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong atomic reconstruction in twisted bilayers of highly flexible InSe: Machine-learned interatomic potential and continuum model approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.014004</link>
      <description>S. J. Magorrian, Anas Siddiqui, Nicholas D. M. Hine, Physical Review Materials. 9(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406365465

                The relaxation of atomic positions to their optimal structural arrangement is crucial for understanding the emergence of new physical behavior in long scale superstructures in twisted bilayers of two-dimensional materials. The amount of deviation from a rigid moir&#233; structure will depend on the elastic properties of the constituent monolayers which, for the twisted bilayer, the more flexible the monolayers are, the lower the energy required to deform the layers to maximize the areas with an energetically optimal interlayer arrangement of atoms. We investigate this atomic reconstruction for twisted bilayers of highly flexible InSe. Results using two methods are demonstrated: first we train a machine-learned interatomic potential (MLIP) to enable fully atomistic relaxations of small-twist-angle large-length-scale moir&#233; supercells while retaining density functional theory (DFT) level accuracy. We find substantial out-of-plane corrugation and in-plane domain formation for a wide range of twist angles and moir&#233; length scales. We then adapt an existing continuum approach and show that it can reproduce some, but not all, features of the fully atomistic calculations. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>S. J. Magorrian, Anas Siddiqui, Nicholas D. M. Hine</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.014004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An In Silico Study of Carbon Active Sites for Oxygen Electroreduction on the Nitrogen and Weak-Binding Transition Metals (Cu, Zn) Doped Carbon Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1070363224120223</link>
      <description>Anton V. Kuzmin, Bagrat A. Shainyan, Russian Journal of General Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406373458

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anton V. Kuzmin, Bagrat A. Shainyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1070363224120223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Dehydrogenation Performance of Cyclohexane on Pt-Skin AgPt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(111) and Ag&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Pt(111) Surface Slabs: A Density Functional Theory Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05825</link>
      <description>Desalegn Nigatu Gemechu, Kingsley Onyebuchi Obodo, Ahmed Mohammed, Yedilfana Setarge Mekonnen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406374101

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Desalegn Nigatu Gemechu, Kingsley Onyebuchi Obodo, Ahmed Mohammed, Yedilfana Setarge Mekonnen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron spin matters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01697-2</link>
      <description>Serhiy Cherevko, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406374662

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Serhiy Cherevko</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01697-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoalloys Composed of Platinum Group Metals and p&#8208;Block Elements for Innovative Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400270</link>
      <description>Megumi Mukoyoshi, Hiroshi Kitagawa, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406376795

                Alloy nanoparticles based on platinum group metals (PGMs) have been intensively investigated in various fields, especially in catalysis. Recently, the scope of alloying has expanded to include not only d&#8208;block transition metals but also p&#8208;block elements, which have a wide range of properties that are very different from those of d&#8208;block transition metals. By alloying PGMs with p&#8208;block elements, the electronic structure and surface properties of the catalysts can be tuned, enhancing their catalytic performance. The focus of this review is on PGM&#8211;p&#8208;block element nanoalloys, their synthesis methods, characterization techniques, and catalytic properties. In addition to typical binary crystalline alloys, such as solid&#8208;solution and intermetallic alloys, this review also highlights the potential of multielement, amorphous, or liquid alloys, which have recently garnered much attention. The review aims to provide valuable perspectives for the development of PGM&#8208;based sustainable and innovative catalysis, while also addressing the current challenges and future directions in this field.</description>
      <author>Megumi Mukoyoshi, Hiroshi Kitagawa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peaks and pitfalls of electrocatalytic descriptor models at the example of CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5559232/v1</link>
      <description>Jihun Oh, Beom-Il Kim, Sheng Han, Suneon Wang, Stefan Ringe, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406380210

                Abstract Electrocatalysis advances rely on the development of efficient catalysts. Systematic material design hinges on identifying activity and selectivity descriptors. While adsorption energy descriptors have helped predict new materials, they are typically based on pure metals, uncertain of their applicability to complex materials like alloys. Here, we systematically analyze the validity of descriptor models for the electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR). For this, we prepare gold, silver, and palladium alloys of variable composition and confirm experimentally the continuous variation of the d-band center (i.e. the CO adsorption energy) and work function (i.e. the potential of zero charge). Our results indicate that while the d-band center is the decisive factor for CO production, it, along with the work function, fails to fully explain the production of HCOO&#8722; and H2. Designing a copper-like alloy based on the matching of these descriptor values showed no formation of C2 products (as commonly expected for copper). This breakdown of the descriptor model is explained from first-principles calculations by the heterogeneity of the surface leading to different deactivation pathways for C2 product formation. Our results highlight the problems in transferring conventional descriptor models to more complex, heterogeneous materials motivating future developments.</description>
      <author>Jihun Oh, Beom-Il Kim, Sheng Han, Suneon Wang, Stefan Ringe</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5559232/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D CaWO4 nanosheets derived from scheelite minerals for enhanced electrocatalysis in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2389-9</link>
      <description>Qing Sun, Yongxiang Sun, Dong Yan, Hong Zhong, Hongbo Zeng, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406380504

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Sun, Yongxiang Sun, Dong Yan, Hong Zhong, Hongbo Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2389-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induction of Nanoscale Magnetic Ordering in Non&#8208;Ferrous Layered Double Hydroxides: Stabilizing Spintronic Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412021</link>
      <description>Sakshi Kansal, Rahul Ravindran, Alok Kumar Srivastava, Amreesh Chandra, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406381670

                Abstract Inducing magnetic ordering in a non&#8208;ferrous layered double hydroxides (LDHs) instigates higher spin polarization, which leads to enhanced efficiency during oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In nano&#8208;sized magnetic materials, the concept of elongated grains drives domain alignment under the application of an external magnetic field. Hence, near the solid electrode interface, modified magnetohydrodynamics (MHD) positively impacts the electrocatalytic ability of non&#8208;ferrous nanocatalysts. Consequently, significant improvement in the water&#8208;splitting kinetics can be obtained by using even low magnetic fields. At 100 Gauss, 20% and 10% decrement in the overpotential is reported for OER and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), respectively. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations are also presented to explain the thermodynamics of the HER/OER processes. It is established that the Gibbs energy of the process can reduce the exchange energy barrier by using dopant like cobalt. The additional cobalt metal active site have the highest probability for adsorption of reactive intermediates during HER and OER, which results in higher efficiencies.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Kansal, Rahul Ravindran, Alok Kumar Srivastava, Amreesh Chandra</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Potentials for Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06717</link>
      <description>Amir Omranpour, Jan Elsner, K. Nikolas Lausch, J&#246;rg Behler, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406385377

                The production of many bulk chemicals relies on heterogeneous catalysis. The rational design or improvement of the required catalysts critically depends on insights into the underlying mechanisms on the atomic scale. In recent years, substantial progress has been made in applying advanced experimental techniques to complex catalytic reactions in operando, but in order to achieve a comprehensive understanding, additional information from computer simulations is indispensable in many cases. In particular, ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) has become an important tool to explicitly address the atomistic level structure, dynamics, and reactivity of interfacial systems, but the high computational costs limit applications to systems consisting of at most a few hundred atoms for simulation times of up to tens of picoseconds. Rapid advances in the development of modern machine learning potentials (MLP) now offer a promising approach to bridge this gap, enabling simulations of complex catalytic reactions with ab initio accuracy at a small fraction of the computational costs. In this Perspective, we provide an overview of the current state of the art of applying MLPs to systems relevant for heterogeneous catalysis along with a discussion of the prospects for the use of MLPs in catalysis science in the years to come.</description>
      <author>Amir Omranpour, Jan Elsner, K. Nikolas Lausch, J&#246;rg Behler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Reaction Pathways for Oxygen Evolution as a Key Factor for the Catalytic Activity of Nickel&#8211;Iron (Oxy)Hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12988</link>
      <description>Giuseppe Mattioli, Leonardo Guidoni, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406386413

                We present a comprehensive theoretical study, using state-of-the-art density functional theory simulations, of the structural and electrochemical properties of amorphous pristine and iron-doped nickel&#8211;(oxy)hydroxide catalyst films for water oxidation in alkaline solutions, referred to as NiCat and Fe:NiCat. Our simulations accurately capture the structural changes in locally ordered units, as reported by X-ray absorption spectroscopy, when the catalyst films are activated by exposure to a positive potential. We emphasize the critical role of proton-coupled electron transfer in the reversible oxidation of Ni(II) to Ni(III/IV) during this activation. After establishing the structural models of NiCat and Fe:NiCat consistent with experimental data, we used them to explore the atomistic mechanism of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is triggered once the applied potential exceeds the overpotential required for water oxidation and oxygen production. We quantitatively compared seven OER pathways applicable to both the adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) and the lattice-oxygen-mediated mechanism (LOM) families, elucidating how iron significantly enhances the catalytic activity of Fe:NiCat compared to NiCat. Our findings suggest that simple metal&#8211;oxygen&#8211;metal motifs, common on the surface of both crystalline and amorphous metal (oxy)hydroxide films, can promote both AEM and LOM mechanisms under typical OER conditions. Furthermore, we propose that the elusive role of iron lies in the distinct behavior of Ni(IV)&#8211;O and Fe(IV)&#8211;O bonds in key intermediates preceding the formation of the O&#8211;O bond, with Fe ions lowering the potential needed to form these intermediates across the investigated pathways.</description>
      <author>Giuseppe Mattioli, Leonardo Guidoni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab Initio Study of a Tandem PdCu Catalyst Supported on Carbon Nitride Nanosheets for Nitrate-to-Ammonia Electrochemical Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05751</link>
      <description>Zhe Xue, Rui Tan, Jinzhong Tian, Hua Hou, Xinyu Zhang, Yuhong Zhao, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406388934

                Electrochemical conversion of nitrate offers an efficient approach to mitigate nitrate pollution and ammonia synthesis but is still challenged by the slow kinetics and selectivity issues of active sites. Herein, by performing density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we report a double-atom catalyst of PdCu&#8211;C7N6 by incorporating Pd and Cu together embedded in C7N6 frameworks, which not only shows outstanding catalytic performance with a low limiting potential of 0.36 V, but also can effectively inhibit the competing hydrogen evolution reactions. The high NO3RR activity on PdCu&#8211;C7N6 is well explained by the polarizable bond length as well as the asymmetric charge distribution of Pd&#8211;Cu dual active sites. This DFT work opens an avenue for developing highly efficient multicomponent NO3RR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhe Xue, Rui Tan, Jinzhong Tian, Hua Hou, Xinyu Zhang, Yuhong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional versus Unconventional Oxygen Reduction Reaction Intermediates on Single Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c23082</link>
      <description>Tahereh Jangjooye Shaldehi, Soosan Rowshanzamir, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406392891

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) stands as a pivotal process in electrochemistry, finding applications in various energy conversion technologies such as fuel cells, metal-air batteries, and chlor-alkali electrolyzers. Hereby, a comprehensive density functional theory (DFT) investigation is presented into the proposed conventional and unconventional ORR mechanisms using single-atom catalysts (SACs) supported on nitrogen-doped graphene (NG) as model systems. Several reaction intermediates have been identified that appear to be more stable than the ones postulated in the conventional mechanism, which follows the *OOH, *O, and *OH intermediates. This finding particularly holds for adsorbed *O2, which can have different adsorption geometries, ranging from &#951;1&#927;2 or &#951;2&#927;2 superoxo complexes as well as sin and anti complexes, with the two O-related ligands binding on the same or opposite sides, respectively. In the case of M@NG (M = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, and Pt), the ORR follows these unconventional *O2 intermediates, whereas for Cr@NG and Cu@NG classical and unconventional *O2 intermediates compete. We approximate the electrocatalytic activity using the concept of the thermodynamic overpotential and demonstrate that the conventional mechanism gives rise to a smaller overpotential compared to mechanisms following unconventional intermediates during the four proton-coupled electron transfer steps. Our trend study indicates that transition metals with fewer d electrons reveal smaller electrocatalytic activity due to a larger thermodynamic overpotential. Among the investigated SAC systems, Co emerges as a promising candidate, with thermodynamic overpotential and limiting potential values of 0.38 and 0.85 V vs the standard hydrogen electrode, respectively, with the conventional mechanism being favored, and with Cu appearing as the second-best candidate.</description>
      <author>Tahereh Jangjooye Shaldehi, Soosan Rowshanzamir, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c23082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computationally efficient machine-learned model for GST phase change materials via direct and indirect learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0246999</link>
      <description>Owen R. Dunton, Tom Arbaugh, Francis W. Starr, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406399926

                Phase change materials such as Ge2Sb2Te5 (GST) are ideal candidates for next-generation, non-volatile, solid-state memory due to the ability to retain binary data in the amorphous and crystal phases and rapidly transition between these phases to write/erase information. Thus, there is wide interest in using molecular modeling to study GST. Recently, a Gaussian Approximation Potential (GAP) was trained for GST to reproduce Density Functional Theory (DFT) energies and forces at a fraction of the computational cost [Zhou et al., Nat. Electron. 6, 746 (2023)]; however, simulations of large length and time scales are still challenging using this GAP model. Here, we present a machine-learned (ML) potential for GST implemented using the Atomic Cluster Expansion (ACE) framework. This ACE potential shows comparable accuracy to the GAP potential but performs orders of magnitude faster. We train the ACE potentials both directly from DFT and also using a recently introduced indirect learning approach where the potential is trained instead from an intermediate ML potential, in this case, GAP. Indirect learning allows us to consider a significantly larger training set than could be generated using DFT alone. We compare the directly and indirectly learned potentials and find that both reproduce the structure and thermodynamics predicted by the GAP and also match experimental measures of GST structure. The speed of the ACE model, particularly when using graphics processing unit acceleration, allows us to examine repeated transitions between crystal and amorphous phases in device-scale systems with only modest computational resources.</description>
      <author>Owen R. Dunton, Tom Arbaugh, Francis W. Starr</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0246999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the potential of metal-free g-C3N5 modified-highly reduced graphene catalysts for hydrogen evolution: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.151</link>
      <description>Abdulraheem K. Bello, Abdulaziz A. Al&#8208;Saadi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406407856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulraheem K. Bello, Abdulaziz A. Al&#8208;Saadi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable electronic structures and oxygen electrocatalytic mechanisms in Fe-N-C catalysts doped with B, P, S, and O heteroatoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162439</link>
      <description>Yue Zhang, Jianguang Feng, Chenchen Ma, Xiaoyun Gu, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406410873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue Zhang, Jianguang Feng, Chenchen Ma, Xiaoyun Gu, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loading silver nanoclusters onto g-C3N4 by formamide-assisted in-situ strategy to achieve efficient photocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2025.116275</link>
      <description>Zhenbang Xie, Chao Wang, Fuqi Wu, Ruiyuan Hu, Jie Zhang, Hongfei Du, Shouchao Zhang, Yongzhu Zhou, Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology A Chemistry. 462(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406414496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenbang Xie, Chao Wang, Fuqi Wu, Ruiyuan Hu, Jie Zhang, Hongfei Du, Shouchao Zhang, Yongzhu Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2025.116275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate QM/MM Molecular Dynamics for Periodic Systems in GPU4P&lt;scp&gt;y&lt;/scp&gt;SCF with Applications to Enzyme Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01698</link>
      <description>Chenghan Li, Garnet Kin&#8208;Lic Chan, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406419501

                We present an implementation of the quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) method for periodic systems using GPU accelerated QM methods, a distributed multipole formulation of the electrostatics, and a pseudobond treatment of the QM/MM boundary. We demonstrate that our method has well-controlled errors, stable self-consistent QM convergence, and energy-conserving dynamics. We further describe an application to the catalytic kinetics of chorismate mutase. Using an accurate hybrid functional reparametrized to coupled cluster energetics, our QM/MM simulations highlight the sensitivity in the calculated rate to the choice of quantum method, quantum region selection, and local protein conformation. Our work is provided through the open-source PySCF package using acceleration from the GPU4PySCF module.</description>
      <author>Chenghan Li, Garnet Kin&#8208;Lic Chan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Microalgae Process for Post-combustion CO2 Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-62660-9_24</link>
      <description>Ashish Gautam, Monoj Kumar Mondal, Environmental science and engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406421211

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashish Gautam, Monoj Kumar Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-62660-9_24</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on support materials for enhanced Pt-based catalysts: applications in oxygen reduction reactions for electrochemical energy storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10606-1</link>
      <description>Feng Zhan, Lingyun Huang, Yue Luo, Muyang Chen, Rui Tan, Xinhua Liu, Gang Liu, Zhiming Feng, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406424581

                Abstract As the demand for sustainable energy solutions grows, developing efficient energy conversion and storage technologies, such as fuel cells and metal-air batteries, is vital. Oxygen Reduction Reaction (ORR) is a significant limitation in electrochemical systems due to its slower kinetics. Although Pt-based catalysts are commonly used to address this challenge, their high cost and suboptimal performance remain significant obstacles to further development. This review offers a comprehensive overview of advanced support materials aimed at improving the efficiency, durability, and cost-effectiveness of Pt-based catalysts. By examining a range of materials, including mesoporous carbon, graphene, carbon nanotubes, and metal oxides, the review clarifies the relationship between the structural properties of these supports and their influence on ORR performance. Additionally, it discusses the fundamental characteristics of these materials, their practical applications in fuel cells, and explores potential solutions and future directions for optimizing Pt-based catalysts to advance sustainable energy conversion technologies. Future research could focus on nano-engineering and composite material development to unlock the full potential of Pt-based catalysts, significantly enhancing their economic viability and performance in energy applications.</description>
      <author>Feng Zhan, Lingyun Huang, Yue Luo, Muyang Chen, Rui Tan, Xinhua Liu, Gang Liu, Zhiming Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10606-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Active Site and Catalytic Activity of N-Coordinated Ni&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Dual-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02649</link>
      <description>Ashok Singh, Srimanta Pakhira, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406437057

                Oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is an indispensable electrochemical reaction in fuel cells. However, the performance of fuel cells has been affected by the slack kinetics of the ORR. Hence, the development of efficient and affordable electrocatalysts for the reduction of O2 is necessary for the large-scale commercialization of fuel cells. Here, we present a Ni2 dual-atom anchored on a N-doped carbon nanotube (Ni2_N3_CNT and Ni2_N4_CNT) and a Ni single-atom anchored on N-doped carbon nanotube (Ni1_N3_CNT and Ni1_N4_CNT) catalysts with two possible active sites, namely, Ni-site and N-site, as efficient catalysts toward the ORR. We have analyzed the energetically favorable active site for O2 reduction on the surface of the Ni1_N3_CNT, Ni1_N4_CNT, Ni2_N3_CNT, and Ni2_N4_CNT catalysts by employing the density functional theory method with van der Waals (vdW) dispersion corrections (in short the DFT-D3) method. Among all possible configurations, Ni2_N3_CNT is a more favorable configuration with the Ni catalytic active site toward the ORR. Then, we have studied the structural, electronic, and catalytic activity of Ni2_N3_CNT by using the same DFT-D3 method. The analysis of the ORR intermediate species reveals that the associative reaction pathway is a more favorable path for reducing the O2 into H2O at the Ni catalytic site of Ni2_N3_CNT than the dissociative reaction pathway. In the free energy profile, all of the ORR reaction intermediate steps are downhill, indicating the good catalytic activity of Ni2_N3_CNT toward the ORR. Moreover, we have also studied the structural and electronic properties of all of the reaction intermediate steps by employing the same DFT-D3 method. These findings point out that the Ni2 dual-atom catalysts provide an efficient electrocatalytic activity toward the ORR, and it holds great promise as a replacement for Pt-based catalysts in future proton-exchange membrane fuel cells. This work highlights the potential and importance of the subject material as a durable electrocatalyst for the ORR, offering insights into Ni2 dual-atom electrochemistry and the design of advanced catalysts, which may be a promising candidate to substitute for Pt electrodes, and it is an excellent material for fuel-cell components.</description>
      <author>Ashok Singh, Srimanta Pakhira</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Structure&#8211;Function Relationship in Iridium&#8211;Cobalt Oxide Catalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction across Different Electrolyte Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06814</link>
      <description>Marc Francis Labata, Nitul Kakati, Guangfu Li, M. Virginia P. Alto&#233;, Po&#8208;Ya Abel Chuang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406439237

                Renewable hydrogen generation from water electrolysis offers a viable path to decarbonization if the costs can be reduced. The iridium-based anode catalyst is one of the most expensive components in electrolyzers. We propose reducing iridium usage by substituting Ir with Co, a more affordable metal, in the mixed oxide phase to enhance the catalytic activity while minimizing Ir consumption. A modified surfactant-assisted Adams fusion synthesis technique was developed as a scalable method for producing IrCo oxide nanoparticles. The synthesized material outperforms the commercial baseline, iridium oxide with carbon (IrOx_C), in both acidic and alkaline media. Acid etching (IrCo_ae) further enhances activity by selectively removing Co to expose more active sites. IrCo_ae achieved a significantly lower overpotential at 10 mA/cm2 compared to IrOx_C, with reductions of approximately 18% under acidic conditions and 14% under alkaline conditions. This work demonstrates that the proposed synthesis method enables efficient Ir utilization and can be adapted to enhance catalyst stability for renewable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Marc Francis Labata, Nitul Kakati, Guangfu Li, M. Virginia P. Alto&#233;, Po&#8208;Ya Abel Chuang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microhabitat mechanisms induced by cationic amino-functionalized ionic liquid electrolytes on CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131672</link>
      <description>Kuilin Peng, Shaojuan Zeng, Haifei Zhang, Haiyan Jiang, Guilin Li, Lei Yuan, Xin Li, Min Wang, Xiangping Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406450483

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kuilin Peng, Shaojuan Zeng, Haifei Zhang, Haiyan Jiang, Guilin Li, Lei Yuan, Xin Li, Min Wang, Xiangping Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Confinement Effects on the Dynamical Aspects of CO Oxidation over Pt(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06593</link>
      <description>Nidhi Tiwari, Sandip Ghosh, Ashwani K. Tiwari, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406465179

                This study investigates the effects of two-dimensional (2D) confinement on CO oxidation reaction over Pt(111) surfaces, emphasizing the structural, electronic, and dynamical aspects of CO2 formation and desorption. Using pristine and single-defect hexagonal boron nitride (h-BN) and graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) as overlayers, we found that confinement by nitrogen-vacancy h-BN (NV) induces a significant reduction, greater than that of graphene (Gr), in the activation energy barrier for CO2 formation. The confinement effect on adsorption depends on the reference states chosen for adsorption energy calculations. Reference states, such as stable or original intersurface gaps, can yield either positive or negative confinement energy values, indicating adsorption weakening or strengthening, respectively. Importantly, adsorption weakening correlates better with barrier reduction. Post-transition-state dynamical simulations of CO2 desorption revealed pronounced vibrational oscillations. NV and Gr confinement led to complex vibrational features, indicating stronger interactions between CO2 and the 2D cover. This study highlights the profound impact of 2D confinement on catalytic processes, providing insights into how 2D materials modulate the electronic structure and vibrational dynamics of reactions. The findings could guide the design of efficient catalysts for industrial applications, particularly in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Nidhi Tiwari, Sandip Ghosh, Ashwani K. Tiwari</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrOx Supported on Submicron-Sized Anatase TiO2 as a Catalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010079</link>
      <description>Josep Boter-Carbonell, Carlos Calabr&#233;s-Casellas, M. Sarret, Teresa Andreu, Pere Llu&#305;&#769;s Cabot, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406465519

                Ir-based catalysts are the best in terms of activity and stability for oxygen evolution reactions (OERs) in proton exchange water electrolysis. Due to their cost, efforts have been made to decrease their load without a loss of activity. In this paper, Ir nanoparticles measuring 2&#8211;3 nm were loaded on TiO2 anatase supports of submicrometric size in different amounts using the microwave polyol method to optimize their mass activity. Using anatase particles with a diameter of about 100 nm and titania nanotubes (TNTs), Ir/TiO2 catalysts with Ir contents of 5, 10, 20, and 40 wt.% were synthesized and characterized via structural and electrochemical techniques. It was shown that the amount of Ir must be regulated to obtain continuous coverage on titania with strong Ir&#8211;TiO2 interactions which, for the 100 nm diameter anatase, is limited to about 20 wt.%. A higher percentage of Ir over 40 wt.% can be dispersed over the TNTs. Exceeding one layer of coverage leads to a decrease in the catalyst&#8217;s utilization. Ir/TiO2(10:90), Ir/TiO2(20:80), and Ir/TiO2(40:60) presented the highest pseudocapacitive currents per unit of Ir mass. The electrochemical active areas and mass activities for these later catalysts were also the highest compared to Ir/TiO2(05:95), Ir/TNT(40:60), and the unsupported catalysts and increased from 40 to 10 wt.% Ir. They also presented the lowest overpotentials of about 300 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for the OER, with Ir/TiO2(10:90) presenting the best specific activities and surface turnover frequencies, thus showing that the size of the support can be regulated to decrease the Ir content of the catalyst without a loss of activity.</description>
      <author>Josep Boter-Carbonell, Carlos Calabr&#233;s-Casellas, M. Sarret, Teresa Andreu, Pere Llu&#305;&#769;s Cabot</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid synthesis of an aluminum-doped ultrathin Ru&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; heterostructure optimized through combined wet&#8211;dry microwave radiation for efficient acidic and alkaline overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07453j</link>
      <description>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Shaorou Ke, Bozhi Yang, Shujie Yang, Yanghong Li, Meiling Zhan, Xin Min, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406477985

                By employing an efficient &#8220;wet-dry&#8221; microwave strategy, we have developed Al-doped Ru x /RuO 2 (A-RRO@G) in just 110 s. Its unique structure optimizes electronic configurations, enhancing water-splitting activity in both acidic and alkaline conditions.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, Shaorou Ke, Bozhi Yang, Shujie Yang, Yanghong Li, Meiling Zhan, Xin Min</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07453j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysts via Direct Oxygen&#8211;Oxygen Radical Coupling Pathway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202416362</link>
      <description>Chengli Rong, Xinyi Huang, Hamidreza Arandiyan, Zongping Shao, Yuan Wang, Yuan Chen, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406482848

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a cornerstone of various electrochemical energy conversion and storage systems, including water splitting, CO 2 /N 2 reduction, reversible fuel cells, and rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries. OER typically proceeds through three primary mechanisms: adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM), lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM), and oxide path mechanism (OPM). Unlike AEM and LOM, the OPM proceeds via direct oxygen&#8211;oxygen radical coupling that can bypass linear scaling relationships of reaction intermediates in AEM and avoid catalyst structural collapse in LOM, thereby enabling enhanced catalytic activity and stability. Despite its unique advantage, electrocatalysts that can drive OER via OPM remain nascent and are increasingly recognized as critical. This review discusses recent advances in OPM&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts. It starts by analyzing three reaction mechanisms that guide the design of electrocatalysts. Then, several types of novel materials, including atomic ensembles, metal oxides, perovskite oxides, and molecular complexes, are highlighted. Afterward, operando characterization techniques used to monitor the dynamic evolution of active sites and reaction intermediates are examined. The review concludes by discussing several research directions to advance OPM&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts toward practical applications.</description>
      <author>Chengli Rong, Xinyi Huang, Hamidreza Arandiyan, Zongping Shao, Yuan Wang, Yuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202416362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus&#8208;Mediated Selenium Dual Atoms for Bifunctional Oxygen Reactions and Long&#8208;Life Low&#8208;Temperature Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423476</link>
      <description>Lingzhi Xia, Jianhua Zhang, Pengfei Yan, Kailing Zhou, Yuhong Jin, Xiaoxing Ke, Jingbin Liu, Hao Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406493485

                Abstract Rapid kinetics and stable atom configuration of the catalysts are essential and greatly sought after for bifunctional oxygen reactions and energy conversion devices, but remain unsatisfactory. Herein, the Se dual atoms structure consisting of the periodically arranged Se&#8208;P&#8208;Se configurations within graphitic nitrogen carbon framework (P&#8208;Se dual atoms&#8208;NC) is constructed by P directionally mediated single atoms deposition strategy. The in situ/ex situ experiments combining the theoretical calculations reveal that both the inter&#8208;site distance effect of the adjacent Se atoms in the NC and the Se&#8208;P binding effect endow P&#8208;Se dual atoms&#8208;NC with a stable atom configuration and ultra&#8208;durable lifespan, and the locally polarized electronic micro&#8208;environment built by P 2 p &#8208;Se 3 d &#8208;C 2 p orbital hybridization and the electrons transfer significantly promotes H 2 O&#8208;O 2 coupling, boosts the adsorption/desorption of O&#8208;intermediates and accelerates the electron transport kinetics. Moreover, the adjacent Se atoms with a periodically arranged structure could provide more sites for the absorption and conversion of reactants. Thus, the as&#8208;prepared catalyst exhibits the top&#8208;level bifunctional activity with an ultra&#8208;low potential difference (&#916; E ) of 0.58 V and delivers the outstandingly low&#8208;temperature specific capacity of 796.41 mAh g Zn &#8722;1 and the ultra&#8208;durable lifespan over 1000 h for assembled zinc&#8208;air batteries at &#8722;40 &#176;C.</description>
      <author>Lingzhi Xia, Jianhua Zhang, Pengfei Yan, Kailing Zhou, Yuhong Jin, Xiaoxing Ke, Jingbin Liu, Hao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of Fe2O3-based nanoparticles on nitrogen-incorporated carbon as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.212</link>
      <description>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, Selvam Mathi, Shankara S. Kalanur, T. Maiyalagan, Mohammed Ali Alshehri, Nagaraj P. Shetti, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 103(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406504119

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, Selvam Mathi, Shankara S. Kalanur, T. Maiyalagan, Mohammed Ali Alshehri, Nagaraj P. Shetti</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-based catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolysers: The need to look beyond just another catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.485</link>
      <description>Shailendra Kumar Sharma, Chang Wu, Niall Malone, Laura J. Titheridge, Chuan Zhao, Prasanth Gupta, Hicham Idriss, J. Kennedy, Vedran Jovic, Aaron T. Marshall, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406522527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shailendra Kumar Sharma, Chang Wu, Niall Malone, Laura J. Titheridge, Chuan Zhao, Prasanth Gupta, Hicham Idriss, J. Kennedy, Vedran Jovic, Aaron T. Marshall</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of &#946;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Ir/Ru Co-substitution for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</link>
      <description>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406534076

                The efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media is severely limited by the poor stability, low activity, and high cost of available catalysts. Enhancing intrinsic activity while maintaining stability and reducing reliance on precious metals is crucial. The typical adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) leads to high overpotentials and low activity, making the transition to alternative mechanisms, such as the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) or oxide path mechanism (OPM), highly desirable due to their lower overpotentials. Here, we combine density functional theory (DFT) calculations with experimental validation to enhance the activity and stability of &#946;-MnO2 via co-substitution with ruthenium (Ru) and iridium (Ir), enabling the transition from AEM to OPM. DFT calculations reveal that AEM is hindered by the weak nucleophilicity of water, while LOM suffers from high kinetic barriers due to structural distortions. In contrast, OPM demonstrates a significantly lower kinetic barrier, facilitated by the synergistic interaction between Ru and Ir. Experimentally, IrRuMnOx was synthesized through co-precipitation and hydrothermal methods, showing an 80-fold improvement in mass activity and a 96-fold increase in stability compared to commercial IrO2, with minimal noble metal leaching, as confirmed by inductively coupled plasma optical emission spectroscopy (ICP-OES). IrRuMnOx exhibited an ultralow overpotential of 475 mV at 1 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 44.26 mV&#183;dec&#8211;1 in 0.5 M H2SO4, maintaining stable performance for over 100 h. Moreover, the IrRuMnOx-based membrane electrode, with a low Ir loading of 0.075 mgIr&#183;cm&#8211;2, achieved remarkable current densities of 1.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.66 V and 2.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.91 V at 80 &#176;C. This performance surpasses that of both unsupported and conventional supported Ir-based catalysts at comparable Ir loading levels. This study offers critical insights into OER mechanisms in acidic media and paves the way for developing efficient and durable OER electrocatalysts for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase&#8208;Engineered Bi&#8208;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Single&#8208;Atom Alloy Oxide Boosting Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417777</link>
      <description>Zhichao Yang, Yutian Ding, Wen Chen, Shuiping Luo, Daofan Cao, Xin Long, Lei Xie, Xincheng Zhou, Xinyi Cai, Ke Liu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406543620

                Abstract Engineering nanomaterials at single&#8208;atomic sites can enable unprecedented catalytic properties for broad applications, yet it remains challenging to do so on RuO 2 &#8208;based electrocatalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE). Herein, the rational design and construction of Bi&#8208;RuO 2 single&#8208;atom alloy oxide (SAAO) are presented to boost acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), via phase engineering a novel hexagonal close packed ( hcp ) RuBi single&#8208;atom alloy. This Bi&#8208;RuO 2 SAAO electrocatalyst exhibits a low overpotential of 192 mV and superb stability over 650 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , enabling a practical PEMWE that needs only 1.59 V to reach 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 under industrial conditions. Operando differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy analysis, coupled with density functional theory studies, confirmed the adsorbate&#8208;evolving mechanism on Bi&#8208;RuO 2 SAAO and that the incorporation of Bi 1 improves the activity by electronic density optimization and the stability by hindering surface Ru demetallation. This work not only introduces a new strategy to fabricate high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts at atomic&#8208;level, but also demonstrates their potential use in industrial electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Zhichao Yang, Yutian Ding, Wen Chen, Shuiping Luo, Daofan Cao, Xin Long, Lei Xie, Xincheng Zhou, Xinyi Cai, Ke Liu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable adsorption configuration searching in hetero-catalysis based on similar distribution and active learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115971</link>
      <description>Jiaqiang Yang, Xiaofei Zhang, Xiaofeng Zhang, Bingbo Niu, Feifeng Wu, Ning Luo, Jilin He, Chengduo Wang, Bin Shan, Qingkui Li, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406559764

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqiang Yang, Xiaofei Zhang, Xiaofeng Zhang, Bingbo Niu, Feifeng Wu, Ning Luo, Jilin He, Chengduo Wang, Bin Shan, Qingkui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyrrole-type TM-N3 sites as high-efficient bifunctional oxygen reactions electrocatalysts: From theoretical prediction to experimental validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.01.002</link>
      <description>Chunxia Wu, Yanhui Yu, Yiming Song, Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Ying Liang, Liqiang Jing, Kai Zhang, Zhenjie Zhang, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406560069

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunxia Wu, Yanhui Yu, Yiming Song, Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Ying Liang, Liqiang Jing, Kai Zhang, Zhenjie Zhang, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.01.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing energy and economic costs in post-combustion carbon capture with intelligent amine selection system: A case study on the Abadan power plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2025.01.034</link>
      <description>Farzin Hosseinifard, Amir Mohsen Soufeh, Mohsen Salimi, Milad Hosseinpour, Majid Amidpour, Energy Reports. 13(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406561569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Farzin Hosseinifard, Amir Mohsen Soufeh, Mohsen Salimi, Milad Hosseinpour, Majid Amidpour</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2025.01.034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of the onset voltage of water adsorption on Pt(111) surface using density functional theory/Implicit model calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105809</link>
      <description>Maxim Shishkin, Takeo Yamaguchi, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406562334

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maxim Shishkin, Takeo Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor for electro-oxidation of glycerol with high-efficiency bifunctional Cu-N single atom catalyst and coupled with hydrogen evolution/carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.122</link>
      <description>Mingyue Lv, Hao Sun, Hui Wang, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyue Lv, Hao Sun, Hui Wang, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of transition metal atom doped MoS2 as single-atom electrocatalysts for nitrogen fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115090</link>
      <description>Wei Song, Zhe Fu, Jiale Liu, Jinqiang Li, Chaozheng He, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Song, Zhe Fu, Jiale Liu, Jinqiang Li, Chaozheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ growth of Ni2.86Te2 and Mo6Te8 telluride catalysts on foam NiMo substrates for enhanced oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</link>
      <description>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406570335

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical approaches for CO2 point source, direct air, and seawater capture: identifying opportunities and synergies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-025-35890-x</link>
      <description>Mehar U Nisa, Haris Ishaq, Curran Crawford, Environmental Science and Pollution Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406500378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mehar U Nisa, Haris Ishaq, Curran Crawford</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-025-35890-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress of porous covalent organic frameworks membranes for gas- and liquid-phase separation towards environmental chemical engineering applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115487</link>
      <description>Xiaojian Yang, Wenxuan Li, Shenglin Wang, Honglei Shuai, Han Zhang, Xinsheng Zhao, Yanan Gao, Hui L&#252;, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406560945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojian Yang, Wenxuan Li, Shenglin Wang, Honglei Shuai, Han Zhang, Xinsheng Zhao, Yanan Gao, Hui L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for metal additive manufacturing process optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-22145-3.00006-2</link>
      <description>Harpreet Kaur Channi, Raman Kumar, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406568255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harpreet Kaur Channi, Raman Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-22145-3.00006-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Solid-Supported Amines for Thermocatalytic Reactive CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10049</link>
      <description>W. Wilson McNeary, Nathan C. Ellebracht, Melinda L. Jue, Mathew J. Rasmussen, James M. Crawford, Matthew M. Yung, Anh T. To, Simon H. Pang, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406468596

                Reactive CO2 capture (RCC) is a promising strategy for process intensification of carbon capture and conversion for production of low-carbon fuels and chemicals. As state-of-the-art sorbent materials in point source and direct air capture systems, solid-supported amines are a natural choice to pair with supported CO2 hydrogenation catalysts (e.g., metallic nanoparticles) for developing high-capacity sorbent-catalyst materials for use in RCC. In this Perspective, we summarize the relevant literature combining solid-supported amines with metallic nanoparticles for thermocatalytic RCC and detail two of our own case studies using RCC to synthesize methane and methanol. Our observations suggest that the temperature mismatch between CO2 desorption and reaction, along with potential catalyst site poisoning by grafted aminosilanes, is a significant obstacle to realizing the potential of amine-based RCC materials in the decarbonization of chemical production. This stands in contrast to literature detailing successful RCC using liquid amines and solid catalysts, which may benefit from more favorable mass transfer dynamics, as well as early stage reports into RCC solid-phase amine-Pd materials, whose findings we were not able to replicate. More judicious reaction selection and synthetic design strategies to match materials with process conditions offer alternative pathways for future research.</description>
      <author>W. Wilson McNeary, Nathan C. Ellebracht, Melinda L. Jue, Mathew J. Rasmussen, James M. Crawford, Matthew M. Yung, Anh T. To, Simon H. Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Checking of Asymmetric Catalysis Literature Using a Graph Neural Network Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020355</link>
      <description>Eduardo Alberto Aguilar Bejarano, Viraj Deorukhkar, Simon Woodward, Molecules. 30(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406439159

                The range of chemical databases available has dramatically increased in recent years, but the reliability and quality of their data are often negatively affected by human-error fidelity. The size of chemical databases can make manual data curation/checking of such sets time consuming; thus, automated tools to help this process are highly desirable. Herein, we propose the use of Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) to identifying potential stereochemical misassignments in the primary asymmetric catalysis literature. Our method relies on the use of an ensemble of GNN models to predict the expected stereoselectivity of exemplars for a particular asymmetric reaction. When the majority of these models do not correlate to the reported outcome, the point is labeled as a possible stereochemical misassignment. Such identified cases are few in number and more easily investigated for their cause. We demonstrate the use of this approach to spot potential literature stereochemical misassignments in the ketone products resulting from catalytic asymmetric 1,4-addition of organoboron nucleophiles to Michael acceptors in two different databases, each one using a different family of chiral ligands (bisphosphine and diene ligands). Our results demonstrate that this methodology is useful for curation of medium-sized databases, speeding this process significantly compared to complete manual curation/checking. In the datasets investigated, human expert checking was reduced to 2.2% and 3.5% of the total data exemplars.</description>
      <author>Eduardo Alberto Aguilar Bejarano, Viraj Deorukhkar, Simon Woodward</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficacy of biochar as a catalyst for a Fenton-like reaction: Experimental, statistical and mathematical modeling analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2025.107014</link>
      <description>Oscar M. Rodr&#237;guez-Narv&#225;ez, Bhuman Pandita, Omesh Goyal, Srinivas Rallapalli, Mahinda I. Ranasinghe, Alain S. Conejo-D&#225;vila, Erick R. Bandala, Ashantha Goonetilleke, Journal of Water Process Engineering. 70(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406561020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oscar M. Rodr&#237;guez-Narv&#225;ez, Bhuman Pandita, Omesh Goyal, Srinivas Rallapalli, Mahinda I. Ranasinghe, Alain S. Conejo-D&#225;vila, Erick R. Bandala, Ashantha Goonetilleke</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2025.107014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development and Thermo-Mechanical Testing of Low Hysteresis Shape Memory Alloy for Satellite Actuators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12794/metadc2048636</link>
      <description>Andre Montagnoli, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4406530876

                Shape memory alloys (SMAs) have gained much attention as a powerful source of actuation due to their improved performance, reduced size, and reduced complexity between components as well as having a high work output density. Their primary mechanism of actuation relies on a non-diffusional cyclic phase transformation from martensite to austenite, where the amount of thermal energy needed per cycle is directly associated with the hysteresis width between the austenite final and martensite final temperatures. Consequently, a narrower gap between those two temperature ranges requires a much lower energy demand to produce the actuation needed. Previous studies have indicated that the hysteresis width is linked to a strong coherence between the austenite/martensite interface. It has been shown that elemental additions to NiTi-based SMAs can further improve this coherency. Another huge challenge facing this unique technology is linked with its thermo-mechanical stability. Binary NiTi SMAs often exhibit significant transformation temperature shifts after each thermo-mechanical cycle, which can contribute to a shorter lifespan. The primary goal of this project is to identify and develop thermo-mechanically stable, low hysteresis shape memory alloys (LHSMAs) for actuator applications. To accomplish this goal, elemental additions of Cu, Co, Hf, and Pd were incorporated into NiTi-based SMAs and the results were compared in respect to their hysteresis width and thermo-mechanical stability through differential scanning calorimetry, scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive spectroscopy, and compressive thermo-mechanical testing. Two quaternary SMAs containing small additions of Cu and Pd were shown to exhibit promising results with respect to hysteresis width and good thermo-mechanical stability.</description>
      <author>Andre Montagnoli</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12794/metadc2048636</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
