<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 01:44:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Proton-Relaying Adsorbates Induce Non-Nernstian Behavior in Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01767</link>
      <description>Lulu Zhang, Donghui Zhao, Weiqiang Tang, Yanxia Chen, Jun Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412839552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lulu Zhang, Donghui Zhao, Weiqiang Tang, Yanxia Chen, Jun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01767</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells: Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-9845-5_5</link>
      <description>Yinshi Li, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412845495

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yinshi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-9845-5_5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and Theoretical Investigations on Magneto&#8208;Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction of CoFeP Nanorods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500321</link>
      <description>Mohammed Arkham Belgami, Afsal S. Shajahan, Erdenebayar Baasanjav, Vishwanath Ankalgi, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Sang Mun Jeong, Chandra Sekhar Rout, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412845647

                Abstract The pursuit of low&#8208;cost, efficient, and durable electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution in alkaline media is vital for water&#8208;splitting applications. Herein, the hydrothermal&#8208;based synthesis of a multiphase ferromagnetic catalyst CoFeP, comprising FeP, CoP, and Fe 2 P is reported. Structural analyses confirm the coexistence of phases, and electrochemical studies reveal excellent OER activity. CoFeP exhibits an overpotential of 335 mV at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 116 mV dec &#8722;1 without a magnetic field, whereas under the magnetic field of 2000 G, these values lowered to 235 mV and 93 mV dec &#8722;1 , respectively. The enhancement is attributed to magnetic&#8208;field&#8208;induced spin polarization, surface reconstruction, and increased ECSA from 70 to 110 mF cm &#8722;2 , highlighting the potential of magnetic modulation for boosting catalytic performance. Through spin&#8208;polarized Density Functional Theory (DFT) simulations, the structural and electronic features of CoFeP, providing theoretical insights into its role in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) is elucidated. This investigation demonstrates that the application of an external magnetic field significantly reduces the overpotential required for OER as the adsorption of intermediate species becomes stronger due to more charge transfer, aligning with experimental observations. These findings highlight the interplay between magnetic fields and electrocatalytic performance, offering a pathway to enhance energy conversion efficiency.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Arkham Belgami, Afsal S. Shajahan, Erdenebayar Baasanjav, Vishwanath Ankalgi, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Sang Mun Jeong, Chandra Sekhar Rout</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast synthesis of V8C7 catalysts for efficient chemical hydrogen evolution via decoupled water electrolysis in a dual-circuit redox flow battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150665</link>
      <description>Ying Ma, Huimei Yuan, Guanghui Zhang, Shengliang Qi, Shumin Liu, Xiaofei Lei, Xu Zong, Weiguang Ma, Xiangkun Ma, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 162(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412848627

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Ma, Huimei Yuan, Guanghui Zhang, Shengliang Qi, Shumin Liu, Xiaofei Lei, Xu Zong, Weiguang Ma, Xiangkun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric hydrogenation-driven enhancement of activity and selectivity in V-anchored N3-doped graphene catalysts for nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150787</link>
      <description>Wenming Lu, Kai Guo, Daifei Ye, Xiaxia Gong, Wei Liu, Jing Xu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 162(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412860694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenming Lu, Kai Guo, Daifei Ye, Xiaxia Gong, Wei Liu, Jing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Empirical Energy Functions Using Physics&#8208; and Machine Learning&#8208;Based Extensions: Structure, Dynamics and Spectroscopy of Modified Benzenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70162</link>
      <description>Kham Lek Chaton, Markus Meuwly, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(21)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412861632

                The effects of replacing individual contributions to an empirical energy function are assessed for halogenated benzenes (X-Bz, X = H, F, Cl, Br) and chlorinated phenols (Cl-PhOH). Introducing electrostatic models based on minimal distributed charges (MDCM) instead of usual atom-centered point charges (PCs) to realistically describe features such as &#963;-holes yields overestimated hydration free energies unless the van der Waals parameters are reparametrized. Scaling van der Waals ranges by 10% to 20% for three Cl-PhOH and most X-Bz yield results within experimental error bars, which is encouraging, whereas for benzene (H-Bz) PC-based models are sufficient. Replacing the bonded terms by a neural network-trained energy function featuring fluctuating atom-centered PCs also yields qualitatively correct hydration free energies, which can be brought into agreement with experiments within error bars after adaptation of the van der Waals parameters. The infrared spectroscopy of Cl-PhOH is rather well captured by all models, although the ML-based energy function performs somewhat better in the region of the framework modes. The present work finds that refinements of empirical energy functions for targeted applications are a meaningful way toward more quantitative and physics-based simulations. At the same time, empirical energy functions have matured to a remarkable degree, at least for the species considered in the present work.</description>
      <author>Kham Lek Chaton, Markus Meuwly</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of Hydrogen Storage in MOF-5 and Li-MOF-5 by Ring Polymer Molecular Dynamics on Self-Consistently Fine-Tuned Machine-Learned Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01522</link>
      <description>Julien Steffen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. 129(30)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412865197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Julien Steffen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A sustainable Ru catalyzed aerobic oxidation based on high loading magnetic ionic nanoparticles network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-07505-5</link>
      <description>Sepideh Asgari, Mina Ghahremani, Sepideh Najafvand-Derikvandi, Hesamodin Moradi, Mina Tavakolian, Fariborz Mansouri, Babak Karimi, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412867463

                In this study, we describe the production of a novel high loading magnetic ionic nanoparticle network (HMINN) encompassing a functionalized imidazolium structure bridging between the core-shell magnetic nanoparticles. The network was constructed through the in situ radical polymerization of tris-vinyl imidazolium moieties on the surface of mercaptopropyl functionalized silica-coated magnetite. The structural and chemical features of the resulting material were comprehensively characterized utilizing various analytical methods such as N2 adsorption-desorption, FTIR, TGA, HRTEM, ICP, XPS, VSM and elemental analysis. This material was then served to produce a Ru-supported catalyst for the oxidation of alcohols and amines under aerobic conditions. The aerobic oxidation of a diverse variety of benzylic, aliphatic, allylic, cyclic, and heterocyclic substrates was efficiently accomplished in the presence of Ru@HMINN under additive-free conditions and excellent E-factor and EcoScale factor, affording good to excellent yields of the related aldehydes and nitriles. Some of the advantages are the highly available active sites, high ionic density and porous high loading network, the outstanding dispersion of the catalyst in organic media, and the superior ability of imidazolium units to stabilize the Ru nanoparticles while allowing convenient separation of the whole system by applying an external magnet.</description>
      <author>Sepideh Asgari, Mina Ghahremani, Sepideh Najafvand-Derikvandi, Hesamodin Moradi, Mina Tavakolian, Fariborz Mansouri, Babak Karimi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-07505-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Dynamics of Amorphous Phase in Sriro3 Catalyst During Oxygen Evolution Reaction Revealed by Operando Total X-Ray Scattering Measurements and Pair Distribution Function Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5358492</link>
      <description>Kentaro Kobayashi, Satoshi Hiroi, Koji Ohara, Neha Thakur, Mukesh Kumar, Weijie Cao, Kengo Nakada, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Hiroki Yamada, Seiya Shimono, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yoshiharu Uchimoto, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412873697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kentaro Kobayashi, Satoshi Hiroi, Koji Ohara, Neha Thakur, Mukesh Kumar, Weijie Cao, Kengo Nakada, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Hiroki Yamada, Seiya Shimono, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yoshiharu Uchimoto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5358492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal-Doped Mo-Vacancy Defects at MoS2 Basal Plane for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-025-00515-z</link>
      <description>Donghwi Kim, Sangheon Lee, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim, Korean Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412874275

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Donghwi Kim, Sangheon Lee, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-025-00515-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPUMD 4.0: A high&#8208;performance molecular dynamics package for versatile materials simulations with machine&#8208;learned potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.70028</link>
      <description>Ke Xu, H. Bu, Shuning Pan, Eric Lindgren, Yong-Chao Wu, Yong Wang, Jiahui Liu, Keke Song, Bin Xu, Yifan Li, Tobias Hainer, L.A. Svensson, Julia Wiktor, Rui Zhao, Hongfu Huang, Cheng Qian, Shuo Zhang, Zezhu Zeng, Bohan Zhang, Bing Tang, Yang Xiao, Zihan Yan, Jiuyang Shi, Zhixin Liang, Junjie Wang, Ting Liang, Shuo Cao, Yanzhou Wang, Penghua Ying, Nan Xu, Chengbing Chen, Yuwen Zhang, Zherui Chen, Xin Wu, Wenjian Jiang, Esm&#233;e Berger, Yanlong Li, Shunda Chen, Alexander J. Gabourie, Haikuan Dong, Shiyun Xiong, Ning Wei, Yue Chen, Jianbin Xu, Feng Ding, Zhimei Sun, Tapio Ala-Nissil&#228;, Ari Harju, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, Pengfei Guan, Paul Erhart, Jian Sun, Wengen Ouyang, Yanjing Su, Zheyong Fan, Materials Genome Engineering Advances. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412881701

                Abstract This paper provides a comprehensive overview of the latest stable release of the graphics processing units molecular dynamics (GPUMD) package, GPUMD 4.0. We begin with a brief review of its development history, starting from the initial version. We then discuss the theoretical foundations for the development of the GPUMD package, including the formulations of the interatomic force, virial and heat current for many&#8208;body potentials, the development of the highly efficient and flexible neuroevolution potential (NEP) method, the supported integrators and related operations, the various physical properties that can be calculated on the fly, and the GPUMD ecosystem. After presenting these functionalities, we review a range of applications enabled by GPUMD, particularly in combination with the NEP approach. Finally, we outline possible future development directions for GPUMD.</description>
      <author>Ke Xu, H. Bu, Shuning Pan, Eric Lindgren, Yong-Chao Wu, Yong Wang, Jiahui Liu, Keke Song, Bin Xu, Yifan Li, Tobias Hainer, L.A. Svensson, Julia Wiktor, Rui Zhao, Hongfu Huang, Cheng Qian, Shuo Zhang, Zezhu Zeng, Bohan Zhang, Bing Tang, Yang Xiao, Zihan Yan, Jiuyang Shi, Zhixin Liang, Junjie Wang, Ting Liang, Shuo Cao, Yanzhou Wang, Penghua Ying, Nan Xu, Chengbing Chen, Yuwen Zhang, Zherui Chen, Xin Wu, Wenjian Jiang, Esm&#233;e Berger, Yanlong Li, Shunda Chen, Alexander J. Gabourie, Haikuan Dong, Shiyun Xiong, Ning Wei, Yue Chen, Jianbin Xu, Feng Ding, Zhimei Sun, Tapio Ala-Nissil&#228;, Ari Harju, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, Pengfei Guan, Paul Erhart, Jian Sun, Wengen Ouyang, Yanjing Su, Zheyong Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.70028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VeloxChem Quantum&#8211;Classical Interoperability for Modeling of Complex Molecular Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c03187</link>
      <description>Juan &#193;ngel de Gracia Trivi&#241;o, Iulia Emilia Brumboiu, David Carrasco&#8208;Busturia, Xin Li, Chenxi Li, Mathieu Linares, Valentin Lindfeld, Young Min Rhee, Julia Rune, Bastiaan van Hoorn, Patrick Norman, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412882403

                Being a program written primarily in Python that strictly adheres to modern object-oriented software engineering and parallel programming practices, VeloxChem is shown to be suitable for the development of (semi)automatized workflows that extend its scope from first-principles quantum chemical purism to hybrid quantum-classical interoperability and some degree of semiempiricism. Methods are presented for building complex systems such as metal-organic frameworks, constructing molecular mechanics and interpolation mechanics force fields, conformer searches, system solvation, determining free energies of solvation, and determining free energy profiles of reaction pathways using the empirical valence bond method. The implementations are made intuitive with opportunities for interactive plotting and 3D molecular structure illustrations through the use of Jupyter notebooks.</description>
      <author>Juan &#193;ngel de Gracia Trivi&#241;o, Iulia Emilia Brumboiu, David Carrasco&#8208;Busturia, Xin Li, Chenxi Li, Mathieu Linares, Valentin Lindfeld, Young Min Rhee, Julia Rune, Bastiaan van Hoorn, Patrick Norman, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c03187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amplifying Intermetal Bias of Pt&#8208;Rh Alloy Nanolayers for Facilitated Hydrogen Inter&#8208;Diffusion and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202512299</link>
      <description>Shi&#8208;Nan Zhang, Qianyu Liu, Bing&#8208;Liang Leng, Zhongmin Wang, Zhenfeng Zhang, Zhiyong Zhong, Xi Liu, Jie&#8208;Sheng Chen, Xin&#8208;Hao Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412883899

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer driven by renewable electricity has been regarded as a sustainable energy production technology, but is greatly limited by the high cost and unsatisfactory durability of noble metal catalysts. Here, we present the proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept application of the amplified intermetal bias in PtRh alloy nanolayer to promote the intrinsic catalytic activity of hydrogen evolution reaction and the lifespan of the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Both experimental and theoretical results revealed the key role of the intermetal bias between Pt and Rh amplified by the rectifying contact with nitrogen&#8208;doped carbons support in accelerating the pre&#8208;enrichment of protons on Rh sites, diffusion of H species from Rh to Pt sites, and final H dissociation from Pt sites. Consequently, the optimized Pt 3 Rh 2 /NC cathode with the most pronounced intermetal bias gives a record&#8208;high mass activity of 282 A mg Pt+Rh &#8722;1 at a cell voltage of 1.8 V in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Moreover, the Pt 3 Rh 2 /NC cathode can reduce the proton diffusion resistance from 0.95 &#937; of Pt/C to 0.69 &#937; at a cell voltage of 1.5 V due to the promoted hydrogen species diffusion on catalyst surface, largely decreasing the cell voltage and extending the lifespan by 3.2 times.</description>
      <author>Shi&#8208;Nan Zhang, Qianyu Liu, Bing&#8208;Liang Leng, Zhongmin Wang, Zhenfeng Zhang, Zhiyong Zhong, Xi Liu, Jie&#8208;Sheng Chen, Xin&#8208;Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202512299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amplifying Intermetal Bias of Pt&#8208;Rh Alloy Nanolayers for Facilitated Hydrogen Inter&#8208;Diffusion and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202512299</link>
      <description>Shi&#8208;Nan Zhang, Qianyu Liu, Bing&#8208;Liang Leng, Zhaowu Wang, Zhenfeng Zhang, Zhiyong Zhong, Xi Liu, Jie&#8208;Sheng Chen, Xin&#8208;Hao Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412883947

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer driven by renewable electricity has been regarded as a sustainable energy production technology, but is greatly limited by the high cost and unsatisfactory durability of noble metal catalysts. Here, we present the proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept application of the amplified intermetal bias in PtRh alloy nanolayer to promote the intrinsic catalytic activity of hydrogen evolution reaction and the lifespan of the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Both experimental and theoretical results revealed the key role of the intermetal bias between Pt and Rh amplified by the rectifying contact with nitrogen&#8208;doped carbons support in accelerating the pre&#8208;enrichment of protons on Rh sites, diffusion of H species from Rh to Pt sites, and final H dissociation from Pt sites. Consequently, the optimized Pt 3 Rh 2 /NC cathode with the most pronounced intermetal bias gives a record&#8208;high mass activity of 282 A mg Pt+Rh &#8722;1 at a cell voltage of 1.8 V in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Moreover, the Pt 3 Rh 2 /NC cathode can reduce the proton diffusion resistance from 0.95 &#937; of Pt/C to 0.69 &#937; at a cell voltage of 1.5 V due to the promoted hydrogen species diffusion on catalyst surface, largely decreasing the cell voltage and extending the lifespan by 3.2 times.</description>
      <author>Shi&#8208;Nan Zhang, Qianyu Liu, Bing&#8208;Liang Leng, Zhaowu Wang, Zhenfeng Zhang, Zhiyong Zhong, Xi Liu, Jie&#8208;Sheng Chen, Xin&#8208;Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202512299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrificial Template&#8208;Derived CoMo&#8208;LDH Gas Diffusion Electrode for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202508370</link>
      <description>Sung Jun Lee, Youngtae Park, Seung Hun Lee, Seo Hyun Park, In Tae Kim, Youngji Kim, Baek San Soh, Geon Hwee Kim, Jooyoung Lee, Seunghwa Lee, Kihyun Shin, Yoo Sei Park, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412887644

                Abstract Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) offers a cost&#8208;effective and efficient platform for hydrogen production by enabling the use of non&#8208;platinum group metal (non&#8208;PGM) electrode materials. However, the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a key challenge. In this study, a CoMo&#8208;LDH OER electrode for AEMWE is developed via a sacrificial template strategy. The high valence state of Mo promotes oxygen vacancy formation, enhancing OER performance. Electrochemical reconstruction also induces a phase transition into active (oxy)hydroxide species during OER. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that the weak OH &#8722; adsorption energy of CoMo&#8208;LDH lowers the energy barrier for OH &#8722; deprotonation, improving catalytic activity. The CoMo&#8208;LDH electrode demonstrates superior performance in AEMWE compared to the PGM&#8208;based IrO 2 electrode. This study highlights the potential of sacrificial template&#8208;based electrodes for high&#8208;performance AEMWE.</description>
      <author>Sung Jun Lee, Youngtae Park, Seung Hun Lee, Seo Hyun Park, In Tae Kim, Youngji Kim, Baek San Soh, Geon Hwee Kim, Jooyoung Lee, Seunghwa Lee, Kihyun Shin, Yoo Sei Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202508370</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the conversion of N 2 to NH 3 bygraphene- supported transition metal catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7179356/v1</link>
      <description>Jiale Liu, Jinqiang Li, Xiao Liu, Wei Song, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412899381

                Abstract NH3 is the most basic raw material in industrial and agricultural production, and it is also an excellent hydrogen carrier, which plays a vital role in the global economy. NH3 synthesis usually adopts the traditional Haber-Bosch method, which not only consumes a lot of energy but also causes damage to the ecological environment. Electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) can produce NH3 at normal temperature and pressure, so it has attracted a lot of attention. In this study, density functional theory was used to calculate the NRR catalytic mechanism and electrocatalytic performance of graphene-supported triatomic metal clusters. The results showed that VMn2@Gra has potential as an NRR catalyst, and the lowest energy barrier simulated was 0.56 eV. Through the analysis of electronic properties, it was found that there was charge transfer between metal and N atom, which further promoted the catalytic process. This study promotes the application of triatomic cluster catalysts in the field of NRR, and these findings provide a new understanding of the theory and experiment of new cluster catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Jiale Liu, Jinqiang Li, Xiao Liu, Wei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7179356/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-template fabrication of a Cu/Fe bimetallic dual-atom catalyst for enhanced ORR activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5qi01160d</link>
      <description>Weihua Tang, Xiaoyu Guo, Yuting Chen, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Kang Liu, Lei Wang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412900622

                We explore a fresh approach for generating Cu/Fe bimetallic dual-atom active sites in N-doped carbon nanosheets (CuFe&#8211;NCN) by utilizing CuTDPAT modified with melamine as a template, resulting in a high-performance pH-universal ORR catalyst.</description>
      <author>Weihua Tang, Xiaoyu Guo, Yuting Chen, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Kang Liu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5qi01160d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Erweiterung des Repertoires an lichtschaltbaren unnat&#252;rlichen Aminos&#228;uren f&#252;r das Enzym&#8208;Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202508562</link>
      <description>Caroline Hiefinger, Michela Marcon, Verena Pape, Guillem Casadevall, Ranit Lahmy, Christoph Haag, Julian Nazet, Michael H. Bartl, Astrid Bruckmann, S&#237;lvia Osuna, Burkhard Koenig, Andrea C. Kneuttinger, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412902559

                Zusammenfassung Lichtschaltbare unnat&#252;rliche Aminos&#228;uren (lsUAs) spielen eine entscheidende Rolle bei der Entwicklung von lichtsensitiven Enzymen, was erhebliches Potenzial f&#252;r vielf&#228;ltige Anwendungen wie Biotherapie und Biokatalyse birgt. Neben einer nahezu quantitativen lichtinduzierten Schaltung bestimmen vor allem das Interaktionspotenzial mit dem Enzym, die thermische Stabilit&#228;t und die effektive Belichtungswellenl&#228;nge den Erfolg und die Eignung einer lsUA f&#252;r eine bestimmte Anwendung. Um eine hohe Vielseitigkeit im aktuell verf&#252;gbaren Repertoire zu etablieren, wurden sechs lsUAs auf Basis von Azobenzol, Arylazopyrazol, Arylazothiazol, Hemithioindigo und Spiropyran entworfen und synthetisiert. Die resultierenden lsUAs weisen ein erweitertes Interaktionspotenzial auf, das auf ihre F&#228;higkeit zur Ausbildung von Wasserstoffbr&#252;ckenbindungen, ionischen Wechselwirkungen und Metallionenkoordination zur&#252;ckzuf&#252;hren ist. Dar&#252;ber hinaus zeigen die lsUAs unterschiedliche photochemische Eigenschaften, wobei vier von ihnen ausschlie&#223;lich mit sichtbarem Licht reversibel zwischen den Isomeren schalten. F&#252;r f&#252;nf der sechs lsUAs konnten jeweils orthogonale Aminoacyl&#8208;tRNA&#8208;Synthetasen identifiziert werden, die den co&#8208;translationalen Einbau in ein Protein erm&#246;glichen. Zus&#228;tzlich dazu wurden die Wechselwirkungen zwischen der Synthetase und der lsUA computergest&#252;tzt analysiert. Schlie&#223;lich wurde das photochemische Verhalten der f&#252;nf lsUAs in einem enzymatischen Modellsystem validiert, wobei deren Eignung zur lichtgesteuerten Regulation enzymatischer Aktivit&#228;t best&#228;tigt werden konnte. Die Ergebnisse zeigen die signifikante Erweiterung des lsUA&#8208;Repertoires und demonstrieren dessen Anwendbarkeit f&#252;r die gezielte Modulation enzymatischer Aktivit&#228;t.</description>
      <author>Caroline Hiefinger, Michela Marcon, Verena Pape, Guillem Casadevall, Ranit Lahmy, Christoph Haag, Julian Nazet, Michael H. Bartl, Astrid Bruckmann, S&#237;lvia Osuna, Burkhard Koenig, Andrea C. Kneuttinger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202508562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the Repertoire of Photoswitchable Unnatural Amino Acids for Enzyme Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202508562</link>
      <description>Caroline Hiefinger, Michela Marcon, Verena Pape, Guillem Casadevall, Ranit Lahmy, Christoph Haag, Julian Nazet, Michael H. Bartl, Astrid Bruckmann, S&#237;lvia Osuna, Burkhard Koenig, Andrea C. Kneuttinger, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412902602

                Abstract Photoswitchable unnatural amino acids (psUAAs) play a crucial role in the engineering of light&#8208;sensitivity in enzymes, which holds significant promise for diverse applications such as biotherapy and biocatalysis. Besides near&#8208;quantitative photoconversion, the success and expediency of a psUAA for a certain application is defined by its interaction potential with the enzyme, its thermal stability and its effective wavelength of irradiation. To establish high versatility in the current repertoire, we have designed and synthesized six psUAAs based on azobenzene, arylazopyrazole, arylazothiazole, hemithioindigo and spiropyran photoswitches. The resulting psUAAs exhibit an enhanced interaction potential within an enzyme owing to their capacity for hydrogen bonding, ionic interactions and metal ion coordination. Moreover, we observed diverse photochemical behaviors among the psUAAs, with four of them reversibly switching between the isomers with purely visible light. Notably, we identified orthogonal aminoacyl&#8208;tRNA synthetases that facilitate the incorporation of five of the six psUAAs co&#8208;translationally and computationally analyzed the synthetase&#8208;psUAA interactions. Finally, we evaluated the photochemical behavior of the five psUAAs within an enzymatic model and tested the photocontrol of catalysis confirming their diversity. Ultimately, our findings significantly expanded the repertoire of psUAAs and demonstrated their feasibility for enzyme engineering studies.</description>
      <author>Caroline Hiefinger, Michela Marcon, Verena Pape, Guillem Casadevall, Ranit Lahmy, Christoph Haag, Julian Nazet, Michael H. Bartl, Astrid Bruckmann, S&#237;lvia Osuna, Burkhard Koenig, Andrea C. Kneuttinger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202508562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Dissolution&#8208;Deposition Equilibrium Enables Unprecedented HER Stability in Acidic PEMWE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202510703</link>
      <description>Zhibin Li, Haonan Zhong, Xiongjun Liu, Fu&#8208;Kuo Chiang, Rui Li, Houwen Chen, Xianzhen Wang, Chubin Wan, Yuan Wu, Hui Wang, Suihe Jiang, Xiaobin Zhang, Zhaoping L&#252;, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412902750

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) holds substantial promise for effectively utilizing renewable energy to produce green hydrogen. However, it faces critical durability challenges due to acid&#8208;driven catalyst degradation under intermittent renewable power. Here, this study reports a dynamic dissolution&#8208;deposition equilibrium that achieves exceptional hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) stability through rational design of a high&#8208;entropy alloy&#8208;derived architecture. Dealloying FeCoNiNbPt HEA creates a porous scaffold with dual&#8208;functional components: an amorphous NbOx buffer suppressing metal dissolution, while multicomponent Pt 3 (FeCoNi) nanocrystals synergistically enhancing HER activity (137 mV@1 A cm &#8722;2 , 2.5 &#215; lower than Pt/C) that thermodynamically favors redeposition. This dynamic self&#8208;adaptive mechanism maintains equilibrium under harsh operating conditions, demonstrating exceptional durability (&gt;2200 h @1 A cm &#8722;2 and 1 000 000 cycles). The self&#8208;supported catalysts can be easily mass&#8208;produced with 8.87 wt.% Pt loading (60% reduction vs Pt/C), indicating its industrial applicability. The equilibrium&#8208;driven design paradigm opens new avenues for industrial proton&#8208;exchange&#8208;membrane devices operating under fluctuating power.</description>
      <author>Zhibin Li, Haonan Zhong, Xiongjun Liu, Fu&#8208;Kuo Chiang, Rui Li, Houwen Chen, Xianzhen Wang, Chubin Wan, Yuan Wu, Hui Wang, Suihe Jiang, Xiaobin Zhang, Zhaoping L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202510703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Active Site Engineering of Nickel Selenides by a Substrate Effect for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202501326</link>
      <description>Pengyan Wang, Zubing Huang, Chao Ding, Qing Li, Jun Lv, Junxiang Feng, Lijun Yang, Haiyan Wang, Meiyan Li, Shiwei Zhang, Shichun Mu, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412907074

                Developing efficient catalysts for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) requires rapid water/hydrogen adsorption/dissociation kinetics. However, challenges remain in reducing energy barriers by simultaneously activating the anionic and cationic sites in a single compound. In this article, a heterogeneous substrate (NiS 2 &#8208;NiS) regulatory strategy is developed to construct dual active sites in NiSe 2 toward the HER. The obtained NiSe 2 /NiS 2 &#8208;NiS electrode delivers excellent catalytic performance, achieving an overpotential of 46 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 under alkaline conditions. Density functional theory calculations demonstrate that the NiS 2 &#8208;NiS heterogeneous substrate induces charge distribution and activates Ni 3d electrons. Combined with in situ Raman spectroscopy analysis, the Ni and Se atoms, as the dual active site for the HER, possess the minimum water adsorption&#8211;dissociation energy barrier and the optimal hydrogen adsorption Gibbs free energy, respectively. This finding provides novel insights into the dual active site engineering for highly efficient catalysts based on the substrate effect.</description>
      <author>Pengyan Wang, Zubing Huang, Chao Ding, Qing Li, Jun Lv, Junxiang Feng, Lijun Yang, Haiyan Wang, Meiyan Li, Shiwei Zhang, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202501326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Electron Microscopy of Zeolites Using Aberration Corrected (S)TEM and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mam/ozaf048.1064</link>
      <description>Tahmid Choudhury, Chen Huang, Aakash Varambhia, Alessandro Turrina, Mervyn D. Shannon, Do&#287;an &#214;zkaya, Angus I. Kirkland, Microscopy and Microanalysis. 31(Supplement_1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412909113

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tahmid Choudhury, Chen Huang, Aakash Varambhia, Alessandro Turrina, Mervyn D. Shannon, Do&#287;an &#214;zkaya, Angus I. Kirkland</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mam/ozaf048.1064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroelectric STO? Tilt and Astigmatism May Lead to Misleading Displacements at Atomic Resolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mam/ozaf048.580</link>
      <description>Sarah J. Stock, Milan Haddad, Seungwon Shin, N. P. Maity, N. D. SHARMA, &#1042;. &#1040;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1073;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1074;, Kristina M. Holsgrove, Amit Kumar, Raymond G. P. McQuaid, S. Lisenkov, I. Ponomareva, Nazanin Bassiri&#8208;Gharb, Lewys Jones, Microscopy and Microanalysis. 31(Supplement_1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412910549

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarah J. Stock, Milan Haddad, Seungwon Shin, N. P. Maity, N. D. SHARMA, &#1042;. &#1040;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1073;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1074;, Kristina M. Holsgrove, Amit Kumar, Raymond G. P. McQuaid, S. Lisenkov, I. Ponomareva, Nazanin Bassiri&#8208;Gharb, Lewys Jones</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mam/ozaf048.580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterointerface Anchored Ir with Localized Strong Orbital Coupling for Durable Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202509985</link>
      <description>Jing Ni, Zhaoping Shi, Jingsen Bai, Mingrui Yu, Xiaohui Liu, Kai Li, Tao Gan, Jiong Li, Di Yang, Minhua Shao, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Xing Wei, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412912074

                Abstract The imperative to minimize iridium usage in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) process presents a pivotal challenge for hydrogen economy deployment, while inherent destabilization of iridium (Ir) active sites under corrosive operational conditions, originating from insufficient Ir bonding strength, remains a fundamental barrier. Here, we resolve this dilemma through heterointerface&#8208;engineered stabilization, where the strategically constructed Nb&#8208;TiO 2 rutile/anatase heterophase homojunction stabilizes Ir sites with enhanced orbital overlap and intensified charge transfer. This atomic&#8208;scale anchoring mechanism, validated by operando characterization and theoretical calculations, strengthens Ir&#9472;O support bonding and optimizes *OOH adsorption energetics, thereby enabling concurrent activity&#8208;stability improvements. The resultant Ir@IrO x /m&#8208;Nb&#8208;TiO 2 anode achieves exceptional PEMWE performance with ultralow loading (0.27 mg Ir cm &#8722;2 ), requiring a low electrolysis voltage of 1.72 V to reach industrial current densities of 2 A cm &#8722;2 , coupled with unprecedented durability with &lt;1.7% voltage decay over 3000 h. This interface design philosophy establishes a general paradigm for developing active and stable supported electrocatalysts for PEMWE and beyond.</description>
      <author>Jing Ni, Zhaoping Shi, Jingsen Bai, Mingrui Yu, Xiaohui Liu, Kai Li, Tao Gan, Jiong Li, Di Yang, Minhua Shao, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Xing Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202509985</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; Fullerene as the Active Site for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202511924</link>
      <description>Si&#8208;Wei Ying, Yuhang Wang, Peng Du, Qiang Wang, Changming Yue, Di Zhang, Zuo&#8208;Chang Chen, Jianwei Zheng, Su&#8208;Yuan Xie, Hao Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412912673

                Abstract Fullerene (C 60 ) was considered as a catalyst promoter in various electrochemical reactions, yet its catalytic role in enhancing catalytic performance beyond electron transfer remains a puzzle to chemists. Traditional simulations imply C 60 &#8217;s inertness in CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) due to weak interaction with COOH* intermediates. Here, according to a pH&#8208;field coupled microkinetic model at reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) scale, we demonstrate that C 60 acts as molecular active sites to facilitate the CO 2 RR toward CO through a strong binding to COOH* in the electrochemical conditions. This binding is mainly due to the unique structure of C 60 that induces large dipole moment changes to stabilize COOH* intermediates across different pH conditions. By detailed comparison of experimental CO 2 RR observations and quantitative pH&#8208;dependent modeling, this work provides new insights on C 60 &#8208;based catalysts, highlighting the large dipole moment change upon adsorption at curved surfaces should not be dismissed when analyzing the pH&#8208;dependent binding strength and electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Si&#8208;Wei Ying, Yuhang Wang, Peng Du, Qiang Wang, Changming Yue, Di Zhang, Zuo&#8208;Chang Chen, Jianwei Zheng, Su&#8208;Yuan Xie, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202511924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the role of Fe and Ni in oxygen evolution reaction on pentlandite using three generations of computational surface models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7096145/v1</link>
      <description>Maksim Sokolov, Kai S. Exner, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412914121

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) &#8211; 2H2O &#8594; O2 + 4H+ + 4e&#8722; &#8211; remains the primary bottleneck in electrochemical water splitting for green hydrogen production. Pentlandite, a bimetallic chalcogenide mineral, has recently shown promise under alkaline conditions, although the elementary processes at the atomic level remain largely unclear. Using density functional theory calculations, we report three generations of pentlandite surface models with varying complexity to decipher the contributions of Fe and Ni sites to OER activity. The first-generation model is based on the pristine pentlandite surface and purports that no OER catalytic activity is observed. The second-generation model takes surface coverage by adsorbed oxygen or hydroxyl into account and suggests that Fe corresponds to the active site in the OER. In contrast, the third-generation model considers not only the surface coverage but also the surface oxidation of pentlandite by exchanging lattice sulfur atoms with oxygen, as observed experimentally. Only this extension shows that both Fe and Ni sites are active centers for OER and that Fe and Ni exhibit distinct limiting steps depending on applied bias, as determined by a degree of span control analysis. Our results demonstrate that when assessing pentlandite with regard to OER, surface oxidation and coverage effects must be explicitly considered in addition to the mechanistic breadth. The reported modeling approach provides the basis for the rational design of next-generation catalysts by highlighting the importance of considering surface oxidation in the theoretical description of energy conversion processes.</description>
      <author>Maksim Sokolov, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7096145/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H2 binding energy may be an auxiliary criterion of H adsorption free energy to estimate hydrogen evolution catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxener.2025.100361</link>
      <description>Chao Kong, Yanxia Han, Lijie Hou, Chao Shuai, Ke Gai, Xiaoli Song, Next Energy. 8(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412917952

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Kong, Yanxia Han, Lijie Hou, Chao Shuai, Ke Gai, Xiaoli Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxener.2025.100361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;organic frameworks based nanostructures for energy conversion and storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-21855-2.00002-7</link>
      <description>Muhammad Waqas Khan, Enamul Haque, Jian Zhen Ou, Nasir Mahmood, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412918995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Waqas Khan, Enamul Haque, Jian Zhen Ou, Nasir Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-21855-2.00002-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compositional Engineering of Ti&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; MXene-NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Hybrid Nanostructures for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01467</link>
      <description>Saeed Sajjadi, Thorsten Schultz, Danielle Douglas-Henry, Karuppasamy Dharmaraj, Aline Alencar Emerenciano, C. Kaplan, Nigel A. Marks, Kai S. Exner, Valeria Nicolosi, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412920300

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saeed Sajjadi, Thorsten Schultz, Danielle Douglas-Henry, Karuppasamy Dharmaraj, Aline Alencar Emerenciano, C. Kaplan, Nigel A. Marks, Kai S. Exner, Valeria Nicolosi, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced ionic conductivity and grain boundary conduction behavior of YSZ-LSGM heterostructure composite electrolyte for SOFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2025.07.023</link>
      <description>Cui Qiao, Jie Yu, Guoqiang Lv, Shaoyuan Li, Jijun Lu, Fengshuo Xi, Zhongqiu Tong, Wenhui Ma, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412921779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cui Qiao, Jie Yu, Guoqiang Lv, Shaoyuan Li, Jijun Lu, Fengshuo Xi, Zhongqiu Tong, Wenhui Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2025.07.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roles of sulfur and nitrogen dopants in tuning cobalt phosphide catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150819</link>
      <description>Meena Rittiruam, Wanaree Suwannatrai, Annop Ektarawong, Tinnakorn Saelee, Wilson Agerico Di&#241;o, Allan Abraham B. Padama, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 163(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412931605

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meena Rittiruam, Wanaree Suwannatrai, Annop Ektarawong, Tinnakorn Saelee, Wilson Agerico Di&#241;o, Allan Abraham B. Padama, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab initio modeling of TWIP and TRIP effects in $$\beta$$-Ti alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1557/s43578-025-01657-w</link>
      <description>David Holec, Johann Grillitsch, Jos&#233; Marques Correia Neves, David Obersteiner, Thomas Klein, Journal of materials research/Pratt's guide to venture capital sources. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412933884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>David Holec, Johann Grillitsch, Jos&#233; Marques Correia Neves, David Obersteiner, Thomas Klein</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1557/s43578-025-01657-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing 1D ionic conductivity in lithium manganese iron phosphate with low-energy optical phonons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-13769-8</link>
      <description>Hyungju Oh, Chanwoo Noh, Ayoung Cho, Jong Chan Kim, N Kim, Kyoung Hoon Kim, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412941056

                Lithium manganese iron phosphate (LMFP) is a promising cathode material for lithium-ion batteries due to its enhanced safety and structural stability. However, its ionic conductivity is limited by the 1D channels within its olivine crystal structure. In this study, we investigate the influence of Mn/Fe atomic configurations on LMFP's ionic conductivity by integrating ab initio density-functional theory (DFT) calculations with molecular dynamics (MD) simulations using graph neural network-based interatomic potentials. Our results show that variations in the Mn/Fe environment around Li ions significantly affect the Li-ion migration barrier and transport mechanisms. Specifically, asymmetric Mn/Fe configurations break Li-site degeneracy and induce a low-energy optical (LEO) phonon mode below 50 cm- 1, enhancing ionic conductivity. This study demonstrates that LMFP's ionic conductivity can be improved by more than 60% when this LEO phonon mode is present. These findings highlight the potential to optimize LMFP cathode performance by employing controlled synthesis methods that exploit favorable atomic configurations, laying the groundwork for accelerating the development of safer and more efficient lithium-ion batteries.</description>
      <author>Hyungju Oh, Chanwoo Noh, Ayoung Cho, Jong Chan Kim, N Kim, Kyoung Hoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-13769-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring of Fe-N-C single atom catalyst's coordination spheres via S-doping for oxygen reduction reaction activity: a DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.115203</link>
      <description>Monika Singh, Dipak K. Das, Anuj Kumar, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. 181(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412950906

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Monika Singh, Dipak K. Das, Anuj Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.115203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High entropy alloys: a comprehensive review of synthesis, properties, and characterization for electrochemical energy conversion and storage applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta03746h</link>
      <description>Selvaganapathy Ganesan, Diksha Bhatt, Divyadharshini Satheesh, Thangavelu Kokulnathan, Pradeep Pant, Devaraj Bharathi, Leena Baskar, Nanda Gopal Sahoo, Arunkumar Palaniappan, Kovendhan Manavalan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412951649

                A comprehensive overview of recent developments in catalysis related to HEAs, focusing on critical areas such as the HER, OER, ORR, hydrogen storage, zinc&#8211;air batteries, and supercapacitors.</description>
      <author>Selvaganapathy Ganesan, Diksha Bhatt, Divyadharshini Satheesh, Thangavelu Kokulnathan, Pradeep Pant, Devaraj Bharathi, Leena Baskar, Nanda Gopal Sahoo, Arunkumar Palaniappan, Kovendhan Manavalan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta03746h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty in Software Development Projects: A Review of Causes, Types, Challenges, and Future Research Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/systems13080650</link>
      <description>Mingqi Zhang, Maxwell Fordjour Antwi&#8208;Afari, Chonghui Wang, Weihao Sun, Saeed Reza Mohandes, Sulemana Fatoama Abdulai, Systems. 13(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412954210

                In a rapidly evolving business landscape, the success of software development (SD) projects is increasingly impacted by uncertainty, which poses significant challenges for project managers. Despite the known influence of uncertainty on project outcomes, its types, causes, and challenges in software remain inadequately understood. This review conducts a systematic analysis of previous related SD projects and related research to clarify these aspects, ultimately identifying key research gaps and proposing future research directions. By adopting a mixed-methods review that integrates scientometric analysis and systematic review methods, this study analysed 60 articles from the Scopus database. The results reported nine causes, six types, and nine challenges associated with uncertainty in SD to provide insights for project managers and researchers in understanding and managing uncertainty more effectively. Additionally, this study proposes four areas for further research to enhance focus and innovation in SD project management.</description>
      <author>Mingqi Zhang, Maxwell Fordjour Antwi&#8208;Afari, Chonghui Wang, Weihao Sun, Saeed Reza Mohandes, Sulemana Fatoama Abdulai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/systems13080650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au&#8208;Modified SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoarray Featuring Enhanced Ultrasound&#8208;Responsive Mott&#8211;Schottky Heterojunction Speeds Bone Regeneration Through Sonodynamic Antibacterial and Inflammatory Management</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202505769</link>
      <description>Zheng Liu, Hong Ding, Huilun Xu, Hao Yang, Jiangshan Liu, Zhendong Zhang, M. Xiao, Limin Liu, Leizhen Huang, Li Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412956225

                Abstract Eradicating the bacteria on the surface of titanium&#8208;based (Ti) implants and optimizing the local immune environment is urgently needed to minimize the clinical implantation failures. Here, an ultrasound (US)&#8208;responsive Ti implant aiming at killing bacteria is prepared by building strontium titanate (SrTiO 3 ) nanoarrays on Ti substrate through a multi&#8208;step hydrothermal method and the subsequent decoration of Au nanoparticles (Au NPs). As an n&#8208;type semiconductor, SrTiO 3 can combine with Au NPs to form a Mott&#8211;Schottky heterostructure. The results reveal that the built&#8208;in electric field of the M&#8211;S heterojunction composed of Au NPs and SrTiO 3 significantly promotes the separation of electrons and holes while reducing the bandgap. Under US irradiation, Au@SrTiO 3 generates a large amount of reactive oxygen species (ROS) to kill bacteria, meanwhile eliminating bacterial biofilms that adhere to the implant surface. Besides, Au NPs accelerate bone remodeling by modulating macrophage polarization toward inflammation&#8208;suppressive orientation. Also, SrTiO 3 and Au NPs synergistically directed the osteogenic differentiation. The implantation in vivo shows that continuously optimizing the osteogenic microenvironment can obviously accelerate the osseointegration of Ti implant. Transcriptomic analysis reveals the in vivo pro&#8208;osteointegration mechanism of heterostructured Au@SrTiO 3 nanoarrays on Ti implant.</description>
      <author>Zheng Liu, Hong Ding, Huilun Xu, Hao Yang, Jiangshan Liu, Zhendong Zhang, M. Xiao, Limin Liu, Leizhen Huang, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202505769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial Ligand Engineering: A Strategy for Promoting Oxygen Reduction Activity of Mn4 Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5358180</link>
      <description>Yamin Wang, Bo Luo, Yumei Yang, Li Chen, Guang&#8208;Jie Xia, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412960577

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yamin Wang, Bo Luo, Yumei Yang, Li Chen, Guang&#8208;Jie Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5358180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials Graph Library (MatGL), an open-source graph deep learning library for materials science and chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01742-y</link>
      <description>Tsz Wai Ko, Bowen Deng, Marcel Nassar, Luis Barroso-Luque, Runze Liu, Ji Qi, Atul C. Thakur, Amiya Kanta Mishra, Eric Hsien Lung Liu, Gerbrand Ceder, Santiago Miret, Shyue Ping Ong, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412974141

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tsz Wai Ko, Bowen Deng, Marcel Nassar, Luis Barroso-Luque, Runze Liu, Ji Qi, Atul C. Thakur, Amiya Kanta Mishra, Eric Hsien Lung Liu, Gerbrand Ceder, Santiago Miret, Shyue Ping Ong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01742-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contribuciones, tendencias y metodolog&#237;as de la Agroecolog&#237;a en la adaptaci&#243;n al cambio clim&#225;tico</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56712/latam.v6i4.4298</link>
      <description>Gisela Ay&#243;n &#193;vila, Jos&#233; Luis Hern&#225;ndez-Hern&#225;ndez, H&#233;ctor Segura Pacheco, Yan Pallac Maldonado Astudillo, Rayma Ireri Maldonado Astudillo, LATAM Revista Latinoamericana de Ciencias Sociales y Humanidades. 6(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412975473

                Este estudio realiz&#243; una revisi&#243;n sistem&#225;tica bajo el protocolo PRISMA, con el objetivo de analizar las contribuciones, tendencias y metodolog&#237;as de las investigaciones cient&#237;ficas para identificar la relaci&#243;n entre la agroecolog&#237;a y la adaptaci&#243;n de las comunidades rurales al cambio clim&#225;tico. La revisi&#243;n abarc&#243; el periodo comprendido entre 2015 y 2025. Se analizaron 72 estudios recuperados en Scopus mediante el software Publish or Perish, de los cuales se filtraron 28 art&#237;culos. La metodolog&#237;a integr&#243; criterios de inclusi&#243;n y clasificaci&#243;n tem&#225;tica. Los hallazgos destacan que la agroecolog&#237;a se considera como una ciencia, un movimiento social y un conjunto de pr&#225;cticas. Su implementaci&#243;n mediante pr&#225;cticas agroecol&#243;gicas y conocimientos ind&#237;genas mejor&#243; la resiliencia agroalimentaria, redujo el impacto ambiental y fortaleci&#243; la justicia social. Las metodolog&#237;as identificadas incluyeron la etnograf&#237;a, los estudios de caso y los enfoques experimentales, aunque se observ&#243; una falta de estandarizaci&#243;n. Se identificaron tendencias hacia la integraci&#243;n de la agroecolog&#237;a con otros enfoques, como la agricultura clim&#225;ticamente inteligente. La revisi&#243;n sugiere que la agroecolog&#237;a representa una alternativa transformadora frente al cambio clim&#225;tico, aunque requiere de sistematizaci&#243;n y articulaci&#243;n pol&#237;tica.</description>
      <author>Gisela Ay&#243;n &#193;vila, Jos&#233; Luis Hern&#225;ndez-Hern&#225;ndez, H&#233;ctor Segura Pacheco, Yan Pallac Maldonado Astudillo, Rayma Ireri Maldonado Astudillo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56712/latam.v6i4.4298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Dynamics of Amorphous Phase in Sriro3 Catalyst During Oxygen Evolution Reaction Revealed by Operando Total X-Ray Scattering Measurements and Pair Distribution Function Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5357066</link>
      <description>Kentaro Kobayashi, Satoshi Hiroi, Koji Ohara, Neha Thakur, Mukesh Kumar, Weijie Cao, Kengo Nakada, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Hiroki Yamada, Seiya Shimono, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yoshiharu Uchimoto, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412978518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kentaro Kobayashi, Satoshi Hiroi, Koji Ohara, Neha Thakur, Mukesh Kumar, Weijie Cao, Kengo Nakada, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Hiroki Yamada, Seiya Shimono, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yoshiharu Uchimoto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5357066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protonated and Dehydrogenated Melamine Adsorptions onto Terrace Planes of Pt: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122817</link>
      <description>Kohei Tada, Shin&#8208;ichi Yamazaki, Masafumi Asahi, Tsutomu Ioroi, Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412978684

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kohei Tada, Shin&#8208;ichi Yamazaki, Masafumi Asahi, Tsutomu Ioroi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive review on the MXene-based catalysts for hydrogen generation via water splitting processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2025.143534</link>
      <description>Kanika Raj, Ramdevsinh Jhala, S. Sujai, Binayak Pattanayak, Jitendra Singh, Parveen Kumar, M. Kaladhar, Rahul Singh, Yashwant Singh Bisht, Anurag Gautam, Journal of Molecular Structure. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412978759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kanika Raj, Ramdevsinh Jhala, S. Sujai, Binayak Pattanayak, Jitendra Singh, Parveen Kumar, M. Kaladhar, Rahul Singh, Yashwant Singh Bisht, Anurag Gautam</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2025.143534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the role of 3d transition metal anchoring on P-termination and doping on Mo-termination of MoP for water splitting catalysis. A DFT investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146953</link>
      <description>Muhammad Rafiq, Wenjuan Xu, Godefroid Gahungu, Wenliang Li, Jingping Zhang, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412978773

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Rafiq, Wenjuan Xu, Godefroid Gahungu, Wenliang Li, Jingping Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered surface oxidation of porous metal substrate for simultaneous enhancement of kinetics and durability in electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138624</link>
      <description>Kang-Min Seo, Gahyeon Lee, J.W. Ra, Hye Ri Kim, Sejin Im, Hyunseob Lim, Changhee Kim, Jong Hoon Joo, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412978842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kang-Min Seo, Gahyeon Lee, J.W. Ra, Hye Ri Kim, Sejin Im, Hyunseob Lim, Changhee Kim, Jong Hoon Joo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-Stabilized Core@Shell NiFe2O4@CoFe2O4 Nanocages for the Integrated Energy and Electroreduction of Nitrate-to-Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125775</link>
      <description>Kasiviswanathan Muthusamy, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Athis Watwiangkham, Ahreum Min, Siriporn Jungsuttiwong, Myong Yong Choi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412980661

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kasiviswanathan Muthusamy, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Athis Watwiangkham, Ahreum Min, Siriporn Jungsuttiwong, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B and Sr co-doping suppressed Pt oxidative passivation enables fast water oxidation in PEMWE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111657</link>
      <description>Jiawei Ge, Hao Wan, Feng Gao, Heyuan Tian, Jiangying Qu, Wang Xian, Junjie Ge, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412981064

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Ge, Hao Wan, Feng Gao, Heyuan Tian, Jiangying Qu, Wang Xian, Junjie Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Formic Acid and Hydrogen Co-electrosynthesis via Engineering Atom Arrangement in Nickel-Boron Interstitials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125773</link>
      <description>Qiuju Li, Hao Sun, Qiaoyu Liu, Guang Yang, Yijing Pian, Xiaotian Li, Zexuan Zheng, Shurong Li, Zhenyu Li, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Haibin Chu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412988531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiuju Li, Hao Sun, Qiaoyu Liu, Guang Yang, Yijing Pian, Xiaotian Li, Zexuan Zheng, Shurong Li, Zhenyu Li, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Haibin Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-dimensional decoupling local electron spin and inner Helmholtz layer roles in MoS2/MoSe2 superlattice photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166707</link>
      <description>Guoliang Zhu, Jagadeesh Suriyaprakash, Guangri Chen, Dapeng Hong, Jiajun Gu, Yanyang Zhang, Lianwei Shan, Huanyan Xu, Xiaojing Li, Haitao Wu, Limin Dong, Shuyan Qi, Xinxin Jin, Gang Liu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412988940

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoliang Zhu, Jagadeesh Suriyaprakash, Guangri Chen, Dapeng Hong, Jiajun Gu, Yanyang Zhang, Lianwei Shan, Huanyan Xu, Xiaojing Li, Haitao Wu, Limin Dong, Shuyan Qi, Xinxin Jin, Gang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomimetic design for zinc-based energy storage devices: principles, challenges and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cs00093a</link>
      <description>Jian Song, Qian Zhang, Guangjie Yang, Kai Qi, Xue Li, Zhenlu Liu, Haoqi Yang, Ho Seok Park, Shaohua Jiang, Jingquan Han, Shuijian He, Bao Yu Xia, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412995324

                An overview summarizes the research status and progress of biomimetic design for zinc-based energy storage devices, analyzes the challenges and proposes future prospects in this field.</description>
      <author>Jian Song, Qian Zhang, Guangjie Yang, Kai Qi, Xue Li, Zhenlu Liu, Haoqi Yang, Ho Seok Park, Shaohua Jiang, Jingquan Han, Shuijian He, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cs00093a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical High-Throughput Screening of Single-Atom CO2 Electroreduction Catalysts to Methanol Using Active Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eng.2025.03.039</link>
      <description>Honghao Chen, Jun Yin, Jiali Li, Xiaonan Wang, Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412999375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Honghao Chen, Jun Yin, Jiali Li, Xiaonan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eng.2025.03.039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of Zero-Dimensional Carbon Allotrope-Encapsulated Ni&#8211;Co Nanoparticles as a Water Splitting Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01627</link>
      <description>Adyasa Priyadarsini, Bhabani S. Mallik, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412999515

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adyasa Priyadarsini, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient separation of CO2/H2 gas mixtures via hydrate-based method driven by tetrafluoroethane and calcium hydroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.134631</link>
      <description>Chuanxiao Cheng, Qianhao Zhang, Yanqiu Xiao, Cheng Yan, Haoran Zhu, Hongjin He, Zhi Shang, Yifei Hou, Zihan Li, Jinhai Zhang, Yunpeng Shang, Fan Wang, Wenfeng Hu, Shiquan Zhu, Hongsheng Dong, Wei Zhang, Lunxiang Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. 378(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413000671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuanxiao Cheng, Qianhao Zhang, Yanqiu Xiao, Cheng Yan, Haoran Zhu, Hongjin He, Zhi Shang, Yifei Hou, Zihan Li, Jinhai Zhang, Yunpeng Shang, Fan Wang, Wenfeng Hu, Shiquan Zhu, Hongsheng Dong, Wei Zhang, Lunxiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.134631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Investigation of Single-Atom Catalysts Anchored on Nitrogen-Doped Two-Dimensional NbSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Highly Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c01839</link>
      <description>Hao Wang, Wei Jin, De-Chuan Sun, Tong Liu, Chang&#8208;Chun Ding, Junshan Hu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413001881

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is a promising approach for CO2 emission reduction, but the development of efficient catalysts remains a major challenge. Here, a series of transition metal/nitrogen-doped NbSe2 (TM@N3-NbSe2) catalysts were selected to systematically investigate the reaction process and catalytic mechanism involved in the conversion of CO2 to methane (CH4) through density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The results indicate that CO2 has two possible adsorption configurations on TM@N3-NbSe2 surfaces, namely, physisorption and chemisorption. During the CO2 chemical adsorption process, a significant amount of charge is transferred from the substrate to CO2, thereby activating the formation of CO2 into a bent structure. In contrast, physically adsorbed CO2 cannot accept electrons from the substrate, resulting in minimal interaction between CO2 and the TM@N3-NbSe2. According to the reaction pathway and limiting potentials, the catalytic activity of TM@N3-NbSe2 for CO2-to-CH4 conversion can be ranked in the following order: Co &gt; Ir &gt; Pd &gt; Cu &gt; Os &gt; Fe &gt; Rh &gt; Pt &gt; Ag &gt; Ru &gt; Ni &gt; Au. Among them, Co@N3-NbSe2 exhibited more prominent catalytic properties, and the free energy change required to be overcome during the conversion of CO2 to CH4 is only 0.22 eV. Most TM@N3-NbSe2 systems exhibit higher selectivity for the CO2RR compared to the hydrogen evolution reaction, making them promising candidates as CO2RR catalysts. This study reveals the mechanism of transition metal and nitrogen codoped two-dimensional materials in CO2RR, which will help to screen high-efficiency catalysts to improve efficiency and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Hao Wang, Wei Jin, De-Chuan Sun, Tong Liu, Chang&#8208;Chun Ding, Junshan Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c01839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomass-Derived Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Supported Mo/Mo2C Heterojunctions with Interfacial Electronic-Activated Carbon Matrix for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182829</link>
      <description>Junjie Gong, Beibei Xiao, Zhenzhen Wang, Pengyue Wang, Yuhang Liu, Shijie Shen, Wenwu Zhong, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413002243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junjie Gong, Beibei Xiao, Zhenzhen Wang, Pengyue Wang, Yuhang Liu, Shijie Shen, Wenwu Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-regulated Schiff base complexes for efficient electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116356</link>
      <description>Siying Wang, Shuaiqi Wang, Qiangwei Li, Leqing Deng, Lidong Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413008181

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siying Wang, Shuaiqi Wang, Qiangwei Li, Leqing Deng, Lidong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work function-induced spontaneous built-in electric field in Ir/MoSe2 for efficient PEM water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64685-7</link>
      <description>Bingjie Zhang, Chunyan Wang, Fulin Yang, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 75(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413011897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingjie Zhang, Chunyan Wang, Fulin Yang, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64685-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous Surface Charging and Janus Nature of the Hexagonal Boron Nitride&#8211;Water Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07827</link>
      <description>Yongkang Wang, Haojian Luo, Xavier R. Advincula, Zhengpu Zhao, Ali Esfandiar, Da Wu, Kara D. Fong, Lei Gao, Arsh S. Hazrah, Takashi Taniguchi, Christoph Schran, Yuki Nagata, Lyd&#233;ric Bocquet, Marie&#8208;Laure Bocquet, Ying Jiang, Angelos Michaelides, Mischa Bonn, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413013444

                Boron, nitrogen, and carbon are neighbors in the periodic table and can form strikingly similar twin structures&#9472;hexagonal boron nitride (hBN) and graphene&#9472;yet nanofluidic experiments demonstrate drastically different water friction on them. We investigate this discrepancy by probing the interfacial water and atomic-scale properties of hBN using surface-specific vibrational spectroscopy, atomic-resolution atomic force microscopy (AFM), and machine learning-based molecular dynamics. Spectroscopy reveals that pristine hBN acquires significant negative charges upon contacting water at neutral pH, unlike hydrophobic graphene, leading to interfacial water alignment and stronger hydrogen bonding. AFM supports that this charging is not defect-induced. pH-dependent measurements suggest OH- chemisorption and physisorption, which simulations validate as two nearly equally stable states undergoing dynamic exchange. These findings challenge the notion of hBN as chemically inert and hydrophobic, revealing its spontaneous surface charging and Janus nature, and providing molecular insights into its higher water friction compared to carbon surfaces.</description>
      <author>Yongkang Wang, Haojian Luo, Xavier R. Advincula, Zhengpu Zhao, Ali Esfandiar, Da Wu, Kara D. Fong, Lei Gao, Arsh S. Hazrah, Takashi Taniguchi, Christoph Schran, Yuki Nagata, Lyd&#233;ric Bocquet, Marie&#8208;Laure Bocquet, Ying Jiang, Angelos Michaelides, Mischa Bonn</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing precious metal concentration in PEMWE anodes catalyst layer through synergistic optimization of morphology and structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150838</link>
      <description>Zeyi Chen, F. M. Zhang, Xuechang Zhou, Haibo Liu, Xiongbo Duan, Zhiqiang Sun, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 164(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413014874

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyi Chen, F. M. Zhang, Xuechang Zhou, Haibo Liu, Xiongbo Duan, Zhiqiang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic study of C1 product formation from CO2 reduction using transition metal clusters-embedded C2N</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147061</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Jiali Liu, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413019478

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Jiali Liu, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating chemical and electronic structure of Ni-based catalysts via introducing heteroatoms for boosting electrochemical oxidation of borohydride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166900</link>
      <description>Ying Yang, Zhihong Cui, Caini Yi, Meilin Chen, Hang Yang, Xiaolong Hou, Guimiao Wang, Shuo Wang, Yuping Liu, Guozhong Cao, Danmei Yu, Xiaoyuan Zhou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413020290

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Yang, Zhihong Cui, Caini Yi, Meilin Chen, Hang Yang, Xiaolong Hou, Guimiao Wang, Shuo Wang, Yuping Liu, Guozhong Cao, Danmei Yu, Xiaoyuan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166900</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Approach to the Free&#8208;Energy Diagram of the Nitrogen Reduction Reaction on Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500196</link>
      <description>Diwakar Singh, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413020893

                Accurate free&#8208;energy landscapes are essential for understanding electrocatalytic processes, especially those involving proton&#8211;coupled electron transfer. While density functional theory (DFT) is widely used to model such reactions, it often introduces significant errors in the computed free energies of gas&#8208;phase reference molecules, leading to inconsistencies in the derivation of the free&#8208;energy changes of the elementary reaction steps. This study presents and compares different correction schemes to address gas&#8208;phase DFT errors. Unlike conventional methods that rely on bond&#8211;order&#8211;based adjustments, this approach reconstructs the formation free energy of target molecules as a linear combination of theoretically determined formation free energies of carefully selected reference molecules. This framework ensures consistency across the reaction network while avoiding dependence on the bond order. This methodology applies to the nitrogen reduction reaction on Mo 2 C(0001) MXene using dispersion&#8211;corrected DFT calculations. The incorporation of gas&#8208;phase corrections significantly reshapes the free&#8208;energy profile and alters catalytic activity descriptors, including the largest free&#8208;energy span of the G max ( U ) descriptor. Findings highlight the importance of thermodynamic accuracy in computational electrocatalysis and provide a generalizable framework that improves the reliability of DFT&#8208;based predictions across a wide range of electrochemical systems for energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Diwakar Singh, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-faceted IrO2 monolayer enabling high-performing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis beyond 10,000 h stability at 1.5 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62665-2</link>
      <description>Deren Yang, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Yue Yang, Yubo Liu, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Shouwei Zuo, Abdullah Tan, Jianguo Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413023898

                Both commercial and laboratory-synthesized IrO2 catalysts typically possess rutile-type structures with multiple facets. Theoretical results predict the (101) facet is the most energetically favorable for oxygen evolution reaction owing to its lowest energy barrier. Achieving monolayer thickness while exposing this desired facet is a significant opportunity for IrO2. Herein, we develop an ammonia-induced facet engineering for the synthesis of single-faceted IrO2(101) monolayer. It achieves 230 mV overpotential at 10 mA cmgeo-2 in a three-electrode system and 1.70 V at 2 A cmgeo-2 in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer. Though facet engineering primarily contributes to modulating the intrinsic activity rather than stability, single-faceted IrO2 monolayer performs over 10,000-hour stability at constant 1.5 A cmgeo-2 (3.95 mV kh-1 decay) and 1000-hour stability at 0.2 mgIr cmgeo-2 under fluctuating conditions. This work proposes that ammonia-induced facet engineering of IrO2 monolayer enables facet-dependent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance and high stability in industrial-scale PEM electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Deren Yang, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Yue Yang, Yubo Liu, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Shouwei Zuo, Abdullah Tan, Jianguo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62665-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volcano&#8208;Type Behavior in Spatially Resolved Electron Transfer and Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Mapping over 2D Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202501169</link>
      <description>Septia Kholimatussadiah, Mohammad Qorbani, Yu&#8208;Chen Liu, R. Raman, Ying&#8208;Ren Lai, Chih&#8208;Yang Huang, Mario Hofmann, Michitoshi Hayashi, Kuei&#8208;Hsien Chen, Li&#8208;Chyong Chen, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413024582

                Abstract In situ mapping of interfacial electron transfer dynamics to reveal electrocatalytic activity with high spatial resolution is crucial for developing efficient electrochemical devices. While emerging 2D materials for catalysis have attracted substantial attention, there is still a notable lack of studies examining their electrochemical properties at the nanoscale, particularly in a layer&#8208;by&#8208;layer context. Here, both outer&#8208;sphere and inner&#8208;sphere electron transfer at a 2D semiconducting WSe 2 electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface are spatially resolved and quantified in high resolution. The investigations reveal that WSe 2 exhibits a volcano&#8208;type behavior in its electrochemical activity, with a peak performance observed at a specific thickness of four layers. This phenomenon is attributed to the interplay between the layer&#8208;specific electronic density of states and the tunneling of charge carriers across the interlayer regions. This observation is further exemplified by micro&#8208;electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction measurements.</description>
      <author>Septia Kholimatussadiah, Mohammad Qorbani, Yu&#8208;Chen Liu, R. Raman, Ying&#8208;Ren Lai, Chih&#8208;Yang Huang, Mario Hofmann, Michitoshi Hayashi, Kuei&#8208;Hsien Chen, Li&#8208;Chyong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202501169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMPERE-2: an open-hardware, robotic platform for automated electrodeposition and electrochemical validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5dd00180c</link>
      <description>Nis Fisker&#8208;B&#248;dker, Daniel Persaud, Yang Bai, Mark Kozdras, Tejs Vegge, Jason Hattrick&#8208;Simpers, Jin Hyun Chang, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413027967

                AMPERE-2 automates electrodeposition and in situ OER catalyst testing. The open-hardware workflow yields reproducible multi-metal catalysts in 65 min per sample.</description>
      <author>Nis Fisker&#8208;B&#248;dker, Daniel Persaud, Yang Bai, Mark Kozdras, Tejs Vegge, Jason Hattrick&#8208;Simpers, Jin Hyun Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5dd00180c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Single&#8208;Atom Catalyst for Efficient C&#9472;S Coupling in Thioether Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202510632</link>
      <description>Theodore A. Gazis, Santi R. Palit, Luis A. Cipriano, Nicol&#242; Allasia, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Martin Sterrer, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413028711

                Abstract Carbon&#8208;heteroatom cross&#8208;coupling reactions have become indispensable tools in synthetic chemistry. However, the formation of carbon&#8211;sulfur (C&#9472;S) bonds, which are essential for producing thioethers used in pharmaceuticals, agrochemicals, and advanced materials, remains significantly underdeveloped. Industrial C&#9472;S coupling methods still rely on expensive, homogeneous catalysts that suffer from poor recyclability and are susceptible to sulfur&#8208;induced deactivation. In this work, we report a copper single&#8208;atom catalyst, where Cu sites are atomically dispersed on mesoporous graphitic carbon nitride, to enable efficient, selective, and recyclable C&#9472;S cross&#8208;coupling reactions under mild conditions and on a gram scale. The catalyst exhibits excellent resistance to thiol poisoning and maintains high performance over multiple catalytic cycles. Advanced characterization techniques, including aberration&#8208;corrected electron microscopy, X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, and single&#8208;atom&#8208;sensitive electron energy loss spectroscopy, confirm the atomic dispersion and stable coordination environment of Cu sites. Combined with density functional theory simulations and radical scavenging experiments, our mechanistic investigations support a concerted oxidative addition pathway, which excludes radical intermediates. These results provide key insights into heterogeneous C&#9472;S coupling and demonstrate the power of single&#8208;atom catalysts in addressing long&#8208;standing challenges in sulfur chemistry, paving the way toward greener and more scalable processes for fine chemical and pharmaceutical synthesis.</description>
      <author>Theodore A. Gazis, Santi R. Palit, Luis A. Cipriano, Nicol&#242; Allasia, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Martin Sterrer, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianvito Vil&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202510632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Single&#8208;Atom Catalyst for Efficient C&#9472;S Coupling in Thioether Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202510632</link>
      <description>Theodore A. Gazis, Santi R. Palit, Luis A. Cipriano, Nicol&#242; Allasia, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Martin Sterrer, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413028712

                Abstract Carbon&#8208;heteroatom cross&#8208;coupling reactions have become indispensable tools in synthetic chemistry. However, the formation of carbon&#8211;sulfur (C&#9472;S) bonds, which are essential for producing thioethers used in pharmaceuticals, agrochemicals, and advanced materials, remains significantly underdeveloped. Industrial C&#9472;S coupling methods still rely on expensive, homogeneous catalysts that suffer from poor recyclability and are susceptible to sulfur&#8208;induced deactivation. In this work, we report a copper single&#8208;atom catalyst, where Cu sites are atomically dispersed on mesoporous graphitic carbon nitride, to enable efficient, selective, and recyclable C&#9472;S cross&#8208;coupling reactions under mild conditions and on a gram scale. The catalyst exhibits excellent resistance to thiol poisoning and maintains high performance over multiple catalytic cycles. Advanced characterization techniques, including aberration&#8208;corrected electron microscopy, X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, and single&#8208;atom&#8208;sensitive electron energy loss spectroscopy, confirm the atomic dispersion and stable coordination environment of Cu sites. Combined with density functional theory simulations and radical scavenging experiments, our mechanistic investigations support a concerted oxidative addition pathway, which excludes radical intermediates. These results provide key insights into heterogeneous C&#9472;S coupling and demonstrate the power of single&#8208;atom catalysts in addressing long&#8208;standing challenges in sulfur chemistry, paving the way toward greener and more scalable processes for fine chemical and pharmaceutical synthesis.</description>
      <author>Theodore A. Gazis, Santi R. Palit, Luis A. Cipriano, Nicol&#242; Allasia, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Martin Sterrer, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianvito Vil&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202510632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indirect Heteroatom Doping of TMN4 Single Atom Catalysts for Bifunctional ORR/OER Electrocatalysis: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113505</link>
      <description>Zeyu Wang, Lili Sun, Wolong Li, Junda Qin, Yongcun Li, Yong Wang, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413031099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyu Wang, Lili Sun, Wolong Li, Junda Qin, Yongcun Li, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular bridge-reshaped interfacial water configuration on oxygen-deficient silica for robust electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166863</link>
      <description>Minxia Jiang, Yingjie Hu, Jie Zhu, Wen Wei, Shuaifeng Wang, Zhen Yang, Jie Wang, Xiaowan Zhan, Ying Wang, Minhua Cao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413031474

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minxia Jiang, Yingjie Hu, Jie Zhu, Wen Wei, Shuaifeng Wang, Zhen Yang, Jie Wang, Xiaowan Zhan, Ying Wang, Minhua Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into electrocatalytic urea synthesis on graphdiyne-supported transition metal-boron triatomic clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164202</link>
      <description>Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Aling Ma, Yukun Han, Zhenzhen Wang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413032259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Aling Ma, Yukun Han, Zhenzhen Wang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Synergism in Boron Interstitial Doping Ordered Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co Nanoparticles Enhances the Protonation Process: Application to Efficient Oxygen Reduction in Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503590</link>
      <description>Guangrui Xu, Xinyuan Zhou, Miao Yu, Baolin Jiang, Qiyan Sun, Zexing Wu, Bin Li, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413038207

                Abstract Ordered intermetallic Pt 3 Co compounds are highly promising alloy materials for oxygen electrocatalysis, while the sluggish kinetics and high cost of Pt still hinder their wide use in practical applications. In this work, boron atom gap&#8208;doped Pt 3 Co nanoparticles loaded on carbon nanobowls (B&#8208;Pt 3 Co/CNBs) are obtained to enhance the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance. The introduction of B atoms is responsible for the negative shift of the d&#8208;band center compared to Pt 3 Co, and the subsequent reduction process leads to the uniform loading of B&#8208;Pt 3 Co nanoparticles on hollow carbon nanobowls. It is demonstrated that B&#8208;Pt 3 Co/CNBs exhibit the best electrocatalytic performance for ORR with an onset potential of 1.095 V versus RHE and a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.985 versus RHE, as well as robust electrocatalytic stability with negligible activity decay even after 50 000 cycles. Experimental and theoretical calculations show that the introduction of the highly electronegative metalloid B leads the Pt atoms to lose electrons, which changes the electronic structure of Pt 3 Co that can weaken the bonding strength of Pt&#8208;O and accelerate the protonation and desorption of O* on the surface of the B&#8208;Pt 3 Co/ CNB, reducing the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step during the ORR process.</description>
      <author>Guangrui Xu, Xinyuan Zhou, Miao Yu, Baolin Jiang, Qiyan Sun, Zexing Wu, Bin Li, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pH&#8208;Dependent Electroreduction of Nitrate on Fe Single&#8208;Atom Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202500717</link>
      <description>Zhen Meng, Adyasa Priyadarsini, Kaige Shi, Zhuanghe Ren, Deepak Prasad Subedi, Daniel W. Israel, William E. Kaden, Xiaofeng Feng, Shyam Kattel, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413044311

                Electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) has received considerable attention due to its potential for the denitrification of wastewater and sustainable NH 3 production. Among various catalysts for NO 3 RR, Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C single&#8208;atom catalyst has attracted significant interest due to its well&#8208;defined active sites and high stability across various media. Here, we investigate the pH dependence of NO 3 RR on Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C by combining experiments and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C catalyst achieves high activity and &gt;80% Faradaic efficiency for NH 3 production in the NO 3 RR across acidic, neutral, and alkaline electrolytes, while the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) exhibits the strongest competition with NO 3 RR in alkaline electrolyte. DFT calculations identify the NHO*&#8208;mediated pathway as the most favorable for NO 3 RR on Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C and further reveal the pH dependence of the potential&#8208;determining steps for both NO 3 RR and HER, elucidating the origin of the pH&#8208;dependent selectivity. Our studies provide new mechanistic insights into the NO 3 RR on single&#8208;atom catalysts and guide the design of broad pH&#8208;range electrocatalysts for efficient and versatile nitrate recycling.</description>
      <author>Zhen Meng, Adyasa Priyadarsini, Kaige Shi, Zhuanghe Ren, Deepak Prasad Subedi, Daniel W. Israel, William E. Kaden, Xiaofeng Feng, Shyam Kattel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202500717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of carboxymethyl chitosan chain length on its interaction with vitamin C and curcumin: molecular docking and molecular dynamic approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06458-w</link>
      <description>Nabela Audryna Amalia Insani, Nurwarrohman Andre Sasongko, Suci Zulaikha Hildayani, Dwi Hudiyanti, Khairul Anam, Daniel Sethio, Vivitri Dewi Prasasty, Parsaoran Siahaan, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 31(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413029349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nabela Audryna Amalia Insani, Nurwarrohman Andre Sasongko, Suci Zulaikha Hildayani, Dwi Hudiyanti, Khairul Anam, Daniel Sethio, Vivitri Dewi Prasasty, Parsaoran Siahaan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06458-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CO&#8322; adsorption kinetics in direct air capture: The role of steam desorption in amine-based anion exchange sorbents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2025.103184</link>
      <description>Florian M. Chimani, Josef Fuchs, Andreas Wallm&#252;ller, Jean Pierre Matriciani, Gerhard Sch&#246;ny, Stefan M&#252;ller, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 100(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413046267

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Florian M. Chimani, Josef Fuchs, Andreas Wallm&#252;ller, Jean Pierre Matriciani, Gerhard Sch&#246;ny, Stefan M&#252;ller</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2025.103184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy-driven coordination field modulating electron spin state for enhanced bidirectional polysulfide conversion in lithium-sulfur batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.065</link>
      <description>Kangdong Tian, Ruifeng Li, Miaofa Yuan, Jiafeng Li, Chengxiang Wang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412980381

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kangdong Tian, Ruifeng Li, Miaofa Yuan, Jiafeng Li, Chengxiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dual Subsurface Hydrogen (2H&#8217;) Mechanism for Ethylene Hydrogenation on Pd</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02240</link>
      <description>Nicholas Golio, Andrew J. Gellman, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413040709

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicholas Golio, Andrew J. Gellman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02240</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
