<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 01:09:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Photothermal RuNiFeOx/FeNi3 heterostructured arrays with Janus wettability for highly enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132368</link>
      <description>Lunhong Ai, Yao Tian, Tiancun Xiao, Jiayi Zhang, Chenghui Zhang, Jing Jiang, Fuel. 373(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400267754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lunhong Ai, Yao Tian, Tiancun Xiao, Jiayi Zhang, Chenghui Zhang, Jing Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances, mechanisms and applications in oxygen evolution electrocatalysis of gold-driven</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153719</link>
      <description>Tong Liu, Jiangbo Lu, Zhihao Chen, Zhihong Luo, Yurong Ren, Xiangqun Zhuge, Zhihong Luo, Guogang Ren, Lei Wei-Wei, Dan Li&#250;, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400269040

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role in electrochemical energy storage and conversion. Among different metal elements, gold (Au) stands out due to its high electronegativity and remarkable catalytic properties, especially when it is in nanoscale size. In this review, we aim to comprehensively analyze the oxygen electrocatalytic performance of nanosized Au, including the influence of the crystal surface, morphology, substrate materials of Au nanoparticles, size and ligands of Au nanoclusters, and Au single atoms on oxygen electrocatalysis. By exploring the catalytic performance of noble metals, non-noble metals, oxides, hydroxides/oxyhydroxides/layered double hydroxides, sulfides, phosphides, nitrides, and selenides through the integration of nanosized Au, which offers valuable insights for enhancing the OER efficiency. These effects can be attributed to two mechanisms: i) adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) and ii) lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM), where the nanosized Au changed the electronic structure of the catalysts and improved the adsorption of reaction intermediates to accelerate electron transfer process or exerts the synergistic effect between metallic Au and oxygen vacancies. For instance, Gold-driven OER catalysts can be widely used in zinc-air batteries and water splitting in the future.</description>
      <author>Tong Liu, Jiangbo Lu, Zhihao Chen, Zhihong Luo, Yurong Ren, Xiangqun Zhuge, Zhihong Luo, Guogang Ren, Lei Wei-Wei, Dan Li&#250;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153719</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in selenide-based electrocatalysts for hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction: From mechanism and synthesis to application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101641</link>
      <description>Yunlong Zhang, Ying&#8208;Bing Jiang, Abdukader Abdukayum, Xusheng Xie, Sanshuang Gao, Xijun Liu, L. Zhang, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400269924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunlong Zhang, Ying&#8208;Bing Jiang, Abdukader Abdukayum, Xusheng Xie, Sanshuang Gao, Xijun Liu, L. Zhang, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering both intrinsic characteristic and local microenvironment of platinum sites toward highly efficient oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.012</link>
      <description>Haibin Wang, Chunlei Li, Mengling Liu, Di Dou, L. Chen, Limin Zhang, Qiuping Zhao, Yuanyuan Cong, Yi Wang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400271700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Wang, Chunlei Li, Mengling Liu, Di Dou, L. Chen, Limin Zhang, Qiuping Zhao, Yuanyuan Cong, Yi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948; and its catalytic oxidation of NO and its reaction path</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e33580</link>
      <description>Yige Guo, Xiaoxue Niu, Huaiyu Yang, Liwen Chen, Yi Ren, Hao Guo, Bo Wu, Heliyon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400278855

                The oxidation rate of NO to NO2 is a critical parameter in the removal of NOx within selective catalytic reduction (SCR) systems. LaCoO3-&#948; is a kind of potential catalyst to enhance the oxidation of NO to NO2, it may offers an economic and stable alternative to noble metal catalysts, particularly at elevated temperatures. This study aimed to enhance the catalytic efficiency of LaCoO3-&#948; through strontium (Sr) doping. La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948; (with varying x values of 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, 0.4) was synthesized using a sol-gel method. La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948; exhibited superior NO oxidation catalytic activity compared to LaCoO3-&#948;, with the most notable enhancement observed at x = 0.3 (84% conversion). This improvement can be attributed to the substitution of La3+ with Sr2+, which induces lattice distortion and charge imbalance, thereby creating more oxygen vacancies that enhance the catalytic oxidation capability of La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948;. However, it's important to note that an excessive amount of Sr can result in the formation of SrCO3 deposits on the surface of La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948;, thereby diminishing its catalytic oxidation performance. The catalytic oxidation reaction behavior adhered most closely to the O2-adsorbed E-R model, the surface defects in La1-xSrxCoO3-&#948; playing a pivotal role in the catalytic reaction.</description>
      <author>Yige Guo, Xiaoxue Niu, Huaiyu Yang, Liwen Chen, Yi Ren, Hao Guo, Bo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e33580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic enhancement of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction by role of Ni-Fe LDH introducing frustrated Lewis pairs via vacancy-engineered</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110199</link>
      <description>M. Li, Haozhi Wang, Zijun Yang, Zhiping Yin, Yuan Liu, Yingmei Bian, Yang Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400279219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Li, Haozhi Wang, Zijun Yang, Zhiping Yin, Yuan Liu, Yingmei Bian, Yang Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some remaining puzzles in hydrogen electrocatalysis mechanisms on platinum surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.002</link>
      <description>Shangqian Zhu, X.M. Liu, Xuesi Wang, Qinglan Zhao, Minhua Shao, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400281751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shangqian Zhu, X.M. Liu, Xuesi Wang, Qinglan Zhao, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cobalt&#8211;Platinum&#8211;Ruthenium System for Acidic Methanol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01008</link>
      <description>Hai Tao Xu, Daoyuan Zheng, Haldrian Iriawan, Jen-Hung Fang, Junghwa Kim, Xiao Wang, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Ju Li, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Chemistry of materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400283865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hai Tao Xu, Daoyuan Zheng, Haldrian Iriawan, Jen-Hung Fang, Junghwa Kim, Xiao Wang, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Ju Li, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coverage-dependent activation of CO over Ni/Cu(100) single atom alloys (SAAs)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213809</link>
      <description>Wu Meng, Ling Zhao Li, Ruijiao Zhao, Yu Liu, X.D. Wang, Han&#8208;Yue Qiu, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 161(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400294030

                Single atom alloys (SAAs) often bring new chemistry in heterogeneous catalysis and well-defined structure for the study of structure&#8211;activity relationship (SAR). However, the existing pressure gap causes the reported SARs quite divergent. Herein, we have studied CO activation over Ni/Cu(100) SAAs in ultrahigh vacuum (UHV) and millibar range. While the Ni SAAs formed on Cu(100) significantly enhance the CO adsorption strength under UHV conditions, the CO treatment at elevated pressure leads to notable surface carbon and oxygen deposition through surface reaction. Density functional theory calculations revealed that either dissociation or disproportionation is thermodynamically forbidden for the coverage of CO less than 5/16 ML. However, these two reaction pathways can be opened at higher CO coverages due to the elevated energy state involving repulsion between adsorbed CO. This work uncovers the initial activation process of CO and demonstrates one typical cause for the pressure gap in surface science study as well.</description>
      <author>Wu Meng, Ling Zhao Li, Ruijiao Zhao, Yu Liu, X.D. Wang, Han&#8208;Yue Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0213809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated workflows and interfaces for data-driven semi-empirical electronic structure calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0209742</link>
      <description>P. V. Stishenko, Adam McSloy, Berk Onat, B. Hourahine, Reinhard J. Maurer, James R. Kermode, Andrew J. Logsdail, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 161(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400294489

                Modern software engineering of electronic structure codes has seen a paradigm shift from monolithic workflows toward object-based modularity. Software objectivity allows for greater flexibility in the application of electronic structure calculations, with particular benefits when integrated with approaches for data-driven analysis. Here, we discuss different approaches to create deep modular interfaces that connect big-data workflows and electronic structure codes and explore the diversity of use cases that they can enable. We present two such interface approaches for the semi-empirical electronic structure package, DFTB+. In one case, DFTB+ is applied as a library and provides data to an external workflow; in another, DFTB+receives data via external bindings and processes the information subsequently within an internal workflow. We provide a general framework to enable data exchange workflows for embedding new machine-learning-based Hamiltonians within DFTB+ or enabling deep integration of DFTB+ in multiscale embedding workflows. These modular interfaces demonstrate opportunities in emergent software and workflows to accelerate scientific discovery by harnessing existing software capabilities.</description>
      <author>P. V. Stishenko, Adam McSloy, Berk Onat, B. Hourahine, Reinhard J. Maurer, James R. Kermode, Andrew J. Logsdail</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0209742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity-Selectivity Trade-off in Propane Dehydrogenation: Pt&#8211;C Repulsion is the Essence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01253</link>
      <description>Xin Chang, Lyudmila V. Moskaleva, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400294516

                While linear scaling relationships have made enormous progress in the computational design of new catalysts, the simultaneous enhancement or weakening of adsorbates for a specific reaction leads to an activity-selectivity trade-off. Focusing on the important industrial reaction, propane dehydrogenation, strategies to break linear scaling relationships have been established to maintain activity with increased selectivity. Nonetheless, elucidating the essential reason for generating the trade-off in propane dehydrogenation from electronic and geometric aspects is still elusive. Moreover, it remains uncertain whether the modified catalyst is restricted by another trade-off. This work begins by examining the effect of electronic regulation on the activity-selectivity trade-off and reveals that either too weak or too strong Pt&#8211;C repulsion is the essence of this trade-off. When geometric modulation is introduced, the alloy exhibiting similar Pt&#8211;C repulsion to Pt maintains catalytic activity with remarkably improved selectivity. However, despite establishing a better scaling relationship through geometric modulation, the activity-selectivity trade-off still exists with Pt&#8211;C repulsion as its essence.</description>
      <author>Xin Chang, Lyudmila V. Moskaleva, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in Ni-based catalysts for the electrochemical oxidation of ethanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.06.045</link>
      <description>Xin Tan, Shiming Chen, Dafeng Yan, Ruixing Du, Qitong Zhong, Longfei Liao, Zhenchen Tang, Feng Zeng, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400299514

                The electrochemical ethanol oxidation reaction (EOR) plays a crucial role in electrochemical hydrogen production and direct ethanol fuel cells, both vital for utilizing renewable energies. Ni-based catalysts are pivotal in enabling efficient EOR, leading to the formation of acetic acid/acetaldehyde or CO2. These can serve as alternative anodic oxidation reactions for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water electrolysis or the anodic reaction for direct ethanol fuel cells, respectively. This review explores recent advancements in EOR over Ni-based catalysts. It begins with an overview of EOR performance across various Ni-based catalysts, followed by an examination of the reaction chemistry, mechanism, and active sites. The review then delves into strategies for designing highly active Ni-based EOR catalysts. These strategies include promotion with transition metals, noble metals, nonmetals, and carbon materials, as well as creating amorphous structures, special morphologies, and single-atom catalysts. Additionally, it discusses the concept of self-supporting catalysts using three-dimensional porous substrates. Finally, the review highlights emerging methodologies that warrant further exploration, along with future directions for designing highly active and stable EOR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xin Tan, Shiming Chen, Dafeng Yan, Ruixing Du, Qitong Zhong, Longfei Liao, Zhenchen Tang, Feng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.06.045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxyl Group Modification Improves the Selectivity of Metal Single Atom on Poly(Heptazine Imide) for Electrocatalytic Acetylene Semi-Hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4885298</link>
      <description>Xiaoxiao Chen, Yang Li, Yaofeng Yuan, Wei Lin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400315165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxiao Chen, Yang Li, Yaofeng Yuan, Wei Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4885298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing the relationship between the activity and stability of anode oxide-based electrocatalysts in acid for PEMWE electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02869d</link>
      <description>Yingying Xu, Yingxia Zhao, Zihui Yuan, Yue Sun, Shaomin Peng, Yuanhong Zhong, Ming Sun, Lin Yu, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400320837

                This review covers advancements in noble and non-noble metal oxides for acidic OER, emphasizing the evaluation of catalyst instability, and strategies to enhance IrO 2 , RuO 2 , and TM oxides.</description>
      <author>Yingying Xu, Yingxia Zhao, Zihui Yuan, Yue Sun, Shaomin Peng, Yuanhong Zhong, Ming Sun, Lin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02869d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Ammonia Yield Rate from Dilute Nitrate Solutions Using a Cu(100)-Rich Foil: A Step Closer to Large-Scale Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05818</link>
      <description>Abhishek Garg, Arunava Saha, Supriti Dutta, Swapan K. Pati, M. Eswaramoorthy, C. N. R. Rao, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400321361

                The electrochemical reduction of nitrate (NO3&#8211;) ions to ammonia (NH3) provides an alternative method to eliminate harmful NO3&#8211; pollutants in water as well as to produce highly valuable NH3 chemicals. The NH3 yield rate however is still limited to the &#956;mol h&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 range when dealing with dilute NO3&#8211; concentrations found in waste streams. Copper (Cu) has attracted much attention because of its unique ability to effectively convert NO3&#8211; to NH3. We have reported a simple and scalable electrochemical method to produce a Cu foil having its surface covered with a porous Cu nanostructure enriched with (100) facets, which efficiently catalyzes NO3&#8211; to NH3. The Cu(100)-rich electrocatalyst showed a very high NH3 production rate of 1.1 mmol h&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 in NO3&#8211; concentration as low as 14 mM NO3&#8211;, which is 4&#8211;5 times higher than the best-reported values. Increasing the NO3&#8211; concentration (140 mM) resulted in an NH3 production yield rate of 3.34 mmol h&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2. The durability test conducted for this catalyst foil in a flow cell system showed greater than 100 h stability with a Faradaic efficiency greater than 98%, demonstrating its potential to be used on an industrially relevant scale. Further, density functional theory (DFT) calculations have been performed to understand the better catalytic activity of Cu(100) compared to Cu(111) facets toward NO3&#8211;RR.</description>
      <author>Abhishek Garg, Arunava Saha, Supriti Dutta, Swapan K. Pati, M. Eswaramoorthy, C. N. R. Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulated Reaction Route for Oxyhydroxides toward Top&#8208;Performing Water Oxidation via &lt;i&gt;e&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;g&lt;/sub&gt; Electron Filling State</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405474</link>
      <description>Na Yao, Na Luo, Shan Jiang, Aofei Cai, Wei Pi, Xing Wang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400323980

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity on transition metal (TM) catalysts is governed by OER mechanism, yet discovering a controllable parameter to custom&#8208;tailor OER mechanism remains a challenge. Here, the study highlights an e g electron&#8208;filling state in octahedral TM&#8208;catalysts, achieved by the modulation of splitting energy (&#916;) via different anions (R) (Cl &#8722; , PO 4 3&#8722; , NO 3 &#8722; , F &#8722; , SO 4 2&#8722; , CO 3 2&#8722; ). The e g &#8208; electron filling state customization predominantly arises from the adjustment of Co&#8208; d z 2 orbital energy, which can tailor the bandgap between Co&#8208; d z 2 and O&#8208; p orbits (&#916;&#949; d&#8208;p ), thus customizing lattice&#8208;oxygen (O L ) activities and the OER mechanism. Combining the experimental measurements with DFT calculations, it is concluded that increased e g electron in TM&#8208;catalysts brings decreased &#916;&#949; d&#8208;p , which can manageably strengthen lattice&#8208;oxygen reactivity. Consequently, the OER mechanism on TM catalyst is transformed from adsorbate precipitation mechanism (AEM) to lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) and customized OER pathways with different lattice&#8208;oxygen activities. The screened PO 4 3&#8208;_ TM, with the optimal O L activity in LOM path, possesses excellent activity and stability, achieving a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at 236 mV overpotential and maintaining stable operation for 300 h with inapparent degradation at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Na Yao, Na Luo, Shan Jiang, Aofei Cai, Wei Pi, Xing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Structure Prediction for Battery Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-47303-6_7</link>
      <description>Ziheng Lu, Bonan Zhu, Topics in applied physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400330694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziheng Lu, Bonan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-47303-6_7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Investigation on the Nitrogen Reduction Mechanism in Two-Dimensional Transition-Metal Boride with Ordered Metal Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00951</link>
      <description>L.-C. Ma, Xianfei Chen, Yi Huang, Peicong Zhang, Beibei Xiao, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400330812

                The creation of ordered collective vacancies in experiment proves challenging within a two-dimensional lattice, resulting in a limited understanding of their impact on catalyst performance. Motivated by the successful experimental synthesis of monolayer molybdenum borides with precisely ordered metal vacancies [Zhou et al. Science 2021, 373, 801&#8211;805] through dealloying, the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) in monolayer borides was systematically investigated to elucidate the influence of such ordered metal vacancies on catalytic reactions and the underlying mechanisms. The results reveal that the N-containing intermediates tend to dissociate, facilitating the NRR process with reduced UL. The emergence of ordered metal vacancies modulates the electronic properties of the catalyst and partially facilitates the decomposition of N-containing intermediates. However, the UL for NRR in Mo4/3B2 and W4/3B2 exhibits a significant increase. The compromised electrochemical performance is explained through the development of a simple electronic descriptor of the d&#8211;p band center (&#916;dM&#8211;pB). Among these materials, Mo4/3Sc2/3B2 exhibits the most superior catalytic activity with a UL of &#8722;0.5 V and favorable NRR selectivity over the HER. Our results provide mechanistic insights into the role of ordered metal vacancies in transition-metal boride for the NRR and highlight a novel avenue toward the rational design of superior NRR catalysts.</description>
      <author>L.-C. Ma, Xianfei Chen, Yi Huang, Peicong Zhang, Beibei Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00951</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab Initio Interfacial Electrochemistry Applied to Understanding, Tuning and Designing Battery Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-47303-6_3</link>
      <description>Arthur Hagopian, Anja Kopa&#269; Lautar, Jean&#8208;S&#233;bastien Filhol, Topics in applied physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400331032

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arthur Hagopian, Anja Kopa&#269; Lautar, Jean&#8208;S&#233;bastien Filhol</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-47303-6_3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic stability of Pt-based alloys for fuel-cell catalysts calculated from atomistics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00463a</link>
      <description>Shubham Sharma, Cheng Zeng, Andrew A. Peterson, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400332737

                New atomistic models dissect dissolution, near-surface, and bulk diffusion, elevating Pt-alloy catalyst's stability analysis.</description>
      <author>Shubham Sharma, Cheng Zeng, Andrew A. Peterson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00463a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Strain&#8208;Induced Noble Metal Nanohybrids for Electro&#8208;catalysis: From Theoretical Mechanisms to Practical Use</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400154</link>
      <description>Zhaoyang Chen, Lingtong Li, Fujun Zhao, Yinghong Zhu, Youqun Chu, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400336100

                Abstract In response to the climate goal of achieving carbon neutrality by 2050, efficient electrochemical energy conversion devices are garnering increasing attention. However, the enhancement of electrochemical performance using noble metal electrocatalysts, along with cost reduction and electrode fabrication, remain significant challenges. Noble metal hybrid nanostructures, possessing multiple surface functionalities, lead to outstanding electrocatalytic performances and low&#8208;cost potential. Strain effects can bolster the bonding strength between the noble metal layers and the substrate or core layers, while simultaneously affecting electrocatalytic performance through tuning the binding strength between catalytically active sites and reactants, including intermediates. This review encapsulates the research efforts directed towards improving the performance of noble metal electrocatalysts and provides an overview of the latest advancements in controlling the surface state of noble metals by incorporating a secondary component. We discuss systematic approaches to adjusting surface strain effects on noble metals, characterization techniques, and application case studies, while extracting key design indicators for readers to consider from a macroscopic perspective. Further, we outline the challenges encountered and current solutions when advancing noble metal catalysts from theoretical mechanisms to practical use. Finally, the perspectives on the future research of noble metal surface layer control techniques were also provided.</description>
      <author>Zhaoyang Chen, Lingtong Li, Fujun Zhao, Yinghong Zhu, Youqun Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Intrinsic Mechanism of High-Performance Two-Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for ORR/OER through Theoretical Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00961</link>
      <description>Xiaofei Wei, Shoufu Cao, Shaohua Cheng, Chunyu Lu, Xinhui Chen, Xiaoqing Lu, Xiaobo Chen, Fangna Dai, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400346361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaofei Wei, Shoufu Cao, Shaohua Cheng, Chunyu Lu, Xinhui Chen, Xiaoqing Lu, Xiaobo Chen, Fangna Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure- and Morphology-Controlled Synthesis of Hexagonal Ni&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Zn&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;P Nanocrystals and Their Composition-Dependent Electrocatalytic Activity for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00539</link>
      <description>Lisa S. Graves, Rajib Sarkar, J. E. Baker, Ka Un Lao, Indika U. Arachchige, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400346688

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lisa S. Graves, Rajib Sarkar, J. E. Baker, Ka Un Lao, Indika U. Arachchige</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile and Scalable Colloidal Synthesis of Transition Metal Dichalcogenide Nanoparticles with High-Performance Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04968</link>
      <description>Jing Li, Angelika Wrzesi&#324;ska&#8208;Lashkova, Marielle Deconinck, M.W. Gobel, Yana Vaynzof, Vladimir Lesnyak, Alexander Eychm&#252;ller, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400350027

                Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) have garnered significant attention as efficient electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to their high activity, stability, and cost-effectiveness. However, the development of a convenient and economical approach for large-scale HER applications remains a persistent challenge. In this study, we present the successful synthesis of TMD nanoparticles (including MoS</description>
      <author>Jing Li, Angelika Wrzesi&#324;ska&#8208;Lashkova, Marielle Deconinck, M.W. Gobel, Yana Vaynzof, Vladimir Lesnyak, Alexander Eychm&#252;ller</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arc plasma&#8208;deposited Co single&#8208;atom catalysts supported on an aligned carbon nanofiber for hydrogen peroxide electrosynthesis and an electro&#8208;Fenton process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.582</link>
      <description>Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Sooyeon Kim, Ki Ro Yoon, Thao Thi Le, Chinh V. Hoang, Jae Won Choi, Wenjun Zhang, Sae Yane Paek, Chung Hyeon Lee, Ji Hyun Lee, Keun Hwa Chae, Sohee Jeong, Seung&#8208;Yong Lee, Byeong&#8208;Kwon Ju, Sang Hoon Kim, Sang Soo Han, Jong Min Kim, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400359072

                Abstract Atomically dispersed single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) on carbon supports show great promise for H 2 O 2 electrosynthesis, but conventional wet chemistry methods using particulate carbon blacks in powder form have limited their potential as two&#8208;electron (2e &#8722; ) oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts. Here, we demonstrate high&#8208;performance Co SACs supported on a free&#8208;standing aligned carbon nanofiber (CNF) using electrospinning and arc plasma deposition (APD). Based on the surface oxidation treatment of aligned CNF and precise control of the deposition amount in a dry&#8208;based APD process, we successfully form densely populated Co SACs on aligned CNF. Through experimental analyses and density functional theory calculations, we reveal that Co SAC has a Co&#8211;N 2 &#8211;O 2 moiety with one epoxy group, leading to excellent 2e &#8722; ORR activity. Furthermore, the aligned CNF significantly improves mass transfer in flow cells compared to randomly oriented CNF, showing an overpotential reduction of 30 mV and a 1.3&#8208;fold improvement (84.5%) in Faradaic efficiency, and finally achieves an outstanding production rate of 15.75 mol g cat &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 at 300 mA cm &#8722;2 . The high&#8208;performance Co SAC supported on well&#8208;aligned CNF is also applied in an electro&#8208;Fenton process, demonstrating rapid removal of methylene blue and bisphenol F due to its exceptional 2e &#8722; ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Sooyeon Kim, Ki Ro Yoon, Thao Thi Le, Chinh V. Hoang, Jae Won Choi, Wenjun Zhang, Sae Yane Paek, Chung Hyeon Lee, Ji Hyun Lee, Keun Hwa Chae, Sohee Jeong, Seung&#8208;Yong Lee, Byeong&#8208;Kwon Ju, Sang Hoon Kim, Sang Soo Han, Jong Min Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curvature-Dependent Electrochemical Hydrogen Peroxide Synthesis Performance of Oxidized Carbon Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01637</link>
      <description>Fangxin She, Zhongyuan Guo, Fangzhou Liu, Zixun Yu, Jiaxiang Chen, Yuhang Fan, Yaojie Lei, Yuan Chen, Hao Li, Wei Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400360164

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangxin She, Zhongyuan Guo, Fangzhou Liu, Zixun Yu, Jiaxiang Chen, Yuhang Fan, Yaojie Lei, Yuan Chen, Hao Li, Wei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing Mo&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Clusters and Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C Nanoparticles on Oxidized Carbon Nanotubes Boosting the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02069</link>
      <description>Shuo Cao, Zun Guan, Ying Ma, Bing Xu, Jinghong Ma, Wei Chu, Riguang Zhang, Giuliano Giambastiani, Yuefeng Liu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400360420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuo Cao, Zun Guan, Ying Ma, Bing Xu, Jinghong Ma, Wei Chu, Riguang Zhang, Giuliano Giambastiani, Yuefeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Hydroxide Growth over Nickel&#8211;Iron Phosphide with Enhanced Overall Water Splitting Performances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402881</link>
      <description>Jian Hu, Jinwei Yin, Aoyuan Peng, Dishu Zeng, Jia-Hong Ke, Jilei Liu, Kaifeng Guo, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400361332

                Abstract In this work, three dimensional (3D) self&#8208;supported Ni&#8208;FeOH@Ni&#8208;FeP needle arrays with core&#8208;shell heterojunction structure are fabricated via in situ hydroxide growth over Ni&#8208;FeP surface. The as&#8208;prepared electrodes show an outstanding oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, only requiring the low overpotential of 232 mV to reach 200 mA cm &#8722;2 with the Tafel slop of 40 mV dec &#8722;1 . For overall water splitting, an alkaline electrolyzer with these electrodes only requires a cell voltage of 2.14 V to reach 1 A cm &#8722;2 . Mechanistic investigations for such excellent electrocatalytic performances are utilized by in situ Raman spectroscopy in conjunction with density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The computation results present that Ni&#8208;FeOH@Ni&#8208;FeP attains better intrinsic conductivity and the D&#8208;band center (close to that of the ideal catalyst), thus giving superior excellent catalytic performances. Likewise, the surface Ni&#8208;FeOH layer can improve the structural stability of Ni&#8208;FeP cores and attenuate the eventual formation of irreversible FeOOH products. More importantly, the appearance of FeOOH intermediates can effectively decrease the energy barrier of NiOOH intermediates, and then rapidly accelerate the sluggish reaction dynamics, as well as further enhance the electrocatalytic activities, reversibility and cycling stability.</description>
      <author>Jian Hu, Jinwei Yin, Aoyuan Peng, Dishu Zeng, Jia-Hong Ke, Jilei Liu, Kaifeng Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pserformance Enhancement of Rechargeable Zinc-Air Battery through Synergistic Ex-solution of Multi-component Pt/CoWO4-x Nanofiber in Hybrid Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124371</link>
      <description>Chang&#8208;Ho Lee, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Jaewook An, Ji&#8208;Soo Jang, Bonjae Koo, Jong Min Kim, Kihyun Shin, Lee C, Ki Ro Yoon, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400363166

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang&#8208;Ho Lee, Chang&#8208;Kyu Hwang, Jaewook An, Ji&#8208;Soo Jang, Bonjae Koo, Jong Min Kim, Kihyun Shin, Lee C, Ki Ro Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Construction of Interfacial Akagan&#233;ite FeOOH Phase to Enable the Long&#8208;Term Stability of Nickel&#8208;Iron Hydroxides for Seawater Splitting at Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407781</link>
      <description>Z.X. Liu, Yuanyuan Li, Libin Zeng, Xiaofeng Peng, Dashuai Wang, Zhongjian Li, Boguang Yang, Yuanyuan Li, Lecheng Lei, Yang Hou, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400365766

                Abstract NiFe&#8208;based hydroxides are well&#8208;established as efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline purified water. However, they usually degrade rapidly in seawater electrolysis because of concentrated Cl &#8722; anions in seawater. In this work, a facile approach utilizing an ultrafast dipping method is presented to fabricate durable and scalable NiFe hydroxides, enhanced by interfacial akagan&#233;ite FeOOH for seawater splitting. This study reveals significantly improved electrocatalytic stability of NiFe hydroxides at an ampere&#8208;level current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for 100 h in alkaline seawater. It is realized by the formed FeOOH in a specific akagan&#233;ite phase whose lattice tunnels are well filled by intrinsic Cl &#8722; anions, that serve to electrostatically repel corrosive chlorides in electrolyte. This anionic design also provides superior corrosion protection for other active metal&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts when deployed in alkaline purified water and allows for facile scaling up of the anode, facilitating the practical utilization for seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Z.X. Liu, Yuanyuan Li, Libin Zeng, Xiaofeng Peng, Dashuai Wang, Zhongjian Li, Boguang Yang, Yuanyuan Li, Lecheng Lei, Yang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reconstruction of Pt(001) Surface and the Shell&#8208;Like Reconstruction of the Vicinal Pt(001) Surfaces Revealed by Neural Network Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404274</link>
      <description>Cheng Qian, Daniel Hedman, Pai Li, Sung Youb Kim, Feng Ding, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400366058

                Abstract In this work, a highly accurate neural network potential (NNP) is presented, named Pt NNP , and the exploration of the reconstruction of the Pt(001) surface and its vicinal surfaces with it. Contrary to the most accepted understanding of the Pt(001) surface reconstruction, the study reveals that the main driving force behind Pt(001) quasi&#8208;hexagonal reconstruction is not the surface stress relaxation but the increased coordination number of the surface atoms resulting in stronger intralayer binding in the reconstructed surface layer. In agreement with experimental observations, the optimized supercell size of the reconstructed Pt(001) surface contains (5 &#215; 20) unit cells. Surprisingly, the reconstruction of the vicinal Pt(001) surfaces leads to a smooth shell&#8208;like surface layer covering the whole surface and diminishing sharp step edges.</description>
      <author>Cheng Qian, Daniel Hedman, Pai Li, Sung Youb Kim, Feng Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing photoelectrocatalytic water splitting performance through PdCoP co-modification of Ti:Fe2O3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.336</link>
      <description>Penghui Bai, Juan Xie, Hu Wang, Xiaolan Kang, Ke Jiang, Chen Yang, Xia Wang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 79(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400366739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Penghui Bai, Juan Xie, Hu Wang, Xiaolan Kang, Ke Jiang, Chen Yang, Xia Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-engineered ruthenium oxide on titanium oxide oxygen evolution electrocatalysts for proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124382</link>
      <description>Hyung&#8208;Koo Yoon, Hee Jo Song, Ji Seong Hyoung, Sang Won Jung, Andi Haryanto, Chan Woo Lee, Dong&#8208;Wan Kim, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400381918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyung&#8208;Koo Yoon, Hee Jo Song, Ji Seong Hyoung, Sang Won Jung, Andi Haryanto, Chan Woo Lee, Dong&#8208;Wan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First and Second Reductions in an Aprotic Solvent: Comparing Computational and Experimental One-Electron Reduction Potentials for 345 Quinones</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00602</link>
      <description>Sarah Elhajj, Samer Gozem, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400382975

                Using reference reduction potentials of quinones recently measured relative to the saturated calomel electrode (SCE) in N,N-dimethylformamide (DMF), we benchmark absolute one-electron reduction potentials computed for 345 Q/Q&#8226;&#8211; and 265 Q&#8226;&#8211;/Q2&#8211; half-reactions using adiabatic electron affinities computed with density functional theory and solvation energies computed with four continuum solvation models: IEF-PCM, C-PCM, COSMO, and SM12. Regression analyses indicate a strong linear correlation between experimental and absolute computed Q/Q&#8226;&#8211; reduction potentials with Pearson's correlation coefficient (r) between 0.95 and 0.96 and the mean absolute error (MAE) relative to the linear fit between 83.29 and 89.51 mV for different solvation methods when the slope of the regression is constrained to 1. The same analysis for Q&#8226;&#8211;/Q2&#8211; gave a linear regression with r between 0.74 and 0.90 and MAE between 95.87 and 144.53 mV, respectively. The y-intercept values obtained from the linear regressions are in good agreement with the range of absolute reduction potentials reported in the literature for the SCE but reveal several sources of systematic error. The y-intercepts from Q&#8226;&#8211;/Q2&#8211; calculations are lower than those from Q/Q&#8226;&#8211; by around 320&#8211;410 mV for IEF-PCM, C-PCM, and SM12 compared to 210 mV for COSMO. Systematic errors also arise between molecules having different ring sizes (benzoquinones, naphthoquinones, and anthraquinones) and different substituents (titratable vs nontitratable). SCF convergence issues were found to be a source of random error that was slightly reduced by directly optimizing the solute structure in the continuum solvent reaction field. While SM12 MAEs were lower than those of the other solvation models for Q/Q&#8226;&#8211;, SM12 had larger MAEs for Q&#8226;&#8211;/Q2&#8211; pointing to a larger error when describing multiply charged anions in DMF. Altogether, the results highlight the advantages of, and further need for, testing computational methods using a large experimental data set that is not skewed (e.g., having more titratable than nontitratable substituents on different parent groups or vice versa) to help further distinguish between sources of random and systematic errors in the calculations.</description>
      <author>Sarah Elhajj, Samer Gozem</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using ethanol and isopropanol as biomass model compounds for understanding bond scission mechanisms over Cu/Mo2N catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124362</link>
      <description>William N. Porter, Wenjie Liao, Marcus Yu, Yong Yuan, Zhexi Lin, Ping Liu, Kuan Chang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400388059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>William N. Porter, Wenjie Liao, Marcus Yu, Yong Yuan, Zhexi Lin, Ping Liu, Kuan Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XtalOpt Version 13: Multi-Objective Evolutionary Search for Novel Functional Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109306</link>
      <description>Samad Hajinazar, Eva Zurek, Computer physics communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400392210

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samad Hajinazar, Eva Zurek</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset for quantum-mechanical exploration of conformers and solvent effects in large drug-like molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03521-8</link>
      <description>Leonardo Medrano Sandonas, Dries Van Rompaey, Alessio Fallani, Mathias Hilfiker, David F. Hahn, Laura P&#233;rez&#8208;Benito, Jonas Verhoeven, Gary Tresadern, J&#246;rg K. Wegner, Hugo Ceulemans, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Scientific data. 11(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400396982

                Abstract We here introduce the Aquamarine (AQM) dataset, an extensive quantum-mechanical (QM) dataset that contains the structural and electronic information of 59,783 low-and high-energy conformers of 1,653 molecules with a total number of atoms ranging from 2 to 92 (mean: 50.9), and containing up to 54 (mean: 28.2) non-hydrogen atoms. To gain insights into the solvent effects as well as collective dispersion interactions for drug-like molecules, we have performed QM calculations supplemented with a treatment of many-body dispersion (MBD) interactions of structures and properties in the gas phase and implicit water. Thus, AQM contains over 40 global and local physicochemical properties (including ground-state and response properties) per conformer computed at the tightly converged PBE0+MBD level of theory for gas-phase molecules, whereas PBE0+MBD with the modified Poisson-Boltzmann (MPB) model of water was used for solvated molecules. By addressing both molecule-solvent and dispersion interactions, AQM dataset can serve as a challenging benchmark for state-of-the-art machine learning methods for property modeling and de novo generation of large (solvated) molecules with pharmaceutical and biological relevance.</description>
      <author>Leonardo Medrano Sandonas, Dries Van Rompaey, Alessio Fallani, Mathias Hilfiker, David F. Hahn, Laura P&#233;rez&#8208;Benito, Jonas Verhoeven, Gary Tresadern, J&#246;rg K. Wegner, Hugo Ceulemans, Alexandre Tkatchenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03521-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrocatalytic nitrate-to-ammonia of single Fe active sites via coordination engineering: From theory to experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.055</link>
      <description>Heying Li, Xinyang Liu, Ziwang Kan, Song Liu, Jingxiang Zhao, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400398824

                Atomically dispersed iron&#8211;nitrogen-carbon (Fe&#8211;N4&#8211;C) catalysts show great promises for the electrocatalytic nitrate (NO3&#8722;) reduction to ammonia (NH3). Nevertheless, the microenvironmental engineering of the single Fe active sites for further optimizing the catalytic performance remains a challenge. Herein, we proposed to regulate the coordination environment of single Fe active sites to boost its intrinsic electrocatalytic activity for NO3&#8722; &#8211;to&#8211;NH3 conversion by the incorporation of new heteroatoms, including B, C, O, Si, P, and S. Our results revealed that most of the candidates possess low formation energies, showing great potential for experimental synthesis. Moreover, incorporating heteroatoms effectively modulates the charge redistribution and the d&#8211;band center of single Fe active sites, enabling the regulation of the binding strength of nitrogenous intermediates. As a result, the N and C coordinated Fe active site (Fe&#8211;N3C) exhibits superior catalytic performance for NO3&#8722; electroreduction with a relatively low limiting potential (&#8211;0.13 V) due to its optimal adsorption strength with nitrogenous intermediates induced by its moderate charge and d&#8211;band center. Importantly, our experimental measures confirmed such theoretical prediction: a maximum NH3 yield rate of 21.07 mg h&#8722;1 mgcat.&#8722;1 and 95.74 % Faradaic efficiency were achieved for NO3&#8722; electroreduction on Fe&#8211;N3C catalyst. These findings not only suggest a highly efficient catalyst for nitrate reduction but also provide insight into how to design and prepare electrocatalysts with enhanced catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Heying Li, Xinyang Liu, Ziwang Kan, Song Liu, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron distribution regulating of nonmetal doped monolayer g-GaN for enhanced electrocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160683</link>
      <description>Yafei Zhao, Liang He, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400398871

                Exploring inexpensive electrocatalysts that can efficiently and selectively convert CO2 into hydrocarbon fuels is important to promote carbon neutrality and solve the energy crisis. Current electrocatalysts, such as Cu-based alloys, single-atom catalysts, and dual-atom catalysts, use the d states of metal in the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction. Inspired by this, this work studies CO2 reduction reaction from another approach. Herein, using first principles study, we systematically investigate the prospect of nonmetal (B, C, O and F) doped monolayers g-GaN as electrocatalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction. We found that nonmetal doping can effectively regulate the electron distribution and p-band center of the active center (N site), which can adjust the initial adsorption, activation degree, charge transfer amount of CO2, and promote the formation of intermediates. Interestingly, B and C doped systems have better catalytic activity for CH4, with limiting potentials of &#8722;0.61 and &#8722;0.53 V, respectively. More importantly, F doped system has higher activity and selectivity for CH3OH production and inhibit competitive HER, with lower limiting potentials of &#8722;0.60 V. This study provides a new theoretical basis for the design and screening of electrocatalysts with high activity and product selectivity using nonmetal as the active site.</description>
      <author>Yafei Zhao, Liang He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the electrochemical reduction of CO2 on Au25(SR)18&#8722; nanocluster</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141462</link>
      <description>Dominic Alfonso, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400400371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dominic Alfonso</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-controlled synthesis of starch-derived Mo2C&#8211;MoC/C heterostructure catalyst for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.023</link>
      <description>Xiang Zhang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Liping Li, NULL AUTHOR_ID, International journal of hydrogen energy. 79(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400405230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Zhang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Liping Li, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction of Co2 on Pure and Doped Cu2o(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4888703</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhichao Yu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400405522

                No abstract</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Zhichao Yu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4888703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; Electrodeposition of Nonprecious Metal Copper Nanocatalysts on Low-Dimensional Support Materials for Nitrate Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04947</link>
      <description>Shu Fen Tan, Hany Roslie, Teddy Salim, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dongshuang Wu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, L.W. Teo, Yeng Ming Lam, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400408645

                Supported nonprecious metal catalysts such as copper (Cu) are promising replacements for Pt-based catalysts for a wide range of energy-related electrochemical reactions. Direct electrochemical deposition is one of the most straightforward and versatile methods to synthesize supported nonprecious metal catalysts. However, further advancement in the design of supported nonprecious metal catalysts requires a detailed mechanistic understanding of the interplay between kinetics and thermodynamics of the deposition phenomena under realistic reaction conditions. Here, we study the electrodeposition of Cu on carbon nanotubes and graphene derivatives under electrochemical conditions using</description>
      <author>Shu Fen Tan, Hany Roslie, Teddy Salim, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Dongshuang Wu, NULL AUTHOR_ID, L.W. Teo, Yeng Ming Lam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate and efficient prediction of optical gaps in silicon and germanium nanoparticles using a high-local-exchange density functional</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141460</link>
      <description>Corentin Villot, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400409897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Corentin Villot, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming the Chemical Complexity Bottleneck in on-the-Fly Machine Learned Molecular Dynamics Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00474</link>
      <description>Lucas R. Timmerman, Shashikant Kumar, Phanish Suryanarayana, Andrew J. Medford, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400420883

                We develop a framework for on-the-fly machine learned force field molecular dynamics simulations based on the multipole featurization scheme that overcomes the bottleneck with the number of chemical elements. Considering bulk systems with up to 6 elements, we demonstrate that the number of density functional theory calls remains approximately independent of the number of chemical elements, in contrast to the increase in the smooth overlap of the atomic positions scheme.</description>
      <author>Lucas R. Timmerman, Shashikant Kumar, Phanish Suryanarayana, Andrew J. Medford</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-scale identification of active sites of oxygen reduction nanocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01175-8</link>
      <description>Yao Yang, Jihan Zhou, Zipeng Zhao, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Colin Ophus, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qiang Sun, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Jim Ciston, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Philippe Sautet, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400422748

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Yang, Jihan Zhou, Zipeng Zhao, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Colin Ophus, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Qiang Sun, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Jim Ciston, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Philippe Sautet, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01175-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional high-entropy alloys: promising catalysts for high-performance water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02271h</link>
      <description>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yuzhi Ke, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Simin Jiang, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400426149

                State-of-the-art HEAs with outstanding water splitting performance is rationally designed, which provides a blueprint for the design of a next-generation platform for hydrogen regeneration.</description>
      <author>NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Yuzhi Ke, NULL AUTHOR_ID, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Simin Jiang, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02271h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperativity between atoms in supported &#8220;Single-Atom Catalysts&#8221; and metal clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153840</link>
      <description>Pedro Serna, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400428831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pedro Serna</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choline chloride modification of nanofiltration membranes for improving heavy metal ions separation in wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.memsci.2024.123079</link>
      <description>Junwei Li, Ying-Xue Song, Daliang Xu, Xi Zhang, Jiale Du, Riri Liu, Rui Zhao, Qin Chen, Alexander Volodine, Raf Dewil, Qieyuan Gao, Bart Van der Bruggen, Journal of membrane science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400433450

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junwei Li, Ying-Xue Song, Daliang Xu, Xi Zhang, Jiale Du, Riri Liu, Rui Zhao, Qin Chen, Alexander Volodine, Raf Dewil, Qieyuan Gao, Bart Van der Bruggen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.memsci.2024.123079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The excellent performance of oxygen evolution reaction on stainless steel electrodes by halogen oxyacid salts etching</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.043</link>
      <description>Junyu Shen, Tao Wang, Tian Xie, Ruihan Wang, Dingwei Zhu, Yuxi Li, S. Xue, Yazi Liu, Hehua Zeng, Wenhui Zhao, Shaobin Wang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400439514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junyu Shen, Tao Wang, Tian Xie, Ruihan Wang, Dingwei Zhu, Yuxi Li, S. Xue, Yazi Liu, Hehua Zeng, Wenhui Zhao, Shaobin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stimulating Electron Delocalization of Lanthanide Elements through High-Entropy Confinement to Promote Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04176</link>
      <description>Yong Jiang, Liang Zhong, Jin&#8208;Cheng Liu, Hao Fu, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Yaping Du, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400446876

                High-entropy alloys (HEAs) have aroused extensive attention in the field of catalysis. However, due to the integration of multiple active sites in HEA, it exhibits excessive adsorption behavior resulting in difficult desorption of active species from the catalyst surfaces, which hinders the catalytic efficiency. Therefore, adjusting the adsorption strength of the active site in HEA to enhance the catalytic activity is of great importance. By introducing rare-earth (RE) elements into the high-entropy alloy, the delocalization of 4f electrons can be achieved through the interaction between the multimetal active site and RE, which benefits to regulate the adsorption strength of the HEA surface. Herein, the RE Ce-modified hexagonal-close-packed PtRuFeCoNiZn-Ce/C HEAs are synthesized and showed an excellent electrocatalytic activity for hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction with ultralow overpotentials of 4, 7 and 156, 132 mV, respectively, to reach 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Yong Jiang, Liang Zhong, Jin&#8208;Cheng Liu, Hao Fu, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Yaping Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe hydroxide towards CoP2-FeP4 heterojunction for efficient and long-term stable water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.073</link>
      <description>Zhi Liu, Yu Dai, Xin Han, Chengyi Hou, Kerui Li, Yaogang Li, Hongzhi Wang, Qinghong Zhang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400449313

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhi Liu, Yu Dai, Xin Han, Chengyi Hou, Kerui Li, Yaogang Li, Hongzhi Wang, Qinghong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Computational Materials Discovery with Machine Learning and Cloud High-Performance Computing: from Large-Scale Screening to Experimental Validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03849</link>
      <description>Chi Chen, Dan Thien Nguyen, Shannon Lee, Nathan Baker, Ajay Karakoti, Linda Lauw, David Owen, Karl T. Mueller, Brian A. Bilodeau, Vijayakumar Murugesan, Matthias Troyer, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400451665

                High-throughput computational materials discovery has promised significant acceleration of the design and discovery of new materials for many years. Despite a surge in interest and activity, the constraints imposed by large-scale computational resources present a significant bottleneck. Furthermore, examples of very large-scale computational discovery carried out through experimental validation remain scarce, especially for materials with product applicability. Here, we demonstrate how this vision became reality by combining state-of-the-art machine learning (ML) models and traditional physics-based models on cloud high-performance computing (HPC) resources to quickly navigate through more than 32 million candidates and predict around half a million potentially stable materials. By focusing on solid-state electrolytes for battery applications, our discovery pipeline further identified 18 promising candidates with new compositions and rediscovered a decade's worth of collective knowledge in the field as a byproduct. We then synthesized and experimentally characterized the structures and conductivities of our top candidates, the Na</description>
      <author>Chi Chen, Dan Thien Nguyen, Shannon Lee, Nathan Baker, Ajay Karakoti, Linda Lauw, David Owen, Karl T. Mueller, Brian A. Bilodeau, Vijayakumar Murugesan, Matthias Troyer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acetylene and Ethylene Adsorption during Floating Fe Catalyst Formation at the Onset of Carbon Nanotube Growth and the Effect of Sulfur Poisoning: a DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01830</link>
      <description>Bal&#225;zs Orb&#225;n, Tibor H&#246;ltzl, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400483060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bal&#225;zs Orb&#225;n, Tibor H&#246;ltzl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold&#8211;Thiolate Nanocluster Dynamics and Intercluster Reactions Enabled by a Machine Learned Interatomic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03094</link>
      <description>Caitlin A. McCandler, Antti Pihlajam&#228;ki, Sami Malola, Hannu H&#228;kkinen, Kristin A. Persson, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400484860

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Caitlin A. McCandler, Antti Pihlajam&#228;ki, Sami Malola, Hannu H&#228;kkinen, Kristin A. Persson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic doping of Iron and selenium on nickel hydroxide nitrate nanoarrays-derived as an efficient electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160657</link>
      <description>Huu Tuan Le, Hyonho Chun, Yong Jung Kwon, Min Ji Ham, Seok Ki Kim, Young Kyu Jeong, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400487044

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huu Tuan Le, Hyonho Chun, Yong Jung Kwon, Min Ji Ham, Seok Ki Kim, Young Kyu Jeong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoscale molecular assembly is favored by the active, crowded cytoplasm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/prxlife.2.033001</link>
      <description>Tong Shu, Gaurav Mitra, Jonathan Alberts, Matheus P. Viana, Emmanuel D. Levy, Glen M. Hocky, Liam J. Holt, PRX life. 2(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400495089

                The mesoscale organization of molecules into membraneless biomolecular condensates is emerging as a key mechanism of rapid spatiotemporal control in cells. Principles of biomolecular condensation have been revealed through reconstitution. However, intracellular environments are much more complex than test-tube environments: they are viscoelastic, highly crowded at the mesoscale, and are far from thermodynamic equilibrium due to the constant action of energy-consuming processes. We developed synDrops, a synthetic phase separation system, to study how the cellular environment affects condensate formation. Three key features enable physical analysis: synDrops are inducible, bioorthogonal, and have well-defined geometry. This design allows kinetic analysis of synDrop assembly and facilitates computational simulation of the process. We compared experiments and simulations to determine that macromolecular crowding promotes condensate nucleation but inhibits droplet growth through coalescence. ATP-dependent cellular activities help overcome the frustration of growth. In particular, stirring of the cytoplasm by actomyosin dynamics is the dominant mechanism that potentiates droplet growth in the mammalian cytoplasm by reducing confinement and elasticity. Our results demonstrate that mesoscale molecular assembly is favored by the combined effects of crowding and active matter in the cytoplasm. These results move toward a better predictive understanding of condensate formation . Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Tong Shu, Gaurav Mitra, Jonathan Alberts, Matheus P. Viana, Emmanuel D. Levy, Glen M. Hocky, Liam J. Holt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/prxlife.2.033001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The defect chemistry and machine learning study 5d transition metal doped on graphitic carbon nitride for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst with low overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.034</link>
      <description>Wentao Wang, Yingdong Qu, Dongying Li, Aodi Zhang, Hongxia Yan, Zhenzhen Feng, Wenzhi Yao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 79(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400498275

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wentao Wang, Yingdong Qu, Dongying Li, Aodi Zhang, Hongxia Yan, Zhenzhen Feng, Wenzhi Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key role of paracrystalline motifs on iridium oxide surfaces for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01187-4</link>
      <description>Bingzhang Lu, Carolin B. Wahl, Roberto dos Reis, Jane Edgington, Xiao Kun Lu, Ruihan Li, Matthew E. Sweers, Brianna N. Ruggiero, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Vinayak P. Dravid, Linsey C. Seitz, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400503861

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingzhang Lu, Carolin B. Wahl, Roberto dos Reis, Jane Edgington, Xiao Kun Lu, Ruihan Li, Matthew E. Sweers, Brianna N. Ruggiero, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Vinayak P. Dravid, Linsey C. Seitz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01187-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multi&#8208;Active Site Subnano Heterostructures Catalyst Grown In situ POM and Fe&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; onto Nickel Foam Toward Efficient Electrocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408968</link>
      <description>Liping Cui, Yu&#8208;wen Wang, Kai Yu, Yajie Ma, Baibin Zhou, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400504070

                Abstract Designing efficient, durable, and cheap bifunctional electrocatalysts is a challenging goal in water splitting. Herein, trivanadium&#8208;substituted Keggin&#8208;type polyoxometalate H 6 PV 3 Mo 9 O 40 (POM) and Fe 0.2 Ni 0.8 Co 2 O 4 (FNCO) are in situ grown onto nickel foam (NF) yielding a self&#8208;supporting nanoflower&#8208;like heterojunction via convenient hydrothermal reaction. The POM&#8208;Fe 0.2 Ni 0.8 Co 2 O 4 /NF as HER and OER electrocatalyst, displays low overpotential (89 and 259 mV) and high electrode stability at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . POM&#8208;FNCO/NF as the cathode and anode requires a lower voltage (1.58 V) to provide 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for overall water splitting (OWS), which is better than that of commercial catalysts. The electronic sponge characteristics of POM provide more active sites and fast reaction kinetics for HER and OER. The synergy of POM and FNCO optimizes the electron distribution at the interface and enhances the intrinsic activity of HER/OER. Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations show that water molecules preferentially bind to Co sites on POM&#8208;FNCO. Additionally, POM has proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer properties and its modified FNCO exhibits thermodynamic advantages. The synergistic effect of these two factors enables the efficient overall water splitting of POM&#8208;FNCO. This study offers a novel pathway for the construction of self&#8208;supporting efficient catalysts by in situ growth of POM nanoclusters and spinel oxide sub&#8208;nanometer heterojunctions on NF.</description>
      <author>Liping Cui, Yu&#8208;wen Wang, Kai Yu, Yajie Ma, Baibin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fractal Characterization of Simulated Metal Nanocatalysts in 3D</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400123</link>
      <description>Jonathan Y. C. Ting, George Opletal, Amanda S. Barnard, Small science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400510966

                The surface roughness of metal nanoparticles is known to be influential toward their properties, but the quantification of surface roughness is challenging. Given the recent availability of large&#8208;scale simulated data and tools for the computation of the box&#8208;counting dimension of simulated atomistic objects, researchers are now enabled to study the connections between the surface roughness of metal nanoparticles and their properties. Herein, the relationships between the fractal box&#8208;counting dimension of metal nanoparticle surfaces and structural features relevant to experimental and computational studies are investigated, providing actionable insights for the manufacturing of rough nanoparticles. This approach differs from conventional concepts of roughness, but introduces a possible indicator for their functionalities such as catalytic performance that was not previously accessible. It is found that, while it remains difficult to consistently correlate the dimension with the catalytic activity of surface facets, matching trends with their surface energy, thermodynamic stability, and number of bond vacancy are observed. This highlights the potential of fractal box&#8208;counting dimensions to rationalize catalytic activity trends among metal nanoparticles, and opens up opportunities for the design of nanocatalysts with better performance via surface engineering.</description>
      <author>Jonathan Y. C. Ting, George Opletal, Amanda S. Barnard</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancement in sodium carbonation pathways for sustainable carbon capture and utilization: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102536</link>
      <description>Marta Sibhat, Guodong Yao, Nai Shu Zhu, Gedion Tsegay, Kun Fang, Qiankun Zhu, Yijun Zhou, Jun Zhao, Results in engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400451893

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marta Sibhat, Guodong Yao, Nai Shu Zhu, Gedion Tsegay, Kun Fang, Qiankun Zhu, Yijun Zhou, Jun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D printing of biodegradable polymers and their composites &#8211; Current state-of-the-art, properties, applications, and machine learning for potential future applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101336</link>
      <description>S. A. V. Dananjaya, Venkata S. Chevali, John P. Dear, Prasad Potluri, Chamil Abeykoon, Progress in Materials Science/Progress in materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400477552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. A. V. Dananjaya, Venkata S. Chevali, John P. Dear, Prasad Potluri, Chamil Abeykoon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;D&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Exchange Activity and Electronic Structure of Ag&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Pd&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Alloy Catalysts Spanning Composition Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02309</link>
      <description>Nicholas Golio, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Xiaoxiao Yu, Petro Kondratyuk, NULL AUTHOR_ID, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400406161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicholas Golio, NULL AUTHOR_ID, Xiaoxiao Yu, Petro Kondratyuk, NULL AUTHOR_ID</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OBIWAN: An Element-Wise Scalable Feed-Forward Neural Network Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00342</link>
      <description>Stefano Martire, Sergio Decherchi, Andrea Cavalli, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400466488

                Estimating the potential energy of a molecular system at a quantum level of theory is a task of paramount importance in computational chemistry. The often employed density functional theory approach allows one to accomplish this task, yet most often at significant computational costs. This prompted the community to develop so-called machine learning potentials to achieve near-quantum accuracy at molecular mechanics computational cost. In this paper, we introduce OBIWAN, a feed-forward neural network that bears some relevant structural properties that also led to the definition of a new kind of general-purpose neural network layer. Its featurization process scales efficiently with newly added atomic species. This allows one to seamlessly add new atom types without requiring to change the topology of the network. Also, this allows one to train on new data sets leveraging a previously trained OBIWAN, hence converging very quickly. This avoids training from scratch and renders the approach more compliant with a green computing perspective.</description>
      <author>Stefano Martire, Sergio Decherchi, Andrea Cavalli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active and Stable Plasma-Enhanced Ald Pt@Ni-Ysz Hydrogen Electrode for Steam Reversible Solid Oxide Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4889739</link>
      <description>Hyong June Kim, Haoyu Li, Dae Hyun Kim, Geonwoo Park, Seungki Jo, K. Ju, Yongchai Kwon, Haesun Park, Min Hwan Lee, Jihwan An, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400443678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyong June Kim, Haoyu Li, Dae Hyun Kim, Geonwoo Park, Seungki Jo, K. Ju, Yongchai Kwon, Haesun Park, Min Hwan Lee, Jihwan An</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4889739</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
