<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 01:42:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Evaluation of N&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; Polynitrogen-Stabilized Single-Atom Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c00856</link>
      <description>Melisa Bilgili, Xianqin Wang, Joshua Young, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410558916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Melisa Bilgili, Xianqin Wang, Joshua Young</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c00856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Ab-Initio Study of the Adsorption of H2O, NaCl, and Salt Water on Graphite and Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.1009496</link>
      <description>Abdellah Sellam, Houda Khattab, Mohammed Benchtia, Abderrahim Bakak, Mohamed Amine Souktani, El Habib El Fakir, Aymen Bourkab, Rachid Mohallou, Youssef Lghazi, Omar Mounkach, E.K. Hlil, Abdelaziz Koumina, Rodolphe Heyd, IntechOpen eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410566936

                In view of climate change, seawater desalination is of concern to mankind, as the most difficult step in water treatment is the isolation of NaCl from seawater. The methods currently used to disable seawater remain costly, so it is important to understand and improve other methods for reducing the cost of seawater filtration. An atomic-scale computational study of NaCl and H2O adsorption on graphite and graphene is presented, with the aim of estimating the ability of graphite-graphene to remove NaCl from seawater to obtain drinking water. The calculations are based on Density Functional Theory (DFT), using the Grid-based Projector-Augmented Wave (GPAW) approach, Atomistic Simulation Environment (ASE), and Quantum ESPRESSO methods. The main results of our work are the optimization of H2O and NaCl molecule energies and densities of molecular states, and the calculation of the optimal adsorption distance of these molecules on the adsorbent (graphite-graphene). The observed changes in adsorption energies and density of states of the adsorbent could be exploited in the perspective of seawater filter applications. Our results could contribute to the optimization of potential seawater filter applications. The present work provides interesting information to the theoretical and experimental communities working in this field of research. It opens up the debate on the adsorption of H2O and NaCl molecules on graphite and graphene.</description>
      <author>Abdellah Sellam, Houda Khattab, Mohammed Benchtia, Abderrahim Bakak, Mohamed Amine Souktani, El Habib El Fakir, Aymen Bourkab, Rachid Mohallou, Youssef Lghazi, Omar Mounkach, E.K. Hlil, Abdelaziz Koumina, Rodolphe Heyd</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.1009496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halogen Atom (Cl, Br, and I) Doping Effects on the Electronic Character and OER Performance of BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; as a Photoanode Nanomaterial for Solar Water Splitting: A Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00532</link>
      <description>Xinxia Li, Yiteng Zhang, Fang Zhou, Xinliang Feng, Ya Xu, Huifang Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410568081

                Halogen elements, as common nonmetal dopants, have attracted significant attention for their potential in creating highly active photocatalysts. To improve the electronic property of BiVO4, a highly promising photoanode nanomaterial for solar water splitting, the halogen atom (Cl, Br, and I) doping strategy and underlying modification mechanisms were explored in detail by the first-principles calculations here. Formation energies confirmed that halogen doping at the O sites of BiVO4 is energetically favorable and can be realized experimentally. The conduction band minimum (CBM) energy level is stabilized and even shifted into the occupied electron states, while the valence band maximum (VBM) energy level is increased for BiVO4 upon halogen atom doping with a trend: I &gt; Br &gt; Cl. Furthermore, the n-type electron-donating behavior becomes increasingly significant with higher dopant mass concentrations, which is attributed to the lower electronegativity of introduced halogen atoms compared to that of the substituted O atoms. Moreover, doping with Cl, Br, or I atoms induces strong spin polarization and effectively suppresses the recombination of photogenerated electron-hole pairs in BiVO4. Furthermore, H2O adsorption energy and Gibbs free energy change (&#916;G) results for each fundamental stage confirmed that the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process is favored by such an n-type doping method. All of these results proved that halogen atom (Cl, Br, and I) doping is a reliable strategy to improve photoelectrical properties, consequently boosting the photocatalytic performance of BiVO4 through modifications to its electronic structure.</description>
      <author>Xinxia Li, Yiteng Zhang, Fang Zhou, Xinliang Feng, Ya Xu, Huifang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tutorial on the modeling of the heterogenous captured CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electroreduction reaction and first principles electrochemical modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs01210k</link>
      <description>Robert M. Kowalski, Dongfang Cheng, Philippe Sautet, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410569494

                We review the modelling and mechanism of the electroreduction of captured CO 2 which bypasses the energetically unfavorable release of CO 2 from the capture agent by directly reducing CO 2 in its captured form.</description>
      <author>Robert M. Kowalski, Dongfang Cheng, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs01210k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Mixed High&#8208;Entropy&#8208;Alloy Nanoframes with 3D Subnanometer&#8208;Thick Electrocatalytic Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202505927</link>
      <description>Chih&#8208;Yi Lin, Zuoli He, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Chun&#8208;Wei Chang, Yueh&#8208;Chun Hsiao, Shang&#8208;Cheng Lin, Yi Chen, Yumei Huang, Jeong Yong Lee, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Alexander J. Cowan, Tung&#8208;Han Yang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410569667

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy&#8208;alloy (HEA) nanocrystals, characterized by multicomponent solid solutions and synergistic effects, hold great potential in catalysis. However, synthesizing HEA hollow nanocrystals with 3D architectures and controlled surface atomic arrangements to enhance catalytic activity and durability remains challenging. Highly active and durable electrocatalysts are presented, derived from Pd@HEA core&#8208;shell nanocrystals featuring a few HEA atomic layers containing five platinum&#8208;group metals, synthesized via a Fe(III)&#8208;based wet etching strategy. The controlled etching process transformed Pd@HEA core&#8208;shell nanocubes enclosed by {100} facets into Pd@HEA porous nanocubes, HEA cubic nanocages, and eventually, HEA cubic nanoframes composed of subnanometer&#8208;thick ridges dominated by {110} facets, vacancies, and step atoms. Electron microscopy and synchrotron X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy revealed the randomly mixed coordination environments of the constituent elements, underscoring the excellent atomic mixing within the nanoframes. These nanoframes demonstrated a 9.72&#8208;fold higher acidic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) specific activity at an overpotential of &#8722;0.1 V than commercial Pt/C catalysts, remarkable durability after 15 000 potential cycles, and competitive performance as cathode catalysts for practical applications in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers. Density functional theory calculations attributed the superior HER performance to {110}&#8208;enclosed atomically mixed surfaces and low&#8208;coordination sites, optimizing hydrogen adsorption free energy (&#916;G H* ) near the ideal value of 0.</description>
      <author>Chih&#8208;Yi Lin, Zuoli He, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Chun&#8208;Wei Chang, Yueh&#8208;Chun Hsiao, Shang&#8208;Cheng Lin, Yi Chen, Yumei Huang, Jeong Yong Lee, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Alexander J. Cowan, Tung&#8208;Han Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202505927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybridizing Electrode Interface Structures in Protonic Ceramic Cells for Durable, Reversible Hydrogen and Power Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202503649</link>
      <description>Shuanglin Zheng, Bin Liu, Guntae Kim, Iman Ghamarian, Sooraj Patel, Hanping Ding, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410570877

                Abstract Protonic ceramic electrochemical cells (PCECs) represent a transformative technology for sustainable hydrogen production and power generation by converting energy between chemical and electrical forms. Operating at intermediate temperatures, PCECs utilize proton&#8208;conducting electrolytes, achieving high efficiency and reduced degradation. However, a major bottleneck lies at the oxygen electrode due to sluggish kinetics and limited active sites. To address this, we present a hybrid oxygen electrode featuring PrNi 0.7 Co 0.3 O 3&#8211;&#948; (PNC) backbone infused with oxygen vacancy&#8208;rich praseodymium oxide (PrO x ) nanoparticles. This design leverages the interplay between surface and bulk properties to enhance oxygen adsorption, diffusion, and catalytic kinetics. The PrO x introduces abundant oxygen vacancies and modulates the d &#8208;band center for optimal adsorption energy, while the PNC backbone provides robust proton conduction and stabilizes reaction intermediates. Cells incorporating this hybrid electrode demonstrate a peak power density of 1.56 W cm &#8722;2 at 600 &#176;C in fuel cell mode and a current density of 2.25 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.30 V in electrolysis mode. Faradaic and energy efficiency reach 96.8% and 89.9%, respectively, with exceptional thermal cycling stability and reduced polarization resistance (0.079 &#937; cm 2 ). This study underscores the potential of advanced electrode architectures to enhance the efficiency, durability, and applicability of PCECs in renewable energy systems.</description>
      <author>Shuanglin Zheng, Bin Liu, Guntae Kim, Iman Ghamarian, Sooraj Patel, Hanping Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202503649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating electronic structure of Fe atomic cluster by Cu single-atom sites for enhanced oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03342-7</link>
      <description>Jing Wu, Jian Rong, W. J. Chen, Chaosheng Wang, Chun Feng, Huaisheng Ao, Chengzhang Zhu, Yuzhe Zhang, Zhongyu Li, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410571796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wu, Jian Rong, W. J. Chen, Chaosheng Wang, Chun Feng, Huaisheng Ao, Chengzhang Zhu, Yuzhe Zhang, Zhongyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-025-03342-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Doped Graphitic Carbon Nitride Inorganic Filler in Solid Polymer Electrolytes for All-Solid-State Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18540</link>
      <description>Yu Kang, Ju Ye Kim, Yu Jin Hong, Da Eun Han, Hyo Won Bae, Dong Wook Kim, Kyu Hyoung Lee, Andrew A. Peterson, Mihye Wu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410577218

                In the quest to enhance the safety of lithium-ion batteries, substantial research is underway to develop all-solid-state batteries, facing challenges in achieving high ion conductivity in solid electrolytes. This study aims to enhance the ion conductivity by incorporating carbon-doped graphitic carbon nitride (C-doped g-C3N4) microspheres as an inorganic filler into the poly(ethylene oxide)-based solid polymer electrolyte (SPE). Leveraging the advantageous properties of g-C3N4 as an effective inorganic filler by enhancing its Lewis acid-base interactions with lithium, we modified g-C3N4 through carbon doping to improve the ionic conductivity of the SPE. Our experimental analysis supports the increased lithium transference number after hybridizing electrolytes with C-doped g-C3N4, signifying heightened ion mobility resulting from carbon substitution on g-C3N4. Subsequent density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal increased lithium binding energy due to the carbon doping of g-C3N4, thereby ultimately enhancing the ion conductivity by promoting salt dissociation. Optimizing carbon doping levels and hybrid electrolyte composition yields improved ion conductivity and electrochemical performance, with optimal outcomes observed at 7% C-doped g-C3N4 with SPE. Evaluation in a pouch cell with the NCM811 cathode underscores the applicability of the hybrid electrolyte on a large scale, showcasing promising advancements in battery technology. Our carbon-doped g-C3N4 filler demonstrates promising potential in advancing ion conductivity through enhanced salt dissociations.</description>
      <author>Yu Kang, Ju Ye Kim, Yu Jin Hong, Da Eun Han, Hyo Won Bae, Dong Wook Kim, Kyu Hyoung Lee, Andrew A. Peterson, Mihye Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electron Engineering Unlocks Efficient Nitrate Electrosynthesis by Balancing Nitrogen Activation and Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01568</link>
      <description>Haixia Zeng, Dashuai Wang, Cheng&#8208;Jie Yang, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Weixiao Lin, Xiahan Sang, Bin Yang, Zhongjian Li, Siyu Yao, Qinghua Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Lecheng Lei, Yuanyuan Li, Ra&#250;l D. Rodriguez, Yang Hou, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410577480

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haixia Zeng, Dashuai Wang, Cheng&#8208;Jie Yang, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Weixiao Lin, Xiahan Sang, Bin Yang, Zhongjian Li, Siyu Yao, Qinghua Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Lecheng Lei, Yuanyuan Li, Ra&#250;l D. Rodriguez, Yang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boost proton transfer in water oxidation by constructing local electric fields on BiVO4 photoanodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64665-1</link>
      <description>Zhixing Guan, Ying Zhang, Fang&#8208;Fang Feng, Zhaohui Li, Yanli Liu, Zenghui Wu, Xingxing Zheng, Xionghui Fu, Yuanming Zhang, Wenbin Liao, Jialu Chen, Huajun Liu, Yi Zhu, Yongge Wei, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 72(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410577527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhixing Guan, Ying Zhang, Fang&#8208;Fang Feng, Zhaohui Li, Yanli Liu, Zenghui Wu, Xingxing Zheng, Xionghui Fu, Yuanming Zhang, Wenbin Liao, Jialu Chen, Huajun Liu, Yi Zhu, Yongge Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64665-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous bowl-like carbon support for boosting oxygen transport of fuel cell cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60285-8</link>
      <description>Mingjia Lu, Jinhui Liang, Binwen Zeng, Wei Li, Yunqi Li, Q. Wang, Yuhuai Li, Hong Chen, Jianzheng Li, Yangyang Chen, Lecheng Liang, Li Du, Yan Xiang, Shijun Liao, Zhiming Cui, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 72(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410577565

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingjia Lu, Jinhui Liang, Binwen Zeng, Wei Li, Yunqi Li, Q. Wang, Yuhuai Li, Hong Chen, Jianzheng Li, Yangyang Chen, Lecheng Liang, Li Du, Yan Xiang, Shijun Liao, Zhiming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60285-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient One-Step Electrochemical Synthesis of Ammonia-Hydrogen Fuel for Clean Energy Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5263655</link>
      <description>Lei Miao, xiaojiang mu, Che&#8211;Wun Hong, Zhongmei Yang, Xiaoyang Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410579061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Miao, xiaojiang mu, Che&#8211;Wun Hong, Zhongmei Yang, Xiaoyang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5263655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Formation of Multi-Principal Element Oxide on a Bulk Nanoporous Intermetallic Alloy for Ultra-Efficient Hydrogen Production at Ampere-Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c03821</link>
      <description>Xiang Gao, Wenyu L&#252;, Shuo Shuang, Quanfeng He, Zhaoyi Ding, Yujing Liu, Baisong Guo, Zhe Jia, Shijun Zhao, Yong Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410581537

                Developing highly efficient and durable electrocatalysts for hydrogen production via water splitting remains a pivotal challenge for sustainable energy. In this work, we present a bulk nanoporous C15 intermetallic alloy synthesized through electrodealloying of a eutectic multiprincipal element precursor. Unlike conventional metallic nanostructures, this catalyst features an ultrathin multiprincipal element oxide (MPEO) layer, which generates abundant active sites and achieves exceptional hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity, surpassing most reported catalysts. Crucially, the material demonstrates unprecedented stability at industrial-level current densities (1 A/cm2 at 396 mV), enabled by operando amorphization of the MPEO layer during prolonged operation. This structural evolution stabilizes the catalyst-electrolyte interface while retaining intrinsic activity. Our findings redefine design principles for robust, high-performance electrocatalysts by integrating bulk intermetallic architectures with self-optimizing surface chemistry.</description>
      <author>Xiang Gao, Wenyu L&#252;, Shuo Shuang, Quanfeng He, Zhaoyi Ding, Yujing Liu, Baisong Guo, Zhe Jia, Shijun Zhao, Yong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c03821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Electrocatalytic Activity Investigation for a Single Co Atom with Diverse Coordination Environments on the h-BCN Monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00822</link>
      <description>Na Zhou, Yanning Wang, Jiao Wang, Hang Zhang, Panchao Zhao, Hemu Pi, Xiangping Chen, Bosheng Zhang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410586448

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Zhou, Yanning Wang, Jiao Wang, Hang Zhang, Panchao Zhao, Hemu Pi, Xiangping Chen, Bosheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in transition metal sulphide-based electrocatalysts for the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106784</link>
      <description>Tao Wang, Jun Li, Linfeng Xiao, Sanshuang Gao, Juan Yu, Weiping Liu, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410593681

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Wang, Jun Li, Linfeng Xiao, Sanshuang Gao, Juan Yu, Weiping Liu, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of rare earth elements in hydrogen-electric conversion-related catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2025.05.015</link>
      <description>Shuqi Yu, Chen Liu, Yungui Chen, Yao Wang, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410595175

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuqi Yu, Chen Liu, Yungui Chen, Yao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2025.05.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Engineerable Solid Amine Beads for Efficient Carbon Dioxide Adsorption from Simulated Flue Gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5c00596</link>
      <description>Qiaoqiao Teng, Eric Niyonsenga, Penghao Liu, Meiling Wang, Yi&#8208;Wen Cao, Qi Meng, Ninghong Jia, Shengbin Chen, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410603061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiaoqiao Teng, Eric Niyonsenga, Penghao Liu, Meiling Wang, Yi&#8208;Wen Cao, Qi Meng, Ninghong Jia, Shengbin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5c00596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of a Porous Silver Metal&#8211;Organic Cage with Accessible Ag(I) Active Sites for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00877</link>
      <description>Ananya Debnath, Nilankar Diyali, Sangharaj Diyali, Suraj Kumar Agrawalla, Afshana Hassan, Harshita Bagdwal, Monika Singh, Manzoor Ahmad Dar, Chandra Shekhar Purohit, Goutam Kumar Dalapati, Bhaskar Biswas, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410604928

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ananya Debnath, Nilankar Diyali, Sangharaj Diyali, Suraj Kumar Agrawalla, Afshana Hassan, Harshita Bagdwal, Monika Singh, Manzoor Ahmad Dar, Chandra Shekhar Purohit, Goutam Kumar Dalapati, Bhaskar Biswas</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain Boundary Segregation in BCC Vanadium-based Alloys: Quantum-accurate Computed Segregation Spectra and Targeted Experimental Validations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121169</link>
      <description>Malik Wagih, Tianjiao Lei, Daniel Ng, Christopher A. Schuh, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410606138

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Malik Wagih, Tianjiao Lei, Daniel Ng, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finite-Temperature Double Proton Transfer in Formic Acid Dimer via Constrained Nuclear-Electronic Orbital Molecular Dynamics: Lower Barriers and Enhanced Rates from Nuclear Quantum Delocalization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00532</link>
      <description>Yuzhe Zhang, Zhe Liu, Yang Yang, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410610424

                Proton transfer plays a crucial role in various chemical and biological processes, yet accurately and efficiently describing such reactions remains challenging due to nuclear quantum effects (NQEs). In this work, we employ constrained nuclear-electronic orbital molecular dynamics (CNEO-MD), a method that inherently incorporates NQEs into classical dynamics to investigate double proton transfer in the formic acid dimer (FAD). Leveraging machine learning techniques, we efficiently construct free energy landscapes with NQEs at finite temperatures and obtain transition state theory (TST) rates. Transmission coefficients are further evaluated using flux-side correlation functions to obtain corrected rates that account for recrossing effects. CNEO-MD predicts significantly lowered free energy barriers and enhanced rates compared to conventional DFT-based ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD), agreeing qualitatively with previous path-integral simulations. Additionally, we explore solvent effects using CNEO-MD with a dielectric continuum solvent model and find the change of the solvent model makes negligible effects. Our findings demonstrate the effectiveness of CNEO-MD in describing proton transfer reactions at finite temperatures and highlight its potential for applications in more complex systems.</description>
      <author>Yuzhe Zhang, Zhe Liu, Yang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Selectivity in Graphene-based CO2 Reduction Catalysts: A First-Principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106787</link>
      <description>Yunxia He, Jing Li, Shuai Nie, Qi Wang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410618719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunxia He, Jing Li, Shuai Nie, Qi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SnSe nanosheets with Sn vacancies catalyse H2O2 production from water and oxygen at ambient conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01335-4</link>
      <description>Xinyue Zhang, Yangyang Wan, Yi Wen, Yingcai Zhu, Hong Liu, Jiaxiang Qiu, Zhanpeng Zhu, Zhongti Sun, Xiang Gao, Shulin Bai, Yuqiao Zhang, Long Zhang, Xiaohong Yan, Jianming Zhang, Yong Liu, Shun Li, Li&#8208;Dong Zhao, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410621405

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyue Zhang, Yangyang Wan, Yi Wen, Yingcai Zhu, Hong Liu, Jiaxiang Qiu, Zhanpeng Zhu, Zhongti Sun, Xiang Gao, Shulin Bai, Yuqiao Zhang, Long Zhang, Xiaohong Yan, Jianming Zhang, Yong Liu, Shun Li, Li&#8208;Dong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01335-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Heteroatom-Containing Metalloporphyrin-Based Catalysts for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30112287</link>
      <description>Zhuo Li, Qianqian Wei, Zhixin Ren, Jing Xie, Molecules. 30(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410622109

                Metalloporphyrins, owing to their structural resemblance to natural enzyme active sites and highly tunable coordination environments, have emerged as promising catalysts for converting CO2 into value-added chemicals and fuels. Considerable efforts have been made to modify metalloporphyrins to improve their catalytic capability for CO2 reduction. One approach involves modifying the metal coordination environment (known as the first coordination sphere) to generate heteroatom-containing metalloporphyrins, particularly N-confused and O/S-substituted variants. While heteroatom-containing metalloporphyrins were first synthesized in 1989, their use in CO2 reduction catalysis was not reported until after 2020. Herein, we review the recent progress in the design, catalytic performance, and mechanistic studies of N-confused and O/S-substituted metalloporphyrins towards CO2 reduction. This review encompasses both experimental and theoretical computational work, as well as the use of porphyrins as catalysts in photocatalysis and electrocatalysis. Finally, based on the current research advances, we present critical recommendations and future research directions, with a focus on theoretical studies, in the hope of facilitating the rational design of novel catalysts for sustainable energy conversion and environmental remediation.</description>
      <author>Zhuo Li, Qianqian Wei, Zhixin Ren, Jing Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30112287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Atom Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction: Unraveling Atomic Structures under Reaction Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c04776</link>
      <description>Courtney Brea, Guoxiang Hu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410628742

                Metal-nitrogen-carbon (M-N-C, M = Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, and Pt) dual-atom catalysts (DACs) show great potential for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at the cathode of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). During catalytic reactions, multiple reactants and intermediates interact with the active sites, yet understanding their dynamic structural evolution under the operating conditions remains challenging. In this study, we analyze 186 heteronuclear FeM-N-C DACs using ab initio thermodynamic phase diagrams and find that OH-ligated structures become predominant at higher applied potentials. This indicates that catalytic activity is governed by electrochemically modified metal sites rather than by the bare structures. We further investigate the catalytic mechanism of these ligated structures and reveal that the ORR limiting potential can be efficiently predicted from the phase diagrams. Among the 186 DACs studied, 29 were found to outperform Pt-based catalysts, with FeCo-N-C DACs demonstrating the highest activity. Our computational predictions align well with experimental observations, highlighting the crucial role of dynamic structural changes under reaction conditions in enhancing the electrocatalytic performance of DACs.</description>
      <author>Courtney Brea, Guoxiang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c04776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Adaptive Palladium Single-Atom Catalyst Enabling Reactivity Switching between Borylation and C&#8211;C Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17943</link>
      <description>Vitthal B. Saptal, Clara Saetta, Adriana Laufenb&#246;ck, Martin Sterrer, Ik Seon Kwon, Andrea Lucotti, Matteo Tommasini, Ond&#345;ej Tomanec, Aristides Bakandritsos, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410632144

                The development of single-atom catalysts (SACs) with site-specific and tunable catalytic functionalities remains a highly desirable yet challenging goal in catalysis. In this study, we report a SAC featuring anisotropic coordination cavities synthesized via a one-step polymerization of 2,6-diaminopyridine and cyanuric chloride. These cavities provide a robust framework for anchoring isolated Pd single atoms with exceptional stability. The unique broken symmetry of the catalyst's local structure enables precise control over reaction pathways, allowing reactivity to be switched between distinct catalytic outcomes. Specifically, under tailored reaction conditions, the catalyst can either halt at the borylation step or proceed seamlessly to Suzuki coupling in a self-cascade process. Mechanistic studies unveil the pivotal role of Pd single atoms in driving key steps, including oxidative addition, base exchange, and reductive elimination. Furthermore, green metrics demonstrate the process's sustainability, with minimized waste generation and reduced reliance on hazardous reagents in the self-cascade transformation. This work establishes an innovative benchmark in the field of single-atom catalysis: by enabling complex, multistep transformations via strategic activation of multiple functional groups, this catalyst exemplifies the potential of self-cascade processes to revolutionize synthetic chemistry via catalysis engineering.</description>
      <author>Vitthal B. Saptal, Clara Saetta, Adriana Laufenb&#246;ck, Martin Sterrer, Ik Seon Kwon, Andrea Lucotti, Matteo Tommasini, Ond&#345;ej Tomanec, Aristides Bakandritsos, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Gianvito Vil&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c17943</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing the NO electroreduction mechanism in single phosphorus atom decorated defective MXene: A first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142178</link>
      <description>Bin Huang, Guosheng Ren, Rong Chen, Neng Li, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410642625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Huang, Guosheng Ren, Rong Chen, Neng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling CoNi&#8208;LDH and Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N Nanoparticles on N&#8208;Doped Biomass&#8208;Derived Carbon as Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502145</link>
      <description>Guosheng Han, Ting Zhou, Yumeng Wu, Pengxiang Zhang, Yanyan Liu, Xianli Wu, Baojun Li, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410698547

                Abstract The engineering of structure and composition is crucial and challenging for modulating electrocatalytic activity. Herein, a bifunctional electrocatalyst, CoNi@Fe 2 N/C, is designed and prepared by coupling CoNi&#8208;layered double hydroxides (CoNi&#8208;LDH) nanosheets and Fe 2 N nanoparticles on 3D N&#8208;doped biomass&#8208;derived carbon through pyrolysis and electric field induction. CoNi@Fe 2 N/C delivers remarkable bifunctional electrocatalytic activity with a narrow overpotential gap (&#916; E ) of only 0.63 V for ORR and OER, surpassing commercial Pt/C+RuO 2 . Additionally, the aqueous rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries (RZABs) assembled with CoNi@Fe 2 N/C as a catalyst on the air electrode show a high peak power density (177.4 mW cm &#8722;2 ) and excellent durability (over 360 h). The high stability of 3D biomass&#8208;derived carbon assures the high durability of catalysts. Assistance of electric field induction ensures the uniform dispersion of CoNi&#8208;LDH nanosheets on 3D N&#8208;doped biomass&#8208;derived carbon. The interaction at the interface between two components appropriately modulates the electronic structure of hybrids via charge transfer to promote reaction kinetics. This work will provide a practical avenue to create ORR/ OER bifunctional biomass&#8208;derived catalytically active carbon hybrid catalysts for efficient RZABs.</description>
      <author>Guosheng Han, Ting Zhou, Yumeng Wu, Pengxiang Zhang, Yanyan Liu, Xianli Wu, Baojun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile co-precipitation synthesis of robust NiFe phosphate electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution in AEMWE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2025.207056</link>
      <description>Yu Yu, Jun Liu, Changhao Liang, Applied Catalysis O Open. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410701398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Yu, Jun Liu, Changhao Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2025.207056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverse design of catalytic active sites via interpretable topology-based deep generative models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01649-8</link>
      <description>Bingxu Wang, Shisheng Zheng, Jie Wu, Jingyan Li, Feng Pan, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410702307

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingxu Wang, Shisheng Zheng, Jie Wu, Jingyan Li, Feng Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01649-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt-CeO2/SDB ternary structure Achieved by Modulating Electronic interaction for high-efficiency Toluene Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117267</link>
      <description>Liu Zun, Guotan Liu, Xi Liu, Weihong Gao, Yudong Fu, Bin Sun, Yawei Shao, Guojun Dong, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410708258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liu Zun, Guotan Liu, Xi Liu, Weihong Gao, Yudong Fu, Bin Sun, Yawei Shao, Guojun Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.117267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zn-Co nanoferrite electrocatalysts for enhanced hydrogen and oxygen generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rechem.2025.102392</link>
      <description>Kiran Shahzadi, Muhammad Sarfraz, Muneerah Alomar, M.A. Mujtaba, Muhammad Nasir Bashir, Muhammad Mahmood Ali, Faisal Ali, Results in Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410708273

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kiran Shahzadi, Muhammad Sarfraz, Muneerah Alomar, M.A. Mujtaba, Muhammad Nasir Bashir, Muhammad Mahmood Ali, Faisal Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rechem.2025.102392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum Microalloying L1&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co Intermetallic Compounds via Bimodal Ordering Process by Mo Surface Termination and PDA&#8208;Coated Particle Confinement for Stable PEMFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503999</link>
      <description>Qiheng Wang, Jingkun Chen, Jingbo Fu, Ju Wang, Zhipeng Xing, Jingjun Liu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410709605

                Abstract Ordered platinum (Pt) intermetallic compounds with high performance expression under proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) operating conditions are a prerequisite for practical application. However, the heat treatment required for forming an ordered structure can lead to severe agglomeration and uneven distribution of nanoparticles, posing a significant challenge to efficient synthesis. Here, a molybdenum (Mo) assisted structural evolution strategy to controllably synthesize sub&#8208;4 nm Pt 3 Co intermetallic compounds is proposed. The results of experiments combined with density functional theory calculations demonstrate that the participation of trace Mo (0.2 wt.%) not only triggers the &#8220;growth site locking effect&#8221; and effectively suppresses the growth of nanoparticles, but also effectively adjusts the electronic structure, thereby optimizing the adsorption/desorption of oxygen intermediates. The preeminent intrinsic activity on an optimized catalyst reaches a mass activity as high as 1.22 A mg Pt &#8722;1 and has extraordinary stability with only a 5.7% decrease after 30 k cycles. This study paves a new path for the practical application of low Pt catalysts in PEMFCs in the future.</description>
      <author>Qiheng Wang, Jingkun Chen, Jingbo Fu, Ju Wang, Zhipeng Xing, Jingjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon&#8208;Based Flexible Electrode for Efficient Electrochemical Generation of Reactive Chlorine Species in Tumor Therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.202500369</link>
      <description>Cuinan Jiang, Zhaoyu Chen, Ruihao Yang, Ziga Luogu, Qian Ren, Hao Hu, Kaixin Wang, Senlin Li, Changlin Deng, Meng Li, Lu Zheng, Advanced Healthcare Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410709639

                Abstract Reactive chlorine species (RCS) are alternatives to reactive oxygen species (ROS) in tumor therapeutics. Unlike ROS, whose generation is limited by hypoxic conditions or insufficient H 2 O 2 levels in the tumor, RCS can be generated through the electrochemical oxidation of abundant Cl &#8722; present in body fluids. However, traditional electrochemical therapy modalities have shown suboptimal outcomes. Herein, a flexible anodic electrode is fabricated by growing a carbon nanowire network (C&#8208;NWN) onto carbon cloth (CC). Attributing to its excellent hydrophilicity, high specific surface area, and electrochemical surface area, CC@C&#8208;NWN demonstrates a superior capability for RCS generation. Additionally, the carbon vacancies in CC@C&#8208;NWN not only enhance Cl &#8722; adsorption but also reduce the reaction free energy of the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) more significantly compared to that of the oxygen evolution reaction, thereby promoting the CER process. RCS generated from the CC@C&#8208;NWN electrochemical system induces severe oxidative stress, disrupting the redox homeostasis in tumor cells and promoting the synergistic anti&#8208;tumor effect of apoptosis and ferroptosis. The pliability of CC@C&#8208;NWN enables it to conform closely to the tumor, and it has demonstrated remarkable tumor&#8208;suppressive efficacy under low&#8208;voltage (3 V) condition in in vivo experiments. Therefore, the work holds significant promise for the development of novel tumor treatment strategies.</description>
      <author>Cuinan Jiang, Zhaoyu Chen, Ruihao Yang, Ziga Luogu, Qian Ren, Hao Hu, Kaixin Wang, Senlin Li, Changlin Deng, Meng Li, Lu Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.202500369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of C1 and C2 Products Formation on (110) Facets of Carbides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106793</link>
      <description>Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410712051

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naveed Ashraf, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding magnesium dissolution through Machine learning molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163578</link>
      <description>Zhoulin Liu, Jianchun Sha, Guang&#8208;Ling Song, Ziliang Wang, Yinghe Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410714218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhoulin Liu, Jianchun Sha, Guang&#8208;Ling Song, Ziliang Wang, Yinghe Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Janus VSeTe monolayers for efficient HER by transition metal doping: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.292</link>
      <description>Lujing Zhao, W. L. Tan, Changmin Shi, D. Wang, Guangliang Cui, Hongmei Liu, Feifei Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 139(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410718270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lujing Zhao, W. L. Tan, Changmin Shi, D. Wang, Guangliang Cui, Hongmei Liu, Feifei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liquid&#8211;Liquid Interface-Based Thiocyanate Surface Treatment for Bright and Stable CsPbBr&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocrystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00803</link>
      <description>Rachel Lifer, Nathan Rafisiman, Saar Shaek, Arghyadeep Basu, Yaron Kauffmann, Nicholas G. Pavlopoulos, Ivano E. Castelli, Lev Chuntonov, Yehonadav Bekenstein, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410718339

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rachel Lifer, Nathan Rafisiman, Saar Shaek, Arghyadeep Basu, Yaron Kauffmann, Nicholas G. Pavlopoulos, Ivano E. Castelli, Lev Chuntonov, Yehonadav Bekenstein</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c00803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Loaded Catalyst Layers For Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell Dynamic Operation Part 2: Modeling Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146542</link>
      <description>Florent Vandenberghe, Fabrice Micoud, Pascal Schott, Marian Chatenet, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410733805

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Florent Vandenberghe, Fabrice Micoud, Pascal Schott, Marian Chatenet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-Doped Induced Phase Engineering of MoS2 for Boosting Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15100777</link>
      <description>Renjie Li, Meng Yu, Junjie Li, Ning Wang, Xiaolong Yang, Yanhua Peng, Nanomaterials. 15(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410581059

                Electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) holds great potential as a sustainable strategy for green hydrogen production. However, it still faces significant challenges due to the lack of highly efficient electrocatalysts. Herein, a synergistic approach by incorporating Ru atoms into MoS2 nanosheets to optimize the structure and conductivity has been proposed, which could improve the HER performance of MoS2 under alkaline conditions. Combining theoretical calculations and structural characterizations, it is demonstrated that the Ru atom introduction leads to the localized distortions of MoS2, generating additional active sites for H* adsorption, and reduces the free energy to adsorb and desorb hydrogen. Furthermore, the Ru introduction makes partial transformation from the 2H phase to the 1T phase in MoS2, which results in the change of the electronic structure and further enhances the electrical conductivity. As a result, the Ru-doped MoS2 electrocatalysts exhibit the high HER activities with the low overpotentials of 61 mV and 79 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1.0 M KOH and alkaline seawater, respectively. This work provides a novel design strategy for enhancing HER activity through the synergistic modulation of structural and electronic properties, offering valuable insights for the development of efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Renjie Li, Meng Yu, Junjie Li, Ning Wang, Xiaolong Yang, Yanhua Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15100777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain effects on catalytic activity and stability of PdM nanoalloys with grain boundaries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra02127h</link>
      <description>Junpeng Wang, Tao Jin, Longfei Guo, Zhen Li, Chongyang Wang, Shuang Shan, Quan Tang, Bowei Pan, Fuyi Chen, RSC Advances. 15(22)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410696812

                The PdIr nanoalloys with core&#8211;shell structure and Janus-structured PdAg nanoalloys exhibited the best FDR and FOR catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Junpeng Wang, Tao Jin, Longfei Guo, Zhen Li, Chongyang Wang, Shuang Shan, Quan Tang, Bowei Pan, Fuyi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra02127h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain in Core&#8211;Shell Spinel Nanocrystals Enhances ORR Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00896</link>
      <description>Jonathan L. Rowell, Aditya Joshi, H. S. Tan, Dasol Yoon, Jason Manassa, Alex Stangel, Colin R. Bundschu, Yafu Jia, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Robert Hovden, David A. Muller, Richard D. Robinson, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410714222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jonathan L. Rowell, Aditya Joshi, H. S. Tan, Dasol Yoon, Jason Manassa, Alex Stangel, Colin R. Bundschu, Yafu Jia, H&#233;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Robert Hovden, David A. Muller, Richard D. Robinson</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00896</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group-VIII-metal-based electrocatalysts for acidic hydrogen evolution reaction: Recent progress and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.05.013</link>
      <description>Qingshui Xie, Linfeng Xiao, Xue Zhao, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Materials Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410737174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingshui Xie, Linfeng Xiao, Xue Zhao, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.05.013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parametrization of Zirconium for DFTB3/3OB: A Pathway to Study Complex Zr&#8208;Compounds for Biomedical and Material Science Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70140</link>
      <description>Andreas Penz, Jakob Gamper, Josef M. Gallmetzer, Felix R. S. Purtscher, Thomas S. Hofer, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410739168

                ABSTRACT This work presents the extension of the semi&#8208;empirical density functional tight binding method, DFTB3, to include zirconium for biomedical and material science applications. The parametrization of Zr has been carried out in consistency with already established 3OB parameters including the elements C, H, N, O, S, P, Mg, Zn, Na, K, Ca, F, Cl, Br, and I. Zirconium&#8208;ligand association and reaction energies have been compared with results from quantum chemical calculations obtained at MP2 and DFT (PBE and B3LYP) level of theory, as well as with those from the semi&#8208;empirical methods DFTB2/PTBP and GFN2&#8208;xTB. A structural validation has been carried out on 1,897 compounds reported in the Cambridge Structural Database, revealing an average root mean square deviation comparable to that obtained at semi&#8208;empirical (DFTB2/PTBP and GFN2&#8208;xTB) level of theory and via the novel neural network potential MACE&#8208;MP&#8208;0. To provide a critical validation of the newly derived parameters, the structure of the biomedically relevant Zr&#8208;DFO complex has been evaluated with respect to a DFT (B3LYP) reference calculation. In addition, extensive DFTB3 MD simulations of the two prominent metal&#8208;organic frameworks UiO&#8208;66 and UiO&#8208;67 have been performed. The results demonstrate the applicability of the newly developed parameters for the study of zirconium&#8208;containing metal&#8208;organic frameworks, when compared to experimental measurements, as well as computational approaches.</description>
      <author>Andreas Penz, Jakob Gamper, Josef M. Gallmetzer, Felix R. S. Purtscher, Thomas S. Hofer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Stability and Catalytic Performance of Iron&#8211;Manganese Dual-Atoms Supported on Graphene Edges for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02424</link>
      <description>Sasfan Arman Wella, Ahmad N. Hakim, Muhammad Luqman Hakim, Nadya Amalia, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410743503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sasfan Arman Wella, Ahmad N. Hakim, Muhammad Luqman Hakim, Nadya Amalia, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anharmonic effects control interaction of carbyne confined in carbon nanotubes shaping their vibrational properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59863-3</link>
      <description>Emil Parth, Andrea Corradini, Weili Cui, Davide Romanin, C. Schuster, Clara Freytag, Lei Shi, Kazuhiro Yanagi, Matteo Calandra, Thomas Pichler, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410754738

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Emil Parth, Andrea Corradini, Weili Cui, Davide Romanin, C. Schuster, Clara Freytag, Lei Shi, Kazuhiro Yanagi, Matteo Calandra, Thomas Pichler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59863-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling surplus acetone into long-chain chemicals using a tandem electro-biosystem</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01568-y</link>
      <description>Chunxiao Liu, Jiankang Zhao, Hongting Tang, Jing Xue, Weiqing Xue, Xu Li, Hongliang Li, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Tao Yu, Jie Zeng, Chuan Xia, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410755367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunxiao Liu, Jiankang Zhao, Hongting Tang, Jing Xue, Weiqing Xue, Xu Li, Hongliang Li, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Tao Yu, Jie Zeng, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01568-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ordered single active sites for cascade hydrogenation and hydroformylation reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01346-1</link>
      <description>Xiaojun Lu, Jiazhen Wu, Xinyi He, Zichuang Li, Yangfan Lu, Wenqian Li, Jiang Li, Miao Xu, Yanpeng Qi, Qing Zhang, Yijia Liu, Meng Du, Toshio Kamiya, Hideo Hosono, Fusheng Pan, Jie&#8208;Sheng Chen, Tian&#8208;Nan Ye, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410755960

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojun Lu, Jiazhen Wu, Xinyi He, Zichuang Li, Yangfan Lu, Wenqian Li, Jiang Li, Miao Xu, Yanpeng Qi, Qing Zhang, Yijia Liu, Meng Du, Toshio Kamiya, Hideo Hosono, Fusheng Pan, Jie&#8208;Sheng Chen, Tian&#8208;Nan Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01346-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials-discovery workflow guided by symbolic regression for identifying acid-stable oxides for electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01596-4</link>
      <description>Akhil S. Nair, Lucas Foppa, Matthias Scheffler, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410759542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akhil S. Nair, Lucas Foppa, Matthias Scheffler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01596-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C single atom/cluster catalyst on ORR of PEMFC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.294</link>
      <description>Ruina Li, Xu&#8208;Wen Li, Qingcheng Liu, Hua Yue, Yang Meng, Yuanyuan Tian, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 139(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410760958

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruina Li, Xu&#8208;Wen Li, Qingcheng Liu, Hua Yue, Yang Meng, Yuanyuan Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design Strategies for Covalent Organic Frameworks Toward Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Peroxide Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15050500</link>
      <description>Yingjie Zheng, Yi Zhao, Wen Luo, Yifan Zhang, Yong Wang, Yang Wu, Catalysts. 15(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410565136

                Hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) is a versatile and environmentally friendly oxidant with broad applications in industry, energy, and environmental remediation. Electrocatalytic H2O2 production via the two-electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e&#8722; ORR) has emerged as a sustainable alternative to traditional anthraquinone processes. Covalent organic frameworks (COFs), as a class of crystalline porous materials, exhibit high structural tunability, large surface areas, and chemical stability, making them promising electrocatalysts for 2e&#8722; ORR. This review systematically summarizes recent advances in COF-based electrocatalysts for H2O2 production, including both metal-free and metal-containing systems. We discuss key strategies in COF design&#8212;such as dimensional modulation, linkage engineering, heteroatom doping, and post-synthetic modification&#8212;and highlight their effects on activity, selectivity, and stability. Fundamental insights into the 2e&#8722; ORR mechanism and evaluation metrics are also provided. Finally, we offer perspectives on current challenges and future directions, emphasizing the integration of machine learning, conductivity enhancement, and scalable synthesis to advance COFs toward practical H2O2 electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Yingjie Zheng, Yi Zhao, Wen Luo, Yifan Zhang, Yong Wang, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15050500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Functional Properties of Ferroelectric Perovskite Thin Films: Mechanisms of Dielectric and Photoelectrochemical Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15060496</link>
      <description>Ioan Ghitiu, George Alexandru Nemne&#351;, N. Scarisoreanu, Crystals. 15(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410695650

                Various types of strain, as well as chemical pressure induced by dopants, can effectively tailor the performance of perovskite thin films, including their optical, electrical or photoelectrochemical properties. The control of these functional properties through such engineering techniques is key to fulfilling the application-specific requirements of ferroelectric devices in various fields. Numerous models and experimental data have been published on this subject, especially on ferrite-based ferroelectric materials. Within this paper, the mechanisms of tuning ferroelectric intrinsic properties, such as polarization and ferroelectric domain configurations, through epitaxial strain and doping, as well as the role of these techniques in influencing functional properties such as dielectric and photoelectrochemical ones, are presented. This review examines the significant improvements in dielectric properties and photoelectrochemical efficiency achieved by the strategical control of key functionalities including dielectric losses, domain structures, charge separation and surface reactions in strained/doped ferroelectric thin films, highlighting the advancements and research progress made in this field in recent years.</description>
      <author>Ioan Ghitiu, George Alexandru Nemne&#351;, N. Scarisoreanu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15060496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating ultrastable catalyst exploration for large-scale water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2025.47</link>
      <description>Ning Han, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Chemical Synthesis. 5(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410757743

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Han, Bao&#8208;Lian Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2025.47</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transferable predictions of energetic and structural properties for refractory solid solution alloys across chemical compositions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113908</link>
      <description>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, Pei Zhang, Jong Youl Choi, German Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Ying Yang, Computational Materials Science. 257(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410708703

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, Pei Zhang, Jong Youl Choi, German Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Ying Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113908</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
