<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 01:22:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening of Group V&#8546;@C5N4 single-atom electrocatalysts for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114619</link>
      <description>Cuimei Li, Dong Cao, Dandan Guo, Chun&#8208;Ran Chang, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403590090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cuimei Li, Dong Cao, Dandan Guo, Chun&#8208;Ran Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supramolecular Catalyzed Cascade Reduction of Azaarenes Interrogated via Data Science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11482</link>
      <description>Sean M. Treacy, Andrew L. Smith, Robert G. Bergman, Kenneth N. Raymond, F. Dean Toste, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403596888

                Catalysis of multicomponent transformations requires controlled assembly of reactants within the active site. Supramolecular scaffolds possess synthetic microenvironments that enable precise modulation over noncovalent interactions (NCIs) engaged by reactive, encapsulated species. While molecular properties that describe the behavior of single guests in host cavities have been studied extensively, multicomponent transformations remain challenging to design and deploy. Here, simple univariate regression and threshold analyses are employed to model reactivity in a cascade reduction of azaarenes catalyzed by water-soluble metal organic cages. Yield and stereoselectivity models help deduce unknown mechanisms of reactivity by the multicomponent, host&#8211;guest complexes. Furthermore, a comprehensive model is established for NCIs driving stereoselectivity in the reported host&#8211;guest adducts.</description>
      <author>Sean M. Treacy, Andrew L. Smith, Robert G. Bergman, Kenneth N. Raymond, F. Dean Toste</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11482</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrode Materials for NO Electroreduction Based on Dithiolene Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks: A Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100739</link>
      <description>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Lixin Ye, Mengyun Mei, Weihua Zhu, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403601369

                To quickly and efficiently screen catalytic materials with both activity and selectivity for the nitric oxide reduction reaction (NORR), we adopted a strategy that considers the activity of the side reaction hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) first. It can be seen that Fe3(THT)2 (THT = triphenylene-2,3,6,7,10,11-hexathiol) has extremely excellent HER activity, with a Gibbs free energy change (&#916;G) of 0.007 eV. Based on the relationship between &#916;G and theoretical exchange current density, all TM3(THT)2 can be divided into two regions: one is the absolute values of &#916;G greater than 1 eV, the other is the absolute values of &#916;G greater than 0 eV and less than 1eV. Obviously, the candidates with the absolute values of &#916;G greater than 1 eV have poor HER performance, but this precisely provides the possibility of obtaining NORR catalytic materials with both excellent selectivity and activity. Subsequent calculation results show that the maximum &#916;G change of the rate-determining step of Ta3(THT)2 is unexpectedly only 0.05 eV. Therefore, Ta3(THT)2 may be regarded as the NORR catalytic material with both excellent performance and selectivity. Based on the electron transfer and partial density of states (PDOS) analysis, it can be seen that Ta plays a crucial role in the activation stage of NO. The approach that considers the activity of the side reaction HER first may provide a new idea for rapidly screening highly selective and active NORR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Lixin Ye, Mengyun Mei, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton exchange membrane&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems for hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.629</link>
      <description>Yangyang Zhou, H. Zhong, Shanhu Chen, Guobin Wen, Liang Shen, Yanyong Wang, Ru Chen, Li Tao, Wang Shuangyin, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403602672

                Abstract Hydrogen energy from electrocatalysis driven by sustainable energy has emerged as a solution against the background of carbon neutrality. Proton exchange membrane (PEM)&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems represent a promising technology for hydrogen production, which is equipped to combine efficiently with intermittent electricity from renewable energy sources. In this review, PEM&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems for H 2 production are summarized systematically from low to high operating temperature systems. When the operating temperature is below 130&#176;C, the representative device is a PEM water electrolyzer; its core components and respective functions, research status, and design strategies of key materials especially in electrocatalysts are presented and discussed. However, strong acidity, highly oxidative operating conditions, and the sluggish kinetics of the anode reaction of PEM water electrolyzers have limited their further development and shifted our attention to higher operating temperature PEM systems. Increasing the temperature of PEM&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems can cause an increase in current density, accelerate reaction kinetics and gas transport and reduce the ohmic value, activation losses, &#916; G H* , and power consumption. Moreover, further increasing the operating temperature (120&#8211;300&#176;C) of PEM&#8208;based devices endows various hydrogen carriers (e.g., methanol, ethanol, and ammonia) with electrolysis, offering a new opportunity to produce hydrogen using PEM&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems. Finally, several future directions and prospects for developing PEM&#8208;based electrocatalytic systems for H 2 production are proposed through devoting more efforts to the key components of devices and reduction of costs.</description>
      <author>Yangyang Zhou, H. Zhong, Shanhu Chen, Guobin Wen, Liang Shen, Yanyong Wang, Ru Chen, Li Tao, Wang Shuangyin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASIMTools: A lightweight framework for scalable and reproducible atomic simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07085</link>
      <description>Mgcini Keith Phuthi, Emil Annevelink, Venkatasubramanian Viswanathan, The Journal of Open Source Software. 9(102)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403614018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mgcini Keith Phuthi, Emil Annevelink, Venkatasubramanian Viswanathan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.07085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Site-Enabled O&#8211;O Coupling in Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</link>
      <description>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403624087

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring pyrolusite &#946;-MnO2 as a robust support for noble metal catalysts in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.246</link>
      <description>Nur Tursina, Ashish Gaur, Min Su Cho, Mingony Kim, Kyung Yoon Chung, Sungwook Mhin, H. Han, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403626456

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nur Tursina, Ashish Gaur, Min Su Cho, Mingony Kim, Kyung Yoon Chung, Sungwook Mhin, H. Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir Doping Modulates the Electronic Structure of Flower-Shaped Phosphides for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</link>
      <description>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633322

                Electrolysis of water to produce hydrogen is an efficient, clean, and environmentally friendly hydrogen production method with unlimited development prospects. However, its overall efficiency is hampered by the slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with complex electron transfer processes. Therefore, designing efficient and low-cost OER catalysts is the key to solving this problem. In this paper, Ir-doped Co</description>
      <author>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into efficient electrocatalysts for nitrogen reduction reaction by transition metal atoms supported on g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114932</link>
      <description>Pengfei Ma, Rui Wang, Chengsong Liu, Pengfei Liu, Chaozheng He, Wei Song, Tao Zhang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403645722

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Ma, Rui Wang, Chengsong Liu, Pengfei Liu, Chaozheng He, Wei Song, Tao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114932</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single&#8208;Nanometer Spinel with Precise Cation Distribution for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202413141</link>
      <description>Long Shang, Youxuan Ni, Yuankun Wang, Wenxuan Yang, Linyue Wang, Haixia Li, Kai Zhang, Zhenhua Yan, Jun Chen, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403646233

                Abstract Designing spinel nanocrystals (NCs) with tailored structural composition and cation distribution is crucial for superior catalytic performance but remarkably challenging due to their intricate nature. Here, an aggregation growth restricted hot&#8208;injection method is presented by meticulously investigating the fundamental nucleation and aggregation&#8208;driven growth kinetics governing spinel NC formation to address this challenge. Through controlled collision probability of nuclei during growth, this approach enables the synthesis of spinel NCs with unprecedented, single nanometer (1.2 nm). Single&#8208;nanometer CoMn 2 O 4 spinel via this method exhibits a highly tailored structure with a maximized population of highly active octahedral Mn atoms, thereby optimizing oxygen intermediate adsorption during oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Consequently, it exhibits a remarkable half&#8208;wave potential of 0.88 V in ORR and leads to a superior power density (170.9 mW cm &#8722;2 ) in zinc&#8211;air battery, outperforming commercial Pt/C and most reported spinel oxides, revealing a clear structure&#8211;property relationship. This structure design strategy is readily adaptable for the precise synthesis and engineering of various spinel structures, opening new avenues for developing advanced electrocatalysts and energy storage materials.</description>
      <author>Long Shang, Youxuan Ni, Yuankun Wang, Wenxuan Yang, Linyue Wang, Haixia Li, Kai Zhang, Zhenhua Yan, Jun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202413141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of unique electronic structures of single-atom alloys unraveled by interpretable deep learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232141</link>
      <description>Yang Huang, Shih&#8208;Han Wang, Luke E. K. Achenie, Kamal Choudhary, Hongliang Xin, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403649617

                We uncover the origin of unique electronic structures of single-atom alloys (SAAs) by interpretable deep learning. The approach integrates tight-binding moment theory with graph neural networks to accurately describe the local electronic structure of transition and noble metal sites upon perturbation. We emphasize the complex interplay of interatomic orbital coupling and on-site orbital resonance, which shapes the d-band characteristics of an active site, shedding light on the origin of free-atom-like d-states that are often observed in SAAs involving d10 metal hosts. This theory-infused neural network approach significantly enhances our understanding of the electronic properties of single-site catalytic materials beyond traditional theories.</description>
      <author>Yang Huang, Shih&#8208;Han Wang, Luke E. K. Achenie, Kamal Choudhary, Hongliang Xin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress and challenges in structural, &lt;i&gt;in situ&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;operando&lt;/i&gt; characterization of single-atom catalysts by X-ray based synchrotron radiation techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00967j</link>
      <description>Yuhang Liu, Xiaozhi Su, Jie Ding, Jing Zhou, Zhen Liu, Xiangjun Wei, Hong Bin Yang, Bin Liu, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403655107

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) represent the ultimate size limit of nanoscale catalysts, combining the advantages of homogeneous and heterogeneous catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Liu, Xiaozhi Su, Jie Ding, Jing Zhou, Zhen Liu, Xiangjun Wei, Hong Bin Yang, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00967j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring reactivity of small Ag/Pt bimetallic cluster for ORR: A comprehensive study using density functional theory approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115102</link>
      <description>Sandeep Nigam, Chiranjib Majumder, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403656378

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sandeep Nigam, Chiranjib Majumder</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the multifaceted potential of copper sulfide heterojunctions for sustainable energy solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.042</link>
      <description>Ahmad Farhan, Aman Khalid, Wajeeha Qayyum, Saima Noreen, Asim Jilani, Rizwan Haider, Qamar Abbas, Muhammad Zahid, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403672940

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ahmad Farhan, Aman Khalid, Wajeeha Qayyum, Saima Noreen, Asim Jilani, Rizwan Haider, Qamar Abbas, Muhammad Zahid</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reaction Activity of Transition Metal-Doped T-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Monolayer: A Density Functional Theory Study Assisted by Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04467</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Lin Ju, Zhenjie Tang, Shu Zhang, Genqiang Zhang, Wentao Wang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403674764

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Lin Ju, Zhenjie Tang, Shu Zhang, Genqiang Zhang, Wentao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest advances in the deep reconstruction of pre-catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177225</link>
      <description>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403679718

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemistry In Rechargeable Zinc-Air battery: A Mechanistic Overview</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115108</link>
      <description>Arkaj Singh, Ravinder Sharma, A. K. Gautam, Bindey Kumar, Sneha Mittal, Aditi Halder, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403679884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arkaj Singh, Ravinder Sharma, A. K. Gautam, Bindey Kumar, Sneha Mittal, Aditi Halder</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pythonic Chemistry: The Beginner&#8217;s Guide to Digital Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jchemed.4c00840</link>
      <description>Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Diego Garay&#8208;Ruiz, Journal of Chemical Education. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403685033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Diego Garay&#8208;Ruiz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jchemed.4c00840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diatomic Active Sites Embedded Graphyne as Electrocatalysts for Ammonia Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13025</link>
      <description>Xiaoting Chen, Man-Rong Zhao, Bingyi Song, Guoliang Li, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403685995

                Ammonia (NH</description>
      <author>Xiaoting Chen, Man-Rong Zhao, Bingyi Song, Guoliang Li, Li&#8208;Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Doping Effects in a V-Doped Ni Catalyst for Hydrogen Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03785</link>
      <description>Siguang Lu, Luhong Fu, Fulin Yang, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403686539

                The improved performance of soluble metal-doped Ni catalysts is perplexed by the evolvable surface structures in the alkaline electrolytes for hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR). Herein, V-doped Ni nanoparticles, as a proof of concept, were carefully evaluated to explore the intrinsic function of the enthetic V-species in assisting the HOR kinetic improvement. As expected, it exhibits a mass-normalized kinetic current density of 50.34 mA mg</description>
      <author>Siguang Lu, Luhong Fu, Fulin Yang, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combining Hammett &lt;i&gt;&#963;&lt;/i&gt; constants for &#916;-machine learning and catalyst discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00228h</link>
      <description>V. Diana Rakotonirina, Marco Bragato, Stefan Heinen, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403687003

                We present a simple and fast linear model for discovering organometallic catalysts for the Suzuki&#8211;Miyaura cross-coupling reaction, using a combinatorial approach.</description>
      <author>V. Diana Rakotonirina, Marco Bragato, Stefan Heinen, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00228h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Activity on Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C and Promoting C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Product by Grain Boundary Engineering: Insights from First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03202</link>
      <description>Yuxing Lin, Fang-Qi Yu, Lei Li, Yameng Li, Rao Huang, Yu&#8208;Hua Wen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403687778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxing Lin, Fang-Qi Yu, Lei Li, Yameng Li, Rao Huang, Yu&#8208;Hua Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Two&#8208;Electron Water Oxidation Reaction for Hydrogen Peroxide Production: Catalyst Design and Interface Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401100</link>
      <description>Hu Cao, Guangming Chen, Yong Yan, Dong Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403689728

                Abstract Hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) is a versatile and zero&#8208;emission material that is widely used in the industrial, domestic, and healthcare sectors. It is clear that it plays a critical role in advancing environmental sustainability, acting as a green energy source, and protecting human health. Conventional production techniques focused on anthraquinone oxidation, however, electrocatalytic synthesis has arisen as a means of utilizing renewable energy sources in conjunction with available resources like oxygen and water. These strides represent a substantial change toward more environmentally and energy&#8208;friendly H 2 O 2 manufacturing techniques that are in line with current environmental and energy goals. This work reviews recent advances in two&#8208;electron water oxidation reaction (2e&#8208;WOR) electrocatalysts, including design principles and reaction mechanisms, examines catalyst design alternatives and experimental characterization techniques, proposes standardized assessment criteria, investigates the impact of the interfacial milieu on the reaction, and discusses the value of in situ characterization and molecular dynamics simulations as a supplement to traditional experimental techniques and theoretical simulations, as shown in Figure 1. The review also emphasizes the importance of device design, interface, and surface engineering in improving the production of H 2 O 2 . Through adjustments to the chemical microenvironment, catalysts can demonstrate improved performance, opening the door for commercial applications that are scalable through tandem cell development.</description>
      <author>Hu Cao, Guangming Chen, Yong Yan, Dong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Chemical and Catalytic Activity of Metal Surface Sites by Controlling Strain and Ligand Effects in Nonmodel Nanoparticle Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03857</link>
      <description>Bill Yan, Suljo Linic, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403692782

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bill Yan, Suljo Linic</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru/MgO Catalysts Modified with Various Alkali Metals (Na, Cs, K) for CO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-Free H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production from NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03658</link>
      <description>Tianxu Su, Bin Guan, Chunzheng Zheng, Jiefei Zhou, Zhen Huang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403692862

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianxu Su, Bin Guan, Chunzheng Zheng, Jiefei Zhou, Zhen Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Surface Dealloying for Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co/C Catalysts with a Pt-Enriched Surface for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02062</link>
      <description>Mingjie Xu, Ye Xiao, Jingxi Zhang, Yuting Xia, Tianli Liu, Yanhao Dong, Chang&#8208;An Wang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403693496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingjie Xu, Ye Xiao, Jingxi Zhang, Yuting Xia, Tianli Liu, Yanhao Dong, Chang&#8208;An Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Machine Learning to Expedite Screening of Single-atom Catalysts in Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177180</link>
      <description>Zhongli Lu, Jiming Liu, Houfen Li, Rui Li, Xiao Zhang, Juan Jian, Xiaoming Gao, Xuqian Zhang, Yanze Wu, Xiuping Yue, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403695068

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongli Lu, Jiming Liu, Houfen Li, Rui Li, Xiao Zhang, Juan Jian, Xiaoming Gao, Xuqian Zhang, Yanze Wu, Xiuping Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sliding catalysis for on-off switching of the hydrogen evolution reaction on two-dimensional van der Waals bilayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.22.044061</link>
      <description>Kun Liu, Xingju Zhao, Xiaoyan Ren, Shunfang Li, Physical Review Applied. 22(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403705961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kun Liu, Xingju Zhao, Xiaoyan Ren, Shunfang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.22.044061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Assisted Selection of Catalyst for &#947;-Valerolactone Hydrogenation from Levulinic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05941</link>
      <description>Liu Dongyu, Zhen Jia, Lu Shen, Wenman Liu, Ronald T.K. Pang, Shitao Yu, Shiwei Liu, Lu Li, Yue Liu, Longzhen Yu, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403716968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liu Dongyu, Zhen Jia, Lu Shen, Wenman Liu, Ronald T.K. Pang, Shitao Yu, Shiwei Liu, Lu Li, Yue Liu, Longzhen Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction on Cu-Decorated Biphenylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08499</link>
      <description>Radha N Somaiya, Muhammad Sajjad, Nirpendra Singh, Aftab Alam, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728309

                Developing efficient electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction into value-added products is crucial for a green economy. Inspired by the recent experimental synthesis of biphenylene (BPH) and the excellent catalytic activity of copper dispersed on two-dimensional (2D) materials, we chose to systematically investigate the pristine, defective, and Cu-decorated BPH for the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to value-added hydrocarbons. It is observed that the CO2 molecules bind weakly to the pristine BPH, indicating their chemical inertness. Carbon single-vacancy defects facilitate CO2 adsorption with a strong binding energy (Eb) of &#8722;3.23 eV, detrimental to the CO2 reduction reaction (CRR) mechanism. We have further investigated the binding energy and kinetic stability of Cu-decorated BPH as a single-atom-catalyst (SAC). The molecular dynamics simulations confirm the kinetic stability, revealing that the Cu-atom avoids agglomeration under low metal dispersal conditions. The CO2 molecule gets adsorbed horizontally on the Cu-BPH surface with a &#916;Eb of &#8722;0.52 eV. The CRR mechanism is investigated using two pathways beginning with two different initial states, formate (*OCOH) and carboxylic (*COOH). The formate pathway confirms the conversion of *OCOH to *HCOOH with the rate-limiting potential (UL) of 0.39 eV for the production of HCOOH, while for the carboxylic pathway, the conversion of *COH to *CHOH has a UL of 0.32 eV, eventually producing CH3OH. Our findings highlight the role of Cu-BPH as an efficient SAC for CO2 catalytic activity to C1 products, as compared to the state-of-the-art Cu, and holds promise as an electrocatalyst for CRR.</description>
      <author>Radha N Somaiya, Muhammad Sajjad, Nirpendra Singh, Aftab Alam</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mild polarization electric field in ultra-thin BN-Fe-graphene sandwich structure for efficient nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60114-2</link>
      <description>Ziyuan Xiu, Wei Mu, Xin Zhou, Xiaojun Han, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyuan Xiu, Wei Mu, Xin Zhou, Xiaojun Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60114-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miniaturized Electrochemical Gas Sensor with a Functional Nanocomposite and Thin Ionic Liquid Interface for Highly Sensitive and Rapid Detection of Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c02561</link>
      <description>Zhuoru Huang, Wenjian Yang, Yanchi Zhang, Jiaxi Yin, Xianyou Sun, Jiaying Sun, Guangqing Ren, Shichao Tian, Ping Wang, Hao Wan, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403732719

                Hydrogen has been widely used in industrial and commercial applications as a carbon-free, efficient energy source. Due to the high flammability and explosion risk of hydrogen&#8211;air mixtures, it is vital to develop sensors featuring fast-responding and high sensitivity for hydrogen leakage detection. This paper presents a miniaturized electrochemical gas sensor by elaborately establishing a nanocomposite and thin ionic liquid interface for highly sensitive and rapid electrochemical detection of hydrogen, in which a remarkable response time and recovery time of approximately 6 s was achieved at room temperature. A screen-printed carbon electrode was modified with a reduced graphene oxide&#8211;carbon nanotube (rGO-CNT) hybrid and platinum&#8211;palladium (Pt&#8211;Pd) bimetallic nanoparticles to realize high sensitivity. To achieve miniaturization and high stability of the sensor, a thin-film room-temperature ionic liquid (RTIL) was employed as the electrolyte with a significantly decreased response time. The fast-responding hydrogen sensor demonstrates excellent performance with high sensitivity, linearity, and repeatability at concentrations below the lower explosive limit of 4 vol %. The engineered high-performance interface and gas sensor provide a promising and effective strategy for gas sensor design and rapid hazardous gas monitoring.</description>
      <author>Zhuoru Huang, Wenjian Yang, Yanchi Zhang, Jiaxi Yin, Xianyou Sun, Jiaying Sun, Guangqing Ren, Shichao Tian, Ping Wang, Hao Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c02561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D single-faceted IrO2(101) monolayer enabling high-performing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis beyond 8,000 h stability at 1.5 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</link>
      <description>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745568

                Abstract Both commercially available and laboratory-synthesized IrO2 catalysts typically possess rutile-type structures and diverse facet orientations. According to the theoretical results from density functional theory calculations, distinct IrO2 facets will result in divergent electrocatalytic properties, among which the (101) crystal facet is theoretically predicted as the most energetically favorable for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) owing to its lowest energy barrier. Maintaining a single-unit-cell thickness while exposing a desired facet of 2D IrO2 presents a significant opportunity and challenge for the development of high-performance OER anode catalysts. Herein, we develop an ammonia-induced facet engineering for oriented modulation of crystal facets in the ultimate limit of monolayer thickness, and successfully synthesize 2D monolayer IrO2 exposing unique (101) facet. At the current density of 10 mA cm-2geo, an ultralow overpotential of 230 mV has been achieved on the highly activated (101) facet in a three-electrode system. More importantly, in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, the IrO2 anode reaches a low voltage of 1.74 V at an industrial-level current density of 2 A cm-2geo, much lower than that of all commercial IrO2 electrocatalysts. Though facet engineering primarily contributes to modulating the intrinsic activity rather than stability, the as-prepared IrO2(101) monolayer performs over 8,000 hours of PEM water electrolysis (PEMWE) stability at constant 1.5 A cm-2geo, with a negligible decay rate of 4.0 mV kh-1. Furthermore, even a long-term PEMWE test of 1000 h using the membrane electrode assembly (MEA) with ultra-low Ir loading of 0.2 mgIr cm-2geo under fluctuating operating conditions is performed, ECell remains highly electrochemically stable over time at 1.5 A cm-2geo, without any signs of catalyst degradation. This work proposes that ammonia-induced facet engineering of 2D monolayer IrO2 could represent a novel approach to selectively expose the desired (101) facet, thereby enabling unique facet-dependent OER performance and ultrahigh stability in industrial-scale PEM electrolysis, even under voltage fluctuations generated by solar and wind power.</description>
      <author>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chirality Engineering of Nanostructured Copper Oxide for Enhancing Oxygen Evolution from Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</link>
      <description>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745745

                Abstract The exploration of a new conceptual strategy for improving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) of earth&#8208;abundant electrocatalysts is critical. In this study, chiral copper oxide nanoflower is explored by a self&#8208;assembly method. The characterization suggests the chiral structure originates from the crystal plane&#8208;level helical stack of the secondary nanosheets. Of note, the assembly illustrates a record&#8208;high degree of spin polarization of 96%, indicating the ideal alignment of electron spin. Moreover, density function theory calculations show the chiral structure reducing the reaction energy barrier (REB) while switching the potential&#8208;determining step from *O&#8594;*OOH to *OH&#8594;*O. Together with the enhanced electrochemical active surface area and accelerated charge transfer, the production of ground&#8208;state triplet O 2 is improved via a spin&#8208;forbidden route that involves the singlet H 2 O/OH&#8226;. Consequently, the chiral nanoflower shows a overpotential of 308 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 93.5 mV dec &#8722;1 , which is even superior to the commercial RuO 2 (310 mV, 101 mV dec &#8722;1 ). This study presents a new strategy for improving the OER activity by simultaneously enhancing electronic properties and lowering the REB of an non&#8208;noble electrocatalyst via chirality engineering.</description>
      <author>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Modulation of RuCo Catalysts on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanotubes Promoting Durable Acidic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</link>
      <description>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745765

                Abstract The development of efficient and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts is essential for hydrogen production from acidic water splitting. Herein, a TiO 2 nanotube&#8208;loaded Co&#8208;doped Ru nanoparticle catalyst (RuCo/TiO 2 NTs) is reported that exhibits excellent activity and stability toward acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The Ru&#9472;O&#9472;Ti bonding is enhanced by Co doping, and the metal carrier interaction between Ru nanoparticles and TiO 2 NTs is enhanced, which effectively stabilizes Ru species during OER and initiates hydrogen spillover accelerating HER kinetics. As a result, RuCo/TiO 2 NTs catalyst requires only 156 mV OER overpotential and 17 mV HER overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a stability more than 500 h in acidic conditions. More importantly, benefiting from the excellent bifunctional activities, the proton exchange membrane electrolyte assembled from RuCo/TiO 2 NTs has excellent activity and robust stability (1000 h). This work opens a new avenue for the efficient energy conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Host-guest-induced electronic state triggers two-electron oxygen reduction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53714-3</link>
      <description>Hongni Chen, Chao Wang, Han Wu, Lili Li, Yali Xing, Chuanhui Zhang, Xiaojing Long, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403749872

                Supramolecular polymers possess great potential in catalysis owing to their distinctive molecular recognition and dynamic crosslinking features. However, investigating supramolecular electrocatalysts with high efficiency in oxygen reduction reaction to hydrogen peroxide (ORHP) remains an unexplored frontier. Herein, we present organic polymers for ORHP by introducing cyclodextrin-containing noncovalent building blocks, affording these supramolecules with abundant dynamic bonds. The electronic states and reaction kinetics are further well-modulated via a host-guest strategy, resulting in appropriate regional electron binding force and controllable chemical activity. Notably, integrating supramolecular units into phenyl group-containing model covalent polymer achieves a production rate of 9.14 mol g</description>
      <author>Hongni Chen, Chao Wang, Han Wu, Lili Li, Yali Xing, Chuanhui Zhang, Xiaojing Long</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53714-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom anchored van der Waals heterojunctions for efficient Z-scheme photocatalytic overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.308</link>
      <description>Jie Yang, Nianjun Luo, Wenyi Tang, Min-Quan Kuang, Chunling Tian, Hong Chen, Hongkuan Yuan, Biao Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403753108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Yang, Nianjun Luo, Wenyi Tang, Min-Quan Kuang, Chunling Tian, Hong Chen, Hongkuan Yuan, Biao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Catalyst Screening of Multielement Alloy Catalysts for Ammonia Synthesis Using Machine Learning Potential and Generative Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04018</link>
      <description>Kaoru Hisama, Atsushi Ishikawa, Susan Me&#241;ez Aspera, Michihisa Koyama, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403753284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaoru Hisama, Atsushi Ishikawa, Susan Me&#241;ez Aspera, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study of Highly Active Bifunctional Double-Atom Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02759</link>
      <description>Wei Zhang, Xueqi Cheng, Xiongyi Liang, Keke Mao, Xiao Cheng Zeng, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757553

                Dual-atom catalysts (DACs) can be very effective for catalyzing both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we present theoretical evidence of a new class of highly active DACs, namely, the double-atom embedded in nitrogen-doped graphene sheet 2M-N-C (M = Mn, Fe) on the basis of density functional theory calculations. Importantly, we find that the double active sites of 2M-N-C DACs entail an unconventional catalytic reaction pathway for ORR and OER. We also show that the local coordination environment of the active sites can significantly affect the stability and oxygen catalytic activity of 2M-N-C DACs. In particular, MnFe-N-C DAC not only exhibits good stability but also possesses outstanding bifunctional ORR/OER catalytic activity with the potential difference (&#916;</description>
      <author>Wei Zhang, Xueqi Cheng, Xiongyi Liang, Keke Mao, Xiao Cheng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and Activity of Organometallic Phthalocyanine Sheets for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999676</link>
      <description>Walter Orellana, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Walter Orellana</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interlayer Hydrogen Recombination from Hydrogen Boride Nanosheets Elucidated by Isotope Labeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01975</link>
      <description>Shin&#8208;ichi Ito, Kurt Irvin M. Rojas, Yukihiro Yasuda, Natsumi Noguchi, Kosei Fukuda, Miwa Hikichi, Zihao Kang, Mei Yuan, Ryuki Tsuji, Osamu Oki, Susmita Roy, Yasuyuki Hikita, Iwao Matsuda, Masahiro Miyauchi, Ikutaro Hamada, Takahiro Kondo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403761453

                In this study, deuterium boride (DB) nanosheets were synthesized as deuterated borophane through the ion exchange of magnesium cations in magnesium diboride with deuterons from a deuterium-type ion-exchange resin in acetonitrile. The Fourier-transform infrared absorption spectrum of DB exhibited clear isotope effects, namely the shift in the absorption peak of the B-H stretching vibrational mode to a lower wavenumber. Temperature-programmed desorption (TPD) from a mixture of DB and hydrogen boride (HB) nanosheets yielded a more intense hydrogen-deuterium (HD) signal compared to the H</description>
      <author>Shin&#8208;ichi Ito, Kurt Irvin M. Rojas, Yukihiro Yasuda, Natsumi Noguchi, Kosei Fukuda, Miwa Hikichi, Zihao Kang, Mei Yuan, Ryuki Tsuji, Osamu Oki, Susmita Roy, Yasuyuki Hikita, Iwao Matsuda, Masahiro Miyauchi, Ikutaro Hamada, Takahiro Kondo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace Ru Incorporation Boosted Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P Nanorods for Superior Water Electrolysis and Substrate&#8208;Paired Electrolysis Toward Value&#8208;Added Chemicals in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405056</link>
      <description>Souradip Ganguly, Pooja Basera, Sahnawaz Ahmed, Sukanta Saha, Arnab Dutta, Chanchal Loha, Sirshendu Ghosh, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776601

                Abstract Electro&#8208;valorization of biomass&#8208;derived chemicals has ensured sustainable production of value&#8208;added products, an effective approach for reducing carbon footprint, through renewable energy. Electrochemical oxidation and reduction reactions in aqueous media using H 2 O as a potential source for active hydrogenated and oxygenated species fulfill the purpose. In this study, Ru&#9472;Co 2 P nanorods are explored as a bifunctional electrocatalyst toward valorization of Organics at basic media. The in&#8208;situ electrogenerated Co 3+ and Co 4+ species act as active oxidants toward product selectivity. An overpotential of 68 mV is found for hydrogen evolution reaction (1 m NaOH) with Ru&#9472;Co 2 P. Further, used as cathode, Ru&#9472;Co 2 P effectively reduces furfuraldehyde to furfuryl alcohol and p &#8208;nitrophenol to p &#8208;aminophenol. Ru doping enables ease of formation of active species both for reduction and oxidation, faster charge transfer between catalyst to absorbates. Density Functional Theory calculation establishes Ru incorporation in Co 2 P surface results in enhanced adsorption of substrates. Ru doping modulates the electronic structure of Co 2 P which changes the density of states resulting in faster water dissociation and water splitting. To reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 current density only 1.6 V is required for water electrolysis, whereas 1.4 V is enough for substrate&#8208;paired electrolysis with simultaneous oxidation of benzyl alcohol and reduction of p &#8208;nitro phenol.</description>
      <author>Souradip Ganguly, Pooja Basera, Sahnawaz Ahmed, Sukanta Saha, Arnab Dutta, Chanchal Loha, Sirshendu Ghosh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threefold Impact on Reaction Coordinate Mapping of Zirconium Based Tri&#8208;Chalcogenide Pseudo&#8208;Monolayers as Emerging Ultrathin Catalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400816</link>
      <description>Ponnappa Kechanda Prasanna, Sudip Chakraborty, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403782112

                Abstract The continuous quest of finding optimum catalysts for photo&#8208;electrocatalytic (PEC) water splitting has been revolving around 2D ultrathin materials because of the fact of exploiting both the surface area. In this work, a threefold impact is envisaged route to enhance the activity both in terms of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in the emerging Zirconium Tri&#8208;sulfides (ZrS 3 ) based pseudo&#8208;monolayers. Due to the unique and distinct electronic properties of the tri&#8208;chalcogenide systems as compared to the di&#8208;chalcogenide counterpart of Zirconium, one could afford to explore the implications of not only single&#8208;atom functionalization and vacancy defect, but also the external strain to expedite the bifunctional catalytic activity in this promising material. Rigorous electronic structure calculations have been performed for the mentioned threefold effect on not only the band&#8208;edge alignment, but going beyond to it by further constructing the reaction coordinate mapping corresponding to HER and OER mechanism. The repercussion of external strain in addition to the single atom functionalization and vacancy defect on the adsorption free energies of the prime intermediates of HER and OER reaction has been further correlated with the work function variation in this pseudo&#8208;monolayer system.</description>
      <author>Ponnappa Kechanda Prasanna, Sudip Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing atomic-scale processes at the ferrihydrite-water interface with reactive molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12932-024-00094-8</link>
      <description>Ardalan Hayatifar, Simon Gravelle, Beatriz D. Moreno, Valerie A. Schoepfer, Matthew B.J. Lindsay, Geochemical Transactions. 25(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403782459

                Interfacial processes involving metal (oxyhydr)oxide phases are important for the mobility and bioavailability of nutrients and contaminants in soils, sediments, and water. Consequently, these processes influence ecosystem health and functioning, and have shaped the biological and environmental co-evolution of Earth over geologic time. Here we employ reactive molecular dynamics simulations, supported by synchrotron X-ray spectroscopy to study the molecular-scale interfacial processes that influence surface complexation in ferrihydrite-water systems containing aqueous</description>
      <author>Ardalan Hayatifar, Simon Gravelle, Beatriz D. Moreno, Valerie A. Schoepfer, Matthew B.J. Lindsay</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12932-024-00094-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Metal&#8208;Support Interactions in Heterogeneous Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407167</link>
      <description>Zhiqian Hou, Chenghao Cui, Yanan Yang, Zhikun Huang, Yu Zhuang, Ye Zeng, Xi Gong, Tao Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403791868

                Molecular oxygen redox electrocatalysis involves oxygen reduction and evolution as core reactions in various energy conversion and environmental technology fields. Strong metal-support interactions (SMSIs) based nanomaterials are regarded as desirable and state-of-the-art heterogeneous electrocatalysts due to their exceptional physicochemical properties. Over the past decades, considerable advancements in theory and experiment have been achieved in related studies, especially in modulating the electronic structure and geometrical configuration of SMSIs to enable activity, selectivity, and stability. In this focuses on the concept of SMSI, explore their various manifestations and mechanisms of action, and summarizes recent advances in SMSIs for efficient energy conversion in oxygen redox electrocatalysis applications. Additionally, the correlation between the physicochemical properties of different metals and supports is systematically elucidated, and the potential mechanisms of the structure-activity relationships between SMSIs and catalytic performance are outlined through theoretical models. Finally, the obstacles confronting this burgeoning field are comprehensively concluded, targeted recommendations and coping strategies are proposed, and future research perspectives are outlined.</description>
      <author>Zhiqian Hou, Chenghao Cui, Yanan Yang, Zhikun Huang, Yu Zhuang, Ye Zeng, Xi Gong, Tao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Non&#8208;Noble Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Focus on Transition and Rare&#8208;Earth Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400151</link>
      <description>Jala Bib Khan, Yuan&#8208;Chang Liang, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403792218

                Abstract The demand for renewable energy sources has become more urgent due to climate change and environmental pollution. The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role in green energy sources. This article primarily explores the potential of using non&#8208;noble metals, such as transition and rare earth metals, to enhance the efficiency of the OER process. Due to their cost&#8208;effectiveness and unique electronic structure, these non&#8208;noble metals could be a game&#8208;changer in the field. &#8242;Doping,&#8242; which is the process of adding a small amount of impurity to a material to alter its properties, and &#8242;synergistic effects,&#8242; which refer to the combined effect of two or more elements that is greater than the sum of their individual effects, are two key concepts in this field. Transition and rare earth metals can reduce the overpotential, a measure of the excess potential required to drive a reaction, thus enhancing the OER process by engineering the electronic and surface molecular structure. This article summarizes the roles of various non&#8208;noble metals in the OER process and highlights opportunities for researchers to propose innovative ways to optimize the OER process.</description>
      <author>Jala Bib Khan, Yuan&#8208;Chang Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;ROBERT&lt;/scp&gt;: Bridging the Gap Between Machine Learning and Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.1733</link>
      <description>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena, Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews Computational Molecular Science. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403697375

                ABSTRACT Beyond addressing technological demands, the integration of machine learning (ML) into human societies has also promoted sustainability through the adoption of digitalized protocols. Despite these advantages and the abundance of available toolkits, a substantial implementation gap is preventing the widespread incorporation of ML protocols into the computational and experimental chemistry communities. In this work, we introduce ROBERT, a software carefully crafted to make ML more accessible to chemists of all programming skill levels, while achieving results comparable to those of field experts. We conducted benchmarking using six recent ML studies in chemistry containing from 18 to 4149 entries. Furthermore, we demonstrated the program's ability to initiate workflows directly from SMILES strings, which simplifies the generation of ML predictors for common chemistry problems. To assess ROBERT's practicality in real&#8208;life scenarios, we employed it to discover new luminescent Pd complexes with a modest dataset of 23 points, a frequently encountered scenario in experimental studies.</description>
      <author>David Dalmau, Juan V. Alegre&#8208;Requena</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wcms.1733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO2-conjugated CoFe layered double oxides as efficient non-noble metal catalysts for NH3-decomposition enabling carbon-free hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156986</link>
      <description>Su&#8208;Un Lee, Thien An Le, Youngmin Kim, You&#8208;Jin Lee, Jeong-Rang Kim, Tae&#8208;Wan Kim, Kwang-Eun Jeong, Ho&#8208;Jeong Chae, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403656953

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Su&#8208;Un Lee, Thien An Le, Youngmin Kim, You&#8208;Jin Lee, Jeong-Rang Kim, Tae&#8208;Wan Kim, Kwang-Eun Jeong, Ho&#8208;Jeong Chae</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing 2D PtSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/PtCo Heterojunctions by Partial Selenization for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413916</link>
      <description>Bing Hao, Manyuan Gan, Jingjing Guo, Li Guo, Yanhui Song, Yongqing Shen, Bingshe Xu, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403792023

                Abstract The rational design and fabrication of 2D heterojuctions are proven a promising strategy for boosting the performance of electrocatalysts. Although 2D platinum diselenide (PtSe 2 ) exhibits catalytic activity for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the catalytic performance is still unsatisfactory due to its inert basal plane, wide bandgap, and poor electron transfer ability. Herein, a new strategy is reported to construct PtSe 2 /PtCo heterojunctions by partial selenization of PtCo alloy for high&#8208;efficiency HER electrocatalyst, which exhibits a low overpotential of 38 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , a small Tafel slope of 22 mV dec &#8722;1 , and a superior stability over 24 h and 1000 cycles. The outstanding HER activity of the catalyst arises from the strong electronic interactions between PtSe 2 and PtCo in the heterojunctions, which induce electron transferring from PtSe 2 to PtCo and the d&#8208;band center down shifting, and thus optimize the H * adsorption/desorption. This work provides a novel strategy for constructing highly efficient heterostructure electrocatalysts, which facilitates the applications of hydrogen energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Bing Hao, Manyuan Gan, Jingjing Guo, Li Guo, Yanhui Song, Yongqing Shen, Bingshe Xu, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the involvement/exclusion paradox in disaster volunteering from a field-theoretical perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2024.104913</link>
      <description>Sandra Maria Pfister, International Journal of Disaster Risk Reduction. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sandra Maria Pfister</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2024.104913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Association between Thai language proficiency and adherence to COVID-19 protective behaviors (CPB) among Myanmar migrant workers in Southern Thailand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0312571</link>
      <description>Hein Htet, Aungkana Chuaychai, Tida Sottiyotin, Kyaw Ko Ko Htet, Hutcha Sriplung, Wit Wichaidit, Virasakdi Chongsuvivatwong, PLoS ONE. 19(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403758751

                The association between host country language proficiency and disease prevention among migrants is underexplored. The objective of this study is to assess the extent to which self-reported command of the Thai language is associated with adherence to COVID-19 protective behaviors (CPB) among Myanmar migrant workers in Thailand. We distributed a self-administered structured questionnaire in Burmese language to 1,050 Myanmar migrant workers in Southern Thailand from September 2022 to January 2023. The questionnaire included background characteristics, self-reported Thai language proficiency based on the Common European Framework Reference (CEFR), and self-reported CPB adherence at residence and workplace. We analyzed data using descriptive statistics and multivariate linear regression analysis. Although slightly less than half of the participants reported CEFR A1 level or higher in Thai speaking and listening skills, less than 10 percent did so for reading and writing skills. Workplace COVID-19 preventive adherence scores were initially found to be significantly associated with A1 level or higher speaking and listening skills. However, after adjusting for confounders, these associations were not statistically significant (Speaking skill's Adjusted Beta = 0.713, 95% CI = -0.011, 1.437; Listening skill's Adjusted Beta = -0.367, 95% CI = -1.087, 0.353). No significant associations were found between any language skill domain and residence COVID-19 preventive adherence scores for both unadjusted and adjusted analysis. The study findings may have implications for relevant stakeholders in migrant services, migrant health, and infectious disease control. However, information biases, language barriers, and lack of generalizability should be considered as caveats in the interpretation of the study findings.</description>
      <author>Hein Htet, Aungkana Chuaychai, Tida Sottiyotin, Kyaw Ko Ko Htet, Hutcha Sriplung, Wit Wichaidit, Virasakdi Chongsuvivatwong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0312571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active and Stable Plasma-Enhanced ALD Pt@Ni-YSZ Hydrogen Electrode for Steam Reversible Solid Oxide Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124740</link>
      <description>Hyong June Kim, Haoyu Li, Dae&#8208;Hyun Kim, Geonwoo Park, Sung Eun Jo, Kyoungjae Ju, Geongu Han, Yongchai Kwon, Haesun Park, Min Hwan Lee, Jihwan An, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403601128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyong June Kim, Haoyu Li, Dae&#8208;Hyun Kim, Geonwoo Park, Sung Eun Jo, Kyoungjae Ju, Geongu Han, Yongchai Kwon, Haesun Park, Min Hwan Lee, Jihwan An</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124740</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
