<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 01:23:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Total Galvanic Replacement Strategy for Synthesizing Hollow Multimetallic Nanocrystals Toward Enhanced Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519243</link>
      <description>Xiaoqian Lin, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, C. C. Tseng, Shang&#8208;Cheng Lin, Zuoli He, Yi Chen, C.Y. Lin, K. Y. Lee, Chueh&#8208;Cheng Yang, Chia&#8208;Hsin Wang, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Tung&#8208;Han Yang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415039331

                Abstract The synergistic effects in multimetallic nanocrystals make them attractive catalysts, but constructing hollow architectures with controlled features poses substantial challenges. Here, the galvanic replacement reaction between Ag nanocubes and three metal precursors (Pd 2+ , Pt 2+ , and Au 3+ ) is used to demonstrate that both atomic mixing and atomic arrangements of the resulting AgPdPtAu hollow nanocrystals can be tuned through four distinct precursor addition strategies. This study reveals that increasing the mixing entropy induces a transition from phase&#8208;separated domains to a homogeneous solid solution. Moreover, preferential bonding between deposited and template metals promotes the formation of nanocubes enclosed by {100} facets with square atomic arrangements. When dispersed on semiconductor supports, these facet&#8208;controlled AgPdPtAu hollow nanocrystals exhibit enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen production. Operando synchrotron X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and density functional theory calculations reveal that Pt&#8208;containing bridge sites act as primary hydrogen adsorption centers, exhibiting high local electron density and strong hydrogen binding. Additionally, bridge sites formed by mixed&#8208;affinity metal pairs (e.g., AuPt and AgPd), coupling strongly (Pt or Pd), and weakly (Au or Ag) hydrogen&#8208;adsorbing elements, exhibit near&#8208;optimal hydrogen adsorption and serve as key active sites for hydrogen evolution. This study establishes a versatile approach for engineering multimetallic hollow nanocrystals with tunable structures for catalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Xiaoqian Lin, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, C. C. Tseng, Shang&#8208;Cheng Lin, Zuoli He, Yi Chen, C.Y. Lin, K. Y. Lee, Chueh&#8208;Cheng Yang, Chia&#8208;Hsin Wang, Kun&#8208;Han Lin, Tung&#8208;Han Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202519243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isopropanol Electro-Oxidation on PtCu Alloys for Aqueous Organic Redox Chemistry Toward Energy Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30194027</link>
      <description>Jinyao Tang, Xiaochen Shen, Laura Newsom, Rongxuan Xie, Parsa Pishva, Yanlin Zhu, Bin Liu, Zhenmeng Peng, Molecules. 30(19)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415040971

                Integration of renewable energy into modern power grids remains limited by intermittency and the need for reliable energy storage. Redox flow batteries (RFBs) are promising for large-scale energy storage, yet their widespread adoption is hindered by the high cost. In this study, we investigate isopropanol as a redox-active species with Pt-Cu alloy electrocatalysts for aqueous-organic RFBs. A series of PtxCu catalysts with varying Pt:Cu ratios were synthesized and studied for isopropanol electro-oxidation reaction (IPAOR) performance. Among them, PtCu demonstrated the best performance, achieving a low activation energy of 14.4 kJ/mol at 0.45 V vs. RHE and excellent stability at 1 M isopropanol (IPA) concentration. Kinetic analysis and in situ attenuated total reflectance-Fourier transform infrared (ATR-FTIR) spectroscopy revealed significantly reduced acetone accumulation on PtCu compared to pure Pt, indicating enhanced resistance to catalyst poisoning. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations further identified the first proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) as the rate-determining step (RDS) with C-H bond scission as the preferred pathway on PtCu. A proof-of-concept PtCu-catalyzed H-cell demonstrated stable cycling over 200 cycles, validating the feasibility of IPA as a low-cost, regenerable redox couple. These findings highlight PtCu-catalyzed IPA/acetone(ACE) chemistry as a promising platform for next-generation aqueous-organic RFBs.</description>
      <author>Jinyao Tang, Xiaochen Shen, Laura Newsom, Rongxuan Xie, Parsa Pishva, Yanlin Zhu, Bin Liu, Zhenmeng Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30194027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single&#8208;Atomic Ni&#8208;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Biofuel Cell for Mimicking Intramolecular Electron&#8208;Harnessing of Laccase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202511892</link>
      <description>Tapan Dey, Anubha Yadav, Nilanjan Seal, Babasaheb M. Matsagar, Norman C.&#8208;R. Chen, Praveen Kumar Yadav, Kevin C.&#8208;W. Wu, Amreen Bano, Saikat Dutta, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415041815

                Abstract Ni&#8211;N 4 &#8211;PAN&#8211;NC, consisting of an atomic Ni&#8211;N 4 site, mimics the intramolecular electron&#8208;harnessing of natural laccase (LAC) confined in a zeolitic imidazolate framework&#8208;8 (LAC@ZIF&#8208;8) for anodic electrooxidation of bisphenol&#8208;A (BPA). We have introduced a facile &#960;&#8208;conjugated unit of polyacrylonitrile (PAN)&#8208;resorcinol&#8208;derived N&#8208;doped conjugated &#8208;C&#8801;N. The atomically dispersed Ni&#8208;single&#8208;atom in Ni&#8211;N 4 &#8208; PAN&#8211;NC exhibits high activity for the paired electrolysis of ORR and the electrooxidation of BPA with an enhanced current density. The single Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC electrode effectively withdraws the electrons from electrooxidizing BPA due to a built&#8208;in electric field via incorporation of Ni&#8211;N 4 . The paired electrolysis of Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC biofuel cells is determined by LSV, EIS, and power&#8208;polarization curve for anodic electrooxidation of BPA. Machine learning molecular dynamics (ML&#8208;MD) simulation depicts non&#8208;covalent interaction (hydrogen bonding) between the O&#8208;hydroxyl of BPA and the N of the Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC, suggesting preferential adsorption on the Ni&#8211;N 4&#8211; PAN&#8211;NC surface via weak van der Waals interactions and &#960;&#8211;&#960; stacking between the aromatic rings of BPA and the conjugated PAN&#8208;NC. An increased power density with increased concentration of BPA in the absence of ABTS suggests a DET mechanism of BPA electrooxidation on Ni&#8211;N 4 , unlike a MET in the presence of ABTS when using LAC@ZIF&#8208;8. Thus, single atomic Ni &#8722; N 4 opens avenues with a DET mechanism.</description>
      <author>Tapan Dey, Anubha Yadav, Nilanjan Seal, Babasaheb M. Matsagar, Norman C.&#8208;R. Chen, Praveen Kumar Yadav, Kevin C.&#8208;W. Wu, Amreen Bano, Saikat Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202511892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable surface-plasma-exfoliated homogeneous ternary MoSe2/WSe2/Graphene nanosheets heterostructures as high-efficiency electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2025.100692</link>
      <description>Chang-Yu Hsiao, Phuoc&#8208;Anh Le, Ya-Wen Hsu, Jui&#8208;Cheng Kao, Chiang&#8208;Ju Chien, Jie Lin, Tzu&#8208;Ching Lu, Chun&#8208;Wei Pao, Yu-Chieh Lo, Kung&#8208;Hwa Wei, Materials Today Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415043207

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang-Yu Hsiao, Phuoc&#8208;Anh Le, Ya-Wen Hsu, Jui&#8208;Cheng Kao, Chiang&#8208;Ju Chien, Jie Lin, Tzu&#8208;Ching Lu, Chun&#8208;Wei Pao, Yu-Chieh Lo, Kung&#8208;Hwa Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2025.100692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radio Frequency-Induced Catalysis using Multi-Component Two-Dimensional Quasicrystals for Effective Sulfamethoxazole Removal from Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126062</link>
      <description>Zahoor Manzoor, R Karthik, M. Ferreira, Douglas S. Galv&#227;o, Nilay Krishna Mukhopadhyay, Thakur Prasad Yadav, Prikshat Dadhwal, Pranith Chander Saka, Cristiano F. Woellner, Shamik Chowdhury, Chandra Sekhar Tiwary, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415043622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahoor Manzoor, R Karthik, M. Ferreira, Douglas S. Galv&#227;o, Nilay Krishna Mukhopadhyay, Thakur Prasad Yadav, Prikshat Dadhwal, Pranith Chander Saka, Cristiano F. Woellner, Shamik Chowdhury, Chandra Sekhar Tiwary</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect on magnetic and electronic structure through hole substitution in pseudo-1-D spin chain compound NiTe2O5</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417854</link>
      <description>Avinash Chandra Maurya, D. Pal, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415043905

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Avinash Chandra Maurya, D. Pal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When wall slip wins over shear flow: A temperature-dependent Eyring slip law and a thermal multiscale model for diamond-like carbon lubricated by a polyalphaolefin oil</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2025.111305</link>
      <description>Stefan Peeters, Edder J. Garc&#237;a, Franziska Stief, Thomas Reichenbach, Kerstin Falk, Gianpietro Moras, Michael Moseler, Tribology International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415045380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefan Peeters, Edder J. Garc&#237;a, Franziska Stief, Thomas Reichenbach, Kerstin Falk, Gianpietro Moras, Michael Moseler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2025.111305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroelectric phase transition in group-IV monochalcogenides from an equivariant machine learned force field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/t63g-4zp3</link>
      <description>Tina N. Mihm, Kasidet Jing Trerayapiwat, Pierre Darancet, Sahar Sharifzadeh, Physical Review Materials. 9(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415046901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tina N. Mihm, Kasidet Jing Trerayapiwat, Pierre Darancet, Sahar Sharifzadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/t63g-4zp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient local atomic cluster expansion for &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;BaTiO&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; close to equilibrium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/fnb6-vzyq</link>
      <description>Anna Gr&#252;nebohm, Matous Mrovec, Maxim N. Popov, L.&#8208;S. Hsu, Yury Lysogorskiy, Anton Bochkarev, Ralf Drautz, Physical Review Materials. 9(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415046938

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna Gr&#252;nebohm, Matous Mrovec, Maxim N. Popov, L.&#8208;S. Hsu, Yury Lysogorskiy, Anton Bochkarev, Ralf Drautz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/fnb6-vzyq</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron transfer and hydrogen spillover Co-driven to enhance hydrogen evolution reaction over oxygen-deficient tungsten oxide-supported iridium clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164792</link>
      <description>Zihao Fan, Chong Gao, Guangping Lei, Huiyuan Cheng, Bo Pang, Fujun Cui, Xuemei Wu, Wanting Chen, Xiangcun Li, Gaohong He, Applied Surface Science. 717(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415054003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihao Fan, Chong Gao, Guangping Lei, Huiyuan Cheng, Bo Pang, Fujun Cui, Xuemei Wu, Wanting Chen, Xiangcun Li, Gaohong He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Ni via heterostructure-induced electron deficiency and spatial intermediate coupling for enhanced alkaline HER/HOR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126069</link>
      <description>W. Liang, Zixuan Dan, Xiyu Gong, Jinchang Xu, Hongjuan Wang, Yonghai Cao, Hao Yu, Yanshuo Jin, Haofan Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415059325

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W. Liang, Zixuan Dan, Xiyu Gong, Jinchang Xu, Hongjuan Wang, Yonghai Cao, Hao Yu, Yanshuo Jin, Haofan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Center Inheritance: A Design Principle for Constructing Atomically Dispersed Bimetallic OER/ORR Catalysts Derived from Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04004</link>
      <description>Wenwen Li, Yiming Mo, Lingzhi Kang, Caixia Li, Jingnan Zheng, Chenglong Qiu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415068230

                Atomically dispersed bimetallic catalysts (ADCs), an emerging class of electrocatalysts, combine the synergistic advantages of dual-metal active sites with the atomic dispersion and high metal utilization efficiency characteristic of single-atom catalysts (SACs). Their unique structural features offer the potential to exceed the catalytic performance of conventional systems but simultaneously pose challenges due to the absence of well-established rational design principles. This paper proposes and validates a structural design strategy, "Active Center Inheritance," wherein high-performance SACs are transformed into ADCs by retaining the same active center (M&#8211;Nx). This approach not only preserves high catalytic activity but also significantly reduces the computational cost associated with density functional theory (DFT) calculations over 13,500 candidate systems, thereby accelerating the discovery of bifunctional electrocatalysts. A total of 17 high-performance oxygen evolution reaction (OER)/oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) bifunctional catalysts were identified through this strategy. This strategy was successfully generalized to three other ADC structural systems with different spatial arrangements. Moreover, a unified descriptor (&#966;), composed of four key electronic and atomic features, was constructed to effectively correlate the adsorption behaviors of critical reaction intermediates (*OH, *O, and *OOH) across diverse systems. The results reveal that SACs and ADCs can achieve comparable catalytic activity when constructed with the same M&#8211;Nx active center, thereby enabling the synergistic optimization of active sites. This work provides a theoretical basis and a rational design framework for the development of efficient multisite electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Wenwen Li, Yiming Mo, Lingzhi Kang, Caixia Li, Jingnan Zheng, Chenglong Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Electronic Descriptors for BaMO&#8323; (M=Sc to Zn) Perovskite ORR/OER Electrocatalysis: Decoding Bond Strength, Orbital Hybridization, and Electron Transfer Synergy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5589106</link>
      <description>Taoda Liu, Sheng Ma, Xiaohong Zhang, Jiaqi Wang, Zhong&#8208;Qun Tian, Yajie Dou, Zhiwei Peng, Tian Ouyang, Binbin Lin, Xiao-Ling He, Wenyan Tao, Yinghua Niu, Yinghua Niu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415069318

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Taoda Liu, Sheng Ma, Xiaohong Zhang, Jiaqi Wang, Zhong&#8208;Qun Tian, Yajie Dou, Zhiwei Peng, Tian Ouyang, Binbin Lin, Xiao-Ling He, Wenyan Tao, Yinghua Niu, Yinghua Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5589106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Text Mining and Quantum Simulations for the Design of 2D Monochalcogenide Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04625</link>
      <description>Mateus B. P. Querne, M. Machado, Ronaldo C. Prati, Natan M. Regis, Matheus P. Lima, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415077896

                The formulation of a structured framework dedicated to the systematic review of the literature, identification of potential compounds, theoretical quantum chemistry characterization, and assessment of the significance of stability descriptors is essential for accelerating the discovery of two-dimensional materials for technological applications. In this work, we selected the two-dimensional monochalcogenides (MQ), which have attracted increased interest due to their potential applications in future devices, as prototype materials for the present investigation. Our framework started with a natural language processing analysis of more than 5400 articles, revealing a growing research interest in the two-dimensional MQ compounds, especially in electronics, energy, and fundamental studies. This led to the selection of 27 diverse MQ compounds across 13 distinct two-dimensional structural phases for density functional theory calculations, resulting in an extensive database of physicochemical properties. We evaluated formation enthalpies, uncovering clear stability trends (e.g., stability declines with heavier chalcogens, dynamic robustness of GeSe), and evaluated equilibrium lattice parameters, noting predictable expansions and significant anisotropies. Bader charge analysis offered insights into charge-transfer and ionicity trends. Our electronic structure analysis identified band gaps (direct or indirect, depending on the M element group and the weight of the chalcogen) and optical absorption anisotropies significantly influenced by crystal symmetry and spin orbit coupling. Importantly, band alignment calculations classified all possible heterojunctions as type I, II, or III, underscoring their extensive potential for future optoelectronic device development. Additionally, we incorporated machine learning, using a random forest approach, along with our density functional theory calculations to accurately forecast trends in energetic properties. This analysis identified the electronic charge as a highly significant stability descriptor among the 34 descriptors, underscoring its importance for future machine learning endeavors. Hence, this study offers a streamlined framework for the characterization and discovery of promising two-dimensional materials, highlighting the synergy between data-driven analysis and quantum-based simulations.</description>
      <author>Mateus B. P. Querne, M. Machado, Ronaldo C. Prati, Natan M. Regis, Matheus P. Lima, Juarez L. F. Da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04625</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Oxidation in Medium-Entropy Spinel Oxides via Lattice Oxygen Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02570</link>
      <description>Mao Sun, Yu Tang, Jike Wang, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415094215

                The development of efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts requires advancements in both the mechanism understanding and material design. The lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) typically has a lower thermodynamic barrier than the absorbate evolution mechanism (AEM), yet controlling the OER pathway from the AEM to the LOM remains challenging. Here, we demonstrate efficient lattice oxygen activation in a spinel-structured CoFeMoRu medium-entropy oxide (CoFeMoRuMEO) catalyst through strategic octahedral engineering. The introduction of Mo increases the electron density at the Co sites, thereby weakening OH adsorption and suppressing CoOOH formation via the AEM pathway. Meanwhile, compressed RuO6 octahedra create shortened Ru&#8211;O bonds, enhancing Ru&#8211;O covalency and facilitating the critical O&#8211;O coupling step. As a result, the CoFeMoRuMEO catalyst achieves a remarkable overpotential of 168 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, setting a new benchmark for medium-to-high-entropy OER catalysts. Our work provides valuable insights into the transformation of the OER mechanism and performance optimization.</description>
      <author>Mao Sun, Yu Tang, Jike Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of Fe loss to promote reconstructed surface via black phosphorus over NiFeB nanosheets for efficient water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169571</link>
      <description>Zehao Wang, Huayu Chen, Yesheng Fu, Yin Hang, Dandan Yu, Junhui Liang, Yuexiang Huang, Liuqi Wang, Wei Gao, Da Chen, Yang Hou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415094324

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zehao Wang, Huayu Chen, Yesheng Fu, Yin Hang, Dandan Yu, Junhui Liang, Yuexiang Huang, Liuqi Wang, Wei Gao, Da Chen, Yang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the spin-lattice-band coupling driven photocatalytic selectivity in CuFeO2 single crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.184295</link>
      <description>Sz&#8208;Chian Liou, Xianglin Huang, Yucheng Lan, Shih&#8208;Yun Chen, Ting-Rong Ko, Heng&#8208;Liang Wu, Hsiang&#8208;Lin Liu, Hsin&#8208;An Chen, Guo&#8208;Jiun Shu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1043(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415098485

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sz&#8208;Chian Liou, Xianglin Huang, Yucheng Lan, Shih&#8208;Yun Chen, Ting-Rong Ko, Heng&#8208;Liang Wu, Hsiang&#8208;Lin Liu, Hsin&#8208;An Chen, Guo&#8208;Jiun Shu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.184295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Efficient Electrochemical Water Splitting: Strategies, Mechanisms, and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.183643</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Tao, Xinxia Ma, Jiang Wu, Zhenzhen Guan, Kui Li, Yumin Qi, Jiaqi Zheng, J.J. Xue, Guoqiang Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415100124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Tao, Xinxia Ma, Jiang Wu, Zhenzhen Guan, Kui Li, Yumin Qi, Jiaqi Zheng, J.J. Xue, Guoqiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.183643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction Reaction Activity on Two-Dimensional Conductive Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks: A Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c13688</link>
      <description>Xiaoping Gao, Yanan Zhou, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415101802

                Electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) is a promising alternative to the traditional Haber&#8211;Bosch process to generate ammonia (NH3). Exploring NRR electrocatalysts with efficient performance and stability is crucial for NH3 production. In this work, on the basis of density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we systematically studied various TMO4&#8211;HTP and TMN4&#8211;HTP (TM refers to V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Nb, Mo, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ta, W, Re, Os, Ir, and Pt; HTP refers to hexatriphenylene) of conductive two-dimensional (2D) metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) as potential electrocatalysts for the NRR. The strong interaction between TM atoms and the O4&#8211;HTP/N4&#8211;HTP substrates could guarantee the thermodynamic and electrochemical stabilities of the designed TMO4&#8211;HTP and TMN4&#8211;HTP. The calculated results suggest that ReO4&#8211;HTP, MoO4&#8211;HTP, and MoN4&#8211;HTP could serve as promising electrocatalysts. Moreover, ReO4&#8211;HTP possesses the highest activity with a calculated limiting potential value of &#8722;0.34 V. Notably, ReO4&#8211;HTP exhibits good NRR selectivity with the effective suppression of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Our results contribute to searching for NRR electrocatalysts and highlight a potentially efficient class of catalysts based on 2D MOF materials for electrochemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Xiaoping Gao, Yanan Zhou, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c13688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved hydrogen evolution activity descriptors from first-principles electrochemical kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147476</link>
      <description>Dipam Manish Patel, Simiam Ghan, Andreas Lynge Vishart, Georg Kastlunger, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415122012

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dipam Manish Patel, Simiam Ghan, Andreas Lynge Vishart, Georg Kastlunger</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Deoxygenation of Phenol over Fe-Based Bimetallic Surfaces Using On-the-Fly Surrogate Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c05436</link>
      <description>Isaac Onyango, Qiang Zhu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415141532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Isaac Onyango, Qiang Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c05436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cathode Catalyst Layer Degradation in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells under Idle and Load Cycling Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01392</link>
      <description>Matthew Coats, Svitlana Pylypenko, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415143977

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matthew Coats, Svitlana Pylypenko</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Narrowing the Kinetic Gap Between Alkaline and Acidic Hydrogen Oxidation Reactions Through Intermediate Behaviors Regulated on D&#8208;p Hybridized Pd&#8208;Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202513616</link>
      <description>Lixin Su, Hao Wu, Shengnan Zhou, R. Qian, Chenxi Cui, Shaokun Zhang, Liqing Wu, Wenting Li, Huan Pang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415152029

                Abstract The kinetics of hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) decline by orders of magnitude when varying from acidic to alkaline environments. Consequently, narrowing the kinetic gap between alkaline and acidic HOR (acid&#8211;base kinetic gap) and identifying the prominent reaction intermediates under varying pH conditions remain significant yet challenging. Herein, through introducing p&#8208;block Ga and Sn elements, the HOR behaviors of the constructed d&#8208;p hybridized Pd&#8208;based catalysts are investigated under different electrolyte pH, particularly in alkaline and acidic conditions. Remarkably, the specific activity of PdGa/C alloy surpasses that of other prepared Pd&#8208;based catalysts in both alkaline and acidic electrolytes. Additionally, the PdGa/C alloy exhibits the smallest acid&#8211;base kinetic gap among these catalysts. Combining experimental results and theoretical calculations, it is determined that the incorporation of Ga optimizes the electronic structure of Pd via d&#8208;p orbital hybridization, thereby enhancing the adsorption behaviors of reaction intermediates, facilitating the HOR process, and narrowing the acid&#8211;base kinetic gap. More critically, it can be inferred that the decisive reaction species for HOR vary with increasing pH, namely, it transitions from H/H 2 O species in acidic conditions to OH/H 2 O species in alkaline conditions, which accounts for the observed trends in alkaline/acidic activity as well as acid&#8211;base kinetic gap.</description>
      <author>Lixin Su, Hao Wu, Shengnan Zhou, R. Qian, Chenxi Cui, Shaokun Zhang, Liqing Wu, Wenting Li, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202513616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au&#8211;Pd core&#8211;shell nanoparticles for enhanced catalytic performance in liquid-phase selective hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cy00889a</link>
      <description>Marta Perx&#233;s Perich, Kristiaan H. Helfferich, Petra E. de Jongh, Jessi E. S. van der Hoeven, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415153541

                Au&#8211;Pd core&#8211;shell nanoparticles outperform monometallic and alloyed counterparts in the liquid-phase selective hydrogenation of MBY.</description>
      <author>Marta Perx&#233;s Perich, Kristiaan H. Helfferich, Petra E. de Jongh, Jessi E. S. van der Hoeven</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cy00889a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Metal-Doped Graphitic Materials for Enhanced Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c10546</link>
      <description>Vy T. Nguyen, Xueyan Lin, Rishav Kumar Baranwal, Haiyan Tan, David P. Wright, Zhaoyang Fan, Bin Wang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415165641

                Atomically dispersed metal atoms within graphitic carbon have shown great potential in enhancing the performance of lithium&#8211;sulfur batteries (LSBs), though the fundamental principles to guide their rational design remain to be fully established. Here, we report a combined computational and experimental study demonstrating that a group of metals (Ti, V, Mo, and Nb) incorporated into graphitic carbon have promising catalytic properties due to three factors: strong binding with lithium sulfides, reduced redox overpotentials, and low kinetic barriers for Li&#8211;S bond activation. In contrast, metals such as Fe and Mn show moderate catalytic behavior, while Ni representing a third group of elements has worse performance. To validate these computational predictions, we synthesized and studied three representative metal elements&#9472;Nb, Fe, and Ni&#9472;each exhibiting distinct capabilities in binding LiPSs/Li2S and catalyzing polysulfide conversion with varying overpotentials and kinetic barriers. Among them, Nb delivered the most exceptional performance, including superior rate capability (679.3 mA h g&#8211;1 at 5 C), high capacity retention (837.5 mA h g&#8211;1), and a low capacity decay rate (0.023% per cycle) after 500 cycles at 1 C. This work demonstrates an effective strategy that combines theoretical screening and experimental validation in exploring atomically dispersed metal catalysts for LSBs.</description>
      <author>Vy T. Nguyen, Xueyan Lin, Rishav Kumar Baranwal, Haiyan Tan, David P. Wright, Zhaoyang Fan, Bin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c10546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Ionic&#8211;Covalent Bonds Achieve Durable Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12381</link>
      <description>Shicheng Zhu, Ruoou Yang, Yingying Xu, Xintong Li, Zhengxuan Shi, Lin Yu, Youwen Liu, Huiqiao Li, Tianyou Zhai, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415166781

                The widespread deployment of proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis is hindered by the instability of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts under acidic conditions, stemming from coupled degradation mechanisms: lattice oxygen overoxidation (driven by high metal-oxygen (M-O) covalency) and acid-induced metal leaching/collapse. Here, we introduce an electronegativity-guided Li- and Ru-doped spinel Co3O4 (LRCO) catalyst featuring mixed Li-O (ionic) and Ru/Co-O (covalent) bonding. This design simultaneously stabilizes lattice oxygen via strong Li-O anchoring and modulates metal valence states through Ru-O-Co electron sharing, preventing overoxidation. Operando studies reveal a potential-dependent mechanism where Ru donates electrons to Co at low potentials, forming active Ru species, and electron redistribution prevents Ru overoxidation at high potentials. Crucially, Li-O bonds effectively suppress oxygen vacancy formation throughout, and Ru-O coordination remains stable, even at high potentials. LRCO achieves a record-low overpotential of 141 mV at 10 mA cm-2 with &gt;3,300 h stability. Integrated PEM electrolyzers operated &gt;720 h at 1 A cm-2, achieving a key milestone toward next-decade industry targets.</description>
      <author>Shicheng Zhu, Ruoou Yang, Yingying Xu, Xintong Li, Zhengxuan Shi, Lin Yu, Youwen Liu, Huiqiao Li, Tianyou Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination environment design for enhanced catalytic performance of diamond-based nonmetallic and single-atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta06022b</link>
      <description>Wei Cheng, Nan Gao, Shaoheng Cheng, Zhaolong Sun, Hongdong Li, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415168509

                By adjusting the ratio of B/N atoms and anchoring Sc atoms, the coordination environment is altered, effectively modulating the electronic structure of Sc@N 4&#8722; x B x and thus enhancing the electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Wei Cheng, Nan Gao, Shaoheng Cheng, Zhaolong Sun, Hongdong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta06022b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>W&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; Single-Cluster-Mediated Syngas Electrosynthesis in Single-Sandwich-Layer ZnAl-Layered Double Hydroxide Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c11814</link>
      <description>Peng Zhang, Wenxiong Shi, Hua-Qing Yin, Bao-Qin Sun, Yu&#8208;Fei Song, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Zhiming Zhang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415169242

                Syngas electrosynthesis stands as an energy-saving strategy for producing chemical raw materials, but it remains a great challenge in achieving a balance between the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Herein, a series of single-cluster catalysts (SCCs) were constructed by uniformly dispersing different polyoxometalates (POMs) into ZnAl-layered double hydroxide (ZnAl-LDH) through a simple stripping self-assembly technique, forming single-sandwich-layer-based ZnAl-POM (POM = W10, PW12, and P2W18) with abundant oxygen vacancies and zinc vacancies. The well-defined monodispersed W10 clusters function as electron sponges for reversibly accepting and releasing electrons to boost the level of CO2 reduction. The ZnAl-W10-3 can efficiently adjust HER and CO2RR to achieve a total Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 96.9% for both H2 and CO production. A broad CO/H2 ratio (0.32-1.35) can be obtained over the optimized ZnAl-W10-3 within a wide potential window (-0.8 to -2.0 V vs RHE) via adjusting the W10 amount. Systematic investigations reveal that W10-mediated electron and proton transfer processes and abundant unsaturated sites in ultrathin ZnAl-LDH significantly enhance the tunability of the CO2RR and HER activities.</description>
      <author>Peng Zhang, Wenxiong Shi, Hua-Qing Yin, Bao-Qin Sun, Yu&#8208;Fei Song, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Zhiming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c11814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Loading Single-Atom Catalyst via On-Surface Synthesis of a Metal-Covalent Organic Framework for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c02210</link>
      <description>Wenzhen Dou, Minmin Xu, Tianchao Niu, Taotao Li, Wenjin Gao, Fancang Meng, Qingmin Ji, Dar&#305;&#769;o Stacchiola, Miao Zhou, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415170372

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenzhen Dou, Minmin Xu, Tianchao Niu, Taotao Li, Wenjin Gao, Fancang Meng, Qingmin Ji, Dar&#305;&#769;o Stacchiola, Miao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c02210</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the textural properties and surface active sites of &#945;-MnO2 by Cu-doping to improve the kinetics of oxygen reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-025-15946-x</link>
      <description>Thiruvenkatam Subramaniam, B. S. Krishnaveni, I. Prakash, S. Devaraj, Journal of Materials Science Materials in Electronics. 36(29)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415171116

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thiruvenkatam Subramaniam, B. S. Krishnaveni, I. Prakash, S. Devaraj</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-025-15946-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Electric Field Governed Electronic Manipulation in Schottky Heterostructures toward Efficient Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126074</link>
      <description>Xin Wang, Mingyue Li, Nan Zhang, Guiping Ma, Ruibin Jiang, Ning Zhang, Caihong Fang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415196854

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Wang, Mingyue Li, Nan Zhang, Guiping Ma, Ruibin Jiang, Ning Zhang, Caihong Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126074</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2 hydrogenation to methanol achieved by tuning the Cu-Pd interaction in Cu nanoparticle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.119804</link>
      <description>Xiaojiao Zhang, Caixia Song, Xuan Zhao, Linkai Wang, Dong Duan, Hui Li, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415197469

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojiao Zhang, Caixia Song, Xuan Zhao, Linkai Wang, Dong Duan, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.119804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteronuclear double transition metal synergistic regulation of nitric oxide electroreduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151983</link>
      <description>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Zijian Sun, Hui Li, Lixin Ye, Mengyun Mei, Weihua Zhu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 185(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415200598

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Zijian Sun, Hui Li, Lixin Ye, Mengyun Mei, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorine and Amine Functionalized Co, Rh, and Ir-Doped Porphyrins for Oxygen Reduction and Hydrogen Evolution Catalysis: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00986-y</link>
      <description>Angappan Kausalya, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415202592

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angappan Kausalya, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00986-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid synthesis of subnanoscale high-entropy alloys with ultrahigh durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-025-02358-9</link>
      <description>Chao Zhang, Zhongliao Wang, Chang Liu, Yu Bai, Changhao Liang, Jingxiang Low, Yujie Xiong, Nature Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415208913

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Zhang, Zhongliao Wang, Chang Liu, Yu Bai, Changhao Liang, Jingxiang Low, Yujie Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-025-02358-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposition dynamics of peroxide by a redox mediator-anchored doped graphene catalyst in a Li&#8211;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp02363g</link>
      <description>Babita Behera, Bhabani S. Mallik, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415209649

                DMSO solvent and tetrachloroquinone (TCQ) redox mediator synergistically promote Li 2 O 2 decomposition at the electrode-electrolyte interface via forming LiO 2 (DMSO) 3 and Li(DMSO) 4 complex in Li&#8211;O 2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Babita Behera, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp02363g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability, electronic properties, and synergistic photoelectrocatalytic activity in corrosion-resistant seawater-splitting anodes Co2(OH)3Cl and Ni2(OH)3Cl: constant-potential dynamics via continuum solvation models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164843</link>
      <description>Jiahao Zhang, Chen Kang, Jun-Feng Dong, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen, Zijing Lin, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415215014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahao Zhang, Chen Kang, Jun-Feng Dong, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen, Zijing Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts for Electrochemical Oxidation of Ammonia: A Comprehensive Review of Fundamentals and Optimization Strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202509364</link>
      <description>Yike Ye, Chencheng Dai, Kamal Elouarzaki, Gang Wu, Zhichuan J. Xu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415215383

                Abstract The realization of a hydrogen (H 2 ) economy confronts formidable challenges in storage, transportation, and logistics. To address these challenges, H 2 carriers have been proposed as alternative solutions. Ammonia (NH 3 ), as one of the most promising H 2 carriers, becomes a game&#8208;changer, offering higher volumetric H 2 density than compressed H 2 , simplified logistics, and compatibility with existing infrastructure, which thereby reduces costs and supply chain complexities. However, fully realizing NH 3 &#8217;s potential requires overcoming downstream inefficiencies associated with its conversion either back into H 2 or into energy. Downstream processes primarily include thermal cracking, NH 3 electrolysis, and direct NH 3 fuel cells, two of which are electrochemical systems leveraging the NH 3 oxidation reaction (AOR). The efficiency of these electrochemical systems is significantly limited by severe surface poisoning and poor AOR catalytic activity, underscoring the urgent need for advanced catalyst design. Here, a comprehensive review of AOR electrocatalysis is provided, with a focus on mechanistic insights into activity&#8208;governing steps and surface poisoning pathways. Recent advances in catalyst design are summarized, and overlooked factors are highlighted for performance enhancement. Finally, perspectives on future research directions are presented for AOR catalyst development to accelerate the integration of NH 3 &#8208;based technologies into the hydrogen economy.</description>
      <author>Yike Ye, Chencheng Dai, Kamal Elouarzaki, Gang Wu, Zhichuan J. Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202509364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protective mass-charge transfer regulation layer via magnetron co-sputtering towards stable Zn anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121641</link>
      <description>Xing Fan, Zhongxiao Song, Yangyang Liu, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415215911

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xing Fan, Zhongxiao Song, Yangyang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zigzag-edged B2S nanostructures as highly efficient electrocatalysts for ammonia oxidation: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137155</link>
      <description>Yasmeen G. Abou El-Reash, Mahmoud A. S. Sakr, Abdullah N. Alotaibi, Hazem Abdelsalam, Nahed H. Teleb, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415216447

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yasmeen G. Abou El-Reash, Mahmoud A. S. Sakr, Abdullah N. Alotaibi, Hazem Abdelsalam, Nahed H. Teleb</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and electronic properties of H- and O-Functionalized Diamond (100) with variable coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2025.100580</link>
      <description>James Cruz, Hector Gomez, Michael N. Groves, Mahesh R. Neupane, Carbon Trends. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415218477

                No abstract</description>
      <author>James Cruz, Hector Gomez, Michael N. Groves, Mahesh R. Neupane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2025.100580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Bonding Mediated Interfacial Charge Transfer Between BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and {Co&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;} Cubanes for Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202523057</link>
      <description>Hao Li, Zhiang Hou, Yao Hu, Jinnan Wang, Aimin Li, Philippe F.-X. Corvini, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415218772

                Abstract Although molecular cocatalysts (MCs) have demonstrated significant application potential for photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting, the immobilization and stabilization of them for long&#8208;term application remains challenging. Herein, an integrated photoanode (BiVO 4 @NM88B(Fe)/Co 4 O 4 ) is developed by immobilizing Co 4 O 4 cubanes onto NH 2 &#8208;MIL&#8208;88B(Fe) (NM88B(Fe)) decorated BiVO 4 via site&#8208;isolation strategy. The unoccupied coordination sites in NM88B(Fe) covalently bound to both Co 4 O 4 and BiVO 4 , which significantly decreases the interfacial charge transfer resistance of BiVO 4 @NM88B(Fe)/Co 4 O 4 and achieve prolonged stability. More importantly, the oxygen evolution cocatalyst (OEC) NM88B(Fe)/Co 4 O 4 remarkably lowered the energy barrier and thermodynamically favored surface water oxidation. Consequently, the photocurrent density of BiVO 4 @NM88B(Fe)/Co 4 O 4 photoanode achieved up to 5.26 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V RHE , which is 3.73 times higher than that of bare BiVO 4 . This work presents a site&#8208;isolation strategy to overcome molecular catalyst stabilization challenges in PEC systems while offering crucial insights into designing efficient charge transfer channels between OECs and semiconductors for enhanced water splitting performance.</description>
      <author>Hao Li, Zhiang Hou, Yao Hu, Jinnan Wang, Aimin Li, Philippe F.-X. Corvini</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202523057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning&#8208;Guided Design of L1&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Type Pt&#8208;Based High&#8208;Entropy Intermetallic Compound for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202510424</link>
      <description>Zhe Wang, Xi Chen, Ting Lin, Baokun Zhang, Kepeng Song, Lin Gu, Tomas Edvinsson, Hong Liu, Rafael B. Araujo, Xiaowen Yu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415219099

                Abstract Rational design of high&#8208;entropy intermetallic compounds (HEICs) remains challenging due to complex structure&#8208;property relationships and the lack of predictive tools. Here, a data&#8208;driven framework is presented to evaluate the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity of L1 2 &#8208;type quinary Pt 3 M(4) HEICs, where M comprises any four elements from six 3 d transition metals (Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Zn). Guided by the Pm&#8208;3m space group, 15 distinct compositions with numerous microstates are designed. A deep neural network, trained on 453 computed datasets, predicts hydrogen adsorption energy (&#8710; E H* ) across 20 000 microstructures per composition, enabling statistical mapping of site&#8208;specific performance. To capture the effect of local atomic environments, a novel statistical evaluation approach is introduced that quantifies the number of microstates falling within the optimal &#8710; E H* range, advancing beyond conventional mean&#8208;based evaluations. Among all candidates, Pt 3 (CrMnFeCo) emerges as the most promising HER catalyst, validated experimentally over a wide pH range. Further in&#8208;depth data mining reveals that surface Co, Cr, and Fe optimize Pt&#8208;Pt&#8208;M sites, while subsurface Ni and Co modulate Pt&#8208;Pt&#8208;Pt interactions. This study establishes a new paradigm for HEIC catalyst design and deepens the mechanistic understanding of activity origin in complex multimetal systems.</description>
      <author>Zhe Wang, Xi Chen, Ting Lin, Baokun Zhang, Kepeng Song, Lin Gu, Tomas Edvinsson, Hong Liu, Rafael B. Araujo, Xiaowen Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202510424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of iron, cobalt and copper in nickel-based bimetal catalysts for CO2 activation - Insights from DFT and DRIFTS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115537</link>
      <description>P Athira, Koustuv Ray, Molecular Catalysis. 588(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415219969

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P Athira, Koustuv Ray</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonequilibrium molecular dynamics of ion conduction with equivariant neural network models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/fll6-v5fx</link>
      <description>Saori Minami, Alex Kutana, Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Ryoji Asahi, Physical Review Materials. 9(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415225106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saori Minami, Alex Kutana, Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Ryoji Asahi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/fll6-v5fx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric nano-disordering with favored charge and reaction kinetics to boost CO2 photoreduction with high stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169616</link>
      <description>Yan Shen, Haojie Wang, Miao Jiang, Ziting Liu, Delong Chen, Chengfei Zhu, Yong Zhou, Zhigang Zou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415226020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Shen, Haojie Wang, Miao Jiang, Ziting Liu, Delong Chen, Chengfei Zhu, Yong Zhou, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning (ML)-assisted development of 2D green catalysts to support sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5mh01739d</link>
      <description>Manshu Dhillon, Sadhan Mahapatra, Adreeja Basu, Shyam S. Pandey, Manpreet Singh Manna, Shantanu Bhattacharya, Basab Chakraborty, Ajeet Kaushik, Aviru Kumar Basu, Materials Horizons. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415209188

                Combining green-synthesized 2D nanomaterials with ML for catalytic applications to support sustainability.</description>
      <author>Manshu Dhillon, Sadhan Mahapatra, Adreeja Basu, Shyam S. Pandey, Manpreet Singh Manna, Shantanu Bhattacharya, Basab Chakraborty, Ajeet Kaushik, Aviru Kumar Basu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5mh01739d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Carbon Dioxide Capture and Electrochemical Conversion: Chemistry, Electrode and Electrolyzer Design, and Economic Viability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202502564</link>
      <description>Behnam Nourmohammadi Khiarak, Gelson T. S. T. da Silva, Hongchang Lai, Hossein Esmaeili, Anh Ngoc Nguyen, Khac&#8208;Huy Dinh, Qian Zhang, L&#250;cia H. Mascaro, Cao&#8208;Thang Dinh, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415213415

                Abstract Electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) conversion (ECC) offers a promising route to reduce CO 2 emissions and to store renewable electricity in the form of chemical fuels. To date, ECC has been mainly based on pure CO 2 gas isolated from carbon capture solutions, which is an energy&#8208;intensive step. Recently, direct CO 2 conversion from a capture solution, which enables integrated CO 2 capture and electrochemical conversion, has attracted attention because it can eliminate the energy&#8208;intensive CO 2 isolation step. In addition, producing concentrated gas products in integrated systems reduces the cost for downstream separation. This review discusses the key aspects of integrated CO 2 capture and electrochemical conversion systems, including direct air capture (DAC), the chemistry of CO 2 capture and release, electrode designs and system configurations, as well as technoeconomic viability. First, the fundamental concepts and chemistry of CO 2 capture and in situ CO 2 release in electrochemical reactors are summarized. Then, recent advancements in integrated systems are discussed, covering both system configurations and electrode designs. Potential avenues for enhancing product selectivity toward high&#8208;value chemicals, such as ethylene and ethanol, as well as lowering operating cell voltages and improving the economic viability of integrated systems, are highlighted. Finally, major technical and economic challenges as well as emerging research opportunities in the domain of integrated CO 2 capture and conversion are highlighted.</description>
      <author>Behnam Nourmohammadi Khiarak, Gelson T. S. T. da Silva, Hongchang Lai, Hossein Esmaeili, Anh Ngoc Nguyen, Khac&#8208;Huy Dinh, Qian Zhang, L&#250;cia H. Mascaro, Cao&#8208;Thang Dinh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202502564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of aluminum doping in enhancing high-temperature stability of lithium-rich cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169609</link>
      <description>Min&#8208;Ho Kim, Aditya Narayan Singh, Miran Ha, Wang&#8208;Geun Lee, Saeed Pourasad, Abhishek Meena, Haeseong Jang, Jeongwoo Seo, Jaehyun Park, Seok Ju Kang, Kyung&#8208;Wan Nam, Tae Joo Shin, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Kwang S. Kim, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415225623

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min&#8208;Ho Kim, Aditya Narayan Singh, Miran Ha, Wang&#8208;Geun Lee, Saeed Pourasad, Abhishek Meena, Haeseong Jang, Jeongwoo Seo, Jaehyun Park, Seok Ju Kang, Kyung&#8208;Wan Nam, Tae Joo Shin, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Kwang S. Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169609</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00016-3</link>
      <description>, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415297692

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00016-3</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
