<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 01:42:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced catalytic performance of CoN4 single atom catalysts by engineering the first coordination spheres</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146463</link>
      <description>Feifei Li, Lujing Zhao, W. L. Tan, Changmin Shi, Dong&#8208;Chao Wang, Guangliang Cui, Youchun Wang, Hongmei Liu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410314415

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feifei Li, Lujing Zhao, W. L. Tan, Changmin Shi, Dong&#8208;Chao Wang, Guangliang Cui, Youchun Wang, Hongmei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amine-functionalized MIL-101 sorbents modified with alkali metal cations for enhanced CO2 capture and electroreduction conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163668</link>
      <description>Min Zhang, Jieshu Zhou, Xiulan Guo, Xiangke Zeng, Lan Shi, Tingting Zhang, Yunfei He, Xintao Zhou, Shaoyun Shan, Kaili Yao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410320362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Zhang, Jieshu Zhou, Xiulan Guo, Xiangke Zeng, Lan Shi, Tingting Zhang, Yunfei He, Xintao Zhou, Shaoyun Shan, Kaili Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum Metallenes: Advanced Electrocatalysts for Sustainable Energy Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500858</link>
      <description>Mrinal Kanti Kabiraz, Hafidatul Wahidah, Jong Wook Hong, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410322801

                Abstract Platinum (Pt) metallenes, an emerging class of ultrathin 2D nanomaterials, have redefined the field of electrocatalysis, offering physicochemical properties that are completely new to conventional catalyst materials. Characterized by their high surface&#8208;to&#8208;volume ratios, abundant active sites, and tunable electronic structures, Pt metallenes exhibit remarkable efficiencies across key reactions in fuel cells and electrolyzers, including the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and liquid fuel oxidation reaction (LFOR). Overcoming the inherent limitations of rigid Pt&#8208;Pt bonds and the face&#8208;centered cubic structure, recent advances in synthesis, such as bottom&#8208;up methods and top&#8208;down exfoliation, have enabled precise control over the atomic thickness, morphology, and composition of 2D Pt metallenes. In addition, advanced engineering strategies, such as defect creation, ligand modulation, and strain optimization, have further enhanced the intrinsic activity of the active sites and tailored the electronic structures to accelerate reaction kinetics. This review provides a comprehensive analysis of the latest progress in Pt metallene research, emphasizing challenges in synthesis, structural design, and electrocatalytic applications. It is anticipated that the Pt metallenes, promising catalysts for sustainable energy technologies, will offer transformative solutions for efficient energy conversion and environmental remediation.</description>
      <author>Mrinal Kanti Kabiraz, Hafidatul Wahidah, Jong Wook Hong, Sang&#8208;Il Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-doped XC-72 enhancing cobalt selenide for high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra01039j</link>
      <description>Zhiqiang Peng, H. Li, Qihou Zhou, Tengfei Meng, Kai Huang, Chengdong Wang, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao, RSC Advances. 15(20)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410323129

                As an emerging class of anodic catalyst material for water electrolysis and hydrogen production, transition metal selenides exhibit excellent electron transport properties and multiphase structures with varying conductivities.</description>
      <author>Zhiqiang Peng, H. Li, Qihou Zhou, Tengfei Meng, Kai Huang, Chengdong Wang, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra01039j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Strain&#8208;Engineered Au&#8211;Ag Alloy Nano&#8208;Seed Network for Enhanced Electrochemical Oxygen Reduction and High&#8208;Performance Alkaline Membrane H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Air Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500555</link>
      <description>Sourav Mondal, Swapnil S. Deshpande, Sandip Kumar De, Tanmay Ghosh, Kharwar, Snehangshu Patra, Biswajit Karmakar, Arnab Dutta, Sudip Chakraborty, Dulal Senapati, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410323332

                Abstract The sluggish oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is the limiting cathodic reaction for the low&#8208;temperature H 2 &#8208;Air fuel cell. To overcome the limitations of Pt&#8208;based nano&#8208;scale materials, this work explores the possibility of a simple Au&#8211;Ag alloy&#8208;based nanosystem for enhanced fuel cell activity by exploiting their substantial electrocatalytic activity, stability, and durability toward ORR in an alkaline medium. This work further demonstrates how the ORR activity of this simple nanosystem can be further tuned by formulating an Au&#8211;Ag nanoalloy and manipulating their surface&#8208;ligand chemistry to generate a porous aggregated network structure with enriched crystal defects. The fabricated nanoalloy network follows a 4e&#713; ORR pathway with a substantially low overpotential, demonstrating the role of molecular&#8208;level strain in enhancing its catalytic activity. The enhanced catalytic activity for the ORR mechanism is validated through first&#8208;principles calculations by modeling the twin boundary at the Au&#8211;Ag nanoalloy junction. In the system&#8208;level application, this catalyst shows a peak power density of 98.18 mW cm &#8722;2 at a current density of 443.7 mA cm &#8722;2 in a single&#8208;cell H 2 &#8208;air fuel cell, comparable with a commercial Pt/C catalyst and even shows better performance at higher current density due to which it can serve as potential cathode catalyst in fuel cell devices.</description>
      <author>Sourav Mondal, Swapnil S. Deshpande, Sandip Kumar De, Tanmay Ghosh, Kharwar, Snehangshu Patra, Biswajit Karmakar, Arnab Dutta, Sudip Chakraborty, Dulal Senapati</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning&#8208;accelerated computational screening of CrNiCu ternary alloy as superior cocatalyst for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.70014</link>
      <description>Song Min Sang, Kangyu Zhang, Lichang Yin, Gang Liu, Materials Genome Engineering Advances. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410334533

                Abstract The development of cost&#8208;effective noble&#8208;metal&#8208;free cocatalysts with exceptional hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity is critical for advancing scalable and sustainable photocatalytic hydrogen production. Although platinum (Pt) remains a benchmark HER catalyst, its scarcity and high cost stimulates the search for viable alternatives. In this work, a machine learning (ML)&#8208;accelerated strategy is presented to screen highly active ternary CrNiCu alloys. Combining with density functional theory calculations, XGBoost regression models were trained to predict hydrogen adsorption energies and water dissociation energy barriers on CrNiCu alloy surfaces. Consequently, the theoretical exchange current densities were predicted for all possible compositions of CrNiCu alloys, enabling the identification of alloy catalysts with composition of 10&#8764;30 at.% Cr, 30&#8211;50 at.% Ni, and 20&#8211;60 at.% Cu that exhibits superior HER activity than Pt. Stability assessment of optimal ternary CrNiCu alloys further confirms their excellent resistance to element segregation and hydroxyl poisoning under operational conditions. This work not only identifies promising ternary CrNiCu alloys of non&#8208;noble HER catalysts but also establishes an efficient ML&#8208;accelerated computational framework for the discovery of durable high&#8208;activity alloys for renewable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Song Min Sang, Kangyu Zhang, Lichang Yin, Gang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.70014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Spin State of CoN4-C Single Atom Catalyst for Acidic Electrosynthesis of Hydrogen Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111142</link>
      <description>Yanping Zhu, Chenlu Yang, Tenglong Lu, Yuqiao Gan, Hao Zhao, Yubin Chen, Qingqing Cheng, Hui Yang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410334873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanping Zhu, Chenlu Yang, Tenglong Lu, Yuqiao Gan, Hao Zhao, Yubin Chen, Qingqing Cheng, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking machine learning models for predicting lithium ion migration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01571-z</link>
      <description>Artem D. Dembitskiy, Innokentiy S. Humonen, Roman A. Eremin, Dmitry A. Aksyonov, Stanislav S. Fedotov, Semen Budennyy, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410338500

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Artem D. Dembitskiy, Innokentiy S. Humonen, Roman A. Eremin, Dmitry A. Aksyonov, Stanislav S. Fedotov, Semen Budennyy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01571-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Charge Transport in Mixed-Valence 2D Layered Hybrid Organic&#8211;Inorganic Bronze Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01250</link>
      <description>Suchona Akter, Mohammad R. Momeni, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410343918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suchona Akter, Mohammad R. Momeni</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size and doping effects on the HER performance in Ag and Cu clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6576541/v1</link>
      <description>Uzma Zahoor, Panpan Wang, Faiyaz Shakeel, Abdul Munam Khan, Waqar Ahmed, Chong Li, Yigang Cao, Chun-Yao Niu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410345405

                Abstract Turning non-precious metals into efficient catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) presents both fundamental challenges and significant technological implications. Metal nanoclusters (MNCs) exhibit considerable potential to achieve this objective due to their quantum size effects and low-coordination environments. In this study, we comprehensively investigate the size and doping effects of silver (Ag) and copper (Cu) clusters using first-principles density functional theory (DFT). Our findings indicate that the adsorption free energies of hydrogen on both Cu and Ag clusters are enhanced compared to their periodic surface counterparts, leading to significantly improved HER performance. Specifically, for Cu clusters, Cu55 demonstrates the best HER performance with a hydrogen free energy (&#916;GH) of only &#8722; 0.02 eV at hollow sites. In contrast, Ag13 exhibits the best HER performance among Ag clusters, with a &#916;GH of -0.04 eV at bridge sites. The incorporation of nickel (Ni) and platinum (Pt) weakend the hydrogen adsorption energy of the Cu13 cluster, resulting in improved HER performance for Cu13. Partial density of states (PDOS) analysis reveals that as we transition from bulk materials to clusters, the density of states around the Fermi energy increases due to quantum confinement effects, thereby enhancing hydrogen binding ability. Also, the doping of Ni and Pt in Ag and Cu cluster can shift the position of d-band center effectively and tune the hydrogen binding ability. Furthermore, Bader charge analysis indicates that charge accumulation on the Pt and Ni-doped clusters increases with cluster size. This research provides valuable insights into optimizing catalytic activity for hydrogen adsorption across different cluster sizes, as well as in Ni and Pt-doped Cu and Ag nanoclusters in the context of HER.</description>
      <author>Uzma Zahoor, Panpan Wang, Faiyaz Shakeel, Abdul Munam Khan, Waqar Ahmed, Chong Li, Yigang Cao, Chun-Yao Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-6576541/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of Lanthanum-Based Perovskites for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction at Industrial Conditions for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01223</link>
      <description>Fabian Luca Buchauer, S&#248;ren Bredmose Simonsen, Mikael Jensen, Ivano E. Castelli, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410347148

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fabian Luca Buchauer, S&#248;ren Bredmose Simonsen, Mikael Jensen, Ivano E. Castelli, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-earth doping engineering modulates oxygen vacancy and covalent coordinate of nickel hydroxide for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237273</link>
      <description>Dunqi Lu, Shengping Liu, Zejun Pu, Xianbin Liu, Ting Liu, Yanhong Yin, Ziping Wu, Journal of Power Sources. 647(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410347509

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dunqi Lu, Shengping Liu, Zejun Pu, Xianbin Liu, Ting Liu, Yanhong Yin, Ziping Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237273</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of Diatomic Catalysts with Synergistic Effects for Enhanced OER and ORR Performance: Insights from a TM1TM2N8@BPN Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180961</link>
      <description>Wenting Li, Wenjun Xiao, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Zhen Wang, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xun Chen, Changsong Gao, Jinshun Bi, Yang Luo, Xuemin Zhang, Yao Chen, Wentao Liang, Jiaxing Liu, Xuefei Liu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410349335

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenting Li, Wenjun Xiao, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Zhen Wang, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xun Chen, Changsong Gao, Jinshun Bi, Yang Luo, Xuemin Zhang, Yao Chen, Wentao Liang, Jiaxing Liu, Xuefei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The integration of artificial intelligence and high-throughput experiments: an innovative driving force in catalyst design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjche.2025.04.012</link>
      <description>Zhi Ma, Peng Cui, Xu Wang, Lanyu Li, Haoxiang Xu, Adrian C. Fisher, Daojian Cheng, Chinese Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410350279

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhi Ma, Peng Cui, Xu Wang, Lanyu Li, Haoxiang Xu, Adrian C. Fisher, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjche.2025.04.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of a highly efficient HgAg-based Heusler alloy electrocatalyst with fully-occupied d shell for the direct electrochemical H2O2 synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163409</link>
      <description>Hui Gao, Ruikuan Xie, Guoliang Chai, Zhufeng Hou, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410351397

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Gao, Ruikuan Xie, Guoliang Chai, Zhufeng Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking efficiency Limits in solar water Splitting: Ferroelectric CuInP2Se6 with Ni Single-Atom cocatalysts for enhanced carrier separation and activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137886</link>
      <description>Anyang Wang, Xiting Wang, Xuhao Wan, Jun Jia, Zeyuan Li, Wei Yu, Jinhao Su, Zhaofu Zhang, Yuzheng Guo, Jun Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 696(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410351434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anyang Wang, Xiting Wang, Xuhao Wan, Jun Jia, Zeyuan Li, Wei Yu, Jinhao Su, Zhaofu Zhang, Yuzheng Guo, Jun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137886</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into CO and H2 Oxidation on Cu/CeO2 Single Atom Catalysts: A Computational Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02102-2</link>
      <description>Parinya Tangpakonsab, Alexander Genest, Gareth S. Parkinson, G&#252;nther Rupprechter, Topics in Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410351815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Parinya Tangpakonsab, Alexander Genest, Gareth S. Parkinson, G&#252;nther Rupprechter</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02102-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Multifunctional Electrocatalysts: Integrating DFT and Machine Learning for OER, HER, and ORR Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03213</link>
      <description>Swetarekha Ram, Albert S. Lee, Seung&#8208;Cheol Lee, Satadeep Bhattacharjee, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410355659

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Swetarekha Ram, Albert S. Lee, Seung&#8208;Cheol Lee, Satadeep Bhattacharjee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c03213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning with Interpretable Local Descriptors for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Borophene: Prediction and Physical Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00469</link>
      <description>Yi Sheng Ng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410360488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Sheng Ng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Catalytic Potential of 2D Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C for Lithium Polysulfide Conversion: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00857</link>
      <description>Shrish Nath Upadhyay, Jayant K. Singh, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410361511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shrish Nath Upadhyay, Jayant K. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c00857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in self-citation rates in high-impact neurology, neuroscience, and psychiatry journals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.88540.4</link>
      <description>Matthew Rosenblatt, Saloni Mehta, Hannah Peterson, Javid Dadashkarimi, Raimundo Rodriguez, Maya L Foster, Brendan Adkinson, Qinghao Liang, Violet M Kimble, Jean Ye, Marie C McCusker, Michael C. Farruggia, Max Rolison, Margaret L. Westwater, Rongtao Jiang, Stephanie Noble, Dustin Scheinost, eLife. 12(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410362143

                Citation metrics influence academic reputation and career trajectories. Recent works have highlighted flaws in citation practices in the Neurosciences, such as the under-citation of women. However, self-citation rates&#8212;or how much authors cite themselves&#8212;have not yet been comprehensively investigated in the Neurosciences. This work characterizes self-citation rates in basic, translational, and clinical Neuroscience literature by collating 100,347 articles from 63 journals between the years 2000&#8211;2020. In analyzing over five million citations, we demonstrate four key findings: (1) increasing self-citation rates of Last Authors relative to First Authors, (2) lower self-citation rates in low- and middle-income countries, (3) gender differences in self-citation stemming from differences in the number of previously published papers, and (4) variations in self-citation rates by field. Our characterization of self-citation provides insight into citation practices that shape the perceived influence of authors in the Neurosciences, which in turn may impact what type of scientific research is done and who gets the opportunity to do it.</description>
      <author>Matthew Rosenblatt, Saloni Mehta, Hannah Peterson, Javid Dadashkarimi, Raimundo Rodriguez, Maya L Foster, Brendan Adkinson, Qinghao Liang, Violet M Kimble, Jean Ye, Marie C McCusker, Michael C. Farruggia, Max Rolison, Margaret L. Westwater, Rongtao Jiang, Stephanie Noble, Dustin Scheinost</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.88540.4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhodium-Modified Cobalt&#8211;Organic Framework Structure: An Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Stimulate Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c00440</link>
      <description>Wenze Li, Xian-Chen Meng, Yi Liu, Mei-Yan Ren, Wen-Long Duan, Jian Luan, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410372326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenze Li, Xian-Chen Meng, Yi Liu, Mei-Yan Ren, Wen-Long Duan, Jian Luan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c00440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Approaches to Homogeneous Catalysis with Transition Metal Complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01202</link>
      <description>Luc&#237;a Mor&#225;n&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Arron L. Burnage, Ainara Nova, David Balcells, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410373768

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luc&#237;a Mor&#225;n&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Arron L. Burnage, Ainara Nova, David Balcells</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Catalytic Properties of Palladium/Gold Systems toward Hydrogen Evolution, Oxidation, and Absorption with Scanning Electrochemical Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00783</link>
      <description>Christian M. Schott, J. T. Holl&#8224;, Ra&#250;l Zazpe, Marco Kopp, Ond&#345;ej Man, Sitaramanjaneya Mouli Thalluri, Jhonatan Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Pereira, Peter M. Schneider, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Emre Kele&#351;, Pekka Peljo, Jerzy J. Jasielec, Elena L. Gubanova, Jan M. Mac&#225;k, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410375750

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Christian M. Schott, J. T. Holl&#8224;, Ra&#250;l Zazpe, Marco Kopp, Ond&#345;ej Man, Sitaramanjaneya Mouli Thalluri, Jhonatan Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Pereira, Peter M. Schneider, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Emre Kele&#351;, Pekka Peljo, Jerzy J. Jasielec, Elena L. Gubanova, Jan M. Mac&#225;k, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput calculations of spin Hall conductivity in non-magnetic 2D materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-025-00562-4</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Zhou, Samuel Ponc&#233;, Jean&#8208;Christophe Charlier, npj 2D Materials and Applications. 9(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410376035

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Zhou, Samuel Ponc&#233;, Jean&#8208;Christophe Charlier</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-025-00562-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on one-dimensional carbon nitride doped with transition metal for highly efficient and selective nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137895</link>
      <description>Chenxi Xia, Jianfeng Liu, Hongwei Li, Wei Wei, He Qiu, Lixue Xia, Yan Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410384297

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenxi Xia, Jianfeng Liu, Hongwei Li, Wei Wei, He Qiu, Lixue Xia, Yan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Study of the Mechanism of the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Catalysed by Molybdenum Phosphide in Different Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101141</link>
      <description>Nat&#225;lia Podrojkov&#225;, A. Gub&#243;ov&#225;, M. Stre&#269;kov&#225;, Ren&#225;ta Ori&#328;akov&#225;, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410384426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nat&#225;lia Podrojkov&#225;, A. Gub&#243;ov&#225;, M. Stre&#269;kov&#225;, Ren&#225;ta Ori&#328;akov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into metal-doped nanostructured hematite catalyst supported by graphene underlayer for photoelectrochemical water splitting applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44344-025-00011-w</link>
      <description>Labanya Bhattacharya, Maytal Caspary Toroker, Discover Catalysis.. 2(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410391383

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Labanya Bhattacharya, Maytal Caspary Toroker</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44344-025-00011-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the C&#8211;C coupling barrier: Surface tailoring for efficient CO2-to-C2+ electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.05.002</link>
      <description>Wasihun Abebe Hika, Asfaw G. Yohannes, Yingjie Guo, Lei Shi, Xiangyang Shi, Shilong Li, Ian D. Gates, Shenlong Zhao, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410397909

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wasihun Abebe Hika, Asfaw G. Yohannes, Yingjie Guo, Lei Shi, Xiangyang Shi, Shilong Li, Ian D. Gates, Shenlong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.05.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DFT Study: Single Transition Metal Atom Doped MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as Efficient Electrocatalysts for the Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01644</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Luo, Yu Zhang, Xun Qi, Yanjing Wu, Yiqun Fan, Dan Su, Jie Wen, Arshid Mahmood Ali, Fangli Jing, Hui Zhang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410404233

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Luo, Yu Zhang, Xun Qi, Yanjing Wu, Yiqun Fan, Dan Su, Jie Wen, Arshid Mahmood Ali, Fangli Jing, Hui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c01644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic dipole engineering for enhanced hydrogen evolution of 2D Janus MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0261849</link>
      <description>Zixuan Yang, Tao Huang, Lei Li, Hui Wan, Tao Zhang, X. S. Wang, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang, Journal of Applied Physics. 137(19)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410409153

                Harnessing intrinsic properties to modulate the electronic structure of two-dimensional (2D) materials is essential for clean energy conversion, but challenging. Herein, we demonstrate that tuning intrinsic dipole is an effective strategy to enhance hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity of 2D Janus MXenes, which is exemplified by Mo2C_XY (X/Y = O, F, S, H, OH), using density functional theory calculations. Particularly, Mo2C_OF exhibits four intrinsic dipoles (&#956;S&#8593;, &#956;M&#8593;, &#956;L&#8593;, and &#956;&#8595;), each characterized by distinct magnitudes and/or directions originated from the Mo3+ displacement and its phase change. We propose a single-atom dipole moment to elucidate the underlying mechanism controlling the variation of intrinsic dipole moments in Janus monolayer MXenes. It is found that intrinsic dipole significantly influences the HER activity. Specifically, the adsorption energy of H is reduced when the dipole direction points toward the adsorbed intermediate. Among them, Mo2C_OOH has the Gibbs free energy of &#8722;0.04 eV, surpassing the catalytic performance of commercial Pt. Furthermore, we demonstrate that intrinsic dipoles can be tuned via external strain or electronic doping, providing a pathway for optimizing catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Zixuan Yang, Tao Huang, Lei Li, Hui Wan, Tao Zhang, X. S. Wang, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0261849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of d-electron coupling in dual-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3362-8</link>
      <description>Bin Li, Y. Ren, Haiyan Wang, Chun Zhu, Jinxia Liang, Jun Li, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410412099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Li, Y. Ren, Haiyan Wang, Chun Zhu, Jinxia Liang, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3362-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatized Platform for Bandgap Optimization in Diarylethene Derivatives via Structural Substitutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70052</link>
      <description>Edoardo Fabbrini, Linh Thi Hoai Nguyen, Yasuhide Fukumoto, Yu Kaneko, Pierluigi Cesana, International Journal of Quantum Chemistry. 125(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410413212

                ABSTRACT This study presents an automated framework for discovering Diarylethene derivatives with specific HOMO&#8208;LUMO bandgaps by integrating first&#8208;principles calculations with evolutionary optimization algorithms. We develop a protocol for performing automatic, parallel Density Functional Theory calculations using Turbomole, enabled by the Atomic Simulation Environment Python wrapper. This integration allows for fully autonomous evolutionary searches, removing the need for human intervention. To evaluate our platform, we conduct searches within the chemical space of Diarylethene using two optimization strategies: A &#8220;local&#8221; strategy, which explores local neighborhoods, and a &#8220;glocal&#8221; strategy, which combines local exploration with memory of past achievements.</description>
      <author>Edoardo Fabbrini, Linh Thi Hoai Nguyen, Yasuhide Fukumoto, Yu Kaneko, Pierluigi Cesana</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.70052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in Ru electrocatalyst design for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01849h</link>
      <description>Yingde Cui, Yan Zhao, Zhen Han, Zeyu Wang, Wenjun Li, Yang Zhang, Zhijun Li, Wanglei Wang, Xiaogang Fu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410414323

                This review surveys recent advances in Ru-based electrocatalysts for the acidic OER, focusing on strategies to enhance activity and stability, mitigate Ru dissolution and performance degradation, and inform the design of robust PEMWE.</description>
      <author>Yingde Cui, Yan Zhao, Zhen Han, Zeyu Wang, Wenjun Li, Yang Zhang, Zhijun Li, Wanglei Wang, Xiaogang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01849h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable Artificial Intelligence Elucidates Synthesis&#8208;Structure&#8208;Property&#8208;Function Relationships in Nanostructured Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202420465</link>
      <description>Manu Suvarna, Marc Eduard Usteri, Frank Krumeich, Sharon Mitchell, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410414327

                Abstract Designing high&#8208;performance catalysts based on supported metal atoms and nanoparticles necessitates rigorous assembly control, which affects reactivity. Yet, attaining synthesis precision to discern catalyst speciation and properties remains challenging. This limitation is tackled by pioneering an eXplainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) methodology that combines a decision tree classifier and a random forest regressor sequentially to elucidate synthesis&#8208;structure&#8208;property&#8208;function relationships in nanostructured catalysts, exemplified for the oxygen evolution (OER) and hydrogen evolution (HER) reactions. The decision tree accurately predicts the formation of single atoms versus nanoparticles for 37 metals anchored on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon, identifying the metal's standard reduction potential and cohesive energy as determinants of speciation. The random forest regressor correlates the electrocatalytic performance of synthesized single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) to intrinsic properties, revealing a volcano&#8208;like relationship of current density with the electronegativity of the active site and metal&#8208;support interaction, providing insights beyond traditional adsorption energy descriptors. The integrated models are validated experimentally with an overall accuracy of over 80%, establishing user confidence. This XAI framework, adaptable to diverse synthetic protocols and material classes is a powerful tool to understand synthesis&#8208;structure&#8208;property&#8208;function relationships and promote data&#8208;informed experiments with reduced characterization efforts.</description>
      <author>Manu Suvarna, Marc Eduard Usteri, Frank Krumeich, Sharon Mitchell, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202420465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy&#8208;Increase Assisted Anti&#8208;Sintering for Synthesis of High&#8208;Loaded Pt Intermetallic Compounds as Electrocatalysts in PEMFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503628</link>
      <description>Y.B. Pan, Yihe Chen, Yuze Li, Mengyuan Liu, Lulu Yao, Hao Zhao, Xiaoyu Zhao, Zhouying Yue, Song Gui, Yubin Chen, Qingqing Cheng, Hui Yang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410414418

                Abstract High&#8208;loaded Pt intermetallic compounds (IMCs) present the practical application potential in low&#8208;Pt PEM fuel cells while ordering transformation under high temperature inevitably leads to severe sintering of high&#8208;density IMC nanoparticles (NPs), thus the decayed oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance. Herein, an entropy&#8208;increase assisted anti&#8208;sintering concept is proposed to fundamentally reduce the surface energy of NPs by increasing the mixing entropy, thus hindering the migration and coalescence of NPs. Ex/in situ electron microscopy and density functional theory (DFT) corroborate that the higher the entropy of pristine NPs, the lower the surface energy, the smaller the average size, and the more uniform distribution after annealing. The prepared Pt high&#8208;entropy IMC (Pt&#8208;HEI@Pt/C) demonstrates high metal loading (40.53 wt.%) and small particle size (&#8776;3.15 nm), which endow it with an excellent ORR activity with mass activity (MA@0.9V, 0.65 A mg &#8722;1 Pt ) and durability over 20k potential&#8208;cycling. Membrane electrode assembly integrated with this catalyst delivers a peak power density of 0.96 W cm &#8722;2 and an exceptional stability (12.5% decline in MA) under H2&#8208;air condition at 0.1 mg Pt cm &#8722;2 . DFT reveals the reinforced strain regulation effect of the HEI core on the Pt shell, which optimizes the *OOH adsorption and elevates the energy barrier of Pt dissolution, thus simultaneously enhancing the intrinsic ORR activity and durability.</description>
      <author>Y.B. Pan, Yihe Chen, Yuze Li, Mengyuan Liu, Lulu Yao, Hao Zhao, Xiaoyu Zhao, Zhouying Yue, Song Gui, Yubin Chen, Qingqing Cheng, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High strain rate compressive deformation behavior of nickel microparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.05.014</link>
      <description>B. Bell&#243;n, Lalith Kumar Bhaskar, Tobias Brink, Raquel Aymerich&#8208;Armengol, Dipali Sonawane, D. Chatain, Gerhard Dehm, Rajaprakash Ramachandramoorthy, Materials Today. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410420387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. Bell&#243;n, Lalith Kumar Bhaskar, Tobias Brink, Raquel Aymerich&#8208;Armengol, Dipali Sonawane, D. Chatain, Gerhard Dehm, Rajaprakash Ramachandramoorthy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2025.05.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ regulating the accessibility and structure of Fe-based catalytic sites to break trade-off between the activity and stability for oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137910</link>
      <description>He Zhang, Jinyan Wu, Chaozhong Guo, Xiaoyu Dong, Chenyang Shu, Liumei Teng, Yao Liu, Hongdian Chen, Rong Jin, Caiyi Jiang, Junjie Zhou, Yujun Si, Honglin Li, Yong Zheng Pang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410421870

                No abstract</description>
      <author>He Zhang, Jinyan Wu, Chaozhong Guo, Xiaoyu Dong, Chenyang Shu, Liumei Teng, Yao Liu, Hongdian Chen, Rong Jin, Caiyi Jiang, Junjie Zhou, Yujun Si, Honglin Li, Yong Zheng Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Atomic-Scale Compressive Strain for Oxime Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03600</link>
      <description>Lubing Qin, Yuping Chen, Ziyi Liu, Mengyao Chen, Qing Tang, Zhenghua Tang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410424796

                Tuning the surface strain is a powerful strategy to enhance the catalytic activity of metal nanocatalysts, yet an atomically precise catalyst with intramolecular strain to unlock the atomic-level strain-structure-activity relationship is still highly desired. Herein, we report the synthesis, structural anatomy, and catalytic performance toward cyclohexanone oxime electrosynthesis of an atomically precise Ag16Cu18(C&#8801;C-C6H11)24 (Ag16Cu18) nanocluster, which has a Cu6 ring in the center. The Cu-Cu distance in the Cu6 ring is only 1.616 &#197; in a single crystal, the shortest Cu-Cu bond in Cu nanomaterials to date. Furthermore, once Ag16Cu18 was loaded onto carbon paper, the ultrashort Cu-Cu bond elongated to &#8764;2.40 &#197;, still showing strong intramolecular compressive strain. Ag16Cu18 exhibited excellent catalytic activity toward oxime electrosynthesis, manifested by a maximal Faradaic efficiency, yield, and yield rate of cyclohexanone oxime reaching 47.4%, 95.4%, and 2.66 mmol&#183;h-1&#183;cm-2 at -0.35 V, respectively. In-situ attenuated total reflection surface-enhanced infrared spectroscopy revealed that the Cu sites adjacent to the Ag atoms primarily reduce NO and stabilize it at the *NH2OH stage, while the Cu sites with compressive strain provide H* for NO reduction and adsorb cyclohexanone to react with *NH2OH, forming cyclohexanone oxime simultaneously. Density functional theory calculations confirmed the presence of compressive strain in the Cu6 ring, which facilitates H* formation and cyclohexanone adsorption, hence significantly contributing to oxime generation. This study not only reports a case of atomically precise clusters with intramolecular compressive strain but also provides an atomic-level understanding for employing bimetallic nanocluster-based catalysts toward the electrosynthesis of valuable organic molecules.</description>
      <author>Lubing Qin, Yuping Chen, Ziyi Liu, Mengyao Chen, Qing Tang, Zhenghua Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03600</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting practical reduction potential of electrolyte solvents via computational hydrogen electrode and interpretable machine-learning models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01582-w</link>
      <description>Zonglin Yi, Yitong Zhou, Huan Liu, Li Li, Yan Zhao, Jiayuan Li, Yixuan Mao, Fangyuan Su, Cheng&#8208;Meng Chen, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410431287

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zonglin Yi, Yitong Zhou, Huan Liu, Li Li, Yan Zhao, Jiayuan Li, Yixuan Mao, Fangyuan Su, Cheng&#8208;Meng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01582-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of palladium hierarchical nanosheet assemblies: unraveling the aggregation-induced synergistic effect for enhanced methanol oxidation reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ce00360a</link>
      <description>Li&#8208;Juan Han, Yuanyuan Min, Yingying Wang, Feng Liu, Maochang Liu, Yiqun Zheng, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410432784

                Hierarchical Pd nanosheet assemblies are prepared, exhibiting enhanced MOR activity arising from the aggregation-induced synergistic effect.</description>
      <author>Li&#8208;Juan Han, Yuanyuan Min, Yingying Wang, Feng Liu, Maochang Liu, Yiqun Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ce00360a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of local electric polarization using graph neural networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.184105</link>
      <description>Yuxing Ma, Yingwei Chen, Binhua Zhang, Yali Yang, Hongyu Yu, Xin-Gao Gong, Yang Zhong, Hongjun Xiang, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(18)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410432848

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxing Ma, Yingwei Chen, Binhua Zhang, Yali Yang, Hongyu Yu, Xin-Gao Gong, Yang Zhong, Hongjun Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.184105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning surface curvature in B and N co-doped CNT-derived Fe, Ru and Ir catalysts for electrochemical hydrogenation of N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp00309a</link>
      <description>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410438560

                Modulating the CNT curvature enhances the catalytic performance of the electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR).</description>
      <author>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp00309a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells: Significant Advances, Major Challenges, and Future Directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00903</link>
      <description>Sami Mohammed Alfaifi, Rajkamal Balu, Ken Chiang, Namita Roy Choudhury, Naba K. Dutta, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410443701

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sami Mohammed Alfaifi, Rajkamal Balu, Ken Chiang, Namita Roy Choudhury, Naba K. Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TrIP2: Expanding the Transformer Interatomic Potential Demonstrates Architectural Scalability for Organic Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c00391</link>
      <description>Joshua L. Ebbert, Bryce Hedelius, Jyothish Joy, Daniel H. Ess, Dennis Della Corte, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410451399

                TrIP2 is an advanced version of the transformer interatomic potential (TrIP) trained on the expanded ANI-2x data set, including more diverse molecular configurations with sulfur, fluorine, and chlorine. It leverages the equivariant SE(3)-transformer architecture, incorporating physical biases and continuous atomic representations. TrIP was introduced as a highly promising transferable interatomic potential, which we show here to generalize to new atom types with no alterations to the underlying model design. Benchmarking on COMP6 energy and force calculations, structure minimization tasks, torsion drives, and applications to molecules with unexpected conformational energy minima demonstrates TrIP2's high accuracy and transferability. Direct architectural comparisons demonstrate superior performance against ANI-2x, while holistic model evaluations&#9472;including training data and level-of-theory considerations&#9472;show comparative performance with state-of-the-art models like AIMNet2 and MACE-OFF23. Notably, TrIP2 achieves state-of-the-art force prediction performance on the COMP6 benchmarks and closely approaches DFT-optimized structures in torsion drives and geometry optimization tasks. Without requiring any architectural modifications, TrIP2 successfully capitalizes on additional training data to deliver enhanced generalizability and precision, establishing itself as a robust and scalable framework capable of accommodating future expansions or applications to new domains with minimal reengineering.</description>
      <author>Joshua L. Ebbert, Bryce Hedelius, Jyothish Joy, Daniel H. Ess, Dennis Della Corte</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c00391</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabatier Principle Revisited: The Role of Electronic Properties in Simple Catalytic Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01822</link>
      <description>Ram&#243;n Alain Miranda&#8208;Quintana, Niklas Adebar, Moritz Schulze, Jens Smiatek, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410451410

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ram&#243;n Alain Miranda&#8208;Quintana, Niklas Adebar, Moritz Schulze, Jens Smiatek</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic decomposition mechanism of hydroxyamine nitrate on the Cu(111) surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25259/ajc_86_2024</link>
      <description>Li Men, Tianpeng Li, Xinbao Gao, Yin Huang, Arabian Journal of Chemistry. 0(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410453391

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Men, Tianpeng Li, Xinbao Gao, Yin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25259/ajc_86_2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two different metalloporphyrin composites as promising orr catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114702</link>
      <description>Sergey M. Kuzmin, Svetlana A. Chulovskaya, Yuliya A. Filimonova, V. I. Parfenyuk, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410459434

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sergey M. Kuzmin, Svetlana A. Chulovskaya, Yuliya A. Filimonova, V. I. Parfenyuk</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical investigation of Ta3N5/BaTaO2N heterostructure for solar water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2025.116511</link>
      <description>Huan Zhang, Yue Liu, Xin Zhou, Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology A Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410461407

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Zhang, Yue Liu, Xin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2025.116511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrahigh Pyrrolic Nitrogen Triggers High-Activity Sites in Carbon Catalysts for Selective Oxygen Reduction to Efficient H2O2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120450</link>
      <description>Yanan Shi, Menggai Jiao, Chongyang Wang, Lili Zhang, Shaohui Sun, Carbon. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410461573

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Shi, Menggai Jiao, Chongyang Wang, Lili Zhang, Shaohui Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic niobium and manganese co-doping into RuO2 nanocrystal enables PEM water splitting under high current</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59710-5</link>
      <description>Bichen Yuan, Qian Dang, Hai Liu, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Jian Peng, Yameng Fan, Liang Cai, Aiqing Cao, Shiyao Chen, Hui Li, Yun Kuang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410462343

                Low-cost ruthenium-based catalysts with high activity have emerged as promising alternatives to iridium-based counterparts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE), but the poor stability under high current density remains as a key challenge. Here, we utilize the synergistic complementary strategy of introducing earth-abundant Mn and Nb dopants in ruthenium dioxide (RuO2) for Nb0.1Mn0.1Ru0.8O2 nanoparticle electrocatalyst that exhibits a low overpotential of 209 mV at 10 mA cm-2 and good stability of &gt; 400 h at 0.2 A cm-2 in 0.5 M H2SO4. Significantly, a PEMWE device fabricated with Nb0.1Mn0.1Ru0.8O2 anode can operate continuously at least for 1000 h at 0.5 A cm-2 with 59 &#956;V h-1 decay rate. Operando Raman spectroscopy analysis, differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy measurements, X-ray absorption spectroscopy analysis and theoretical calculations indicate that OER reaction on Nb0.1Mn0.1Ru0.8O2 primarily follows the adsorbate evolution mechanism with much favorable energy barrier accompanied by a locally passivated lattice oxygen mechanism (AEM-LPLOM) and the co-existed Nb and Mn in RuO2 crystal lattice could not only stabilize the lattice oxygen, but also relieve the valence state fluctuation of Ru site to stabilize the catalyst during the reaction.</description>
      <author>Bichen Yuan, Qian Dang, Hai Liu, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Jian Peng, Yameng Fan, Liang Cai, Aiqing Cao, Shiyao Chen, Hui Li, Yun Kuang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59710-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly stable and porous triple perovskite oxide as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163928</link>
      <description>Yousuf Ali, Swarit Dwivedi, Masood S. Alivand, A. Sanjid, Akshat Tanksale, Parama Chakraborty Banerjee, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410475868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yousuf Ali, Swarit Dwivedi, Masood S. Alivand, A. Sanjid, Akshat Tanksale, Parama Chakraborty Banerjee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growth of atmospheric freshly nucleated particles: a semi-empirical molecular dynamics study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/ar-3-237-2025</link>
      <description>Yosef Knattrup, Ivo Neefjes, Jakub Kube&#269;ka, Jonas Elm, Aerosol Research. 3(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410477656

                Abstract. When simulating new particle formation rates, collisions in the system are approximated as hard spheres without long-range interactions. This simplification may lead to an underestimation of the actual formation rate. In this study, we employ semi-empirical molecular dynamics (SEMD) at the GFN1-xTB level of theory to probe the sticking process of the monomers sulfuric acid (SA), methanesulfonic acid (MSA), nitric acid (NA), formic acid (FA), ammonia (AM), methylamine (MA), dimethylamine (DMA), and trimethylamine (TMA) onto freshly nucleated particles (FNPs). The FNPs considered are (SA)10(AM)10, (SA)10(MA)10, (SA)10(DMA)10, and (SA)10(TMA)10. In general, we find that the hard-sphere kinetic approximation, which neglects long-range interactions, significantly underestimates the number of collisions leading to sticking. By calculating the sticking coefficient from SEMD simulations, we obtain enhancement factors of 2.3 and 1.5 for the SA + (SA)10(AM)10 and AM + (SA)10(AM)10 collisions, respectively. A comparison with OPLS (optimized potentials for liquid simulations) all-atom force field simulations shows similar enhancement factors of 2.4 and 1.6 for the SA + (SA)10(AM)10 and AM + (SA)10(AM)10 collisions, respectively. Compared to the force field simulations, SEMD exhibits a more isotropic sticking behavior, with the probability remaining near unity for small offsets before rapidly dropping to 0 % beyond a certain offset. In contrast, the force field simulations show a more gradual decline in sticking probability due to certain orientations still leading to sticking. The largest discrepancy between the two methods occurs at lower collision velocities &#8211; below 200 m s&#8722;1 for SA and below 400 m s&#8722;1 for AM &#8211; where force field simulations, even for head-on collisions, predict low or zero sticking probability. This has previously been attributed to periodic repulsions between the rotating collision partners caused by fluctuations in their charge distributions. In contrast, SEMD simulations do not exhibit this behavior. Since these low velocities are not significantly populated in our simulations, both methods yield similar enhancement factors. However, for systems with larger effective masses, where such velocities are more prevalent, we would expect the two methods to diverge.</description>
      <author>Yosef Knattrup, Ivo Neefjes, Jakub Kube&#269;ka, Jonas Elm</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/ar-3-237-2025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another look at the often ignored role of oxygen functional groups in the oxygen reduction reaction: The promoting effect of carbonyls</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120449</link>
      <description>Rui S. Ribeiro, Krzysztof Biernacki, Marc Florent, Alexandre L. Magalh&#227;es, Teresa J. Bandosz, M.F.R. Pereira, Carbon. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410478367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui S. Ribeiro, Krzysztof Biernacki, Marc Florent, Alexandre L. Magalh&#227;es, Teresa J. Bandosz, M.F.R. Pereira</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-incorporated RuAu composite electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01235j</link>
      <description>Jae&#8208;Won Lee, Jinho Oh, Junhyeong Kim, Hee&#8208;Young Park, Sung Jong Yoo, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim, Jong Hyun Jang, Hyun S. Park, Sung Ki Cho, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410479498

                The electrocatalytic activity of RuAu for the hydrogen evolution reaction is improved by the formation of a composite with MoO x through electrodeposition.</description>
      <author>Jae&#8208;Won Lee, Jinho Oh, Junhyeong Kim, Hee&#8208;Young Park, Sung Jong Yoo, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim, Jong Hyun Jang, Hyun S. Park, Sung Ki Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta01235j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of self-supporting hierarchical porous metallic glass for pH-universal hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163667</link>
      <description>X. Zhao, Junsheng Liu, Heting Zhang, Jihan Jiang, Jiaqing Lin, Jianan Fu, Yu Zhang, Xin Li, Wenqing Ruan, Jiang Ma, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410346966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>X. Zhao, Junsheng Liu, Heting Zhang, Jihan Jiang, Jiaqing Lin, Jianan Fu, Yu Zhang, Xin Li, Wenqing Ruan, Jiang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complex Iridate Solid Solutions for Catalyzing Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Comparison of Elemental Leaching and Stability Numbers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00380</link>
      <description>Ki Hyun Park, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Jun Seop Kim, S.-H. Lee, Dongho Kim, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410449369

                As predicted by the Hume-Rothery rules, forming solid solutions of rutile IrO2 with other metal oxides that have different crystal structures is thermodynamically challenging. Consequently, achieving high solubility of foreign elements in Ir-based solid-solution oxides has been significantly limited. We demonstrate that hexagonal-perovskite BaIrO3 can serve as a flexible matrix oxide capable of incorporating a wide spectrum of (post)transition-metal cations with different electronic structures, ranging from d0 to d10 configurations. Among 12 cation solutes, Ta5+, Nb5+, and Zr4+ are found to be stable without substantial leaching during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under acidic condition. Acceptor-type trivalent cations, including Sc3+, In3+, and Fe3+, are identified to leach out gradually from the particle surface while enhancing the OER catalytic activity. Both X-ray absorption spectroscopy and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations consistently show that the robust face-sharing [IrO6] octahedral framework of the solid solutions remains unperturbed unless electrochemical leaching rapidly occurs. As a result, notably high S-numbers, on the order of 106, are achievable at pH = 1. Although our work focuses on single-element incorporation, it is suggested that the solid-solution methodology is an effective strategy for developing stable, long-lasting OER catalysts with further reduced Ir usage for acidic water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Ki Hyun Park, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Jun Seop Kim, S.-H. Lee, Dongho Kim, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study of Hydrogen Storage and Metal Hydride Systems: Future Energy Storage Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr13051506</link>
      <description>Nesrin &#304;lgin Beyaz&#305;t, Processes. 13(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410368210

                Hydrogen is a key energy carrier, playing a vital role in sustainable energy systems. This review provides a comparative analysis of physical, chemical, and innovative hydrogen storage methods from technical, environmental, and economic perspectives. It has been identified that compressed and liquefied hydrogen are predominantly utilized in transportation applications, while chemical transport is mainly supported by liquid organic hydrogen carriers (LOHC) and ammonia-based systems. Although metal hydrides and nanomaterials offer high hydrogen storage capacities, they face limitations related to cost and thermal management. Furthermore, artificial intelligence (AI)- and machine learning (ML)-based optimization techniques are highlighted for their potential to enhance energy efficiency and improve system performance. In conclusion, for hydrogen storage systems to achieve broader applicability, it is recommended that integrated approaches be adopted&#8212;focusing on innovative material development, economic feasibility, and environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Nesrin &#304;lgin Beyaz&#305;t</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr13051506</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
