<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 01:07:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Design of reaction-driven active configuration for enhanced CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109873</link>
      <description>Shanyong Chen, Tao Luo, Xiaoqing Li, Kejun Chen, Qiyou Wang, Junwei Fu, Kang Liu, Chao Ma, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Hongmei Li, Kishan S. Menghrajani, Changxu Liu, Stefan A. Maier, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Junwei Fu, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399555339

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shanyong Chen, Tao Luo, Xiaoqing Li, Kejun Chen, Qiyou Wang, Junwei Fu, Kang Liu, Chao Ma, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Hongmei Li, Kishan S. Menghrajani, Changxu Liu, Stefan A. Maier, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Junwei Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109873</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The MTO and DTO processes as greener alternatives to produce olefins: A review of kinetic models and reactor design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152906</link>
      <description>Tom&#225;s Cordero&#8208;Lanzac, Ana G. Gayubo, Andr&#233;s T. Aguayo, Javier Bilbao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399556348

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tom&#225;s Cordero&#8208;Lanzac, Ana G. Gayubo, Andr&#233;s T. Aguayo, Javier Bilbao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conformal surface intensive doping of low-valence Bi on Cu2O for highly efficient electrochemical nitrate reduction to ammonia production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.05.007</link>
      <description>Thi Kim Cuong Phu, Won Tae Hong, Hyungu Han, Young In Song, Jong Hun Kim, Seung Hun Roh, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Jai Hyun Koh, Byung&#8208;Keun Oh, Jun Young Kim, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Dong Hoon Lee, Jung Kyu Kim, Materials today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399556499

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thi Kim Cuong Phu, Won Tae Hong, Hyungu Han, Young In Song, Jong Hun Kim, Seung Hun Roh, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Jai Hyun Koh, Byung&#8208;Keun Oh, Jun Young Kim, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Dong Hoon Lee, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.05.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening WS2&#8722;based single&#8722;atom catalysts for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.038</link>
      <description>Mamutjan Tursun, Abdukader Abdukayum, Chao Wu, Caihong Wang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 73(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399558931

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mamutjan Tursun, Abdukader Abdukayum, Chao Wu, Caihong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patterned graphene: An effective platform for adsorption, immobilization, and destruction of SARS-CoV-2 Mpro</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.072</link>
      <description>Jiawen Wang, Huilong Dong, Huilong Dong, Huilong Dong, Huilong Dong, Journal of colloid and interface science. 673(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399563048

                To address the ongoing challenges posed by the SARS-CoV-2 and potentially stronger viruses in the future, the development of effective methods to fabricate patterned graphene (PG) and other precisely functional products has become a new research frontier. Herein, we modeled the "checkerboard" graphene (CG) and stripped graphene (SG) as representatives of PG, and studied their interaction mechanism with the target protein (M</description>
      <author>Jiawen Wang, Huilong Dong, Huilong Dong, Huilong Dong, Huilong Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrahigh resolution x-ray Thomson scattering measurements at the European X-ray Free Electron Laser</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.l241112</link>
      <description>Thomas Gawne, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Oliver Humphries, Karen Appel, Carsten Baehtz, V. Bouffetier, E. Brambrink, Attila Cangi, S. G&#246;de, Zuzana Kon&#244;pkov&#225;, Mikako Makita, Mikhail Mishchenko, M. Nakatsutsumi, Kushal Ramakrishna, Lisa Randolph, Sebastian Schwalbe, Jan Vorberger, Lennart Wollenweber, U. Zastrau, Tobias Dornheim, Thomas R. Preston, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 109(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399566144

                Using an ultrahigh resolution (&#916;E&#8764;0.1eV) setup to measure electronic features in x-ray Thomson scattering (XRTS) experiments at the European XFEL in Germany, we have studied the collective plasmon excitation in aluminium at ambient conditions, which we can measure very accurately even at low momentum transfers. As a result, we can resolve previously reported discrepancies between time-dependent density functional theory simulations and experimental observations. The demonstrated capability for high-resolution XRTS measurements will be a game changer for the diagnosis of experiments with matter under extreme densities, temperatures, and pressures, and unlock the full potential of state-of-the-art x-ray free electron laser (XFEL) facilities to study planetary interior conditions, to understand inertial confinement fusion applications, and for material science and discovery. Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Thomas Gawne, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Oliver Humphries, Karen Appel, Carsten Baehtz, V. Bouffetier, E. Brambrink, Attila Cangi, S. G&#246;de, Zuzana Kon&#244;pkov&#225;, Mikako Makita, Mikhail Mishchenko, M. Nakatsutsumi, Kushal Ramakrishna, Lisa Randolph, Sebastian Schwalbe, Jan Vorberger, Lennart Wollenweber, U. Zastrau, Tobias Dornheim, Thomas R. Preston</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.l241112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuneable bimetallic PdxCu100-x catalysts for selective butadiene hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114877</link>
      <description>Oscar E. Brandt Corstius, Hidde L. Nolten, George F. Tierney, Zhuoran Xu, Eric J. Doskocil, Jessi E. S. van der Hoeven, Petra E. de Jongh, Catalysis today. 441(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399566446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oscar E. Brandt Corstius, Hidde L. Nolten, George F. Tierney, Zhuoran Xu, Eric J. Doskocil, Jessi E. S. van der Hoeven, Petra E. de Jongh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modification of Metals and Ligands in Two-Dimensional Conjugated Metal-Organic Frameworks for Co2 Electroreduction: A Combined Dft and Machine Learning Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4863114</link>
      <description>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Guang&#8208;Yan Sun, Jing-yao Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399570693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Guang&#8208;Yan Sun, Jing-yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4863114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Codebase release r1.0 for amcheck</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21468/scipostphyscodeb.30-r1.0</link>
      <description>Andriy Smolyanyuk, Libor &#352;mejkal, I. I. Mazin, SciPost physics codebases. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399573734

                Altermagnets (AM) is a recently discovered class of collinear magnets that share some properties (anomalous transport, etc) with ferromagnets, some (zero net magnetization) with antiferromagnets, while also exhibiting unique properties (spin-splitting of electronic bands and resulting spin-splitter current). Since the moment compensation in AM is driven by symmetry, it must be possible to identify them by analyzing the crystal structure directly, without computing the electronic structure. Given the significant potential of AM for spintronics, it is very useful to have a tool for such an analysis. This work presents an open-access code implementing such a direct check.</description>
      <author>Andriy Smolyanyuk, Libor &#352;mejkal, I. I. Mazin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21468/scipostphyscodeb.30-r1.0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis via Electrocatalytic N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction on the Defective Surfaces of Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; MXenes: Theoretical and Experimental Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00802</link>
      <description>Feng Ren, Hanqing Yin, Lei Tian, Hui Zhang, Fengwei Tian, Jingquan Liu, Aijun Du, Wenrong Yang, Zhen Liu, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399574786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Ren, Hanqing Yin, Lei Tian, Hui Zhang, Fengwei Tian, Jingquan Liu, Aijun Du, Wenrong Yang, Zhen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal conductivity of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Li&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;PS&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; solid electrolytes with &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; accuracy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.065403</link>
      <description>Davide Tisi, Federico Grasselli, Lorenzo Gigli, Michele Ceriotti, Physical review materials. 8(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399580171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Davide Tisi, Federico Grasselli, Lorenzo Gigli, Michele Ceriotti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.065403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insightful Understanding of Synergistic Oxygen Reduction on PtCo&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(111) Toward Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403894</link>
      <description>Xiangxiong Chen, Jiangnan Guo, Dong Qian, Jie Wu, Weixiong Liao, Geoffrey I.N. Waterhouse, Jinlong Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399581991

                Abstract Theory&#8208;guided materials design is an effective strategy for designing catalysts with high intrinsic activity whilst minimizing the usage of expensive metals like platinum. As proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept, herein it demonstrates that using density functional theory (DFT) calculations and experimental validation that intermetallic PtCo 3 alloy nanoparticles offer enhanced electrocatatalytic performance for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) compared to Pt nanoparticles. DFT calculations established that PtCo 3 (111) surfaces possess better intrinsic ORR activity compared to Pt(111) surfaces, owing to the synergistic action of adjacent Pt and Co active sites which optimizes the binding strength of ORR intermediates to boost overall ORR kinetics. With this understanding, a PtCo 3 /NC catalyst, comprising PtCo 3 nanoparticles exposing predominantly (111) facets dispersed on an N&#8208;doped carbon support, is successfully fabricated. PtCo 3 /NC demonstrates a high specific activity (3.4 mA cm &#8722;2 mg Pt &#8722;1 ), mass activity (0.67 A mg Pt &#8722;1 ), and cycling stability for the ORR in 0.1 M KOH, significantly outperforming a commercial 20 wt.% Pt/C catalyst. Moreover, a zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB) assembled with PtCo 3 /NC as the air&#8208;electrode catalyst delivered an open&#8208;circuit voltage of 1.47 V, a specific capacity of 775.1 mAh g Zn &#8722;1 and excellent operation durability after 200 discharge/charge cycles, vastly superior performance to a ZAB built using commercial Pt/C+IrO 2 as the air&#8208;electrode catalyst.</description>
      <author>Xiangxiong Chen, Jiangnan Guo, Dong Qian, Jie Wu, Weixiong Liao, Geoffrey I.N. Waterhouse, Jinlong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tool to check whether a symmetry-compensated collinear magnetic material is antiferro- or altermagnetic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21468/scipostphyscodeb.30</link>
      <description>Andriy Smolyanyuk, Libor &#352;mejkal, I. I. Mazin, SciPost physics codebases. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399582224

                Altermagnets (AM) is a recently discovered class of collinear magnets that share some properties (anomalous transport, etc) with ferromagnets, some (zero net magnetization) with antiferromagnets, while also exhibiting unique properties (spin-splitting of electronic bands and resulting spin-splitter current). Since the moment compensation in AM is driven by symmetry, it must be possible to identify them by analyzing the crystal structure directly, without computing the electronic structure. Given the significant potential of AM for spintronics, it is very useful to have a tool for such an analysis. This work presents an open-access code implementing such a direct check.</description>
      <author>Andriy Smolyanyuk, Libor &#352;mejkal, I. I. Mazin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21468/scipostphyscodeb.30</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and structure measurements of heavy-ion-heated diamond using &lt;i&gt;in situ&lt;/i&gt; X-ray diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0203005</link>
      <description>J. L&#252;tgert, P. Hesselbach, Maximilian Sch&#246;rner, V. Bagnoud, R.P. Belikov, P. Drechsel, Benedikt Heuser, Oliver Humphries, Peter Katr&#237;k, Bj&#246;rn Lindqvist, Chongbing Qu, R. Redmer, D. Riley, G. Schaumann, S. Schumacher, A. Tauschwitz, D. Varentsov, K. Weyrich, Xiaomei Yu, B. Zielbauer, Zs. Major, P. Neumayer, D. Kraus, Matter and radiation at extremes. 9(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399583691

                We present in situ measurements of spectrally resolved X-ray scattering and X-ray diffraction from monocrystalline diamond samples heated with an intense pulse of heavy ions. In this way, we determine the samples&#8217; heating dynamics and their microscopic and macroscopic structural integrity over a timespan of several microseconds. Connecting the ratio of elastic to inelastic scattering with state-of-the-art density functional theory molecular dynamics simulations allows the inference of average temperatures around 1300 K, in agreement with predictions from stopping power calculations. The simultaneous diffraction measurements show no hints of any volumetric graphitization of the material, but do indicate the onset of fracture in the diamond sample. Our experiments pave the way for future studies at the Facility for Antiproton and Ion Research, where a substantially increased intensity of the heavy ion beam will be available.</description>
      <author>J. L&#252;tgert, P. Hesselbach, Maximilian Sch&#246;rner, V. Bagnoud, R.P. Belikov, P. Drechsel, Benedikt Heuser, Oliver Humphries, Peter Katr&#237;k, Bj&#246;rn Lindqvist, Chongbing Qu, R. Redmer, D. Riley, G. Schaumann, S. Schumacher, A. Tauschwitz, D. Varentsov, K. Weyrich, Xiaomei Yu, B. Zielbauer, Zs. Major, P. Neumayer, D. Kraus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0203005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approaches to Construct High-Performance Mg&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-57012-4_20</link>
      <description>Hao Liang, Wenhui Yao, Wenbo Du, Hao Liang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399586187

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Liang, Wenhui Yao, Wenbo Du, Hao Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-57012-4_20</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of anionic species on the low temperature pyrolysis performance of heated tobacco sheets catalyzed by sodium salts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1425244</link>
      <description>Xuebin Zhao, Qiuling Wang, Dan Ai, Haiying Tian, Zhan Zhang, Ke Cao, Yixuan Wang, Wei Qi, Bo Li, Yapeng Niu, Lingchuang Meng, Beibei Gao, Bin Li, Frontiers in chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399594316

                Development of low temperature catalytic pyrolysis technology for heated tobacco sheets is expected to increase the aroma of heated tobacco products and improve their overall smoking quality. In this study, the low temperature pyrolysis performances of heated tobacco sheets catalyzed by various anionic sodium salts were investigated using TG-DTG, Py-GC-MS technology and smoke routine chemical composition analysis. The results showed that the total weight loss between 100&#176;C and 300&#176;C increased by 7.8%&#8211;13.15% after adding various anionic sodium salts, among which, sodium acetate and sodium tartrate showed a relatively higher weight loss. The relative content of free hydroxyacetone, furfuryl alcohol, butyrolactone and megastigmatrienone in the pyrolysis gas increased, while the relative content of free nicotine decreased. With the change of anionic species, the catalytic decomposition ability of cellulose, lignin, and other substances may change, resulting in the distribution alteration of compounds in the pyrolysis gas. After adding sodium acetate and sodium citrate, the release of total particulate matter (TPM), glycerol, and nicotine in flue gas increased. Overall, the addition of sodium acetate and sodium citrate showed a higher low temperature pyrolysis performance of heated tobacco sheets. The research results in this paper provide data support for changing the low temperature catalytic pyrolysis performance of heated tobacco sheets by adjusting the type of anions in sodium salts.</description>
      <author>Xuebin Zhao, Qiuling Wang, Dan Ai, Haiying Tian, Zhan Zhang, Ke Cao, Yixuan Wang, Wei Qi, Bo Li, Yapeng Niu, Lingchuang Meng, Beibei Gao, Bin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1425244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-Driven Arsenic(V) Transformation, Speciation, and Adsorption on the Chalcopyrite Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestwater.4c00059</link>
      <description>Qingjie Ge, Renji Zheng, Yangyang Liu, Yangzi Shangguan, Xuezhen Feng, Dazhong Yang, Wenfei Wei, Ranhao Wang, Yongfei Ji, Lele Duan, Jia Lin, Liwu Zhang, Hong Chen, ACS ES &amp; T water. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399601046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingjie Ge, Renji Zheng, Yangyang Liu, Yangzi Shangguan, Xuezhen Feng, Dazhong Yang, Wenfei Wei, Ranhao Wang, Yongfei Ji, Lele Duan, Jia Lin, Liwu Zhang, Hong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestwater.4c00059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Nanoparticle-Decorated RuSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanorods: A Chemical Vapor Deposition Approach for Efficient Electrolytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.4c00451</link>
      <description>Daba Deme Megersa, Gutema Teshome Gudena, Young&#8208;Ho Kim, Hak Ki Yu, Crystal growth &amp; design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399612559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daba Deme Megersa, Gutema Teshome Gudena, Young&#8208;Ho Kim, Hak Ki Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.4c00451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin Ni&#8211;Fe MOF Nanosheets: Efficient and Durable Water Oxidation at High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01065</link>
      <description>Xin Zhao, Yang Yang, Yuanshuai Liu, Jiale Shi, Qiaoxia Li, Qing Xu, Wen&#8208;Feng Lin, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399617140

                Efficient, durable, and economical electrocatalysts are crucial for advancing energy technology by facilitating the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, ultrathin Ni-Fe metal-organic skeleton (MOF) nanosheets were created in situ on nickel foam (NiFe-UMNs/NF). The catalyst exhibited excellent OER catalytical abilities, with only 269 mV overpotentials at 250 mA cm</description>
      <author>Xin Zhao, Yang Yang, Yuanshuai Liu, Jiale Shi, Qiaoxia Li, Qing Xu, Wen&#8208;Feng Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of carbon fixation during carbonization of municipal solid waste</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10163-024-01988-6</link>
      <description>Takeshi Shinohara, Sylwia Oleszek, Masaya Shimizu, Naoto Yokoro, Kenji Shiota, Kazuyuki Oshita, Toshio Kusakabe, Masaki Takaoka, Journal of material cycles and waste management. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399628370

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Takeshi Shinohara, Sylwia Oleszek, Masaya Shimizu, Naoto Yokoro, Kenji Shiota, Kazuyuki Oshita, Toshio Kusakabe, Masaki Takaoka</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10163-024-01988-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Fake News: A Systematic Literature Review using &#8220;SmartLitReview&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3630744.3663606</link>
      <description>Siam Sadman, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399629361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siam Sadman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1145/3630744.3663606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-Driven Materials Informatics for Novel Piezoelectric Janus-Type Nanomaterials Discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01444</link>
      <description>Woohyun Hwang, Seung&#8208;Hyun Victor Oh, Jungho Shin, Aloysius Soon, Su&#8208;Hyun Yoo, Woosun Jang, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399635165

                In the recent era of green and sustainable energy, the demand for effective and efficient energy harvesting has dramatically increased. Piezoelectric energy harvesting, which converts mechanical energy into electrical energy, is considered a viable strategy to achieve this goal. Janus-type nanomaterial, a noncentrosymmetric material with different elemental species in the upper and lower atomic layers, has gained interest due to its exotic properties compared to conventional bulk and symmetric materials. In this work, we systematically design and investigate a new class of Janus nanomaterials with enhanced intrinsic polarization via the successive ionic exchange method. Multiple layers of stability standards, including both thermodynamic and dynamic stabilities, are employed in the high-throughput screening procedure of novel Janus-type nanomaterials. The newly proposed Janus-type nanomaterials exhibit more than 10 times higher piezoelectric response compared to that of reported low-dimensional materials and even comparable to that of bulk materials.</description>
      <author>Woohyun Hwang, Seung&#8208;Hyun Victor Oh, Jungho Shin, Aloysius Soon, Su&#8208;Hyun Yoo, Woosun Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of changes in the electronic structure of platinum sub-nanoclusters supported on graphene induced by oxygen adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00555d</link>
      <description>Hinoki Hirase, Kazuhiro Iida, Jun&#8208;ya Hasegawa, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399638118

                The characteristics of changes in the electronic structure of a platinum sub-nanocluster caused by oxygen adsorption is elucidated by analyzing the integrated local density of states.</description>
      <author>Hinoki Hirase, Kazuhiro Iida, Jun&#8208;ya Hasegawa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00555d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Relations on High-Entropy Alloy Catalyst Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01292</link>
      <description>Ana-Iulia Hutu, Emmanouil Pervolarakis, Ioannis N. Remediakis, Henrik H. Kristoffersen, Jan Rossmeisl, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399646832

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ana-Iulia Hutu, Emmanouil Pervolarakis, Ioannis N. Remediakis, Henrik H. Kristoffersen, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mof-Derived Molybdenum Carbide-Copper as an Electrocatalyst for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4863676</link>
      <description>W.Y. Chen, Yu&#8208;Min Shen, Sheng&#8208;Chang Wang, Sanjaya Brahma, D.R. Sahu, Jow&#8208;Lay Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399651778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W.Y. Chen, Yu&#8208;Min Shen, Sheng&#8208;Chang Wang, Sanjaya Brahma, D.R. Sahu, Jow&#8208;Lay Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4863676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron carbide anchored on N-doped hierarchically porous carbon core/shell architecture for highly efficient OER water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.463</link>
      <description>Nagaraj Murugan, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, Shanmugasundaram Kamalakannan, Nimisha Baby, Tae Hwan Oh, Hyung Chul Ham, Yang Zhang, Yoong Ahm Kim, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399653736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nagaraj Murugan, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, Shanmugasundaram Kamalakannan, Nimisha Baby, Tae Hwan Oh, Hyung Chul Ham, Yang Zhang, Yoong Ahm Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lateral spin filter realized by monolayer Fe3GaTe2 and Fe3GaTe2/Graphene van der Waals heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssc.2024.115584</link>
      <description>N. J. Zheng, Jingzhe Chen, Solid state communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399653743

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. J. Zheng, Jingzhe Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssc.2024.115584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation on the Structural Characteristics and Electrocatalytic Co2 Reduction Mechanism of G-C3n4 Supported Ag/Au Single Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4865428</link>
      <description>Hui-Ling Shui, Xin Wei, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399657986

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui-Ling Shui, Xin Wei, Chao Fu, Dong-Heng Li, Xiaoqin Liang, Kai Li, Laicai Li, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4865428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Mechanism and Activity of O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction of Co Nanocluster Encapsulated by Carbon Nanotube</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01355</link>
      <description>Ashok Singh, Srimanta Pakhira, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399661604

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashok Singh, Srimanta Pakhira</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of single-atom catalysts on 1 T-TMD for highly active and selective CO2 reduction reaction: Computational and machine learning insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115610</link>
      <description>Xi Shen, Peng Zhao, Cheng He, W. Zhang, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399662000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xi Shen, Peng Zhao, Cheng He, W. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Transition Metals on CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Supported for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Adsorption by DFT and Machine Learning Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c01200</link>
      <description>Hossein Mashhadimoslem, Peyman Karimi, Mohammad Ali Abdol, Kourosh E. Zanganeh, Ahmed Shafeen, Ali A. AlHammadi, Ali Elkamel, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399667093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hossein Mashhadimoslem, Peyman Karimi, Mohammad Ali Abdol, Kourosh E. Zanganeh, Ahmed Shafeen, Ali A. AlHammadi, Ali Elkamel</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c01200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Proximity to Energetics: Unveiling the Hidden Compass of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00761</link>
      <description>Arun Karmakar, Mahendiran Durairaj, Ragunath Madhu, Aditi De, Hariharan N. Dhandapani, Michelle J. S. Spencer, Subrata Kundu, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399667613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arun Karmakar, Mahendiran Durairaj, Ragunath Madhu, Aditi De, Hariharan N. Dhandapani, Michelle J. S. Spencer, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium&#8208;Based Alkaline Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400838</link>
      <description>Qingqing Lv, Di Liu, Wei Zhu, Zhongbin Zhuang, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399678533

                Abstract The hydroxide exchange membrane fuel cells (HEMFCs) are promising but lack of high&#8208;performance anode hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) electrocatalysts. The platinum group metals (PGMs) have the HOR activity in alkaline medium two to three orders of magnitude lower than those in acid, leading to the high required PGMs amount on anode to achieve high HEMFC performance. The mechanism study demonstrates the hydrogen binding energy of the catalyst determines the alkaline HOR kinetics, and the adsorbed OH and water on the catalyst surface promotes HOR. Iridium (Ir) has a unique advantage for alkaline HOR due to its similar hydrogen binding energy to Pt and enhanced adsorption of OH. However, the HOR activity of Ir/C is still unsatisfied in practical HEMFC applications. Further fine tuning the adsorption of the intermediate on Ir&#8208;based catalysts is of great significance to improve their alkaline HOR activity, which can be reasonably realized by structure design and composition regulation. In this concept, we address the current understanding about the alkaline HOR mechanism and summarize recent advances of Ir&#8208;based electrocatalysts with enhanced alkaline HOR activity. We also discuss the perspectives and challenges on Ir&#8208;based electrocatalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Qingqing Lv, Di Liu, Wei Zhu, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combination of Co Single Atom and MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Antisite Defect for Efficient Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Methanation: A Rational Design at Electronic Scale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400328</link>
      <description>Xiangyu Gao, Tong&#8208;Hui Wang, Zi Wen, Q. Jiang, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399679298

                Abstract Methane, the simplest hydrocarbon, has a high energy density and is widely used as chemical feedstocks or fuels. Converting CO 2 to methane through electrochemical reduction offers a promising strategy for managing the global carbon balance, but is a challenge due to the lack of effective electrocatalysts. Herein, the Co single atom catalyst supported by MoS 2 antisite defect (Co&#8208;Mo S2 ) is designed from both the activity and selectivity aspects. By virtue of i) moderately electron&#8208;deficient state (Co &#948;+ ) ensuring efficient CO 2 activation and HER suppression; ii) the strong adsorption capability for intermediate enhancing selectivity; iii) the single atomic active site avoiding the formation of C 2 products, Co&#8208;Mo S2 could selectively convert CO 2 to CH 4 with a limiting potential of &#8722;0.45 V vs . RHE, which outperforms most of the present catalysts, and is expected to be a promising substitution for Cu&#8208;based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiangyu Gao, Tong&#8208;Hui Wang, Zi Wen, Q. Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring mesoscopic mass transport effects on electrocatalytic selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01177-6</link>
      <description>Hendrik H. Heenen, Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa Jane Bukas, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399679690

                Abstract Electrocatalytic selectivity is often discussed at the atomic level on the basis of the active site, while ignoring more subtle effects of mesoscopic mass transport. Here we show how transport controls selectivity through the exchange of surface-bound reaction intermediates between the electrode and bulk electrolyte. We argue that the arising kinetic competition changes with the catalyst&#8217;s surface area and can become relevant for technologically important reactions including, for example, different products during the electrochemical CO 2 reduction on Cu-based catalysts. Combining microkinetic and transport modelling in a multi-scale approach, we specifically explore and quantify this effect for various showcase examples in the experimental literature. Despite its simplicity, our model correctly reproduces selectivity trends with respect to catalyst roughness on all meso-, micro- and atomic scales. The resulting insight provides an alternative or, at least, complementary explanation to changes in electrocatalytic selectivity that have otherwise been attributed to nano-structuring of active sites or electronic effects due to doping or alloying.</description>
      <author>Hendrik H. Heenen, Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa Jane Bukas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01177-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab-Initio Simulation of Luminescence Spectra in Solids: Hylight, an Easy-to-Use Post-Processing Software</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4864809</link>
      <description>Th&#233;o Cavignac, St&#233;phane Jobic, Camille Latouche, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399679758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Th&#233;o Cavignac, St&#233;phane Jobic, Camille Latouche</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4864809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergetic Effects of Strain Engineering and Carbon Vacancy Modification on Ti&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;n&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;+1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;n&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; MXene for Promising Catalytic Activity of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00779</link>
      <description>C. L. Wang, Xiaodan Hai, Hao Wang, Yongshun Song, Zhang Wan, Yuqi Yang, Ping Huai, Yaru Yin, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399682489

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C. L. Wang, Xiaodan Hai, Hao Wang, Yongshun Song, Zhang Wan, Yuqi Yang, Ping Huai, Yaru Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lithium-coupled electron transfer reactions of nano-confined WOx within Zr-based metal&#8211;organic framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1427536</link>
      <description>Hafsa Abdul Ghuffar, Hyunho Noh, Frontiers in chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399690487

                Interfacial charge transfer reactions involving cations and electrons are fundamental to (photo/electro) catalysis, energy storage, and beyond. Lithium-coupled electron transfer (LCET) at the electrode-electrolyte interfaces of lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) is a preeminent example to highlight the importance of charge transfer in modern-day society. The thermodynamics of LCET reactions define the minimal energy for charge/discharge of LIBs, and yet, these parameters are rarely available in the literature. Here, we demonstrate the successful incorporation of tungsten oxides (WO x ) within a chemically stable Zr-based metal&#8722;organic framework (MOF), MOF-808. Cyclic voltammograms (CVs) of the composite, WO x @MOF-808, in Li + -containing acetonitrile (MeCN)-based electrolytes showed an irreversible, cathodic Faradaic feature that shifted in a Nernstian fashion with respect to the Li + concentration, i.e., &#8764;59 mV/log [(Li + )]. The Nernstian dependence established 1:1 stoichiometry of Li + and e &#8722; . Using the standard redox potential of Li +/0 , the apparent free energy of lithiation of WO x @MOF-808 (&#916;G app,Li ) was calculated to be &#8722;36 &#177; 1 kcal mol &#8722;1 . &#916;G app,Li is an intrinsic parameter of WO x @MOF-808, and thus by deriving the similar reaction free energies of other metal oxides, their direct comparisons can be achieved. Implications of the reported measurements will be further contrasted to proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) reactions on metal oxides.</description>
      <author>Hafsa Abdul Ghuffar, Hyunho Noh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1427536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering single-atom catalysts on triazine-based covalent organic frameworks for enhanced photocatalytic performance in N2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153133</link>
      <description>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Xinyue Xu, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanxia Li, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Qiang Chen, Rongjian Sa, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399693195

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Xinyue Xu, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanxia Li, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Qiang Chen, Rongjian Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density functional theory study of transition metal dual-atom anchored phthalocyanine as high-performance electrocatalysts for carbon dioxide reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160532</link>
      <description>Zhenzhen Wang, Aling Ma, Zhiyi Liu, Zongpeng Ding, Yushan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399697037

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenzhen Wang, Aling Ma, Zhiyi Liu, Zongpeng Ding, Yushan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on fundamentals for designing hydrogen evolution electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234856</link>
      <description>M. A. Qadeer, Xiaoxue Zhang, Muhammad Asim Farid, Muhammad Tanveer, Yue Yan, Shangfeng Du, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, M.N. Tahir, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Journal of power sources. 613(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399699147

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. A. Qadeer, Xiaoxue Zhang, Muhammad Asim Farid, Muhammad Tanveer, Yue Yan, Shangfeng Du, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, M.N. Tahir, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Nickel on Iridium&#8211;Ruthenium Structure and Activity for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction under Acidic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.4c00025</link>
      <description>Erlend Bertheussen, Simon Pitscheider, Susan Cooper, Rebecca Pittkowski, Katrine L. Svane, Aline Bornet, Erik Wisaeus, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz, Christian Kalles&#248;e, Christoffer M&#248;lleskov Pedersen, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399699268

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Erlend Bertheussen, Simon Pitscheider, Susan Cooper, Rebecca Pittkowski, Katrine L. Svane, Aline Bornet, Erik Wisaeus, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz, Christian Kalles&#248;e, Christoffer M&#248;lleskov Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.4c00025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study of the electrochemical CO2 reduction by Sc to Ni single atom catalysts implanted on the pristine and N-doped-H4,4,4-graphyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132225</link>
      <description>Azadeh Masiha, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani, Fuel. 372(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399702713

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Azadeh Masiha, Adel Reisi&#8208;Vanani</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanotubes and other nanostructures of VS2, WS2, and MoS2: Structural effects on the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmt.2024.102288</link>
      <description>Sunil R. Kadam, K. Manjunath, Saptarshi Ghosh, M. B. Sreedhara, Alevtina Neyman, Alexander Upcher, E. Roth, Lothar Houben, Alla Zak, Andrey N. Enyashin, Ronen Bar&#8208;Ziv, Maya Bar&#8208;Sadan, Applied materials today. 39(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399703633

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sunil R. Kadam, K. Manjunath, Saptarshi Ghosh, M. B. Sreedhara, Alevtina Neyman, Alexander Upcher, E. Roth, Lothar Houben, Alla Zak, Andrey N. Enyashin, Ronen Bar&#8208;Ziv, Maya Bar&#8208;Sadan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmt.2024.102288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into efficient oxygen evolution reaction using non-noble metal single-atom catalysts on W2CO2 MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02838-y</link>
      <description>Jing Zhou, Zhen Han, Shu Zhao, Tao Yang, De-Zhen Yan, Haijun Yu, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399707735

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhou, Zhen Han, Shu Zhao, Tao Yang, De-Zhen Yan, Haijun Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02838-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customized Electronic Modulations of Transition Metal Chalcogenide Electrodes Via Heterointerfacing/High&#8208;Valence Doping Toward High&#8208;Performance Water Electrolysis with Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405262</link>
      <description>Xinyu Qin, Bingyi Yan, Tianyu Chen, Zixuan Teng, Deok Ki Cho, Andi Haryanto, Heon Kil Lim, Chan Woo Lee, Yuanzhe Piao, Lin Xu, Jin Young Kim, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399708438

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting offers an advancing approach to producing highly pure hydrogen and oxygen, motivated by the prevalence of a low&#8208;carbon economy and the goal of a sustainable future. The customized modulation of electronic structures enables the electrocatalyst to directionally promote hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is a promising shortcut to overall water splitting (OWS). Herein, 3D homologous WSeS/CoSeS heterojunction nanoarrays (WSeS/CoSeS NAs) and W&#8208;doped CoSeS nanoarrays (W&#8208;CoSeS NAs) are investigated. Abundant heterointerfaces within WSeS/CoSeS NAs facilitate HER kinetics, boosting mass diffusivity, and increasing carrier separation and transfer process. High&#8208;valence W 6+ doping into CoSeS prevents phase separation and stabilizes Co sites by charge offset effect, leading to enhanced OER. Consequently, the WSeS/CoSeS NAs and W&#8208;CoSeS NAs reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at an overpotential of 43.8 and 233.3 mV in 1.0 m KOH electrolyte for HER and OER, respectively. Moreover, when asymmetrically engaged as an electrolyzer, this configuration exhibits extraordinary electrocatalytic performances (cell voltage of 1.51 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) with satisfying stability and mechanical robustness (over 1000 h at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 ). The modulation and manufacture of reaction&#8208;property&#8208;oriented materials are experimentally and theoretically validated potential, illuminating the light of inspiration for multiple applications.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Qin, Bingyi Yan, Tianyu Chen, Zixuan Teng, Deok Ki Cho, Andi Haryanto, Heon Kil Lim, Chan Woo Lee, Yuanzhe Piao, Lin Xu, Jin Young Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homogeneous In&#8208;Plane Lattice Strain Enabling d&#8208;Band Center Modulation and Efficient d&#8211;&#960; Interaction for an Ag&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; Cathode Catalyst With Ultralong Cycle Life in Li&#8208;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401509</link>
      <description>Han Yu, Guoliang Zhang, Dongmei Zhang, Ruonan Yang, Xia Li, Xiuqi Zhang, Gang Lian, Hua Hou, Zhanhu Guo, Chuanxin Hou, Xiaoyang Yang, Feng Dang, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399708604

                Abstract Although lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries (LOBs) hold great promise as future energy storage systems, they are impeded by insulated discharge product Li 2 O 2 and sluggish oxygen reduction reaction/oxygen evolution revolution (ORR/OER) kinetics. The application of a highly efficient cathode catalyst determines the LOBs performance. The d&#8208;band modulation and catalytic kinetics promotion are important concept guidelines for the performance enhancement of cathode catalysts. In this work, the homogeneous in&#8208;plane distortion&#8208;derived synergistic catalytic capability of an Ag 2 Mo 2 O 7 catalyst with modulated d&#8208;band centers and promoted ORR/OER kinetics is demontrated. The uniform elongation of Ag&#9472;O bonds and compression of Mo&#9472;O bonds in (020) plane leads to d&#8208;band splitting and d&#8208;band center optimization and delivers improved adsorption behavior for high ORR/OER capability. Furthermore, the spatial and energy overlap of Ag d xz and O 2 anti&#8208;bonding &#960; * orbitals facilitate electron injection during ORR process and reduce the energy barrier for charge transfer and O 2 desorption during OER process, accelerating the ORR/OER kinetics. As a result, the (020) plane&#8208;exposed Ag 2 Mo 2 O 7 cathode exhibits ultralong cycle stability of 817 cycles at 500 mA g &#8722;1 and large specific discharge/charge capacities of 15898/15180 mAh g &#8722;1 . This work provides facile concept guidance for optimizing catalytic capability through controlled lattice distortion in cathode catalysts for LOBs.</description>
      <author>Han Yu, Guoliang Zhang, Dongmei Zhang, Ruonan Yang, Xia Li, Xiuqi Zhang, Gang Lian, Hua Hou, Zhanhu Guo, Chuanxin Hou, Xiaoyang Yang, Feng Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficient photocatalytic performance of Z-scheme BTe/HfS2 heterostructure for H2O splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115606</link>
      <description>Lan He, Xing Long, Liyan Wang, Cheng Mi, Chaopeng Zhang, Keping Ma, Liang She, Ming Yu, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399710354

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lan He, Xing Long, Liyan Wang, Cheng Mi, Chaopeng Zhang, Keping Ma, Liang She, Ming Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid photothermal reduction-derived Pt1.6Ni nanoalloys embedded in laser-induced graphene for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.063</link>
      <description>Seung Geun Jo, Yoo-Kyum Shin, Min&#8208;Ho Seo, Jung Woo Lee, International journal of hydrogen energy. 77(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399712029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seung Geun Jo, Yoo-Kyum Shin, Min&#8208;Ho Seo, Jung Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure evolution of Cu3Pd single-particles under CO2 hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153208</link>
      <description>Changcheng Xu, Shaobo Han, Qiao Zhao, Shuang Liu, Wei Liu, Yong Li, Wenjie Shen, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399715717

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changcheng Xu, Shaobo Han, Qiao Zhao, Shuang Liu, Wei Liu, Yong Li, Wenjie Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic Molecular Volcano Plots for Enhanced Catalyst Selectivity and Activity Predictions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01175</link>
      <description>Thanapat Worakul, Rub&#233;n Laplaza, Shubhajit Das, Matthew D. Wodrich, Cl&#233;mence Corminb&#339;uf, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399722609

                Molecular volcano plots, which facilitate the rapid prediction of the activity and selectivity of prospective catalysts, have emerged as powerful tools for computational catalysis. Here, we integrate microkinetic modeling into the volcano plot framework to develop "microkinetic molecular volcano plots". The resulting unified computational framework allows the influence of important reaction parameters, including temperature, reaction time, and concentration, to be quickly incorporated and more complex situations, such as off-cycle resting states and coupled catalytic cycles, to be tackled. Compared to previous generations of molecular volcanoes, these microkinetic counterparts offer a more comprehensive understanding of catalytic behavior, in which selectivity and product ratios can be explicitly determined by tracking the evolution of each product concentration over time. This is demonstrated by examining two case studies, rhodium-catalyzed hydroformylation and metal-catalyzed hydrosilylation, in which the unique insights provided by microkinetic modeling, as well as the ability to simultaneously screen catalysts and reaction conditions, are highlighted. To facilitate the construction of these plots/maps, we introduce mikimo, a Python program that seamlessly integrates with our previously developed automated volcano builder, volcanic.</description>
      <author>Thanapat Worakul, Rub&#233;n Laplaza, Shubhajit Das, Matthew D. Wodrich, Cl&#233;mence Corminb&#339;uf</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrocatalytic Urea Formation from Gas Pollutants on Heteronuclear Dual-Metal Atom Anchored N-Doped Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01378</link>
      <description>Lu Song, Jiadi Ying, Tiancun Liu, Xu Jian, Qianqian Wang, Min Guo, Qi Shen, Yong Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399725574

                The electrochemical synthesis of urea under mild conditions is considered a promising alternative to the harsh industrial Haber-Bosch process. However, the development of highly active and selective electrocatalysts remains a formidable challenge. In this study, a novel mechanism for urea synthesis on dual-atom catalysts (DACs) using two gas pollutants (NO and CO) is proposed based on density functional theory (DFT) calculations. It is found that urea can be synthesized through consecutive C&#8211;N coupling and hydrogenation steps on heteronuclear DACs, in which the stable adsorption of NO and CO on DACs significantly contributes to the excellent performance for urea formation. Notably, only CoZn, CoCu, and FeZn@N6/C can continuously accept proton&#8211;electron and ultimately achieve urea formation, exhibiting low limiting potentials of &#8722;0.27, &#8722;0.30, and &#8722;0.60 V, respectively. Furthermore, it is also determined that an alternative mechanism is preferable on three DACs. Moreover, competitive hydrogen evolution reaction, as well as reductions of CO and NO reductions, can be effectively suppressed, thereby endowing high selectivity for urea generation. Importantly, this study not only advances a novel mechanism for urea production utilizing gas pollutants but also broadens the applicability of DACs in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Lu Song, Jiadi Ying, Tiancun Liu, Xu Jian, Qianqian Wang, Min Guo, Qi Shen, Yong Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conjugated Microporous Polymer Derived Hierarchically Porous N-Rich Nanocarbon as a Durable Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Zn-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4868072</link>
      <description>Lunjie Liu, Zian Xu, Yu Xia, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Qiong&#8208;Hua Jin, Baobing Zheng, Chongxuan Liu, Shaoqing Chen, Z. Zhang, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399729859

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lunjie Liu, Zian Xu, Yu Xia, Mei&#8208;Yan Gao, Qiong&#8208;Hua Jin, Baobing Zheng, Chongxuan Liu, Shaoqing Chen, Z. Zhang, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4868072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-based materials for electrocatalytic CO2 to alcohols: Reaction mechanism, catalyst categories, and regulation strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.06.008</link>
      <description>Yaru Lei, Yue Niu, Xiaolong Tang, Xiangtao Yu, Xiubing Huang, Xiaoxi Lin, Honghong Yi, Shunzheng Zhao, Jingjing Jiang, Jiyue Zhang, Feifei Gao, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399730927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaru Lei, Yue Niu, Xiaolong Tang, Xiangtao Yu, Xiubing Huang, Xiaoxi Lin, Honghong Yi, Shunzheng Zhao, Jingjing Jiang, Jiyue Zhang, Feifei Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.06.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Principles Energetic Span Analysis of the Activity of Transition Metal Catalysts for N2O Decomposition: The Reversal of Descriptor Roles in the Presence of NO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114892</link>
      <description>Gunjana Yadav, Abhishek Khetan, Catalysis today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399732840

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gunjana Yadav, Abhishek Khetan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Supported Metal Dual-Atom Site Catalyst for Oxygen Reduction: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700022</link>
      <description>Xianjun Chen, C. F. Xu, Feng He, Minggang Huang, Hua Ji, Russian journal of electrochemistry. 60(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399739457

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianjun Chen, C. F. Xu, Feng He, Minggang Huang, Hua Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-block germanenes as a promising electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211907</link>
      <description>Pengju Wang, Weiyi Xia, Nanshu Liu, Wei Pei, Si Zhou, Yusong Tu, Jijun Zhao, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399740280

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), a pivotal process in hydrogen fuel cells crucial for enhancing fuel cell performance through suitable catalysts, remains a challenging aspect of development. This study explores the catalytic potential of germanene on Al (111), taking advantage of the successful preparation of stable reconstructed germanene layers on Al (111) and the excellent catalytic performance exhibited by germanium-based nanomaterials. Through first-principles calculations, we demonstrate that the O2 molecule can be effectively activated on both freestanding and supported germanene nanosheets, featuring kinetic barriers of 0.40 and 0.04 eV, respectively. The presence of the Al substrate not only significantly enhances the stability of the reconstructed germanene but also preserves its exceptional ORR catalytic performance. These theoretical findings offer crucial insights into the substrate-mediated modulation of germanene stability and catalytic efficiency, paving the way for the design of stable and efficient ORR catalysts for future applications.</description>
      <author>Pengju Wang, Weiyi Xia, Nanshu Liu, Wei Pei, Si Zhou, Yusong Tu, Jijun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes as Electrocatalysts for Energy Conversion Applications: Advances and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400033</link>
      <description>Mohamed El Ouardi, Omar Ait Layachi, Badr&#8208;Eddine Channab, Ayoub El Idrissi, Amal BaQais, Madjid Arab, Mohamed Zbair, Mohamed Saadi, Hassan Ait Ahsaine, Advanced energy and sustainability research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399756246

                Hydrogen as a potential future energy source provides a number of benefits in terms of sustainability, high energy density, and zero emissions. The production of hydrogen via water splitting is regarded as the cleanest and sustainable process. In contrast, fossil fuel combustion causes significant environmental problems through the production and release of secondary gases such as NO x , SO 2 , and CO 2 . It is vital to focus on reducing these harmful gases. CO 2 , a major pollutant produced by the combustion of fossil fuels and various human activities, plays a central role in the greenhouse effect and contributes to global warming. It is therefore imperative to actively eliminate and mitigate CO 2 levels to preserve the global environment. MXenes and MXene&#8208;based catalysts exhibit both outstanding hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance and CO 2 reduction. In this review, recent progress is systematically examined and discussed in the preparation and utilization of MXenes as catalysts for HER and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR). The discussion begins with a concise overview of the fabrication and characteristics of MXenes, followed by a comprehensive exploration of their efficacy as catalysts for HER and CO 2 RR.</description>
      <author>Mohamed El Ouardi, Omar Ait Layachi, Badr&#8208;Eddine Channab, Ayoub El Idrissi, Amal BaQais, Madjid Arab, Mohamed Zbair, Mohamed Saadi, Hassan Ait Ahsaine</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Amorphous Molybdenum Sulfide Thin Film Electrocatalysts: Trade-Off between Specific Activity and Microscopic Porosity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06308</link>
      <description>Thom R. Harris-Lee, Tom Turvey, Gunani Jayamaha, Myunghee Kang, Frank Marken, Andrew L. Johnson, Jie Zhang, Cameron L. Bentley, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399758517

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thom R. Harris-Lee, Tom Turvey, Gunani Jayamaha, Myunghee Kang, Frank Marken, Andrew L. Johnson, Jie Zhang, Cameron L. Bentley</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Exploration of the Origin of Alkaline Dependence in the Oxidation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural Catalyzed by NiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00940</link>
      <description>Si Wang, Haisong Feng, Tianyong Liu, Yuan Deng, Meng Zhang, Sylvia Zhao, Juan Han, Xin Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399760359

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Si Wang, Haisong Feng, Tianyong Liu, Yuan Deng, Meng Zhang, Sylvia Zhao, Juan Han, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening transition metal and nonmetal atoms co-doped graphyne as efficient single-atom catalysts for nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153275</link>
      <description>Shulong Li, Ming Peng, Yu Song, Yutao Chen, Liang Qiao, Bo Wang, Yong Zhao, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399761233

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shulong Li, Ming Peng, Yu Song, Yutao Chen, Liang Qiao, Bo Wang, Yong Zhao, Li&#8208;Yong Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.153275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Ions Synergistic Bilayer H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Pillared MXene Directing In Situ Ordered Embedding Growth of Highly Efficient NiFe Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408303</link>
      <description>Zhongjie Qiu, Jiayan Wu, Baolin Zhang, Hui&#8208;Hua Song, Zhiming Cui, Zhenxing Liang, Li Du, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399764220

                Abstract Efficient, stable, and inexpensive electrocatalysts are essential to overcome the high overpotential and slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process during water electrolysis applications. 2D transition metal carbides (MXene) show great potential in functional heterogeneous interface engineering for electrocatalytic OER. However, it is still a challenge to regulate the interlayer space and realize the heterogeneous layer&#8208;by&#8208;layer ordered embedding for MXene. Herein, a simple hydrothermal&#8208;assisted strategy is proposed to prepare highly conductive Ti 3 C 2 T x MXene supported by synergized Ni 2+ , Co 2+ , and Fe 3+ with bilayer H 2 O, which significantly enlarges the interlayer distances and improves the interlayer ion concentrations. Benefiting from modulated interface chemistry, embedded metal ions undergo multi&#8208;directional in situ growth on the MXene substrate, thereby forming a stable 0D/2D@2D nano&#8208;hybrid material (NiFe/MX&#8208;HT). Combining density functional theory calculations with experiments demonstrates that MXene offers a framework for electron transfer, enhances the exposure of active sites, modulates the electronic structure, and greatly reduces the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step in the process of OER. Thus, NiFe/MX&#8208;HT requires only 230 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and maintains stability even after operating at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for 150 h. This work offers new insights into exploring various functional MXene&#8208;based heterogeneous materials.</description>
      <author>Zhongjie Qiu, Jiayan Wu, Baolin Zhang, Hui&#8208;Hua Song, Zhiming Cui, Zhenxing Liang, Li Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Hydrogen Evolution Reaction with single-atom catalysts on Ti&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si101.svg" display="inline" id="d1e214"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;B MBenes: Insights from computational screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.141</link>
      <description>Aarti Shukla, International journal of hydrogen energy. 77(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399765830

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aarti Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Electronic and Vibrational Spectroscopy of Electrochemical Transformations on a Metal-Oxide Surface during Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05931</link>
      <description>Tanja Cuk, Michael Paolino, Suryansh Singh, James J. P. Stewart, Xihan Chen, Ilya Vinogradov, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399767385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tanja Cuk, Michael Paolino, Suryansh Singh, James J. P. Stewart, Xihan Chen, Ilya Vinogradov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review on Highly Efficient Ru-Based Electrocatalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02080</link>
      <description>Jiayi Li, Zeng Ju, Fangchen Zhao, Xinran Sun, Sibo Wang, Xingwen Lu, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399772787

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayi Li, Zeng Ju, Fangchen Zhao, Xinran Sun, Sibo Wang, Xingwen Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Screening of Tm1tm2/N6-1 (Tm = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Mo) as Effective Electrocatalysts for Nitrogen Fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4868581</link>
      <description>Shujie Yao, Xinlu Cheng, Hong Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399790307

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shujie Yao, Xinlu Cheng, Hong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4868581</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Design of 2D Phosphorus Nanostructures for Renewable Energy Applications: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aelm.202300869</link>
      <description>Chen&#8208;Chen Er, Cheng&#8208;May Fung, Wei&#8208;Kean Chong, Yong Jieh Lee, Lling&#8208;Lling Tan, Yee Sin Ang, Nikhil V. Medhekar, Siang&#8208;Piao Chai, Advanced electronic materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399615055

                Abstract Elemental phosphorus in its various allotropes has received tremendous research attention recently due to its intriguing electronic and structural properties. Notably, the application of nanostructured materials to overcome the inherent flaws in bulk materials is promising. However, many challenges need to be addressed before its widespread implementation. Thus, a specific tenet to design novel and robust nanomaterials is a decisive factor in the desired outcome, and the most daunting task before realizing this is solving the Schr&#246;dinger equation. First principle density functional theory (DFT) calculations have emerged as an insightful and accurate design tool to investigate the structural, electronic, and possible synthesis scenarios of yet undiscovered materials at atomic levels. In this review, the basic principles and the importance of DFT are discussed, followed by a summary of recent advances in the first principle study of elemental phosphorus&#8208;based nanomaterials. Elemental phosphorus&#8208;based nanomaterials and their allotropes have attracted growing interest in the renewable energy community due to their modulable product selectivity. However, the understanding of the physical phenomena of allotropic modification is still lacking. Therefore, the aim is to motivate experimental researchers to conduct DFT studies and experiments to comprehend relevant engineered nanomaterials better. Finally, the challenges and potential future research directions for further theoretical and computational development of phosphorus&#8208;based nanomaterials are outlined.</description>
      <author>Chen&#8208;Chen Er, Cheng&#8208;May Fung, Wei&#8208;Kean Chong, Yong Jieh Lee, Lling&#8208;Lling Tan, Yee Sin Ang, Nikhil V. Medhekar, Siang&#8208;Piao Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aelm.202300869</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
