<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:43:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional materials by large-scale computations and chemical exfoliation of layered solids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adj6556</link>
      <description>Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Jie Zhou, Per Persson, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Science. 383(6688)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392797038

                MXenes are a family of two-dimensional (2D) materials typically formed by etching the A element from a parent MAX phase. Computational screening for other 3D precursors suitable for such exfoliation is challenging because of the intricate chemical processes involved. We present a theoretical approach for predicting 2D materials formed through chemical exfoliation under acidic conditions by identifying 3D materials amenable for selective etching. From a dataset of 66,643 3D materials, we identified 119 potentially exfoliable candidates, within several materials families. To corroborate the method, we chose a material distinctly different from MAX phases, in terms of structure and chemical composition, for experimental verification. We selectively etched Y from YRu 2 Si 2 , resulting in 2D Ru 2 Si x O y . The high-throughput methodology suggests a vast chemical space of 2D materials from chemical exfoliation.</description>
      <author>Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Jie Zhou, Per Persson, Johanna Ros&#233;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adj6556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consecutive Reduction of Five Carbon Dioxide Molecules by Gas-Phase Niobium Carbide Cluster Anions Nb&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;: Unusual Mechanism for Enhanced Reactivity by the Carbon Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00371</link>
      <description>Yiheng Zhang, Jia-Bi Ma, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392799839

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiheng Zhang, Jia-Bi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal evaporation-driven fabrication of Ru/RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles onto nickel foam for efficient overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr06204j</link>
      <description>Yan Huang, Qi Zheng, Han Xu, Yingxin Liu, Wei Zhang, Xueqin Cao, Yongyong Cao, Jian&#8208;Ping Lang, Hongwei Gu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392804222

                A self-supported substrate material of Ru/NF could be obtained by a two-stage metal&#8211;organic thermal evaporation strategy. The synergistic effect between Ru and RuO 2 species greatly promotes water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yan Huang, Qi Zheng, Han Xu, Yingxin Liu, Wei Zhang, Xueqin Cao, Yongyong Cao, Jian&#8208;Ping Lang, Hongwei Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr06204j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of hydrogen binding energy via oxygen vacancy enables an efficient trifunctional Rh-Rh2O3 electrocatalyst for fuel cells and water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.095</link>
      <description>Jie Gao, Wanqing Yu, Jing Liu, Qin Liu, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Xuejing Cui, Luhua Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392815895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Gao, Wanqing Yu, Jing Liu, Qin Liu, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Xuejing Cui, Luhua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-Center Tight-Binding Together with Multipolar Auxiliary Functions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00018</link>
      <description>Matthias Van den Bossche, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392818035

                We present an ab initio tight-binding method that allows to improve on the effective potential and minimal basis approximations employed in semiempirical calculations. Three-center expansions are used to evaluate the zeroth-order Hamiltonian matrix elements and repulsive energy terms in the spirit of the Horsfield method. Self-consistency is handled by expanding atomic orbital products in an auxiliary basis following the work of Giese and York, combined with a two-center expansion of the exchange&#8211;correlation kernels. Together with nonminimal main basis sets (double-&#950; plus polarization), we show that the resulting method trades a modest amount of accuracy for a significant gain in speed, compared to that of numerical atomic orbital density functional theory, in calculations on small molecules, bulk compounds, and metal nanoclusters.</description>
      <author>Matthias Van den Bossche</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring optimal total metal loading of Ni3Fe/Al2O3 catalyst for CO2 methanation and its kinetic model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131447</link>
      <description>Jitendra Kumar Prabhakar, Pankaj A. Apte, Goutam Deo, Fuel. 367(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392826876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jitendra Kumar Prabhakar, Pankaj A. Apte, Goutam Deo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Chemical Environment Dependent Nitrate-Reduction-to-Ammonia Performance on Cu-Based Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03462</link>
      <description>Tao Hu, Mengting Wang, Ling Ren, Chang Ming Li, Chunxian Guo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392845760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Hu, Mengting Wang, Ling Ren, Chang Ming Li, Chunxian Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on machine learning in flexible surgical and interventional robots: Where we are and where we are going</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106179</link>
      <description>Di Wu, R. Zhang, Ameya Pore, Diego Dall&#8217;Alba, Xuan Thao Ha, Zhen Li, Yao Zhang, Francisco Herrera, Mouloud Ourak, Wojtek Kowalczyk, Elena De Momi, Al&#305;&#769;cia Casals, Jenny Dankelman, Jens Kober, Arianna Menciassi, Paolo Fiorini, Emmanuel Vander Poorten, Biomedical Signal Processing and Control. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392848497

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Di Wu, R. Zhang, Ameya Pore, Diego Dall&#8217;Alba, Xuan Thao Ha, Zhen Li, Yao Zhang, Francisco Herrera, Mouloud Ourak, Wojtek Kowalczyk, Elena De Momi, Al&#305;&#769;cia Casals, Jenny Dankelman, Jens Kober, Arianna Menciassi, Paolo Fiorini, Emmanuel Vander Poorten</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonmetal-modification 2D molybdenum carbide (MXene) for enhanced activity in hydrogen evolution reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114649</link>
      <description>Cong Zhang, Wei Chu, Congmei Chen, Wenjing Sun, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392858414

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cong Zhang, Wei Chu, Congmei Chen, Wenjing Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on Cu&#8211;Ag Bimetallic Catalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction: A Mini-Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c05194</link>
      <description>Peiqi Guo, Kaili Liu, Longya Xu, Ruhan Liu, Zongyou Yin, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392858685

                The atmospheric CO2 concentration has increased significantly since the Industrial Revolution, leading to various environmental issues and energy crisis. The electrochemical reduction of CO2 powered by renewable energy is attracting widespread attention, due to its capacity to transform CO2 into value-added chemicals and fuels and contribute to carbon neutrality. Among Cu-based catalysts, Cu&#8211;Ag bimetallic catalysts exhibit superior selectivity for high value-added multicarbon compounds. This mini-review provides an overview of Cu&#8211;Ag bimetallic catalysts including alloy system and composite structure system, emphasizing the relationship between catalysts' structure and the influencing factors for the enhanced selectivity toward C2+. At the end of this review, we outline the challenges and perspectives for the better development of electrochemical CO2 reduction by Cu&#8211;Ag bimetallic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Peiqi Guo, Kaili Liu, Longya Xu, Ruhan Liu, Zongyou Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c05194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Computational Screening of Molecules with Inverted Singlet&#8211;Triplet Energy Gaps Using the Pariser&#8211;Parr&#8211;Pople Semiempirical Quantum Chemistry Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.3c06357</link>
      <description>Kjell Jorner, Robert Pollice, Cyrille Lavigne, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392858753

                Molecules with an inverted energy gap between their first singlet and triplet excited states have promising applications in the next generation of organic light-emitting diode (OLED) materials. Unfortunately, such molecules are rare, and only a handful of examples are currently known. High-throughput virtual screening could assist in finding novel classes of these molecules, but current efforts are hampered by the high computational cost of the required quantum chemical methods. We present a method based on the semiempirical Pariser&#8211;Parr&#8211;Pople theory augmented by perturbation theory and show that it reproduces inverted gaps at a fraction of the cost of currently employed excited-state calculations. Our study paves the way for ultrahigh-throughput virtual screening and inverse design to accelerate the discovery and development of this new generation of OLED materials.</description>
      <author>Kjell Jorner, Robert Pollice, Cyrille Lavigne, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.3c06357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the activity of single atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2005-5</link>
      <description>Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392863026

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2005-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New approach to produce cubic-WC at low temperature for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.107</link>
      <description>Elvis O. L&#243;pez, Ofelia M. Arias-Pinedo, Rub&#233;n Soria-Mart&#237;nez, Antony Bazan-Aguilar, Gonzalo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Pablo L. Bernardo, N.R. Checca, Alexandre Mello, Ang&#233;lica M. Baena&#8208;Moncada, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392876346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elvis O. L&#243;pez, Ofelia M. Arias-Pinedo, Rub&#233;n Soria-Mart&#237;nez, Antony Bazan-Aguilar, Gonzalo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Pablo L. Bernardo, N.R. Checca, Alexandre Mello, Ang&#233;lica M. Baena&#8208;Moncada</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace Fe activates perovskite nickelate OER catalysts in alkaline media via redox-active surface Ni species formed during electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115443</link>
      <description>Liam Twight, Ally Tonsberg, Samji Samira, Kunal Velinkar, Kora Dumpert, Yingqing Ou, Le Wang, Eranda Nikolla, Shannon W. Boettcher, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392878220

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liam Twight, Ally Tonsberg, Samji Samira, Kunal Velinkar, Kora Dumpert, Yingqing Ou, Le Wang, Eranda Nikolla, Shannon W. Boettcher</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D Ferromagnetic M&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;GeTe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (M = Ni/Fe) for Boosting Intermediates Adsorption toward Faster Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202310115</link>
      <description>Guyue Bo, Peng Li, Yuhang Fan, Xiaobo Zheng, Mengting Zhao, Qiang Zhu, Fu Yang, Yitong Li, Wei Pang, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Bernt Johannessen, Lars Thomsen, Bruce C. C. Cowie, Tianyi Ma, Zhidong Chen, Guan Heng Yeoh, Yi Du, Shi Xue Dou, Xiaojing Xu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392880944

                Abstract In this work, 2D ferromagnetic M 3 GeTe 2 (MGT, M = Ni/Fe) nanosheets with rich atomic Te vacancies (2D&#8208;MGT v ) are demonstrated as efficient OER electrocatalyst via a general mechanical exfoliation strategy. X&#8208;ray absorption spectra (XAS) and scanning transmission electron microscope (STEM) results validate the dominant presence of metal&#8208;O moieties and rich Te vacancies, respectively. The formed Te vacancies are active for the adsorption of OH* and O* species while the metal&#8208;O moieties promote the O* and OOH* adsorption, contributing synergistically to the faster oxygen evolution kinetics. Consequently, 2D&#8208;Ni 3 GeTe 2v exhibits superior OER activity with only 370 mV overpotential to reach the current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and turnover frequency (TOF) value of 101.6 s &#8722;1 at the overpotential of 200 mV in alkaline media. Furthermore, a 2D&#8208;Ni 3 GeTe 2v &#8208;based anion&#8208;exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolysis cell (1 cm 2 ) delivers a current density of 1.02 and 1.32 A cm &#8722;2 at the voltage of 3 V feeding with 0.1 and 1 m KOH solution, respectively. The demonstrated metal&#8208;O coordination with abundant atomic vacancies for ferromagnetic M 3 GeTe 2 and the easily extended preparation strategy would enlighten the rational design and fabrication of other ferromagnetic materials for wider electrocatalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Guyue Bo, Peng Li, Yuhang Fan, Xiaobo Zheng, Mengting Zhao, Qiang Zhu, Fu Yang, Yitong Li, Wei Pang, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Bernt Johannessen, Lars Thomsen, Bruce C. C. Cowie, Tianyi Ma, Zhidong Chen, Guan Heng Yeoh, Yi Du, Shi Xue Dou, Xiaojing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202310115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuSe2 nanoparticles loaded MoSe2 hybrid rods via interface engineering as an efficient electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159916</link>
      <description>Manzhou Zhu, Huijun Yu, Cheng&#8208;Han Yang, Qinghua Deng, Huan Liu, Jinqiang Huang, Yiwei Zhang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392881530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manzhou Zhu, Huijun Yu, Cheng&#8208;Han Yang, Qinghua Deng, Huan Liu, Jinqiang Huang, Yiwei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in two-dimensional metallenes and their potential application as electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.068</link>
      <description>Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Muhammad Fazle Rabbee, Hadi M. Marwani, Jehan Y. Al&#8208;Humaidi, Muhammad Altaf, Raed H. Althomali, Kwang-Hyun Baek, Md. Rabiul Awual, Mohammed M. Rahman, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392883430

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Muhammad Fazle Rabbee, Hadi M. Marwani, Jehan Y. Al&#8208;Humaidi, Muhammad Altaf, Raed H. Althomali, Kwang-Hyun Baek, Md. Rabiul Awual, Mohammed M. Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of nitrogen reduction reaction activity of sp-B-doped &#947;-graphyne nanotubes through curvature effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114044</link>
      <description>Renzhi Ma, Yipin Lv, Yaqiong Yang, Xinru Wei, Jin Yong Lee, Shaul Mukamel, Baotao Kang, Molecular Catalysis. 558(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392890465

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Renzhi Ma, Yipin Lv, Yaqiong Yang, Xinru Wei, Jin Yong Lee, Shaul Mukamel, Baotao Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phenol as proton shuttle and buffer for lithium-mediated ammonia electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46803-w</link>
      <description>Xiujun Fu, Aoni Xu, Jakob B. Pedersen, Shaofeng Li, Rokas Sa&#382;inas, Yuanyuan Zhou, Suzanne Zamany Andersen, Mattia Saccoccio, Niklas H. Deissler, Jon Bjarke Valb&#230;k Mygind, Jakob Kibsgaard, Peter Christian Kj&#230;rgaard Vesborg, Jens K. N&#248;rskov, Ib Chorkendorff, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392897390

                Abstract Ammonia is a crucial component in the production of fertilizers and various nitrogen-based compounds. Now, the lithium-mediated nitrogen reduction reaction (Li-NRR) has emerged as a promising approach for ammonia synthesis at ambient conditions. The proton shuttle plays a critical role in the proton transfer process during Li-NRR. However, the structure-activity relationship and design principles for effective proton shuttles have not yet been established in practical Li-NRR systems. Here, we propose a general procedure for verifying a true proton shuttle and established design principles for effective proton shuttles. We systematically evaluate several classes of proton shuttles in a continuous-flow reactor with hydrogen oxidation at the anode. Among the tested proton shuttles, phenol exhibits the highest Faradaic efficiency of 72 &#177; 3% towards ammonia, surpassing that of ethanol, which has been commonly used so far. Experimental investigations including operando isotope-labelled mass spectrometry proved the proton-shuttling capability of phenol. Further mass transport modeling sheds light on the mechanism.</description>
      <author>Xiujun Fu, Aoni Xu, Jakob B. Pedersen, Shaofeng Li, Rokas Sa&#382;inas, Yuanyuan Zhou, Suzanne Zamany Andersen, Mattia Saccoccio, Niklas H. Deissler, Jon Bjarke Valb&#230;k Mygind, Jakob Kibsgaard, Peter Christian Kj&#230;rgaard Vesborg, Jens K. N&#248;rskov, Ib Chorkendorff</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46803-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal-based nanozymes: Classification, catalytic mechanisms and emerging biomedical applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215771</link>
      <description>Dandan Zhang, Qing Chen, Qunxiang Ren, Zhong Wang, Hongjin Zhang, Guannan Wang, Yang Zhang, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 508(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392898345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dandan Zhang, Qing Chen, Qunxiang Ren, Zhong Wang, Hongjin Zhang, Guannan Wang, Yang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biologically Templated Formation of Cobalt-Phosphide-Graphene Hybrid with Charge Redistribution for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4762336</link>
      <description>Xingchen Zhou, Lanqian Gong, Chen Wu, Yanfang Peng, Bin Cao, Xueliang Jiang, Huan Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Bao Yu Xia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392899183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingchen Zhou, Lanqian Gong, Chen Wu, Yanfang Peng, Bin Cao, Xueliang Jiang, Huan Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4762336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoporous Nickel Cathode with an Electrostatic Chlorine-Resistant Surface for Industrial Seawater Electrolysis Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00392</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Yanqi Li, Xu Tian, Jie Zheng, Kaiwen Xiao, Bingbing Sun, Ming Ge, Xiaolei Yuan, Chenggang Zhou, Zhao Cai, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392900270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Yanqi Li, Xu Tian, Jie Zheng, Kaiwen Xiao, Bingbing Sun, Ming Ge, Xiaolei Yuan, Chenggang Zhou, Zhao Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Coordination Environment of Ir Single Atoms with Surface Titanium Oxide Amorphization for Superior Chlorine Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13834</link>
      <description>Jiaxian Wang, Long Zhao, Yunjie Zou, Jie Dai, Qiuling Zheng, Xingyue Zou, Lufa Hu, Wei Hou, Ruizhao Wang, Kaiyuan Wang, Yanbiao Shi, Guangming Zhan, Yancai Yao, Lizhi Zhang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392907480

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaxian Wang, Long Zhao, Yunjie Zou, Jie Dai, Qiuling Zheng, Xingyue Zou, Lufa Hu, Wei Hou, Ruizhao Wang, Kaiyuan Wang, Yanbiao Shi, Guangming Zhan, Yancai Yao, Lizhi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural regulation of amorphous molybdenum sulfide by atomic palladium doping for hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.113</link>
      <description>Yao Xiao, Chee Kiang Ivan Tan, Fangui Zeng, Xinyang Wang, Jian Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392907943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Xiao, Chee Kiang Ivan Tan, Fangui Zeng, Xinyang Wang, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-level charge separation boosting the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150536</link>
      <description>Jingwen Pan, Dongbo Wang, Bingke Zhang, Chenchen Zhao, Donghao Liu, Sihang Liu, Zhi Zeng, Tianyuan Chen, Gang Liu, Shujie Jiao, Zhikun Xu, Tongling Liu, Taifeng Liu, Xuan Fang, Liancheng Zhao, Jinzhong Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392914099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingwen Pan, Dongbo Wang, Bingke Zhang, Chenchen Zhao, Donghao Liu, Sihang Liu, Zhi Zeng, Tianyuan Chen, Gang Liu, Shujie Jiao, Zhikun Xu, Tongling Liu, Taifeng Liu, Xuan Fang, Liancheng Zhao, Jinzhong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Quality and Reliability of Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials through Better Reporting Practices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00028</link>
      <description>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393002362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a 3D Ni-Mn Binary Oxide Anode for Energy-Efficient Electro-Oxidation of Organic Pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112562</link>
      <description>Keyvan Mirehbar, Jaime S. Sanchez, Sergio Pinilla, Freddy E. Oropeza, Ignasi Sir&#233;s, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Jes&#250;s Palma, Julio J. Lado, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392974422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Keyvan Mirehbar, Jaime S. Sanchez, Sergio Pinilla, Freddy E. Oropeza, Ignasi Sir&#233;s, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Jes&#250;s Palma, Julio J. Lado</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112562</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
