<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 01:23:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in CO2 Splitting Processes with Non-Thermal Plasma-Assisted</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114692</link>
      <description>Baiqiang Zhang, Hengfei Zuo, Bo Wu, Kenji Kamiya, Wei Ma, Nobusuke Kobayashi, Y. Ma, Tingxiang Jin, Yuhui Chen, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404171277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baiqiang Zhang, Hengfei Zuo, Bo Wu, Kenji Kamiya, Wei Ma, Nobusuke Kobayashi, Y. Ma, Tingxiang Jin, Yuhui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening and investigation of ligand effect on TM single atom catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114981</link>
      <description>N.J. Hemavathi, Chiranjib Majumder, Suman Kalyan Sahoo, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404171634

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N.J. Hemavathi, Chiranjib Majumder, Suman Kalyan Sahoo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Pathway on RuP&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; through Ab Initio Grand Canonical Monte Carlo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04913</link>
      <description>Shihan Qin, Sayan Banerjee, Mehmet G&#246;khan &#350;ensoy, Andrew M. Rappe, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404185926

                In this study, the high catalytic reactivity of ruthenium phosphide (RuP2) has been identified by first-principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations for the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Complex surface reconstructions are considered by applying the ab initio grand canonical Monte Carlo (ai-GCMC) algorithm, efficiently providing a sufficient phase-space exploration of possible surfaces. Combined with surface-phase Pourbaix diagrams, we are able to identify the actual surfaces that obtained under specific experimental environments, thus leading to a more accurate understanding of the nature of the active sites and the binding strength of adsorbates. Specifically, through hundreds of surface reconstructions and hydrogenation states generated with ai-GCMC, we identify the most favorable surface phases of RuP2 under aqueous acidic conditions. We discover that the HER activity is determined by multiple surfaces with different stoichiometries within a narrow electrode potential window. Low HER overpotential (&#951;) has been found for each of the identified surfaces, as low as 0.04 V. High H-coverage reconstructed surfaces have been discovered under acidic conditions, and the surface Ru sites introduced by additional Ru adatoms or exposed by P-vacancies serve as the active sites for HER based on their nearly reversible H binding. This work provides atomistic insights into the origin of high HER activity on RuP2 by exploring the dynamic surface phases of electrocatalysts and features a generalizable method to explore the reconstructed/hydrogenated surface space as a function of experimental conditions.</description>
      <author>Shihan Qin, Sayan Banerjee, Mehmet G&#246;khan &#350;ensoy, Andrew M. Rappe</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in development of characterization capabilities to evaluate candidate materials for direct air capture applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102975</link>
      <description>Marcus Carter, Huong Giang T. Nguyen, Andrew P. Allen, Feng Yi, Wei&#8208;Chang Yang, Avery E. Baumann, W. Sean McGivern, Jeffrey A. Manion, Ivan Kuzmenko, Zois Tsinas, Charlotte M. Wentz, Malia B. Wenny, Daniel W. Siderius, Roger D. van Zee, Christopher M. Stafford, Craig M. Brown, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 89(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404199074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marcus Carter, Huong Giang T. Nguyen, Andrew P. Allen, Feng Yi, Wei&#8208;Chang Yang, Avery E. Baumann, W. Sean McGivern, Jeffrey A. Manion, Ivan Kuzmenko, Zois Tsinas, Charlotte M. Wentz, Malia B. Wenny, Daniel W. Siderius, Roger D. van Zee, Christopher M. Stafford, Craig M. Brown</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2024.102975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the Origin of Enhanced C2+ Selectivity on Oxide-Derived Copper toward CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124805</link>
      <description>Hui Yu, Wenru Zhao, Xiangzun Dong, J. Wang, Wei Wang, Liu-Liu Shen, Guirong Zhang, Donghai Mei, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404202096

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Yu, Wenru Zhao, Xiangzun Dong, J. Wang, Wei Wang, Liu-Liu Shen, Guirong Zhang, Donghai Mei</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Au decorated Ni(OH)2 nanostructures: the role of alkaline cations solvation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124804</link>
      <description>Lucas D. Germano, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Antonio G. S. de Oliveira&#8208;Filho, Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404205963

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lucas D. Germano, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Antonio G. S. de Oliveira&#8208;Filho, Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalytic Performance of Nickel&#8208;Nitrogen&#8208;Carbon Catalysts through Coordination Environment Engineering&lt;sup&gt;&#8224;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400769</link>
      <description>Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404209081

                Comprehensive Summary Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted significant attention due to their high atomic utilization and tunable coordination environment. However, the catalytic mechanisms related to the active center and coordination environment remain unclear. In this study, we systematically investigated the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalytic activities of NiN 4 , NiN 3 , NiN 3 H 2 , NiN 4 X, NiN 3 X, and NiN 3 H 2 X (X denotes axial ligand) through density functional theory (DFT) calculations. This study unveils two distinct reaction pathways for ORR and OER, involving proton&#8208;electron pairs adsorbed from both the solution and the catalyst surface. The overpotential is the key parameter to evaluate the catalytic performance when proton&#8208;electron pairs are adsorbed from the solution. NiN 3 and NiN 3 H 2 show promise as pH&#8208;universal bifunctional electrocatalysts for both ORR and OER. On the other hand, when proton&#8208;electron pairs are adsorbed from the catalyst surface, the reaction energy barrier becomes the crucial metric for assessing catalytic activity. Our investigation reveals that NiN 3 H 2 consistently exhibits optimal ORR activity across a wide pH range, regardless of the source of proton&#8208;electron pair (solvent or catalyst surface).</description>
      <author>Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational descriptor for electrochemical currents of carbon dioxide reduction on Cu facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115836</link>
      <description>Timothy T. Yang, Wissam A. Saidi, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404211724

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timothy T. Yang, Wissam A. Saidi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of Hydrogen Evolution over Oxidized Cu&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;Y&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; in an Ionic Liquid Electrolyte for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrochemical Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01802</link>
      <description>Xiaofan Hou, Feifei You, Ming&#8208;Hui Zhao, Meng Shen, L.T. Fan, Mingming Peng, Kenji Kamiya, Eika W. Qian, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404220319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaofan Hou, Feifei You, Ming&#8208;Hui Zhao, Meng Shen, L.T. Fan, Mingming Peng, Kenji Kamiya, Eika W. Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Accelerated Surface Reconstruction of CoSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoneedle Forms Active CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@CoOOH Interface to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403744</link>
      <description>Quanxin Guo, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhengrong Xu, Rui Liu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404222203

                Abstract Interface engineering is an efficient strategy to create high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for water splitting. In the present work, CeO 2 @CoSe 2 nanoneedle on carbon cloth (CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC) demonstrates high efficiency for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and water splitting. CeO 2 with abundant O vacancies facilitates the adsorption of OH &#8722; and boosts the reconstruction of CoSe 2 into CoOOH at lower potentials. The in situ generated active CeO 2 @CoOOH heterointerface upshifts the d&#8208;band center of Co site, thereby decreasing the free energy of rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) ( * O to * OOH) during the OER process. It delivers a low OER overpotential of 245 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC is also found to be active for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER, 138 mV overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), profiting from CeO 2 &#8208;facilitated * H 2 O dissociation and * H adsorption on CoSe 2 . The overall water splitting is achieved over the CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC bifunctional electrode with a low electrolysis voltage of 1.54 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work offers valuable insights into CeO 2 &#8208;assisted surface reconstruction as well as provides water electrolysis catalysts through interface engineering.</description>
      <author>Quanxin Guo, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhengrong Xu, Rui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Electronic Properties of CumAgn Bimetallic Clusters for Enhanced CO2 Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252212053</link>
      <description>Turki Alotaibi, Moteb Alotaibi, Fatimah Alhawiti, Norah Aldosari, Majd Alsunaid, Lama Aldawas, Talal F. Qahtan, Ali K. Ismael, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 25(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404224096

                The urgent demand for efficient CO2 reduction technologies has driven enormous studies into the enhancement of advanced catalysts. Here, we investigate the electronic properties and CO2 adsorption properties of CumAgn bimetallic clusters, particularly Cu4Ag1, Cu1Ag4, Cu3Ag2, and Cu2Ag3, using generalized gradient approximation (GGA)/density functional theory (DFT). Our results show that the atomic arrangement within these clusters drastically affects their stability, charge transfer, and catalytic performance. The Cu4Ag1 bimetallic cluster emerges as the most stable structure, revealing superior charge transfer and effective chemisorption of CO2, which promotes effective activation of the CO2 molecule. In contrast, the Cu1Ag4 bimetallic cluster, in spite of comparable adsorption energy, indicates insignificant charge transfer, resulting in less pronounced CO2 activation. The Cu3Ag2 and Cu2Ag3 bimetallic clusters also display high adsorption energies with remarkable charge transfer mechanisms, emphasizing the crucial role of metal composition in tuning catalytic characteristics. This thorough examination provides constructive insights into the design of bimetallic clusters for boosted CO2 reduction. These findings could pave the way for the development of cost-effective and efficient catalysts for industrial CO2 reduction, contributing to global efforts in carbon management and climate change mitigation.</description>
      <author>Turki Alotaibi, Moteb Alotaibi, Fatimah Alhawiti, Norah Aldosari, Majd Alsunaid, Lama Aldawas, Talal F. Qahtan, Ali K. Ismael</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252212053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver Electrodes Are Highly Selective for CO in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction due to Interplay between Voltage Dependent Kinetics and Thermodynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02869</link>
      <description>Michele Re Fiorentin, Francesca Risplendi, Clara Salvini, Juqin Zeng, Giancarlo Cicero, Hannes J&#243;nsson, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404227466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Michele Re Fiorentin, Francesca Risplendi, Clara Salvini, Juqin Zeng, Giancarlo Cicero, Hannes J&#243;nsson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dependence of Oxygen Diffusion on the La and Sr Configuration in Melilite-Type La&lt;sub&gt;1+&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ga&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7+&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;/2&lt;/sub&gt; by Neural Network Potential Molecular Dynamics Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03617</link>
      <description>T KOYAMA, Masanobu Nakayama, Judith Schuett, Steffen Grieshammer, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404230693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>T KOYAMA, Masanobu Nakayama, Judith Schuett, Steffen Grieshammer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped Ni-Based Catalysts Surpass Ir-Baselines for Oxygen Evolution Due to Optimal Charge-Transfer Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</link>
      <description>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Assess and Predict Electrical Double Layer Properties. Implications for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00806</link>
      <description>Christian M. Schott, Peter M. Schneider, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Haiting Yu, Rainer G&#246;tz, Felix Haimerl, Elena L. Gubanova, Jian Zhou, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Qi&#8208;Wei Zhang, Vitaly Alexandrov, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404238022

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Christian M. Schott, Peter M. Schneider, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Haiting Yu, Rainer G&#246;tz, Felix Haimerl, Elena L. Gubanova, Jian Zhou, Thorsten O. Schmidt, Qi&#8208;Wei Zhang, Vitaly Alexandrov, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Co Doping on Copper Nanoclusters for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07514</link>
      <description>Guilherme Rodrigues do Nascimento, Marionir M. C. B. Neto, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404238489

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guilherme Rodrigues do Nascimento, Marionir M. C. B. Neto, Juarez L. F. Da Silva, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-Learning-Assisted Screening of Nanocluster Electrocatalysts: Mapping and Reshaping the Activity Volcano for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14076</link>
      <description>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Milan Kumar Jena, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404241066

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Milan Kumar Jena, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplification of solvation shell with water clusters in the simulation of electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0230137</link>
      <description>Hanxuan Liu, Zheng&#8208;Qing Huang, Xin Gao, Guidong Yang, Chun&#8208;Ran Chang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404244919

                Electrochemical methods for nitrogen reduction have received extensive attention due to the mild reaction conditions. In order to gain an insight into the mechanism of the electrochemical nitrogen reduction process, theoretical simulations are necessary. However, current simulation studies contain many imprecise approximations that may hinder the real recognition of the reaction process. Although solvation methods have recently been developed to provide efficient descriptions, their further applications are hindered by controversy over modeling of solvents and the enormous computational effort required. In this work, we simplify the solvation conditions by using water clusters and compare them with an accurate water layer model. The results demonstrate that the simplified water clusters can effectively capture protons, simulate the surface electric environment, and enable the calculation of the activation energy of the reaction. This method offers an affordable approach for simulating the surface potentials and solvents and provides a new reference for the theoretical study of the electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction.</description>
      <author>Hanxuan Liu, Zheng&#8208;Qing Huang, Xin Gao, Guidong Yang, Chun&#8208;Ran Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0230137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular level insights on the pulsed electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54122-3</link>
      <description>Ke Ye, Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Hyun Dong Jung, Peng Shen, So Min Jang, Zhe Weng, Seoin Back, Wen&#8208;Bin Cai, Kun Jiang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404252638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ke Ye, Tian&#8208;Wen Jiang, Hyun Dong Jung, Peng Shen, So Min Jang, Zhe Weng, Seoin Back, Wen&#8208;Bin Cai, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54122-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Hidden Catalytic Sites in 2D Basal Plane via p&#8211;n Heterojunction Interface Engineering Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403722</link>
      <description>Eugene Kim, Sungsoon Kim, Yong&#8208;Chul Kim, Kiran Hamkins, Jihyun Baek, MinJoong Kim, Tae&#8208;Kyung Liu, Young Moon Choi, Jung Hwan Lee, Gyu Yong Jang, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Geunsik Lee, Xiaolin Zheng, Jong Hyeok Park, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404255224

                Abstract Nonprecious metal&#8208;based 2D materials have shown promising electrocatalytic activity toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the catalytically active sites of 2D materials are mainly presented at the edge, and most of their basal planes are still catalytically inactive, which turns into a significant drawback on the catalytic efficiency. Here, a novel p&#8211;n heterojunction strategy is suggested that generates active sites on the basal plane of 2D NiFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH). The n&#8208;type NiFe&#8208;LDH is first grown on a nickel foam (NF) substrate, and p&#8208;type Co 3 O 4 nanocubes are deposited through a simple dip&#8208;coating method to fabricate a Co 3 O 4 /NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF p&#8211;n heterojunction electrode. As a result, electron transfer is induced at the interface of p&#8208;type Co 3 O 4 and n&#8208;type NiFe&#8208;LDH, which consequently promotes oxidation of the inert Ni 2+ state to a more catalytically active Ni 3+ state on the inert basal plane of NiFe&#8208;LDH. As&#8208;prepared Co 3 O 4 /NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF electrodes obtained enhanced OER performance showing a high current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.48 V (vs RHE) which outperforms that of pristine NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF. The utilization of the p&#8211;n junction concept will disclose a new strategy for modifying the electronic structure of the catalytically inactive basal plane and stimulating its electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Eugene Kim, Sungsoon Kim, Yong&#8208;Chul Kim, Kiran Hamkins, Jihyun Baek, MinJoong Kim, Tae&#8208;Kyung Liu, Young Moon Choi, Jung Hwan Lee, Gyu Yong Jang, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Geunsik Lee, Xiaolin Zheng, Jong Hyeok Park</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A general machine-learning framework for high-throughput screening for stable and efficient RuO2-based acidic oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5347326/v1</link>
      <description>Zhe Shang, Qian Dang, Sheng Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404257326

                Abstract Doping guest elements is an effective way to increase activity and stability of RuO2 catalysts in acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, due to the vastness of doping space, it is challenging for either high-cost experiments or density functional theory (DFT) calculations to screen out the doped structures with the optimized catalytic performance. Herein, we reported a machine-learning (ML) framework that aims to realize high-throughput screening for both stability and activity of doped-RuO2 acidic OER catalysts from mono-doping to triple-doping at a low level of computational cost. Compared to the d-band theory and some other previous models, our ML model was constructed based on more general input features and realized higher prediction accuracy with mean absolute errors (MAEs) of 0.074, 0.142 and 0.082 eV for *OH, *O and *OOH adsorption, respectively. Through the ML models, three doping structures, Ru41Zn7O96, Ru41Zn4Fe3O96, and Ru39Zn4Cu4Co1O96 were found to possess the extraordinarily high stability and comparable or higher activity than the previously reported OER catalysts. This work provided an efficient study paradigm in fields of material screening and a useful guide for experimental synthesis.</description>
      <author>Zhe Shang, Qian Dang, Sheng Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5347326/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Synergistic Multifunctional Electrocatalysis of N-Doped Graphene/WS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure with Single-Atom Catalysts for Water Splitting and Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16119</link>
      <description>Deepak Arumugam, Divyakaaviri Subramani, Akilesh Muralidharan, R. Shankar, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404257452

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deepak Arumugam, Divyakaaviri Subramani, Akilesh Muralidharan, R. Shankar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution activity by two-dimensional van der Waals AlSb/ZnO heterostructure: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105397</link>
      <description>Aroni Ghosh, Ahmed Zubair, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404258858

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aroni Ghosh, Ahmed Zubair</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wear Resistance of N-Doped CoCrFeNiMn High Entropy Alloy Coating on the Ti-6Al-4V Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11666-024-01864-7</link>
      <description>Minhui Yang, J.L. Xu, J.C. Huang, L. W. Zhang, Jiawei Luo, Journal of Thermal Spray Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404259216

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minhui Yang, J.L. Xu, J.C. Huang, L. W. Zhang, Jiawei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11666-024-01864-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty Based Machine Learning-DFT Hybrid Framework for Accelerating Geometry Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00953</link>
      <description>Akksay Singh, Jiaqi Wang, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404259391

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akksay Singh, Jiaqi Wang, Graeme Henkelman, Lei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-Driven Coordinated Oxygen Migration in an Electrocatalyst for Sustainable H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11307</link>
      <description>Zhiping Deng, Song Jin, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Min Ho Seo, Xiaolei Wang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404276344

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiping Deng, Song Jin, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Min Ho Seo, Xiaolei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Ferroelectricity and Photocatalytic Performance in Wurtzite Zn2VN3: A Novel Approach for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110972</link>
      <description>Liting Niu, Huakai Xu, Guo-Xia Lai, Zi-Xuan Chen, Ya-Yi Tian, Xiang-Fu Xu, Xiaodong Yang, Weiling Zhu, Xing-Yuan Chen, Lijuan Chen, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404277101

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liting Niu, Huakai Xu, Guo-Xia Lai, Zi-Xuan Chen, Ya-Yi Tian, Xiang-Fu Xu, Xiaodong Yang, Weiling Zhu, Xing-Yuan Chen, Lijuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron energy loss spectra and exciton band structure of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;WSe&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; monolayers studied by &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; Bethe-Salpeter equation calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.205417</link>
      <description>Y. C. Shih, Fredrik Nilsson, Guang&#8208;Yu Guo, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404280760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y. C. Shih, Fredrik Nilsson, Guang&#8208;Yu Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.205417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the mysteries of hydrogen spillover phenomenon in hydrogen evolution reaction: Fundamentals, evidence and enhancement strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216321</link>
      <description>Shan Zhao, Zhenhong Wang, Jingyu Wang, Pengfei Wang, Zonglin Liu, Jie Shu, Ting&#8208;Feng Yi, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 524(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404281882

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Zhao, Zhenhong Wang, Jingyu Wang, Pengfei Wang, Zonglin Liu, Jie Shu, Ting&#8208;Feng Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopically Elucidating the Local Proton-Coupled Electron Transfer Loop from Amino to Nitro Groups via the Au Surface in a N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c04579</link>
      <description>Yang Lu, Yifan Huang, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404282266

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Lu, Yifan Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c04579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning aided design of high performance copper-based sulfide photocathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06128d</link>
      <description>Yuxi Cao, Keng Shen, Yuanfei Li, F. Lan, Zeyu Guo, K. H. Zhang, Kang Wang, Feng Jiang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404282816

                With the help of machine learning algorithms, we developed software that can predict the performance of copper-based sulfide photocathodes and this system shows excellent accuracy of up to 96%.</description>
      <author>Yuxi Cao, Keng Shen, Yuanfei Li, F. Lan, Zeyu Guo, K. H. Zhang, Kang Wang, Feng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06128d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the catalytic performance of carbon nitrides for overall water splitting by tuning the C/N ratio: A theoretical investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141750</link>
      <description>Afshan Mohajeri, Fatemeh Ansari, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404291995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Afshan Mohajeri, Fatemeh Ansari</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into the essential role of weak interactions in the electrocatalytic reduction of nitrobenzene: Ag-anchored graphene electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112513</link>
      <description>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Lixin Ye, Weihua Zhu, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404293862

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Lixin Ye, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Topological Platinum Telluride Superstructures with Periodic Tellurium Vacancies for Efficient and Robust Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c10085</link>
      <description>Xin Xu, Sheng Wang, Shuming Yu, Chenhui Wang, Guowei Liu, Hao Li, Jiangang Yang, Jing Li, Tao Sun, Xiao Hai, Lei Li, Xue Liu, Ying Zhang, Weifeng Zhang, Quan Zhang, Kedong Wang, Nan Xu, Yaping Ma, Fangfei Ming, Ping Cui, Jiong Lu, Zhenyu Zhang, Xudong Xiao, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404297417

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Xu, Sheng Wang, Shuming Yu, Chenhui Wang, Guowei Liu, Hao Li, Jiangang Yang, Jing Li, Tao Sun, Xiao Hai, Lei Li, Xue Liu, Ying Zhang, Weifeng Zhang, Quan Zhang, Kedong Wang, Nan Xu, Yaping Ma, Fangfei Ming, Ping Cui, Jiong Lu, Zhenyu Zhang, Xudong Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c10085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparison of Modern Solvation Models for Oxygen Reduction at the Pt(111) Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04924</link>
      <description>Tom Demeyere, Chris&#8208;Kriton Skylaris, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404299800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tom Demeyere, Chris&#8208;Kriton Skylaris</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Ultrafast Energy Transfer Pathways in Energetic Materials: Time-Dependent and Quantum State-Resolved</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00775</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Jitai Yang, Gangbei Zhu, Jiarui Li, You Li, Yu Zhai, Hua-Jie Song, Yanqiang Yang, Hui Li, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404302254

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Jitai Yang, Gangbei Zhu, Jiarui Li, You Li, Yu Zhai, Hua-Jie Song, Yanqiang Yang, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward first principles-based simulations of dense hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219405</link>
      <description>M. B&#246;nitz, Jan Vorberger, Mandy Bethkenhagen, Maximilian B&#246;hme, David M. Ceperley, A. Filinov, Thomas Gawne, Frank Graziani, G. Gregori, Paul Hamann, Stephanie B. Hansen, Markus Holzmann, S. X. Hu, H. K&#228;hlert, Valentin V. Karasiev, Uwe Kleinschmidt, Linda Kordts, Christopher Makait, Burkhard Militzer, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Carlo Pierleoni, Martin Preising, Kushal Ramakrishna, R. Redmer, Sebastian Schwalbe, Pontus Svensson, Tobias Dornheim, Physics of Plasmas. 31(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404306208

                Accurate knowledge of the properties of hydrogen at high compression is crucial for astrophysics (e.g., planetary and stellar interiors, brown dwarfs, atmosphere of compact stars) and laboratory experiments, including inertial confinement fusion. There exists experimental data for the equation of state, conductivity, and Thomson scattering spectra. However, the analysis of the measurements at extreme pressures and temperatures typically involves additional model assumptions, which makes it difficult to assess the accuracy of the experimental data rigorously. On the other hand, theory and modeling have produced extensive collections of data. They originate from a very large variety of models and simulations including path integral Monte Carlo (PIMC) simulations, density functional theory (DFT), chemical models, machine-learned models, and combinations thereof. At the same time, each of these methods has fundamental limitations (fermion sign problem in PIMC, approximate exchange&#8211;correlation functionals of DFT, inconsistent interaction energy contributions in chemical models, etc.), so for some parameter ranges accurate predictions are difficult. Recently, a number of breakthroughs in first principles PIMC as well as in DFT simulations were achieved which are discussed in this review. Here we use these results to benchmark different simulation methods. We present an update of the hydrogen phase diagram at high pressures, the expected phase transitions, and thermodynamic properties including the equation of state and momentum distribution. Furthermore, we discuss available dynamic results for warm dense hydrogen, including the conductivity, dynamic structure factor, plasmon dispersion, imaginary-time structure, and density response functions. We conclude by outlining strategies to combine different simulations to achieve accurate theoretical predictions that are based on first principles.</description>
      <author>M. B&#246;nitz, Jan Vorberger, Mandy Bethkenhagen, Maximilian B&#246;hme, David M. Ceperley, A. Filinov, Thomas Gawne, Frank Graziani, G. Gregori, Paul Hamann, Stephanie B. Hansen, Markus Holzmann, S. X. Hu, H. K&#228;hlert, Valentin V. Karasiev, Uwe Kleinschmidt, Linda Kordts, Christopher Makait, Burkhard Militzer, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Carlo Pierleoni, Martin Preising, Kushal Ramakrishna, R. Redmer, Sebastian Schwalbe, Pontus Svensson, Tobias Dornheim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Surface Functionalization of Exfoliated MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets for Improved Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05965</link>
      <description>Leandro Hostert, Matheus Santos Dias, Caroline B. de Aquino, F. Santos, Val&#233;ria S. Marangoni, Cec&#237;lia de Carvalho Castro Silva, Leandro Seixas, Camila M. Maroneze, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404308961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leandro Hostert, Matheus Santos Dias, Caroline B. de Aquino, F. Santos, Val&#233;ria S. Marangoni, Cec&#237;lia de Carvalho Castro Silva, Leandro Seixas, Camila M. Maroneze</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Potential-Dependent Kinetics for the Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CO over Ti@4N-Gr</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00073</link>
      <description>Yousef A. Alsunni, Abdulaziz Alherz, Charles B. Musgrave, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404317122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yousef A. Alsunni, Abdulaziz Alherz, Charles B. Musgrave</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Catalytic Activity of MXene Nanosheet Supported on CuFeO2 Nanoparticles Applied on Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.11.181</link>
      <description>Zhen-Yuan Lan, Dhanapal Vasu, Yung&#8208;Chieh Liu, Chung&#8208;Lun Yu, Te&#8208;Wei Chiu, Tetsu Yonezawa, Hongbing Jia, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404318336

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhen-Yuan Lan, Dhanapal Vasu, Yung&#8208;Chieh Liu, Chung&#8208;Lun Yu, Te&#8208;Wei Chiu, Tetsu Yonezawa, Hongbing Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.11.181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards superior CO2RR catalysts: Deciphering the selectivity puzzle over dual-atom catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.080</link>
      <description>Jia Zhao, Sen Lin, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404319061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Zhao, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Based Layered Perovskite Oxyfluoride Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution: Insights from Crystal Facets with Heteroanionic Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05740</link>
      <description>Ryusuke Mizuochi, Yuuki Sugawara, Kengo Oka, Yoshiyuki Inaguma, Shunsuke Nozawa, Toshiyuki Yokoi, Takeo Yamaguchi, Kazuhiko Maeda, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404320100

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ryusuke Mizuochi, Yuuki Sugawara, Kengo Oka, Yoshiyuki Inaguma, Shunsuke Nozawa, Toshiyuki Yokoi, Takeo Yamaguchi, Kazuhiko Maeda</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafine Ruthenium Nanoparticles Anchored on S,N-Codoped Carbon Nanofibers for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Electricity Coproduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07973</link>
      <description>Yaxin Lai, Lvlv Ji, Jianying Wang, Jiangnan Shen, Junbin Liao, Xiaoyang He, Li Wang, Zuofeng Chen, Li Wang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404320510

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaxin Lai, Lvlv Ji, Jianying Wang, Jiangnan Shen, Junbin Liao, Xiaoyang He, Li Wang, Zuofeng Chen, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual active site pathways in cobalt-based bimetallic catalysts enhance oxygen evolution reaction activity: Density functional theory studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105428</link>
      <description>Zeliang Ju, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Chengfeng Yin, Qingxin Kang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404321196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeliang Ju, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Chengfeng Yin, Qingxin Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of the Conceptual and Functional Factors Affecting the Effectiveness of Proton-Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering8060116</link>
      <description>Gaydaa Al Zohbi, ChemEngineering. 8(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404322371

                Hydrogen has the potential to decarbonize the energy and industrial sectors in the future, mainly if it is generated by water electrolysis. The proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) system is regarded as a propitious technology to produce green hydrogen from water using power supplied by renewable energy sources. It offers many benefits, such as high performance, high proton conductibility, quick response, compact size, and low working temperature. Many conceptual and functional parameters influence the effectiveness of PEM, including temperature, pressure of anode and cathode regions, water content and wideness of the layer, and cathode and anode exchange current density. In addition, the anodic half-reaction (known as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER)) and cathodic half-reaction (known as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)) perform an important function in the development of PEMWE. The current study aims to present these parameters and discuss their impacts on the performance of PEM. Also, the PEM efficiency is presented. The different methods used to enhance the scattering of OER electrocatalysts and minimize catalyst loading to minimize the price of PEMWE are also highlighted. Moreover, the alternative noble metals that could be used as electrocatalysts in HER and OER to minimize the cost of PEM are reviewed and presented.</description>
      <author>Gaydaa Al Zohbi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering8060116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potassium and Boron Co-Doping of g-C3N4 Tuned CO2 Reduction Mechanism for Enhanced Photocatalytic Performance: A First-Principles Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225339</link>
      <description>Gang Fu, Wenqing Zhen, Hongyi Wang, Xin Zhou, Li Yang, Jiaxu Zhang, Molecules. 29(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404331595

                Graphitic phase carbon nitride (g-C3N4, abbreviated as CN) can be used as a photocatalyst to reduce the concentration of atmospheric carbon dioxide. However, there is still potential for improvement in the small band gap and carrier migration properties of intrinsic materials. K-B co-doped CN (KBCN) was investigated as a promising photocatalyst for carbon dioxide reduction via the Density Functional Theory (DFT) method. The electronic and optical properties of CN and KBCN indicate that doping K and B can improve the catalytic performance of CN by promoting charge migration and separation. In terms of the Gibbs free energy change, the CO2 reduction reaction catalysed by KBCN results in CH3OH, and its optimal pathway is CO2 &#8594; *CO2 &#8594; *COOH &#8594; CO &#8594; *OCH &#8594; HCHO &#8594; *OCH3 &#8594; CH3OH. Compared with CN, the doping elements K and B shift the rate-determining step from CO2 &#8594; *CO2 to *CO2 &#8594; *COOH. The K and B elements co-doping tuned the charge distribution between the catalyst and the adsorbate and reduced the Gibbs free energy of the rate-determining step from 1.571 to 0.861 eV, suggesting that the CO2 reduction activity of KBCN is superior to that of CN. Our work provides useful insights for the design of metallic&#8211;nonmetallic co-doped CN for photocatalytic CO2 reduction (CO2PR) reactions.</description>
      <author>Gang Fu, Wenqing Zhen, Hongyi Wang, Xin Zhou, Li Yang, Jiaxu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT modeling of the oxygen electroreduction reaction on SiN3-doped carbon nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044460x24050123</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1079;&#1100;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1046;&#1091;&#1088;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083; &#1054;&#1073;&#1097;&#1077;&#1081; &#1061;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1080;. 94(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404337748

                The thermodynamic features and mechanism of the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction were studied using the revPBE0-D3(BJ)/Def2-TZVP method on the example of (6,6)-armchair carbon nanotube doped with a tricoordinated silicon atom and nitrogen atoms of pyridinic and graphitic nature. Irreversible oxidation of the silicon center as a result of the formation of stable oxygen-containing adsorbates was shown. It was found that Si-poisoned structures are capable of participating in the catalysis of the target reaction along two- and four-electron routes at high overpotentials. For a nanotube doped simultaneously with pyridinic and graphitic nitrogens the potential possibility of eliminating the silicon atom from the catalyst composition in the form of orthosilicic acid and the participation of a silicon-free nitrogen-doped framework in the oxygen electroreduction reaction, for which the stage of tautomerization of pyridin-2(1H)-one to pyridin-2-ol is the limiting step was shown.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1079;&#1100;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044460x24050123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen radical-boosted electrocatalytic CO2 reduction using Ni-partnered heteroatomic pairs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53529-2</link>
      <description>Zhibo Yao, Hao Cheng, Yifei Xu, Xinyu Zhan, Song Hong, Xinyi Tan, Tai&#8208;Sing Wu, Pei Xiong, Y. L. Soo, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Leiduan Hao, Liang Xu, Alex W. Robertson, Bingjun Xu, Ming Yang, Zhenyu Sun, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404348913

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhibo Yao, Hao Cheng, Yifei Xu, Xinyu Zhan, Song Hong, Xinyi Tan, Tai&#8208;Sing Wu, Pei Xiong, Y. L. Soo, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Leiduan Hao, Liang Xu, Alex W. Robertson, Bingjun Xu, Ming Yang, Zhenyu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53529-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-throughput framework for lattice dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01437-w</link>
      <description>Zhuoying Zhu, Junsoo Park, Hrushikesh Sahasrabuddhe, Alex M. Ganose, Rees Chang, John W. Lawson, Anubhav Jain, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404351163

                Abstract We develop an automated high-throughput workflow for calculating lattice dynamical properties from first principles including those dictated by anharmonicity. The pipeline automatically computes interatomic force constants (IFCs) up to 4th order from perturbed training supercells, and uses the IFCs to calculate lattice thermal conductivity, coefficient of thermal expansion, and vibrational free energy and entropy. It performs phonon renormalization for dynamically unstable compounds to obtain real effective phonon spectra at finite temperatures and calculates the associated free energy corrections. The methods and parameters are chosen to balance computational efficiency and result accuracy, assessed through convergence testing and comparisons with experimental measurements. Deployment of this workflow at a large scale would facilitate materials discovery efforts toward functionalities including thermoelectrics, contact materials, ferroelectrics, aerospace components, as well as general phase diagram construction.</description>
      <author>Zhuoying Zhu, Junsoo Park, Hrushikesh Sahasrabuddhe, Alex M. Ganose, Rees Chang, John W. Lawson, Anubhav Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01437-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable production of high-performance electrocatalysts for electrochemical water splitting at large current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100334</link>
      <description>Zichen Xu, Zhong&#8208;Shuai Wu, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404353371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zichen Xu, Zhong&#8208;Shuai Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Storage (CCUS) projects on environmental protection, economic development, and social equity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144218</link>
      <description>Xiaoning Su, Pengfe&#239; Liu, Yingdan Mei, Jixiang Qiu, Journal of Cleaner Production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404353449

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoning Su, Pengfe&#239; Liu, Yingdan Mei, Jixiang Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of Transition Metal-Nitrogen-Carbon Materials as Electrocatalysts for CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145357</link>
      <description>Megan C. Davis, Wilton J. M. Kort-Kamp, Edward F. Holby, Piotr Zelenay, Ivana Matanovi&#263;, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404357011

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Megan C. Davis, Wilton J. M. Kort-Kamp, Edward F. Holby, Piotr Zelenay, Ivana Matanovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedding material graphs using the electron-ion potential: application to material fracture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00246f</link>
      <description>Sherif Abdulkader Tawfik, Tri Minh Nguyen, Salvy P. Russo, Truyen Tran, Sunil Gupta, Svetha Venkatesh, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404194542

                Improving the physics of physics-informed machine learning.</description>
      <author>Sherif Abdulkader Tawfik, Tri Minh Nguyen, Salvy P. Russo, Truyen Tran, Sunil Gupta, Svetha Venkatesh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dd00246f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Oxide Pathway Mechanism for Sustainable Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12942</link>
      <description>Xuejie Cao, Hongye Qin, Jinyang Zhang, Xiaojie Chen, Lifang Jiao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404283747

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuejie Cao, Hongye Qin, Jinyang Zhang, Xiaojie Chen, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12942</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
