<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 01:27:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Machine learning and active motifs-based catalyst design for discovery of oxygen reduction electrocatalysts for hydrogen peroxide production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115906</link>
      <description>G. Yu, Dong Hyeon Mok, Ho Yeon Jang, Hyun Dong Jung, Samira Siahrostami, Seoin Back, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405394547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. Yu, Dong Hyeon Mok, Ho Yeon Jang, Hyun Dong Jung, Samira Siahrostami, Seoin Back</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascade protection strategy for anchoring atomic FeN3 sites within defect-rich wood carbon aerogel for high-performance Zn-air batteries and versatile application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158551</link>
      <description>Jiaojiao Sun, Mengxia Shen, A. C. Chang, Chanjuan Liang, Chuanyin Xiong, Chen Hou, Jinbao Li, Pengbo Wang, Jiayin Li, Jianfeng Huang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405395385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaojiao Sun, Mengxia Shen, A. C. Chang, Chanjuan Liang, Chuanyin Xiong, Chen Hou, Jinbao Li, Pengbo Wang, Jiayin Li, Jianfeng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A FIB-TEM study on evolution of passive film during deactivation processes of Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145528</link>
      <description>Mingshuai Guo, Likun Xu, Yonglei Xin, Lili Xue, Tigang Duan, Rongrong Zhao, Penghe Liu, Shuai Zhou, Li Li, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405409001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingshuai Guo, Likun Xu, Yonglei Xin, Lili Xue, Tigang Duan, Rongrong Zhao, Penghe Liu, Shuai Zhou, Li Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8210;organic framework/graphene-based nanocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction: A comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.132</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ahmad Mudassir, Zainab Tazeen, Shazia Kousar, Muhan Li, Xiaoyu Zhao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405409464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ahmad Mudassir, Zainab Tazeen, Shazia Kousar, Muhan Li, Xiaoyu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the interaction of Ta atoms with Pt(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105640</link>
      <description>Kevin Bertrang, Tobias Hinke, Sebastian Kaiser, Matthias Knechtges, Federico Loi, Luca Sbuelz, Paolo Lacovig, Luca Bignardi, Friedrich Esch, Alessandro Baraldi, Sergio Tosoni, Aras Kartouzian, Ueli Heiz, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405418537

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kevin Bertrang, Tobias Hinke, Sebastian Kaiser, Matthias Knechtges, Federico Loi, Luca Sbuelz, Paolo Lacovig, Luca Bignardi, Friedrich Esch, Alessandro Baraldi, Sergio Tosoni, Aras Kartouzian, Ueli Heiz</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elevating CO2 selective conversion: Insights into copper-based single atom alloy catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-024-01105-z</link>
      <description>Di Tian, Zefeng Wang, Zhou Xu, Zhu Yi-quan, Yan Yan, Jifeng Yang, Siyuan He, Zhichao Xue, Li Wang, Shuo Li, Wenxuan Fan, Miaomiao Xue, Zehua Qu, Wei Xia, Mingkai Liu, Advanced Composites and Hybrid Materials. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405421670

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Di Tian, Zefeng Wang, Zhou Xu, Zhu Yi-quan, Yan Yan, Jifeng Yang, Siyuan He, Zhichao Xue, Li Wang, Shuo Li, Wenxuan Fan, Miaomiao Xue, Zehua Qu, Wei Xia, Mingkai Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-024-01105-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;CoTCNQ&lt;/scp&gt; as a Catalyst for &lt;scp&gt;CO&lt;/scp&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction: A First Principles r&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;scp&gt;SCAN&lt;/scp&gt; Meta&#8208;&lt;scp&gt;GGA&lt;/scp&gt; Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27528</link>
      <description>Oliver J. Conquest, Yijiao Jiang, Catherine Stampfl, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405424833

                ABSTRACT Using first principles calculations we investigate cobalt&#8208;coordinated tetracyanoquinodimethane (R&#8208;CoTCNQ) as a potential catalyst for the CO 2 electroreduction reaction (CO 2 ERR). We determine that exchange&#8211;correlation functionals beyond the generalized gradient approximation (GGA) are required to accurately describe the spin properties of R&#8208;CoTCNQ, therefore, the meta&#8208;GGA r 2 SCAN functional is used in this study. The free energy CO 2 ERR reaction pathways are calculated for the reduced catalyst ([R&#8208;CoTCNQ] &#8722;1 e ) with reaction products HCOOH and HCHO predicted depending on our choice of electrode potential. Calculations are also performed for [R&#8208;CoTCNQ] &#8722;1 e supported on a H&#8208;terminated diamond (1 1 0) surface with reaction pathways being qualitatively similar to the [R&#8208;CoTCNQ] &#8722;1 e monolayer. The inclusion of boron&#8208;doping in the diamond support shows a slightly improved CO 2 ERR reaction pathway. Furthermore, structurally, supported R&#8208;CoTCNQ provide a high specific area of active Co active sites and could be promising catalysts for future experimental consideration.</description>
      <author>Oliver J. Conquest, Yijiao Jiang, Catherine Stampfl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep eutectic solvent-derived carbon-based FeNi bimetallic catalysts for selective hydrogenation of furfural</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158676</link>
      <description>Siyi Pu, Zhouxiao Zhai, Chunyan Yang, Zirui Dao, Wei Yan, Changfu Zhuang, Chungang Min, Jie Zhao, Ying Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405430033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siyi Pu, Zhouxiao Zhai, Chunyan Yang, Zirui Dao, Wei Yan, Changfu Zhuang, Chungang Min, Jie Zhao, Ying Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 capture using Resin-Based solid Amines: Characteristic, Application, regeneration and deactivation mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131125</link>
      <description>Endian Hu, Li Lin, Kailun Chen, Jinglin Li, Yuchen Gao, Jingwen Chang, Weikai Qin, Yukun Zhao, Jianguo Jiang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405436896

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Endian Hu, Li Lin, Kailun Chen, Jinglin Li, Yuchen Gao, Jingwen Chang, Weikai Qin, Yukun Zhao, Jianguo Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial Growth of Atomic-Layer Cu on Pd Nanocatalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02541</link>
      <description>Shikai Liu, Chuqiao Shi, Chaokai Xu, Haichuan Zhang, Wenqi Li, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Qian He, Yimo Han, Yao Yang, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405437565

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shikai Liu, Chuqiao Shi, Chaokai Xu, Haichuan Zhang, Wenqi Li, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Qian He, Yimo Han, Yao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Activity and Stability through Compositional Engineering of Ternary PtNi&#8211;Au Alloy ORR Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05269</link>
      <description>Xianxian Xie, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Pere Alemany, Athira Lekshmi Mohandas Sandhya, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Milan Dopita, Michael Vorochta, Albert Bruix, Serhiy Cherevko, Konstantin M. Neyman, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Ivan Khalakhan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405439103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianxian Xie, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Pere Alemany, Athira Lekshmi Mohandas Sandhya, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Milan Dopita, Michael Vorochta, Albert Bruix, Serhiy Cherevko, Konstantin M. Neyman, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Ivan Khalakhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Modulated by B-Doped Cu Promotes Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction for Ammonia Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05954</link>
      <description>Jia-Jia Wang, Zhuodong Ou, Chenglin Dong, Mengying Su, Amjad Ali, Artem V. Kuklin, Hans &#197;gren, Glib Baryshnikov, Yang Liu, Xue Zhao, Haibo Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443274

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia-Jia Wang, Zhuodong Ou, Chenglin Dong, Mengying Su, Amjad Ali, Artem V. Kuklin, Hans &#197;gren, Glib Baryshnikov, Yang Liu, Xue Zhao, Haibo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Computer-Aided Review of Trends in Heterogeneous Catalysis and Its Theoretical Modelling for Engineering Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00219592.2024.2360928</link>
      <description>Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Kaoru Hisama, Michihisa Koyama, JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL ENGINEERING OF JAPAN. 57(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443753

                Writing scientific literature reviews is highly challenging, especially for broad topics like "heterogeneous catalysis" due to the explosion of knowledge. In this article, we introduce a machine-assisted approach aimed to facilitating this process. It integrates an automated summarization of several sources into the conventional method of writing a literature review. Our approach represents an initial trial to compile recent trends in heterogeneous catalysis. We chose the topic of heterogeneous catalysis due to its significance in various industrial processes and its multidisciplinary nature, which makes reviewing it challenging. The review highlights the pursuit of more advanced and complex catalysts to enhance catalytic performance. These advances significantly influence chemical reaction engineering, which combines reaction chemistry and chemical engineering. The trend of developing complex catalysts faces feasibility challenges, underscoring the importance of balancing practicality and potential benefits. In this interplay, the role of atomistic understanding becomes more important as it provides insights into the fundamental mechanisms governing catalyst behavior. Therefore, this review also covers advances in computational studies, particularly density functional theory calculations and the incorporation of new techniques. The wide scope of knowledge presented in this initial trial will facilitate further development in the field of chemical reaction engineering.</description>
      <author>Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Kaoru Hisama, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00219592.2024.2360928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum transport study of transition-metal dichalcogenide top-contacted geometries investigating the impact of nonuniform doping, dielectric environment, and image-force barrier lowering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.22.064058</link>
      <description>Pranay Baikadi, William G. Vandenberghe, Peter D. Reyntjens, Raseong Kim, Maarten L. Van de Put, Physical Review Applied. 22(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405443859

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pranay Baikadi, William G. Vandenberghe, Peter D. Reyntjens, Raseong Kim, Maarten L. Van de Put</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevapplied.22.064058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Properties of Nanoporous Graphenes: Transferability of Graph Machine&#8208;Learned Force Fields Compared to Local and Reactive Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417891</link>
      <description>Adil M. Kabylda, Bohayra Mortazavi, Xiaoying Zhuang, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405456044

                Abstract Nanoporous and chemically&#8208;bridged graphene nanosheets span a wide chemical space with a broad set of applications in sensing and electronics. Modeling the structure and dynamics of such nanosheets is challenging, as chemical bond making and breaking as well as non&#8208;covalent interactions must be captured accurately and on equal footing. Here it is showed that recent graph&#8208;based machine&#8208;learned force field (MLFF) SO3krates [J. T. Frank et al. , Nat. Commun. 15 , 6539 (2024)] is able to reliably model the dynamics and mechanical response for a broad class of nanoporous graphenes when trained on accurate density functional theory data that includes long&#8208;range many&#8208;body dispersion (MBD) interactions. In contrast, local moment tensor potentials and empirical reactive potentials are much less accurate. It is also found that recent MLFFs trained on solid&#8208;state datasets must be used with care, since even empirical potentials occasionally yield more accurate results. These findings highlight the potential of properly&#8208;trained graph MLFFs in modeling the properties of whole chemical spaces of complex functional materials.</description>
      <author>Adil M. Kabylda, Bohayra Mortazavi, Xiaoying Zhuang, Alexandre Tkatchenko</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-Learning-Enabled Thermochemistry Estimator</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00989</link>
      <description>Tianjun Xie, Gerhard R. Wittreich, Matthew T. Curnan, Geun Ho Gu, Kevin Seals, Justin S. Tolbert, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405457459

                Modeling adsorbates on single-crystal metals is critical in rational catalyst design and other research that requires detailed thermochemistry. First-principles simulations via density functional theory (DFT) are among the prevalent tools to acquire such information about surface species. While they are highly dependable, DFT calculations often require intensive computational resources and runtime. These limiting factors become particularly pronounced when investigating large sets of complex molecules on heavy noble metals. Consequently, our ability to explore these species and their corresponding energetics is limited. In this work, we establish a novel framework that utilizes techniques including molecular encoding, descriptor synthesis, and machine learning to overcome the limitation of costly DFT simulations. Simultaneously, we estimate thermochemical information efficiently at the DFT accuracy level. More specifically, we translated our training molecules into text-based identifiers through a simplified molecular-input line-entry system. Following that, we parametrize our training matrices with sets of short-range descriptors based on group methods, applying first the nearest neighbors to account for linear contributions. This is coupled with the long-range descriptors characterizing second nearest neighbors to account for nonlinear corrections. Finally, we use linear regression and machine learning techniques, such as Gaussian process regressions to regress over the linear and nonlinear matrix systems, respectively. This is the first work to our knowledge that encompasses both the first and second nearest neighbors based on the group theory throughout the featurization, training, and deployment stages. We trained and validated our models with 459 surface species on Pt(111), Ru(0001), and Ir(111) surfaces. Results exhibit robust performance to reproduce the energetics of interest, such as enthalpies, entropies, and heat capacities, at various temperatures. Notably, the mean absolute errors can be reduced by 48% during training and 19% during prediction at a minimum, when compared to the classical group method. Leveraging the novel framework, our machine-learning-enabled thermochemistry estimator significantly empowers us to research the thermochemistry of complex species on metal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tianjun Xie, Gerhard R. Wittreich, Matthew T. Curnan, Geun Ho Gu, Kevin Seals, Justin S. Tolbert</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unavoidable Silicon Oxidation&#8212;the Key to Understanding the High Catalytic Activity of Si,N-Doped Carbon Nanotubes in Oxygen Electroreduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s107036322411015x</link>
      <description>Anton V. Kuzmin, Bagrat A. Shainyan, Russian Journal of General Chemistry. 94(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405461357

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anton V. Kuzmin, Bagrat A. Shainyan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s107036322411015x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically precise MOF-Based electrocatalysts by design: Hydrogen evolution applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134021</link>
      <description>Aneeqa Areeb Amjad, Maida Murtaza, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, Iftikhar Ahmad, Hussain Alawadhi, Waqas Ali Shah, Amir Waseem, Fuel. 385(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405463967

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aneeqa Areeb Amjad, Maida Murtaza, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, Iftikhar Ahmad, Hussain Alawadhi, Waqas Ali Shah, Amir Waseem</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Electrochemical Oxidation and Reduction of Nickel Oxide Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13187</link>
      <description>Wenyu Sun, Nitish Govindarajan, Aditya Prajapati, Jiayi Huang, Hossein Bemana, Jeremy T. Feaster, Sneha A. Akhade, Nikolay Kornienko, Christopher Hahn, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405465554

                Surface oxidation/reduction processes, driven by varying electrochemical potentials, can substantially impact catalyst effectiveness and, consequently, electrolyzer performance. This study combines theoretical and experimental approaches to explore the surface redox behavior of nickel oxides, which are cost-effective and efficient catalysts for many electrochemical reactions. Surface Pourbaix diagrams for three different phases of nickel oxides, i.e., nickel hydroxide (Ni(OH)2), nickel oxyhydroxide (NiOOH), and nickel dioxide (NiO2), were constructed using density functional theory-based simulations. Various experimental methods, including cyclic voltammetry, in situ Raman spectroscopy, and electrochemical titration, were employed to probe the surface redox processes of nickel oxide thin films. Our findings indicate that the ABAB stacking sequence of Ni(OH)2 lacks stability under oxidizing conditions to host the surface oxidation (deprotonation) events, while the AABBCC stacking sequence of NiOOH is energetically favorable due to the presence of interlayer hydrogen bonding. Rapid charge transfer facilitated by interlayer hydrogen bonding accounts for the higher reactivity of partially oxidized/reduced NiOOH (001) surfaces compared to Ni(OH)2 (001) and NiO2 (001) surfaces with the same stoichiometry, where interlayer hydrogen bonding is absent. Insights presented in this work can offer guidelines for optimizing operational conditions and tailoring the surface structures and oxidation states of nickel oxides to enhance performance in applications such as electrocatalysis and supercapacitors.</description>
      <author>Wenyu Sun, Nitish Govindarajan, Aditya Prajapati, Jiayi Huang, Hossein Bemana, Jeremy T. Feaster, Sneha A. Akhade, Nikolay Kornienko, Christopher Hahn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Poisoning of CN&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07363</link>
      <description>A. S. RAO, Vance Gustin, Jonathan Hightower, Seval G&#252;nd&#252;z, Dishari Basu, Yehia Khalifa, Anant Sohale, Anne C. Co, Aravind Asthagiri, Umit S. Ozkan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405474872

                CNx catalysts show promising activity and stability for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) under acidic conditions, but the nature of the active site is still under debate. ORR on CNx has been found to be resistant to common poisons such as CO, H2S, and CN. In this study, we demonstrate that bubbling CO2 in the electrolyte can lead to the partial poisoning of CNx for ORR activity. Cyclic voltammetry (CV) experiments show a partial decrease in the ORR activity for CNx catalysts after bubbling CO2 through a 0.1 M HClO4 electrolyte. The relative stability of CO2-derived species (CO2*, H2CO3*, HCO3*, and CO3*) on 13 CNx site models at 1.0 V-RHE was examined using density functional theory (DFT). The calculations predict that HCO3 is favored adjacent to the N species on several CNx site models and CO3 is favored on pyrrolic sites. Difference spectra of the N 1s from near-ambient pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (NAP-XPS) of the ex-situ poisoned CNx and pristine CNx shows a shift in binding energies of N species that qualitatively match the DFT N 1s binding energy shifts due to HCO3/CO3 on the CNx site models. DFT predicts that these HCO3 surface species can block and delay the initial step of the ORR on several CNx sites.</description>
      <author>A. S. RAO, Vance Gustin, Jonathan Hightower, Seval G&#252;nd&#252;z, Dishari Basu, Yehia Khalifa, Anant Sohale, Anne C. Co, Aravind Asthagiri, Umit S. Ozkan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Synergistic Role of Sm&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;3+&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Doped NiFe&#8208;LDH as High&#8208;Performance Electrocatalysts for Improved Anion Exchange Membrane and Water Splitting Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401655</link>
      <description>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Hemalatha Gurusamy, Harpriya Minhas, Arun Karmakar, S. Ravichandran, Biswarup Pathak, Subrata Kundu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476280

                Abstract Effective first&#8208;row transition metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts are crucial for large&#8208;scale hydrogen energy generation and anion exchange membrane (AEM) devices in water splitting. The present work describes that SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH nanosheets on nickel foam are used as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting and AEM water electrolyzer study. Tuning the Ni&#8208;to&#8208;Fe ratios in NiFe&#8208;LDH and doping with Sm ions improves the electrical structure and intrinsic activity. SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH has higher oxygen evolution reaction (OER), HER, and TWS activity, achieving 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 current density at lower overpotentials (230 mV, 95 mV, and 1.62 V, respectively). In AEMWE cells, SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH as a cathode and anode pair exhibits outstanding activity (0.9 A cm&#8315; 2 at 2 V) and stability over 120 h. Density Functional Theory (DFT) investigations reveal that the Sm doping in NiFe&#8208;LDH surface enhances its bifunctional activity toward OER and HER. These findings emphasize the potential of non&#8208;noble composites for long&#8208;term water electrolysis in total water splitting and AEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Hemalatha Gurusamy, Harpriya Minhas, Arun Karmakar, S. Ravichandran, Biswarup Pathak, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Design and Synthesis of Metal&#8211;Inorganic Frameworks Using Host Atom&#8208;Centered Building Blocks for Efficient Catalysis with Diverse Reactive Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418750</link>
      <description>Chao He, Xingxing Dong, Junqiu Zhang, Shao-Gang Xu, Xiang Huang, Hui Wang, Changchun He, Xiaowei Liang, Maohai Xie, Hu Xu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476300

                Abstract The modular assembly of organic molecules commonly guides the design of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), yet the systematic exploration of inorganic building blocks remains limited. Given the promising applications in catalytic reactions and topological materials, the study of metal&#8211;inorganic frameworks (MIFs)&#8212;which fundamentally differ from the well&#8208;established MOFs&#8212;has become urgent. This study introduces a strategy for designing MIFs using host atom&#8208;centered building blocks, applied to the platinum&#8211;Phosphorus (Pt&#8211;P) system. By combining experimental observations with theoretical calculations, a Pt 18 P 18 framework utilizing PtP 3 building blocks, demonstrating significant energetic benefits is proposed. PtP 3 units are employed to characterize Pt 3 P 6 clusters within the pores, leading to a &#8220;compass&#8221; model that aligns with experimental findings. To address computational challenges associated with the large periodicity of the superstructure, a robust machine learning force field is developed. The analysis, combining surface nucleation studies, first&#8208;principles calculations, and machine learning techniques, provides a comprehensive understanding of MIF structure. This validated Pt&#8211;P MIF exhibits exceptional catalytic properties with diverse reaction sites, significantly outperforming Pt(111) in the hydrogen evolution reaction. The findings not only present additional candidates for practical applications of metal phosphides but also highlight the vast potential of MIFs, paving the way for the discovery of numerous promising materials.</description>
      <author>Chao He, Xingxing Dong, Junqiu Zhang, Shao-Gang Xu, Xiang Huang, Hui Wang, Changchun He, Xiaowei Liang, Maohai Xie, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart Compositional Design of B&#8208;Site Ordered Double Perovskite for Advanced Oxygen Catalysis at Ultra&#8208;High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401480</link>
      <description>Maria Christy, Jiseok Kwon, S. Subramanian, Seunggun Choi, Junghyun Choi, Jung Ho Kim, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476385

                Abstract Perovskite oxides have been considered promising oxygen catalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER), owing to structural and compositional flexibility, and tailorable properties. Ingenious B&#8208;site ordered La 1.5 Sr 0.5 NiMn 0.5 Fe 0.5 O 6 (LSNMF) double perovskite is strategically designed by simultaneously interposing Ni 0.5 Mn 0.5 and Ni 0.5 Fe 0.5 into B&#8242; and B&#8243; sites. Controlling B&#8208;site cation systematically tailors the electronic structure of the B&#8208;site cation with a d&#8208;band center (M d ) upshift close to the Fermi level, increasing the overlap of the M d center and O 2p center (O P ). The strong interaction of M d and O p facilitates the adsorption of oxygen and activates the lattice oxygen to participate in the OER process, thereby enhancing the ORR and OER activity. For ORR, LSNMF exhibited an onset potential of 0.9 V along with a high limiting current of &#8722;8.05 mA cm &#8722;2 . At the same time, for OER at 1 m KOH, LSNMF effectively reached a maximum current density of 3000 mA cm &#8722;2 . Most importantly, the difference between E ORR (at &#8722;1 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and E OER (at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), &#916;E is 0.69 V, which stands among the best of recently reported perovskites. The as&#8208;designed LSNMF is stable, efficient, lucrative, and a promising candidate for practical application.</description>
      <author>Maria Christy, Jiseok Kwon, S. Subramanian, Seunggun Choi, Junghyun Choi, Jung Ho Kim, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture through Aqueous Carbonation Using Green Liquor Dregs as the Absorbent</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.4c00373</link>
      <description>Eduarda C. Queiroz, Emmanouela Leventaki, Christian Kugge, Diana Bernin, ACS Sustainable Resource Management. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405483958

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eduarda C. Queiroz, Emmanouela Leventaki, Christian Kugge, Diana Bernin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.4c00373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of microstructure and electrochemical corrosion tendency of the Al/CeO2 interface in the 7075-CeO2 aluminum matrix composites: experiments and calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178154</link>
      <description>Ying Ling, Xiuliang Zou, Wenjie Hu, Qiang Hu, Hong Yan, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405492515

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Ling, Xiuliang Zou, Wenjie Hu, Qiang Hu, Hong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of single atom electrocatalysts of polyoxotantalate-supported transition-metals for efficient water-splitting and oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115044</link>
      <description>Faheem Abbas, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Zonish Zeb, Zheyu Wei, Sumaira Nazar Hussain, Yichao Huang, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Yongge Wei, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405494463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faheem Abbas, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Zonish Zeb, Zheyu Wei, Sumaira Nazar Hussain, Yichao Huang, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Yongge Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Description of ions properties using molecular orbital energy levels: Trends in interaction with model electrodes and solvents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145541</link>
      <description>Sergey V. Doronin, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405495156

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sergey V. Doronin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial hydrogen bonds induced by porous Fe Cr bimetallic atomic sites for efficient oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.119</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Qing Zhang, Lin Yang, Chuangang Hu, Zhengyu Bai, Zhongwei Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405495386

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Qing Zhang, Lin Yang, Chuangang Hu, Zhengyu Bai, Zhongwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; characterization techniques: main tools for revealing OER/ORR catalytic mechanism and reaction dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02179g</link>
      <description>Siqi Wu, Zexin Liang, Tianshi Wang, Xiaobin Liu, Shaobo Huang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405498245

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are some of the most important reactions in electrochemical energy technologies such as fuel cells and metal&#8211;air cells.</description>
      <author>Siqi Wu, Zexin Liang, Tianshi Wang, Xiaobin Liu, Shaobo Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02179g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-Efficient Multifidelity Training for High-Fidelity Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14455</link>
      <description>Jaesun Kim, Jisu Kim, Jaehoon Kim, Jiho Lee, Yutack Park, Youngho Kang, Seungwu Han, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405499204

                Machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) are used to estimate potential energy surfaces (PES) from</description>
      <author>Jaesun Kim, Jisu Kim, Jaehoon Kim, Jiho Lee, Yutack Park, Youngho Kang, Seungwu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14455</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance by Anchoring Iridium Oxide Nanoparticles on Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18974</link>
      <description>Gege Tao, Zhi-Qiang Wang, Xiaohui Liu, Yanqin Wang, Yong Guo, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405508149

                The sluggish kinetics of the anodic process, known as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), has posed a significant challenge for the practical application of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers in industrial settings. This study introduces a high-performance OER catalyst by anchoring iridium oxide nanoparticles (IrO</description>
      <author>Gege Tao, Zhi-Qiang Wang, Xiaohui Liu, Yanqin Wang, Yong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface reconstruction of copper(&#8544;) sulfide electrode regulated electroreduction CO2 selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162139</link>
      <description>Qin Ding, Jianhua Lin, Xiaoyu Li, Dongli Yu, Yiwang Bao, Huazhong Liang, Quan Zhuang, Jinghai Liu, Yin Wang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405516245

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qin Ding, Jianhua Lin, Xiaoyu Li, Dongli Yu, Yiwang Bao, Huazhong Liang, Quan Zhuang, Jinghai Liu, Yin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum-based catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction simulated with a quantum computer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01460-x</link>
      <description>Cono Di Paola, Evgeny Plekhanov, Micha&#322; Krompiec, Chandan Kumar, Emanuele Marsili, Fengmin Du, Daniel Weber, J. Krauser, Elvira Shishenina, David Mu&#241;oz Ramo, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405528122

                Hydrogen has emerged as a promising energy source for low-carbon and sustainable mobility purposes. However, its applications are still limited by modest conversion efficiency in the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) within fuel cells. The complex nature of the ORR and the presence of strong electronic correlations present challenges to atomistic modelling using classical computers. This scenario opens new avenues for the implementation of novel quantum computing workflows. Here, we present a state-of-the-art study that combines classical and quantum computational approaches to investigate ORR on platinum-based surfaces. Our research demonstrates, for the first time, the feasibility of implementing this workflow on the H1-series trapped-ion quantum computer and identify the challenges of the quantum chemistry modelling of this reaction. The results highlight the great potentiality of quantum computers in solving notoriously difficult systems with strongly correlated electronic structures and suggest platinum/cobalt as ideal candidate for showcasing quantum advantage in future applications.</description>
      <author>Cono Di Paola, Evgeny Plekhanov, Micha&#322; Krompiec, Chandan Kumar, Emanuele Marsili, Fengmin Du, Daniel Weber, J. Krauser, Elvira Shishenina, David Mu&#241;oz Ramo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01460-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizational and Mechanistic Modulation of ORR/OER Activity in M&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;N&#8211;C Bimetallic Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06280</link>
      <description>Xinge Wu, Zhaoying Yang, Decheng Li, Shuai Shao, Gaowu Qin, Xiangying Meng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405529735

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinge Wu, Zhaoying Yang, Decheng Li, Shuai Shao, Gaowu Qin, Xiangying Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of point defect properties near surfaces in metal halide perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.125402</link>
      <description>Bilal Ahmad, Md Salman Rabbi Limon, Zeeshan Ahmad, Physical Review Materials. 8(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405533719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bilal Ahmad, Md Salman Rabbi Limon, Zeeshan Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.125402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The V30 benchmark set for anharmonic vibrational frequencies of molecular dimers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0238491</link>
      <description>Johannes Hoja, A. Daniel Boese, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405541010

                Intermolecular vibrations are extremely challenging to describe but are the most crucial part for determining entropy and hence free energies and enable, for instance, the distinction between different crystal-packing arrangements of the same molecule via THz spectroscopy. Herein, we introduce a benchmark dataset&#8212;V30&#8212;containing 30 small molecular dimers with intermolecular interactions ranging from exclusively van der Waals dispersion to systems with hydrogen bonds. All the calculations are performed with the gold standard of quantum chemistry CCSD(T). We discuss vibrational frequencies obtained via different models starting with the harmonic approximation over independent Morse oscillators up to second-order vibrational perturbation theory (VPT2), which allows a proper anharmonic treatment including coupling of vibrational modes. However, large amplitude motions present in many low-frequency intermolecular modes are problematic for VPT2. In analogy to the often used treatment for internal rotations, we replace such problematic modes by a simple one-dimensional hindered rotor model. We compare selected dimers to the available experimental data or high-level calculations of potential energy surfaces and show that VPT2 in combination with hindered rotors can yield a very good description of fundamental frequencies for the discussed subset of dimers involving small and semi-rigid molecules.</description>
      <author>Johannes Hoja, A. Daniel Boese</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0238491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NMR Investigations of Host&#8211;Guest Interactions in MOFs and COFs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781839167287-00153</link>
      <description>Shoushun Chen, Xin Du, Yuzhen Liu, Jun Xu, Xingguo Han, Bryan E. G. Lucier, Yining Huang, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405551205

                Host&#8211;guest interactions in porous metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) and covalent-organic frameworks (COFs) play a key role in enhancing the performance of these materials for practical applications; however, it is often very challenging to investigate these interactions at the molecular level. In recent years, many solid-state NMR (SSNMR) approaches, including in situ variable temperature (VT), 2D correlation, and pulsed field gradient (PFG) experiments, have offered unique insights into the local structure and dynamics of adsorbed guest molecules in MOFs and COFs. Recent SSNMR studies of MOFs and COFs containing guest molecules are summarized in this chapter. These reports encompass a variety of gaseous and liquid guests such as hydrogen, carbon dioxide, water, and methanol. We also highlight studies involving larger guest molecules, drugs, and biomolecules. It is apparent that SSNMR spectroscopy can provide a wealth of data pertaining to host&#8211;guest interactions in these materials; the information available commonly includes the number and location of guest adsorption sites, guest binding strengths, guest dynamics and diffusion rates, and guest-induced structural changes in the host. The studies discussed in this chapter illustrate how SSNMR spectroscopy serves as a powerful tool to probe host&#8211;guest interactions in MOFs/COFs, especially given the variety of potential target nuclei and the numerous experimental strategies that are available.</description>
      <author>Shoushun Chen, Xin Du, Yuzhen Liu, Jun Xu, Xingguo Han, Bryan E. G. Lucier, Yining Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781839167287-00153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction on graphdiyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.169</link>
      <description>Lei Qin, Shitao Wang, Ju Rong, Yan Wei, Xiaohua Yu, Yudong Sui, Yongqiang Yang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 99(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405555100

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Qin, Shitao Wang, Ju Rong, Yan Wei, Xiaohua Yu, Yudong Sui, Yongqiang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Enhanced ORR Activity of FeN4-Embedded Graphene Through Interface Interactions with Metal Substrates: Electronic vs. Geometric Descriptors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101633</link>
      <description>Silu Li, Donghai Wu, Lulu Gao, Jiahang Li, Gang Tang, Zaiping Zeng, Dongwei Ma, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405565286

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silu Li, Donghai Wu, Lulu Gao, Jiahang Li, Gang Tang, Zaiping Zeng, Dongwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101633</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical interface modelling for electrocatalytic materials design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101638</link>
      <description>Lucas G. Verga, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Aron Walsh, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405585850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lucas G. Verga, Seung&#8208;Jae Shin, Aron Walsh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed iron &amp;amp; iron clusters synergistically accelerate electrocatalytic ammonia synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158785</link>
      <description>Haoran Zhang, Yuelong Liu, Sanshuang Gao, Haijian Wang, Rui Bai, Yan Zhao, Yingtang Zhou, Guangzhi Hu, Xue Zhao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405586089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoran Zhang, Yuelong Liu, Sanshuang Gao, Haijian Wang, Rui Bai, Yan Zhao, Yingtang Zhou, Guangzhi Hu, Xue Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Time Scale Molecular Dynamics Simulation of Magnesium Hydride Dehydrogenation Enabled by Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02627</link>
      <description>Oliver Morrison, Elena Uteva, Gavin S. Walker, David M. Grant, Sanliang Ling, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405591634

                Magnesium hydride (MgH2) is a promising material for solid-state hydrogen storage due to its high gravimetric hydrogen capacity as well as the abundance and low cost of magnesium. The material's limiting factor is the high dehydrogenation temperature (over 300 &#176;C) and sluggish (de)hydrogenation kinetics when no catalyst is present, making it impractical for onboard applications. Catalysts and physical restructuring (e.g., through ball milling) have both shown kinetic improvements, without full theoretical understanding as to why. In this work, we developed a machine learning interatomic potential (MLP) for the Mg&#8211;H system, which was used to run long time scale molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of a thick magnesium hydride surface slab for up to 1 ns. Our MLP-based MD simulations reveal previously unreported behavior of subsurface molecular H2 formation and subsequent trapping in the subsurface layer of MgH2. This hindered diffusion of subsurface H2 offers a partial explanation on the slow dehydrogenation kinetics of MgH2. The kinetics will be improved if a catalyst obstructs subsurface formation and trapping of H2 or if the diffusion of subsurface H2 is improved through defects created by physical restructuring.</description>
      <author>Oliver Morrison, Elena Uteva, Gavin S. Walker, David M. Grant, Sanliang Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding the Role of Adsorbates Entropy in the Reactivity of Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04472</link>
      <description>Elena Simone, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405592086

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) are rapidly gaining attention as a versatile class of materials that combine the advantages of both homogeneous and heterogeneous catalysis. A growing number of studies aim to identify potential new SACs or to describe their structure and reactivity through ab initio quantum chemical simulations. While many computational studies primarily address reactions involving small molecules, such as water splitting or CO2 reduction, the application scope of SACs is rapidly broadening to include the production of fine chemicals and the conversion of biomass-derived platform molecules, processes that involve larger, more complex reactants. Using density-functional theory (DFT) simulations, we demonstrate that, while an approximate treatment of entropy is acceptable for molecules with up to three atoms, it introduces substantial errors in reactions involving more complex molecules. Our results reveal a linear correlation between the entropy of adsorbed molecules and that of the corresponding isolated species, mirroring trends observed on extended catalytic surfaces. For the largest systems investigated in this study, the entropy of the free molecule is reduced by approximately 10&#8211;20% upon adsorption; for small molecules, this reduction can range from 50 to 70%. This disparity arises because, on SACs, the translational entropy is effectively zero, the rotational entropy is minimal, and the vibrational entropy increases with the size of the molecule. Moreover, the entropy of adsorbates scales linearly with the number of atoms in the molecule, allowing for the prediction of entropic contributions of adsorbates on SACs without additional computational cost. Using propyne hydrogenation as a test, we demonstrate that the reaction energy profile computed with current approximate approaches for estimating the entropy of adsorbates differs significantly from the profile where entropy is explicitly included. These findings highlight the importance of considering adsorbate entropy for accurately predicting the catalytic activity of SACs, particularly for reactions involving complex molecules.</description>
      <author>Elena Simone, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Co 3d/O 2p Orbital Hybridization in LaCoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; by Modulating the Co&#8211;O&#8211;Co Bond Angle for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05479</link>
      <description>Baoxin Ge, Pengyang Jiang, Biyi Chen, Caijin Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405601758

                The orbital hybridization between metal and oxygen of perovskite catalysts can lower the overpotential and enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. This study combines density functional theory with experiments to clarify how Sr/Fe codoping modulates orbital hybridization and enhances OER catalytic activity of LaCoO3. The as-prepared La0.50Sr0.50Co0.75Fe0.25O3 shows remarkable performance with a low overpotential of 310 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 current density and a 107.03 mV dec&#8211;1 Tafel slope, outperforming most state-of-the-art perovskite-based OER electrocatalysts. The experimental results confirm that Sr/Fe codoping enhances the expansion of Co&#8211;O&#8211;Co bond angles and strengthens the covalency of the Co&#8211;O bond in LaCoO3, leading to enhanced electrocatalytic activity. Moreover, increasing Sr doping reduces the distance between the Co 3d/O 2p center and the Fermi level, decreasing the energy difference between them and enhancing the degree of orbital hybridization between Co 3d and O 2p. As the degree of Co 3d/O 2p orbital hybridization increases, a higher charge transfer was found between the active center and intermediate product, OOH, reducing the energy barrier of the rate-determining step while lowering the overpotential. This study provides thorough insight into the rational design of OER catalysts based on orbital hybridization.</description>
      <author>Baoxin Ge, Pengyang Jiang, Biyi Chen, Caijin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultivating superior CO2 reduction performance via rationally engineered nitrogen-phosphorus co-doped graphene catalysts: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111895</link>
      <description>Ismail Shahid, Ruixin Zhang, Xiaoliang Zhang, Dawei Tang, Vineet Tirth, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405611556

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ismail Shahid, Ruixin Zhang, Xiaoliang Zhang, Dawei Tang, Vineet Tirth</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally Stimulated Spin Switching Accelerates Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.133.258001</link>
      <description>Mengfei Lu, Yu Du, Shicheng Yan, Tao Yu, Zhigang Zou, Physical Review Letters. 133(25)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405614811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengfei Lu, Yu Du, Shicheng Yan, Tao Yu, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.133.258001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Catalysts: Are You Really Single?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02844</link>
      <description>Ana S. Dobrota, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405615794

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted the attention of the scientific community due to a number of attractive properties allowing their application in different catalytic processes, including electrochemical ones. Due to the nature of the active site, consisting of only a few atoms, SACs are also very attractive for theoretical modeling as the active site can be directly translated into the computational model. However, as a rule, the possibility of the active site change induced by pH and electrode potential is disregarded in theoretical models. This Perspective emphasizes the need to address the actual state of SA electrocatalysts under operating conditions before considering their catalytic activity and selectivity. The concept of surface Pourbaix plot, well-known in electrochemistry, can be directly transferred to SACs, providing valuable insights and guidance for developing novel catalytic materials. We discuss recent approaches to designing Pourbaix plots for SACs and outline the importance of properly treating the actual state of SACs and other emerging types of catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ana S. Dobrota, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculation of Adsorbate Free Energy Using the Damping Function Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01079</link>
      <description>Yanhua Lei, Lei Liu, Erjun Zhang, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405615873

                Adsorbate free energies are important parameters in surface chemistry and catalysis. Because of its simplicity, the harmonic oscillator (HO) model remains the most widely used method for calculating adsorbate free energy in many fields, including microkinetic modeling. However, it is well-known that the HO method is ineffective for weak adsorption. In this study, we propose a translational model with a diffusion barrier to calculate the state functions of near free translation. Furthermore, an effective mass is introduced in this model. To address hindered translation uniformly, a diffusion barrier-based damping function (DF) is proposed that effectively links the harmonic vibration and translation limits. Adsorbates are divided into three categories according to their adsorption strength and diffusion barrier height. Adsorbed hydrogen atoms have a strong binding energy and relatively high vibrational frequency but a low diffusion barrier. The HT and our proposed DF methods predict that the adsorbed hydrogen atoms behave as translation above room temperature, while the previous DF method predicts that they behave as vibration at any temperature. At last, the dehydrogenation reaction of propane on the Pt(111) surface was taken as an example to illustrate the influence of different methods on the thermodynamic functions.</description>
      <author>Yanhua Lei, Lei Liu, Erjun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Library of Seed@High&#8208;Entropy&#8208;Alloy Core&#8211;shell Nanocrystals With Controlled Facets for Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411464</link>
      <description>Yueh&#8208;Chun Hsiao, Cheng&#8208;Yu Wu, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Wen&#8208;Yang Huang, Ho Viet Thang, Chong&#8208;Chi Chi, Wen&#8208;Jing Zeng, Jiaqi Gao, Chih&#8208;Yi Lin, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Adrian M. Gardner, Hansaem Jang, R.-C. Juang, Y.-C. Liu, Islam M. A. Mekhemer, Ming&#8208;Yen Lu, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ho&#8208;Hsiu Chou, Chun&#8208;Hong Kuo, Shan Zhou, Liang&#8208;Ching Hsu, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Alexander J. Cowan, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Jien&#8208;Wei Yeh, Tung&#8208;Han Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405616791

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy&#8208;alloy (HEA) nanocrystals hold immense potential for catalysis, offering virtually unlimited alloy combinations through the inclusion of at least five constituent elements in varying ratios. However, general and effective strategies for synthesizing libraries of HEA nanocrystals with controlled surface atomic structures remain scarce. In this study, a transferable strategy for developing a library of facet&#8208;controlled seed@HEA nanocrystals through seed&#8208;mediated growth is presented. The synthesis of seed@HEA core&#8211;shell nanocrystals incorporating up to ten different metallic elements, with control over the number of solid&#8208;solution HEA atomic layers is demonstrated. Epitaxial HEA growth on nanocrystal seeds with low&#8208;index and high&#8208;index facets leads to the formation of seed@HEA catalyst library with composition&#8208; and facet&#8208;dependent catalytic activities in both electrocatalysis and photocatalysis. In situ synchrotron X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy and density&#8208;functional theory calculations are employed to identify surface active sites of the HEA, rationalizing the high level of catalytic activities achieved. This work enables facet engineering in the multi&#8208;elemental chemical space and unveils the critical needs for their future development toward catalysis.</description>
      <author>Yueh&#8208;Chun Hsiao, Cheng&#8208;Yu Wu, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Wen&#8208;Yang Huang, Ho Viet Thang, Chong&#8208;Chi Chi, Wen&#8208;Jing Zeng, Jiaqi Gao, Chih&#8208;Yi Lin, Jui&#8208;Tai Lin, Adrian M. Gardner, Hansaem Jang, R.-C. Juang, Y.-C. Liu, Islam M. A. Mekhemer, Ming&#8208;Yen Lu, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ho&#8208;Hsiu Chou, Chun&#8208;Hong Kuo, Shan Zhou, Liang&#8208;Ching Hsu, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Alexander J. Cowan, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Jien&#8208;Wei Yeh, Tung&#8208;Han Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally stimulated chirp in a pulsed QCL: Microscopic origins behind Fabry-Perot pattern drift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2024.109618</link>
      <description>Evgeniia D. Cherotchenko, Ivan I. Vrubel, Alexander A. Pavlov, Anna S. Konanykhina, Ilya E. Rafailov, Roman G. Polozkov, V. V. Dudelev, G. S. Sokolovski&#301;, International Journal of Thermal Sciences. 210(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405632163

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Evgeniia D. Cherotchenko, Ivan I. Vrubel, Alexander A. Pavlov, Anna S. Konanykhina, Ilya E. Rafailov, Roman G. Polozkov, V. V. Dudelev, G. S. Sokolovski&#301;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2024.109618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e232" altimg="si37.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;X&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; reduction mechanism: Thermal vs electrochemical step</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145429</link>
      <description>Mohd Riyaz, Alexander Bagger, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405632928

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohd Riyaz, Alexander Bagger</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali metal cations act as homogeneous cocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction in aqueous electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01241-1</link>
      <description>Sang Gu Ji, Minho M. Kim, Man Ho Han, Junsic Cho, Yoosang Son, Young Yong Kim, Jaeyoung Jeong, Zee Hwan Kim, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, Nature Catalysis. 7(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405636810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sang Gu Ji, Minho M. Kim, Man Ho Han, Junsic Cho, Yoosang Son, Young Yong Kim, Jaeyoung Jeong, Zee Hwan Kim, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01241-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of the DES-contained reduced graphene oxide system with efficient CO2 adsorption and photothermal desorption for pre-gas purification in AEMFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131193</link>
      <description>Yifan Li, Xianglin Kong, Dahai Zhu, Tianwen Guo, Xinfeng Wu, Wei Yu, Jinpeng Wang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405529564

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Li, Xianglin Kong, Dahai Zhu, Tianwen Guo, Xinfeng Wu, Wei Yu, Jinpeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131193</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
