<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 01:41:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into electrocatalysis through in situ electrochemical surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100352</link>
      <description>Xiu&#8208;Mei Lin, Yulin Sun, Yanxin Chen, Shunxing Li, Jianfeng Li, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405135126

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiu&#8208;Mei Lin, Yulin Sun, Yanxin Chen, Shunxing Li, Jianfeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-0274-2_1</link>
      <description>Lunbo Duan, Dennis Lu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405143171

                Abstract Climate change is currently one of the most challenging issues to the global ecosystem, which has already caused serious consequences in many aspects, such as increasing wildfires, heat waves, drought, and ice sheet disintegration.</description>
      <author>Lunbo Duan, Dennis Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-0274-2_1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Metal&#8211;Support Interaction on the Structure and Activity of Carbon-Supported Ni Nanoparticle Catalysts for Alkaline Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15120</link>
      <description>Yoshiki Akamine, Fumiya Nishino, Takashi Yamashita, Masayuki Tsushida, Keisuke Awaya, Masato Machida, Syeda Mushrifa Zahan, Dario R. Dekel, Junya Ohyama, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405161821

                The effect of the carbon support&#9472;Ketjenblack (C</description>
      <author>Yoshiki Akamine, Fumiya Nishino, Takashi Yamashita, Masayuki Tsushida, Keisuke Awaya, Masato Machida, Syeda Mushrifa Zahan, Dario R. Dekel, Junya Ohyama</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the role of intrinsic defects in N/S Co-Doped hard carbon for superior sodium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158441</link>
      <description>Yunlei Yang, Chang Liu, Junjun Yao, Zhiyuan Tang, Ying Sun, Kun Zhang, Hui Li, Tianyi Ma, Jieshan Qiu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405172919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunlei Yang, Chang Liu, Junjun Yao, Zhiyuan Tang, Ying Sun, Kun Zhang, Hui Li, Tianyi Ma, Jieshan Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles investigation of hydrogen evolution reaction on doped 2D transition metal sulfides in mackinawite structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.014</link>
      <description>Thillai Govindaraja Senthamaraikannan, Dong&#8208;Hee Lim, Young-Soo Han, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 97(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405173856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thillai Govindaraja Senthamaraikannan, Dong&#8208;Hee Lim, Young-Soo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reduction of CO2 on pure and doped Cu2O(1 1 1)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.056</link>
      <description>H. Y. Liu, Lei Zhu, Zhichao Yu, Haoyun Bai, Hui Pan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405175780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Y. Liu, Lei Zhu, Zhichao Yu, Haoyun Bai, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilization of Novel (KNbO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;1&#8722;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;(Ba&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;FeNbO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; (&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; = 0.1, 0.2, 0.3) Solid Solutions for Efficient Photo&#8208;Assisted Fenton Degradation of Methylene Blue Dye</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400246</link>
      <description>Celal Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Peter Kraus, Suna Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Julian T. M&#252;ller, Aleksander Gurlo, Maged F. Bekheet, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405180780

                Novel (KNbO 3 ) 1&#8722; x (Ba 2 FeNbO 6 ) x ( x = 0.1, 0.2, 0.3) solid solutions corresponding to K 0.82 Ba 0.18 Fe 0.09 Nb 0.91 O 3 , K 0.64 Ba 0.36 Fe 0.18 Nb 0.82 O 3 , and K 0.46 Ba 0.54 Fe 0.27 Nb 0.73 O 3 compounds have been synthesized via molten salt method. X&#8208;ray diffraction confirms the formation of solid solutions, while transmission electron microscopy combined with energy&#8208;dispersive spectroscopy results demonstrates a homogeneous distribution of elements. The obtained solid solutions crystallized in a cubic crystal structure, whereas the parent KNbO 3 possesses an orthorhombic structure. The wide bandgap semiconductor KNbO 3 transformed into a visible&#8208;light&#8208;active material, with its bandgap energy reduced from 3.56 eV to &#8776;2.4 eV. The substitution of K in KNbO 3 with Ba is responsible for structural modification from orthorhombic to cubic symmetry, whereas both structural modification and the substitution of Nb with Fe correlated with optical properties. The photocatalytic activities of all obtained solid solutions are improved compared with the parent KNbO 3 and Ba 2 FeNbO 6 compounds for photocatalytic degradation of methylene blue (MB) dye. Among the series of solid solutions, K 0.82 Ba 0.18 Fe 0.09 Nb 0.91 O 3 photocatalysts show the highest MB removal efficiency owing to its relatively higher surface area, suppressed charge carrier recombination, and more negative conduction band edge. Moreover, K 0.82 Ba 0.18 Fe 0.09 Nb 0.91 O 3 photocatalyst (0.1 g) combined with hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) to form a novel photo&#8208;Fenton system, achieving almost complete degradation of 100 mL of 10 mg L &#8722;1 MB dye in 30 min.</description>
      <author>Celal Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Peter Kraus, Suna Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Julian T. M&#252;ller, Aleksander Gurlo, Maged F. Bekheet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating electronic structure of CoS2 nanorods by Fe doping for efficient electrocatalytic overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110564</link>
      <description>Qiang Shi, Zhiyong Li, Siqi He, Hu Zhou, Yu Zhang, Xia Cao, Aihua Yuan, Jian&#8208;Ping Zou, Jianchun Wu, Yanxin Qiao, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405183473

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Shi, Zhiyong Li, Siqi He, Hu Zhou, Yu Zhang, Xia Cao, Aihua Yuan, Jian&#8208;Ping Zou, Jianchun Wu, Yanxin Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic mechanism for the enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction activity of Cu alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120644</link>
      <description>Ruoyu Wu, Xiongjun Liu, Zhibin Li, S L Li, Huihui Zhu, Haonan Zhong, Hui Wan, Yuan Wu, Suihe Jiang, Shouxin Zhang, Xianzhen Wang, Zhaoping Lu, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405183687

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruoyu Wu, Xiongjun Liu, Zhibin Li, S L Li, Huihui Zhu, Haonan Zhong, Hui Wan, Yuan Wu, Suihe Jiang, Shouxin Zhang, Xianzhen Wang, Zhaoping Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core@Shell Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co@Pt/C Nanoparticles as an Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05129</link>
      <description>Junfang Cheng, Hao Chen, Enping Wang, Huimin Wang, Zehao Tan, Yan Cheng, Yongjian Su, Xinyi Li, Aiming Wu, Yangge Guo, Guanghua Wei, Junliang Zhang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405187954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfang Cheng, Hao Chen, Enping Wang, Huimin Wang, Zehao Tan, Yan Cheng, Yongjian Su, Xinyi Li, Aiming Wu, Yangge Guo, Guanghua Wei, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Sensitivity of Pourbaix Diagrams to Computational Protocols: Electrochemical Stability of Ni Oxides as a Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06788</link>
      <description>Wenyu Sun, Nitish Govindarajan, Aditya Prajapati, Jeremy T. Feaster, Christopher Hahn, Sneha A. Akhade, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405189245

                Pourbaix diagrams stand as a useful tool in assessing and visualizing materials' electrochemical stability and are widely used for electrocatalyst design. However, their reliability hinges on the accuracy of the chemical potentials of involved phases, which may bear uncertainties and can be significantly impacted by decision-making steps in the computational protocol. This study introduces a robust sensitivity analysis framework, exemplified through a detailed examination of the computational Pourbaix diagram of Ni, the oxides of which are used as high-activity and cost-friendly catalysts for many electrochemical reactions. Quantities of interest derived from the Pourbaix diagram include the appearance and stability domain of the catalytically active Ni oxide phases along with the onset electrochemical potentials of phase transitions. These metrics can guide the design of operational conditions for Ni oxide electrocatalysts. We find that the employed DFT exchange-correlation functional has the most significant influence on the computed Pourbaix diagram. Uncertainties on crystal structures, along with their related ab initio energetics, are also found to affect the size of the phase stability domain. Higher-order coupling among input parameters is found to play a crucial role in influencing the appearance and distribution of Ni phases in the diagram. Our findings suggest a need to consider variations and uncertainties associated with the computational procedures on predicted Pourbaix diagrams for materials design.</description>
      <author>Wenyu Sun, Nitish Govindarajan, Aditya Prajapati, Jeremy T. Feaster, Christopher Hahn, Sneha A. Akhade</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements and Challenges in Electrode and Electrolyte Materials for Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/er/9529659</link>
      <description>Konlayutt Punyawudho, Mariyappan Raja Pugalenthi, Xiong Shu, Satoshi Kaneco, Tanakorn Wongwuttanasatian, Amnart Suksri, Laksamee Payattikul, International Journal of Energy Research. 2024(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405195150

                Proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) technology is vital for a cleaner and more sustainable future, offering high efficiency, quiet operation, fuel flexibility, and zero&#8208;emission energy production with versatile applications. The drawbacks of PEMFC include its high cost, susceptibility to degradation, and challenges in scaling up production for commercial use. The gas diffusion layer (GDL), the catalyst layer (CL), and the polymer electrolyte are all very important parts of fuel cell technology. Through the optimization of these components, researchers may strive to develop fuel cells that are more efficient, cost&#8208;effective, durable, and high&#8208;performing, therefore enabling the provision of clean and sustainable energy. In this article, we have reviewed the various components of GDL, CL, and polymer electrolyte materials and their impact on the performance of PEMFC. The various characteristics of the GDL such as porosity, hydrophobic/hydrophilic, polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE), and carbon materials, are fully discussed in this review article. These topics also cover the CL&#8217;s properties, including the catalyst, carbon support, ionomer, and solvent. Explore the different polymer electrolytes that are based on aliphatic Nafion and aromatic hydrocarbons&#8208;based membrane. Finally, this review paper gives suggestions for the way forward in regard to creating electrodes and electrolytes for PEMFCs that are cost&#8208;effective, efficient, and durable.</description>
      <author>Konlayutt Punyawudho, Mariyappan Raja Pugalenthi, Xiong Shu, Satoshi Kaneco, Tanakorn Wongwuttanasatian, Amnart Suksri, Laksamee Payattikul</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/er/9529659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution activity of nickel-based phosphates and effects of their electronic orbitals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00794h</link>
      <description>Yuuki Sugawara, Y Nakase, Gopinathan M. Anilkumar, Keigo Kamata, Takeo Yamaguchi, Nanoscale Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405196768

                Metal phosphate-type compounds have been utilized in diverse applications, and their distinctive chemical properties have recently opened avenues for their use as catalysts. Metal phosphates have previously demonstrated significant electrocatalytic activity for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in electrochemical water splitting. However, the critical factors influencing OER electrocatalysis on Ni-based phosphates have been insufficiently explored. We herein demonstrate nickel (Ni)-based phosphates-monoclinic Ni</description>
      <author>Yuuki Sugawara, Y Nakase, Gopinathan M. Anilkumar, Keigo Kamata, Takeo Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00794h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer-aided amine solvent design for carbon capture based on desorption thermodynamic and reaction kinetic models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130984</link>
      <description>Yujing Zhao, Sheng Xiang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Jianbing Chen, Ming Gao, Bing Xing, Qilei Liu, Lei Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405198919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujing Zhao, Sheng Xiang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Jianbing Chen, Ming Gao, Bing Xing, Qilei Liu, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding of the synergetic effect of FeCoN8C dual active centers catalyst for oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162055</link>
      <description>Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405199310

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D MOF Structure Tuning Atomic Ru Sites for Efficient and Robust Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410657</link>
      <description>Jia Wang, De Wang, Zelin Zhao, Ganggang Chang, Wei Guo, Jun Xu, Yinyu Xiang, Junrui Li, Junsheng Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405200807

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;based HER electrocatalysts as alternatives to commercial Pt/C is crucial for the advancement of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). However, the strong hydrogen adsorption of Ru&#8208;based catalysts restricts its activity. Herein, a strategy is reported to tune the electronic structure and improve mass transfer by implanting Ru atoms onto the (002) facet of two&#8208;dimensional zeolitic imidazolate framework&#8208;67 (Ru@ L ZIF (002) ) to optimize the d &#8208;band center ( &#949; d ) of Ru and the hydrogen spillover behavior. Benefiting from the ultrathin nanosheet structure and optimized &#949; d of Ru, the over&#8208;strong H adsorption energy is weakened and the electron/mass transfer is facilitated. Ru@ L ZIF (002) exhibits an overpotential of 9.2 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a long&#8208;lasting stability of 35 days at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . The mass activity and price activity of Ru@ L ZIF (002) is 2.9 and 14.7 times higher than Pt/C, respectively. More impressively, Ru@ L ZIF (002) delivers a cell voltage of 2.01 V at a high current density of 4 A cm &#8722;2 in PEMWE. The excellent long&#8208;term durability of 1200 hours operating at 4 A cm &#8722;2 with an ultralow decay rate of 7.5 &#215; 10 &#8722;3 mV h &#8722;1 has been achieved, making it promising as a cost&#8208;effective alternative to Pt/C catalyst for PEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Jia Wang, De Wang, Zelin Zhao, Ganggang Chang, Wei Guo, Jun Xu, Yinyu Xiang, Junrui Li, Junsheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice modulation strategy toward efficient and durable &lt;scp&gt;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;based catalysts for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18665</link>
      <description>Linkai Han, Zhonghua Xiang, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405201017

                Abstract Rutile RuO 2 is recognized for its outstanding acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and notable cost advantage compared to iridium oxide for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). However, the unsatisfactory stability of RuO 2 hinders its practical application. Here, we report a lattice modulation strategy to enhance both the OER activity and stability of RuO 2 . Interestingly, the newly synthesized Mo 0.15 Nb 0.05 &#8208;RuO 2 , with Mo doped first and then Nb, presents the greatest lattice spacing and possesses an overpotential of merely 205 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , which significantly outperforms Nb 0.05 Mo 0.15 &#8208;RuO 2 (239 mV), where Nb was doped first followed by Mo, as well as the initial RuO 2 (323 mV). Remarkably, Mo 0.15 Nb 0.05 &#8208;RuO 2 requires only 1.76 V to achieve 1 A cm &#8722;2 and exhibits exceptional stability in PEMWE testing, with a voltage rise of only 58 mV at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 for more than 80 h.</description>
      <author>Linkai Han, Zhonghua Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling the Activity Trend of Metal&#8208;Loaded Metal Nitride Catalysts for NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis by a First&#8208;Principles Microkinetic Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408863</link>
      <description>Qianqian Yang, Qijun Gao, Jia Song, Anqi Cheng, Xinhe Wu, Pengfei Liu, Hua Yang, Haiyang Yuan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405201888

                Abstract Ammonia (NH 3 ) is one of the most widely produced chemicals globally, primarily synthesized through the Haber&#8208;Bosch process, which requires high temperatures and pressures. Dual&#8208;site catalysts can activate N 2 and H 2 at spatially separated sites, enabling efficient NH 3 synthesis under milder conditions. Despite the rapid experimental progress of the dual&#8208;site catalysts (e.g., Ni&#8208;LaN), the feasibility and design of dual&#8208;site catalysts are challenged recently. Herein, the different metal&#8208;loaded metal nitride catalyst models are employed, and their activity map for NH 3 synthesis is explored by the first&#8208;principles microkinetic simulation. The optimum active region of this type of dual&#8208;site catalyst is identified in terms of the formation energy ( E v ) of nitrogen vacancy (N vac ) on metal nitride and the adsorption energy ( E H ) of hydrogen atom on metal cluster, with E v and E H ideally located around &#8776;1.50 and &#8776;&#8722;0.30 eV, respectively. This offers a framework for designing effective metal&#8208;loaded metal nitride catalysts for NH 3 synthesis. Importantly, this trend aligns with and rationalizes the current experimental observations of metal&#8208;loaded metal nitride reported for NH 3 synthesis. This theoretical work provides significant insights into NH 3 synthesis on dual&#8208;site mechanism, and provides a rational direction for designing metal&#8208;loaded metal nitride catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qianqian Yang, Qijun Gao, Jia Song, Anqi Cheng, Xinhe Wu, Pengfei Liu, Hua Yang, Haiyang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industrial Scale-Up Variability and Life Cycle Assessment of Microbial Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32388/4ynyhr</link>
      <description>Harshit Mittal, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405218982

                In the instantaneous global industrialisation, there has been an increase in the generalised waste, one of the major pollutants of wastewater. There should be advancements in the existing wastewater treatment technologies to cater for the current water demands. Wastewater treatment requires the oxidation and reduction of organic and drug molecules. Conventional wastewater technologies are expensive for such degradation, and the treatment efficiency is inadequate per the current demands. Hence microbial fuel cells, which are affordable, multi-applicability systems, should be considered for wastewater treatment technologies. This study analyses various country- and industry-wise wastewater production to demonstrate microbial fuel cell treatment technology requirements. According to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG), this review also thoroughly discusses the Life Cycle Assessment of various types of Microbial Fuel Cells in order to observe which microbial fuel cells could be applied for different levels of wastewater accumulated geologically as well as industrially. For a thorough treatment of wastewater through MFCs, the review also economically analysed the microbial fuel cells both component-wise and unit-wise, especially towards scale-up. A comprehensive socioeconomic and technological perspective has also been portrayed in order to showcase the need to transition from conventional wastewater treatment technologies towards microbial fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Harshit Mittal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32388/4ynyhr</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Pt/C Catalysts Synthesized Via Ethylene Glycol Reduction: Effects of Complexing Agents on Orr Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5051189</link>
      <description>Lu Jia, Zeyu Huang, Jianyin Xu, Jinfeng Wu, Liuwei Zhan, Haifeng Wang, Zonghua Wang, Lu Zhou, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405219679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Jia, Zeyu Huang, Jianyin Xu, Jinfeng Wu, Liuwei Zhan, Haifeng Wang, Zonghua Wang, Lu Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5051189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain&#8722;free 2D h&#8722;B2S3 nano&#8722;electrocatalyst for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction: An ab initio study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.102</link>
      <description>Muhammad Huzaifa, Mohammad Nur&#8208;e&#8208;Alam, Caterina Cocchi, Zaheer Ul&#8208;Haq, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405227119

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Huzaifa, Mohammad Nur&#8208;e&#8208;Alam, Caterina Cocchi, Zaheer Ul&#8208;Haq</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen grain-boundary segregation in HCP Ti &#8212; Computational investigations using an atomic cluster expansion potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113577</link>
      <description>Buyu Zhang, Enze Chen, Mark Asta, Computational Materials Science. 248(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405232245

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Buyu Zhang, Enze Chen, Mark Asta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113577</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of MIMII-PC6 dual-atom electrocatalysts for efficient and selective electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to C1 and C2 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101613</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Xiang Feng, Yangyang Song, Haixia Wang, Chen Chen, Xian Zhao, Weiliu Fan, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405237089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Xiang Feng, Yangyang Song, Haixia Wang, Chen Chen, Xian Zhao, Weiliu Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain engineering of ZrS2/PtSe2 heterojunction photocatalytic system for building environmental remediation: first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113941</link>
      <description>Jie Shi, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405237921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of ruthenium catalysts based on Ce-Al composite supports for hydrogen production from ammonia decomposition: Mechanism exploration via DFT calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134043</link>
      <description>Ranlei Shao, Lu Zhang, Luyuan Wang, Jianmei Wang, Xingyu Zhang, Shiwang Han, Xingxing Cheng, Zhiqiang Wang, Fuel. 384(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405242920

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ranlei Shao, Lu Zhang, Luyuan Wang, Jianmei Wang, Xingyu Zhang, Shiwang Han, Xingxing Cheng, Zhiqiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;Designing&lt;/scp&gt; and screening single&#8208;atom alloy catalysts for &lt;scp&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; reduction to &lt;scp&gt;CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;OH&lt;/scp&gt; via &lt;scp&gt;DFT&lt;/scp&gt; and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18678</link>
      <description>Wenyu Zhou, Haisong Feng, Shihong Zhou, Mengxin Wang, Yuping Chen, Chenyang Lu, Hao Yuan, Jing Yang, Qun Li, Luxi Tan, Lichun Dong, Yong&#8208;Wei Zhang, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405247170

                Abstract Carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) utilization technology is of great significance for achieving carbon neutrality, in which the catalytic materials play crucial roles, and among them, single&#8208;atom alloys (SAAs) are of particular interests. In this study, density functional theory (DFT) calculations and machine learning are employed to assess the effectiveness of Cu&#8208;, Ag&#8208;, and Ni&#8208;host SAAs as catalysts for electrochemical CO 2 reduction to CH 3 OH. The Gibbs free energies of 477 elementary reactions across 35 SAAs involved in CO 2 reduction are calculated, and by utilizing this dataset, a trained gradient boosting regression model is established with an excellent accuracy. Subsequently, the properties of 46 unknown SAAs are predicted, including their pathways, products, potential&#8208;determining steps (PDS), and corresponding Gibbs free energies of the PDS ( G PDS ). Three promising candidates, ZnCu, AuAg and MoNi, stand out due to their lowest G PDS among Cu&#8208;, Ag&#8208; and Ni&#8208; hosted SAAs, respectively.</description>
      <author>Wenyu Zhou, Haisong Feng, Shihong Zhou, Mengxin Wang, Yuping Chen, Chenyang Lu, Hao Yuan, Jing Yang, Qun Li, Luxi Tan, Lichun Dong, Yong&#8208;Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the increase of the melting temperature of water confined in one-dimensional nano-cavities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0239452</link>
      <description>Flaviano Della Pia, Andrea Zen, Venkat Kapil, Fabian L. Thiemann, Dario Alf&#232;, Angelos Michaelides, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405247918

                Water confined in nanoscale cavities plays a crucial role in everyday phenomena in geology and biology, as well as technological applications at the water&#8211;energy nexus. However, even understanding the basic properties of nano-confined water is extremely challenging for theory, simulations, and experiments. In particular, determining the melting temperature of quasi-one-dimensional ice polymorphs confined in carbon nanotubes has proven to be an exceptionally difficult task, with previous experimental and classical simulation approaches reporting values ranging from &#8764;180 K up to &#8764;450 K at ambient pressure. In this work, we use a machine learning potential that delivers first principles accuracy (trained to the density functional theory approximation revPBE0-D3) to study the phase diagram of water for confinement diameters 9.5 &amp;lt; d &amp;lt; 12.5 &#197;. We find that several distinct ice polymorphs melt in a surprisingly narrow range between &#8764;280 and &#8764;310 K, with a melting mechanism that depends on the nanotube diameter. These results shed new light on the melting of ice in one-dimension and have implications for the operating conditions of carbon-based filtration and desalination devices.</description>
      <author>Flaviano Della Pia, Andrea Zen, Venkat Kapil, Fabian L. Thiemann, Dario Alf&#232;, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0239452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Machine Learning&#8208;Assisted Multiscale Design of Energy Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403876</link>
      <description>Bohayra Mortazavi, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405257673

                Abstract This review highlights recent advances in machine learning (ML)&#8208;assisted design of energy materials. Initially, ML algorithms were successfully applied to screen materials databases by establishing complex relationships between atomic structures and their resulting properties, thus accelerating the identification of candidates with desirable properties. Recently, the development of highly accurate ML interatomic potentials and generative models has not only improved the robust prediction of physical properties, but also significantly accelerated the discovery of materials. In the past couple of years, ML methods have enabled high&#8208;precision first&#8208;principles predictions of electronic and optical properties for large systems, providing unprecedented opportunities in materials science. Furthermore, ML&#8208;assisted microstructure reconstruction and physics&#8208;informed solutions for partial differential equations have facilitated the understanding of microstructure&#8211;property relationships. Most recently, the seamless integration of various ML platforms has led to the emergence of autonomous laboratories that combine quantum mechanical calculations, large language models, and experimental validations, fundamentally transforming the traditional approach to novel materials synthesis. While highlighting the aforementioned recent advances, existing challenges are also discussed. Ultimately, ML is expected to fully integrate atomic&#8208;scale simulations, reverse engineering, process optimization, and device fabrication, empowering autonomous and generative energy system design. This will drive transformative innovations in energy conversion, storage, and harvesting technologies.</description>
      <author>Bohayra Mortazavi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coaxial Metal&#8208;Nitrogen&#8211;Carbon Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts Boost Acid Hydrogen Peroxide Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419220</link>
      <description>Hongshang Hu, Chang Zhang, Shiyuan Liu, Hangyu Qi, Haoyu Wang, Xinyu Wang, Lilong Zhang, Lei Liu, Lipiao Bao, Muneerah Alomar, Jian Zhang, Xing L&#252;, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405258100

                Abstract Electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) by two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e &#8722; ORR) under acidic conditions is promising. However, constructing a highly efficient acid&#8208;resistant 2e &#8722; ORR electrocatalyst is critical but challenging. Herein, a coaxial cobalt single&#8208;atom catalyst on carbon nanotubes (Co SA &#8208;N&#8208;C/CNTs) is designed and synthesized by an ingenious separation chemical vapor deposition (SCVD) strategy, which achieves higher ORR activity, dominated 2e &#8722; selectivity, and superior stability in acid, compared to the counterpart nanoparticle catalyst prepared by traditional mixture pyrolysis. The as&#8208;assembled electrode using Co SA &#8208;N&#8208;C/CNTs catalyst demonstrates a high H 2 O 2 yield in excess of 2000 mmol g cat &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 with a Faraday efficiency of &gt;90% over 100 h without decay in a flow cell, as superior to the most reported acidic H 2 O 2 production catalysts. Experimental characterization and theoretical calculations reveal that such excellent 2e &#8722; ORR performance of Co SA &#8208;N&#8208;C/CNTs originate from the combined advantages of strongly coupled coaxial core&#8211;shell structure and highly dispersed single&#8208;atom property. Most importantly, a series of other coaxial transition metal single&#8208;atom catalysts (M SA &#8208;N&#8208;C/CNTs, M = Fe, Cu, or Ni) are prepared through this SCVD strategy, and they all show enhanced ORR performance, demonstrating universality.</description>
      <author>Hongshang Hu, Chang Zhang, Shiyuan Liu, Hangyu Qi, Haoyu Wang, Xinyu Wang, Lilong Zhang, Lei Liu, Lipiao Bao, Muneerah Alomar, Jian Zhang, Xing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive Review based on the synthesis, properties, morphology, functionalization, and potential applications of transition metals nitrides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216353</link>
      <description>Hamid Ali, Yasin Orooji, Zeeshan Ajmal, Mohamed Abboud, Ahmed M. Abu&#8208;Dief, Khulood A. Abu Al&#8208;Ola, Hassan M.A. Hassan, Dewu Yue, Shengrong Guo, Asif Hayat, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 526(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405266578

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hamid Ali, Yasin Orooji, Zeeshan Ajmal, Mohamed Abboud, Ahmed M. Abu&#8208;Dief, Khulood A. Abu Al&#8208;Ola, Hassan M.A. Hassan, Dewu Yue, Shengrong Guo, Asif Hayat</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkene Epoxidation and Oxygen Evolution Reactions Compete for Reactive Surface Oxygen Atoms on Gold Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08948</link>
      <description>Richa Ghosh, Geoffrey M. Hopping, Jiong Lu, Drew W. Hollyfield, David W. Flaherty, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274268

                Rates and selectivities for the partial oxidation of organic molecules on reactive electrodes depend on the identity and prevalence of reactive and spectator species. Here, we investigate the mechanism for the epoxidation of 1-hexene (C</description>
      <author>Richa Ghosh, Geoffrey M. Hopping, Jiong Lu, Drew W. Hollyfield, David W. Flaherty</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Polymerization Electrospinning of Amine&#8211;Epoxy/Poly(vinyl alcohol) Nanofiber Webs for Direct CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture from the Air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07631</link>
      <description>Chisato Okada, Zongzi Hou, Hiroaki Imoto, Kensuke Naka, Takeshi Kikutani, Midori Takasaki, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405277088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chisato Okada, Zongzi Hou, Hiroaki Imoto, Kensuke Naka, Takeshi Kikutani, Midori Takasaki</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c07631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond conventional structures: emerging complex metal oxides for efficient oxygen and hydrogen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01020a</link>
      <description>Yinlong Zhu, Zheng Tang, Ling Yuan, Bowen Li, Zongping Shao, Wanlin Guo, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405281726

                The core of clean energy technologies such as fuel cells, water electrolyzers, and metal-air batteries depends on a series of oxygen and hydrogen-based electrocatalysis reactions, including the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), which necessitate cost-effective electrocatalysts to improve their energy efficiency. In the recent decade, complex metal oxides (beyond simple transition metal oxides, spinel oxides and ABO</description>
      <author>Yinlong Zhu, Zheng Tang, Ling Yuan, Bowen Li, Zongping Shao, Wanlin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01020a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable machine learning for chiral induced symmetry breaking of spin density boosting hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.066</link>
      <description>Xin Song, Zhonghua Li, Sheng Li, Yang Liu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405283541

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Song, Zhonghua Li, Sheng Li, Yang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the scales within transport-coupled kinetic models for heterogeneous electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101631</link>
      <description>Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Hendrik H. Heenen, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa J. Bukas, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405286845

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hemanth Somarajan Pillai, Hendrik H. Heenen, Karsten Reuter, Vanessa J. Bukas</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bismuth mediated tuning of electronic structure and enhanced adhesion in molybdenum based bifunctional catalysts for efficient water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131037</link>
      <description>Junzi Huang, Weitao Han, Li Liang, Bingbing Gong, Lin He, Wei Peng, Yahong Xie, Yi Zhang, Zhiyu Wang, Ying Qi, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405286921

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junzi Huang, Weitao Han, Li Liang, Bingbing Gong, Lin He, Wei Peng, Yahong Xie, Yi Zhang, Zhiyu Wang, Ying Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Design of Dual-Site Metallo-Covalent Organic Frameworks for Efficient CO2 Photoreduction into C2H4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124933</link>
      <description>K.M Chen, Wei Wang, Yuqi Dong, Zhihao Zhao, Ying Zang, Guiling Zhang, Yang Liu, Fengming Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405287328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K.M Chen, Wei Wang, Yuqi Dong, Zhihao Zhao, Ying Zang, Guiling Zhang, Yang Liu, Fengming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled deposition of trimetallic Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;V oxides on nickel foam as high-performance electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.044</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ali Ehsan, Rashida Batool, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Sameer Ali, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Zaka Ullah, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405318518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ali Ehsan, Rashida Batool, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Sameer Ali, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Zaka Ullah</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Composite Infrared Spectroscopy: Combining the Double-Harmonic Approximation with Machine Learning Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01157</link>
      <description>Philipp Pracht, Yuthika Pillai, Venkat Kapil, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Nils G&#246;nnheimer, Martin Vondr&#225;k, Johannes T. Margraf, David J. Wales, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405319422

                Vibrational spectroscopy is a cornerstone technique for molecular characterization and offers an ideal target for the computational investigation of molecular materials. Building on previous comprehensive assessments of efficient methods for infrared (IR) spectroscopy, this study investigates the predictive accuracy and computational efficiency of gas-phase IR spectra calculations, accessible through a combination of modern semiempirical quantum mechanical and transferable machine learning potentials. A composite approach for IR spectra prediction based on the double-harmonic approximation, utilizing harmonic vibrational frequencies in combination squared derivatives of the molecular dipole moment, is employed. This approach allows for methodical flexibility in the calculation of IR intensities from molecular dipoles and the corresponding vibrational modes. Various methods are systematically tested to suggest a suitable protocol with an emphasis on computational efficiency. Among these methods, semiempirical extended tight-binding (xTB) models, classical charge equilibrium models, and machine learning potentials trained for dipole moment prediction are assessed across a diverse data set of organic molecules. We particularly focus on the recently reported foundational machine learning potential MACE-OFF23 to address the accuracy limitations of conventional low-cost quantum mechanical and force-field methods. This study aims to establish a standard for the efficient computational prediction of IR spectra, facilitating the rapid and reliable identification of unknown compounds and advancing automated high-throughput analytical workflows in chemistry.</description>
      <author>Philipp Pracht, Yuthika Pillai, Venkat Kapil, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, Nils G&#246;nnheimer, Martin Vondr&#225;k, Johannes T. Margraf, David J. Wales</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDF CO2 Lab: A New Facility to Advance CO2 Capture from Flue Gases and Ambient Air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5019579</link>
      <description>Nicolas Jourdan, Antony Vanheghe, Serena Delgado, Christophe Castel, &#201;ric Favre, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405323199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicolas Jourdan, Antony Vanheghe, Serena Delgado, Christophe Castel, &#201;ric Favre</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5019579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal atom supported on N-terminated diamond (100) surface as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution and reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242133</link>
      <description>Gaoxian Li, Yuanhang Wang, Nan Gao, Hongdong Li, Applied Physics Letters. 125(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405323235

                To alleviate the increasingly serious energy issues, it is essential to develop highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we employed density functional theory to investigate a broad spectrum of transition metal (TM = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Y, Zr, Mo, Ru, Rh, Ag, W, Ir, and Pt) atoms supported on N-terminated diamond (100) surface (TM@ND) as single-atom catalysts for their OER and ORR performances. TM atoms (Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Y, Zr, and Ir) show large binding energy with substrate and thermal stability, which is advantageous for electrocatalytic reactions. Especially, Ir@ND demonstrates high efficacy as an OER electrocatalyst, and Mn@ND is identified as an efficient ORR electrocatalyst, exhibiting the theoretical overpotentials smaller than 1 V. Consequently, it suggests that diamond-based catalysts could serve as promising candidates for energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Gaoxian Li, Yuanhang Wang, Nan Gao, Hongdong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cathode-mediated electrochemical conversion of phenol to benzoquinone in wastewater: High yield rate and low energy consumption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.122967</link>
      <description>Zonglin Li, Zhiyuan Feng, Min Chen, Yankai Song, Yongkang Dai, Shun Mao, Hongying Zhao, Water Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405338488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zonglin Li, Zhiyuan Feng, Min Chen, Yankai Song, Yongkang Dai, Shun Mao, Hongying Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.122967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory for Electrocatalytic Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch2</link>
      <description>Wei Li, Yi Ding, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405358277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Li, Yi Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering atomic Pt-N3 sites on CdS nanorods for overcoming the rate-determining organic dehydrogenation in photocatalytic coproduction of H2 and value-added chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158618</link>
      <description>Huanmin Liu, Jiayi Peng, Shouxin Zhang, Kun Zheng, Lirong Zheng, Kangle Lv, Qin Li, Peng Zhou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405365290

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huanmin Liu, Jiayi Peng, Shouxin Zhang, Kun Zheng, Lirong Zheng, Kangle Lv, Qin Li, Peng Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CatTestHub: A benchmarking database of experimental heterogeneous catalysis for evaluating advanced materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115902</link>
      <description>Atharva S. Burte, Advaith Nair, Lars C. Grabow, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Susannah L. Scott, Omar Abdelrahman, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405365777

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Atharva S. Burte, Advaith Nair, Lars C. Grabow, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Susannah L. Scott, Omar Abdelrahman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115902</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lewis Acid-Mediated Interfacial Water Supply for Sustainable Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14529</link>
      <description>Liming Deng, Hongjun Chen, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ying Zhang, Hanzhi Yu, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405275902

                The catalyst-electrolyte interface plays a crucial role in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). However, optimizing the interfacial hydrogen bonding to enhance both catalytic activity and stability remains a significant challenge. Here, a novel catalyst design strategy is proposed based on the hard-soft acid-base principle, employing hard Lewis acids (LAs = ZrO</description>
      <author>Liming Deng, Hongjun Chen, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ying Zhang, Hanzhi Yu, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient parameterization of adsorbate-adsorbate interactions on metal surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122678</link>
      <description>Willem Vanmoerkerke, Rasmus Svensson, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405317176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Willem Vanmoerkerke, Rasmus Svensson, Henrik Gr&#246;nbeck</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyoxometalates based transition metal sulfide composites for hydrodesulfurization and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.048</link>
      <description>Ghulam Murtaza, Tayyaba Najam, Naseem Ahmad Khan, Muhammad Sher, Muhammad Kashif Aslam, Ibrahim A. Shaaban, Muhammad Altaf Nazir, Manzar Sohail, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405285487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ghulam Murtaza, Tayyaba Najam, Naseem Ahmad Khan, Muhammad Sher, Muhammad Kashif Aslam, Ibrahim A. Shaaban, Muhammad Altaf Nazir, Manzar Sohail, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Observed Data and Reaction Mechanisms in Deep Learning for Designing Sustainable Glycolic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527845491.ch4</link>
      <description>Xin Zhou, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405352480

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527845491.ch4</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
