<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:21:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable synthesis of Cu-cluster catalysts via spark ablation for the electrochemical conversion of CO2 to acetaldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00705-3</link>
      <description>Cedric David Koolen, Jack K. Pedersen, Bernardus Zijlstra, Maximilian Winzely, Jie Zhang, Tobias Pfeiffer, Wilbert L. Vrijburg, Mo Li, Ayush Agarwal, Zohreh Akbari, Yasemen Kuddusi, Juan Herranz, &#1054;lga V. Safonova, A. Schmidt&#8208;Ott, Wen Luo, A. ZUETTEL, Nature Synthesis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406036475

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cedric David Koolen, Jack K. Pedersen, Bernardus Zijlstra, Maximilian Winzely, Jie Zhang, Tobias Pfeiffer, Wilbert L. Vrijburg, Mo Li, Ayush Agarwal, Zohreh Akbari, Yasemen Kuddusi, Juan Herranz, &#1054;lga V. Safonova, A. Schmidt&#8208;Ott, Wen Luo, A. ZUETTEL</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00705-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling electronic constraints on basal planes of 2D transition metal chalcogenides for optimizing hydrogen evolution catalysis: A theoretical analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113658</link>
      <description>Faling Ling, Shuijie Zhang, Zheng Dai, Shaobo Wang, Yuting Zhao, Li Li, Xianju Zhou, Xiao Tang, Dengfeng Li, Xiaoqing Liu, Computational Materials Science. 249(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406079744

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faling Ling, Shuijie Zhang, Zheng Dai, Shaobo Wang, Yuting Zhao, Li Li, Xianju Zhou, Xiao Tang, Dengfeng Li, Xiaoqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Effect of Shape Anisotropy of Plasmonic Tungsten Oxide Nanostructures for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02233</link>
      <description>G. A. Davis, Brian C. Wyatt, Barry B. Muhoberac, Rajesh Sardar, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406094095

                Platinum is the most efficient electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER); however, the lack of earth abundance and high cost restrict its widespread use. Herein, we report electrocatalytic HER efficacy of oxygen-deficient, localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR)-active tungsten-oxide (WO3&#8211;x) nanocrystals (NCs) as a function of free conduction electron density and metal oxidation states. These plasmonic, anisotropic WO3&#8211;x NCs display &#8764;160 mV overpotential at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and a Tafel slope of 54 mV/dec. Ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopic measurements support the HER electrocatalytic properties attributed to the Fermi energy pinning as a function of the NC shape (i.e., nanowires, nanorods, and nanoplatelets) and chemical composition of the inorganic WO3&#8211;x lattice. Furthermore, our experimental data show that increasing the number of coordinatively unsaturated tungsten sites, which are generated from the ionization of surface oxygen atoms in WO3&#8211;x NCs, improves the surface reactivity and thus, enhances the catalytic performance. Together, structure&#8211;property relationship delineating the NC morphology and the resulting optoelectronic properties studied here provide the opportunity to unravel the correlation between the NC shape, free conduction electron density and the HER kinetics of this unique class of NC and to potentially initiate the designer principle of noble metal-free, highly active, but not limited to HER catalysts to produce an energy-dense fuel.</description>
      <author>G. A. Davis, Brian C. Wyatt, Barry B. Muhoberac, Rajesh Sardar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spillover Promoted Dual CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Ethanol via Low C&#8211;C Coupling Barrier on Co-Embedded &#947;-Graphyne with d&#8722;&#960; Orbital Centers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02563</link>
      <description>Poobodin Mano, Kaito Takahashi, Chularat Wattanakit, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406094867

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Poobodin Mano, Kaito Takahashi, Chularat Wattanakit, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood&#8208;Inspired Electrode for Sustainable Electrocatalytic Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smm2.1326</link>
      <description>Weijia Guo, Yawen Wang, Shunyu Shen, Han Wang, Kai Shao, Zhenjie Wang, Yao Shi, Caicai Li, Qingfeng Sun, Huiqiao Li, SmartMat. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406101616

                ABSTRACT Electrocatalysis plays a central role in electrochemical energy storage and conversion systems, providing a number of sustainable processes for future technologies. As a green, renewable, and abundant natural polymer material, the unique structure and physicochemical properties of wood and its derivatives provide a unique application advantage in the field of electrocatalysis, which has aroused intense attention from researchers. At present, researchers have developed many wood&#8208;based catalytic electrodes by taking advantage of the anisotropic hierarchical porous structure of wood and abundant active functional groups on the cell wall surface of wood. Here, a comprehensive review of recent progress in the design and synthesis of wood&#8208;inspired electrodes for electrocatalytic reactions is summarized. Starting from the role and importance of the electrocatalytic process in the whole energy conversion system, this review highlights the composition and structure of wood, analyzes the mechanisms of electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), urea oxidation reaction (UOR), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and discusses the structure&#8208;activity relationship between the structural properties and electrochemical activity of wood&#8208;inspired electrodes. Finally, the opportunities, challenges, and future directions in the application of wood and its derivatives in the field of electrocatalysis are prospected.</description>
      <author>Weijia Guo, Yawen Wang, Shunyu Shen, Han Wang, Kai Shao, Zhenjie Wang, Yao Shi, Caicai Li, Qingfeng Sun, Huiqiao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smm2.1326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiMo-C Coatings Synthesized by Reactive Magnetron Sputtering for Application as a Catalyst for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in an Acidic Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17743</link>
      <description>T. Suszko, Ewa Dobruchowska, W. Gulbi&#324;ski, Grzegorz Greczy&#324;ski, J. Morgiel, Bartosz Kawczy&#324;ski, Karol Za&#322;&#281;ski, Krzysztof Dorywalski, Stanis&#322;aw Pogorzelski, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406105163

                This study examines the structure and properties of NiMo-C coatings synthesized via reactive magnetron sputtering of a NiMo alloy target in an argon/acetylene atmosphere. The coating structure evolves with carbon content from nanocrystalline, through amorphous to quasi-amorphous with a nanocolumnar structure. The nanostructure consists of metallic columns perpendicular to the substrate surrounded by an amorphous carbon shell. The coatings are evaluated for their potential use as catalytic materials in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in an acidic environment. The medium carbon content coatings show optimal properties in this direction, i.e., high corrosion resistance in an acidic environment and good HER performance described by the Tafel slope and characteristic overpotentials. Even at the highest carbon content, 74 at. %, the Tafel slope does not increase substantially, which is more likely attributable to the distinctive nanocolumnar structure, ensuring the presence of catalytic centers in the form of metallic islands on the surface. At the highest current densities applied, a weak but visible correlation is observed between the characteristic overpotentials and the contact angle hysteresis derived from the wettability measurements.</description>
      <author>T. Suszko, Ewa Dobruchowska, W. Gulbi&#324;ski, Grzegorz Greczy&#324;ski, J. Morgiel, Bartosz Kawczy&#324;ski, Karol Za&#322;&#281;ski, Krzysztof Dorywalski, Stanis&#322;aw Pogorzelski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superatoms as Superior Catalysts: ZrO versus Pd</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409289</link>
      <description>Mehmet Emin K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, P. Jena, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406112104

                Single-atom catalysts are the focus of studies for over a decade due to their enhanced reactivity at smaller sizes. However, they have limitations as they offer only one active site, which may not be sufficient for reactions requiring the co-adsorption of multiple reactants. Additionally, atoms can migrate on a substrate and coalesce, resulting in decreased reactivity. Here, an alternate path, a single-superatom catalyst is provided. Superatoms are clusters of atoms that mimic the chemistry of atoms even if they do not contain a single atom whose chemistry they mimic. Motivated by an experimental paper on the photoelectron-spectroscopy of negatively charged ions where ZrO is found to mimic properties of a Pd atom, first the reaction of Pd and ZrO with small molecules in the gas-phase is studied and found that ZrO not only mimics the chemistry of Pd, but is able to activate these molecules more strongly than Pd. A detailed first-principles study of CO</description>
      <author>Mehmet Emin K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, P. Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D Co&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;C&#8208;Based Heterojunctional Nanowires from Pyrolytically &#8220;Squeezing&#8221; PMo&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;/ZIF&#8208;67 Cubes for Efficient Overall Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409703</link>
      <description>Xinhui Zhang, Aiping Wu, Dongxu Wang, Ying Xie, Alexander I. Gubanov, Gennadiy &#1040;. &#1050;&#1086;stin, Chungui Tian, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406115361

                Abstract The bi&#8208;transition&#8208;metal interstitial compounds (BTMICs) are promising for water electrolysis. The previous BTMICs are usually composed of irregular particles. Here, this work shows the synthesis of novel 1D Co 6 Mo 6 C&#8208;based heterojunction nanowires (1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C) with diameters about 50 nm and a length&#8208;to&#8208;diameter ratio about 20 for efficient water electrolysis. An interesting growth process based on pyrolytically &#8220;squeezing&#8221; PMo 12 (Phosphomolybdic acid)/ZIF&#8208;67 (Zeolitic Imidazolate Framework&#8208;67) cube precursor is demonstrated. The &#8220;squeezing&#8221; growth is related to the role of Mo species for isolating Co species. A series of tests and theoretical calculation show the mutual regulation of Co and Mo to optimize the electronic structure, accelerating H 2 O dissociation and the reduction kinetics of H + . Additionally, the nanowires provide pathways for electron transfer and the transmission of reactants. Consequently, the 1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C exhibits high activity for hydrogen evolution reaction ( &#951; 10 of 31 mV) and oxygen evolution reaction ( &#951; 10 of 210 mV) in 1 m KOH. The electrolytic cell based on 1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C requires a low voltage of 1.43 V to drive 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . The catalyst also exhibits good HER performance in 1 m phosphate&#8208;buffered saline solution, exceeding Pt/C at a current density &gt;42 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Xinhui Zhang, Aiping Wu, Dongxu Wang, Ying Xie, Alexander I. Gubanov, Gennadiy &#1040;. &#1050;&#1086;stin, Chungui Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Driven Screening of Atomically Precise Pure Metal Nanoclusters for Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01737</link>
      <description>Nishchal Bharadwaj, Diptendu Roy, A. Das, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406116618

                Developing efficient catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in proton-exchange membrane fuel cells is challenging due to high power density and durability requirements. Subnanometer clusters (SNCs) show promise, but their fluxional behavior and complex structure&#8211;activity relationships hinder catalyst design. We combine density functional theory (DFT) and machine learning (ML) to study transition metal-based subnanometer nanoclusters (TMSNCs) ranging from 3 to 30 atoms, aiming to establish structure activity relationship (SAR) for ORR. Subdividing the data set based on size and periodic groups significantly improves the accuracy of our ML models. Importantly, the ML model predicting the ORR catalytic performance is validated through DFT calculations, identifying 12 promising catalysts. Late group TMSNCs exhibit enhanced ORR activity, reflected in a noticeable shift toward Au/Ag metals on the volcano plot. This underscores the importance of investigating late group TMSNCs alongside Pt for the ORR. ML accelerates TMSNC design, surpassing computational screening and advancing catalyst development.</description>
      <author>Nishchal Bharadwaj, Diptendu Roy, A. Das, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Systematic investigation as a Strategic Tool for the design of more efficient pure and doped MoS2 catalysts for CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112597</link>
      <description>Viviane S. Vaiss, Luciano T. Costa, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406117495

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Viviane S. Vaiss, Luciano T. Costa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112597</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchoring ordered PtZn nanoparticles on MOF-derived carbon support for efficient oxygen reduction reaction in proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159350</link>
      <description>KwangHo Lee, Eoyoon Lee, HyunWoo Chang, JeongHan Roh, SangJae Lee, Junu Bak, YongKeun Kwon, Hyung Chul Ham, EunAe Cho, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406117532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>KwangHo Lee, Eoyoon Lee, HyunWoo Chang, JeongHan Roh, SangJae Lee, Junu Bak, YongKeun Kwon, Hyung Chul Ham, EunAe Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal-anchored BN tubes as single-atom catalysts for NO reduction reaction: A study of DFT and deep learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134302</link>
      <description>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Weihua Zhu, Fuel. 386(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406119678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiake Fan, Lei Yang, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precisely designing asymmetrical selenium-based dual-atom sites for efficient oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55862-6</link>
      <description>Xiaochen Wang, Ning Zhang, Huishan Shang, Haojie Duan, Zhiyi Sun, Lili Zhang, Yuanting Lei, Xuan Luo, Liang Zhang, Bing Zhang, Wenxing Chen, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406120170

                Owing to their synergistic interactions, dual-atom catalysts (DACs) with well-defined active sites are attracting increasing attention. However, more experimental research and theoretical investigations are needed to further construct explicit dual-atom sites and understand the synergy that facilitates multistep catalytic reactions. Herein, we precisely design a series of asymmetric selenium-based dual-atom catalysts that comprise heteronuclear SeN2&#8211;MN2 (M = Fe, Mn, Co, Ni, Cu, Mo, etc.) active sites for the efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Spectroscopic characterisation and theoretical calculations revealed that heteronuclear selenium atoms can efficiently polarise the charge distribution of other metal atoms through short-range regulation. In addition, compared with the Se or Fe single-atom sites, the SeFe dual-atom sites facilitate a reduction in the conversion energy barrier from *O to *OH via the coadsorption of *O intermediates. Among these designed selenium-based dual-atom catalysts, selenium-iron dual-atom catalysts achieves superior alkaline ORR performance, with a half-wave potential of 0.926 V vs. a reversible hydrogen electrode. In addition, the SeN2&#8211;FeN2-based Zn&#8211;air battery has a high specific capacity (764.8 mAh g&#8722;1) and a maximum power density (287.2 mW cm&#8722;2). This work may provide a good perspective for designing heteronuclear DACs to improve ORR efficiency. Dual-atom catalysts with precise active sites are gaining attention, but further studies are needed to optimise their construction and understand their catalytic synergy. Here the authors report a series of asymmetric selenium-based dual- atom catalysts that comprise heteronuclear SeN2&#8211;MN2 (M = Fe, Mn, Co, Ni, Cu, Mo, etc.) active sites for the efficient oxygen reduction reaction.</description>
      <author>Xiaochen Wang, Ning Zhang, Huishan Shang, Haojie Duan, Zhiyi Sun, Lili Zhang, Yuanting Lei, Xuan Luo, Liang Zhang, Bing Zhang, Wenxing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55862-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery and Characterization of a Metastable Cubic Interstitial Nickel&#8211;Carbon System with an Expanded Lattice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c15300</link>
      <description>Albert Gili, Martin Kunz, Daniel Gaissmaier, Christoph Jung, Timo Jacob, Thomas Lunkenbein, Walid Hetaba, Kassiog&#233; Demb&#233;l&#233;, S&#246;ren Selve, Reinhard Schomaecker, Aleksander Gurlo, Maged F. Bekheet, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406125409

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Albert Gili, Martin Kunz, Daniel Gaissmaier, Christoph Jung, Timo Jacob, Thomas Lunkenbein, Walid Hetaba, Kassiog&#233; Demb&#233;l&#233;, S&#246;ren Selve, Reinhard Schomaecker, Aleksander Gurlo, Maged F. Bekheet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c15300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening and Design of Metal-Organic Frameworks for CO2 Separation from Flue Gas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/2025.19579</link>
      <description>Xiuling Jiao, Aiping Chen, Applied and Computational Engineering. 123(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126000

                Rising CO2 levels, largely from flue gas emissions, are a significant contributor to global climate change. Adsorption using Metal-Organic Frameworks (MOFs) offers a promising solution for CO2 capture due to their high surface area, tunable porosity, and selectivity. To streamline the discovery of efficient MOFs, we developed a high-throughput virtual screening (HTVS) pipeline by integrating Grand-Canonical Monte Carlo (GCMC) simulations, molecular modeling and machine learning. We screened a filtered subset of the CoREMOF database and a user-defined hypothetical MOF bank to identify candidates with high CO2 adsorption capacity and selectivity. This approach yielded several high-performing MOFs, including five from the CoREMOF dataset and a new structure from the hypothetical bank exceeding the performance of existing MOFs. Our findings highlight the complex relationship between MOF geometries and CO2 capture performance, emphasizing the importance of features like open metal sites and pore geometry. This computational framework accelerates MOF discovery and provides valuable insights for experimental synthesis. Future work will focus on expanding the hypothetical MOF dataset, improving simulation accuracy, and employing advanced optimization techniques to enhance the screening process.</description>
      <author>Xiuling Jiao, Aiping Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/2025.19579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom Tungsten Anchoring on Monolayer T-C3N2 as a Promising Nitrogen Reduction Electrocatalyst: A combined DFT and Machine Learning Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105764</link>
      <description>Yunxia Liang, Chengwei Yang, Liangshi Wang, Hongxia Yan, Jinli Zhang, Wentao Wang, Guixian Ge, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126959

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunxia Liang, Chengwei Yang, Liangshi Wang, Hongxia Yan, Jinli Zhang, Wentao Wang, Guixian Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationally Designed Air Electrode Boosting Electrochemical Performance of Protonic Ceramic Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402654</link>
      <description>Chunmei Tang, Baoyin Yuan, Xiaohan Zhang, Fangyuan Zheng, Qingwen Su, Ling Meng, Lei Du, Dongxiang Luo, Yoshitaka Aoki, Ning Wang, Siyu Ye, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406127006

                Abstract Protonic ceramic cells (PCCs) have gained significant attention as a promising electrochemical device for hydrogen production and power generation at intermediate temperatures. However, the lack of high&#8208;performance air electrodes, specifically in terms of proton conduction ability, has severely hindered the improvement of electrochemical performances for PCCs. In this study, a high&#8208;efficiency air electrode La 0.8 Ba 0.2 CoO 3 (LBC) is rationally designed and researched by a machine&#8208;learning model and density functional theory (DFT) calculation, which boosts the performances of PCCs. Specifically, an elements&#8208;property map for designing high&#8208;efficiency oxides is created by predicting and studying the proton uptake ability of La 1&#8211; x A&#8242; x BO 3 (A&#8242; = Na, K, Ca, Mg, Ba, Cu, etc.) by an eXtreme Gradient Boosting model. PCC with LBC air electrode yields high current destiny in electrolysis mode (1.72 A cm &#8722;2 at 600 &#176;C) and power density in fuel cell mode (1.00 W cm &#8722;2 at 600 &#176;C). In addition, an ultra&#8208;low air electrode reaction resistance (0.03 &#937; cm 2 at 600 &#176;C) is achieved, because LBC can significantly facilitate the formation of O 2 * . This work not only reports an effective air electrode but also presents a new avenue for the rational design of air electrodes for PCCs.</description>
      <author>Chunmei Tang, Baoyin Yuan, Xiaohan Zhang, Fangyuan Zheng, Qingwen Su, Ling Meng, Lei Du, Dongxiang Luo, Yoshitaka Aoki, Ning Wang, Siyu Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt/cobalt phosphide/nitrogen-doped carbon derived from zeolitic imidazolate framework-11@zeolitic imidazolate framework-12 core-shell structure as efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.014</link>
      <description>Chen-Han Lin, Yin-Chen Lin, Chia&#8208;Lin Yeh, L. Lin, Kuo&#8208;Chuan Ho, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406133976

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen-Han Lin, Yin-Chen Lin, Chia&#8208;Lin Yeh, L. Lin, Kuo&#8208;Chuan Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage Regulation of &#946;-Ketoamine Covalent Organic Frameworks for Boosting Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20472</link>
      <description>Yiwen Yang, Hong&#8208;Da Ren, Hanyu Zhang, Yingnan Zhao, Huaqiao Tan, Zhongling Lang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406134747

                Two dimensional &#946;-ketoamine covalent organic frameworks (2D TP-COFs) are one category of promising metal-free catalysts for photocatalytic overall water splitting (OWS) because of their unusual stability and versatile electronic/optical properties. However, none of the currently reported TP-COFs can accomplish the hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER) simultaneously without adding any sacrificial agents and cocatalysts. To address this challenging issue, we rationally designed 23 2D TP-COFs by regulating the linkage groups and comprehensively evaluated their OWS activity by using the first-principles method. First, the electronic band structure calculations at the HSE06 level reveal that the band gap can be reasonably adjusted with values ranging from 1.67&#8211;3.16 eV. Among these 23 systems, 10 TP-COFs are realized to match well with both the chemical potentials of H2/H+ and O2/H2O, which are capable of visible-light-driven OWS from an electronic perspective. Further thermal activity results on OWS demonstrate that only Hep-BDA (heptazine-aniline) and Bpy-4 (bipyrimidinamine) based COFs can satisfy the completely spontaneous of HER and OER under light irradiation and neutral conditions. Importantly, the calculated small exciton binding energies and high carrier mobility for Hep-BDA and Bpy-4 TP-COFs propose they are potentially applied in photocatalytic OWS. We also achieved the theoretical energy conversion efficiency of Hep-BDA can reach as high as 13.01%. Because there are very few successful applications of TP-COFs on OWS, this theoretical work not only offers valuable insights and innovative ideas for the exploration of novel metal-free photocatalysts for OWS but also supplies a direction for the development of new TP-COF derivatives.</description>
      <author>Yiwen Yang, Hong&#8208;Da Ren, Hanyu Zhang, Yingnan Zhao, Huaqiao Tan, Zhongling Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Radial Ligand Effect of Biomimetic Amino Acid toward Stable Alkaline Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04889</link>
      <description>Jianye Wang, Zengxuan Chen, Xiaojing Lin, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaodong Chen, Xingheng Zhang, Jiao Li, Jinpeng Liu, Siyuan Liu, Shuxian Wei, Daofeng Sun, Xiaoqing L&#252;, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianye Wang, Zengxuan Chen, Xiaojing Lin, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaodong Chen, Xingheng Zhang, Jiao Li, Jinpeng Liu, Siyuan Liu, Shuxian Wei, Daofeng Sun, Xiaoqing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoS2-confined Rh-Zn atomic pair boosts photo-driven methane carbonylation to acetic acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54061-z</link>
      <description>Yanan Li, Chenguang Liu, Jun Mao, Meng Gao, Yunlong Zhang, Qiao Zhao, Meng Liu, Yao Song, Jingting Hu, Wangwang Zhang, Rui Huang, Wu Zhou, Kaifeng Wu, Wei Liu, Liang Yu, Xiaoju Cui, Dehui Deng, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406153476

                Direct carbonylation of CH4 to CH3COOH provides a promising pathway for upgrading of natural gas to transportable liquid chemicals, in which high-efficiency CH4 activation and controllable C&#8211;C coupling are both critical but challenging. Herein, we report that highly efficient photo-driven carbonylation of CH4 with CO and O2 to CH3COOH is achieved over MoS2-confined Rh-Zn atomic-pair in conjunction with TiO2. It delivers a high CH3COOH productivity of 152.0 &#956;mol gcat.&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 and turnover frequency of 62.0 h&#8722;1 with a superior selectivity of 96.5%, outperforming previous photocatalytic CH4 carbonylation processes. Mechanistic investigations disclose the key effect of Rh-Zn synergy in combination with photo-excited electrons from TiO2 for CH3COOH formation. The active OH species produced from O2 photoreduction on the Zn site through proton-coupled electron transfer promotes CH4 dissociation to CH3 species, which then facilely couples with adsorbed CO on the adjacent Rh site forming the key CH3CO intermediate for CH3COOH formation. The authors report a catalyst featuring Rh-Zn dual sites in a MoS2 lattice integrated with TiO2 for the photocatalytic carbonylation of CH4 with CO and O2 to CH3COOH with a high productivity of 152.0 &#956;mol gcat.&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 and selectivity of 96.5%.</description>
      <author>Yanan Li, Chenguang Liu, Jun Mao, Meng Gao, Yunlong Zhang, Qiao Zhao, Meng Liu, Yao Song, Jingting Hu, Wangwang Zhang, Rui Huang, Wu Zhou, Kaifeng Wu, Wei Liu, Liang Yu, Xiaoju Cui, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54061-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing the &#8220;anomalous&#8221; electrochemical Stark shift of CO at Pt(111) through vibrational spectroscopy and density-functional theory calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122694</link>
      <description>Elias Diesen, Mehmet Ugur Coskun, S. D&#237;az-Coello, Vanessa J. Bukas, Julia Kunze&#8208;Liebh&#228;user, Karsten Reuter, Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406160174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elias Diesen, Mehmet Ugur Coskun, S. D&#237;az-Coello, Vanessa J. Bukas, Julia Kunze&#8208;Liebh&#228;user, Karsten Reuter</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/crystalline NiZr heterojunction nanorods for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction prepared by magnetron sputtering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178575</link>
      <description>Jinsen Tian, Junhao Qin, Han Zhang, Mingwei Tang, Jing Wu, Jiahua Zhu, Jun Shen, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406161078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinsen Tian, Junhao Qin, Han Zhang, Mingwei Tang, Jing Wu, Jiahua Zhu, Jun Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into tunable photocatalytic water splitting performance of black phosphorus quantum dots through doping different nonmetallic heteroatoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.503</link>
      <description>Song Xu, Jianguang Feng, Xiaoning Wang, Qiong Sun, Hongzhou Dong, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406165308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Song Xu, Jianguang Feng, Xiaoning Wang, Qiong Sun, Hongzhou Dong, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of transition-metal-cluster-anchored g-C3N4 for the electrochemical catalytic hydrogenation of carbon dioxide to C1 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115076</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Huining Feng, Ruiyang Tang, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406167755

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Huining Feng, Ruiyang Tang, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning covalent bonding of single transition metal atom doped in S vacant MoS2 for catalytic CO2 reduction reaction product selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162339</link>
      <description>Poobodin Mano, Thanadol Jitwatanasirikul, Thantip Roongcharoen, Kaito Takahashi, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406168446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Poobodin Mano, Thanadol Jitwatanasirikul, Thantip Roongcharoen, Kaito Takahashi, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Reduction of Nitric Oxide on Alumina-Supported Ultra-Small Nickel Particles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/surfaces8010006</link>
      <description>Ramazan T. Magkoev, Yong Men, Reza Behjatmanesh&#8208;Ardakani, Mohammadreza Elahifard, N. Pukhaeva, Aleksandr A. Takaev, Ramazan A. Khekilaev, &#1058;. &#1058;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1075;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077;&#1074;, &#1054;. &#1043;. &#1040;&#1096;&#1093;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Surfaces. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406169609

                The adsorption and reaction of nitric oxide (NO) molecules on the surface of the model-supported metal/oxide system, consisting of Ni nanoparticles deposited on &#945;-Al2O3 (0001) in ultra-high vacuum, have been studied using in situ surface-sensitive techniques and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. As a combination of X-ray and Auger electron spectroscopy (XPS, AES), Fourier-transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy, and temperature-programmed desorption (TPD) techniques reveals, there is a threshold of Ni particle mean size (&lt;d&gt;) of c.a. 2 nm, differentiating the electron state of adsorbed NO molecules and their reaction. The main feature of Ni particles normally not exceeding 2 nm is that the NO adsorbs in the form of (NO)2 dimers, whereas, for larger particles, the NO molecules adsorb in the form of monomers, usually characteristic for the bulk Ni substrate. This difference is demonstrated to be the main reason for the different reaction of NO molecules on the surface of Ni/alumina. The striking feature is that, in the case of ultra-small Ni particles (&lt;d&gt; &#8804; 2 nm), the nitrous oxide (N2O) molecules are formed upon heating as a result of the NO self-reduction mechanism, which are otherwise not formed in the case of larger Ni particles. According to DFT results, this is due to the significant synergistic impact of NO co-adsorption on the neighboring NO dissociation reaction over ultra-small Ni particles, mediated by the metal/oxide perimeter interface. The observed molecular conversion effects offer an opportunity to tune the catalytic selectivity of this and related metal/oxide systems via varying the supported metal particle size.</description>
      <author>Ramazan T. Magkoev, Yong Men, Reza Behjatmanesh&#8208;Ardakani, Mohammadreza Elahifard, N. Pukhaeva, Aleksandr A. Takaev, Ramazan A. Khekilaev, &#1058;. &#1058;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1075;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077;&#1074;, &#1054;. &#1043;. &#1040;&#1096;&#1093;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/surfaces8010006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same FeN4 Active Site, Different Activity: How Redox Peaks Control Oxygen Reduction on Fe Macrocycles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00146</link>
      <description>Silvia Favero, Ruixuan Chen, Jacob C. H. Cheung, Luke Higgins, Hui Luo, Mengnan Wang, Jes&#250;s Barrio, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Alexander Bagger, Ifan E. L. Stephens, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406172700

                Macrocycles show high activity for the electrochemical reduction of oxygen in alkaline media. However, even macrocycles with the same metal centers and MN4 active site can vary significantly in activity and selectivity, and to this date, a quantitative insight into the cause of these staggering differences has not been unambiguously reached. These macrocycles form a fundamental platform, similarly to platinum alloys for metal ORR catalyst, to unravel fundamental properties of FeNx catalysts. In this manuscript, we present a systematic study of several macrocycles, with varying active site motif and ligands, using electrochemical techniques, operando spectroscopy, and density functional theory (DFT) simulations. Our study demonstrates the existence of two families of Fe macrocycles for oxygen reduction in alkaline electrolytes: (i) weak *OH binding macrocycles with one peak in the voltammogram and high peroxide selectivity and (ii) macrocycles with close to optimal *OH binding, which exhibit two voltametric peaks and almost no peroxide production. Here, we also propose three mechanisms that would explain our experimental findings. Understanding what differentiates these two families could shed light on how to optimize the activity of pyrolyzed FeNx catalysts.</description>
      <author>Silvia Favero, Ruixuan Chen, Jacob C. H. Cheung, Luke Higgins, Hui Luo, Mengnan Wang, Jes&#250;s Barrio, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Alexander Bagger, Ifan E. L. Stephens</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling Multiple pH-Dependent Factors on the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction at Au(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00081</link>
      <description>Er-Fei Zhen, Bing-Yu Liu, Mengke Zhang, Lulu Zhang, Chenyu Zhang, Jun Cai, Marko Melander, Jun Huang, Yanxia Chen, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406175469

                Understanding how the electrolyte pH affects electrocatalytic activity is a topic of crucial importance in a large variety of systems. However, unraveling the origin of the pH effects is complicated often by the fact that both the reaction driving forces and reactant concentrations in the electric double layer (EDL) change simultaneously with the pH value. Herein, we employ the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at Au(111)-aqueous solution interfaces as a model system to disentangle different pH-dependent factors. In 0.1 M NaOH, the HER current density at Au(111) in the potential range of &#8722;0.4 V &lt; ERHE &lt; 0 V is up to 60 times smaller than that in 0.1 M HClO4. A reaction model with proper consideration of the local reaction conditions within the EDL is developed. After correcting for the EDL effects, the rate constant for HER is only weakly pH-dependent. Our analysis unambiguously reveals that the observed pH effects are mainly due to the pH-dependent reorganization free energy, which depends on the electrostatic potential and the local reaction conditions within the EDL. Possible origins of the pH and temperature dependence of the activation energy and the electron transfer coefficients are discussed. This work suggests that factors influencing the intrinsic pH-dependent kinetics are easier to understand after proper corrections of EDL effects.</description>
      <author>Er-Fei Zhen, Bing-Yu Liu, Mengke Zhang, Lulu Zhang, Chenyu Zhang, Jun Cai, Marko Melander, Jun Huang, Yanxia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of CNTs composites with mono and bimetallic oxides for the oxygen evolution reactions in water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.111961</link>
      <description>Muhammad Khurram, Nadiah Yousef Aldaleeli, Muhammad Yasir, Abid Ali, Sheza Muqaddas, Muhammad Naveed Arshad, Rizwan Shoukat, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406185824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Khurram, Nadiah Yousef Aldaleeli, Muhammad Yasir, Abid Ali, Sheza Muqaddas, Muhammad Naveed Arshad, Rizwan Shoukat</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.111961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of High Purity Ethylene Using High-Index Facet Cu2O Nanocrystals Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125053</link>
      <description>Ahmad M. Harzandi, Seyed Parsa Amouzesh, Jiayi Xu, Taha Baghban-Ronaghi, Sahar Shadman, Fiona Collins, Gayoon Kim, Werner Kaminsky, Larry A. Curtiss, Cong Liu, Mohammad Asadi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406194395

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ahmad M. Harzandi, Seyed Parsa Amouzesh, Jiayi Xu, Taha Baghban-Ronaghi, Sahar Shadman, Fiona Collins, Gayoon Kim, Werner Kaminsky, Larry A. Curtiss, Cong Liu, Mohammad Asadi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focus on the catalysts to resist the phosphate poisoning in high-temperature proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60162-2</link>
      <description>Liyuan Gong, Li Tao, Lei Wang, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Shuangyin Wang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 68(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406199714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liyuan Gong, Li Tao, Lei Wang, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Shuangyin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60162-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect-Induced Bimetallic Cubic-Spinel NiO/NiCo2O4 heterostructures via Na-Incorporation towards efficient electrochemical water splitting performances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162352</link>
      <description>Sebastian Cyril Jesudass, Subramani Surendran, Gnanaprakasam Janani, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kim, Yong Il Park, Uk Sim, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406205422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sebastian Cyril Jesudass, Subramani Surendran, Gnanaprakasam Janani, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kim, Yong Il Park, Uk Sim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of La&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;NiMnO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; Double Perovskite as a Highly Selective Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Reduction to Hydrogen Peroxide in Electrochemical Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02469</link>
      <description>Mohammad Imran Hossain, Syed Abdul Monim, Zannatul Mumtarin Moushumy, Neamul H. Khansur, Iqbal Mahmud, Mostafizur Rahaman, Ali Aldalbahi, Shakhawat H. Firoz, Mohammad A. Hasnat, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406031911

                Oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), a key process in sustainable energy conversion, utilizing a perovskite catalyst to achieve higher currents at lower overpotentials along with the production of value-added product hydrogen peroxide (H2O2), serves the dual functionality of both energy production and a green route for H2O2 generation. Here, we report the synthesis of a highly efficient double perovskite La2NiMnO6 (LNMO), achieved through the incorporation of two transition metals, Ni and Mn, in the perovskite structure, and explore its activity for ORR. During ORR at a rotation rate of 1600 rpm in 1.0 M NaOH, LNMO exhibits an onset potential of 0.75 V (corresponding to a current density of 0.1 mA cm&#8211;2) and a Tafel slope of 95 mV dec&#8211;1, achieving over 88% H2O2 selectivity and 73% faradaic efficiency across a wide potential range of 0.2&#8211;0.6 V vs RHE. Characterization techniques including OCP, EIS, ICP-OES, XRD, XPS, FE-SEM, and FTIR confirmed the successful preparation of LNMO and its catalytic activity. The kinetic investigation unveiled by the transfer coefficient (&#945;) demonstrated that ORR on the LNMO surface followed a stepwise mechanism, involving an overall two irreversible electron transfer steps, where the first electron transfer was the rate-determining step. The analyses further revealed a diffusion-limited process for ORR accompanied by first-order kinetics with a standard rate constant (k0) of 3.97 &#215; 10&#8211;3 cm s&#8211;1 and a formal potential (E0) value of 0.96 V vs RHE. Finally, a stability test via chronoamperometry showed that LNMO outperformed the Pt/C catalyst.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Imran Hossain, Syed Abdul Monim, Zannatul Mumtarin Moushumy, Neamul H. Khansur, Iqbal Mahmud, Mostafizur Rahaman, Ali Aldalbahi, Shakhawat H. Firoz, Mohammad A. Hasnat</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Machine Learning/Molecular Mechanics End-State Corrections with Mechanical Embedding to Calculate Relative Protein&#8211;Ligand Binding Free Energies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01427</link>
      <description>Johannes Karwounopoulos, M. Bieniek, Zhiyi Wu, Adam L. Baskerville, Gerhard K&#246;nig, Benjamin P. Cossins, Geoffrey P. F. Wood, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406033300

                The development of machine-learning (ML) potentials offers significant accuracy improvements compared to molecular mechanics (MM) because of the inclusion of quantum-mechanical effects in molecular interactions. However, ML simulations are several times more computationally demanding than MM simulations, so there is a trade-off between speed and accuracy. One possible compromise are hybrid machine learning/molecular mechanics (ML/MM) approaches with mechanical embedding that treat the intramolecular interactions of the ligand at the ML level and the protein&#8211;ligand interactions at the MM level. Recent studies have reported improved protein&#8211;ligand binding free energy results based on ML/MM using ANI-2x with mechanical embedding, arguing that intramolecular interactions like torsion potentials of the ligand are often the limiting factor for accuracy. This claim is evaluated based on 108 relative binding free energy calculations for four different benchmark systems. As an alternative strategy, we also tested a tool that fits the MM dihedral potentials to the ML level of theory. Fitting was performed with the ML potentials ANI-2x and AIMNet2, and, for the benchmark system TYK2, also with quantum-mechanical calculations using &#969;B97M-D3(BJ)/def2-TZVPPD. Overall, the relative binding free energy results from MM with Open Force Field 2.2.0, MM with ML-fitted torsion potentials, and the corresponding ML/MM end-state corrected simulations show no statistically significant differences in the mean absolute errors (between 0.8 and 0.9 kcal mol&#8211;1). This can probably be explained by the usage of the same MM parameters to calculate the protein&#8211;ligand interactions. Therefore, a well-parametrized force field is on a par with simple mechanical embedding ML/MM simulations for protein&#8211;ligand binding. In terms of computational costs, the reparametrization of poor torsional potentials is preferable over employing computationally intensive ML/MM simulations of protein&#8211;ligand complexes with mechanical embedding. Also, the refitting strategy leads to lower variances of the protein&#8211;ligand binding free energy results than the ML/MM end-state corrections. For free energy corrections with ML/MM, the results indicate that better convergence and more advanced ML/MM schemes will be required for applications in computer-guided drug discovery.</description>
      <author>Johannes Karwounopoulos, M. Bieniek, Zhiyi Wu, Adam L. Baskerville, Gerhard K&#246;nig, Benjamin P. Cossins, Geoffrey P. F. Wood</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Dual-Atom Catalysts with Tunable Electron Synergistic Effect via Photoinduced Ligand Exchange Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06059</link>
      <description>Yamei Pang, Xu Zhang, Pengfei Li, Guang&#8208;Jie Xia, Xupeng Zong, Yichang Liu, Dan Qu, Kun Zheng, Li An, Xiayan Wang, Zaicheng Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406037761

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yamei Pang, Xu Zhang, Pengfei Li, Guang&#8208;Jie Xia, Xupeng Zong, Yichang Liu, Dan Qu, Kun Zheng, Li An, Xiayan Wang, Zaicheng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Insight Into Electronic Modulation of Rare&#8208;Earth Elements for Enhancing Electrocatalytic Performance of Atomically Dispersed Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423158</link>
      <description>Yanhui Cao, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Wenbin Hu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406038908

                Abstract Atomically dispersed materials have been a thriving research field due to their maximum atomic utilization and remarkable performance in energy conversion and storage systems. Owing to the large atomic radius, strong oxophilicity, and unique electronic properties, rare&#8208;earth (RE) elements have been widely investigated as oxide carriers and promoters in atomically dispersed materials to manipulate and regulate the electronic structure of active species. Single&#8208;atom state with an adjustable coordination environment on the N&#8208;doped carbon endows RE metals with special electronic states and outstanding catalytic performances. A thorough comprehension of the electronic modulation mechanism of RE elements paves the way for the construction of advanced RE&#8208;based electrocatalysts with high activity, stability, and selectivity. This review provides a widespread insight into the roles of RE elements in modulating the electronic properties of atomically dispersed materials combined with the structure&#8211;performance relationship in electrocatalysis processes. The characteristic physical and chemical properties of RE elements are highlighted, and the synthetic strategy of RE&#8208;based atomically dispersed materials is discussed. Finally, a summary and perspectives for rational design and development of highly efficient RE&#8208;based catalysts are proposed. This review aims to provide a guideline for promoting the rational and effective utilization of RE elements in advanced functional materials.</description>
      <author>Yanhui Cao, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Wenbin Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ViPErLEED package I: Calculation of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;I&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;(&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;V&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;)&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; curves and structural optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevresearch.7.013005</link>
      <description>Florian Kraushofer, Alexander M. Imre, Giada Franceschi, Tilman Ki&#223;linger, Erik Rheinfrank, Michael Schmid, Ulrike Diebold, Lutz Hammer, Michele Riva, Physical Review Research. 7(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406048601

                Low-energy electron diffraction (LEED) is a widely used technique in surface-science laboratories. Yet, it is rarely used to its full potential. The quantitative information about the surface structure, contained in the modulation of the intensities of the diffracted beams as a function of incident electron energy, LEED I(V), is underutilized. To acquire these data, only minor adjustments would be required in most experimental setups, but existing analysis software is cumbersome to use and often computationally inefficient. The ViPErLEED (Vienna package for Erlangen LEED) project lowers these barriers, introducing a combined solution for user-friendly data acquisition, extraction, and computational analysis. These parts are discussed in three separate publications. Here, the focus is on the computational part of ViPErLEED, which performs highly automated LEED-I(V) calculations and structural optimizations. Minimal user input is required, and the functionality is significantly enhanced compared to existing solutions. Computation is performed by embedding the existing Erlangen tensor-LEED package (). ViPErLEED manages additional parallelization, monitors convergence, and processes all input and output. This makes LEED I(V) more accessible to new users while minimizing the potential for errors and the manual labor. Added functionalities include intelligent structure-dependent defaults for most calculation parameters, automatic detection of bulk and surface symmetries and their relationship, automated search procedures that preserve the symmetry and speed up convergence, adjustments to the code to handle larger systems than before, as well as parallelization and optimization. Modern file formats are used as input and output, and there is a direct interface to the atomic simulation environment (ASE) package. The software is implemented primarily in (version &#8805;3.7) and provided as an open-source package (GNU GPLv3 or any later version). A structure determination of the &#945;-Fe2O3(11&#175;02)&#8722;(1&#215;1) surface is presented as an example for the application of the software. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>Florian Kraushofer, Alexander M. Imre, Giada Franceschi, Tilman Ki&#223;linger, Erik Rheinfrank, Michael Schmid, Ulrike Diebold, Lutz Hammer, Michele Riva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevresearch.7.013005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering structure-activity relationships in rhodium-based catalysts for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216418</link>
      <description>Juan Bai, Jun Mei, Ting Liao, Ziqi Sun, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 528(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406053679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juan Bai, Jun Mei, Ting Liao, Ziqi Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the promotional role of Pd in oxidative alcohol coupling reactions over dilute PdAu alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115942</link>
      <description>Oluwatofunmi O. Akinsanya, Deep M. Patel, C. R. O'Connor, Marta Perx&#233;s Perich, Jessi E. S. van der Hoeven, C. Reece, Luke T. Roling, Nathaniel M. Eagan, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406057237

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oluwatofunmi O. Akinsanya, Deep M. Patel, C. R. O'Connor, Marta Perx&#233;s Perich, Jessi E. S. van der Hoeven, C. Reece, Luke T. Roling, Nathaniel M. Eagan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-scale covariance for material property prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01453-w</link>
      <description>Benjamin A. Jasperson, Ilia Nikiforov, Amit Samanta, Fei Zhou, Ellad B. Tadmor, Vincenzo Lordi, Vasily V. Bulatov, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406060145

                A simulation can stand its ground against an experiment only if its prediction uncertainty is known. The unknown accuracy of interatomic potentials (IPs) is a major source of prediction uncertainty, severely limiting the use of large-scale classical atomistic simulations in a wide range of scientific and engineering applications. Here we explore covariance between predictions of metal plasticity, from 178 large-scale (~108 atoms) molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, and a variety of indicator properties computed at small-scales (&#8804;102 atoms). All simulations use the same 178 IPs. In a manner similar to statistical studies in public health, we analyze correlations of strength with indicators, identify the best predictor properties, and build a cross-scale "strength-on-predictors" regression model. This model is then used to estimate regression error over the statistical pool of IPs. Small-scale predictors found to be highly covariant with strength are computed using expensive quantum-accurate calculations and used to predict flow strength, within the statistical error bounds established in our study.</description>
      <author>Benjamin A. Jasperson, Ilia Nikiforov, Amit Samanta, Fei Zhou, Ellad B. Tadmor, Vincenzo Lordi, Vasily V. Bulatov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01453-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping La into NiFe LDH/NiS heterostructure achieving high-current-density oxygen evolution for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157526</link>
      <description>Qi Song, Kangnan Li, Zhenhua Cao, Mi Yang, Qian Kong, Gang He, Hongyu Liu, Qian Qiao, Liangzhong Yao, Yufan Wang, Xiaoping Dai, Xin Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Song, Kangnan Li, Zhenhua Cao, Mi Yang, Qian Kong, Gang He, Hongyu Liu, Qian Qiao, Liangzhong Yao, Yufan Wang, Xiaoping Dai, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarization switching-controlled oxygen evolution and reduction reactions for ferroelectric single-atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159247</link>
      <description>Wenqing Li, Hongyu Zhang, Ruoyan Xu, Xingxing Jiang, Haiyu Meng, Xiong&#8208;Xiong Xue, Shengli Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqing Li, Hongyu Zhang, Ruoyan Xu, Xingxing Jiang, Haiyu Meng, Xiong&#8208;Xiong Xue, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening van der Waals transition metal carbo-selenide MXenes as efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.295</link>
      <description>Chen Zhou, Renfei Cheng, Junchao Wang, Min Zhao, Lijun Ren, Tao Hu, Xiaohui Wang, Chunxian Guo, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074415

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Zhou, Renfei Cheng, Junchao Wang, Min Zhao, Lijun Ren, Tao Hu, Xiaohui Wang, Chunxian Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous Co-MoS2 with sulfur vacancies: A bifunctional electrocatalyst for enhanced water-splitting reactions in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.017</link>
      <description>Hongmei Wu, Yao Zhang, Baoshan Liu, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074619

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongmei Wu, Yao Zhang, Baoshan Liu, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Metal&#8211;Nitrogen&#8211;Carbon Catalysts for Acidic Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16972</link>
      <description>Xiang Ao, Haoran Wang, Xia Zhang, Chundong Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406058102

                Designing efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts toward oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) under demanding acidic environments plays a critical role in advancing proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). Metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) catalysts with atomically dispersed metals have gained attention for their affordability, excellent catalytic performance, and distinctive features including consistent active sites and high atomic utilization. Over the past decade, significant achievements have been made in this field. This review offers a comprehensive summary of the latest developments in atomically dispersed M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts for ORR in acidic environments along with their applications in PEMFCs. The ORR mechanisms, PEMFC configuration, and operational principles are presented first, followed by an in-depth discussion of strategies to improve the activity and stability of the PEMFC using atomically dispersed M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts at the cathode. Lastly, this review highlights the unresolved challenges and proposes future research pathways for advancing high-performance atomically dispersed M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts and PEMFCs.</description>
      <author>Xiang Ao, Haoran Wang, Xia Zhang, Chundong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High content Fe(III) electrocatalyst for the oxygen reduction and evolution reactions. Spectroscopic, electrochemical, and theoretical insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.385</link>
      <description>C&#233;sar Z&#250;&#241;iga Loyola, Andrea Zitolo, Nicol&#225;s Troncoso, Jesus Carrasco, Sergio Choque, Gabriel Abarca, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Walter Orellana, Federico Tasca, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074461

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C&#233;sar Z&#250;&#241;iga Loyola, Andrea Zitolo, Nicol&#225;s Troncoso, Jesus Carrasco, Sergio Choque, Gabriel Abarca, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Walter Orellana, Federico Tasca</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Impact of Trace SO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on Amine Absorbents for Chemical Absorption of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04163</link>
      <description>Songtao Zheng, Shaojun Jia, Yan Wu, Qi Wang, Yao Jiang, Peng Cui, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406188239

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Songtao Zheng, Shaojun Jia, Yan Wu, Qi Wang, Yao Jiang, Peng Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Sampling for Machine Learning Electron Density and Its Response in Real Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01355</link>
      <description>Chaoqiang Feng, Yaolong Zhang, Bin Jiang, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406051705

                Electron density is a fundamental quantity that can in principle determine all ground state electronic properties of a given system. Although machine learning (ML) models for electron density based on either an atom-centered basis or a real-space grid have been proposed, the demand for a number of high-order basis functions or grid points is enormous. In this work, we propose an efficient grid-point sampling strategy that combines targeted sampling favoring a large density and a screening of grid points associated with linearly independent atomic features. This new sampling strategy is integrated with a field-induced recursively embedded atom neural network model to develop a real-space grid-based ML model for the electron density and its response to an electric field. This approach is applied to a QM9 molecular data set, a H2O/Pt(111) interfacial system, an Au(100) electrode, and an Au nanoparticle under an electric field. The number of training points is found to be much smaller than previous models, while yielding comparably accurate predictions for the electron density of the entire grid. The resultant machine-learned electron density model enables us to properly partition partial charge onto each atom and analyze the charge variation upon proton transfer in the H2O/Pt(111) system. The machine-learning electronic response model allows us to predict charge transfer and the electrostatic potential change induced by an electric field applied to an Au(100) electrode or an Au nanoparticle.</description>
      <author>Chaoqiang Feng, Yaolong Zhang, Bin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SurFF: Universal Model for Surface Exposure and Synthesizability Across Intermetallic Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4863775/v1</link>
      <description>Xiaonan Wang, Jun Yin, Honghao Chen, Ju Qiu, Wentao Li, Peng He, Jiali Li, Iftekhar A. Karimi, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406127231

                Abstract Catalysts are crucial in industrial processes, significantly enhancing reaction efficiency. With approximately 90% of industrial reactions occurring on surfaces, the role of heterogeneous catalysts is paramount. Accurate surface exposure prediction is vital for heterogeneous catalyst design but is hindered by the high costs of experimental and computational methods. Here, we introduce a universal force field-based model for predicting surface exposure and synthesizability (SurFF) across intermetallic crystals, essential materials for heterogeneous catalysts. We created a comprehensive intermetallic surface database using a data-efficient active learning method and high-throughput density functional theory (DFT) calculations, encompassing 12,553 unique surfaces and 344,200 single points. SurFF achieves DFT-level precision with a prediction error of 3.0 meV/&#197;&#178; and enables large-scale surface exposure prediction, an impractical task for DFT methods, through a 105-fold acceleration. Validation against computational and experimental data both shows strong alignment. We applied SurFF for large-scale predictions on over 6,000 intermetallic crystals, providing valuable data for the community. Demonstrating transferability to diverse crystal properties, SurFF is a robust tool for advancing catalyst design, representing a significant step toward large-scale catalyst discovery models.</description>
      <author>Xiaonan Wang, Jun Yin, Honghao Chen, Ju Qiu, Wentao Li, Peng He, Jiali Li, Iftekhar A. Karimi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4863775/v1</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
