<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 02:55:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>New insights into Rh-Pt electrocatalysts with low Pt content for ethanol electro-oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146084</link>
      <description>Nelson A. Galiote, Camilo A. Angelucci, Vin&#237;cius Del Colle, Germano Tremiliosi&#8208;Filho, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409191806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nelson A. Galiote, Camilo A. Angelucci, Vin&#237;cius Del Colle, Germano Tremiliosi&#8208;Filho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a molecular-scale picture of water electrolysis: mechanistic insights, fundamental kinetics and electrocatalyst dynamic evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216651</link>
      <description>Man Chen, Yingju Yang, Yuandong Ding, Jing Liu, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 536(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409197050

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Man Chen, Yingju Yang, Yuandong Ding, Jing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of structural modulation of B2 phase on the deformation mechanism in FeNiCrCoAl high entropy alloy: an atomistic insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130840</link>
      <description>K. Vijay Reddy, Punit Kumar, Saurabh Vashistha, Snehanshu Pal, Shailesh K. Singh, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409199255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Vijay Reddy, Punit Kumar, Saurabh Vashistha, Snehanshu Pal, Shailesh K. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Hypervalent Ru Sites in RuO2 Catalysts by Synergistic Bimetal Codoping for Long-Lasting Ampere-Level PEM Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110960</link>
      <description>Pengfei Li, Shupeng Wang, Hongpu Huang, Linrui Wen, Junlin Cai, Yuhang Peng, Zhiyu Zou, Xiaohong Wang, Xiaoliang Fang, Fang Lei, Xue Wang, Zhaoxiong Xie, Shuifen Xie, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409201280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Li, Shupeng Wang, Hongpu Huang, Linrui Wen, Junlin Cai, Yuhang Peng, Zhiyu Zou, Xiaohong Wang, Xiaoliang Fang, Fang Lei, Xue Wang, Zhaoxiong Xie, Shuifen Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts with three-dimensional porous structure for electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01392</link>
      <description>Yuchen Liu, Yanning Zhang, Zulin Sun, Liming Dai, Bin Liu, Wenxian Li, Sustainable materials and technologies. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409201428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuchen Liu, Yanning Zhang, Zulin Sun, Liming Dai, Bin Liu, Wenxian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen radical induced Zn transfer to Ru film surfaces and influence of ambient atmosphere exposure on Zn adsorbates on Ru</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2025.114316</link>
      <description>Ilias Gaffarov, Jacobus Marinus Sturm, Marcelo Ackermann, Igor A. Makhotkin, Vacuum. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409201606

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ilias Gaffarov, Jacobus Marinus Sturm, Marcelo Ackermann, Igor A. Makhotkin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2025.114316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction-Driven Varieties of Active Sites on Cu(100) in Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07168</link>
      <description>Shuoqi Zhang, Qingli Tang, Beien Zhu, Yi Gao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409206316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuoqi Zhang, Qingli Tang, Beien Zhu, Yi Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroelectric Polarization Effects of Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts on Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500285</link>
      <description>Hao Ma, Xinyu Ye, Xiaoning Li, Zhichuan J. Xu, Yuanmiao Sun, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409208207

                Abstract The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) heavily depends on their substrates. However, heterojunctions with traditional substrate materials often fail to provide the desired dynamic interface effects. Here, through a systematic study of the ferroelectric heterostructure In 2 Se 3 /C&#8208;N&#8208;M, the feasibility of using ferroelectric materials to achieve dynamic optimization of the OER activity on SACs is demonstrated. The ferroelectric In 2 Se 3 is confirmed to be an effective substrate for improving the stability of various SACs, supported by theoretical results of their negative formation energy and positive dissolution potential. Activity analysis indicates that among these In 2 Se 3 /C&#8208;N&#8208;M systems, the In 2 Se 3 /C&#8208;N&#8208;Ir can achieve near&#8208;ideal catalytic activities through polarization switching. It can unprecedentedly catalyze OER via a hybrid pathway of adsorbate evolution mechanism and O&#8208;O coupling mechanism under different pH conditions (from pH = 1 to pH = 13). Machine learning models have been developed to conduct feature analysis and make ultrafast predictions of OER activity, which identify that the interfacial charge transfer triggered by ferroelectric polarization is the key to fine&#8208;tuning the OER performance of SACs. This work provides a theoretical framework that utilizes ferroelectric polarization as a powerful approach to navigate the design of efficient SACs.</description>
      <author>Hao Ma, Xinyu Ye, Xiaoning Li, Zhichuan J. Xu, Yuanmiao Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-free two-dimensional nanomaterials supported single atom catalysts for energy conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180261</link>
      <description>Yong Wan, Mingming Zhang, Cui Lai, Fuhang Xu, Shiyu Liu, Yukui Fu, Ling Li, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409211302

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Wan, Mingming Zhang, Cui Lai, Fuhang Xu, Shiyu Liu, Yukui Fu, Ling Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antisite defect unleashes catalytic potential in high-entropy intermetallics for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58679-5</link>
      <description>Tao Chen, Xinkai Zhang, Hangchao Wang, Chonglin Yuan, Yuxuan Zuo, Chuan Gao, Wukun Xiao, Yue Yu, Junfei Cai, Tie Luo, Yan Xiang, Dingguo Xia, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409211400

                Developing highly active, low-cost, and durable catalysts for efficient oxygen reduction reactions remain a challenge, hindering the commercial viability of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). In this study, an ordered PtZnFeCoNiCr high-entropy intermetallic electrocatalyst with Pt antisite point defects (PD-PZFCNC-HEI) is synthesized. The electrocatalyst shows high mass activity of 4.12 A mgPt-1 toward the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), which is 33 times that of the commercial Pt/C. PEMFC, assembled with PD-PZFCNC-HEI as the cathode (0.05 mgPt cm-2), exhibits a peak power density of 1.9 W cm-2 and a high mass activity of 3.0 A mgPt-1 at 0.9 V. Theoretical calculations combined with in situ X-ray absorption fine structure results reveal that defect engineering optimizes Pt's electronic structure and activates non-noble metal site active centers, achieving exceptionally high ORR catalytic activity. This study provides guidance for the development of nanostructured ordered high-entropy intermetallic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Chen, Xinkai Zhang, Hangchao Wang, Chonglin Yuan, Yuxuan Zuo, Chuan Gao, Wukun Xiao, Yue Yu, Junfei Cai, Tie Luo, Yan Xiang, Dingguo Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58679-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate classification of materials with elEmBERT: Element embeddings for chemical benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232529</link>
      <description>Shokirbek Shermukhamedov, Dilorom Mamurjonova, Michael Probst, APL Machine Learning. 3(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409216061

                We introduce the elEmBERT model for chemical classification tasks. It is based on deep learning techniques, such as a multilayer encoder architecture. We demonstrate the opportunities offered by our approach on sets of organic, inorganic, and crystalline compounds. In particular, we developed and tested the model using the Materials Project and MoleculeNet benchmarks, which include crystal properties and drug design-related benchmarks. We also conduct an analysis of vector representations of chemical compounds, shedding light on the underlying patterns in structural data. Our model exhibits exceptional predictive capabilities and proves universally applicable to molecular and material datasets. For instance, on the Tox21 dataset, we achieved an average precision of 96%, surpassing the previously best result by 10%.</description>
      <author>Shokirbek Shermukhamedov, Dilorom Mamurjonova, Michael Probst</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Coverage Carbon Monoxide Adsorption on a ZnAl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Surface: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00722</link>
      <description>Chunyan Sun, Lihong Cheng, Runping Ye, Rongbin Zhang, Qiang Li, Gang Feng, Shi Liu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409219696

                ZnAl2O4 spinel is widely used as a support in various reactions due to its thermal stability. Investigating the interaction between CO and ZnAl2O4 is essential for understanding the surface reaction mechanisms. In the present work, density functional theory (DFT) and ab initio atomistic thermodynamics were employed to investigate the adsorption of CO on perfect and O-defective ZnAl2O4 surfaces at varying CO coverages. The results reveal the formation of C* species and the subsequent aggregation can be hindered by the concentration of surface oxygen vacancy (Ovac) at low CO coverages. Notably, at high CO coverages, carbon deposition (CD) occurs on the ZnAl2O4 surfaces. &#916;&#956;CO is regulated below its threshold based on surface Ovac concentrations to control CO coverage and thereby suppress CD. At 523 K, the CO partial pressures should be maintained below 100, 10-3, 100, and 10-6 atm for surface with Ovac concentrations of 0, 12.5, 25, and 37.5%, respectively, to prevent CD on the surface. DFT-simulated IR spectra show that varying Ovac concentrations significantly affects the CO adsorption peak types and shifts, causing red shifts in vibrational frequencies for linearly adsorbed CO. These findings provide guidance for synthesizing ZnAl2O4 with varying Ovac concentrations to enhance catalyst efficiency and durability while mitigating CD.</description>
      <author>Chunyan Sun, Lihong Cheng, Runping Ye, Rongbin Zhang, Qiang Li, Gang Feng, Shi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From lab to market: Economic viability of modern hydrogen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135227</link>
      <description>Margarita Ryabicheva, Yaroslav Zhigalenok, Saken Abdimomyn, &#1052;&#1072;zhyn Skakov, &#1040;. Zh. Miniyazov, Gainiya Zhanbolatova, Nuriya Mukhamedova, Zhanar Ospanova, Thierry Djenizian, Fyodor Malchik, Fuel. 395(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409228929

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Margarita Ryabicheva, Yaroslav Zhigalenok, Saken Abdimomyn, &#1052;&#1072;zhyn Skakov, &#1040;. Zh. Miniyazov, Gainiya Zhanbolatova, Nuriya Mukhamedova, Zhanar Ospanova, Thierry Djenizian, Fyodor Malchik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Review on Revisiting Marcus Theory and Novel Understanding Heterogeneous Electron Transfer by Programing Tools</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elan.12045</link>
      <description>Xuanze Wang, Jie Deng, Kulika Pithaksinsakul, Yachao Zhu, Jiaxin Ren, Jiangfeng Qian, Olivier Fontaine, Electroanalysis. 37(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409229211

                Electron transfer is always the spotlight in electrochemistry, especially electrochemical energy storage. However, the current understanding of electron transfer, particularly in heterogeneous systems as explained by Marcus theory, faces challenges in accurately accounting for surface effects, solvent reorganization, and quantum tunneling, which are critical to real&#8208;world applications. Here, this review presents a comprehensive analysis of the heterogeneous electron transfer processes within the framework of Marcus theory, focusing on computing approaches using Python and Wolfram Language. The introduction outlines the significance of Marcus theory in explaining electron transfer reactions and sets the stage for the subsequent discussions. In the results and discussions section, the electron distribution in heterogeneous systems is explored, comparing the effects of different formalisms on electron transfer. A detailed comparison of the computational approaches using Python and Mathematica underscores the essential role of programing in tackling complex electron transfer models. These tools offer powerful, complementary capabilities for simulating the nuanced behavior of heterogeneous electron transfer processes, providing researchers with the flexibility and precision necessary to address the limitations of traditional theoretical methods. Finally, the work delves into the law of conservation of energy within the context of Marcus theory, offering a nuanced discussion of its implications for electron transfer studies. This review aims to equip researchers with practical insights and computing tools to enhance their understanding and application of Marcus theory in heterogeneous systems.</description>
      <author>Xuanze Wang, Jie Deng, Kulika Pithaksinsakul, Yachao Zhu, Jiaxin Ren, Jiangfeng Qian, Olivier Fontaine</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elan.12045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curvature-Influenced Electrocatalytic NRR Reactivity by Heme-like FeN4-Site on Carbon Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081670</link>
      <description>Yajie Meng, Ziyue Huang, Xi Chen, Yingqi Li, Xueyuan Yan, Jiawei Xu, Hai&#8208;Yan Wei, Molecules. 30(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409245179

                Two-dimensional carbon materials and their derivatives are widely applied as promising electrocatalysts and supports of single-atom sites. Theoretical investigations of 2D carbon materials are usually based on planar models, yet ignore local curvature brought on by possible surface distortion, which can be significant to the exact catalytic performance as has been realized in latest research. In this work, the curvature-influenced electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) reactivity of heme-like FeN4 single-atom site was predicted by a first-principle study, with FeN4-CNT(m,m) (m = 5~10) models adopted as local curvature models. The results showed that a larger local curvature is favored for NRR, with a lower limiting potential and higher N2 adsorption affinity, while a smaller local curvature shows lower NH3 desorption energy and is beneficial for catalyst recovery. Using electronic structures and logarithm fitting, we also found that FeN4-CNT(5,5) shows an intermediate-spin state, which is different from the high-spin state exhibited by other FeN4-CNT(m,m) (m = 6~10) models with a smaller local curvature.</description>
      <author>Yajie Meng, Ziyue Huang, Xi Chen, Yingqi Li, Xueyuan Yan, Jiawei Xu, Hai&#8208;Yan Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction by tuning the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface in nickel-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-025-01508-z</link>
      <description>Ben Wang, Tomohiro Fukushima, Hiro Minamimoto, Andrey Lyalin, Kei Murakoshi, Tetsuya Taketsugu, Communications Chemistry. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409246364

                A comprehensive understanding of the electrode-electrolyte interface in energy conversion systems remains challenging due to the complex and multifaceted nature of interfacial processes. This complexity hinders the development of more efficient electrocatalysts. In this work, we propose a hybrid approach to the theoretical description of the OER process on nickel-iron-based oxyhydroxides (&#947;-Ni1-xFexOOH) electrodes in alkaline media as a model system. Multiple reaction pathways represented by the single- and dual-site mechanisms were investigated by taking into account the realistic structure of the catalyst, the doping, and the solvation effects using a simple and computationally feasible strategy. Accounting for the variable solvation effects considerably affects the predicted overpotential in a roughly linear relationship between overpotential and dielectric constant. By incorporating quantum chemical simulations with kinetic modeling, we demonstrate that tuning the local solvation environment can significantly enhance the OER activity, opening new routine ways for elucidation of the emerging issues of OER processes on transition metal oxide surfaces and design of cost-effective, efficient electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Ben Wang, Tomohiro Fukushima, Hiro Minamimoto, Andrey Lyalin, Kei Murakoshi, Tetsuya Taketsugu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-025-01508-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy alloy enables multi-path electron synergism and lattice oxygen activation for enhanced oxygen evolution activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58648-y</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Hui-Feng Zhao, Zheng&#8208;Jie Chen, Qun Yang, Niu Gao, Li Li, Na Luo, Jian Zheng, Shanhu Bao, Jing Peng, Peng Xu, Xinwang Liu, Hai&#8208;Bin Yu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409246456

                Electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is key to several energy technologies but suffers from low activity. Leveraging the lattice oxygen activation mechanism (LOM) is a strategy for boosting its activity. However, this approach faces significant thermodynamic challenges, requiring high-valent oxidation of metal ions without compromising their stability. We reveal that high-entropy alloys (HEAs) can efficiently activate the LOM through synergistic multi-path electron transfer. Specifically, the oxidation of nickel is enhanced by this electron transfer, aided by the integration of weaker Co-O bonds, enabling effective LOM at the Ni-Co dual-site. These insights allow the design of a NiFeCoCrW0.2 HEA that exhibits improved activity, achieving an overpotential of 220 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm-2. It also demonstrates good stability, maintaining the potential with less than 5% variation over 90 days at 100 mA cm-2 current density. This study sheds light on the synergistic effects that confer high activity in HEAs and contribute to the advancement of high-performance OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Hui-Feng Zhao, Zheng&#8208;Jie Chen, Qun Yang, Niu Gao, Li Li, Na Luo, Jian Zheng, Shanhu Bao, Jing Peng, Peng Xu, Xinwang Liu, Hai&#8208;Bin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58648-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationally Designing Efficient Biomass Carbon Electrocatalysts for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis and Near-Neutral Zn&#8211;Air Batteries with Preliminary Machine Learning Guidance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00377</link>
      <description>Jiawei He, Zijun Shen, Shengchun Hu, Yuying Zhao, Qixin Yuan, Yuhan Wu, Kang Sun, Shule Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Mengmeng Fan, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409248983

                Biomass-based carbon materials are considered promising metal-free catalysts for the 2e- oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) to synthesize H2O2 and act as air electrodes in Zn-air batteries. However, optimization of the catalyst structure is a complex process due to the diversity of biomass precursors and synthesis parameters. Machine learning, a new artificial intelligence technology, has recently been used in various fields owing to its ability to rapidly analyze large amounts of data and guide material synthesis. Consequently, we constructed a machine learning model based on previously reported experimental data and guided the fabrication of a boron-doped biomass carbon catalyst for the 2e- ORR. The achieved catalytic performance exceeded most reported ORR catalysts in terms of H2O2 selectivity (90-95% in broad potentials of 0.30-0.68 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode), stability (maintaining over 90% selectivity for 12 h), yield (3450 mmol gcatalyst-1 h-1), and Faraday efficiency (over 90%). We applied the catalysts to Zn-air batteries and showed a high capacity (2856 mAh g-1) and stability twice that of traditional commercial metal catalysts. Therefore, this study proposed an effective machine learning model to guide the fabrication of biomass-based catalysts in the field of electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Jiawei He, Zijun Shen, Shengchun Hu, Yuying Zhao, Qixin Yuan, Yuhan Wu, Kang Sun, Shule Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Mengmeng Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular iron phthalocyanines anchoring onto ZIF-67-derived cobalt-carbon nanomaterials as bifunctional oxygen catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-025-1001-9</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Lin, Danna Lin, Weiwu Zhang, Jie Liu, Yanqiong Shen, Jinjie Qian, Frontiers in Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409250226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Lin, Danna Lin, Weiwu Zhang, Jie Liu, Yanqiong Shen, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-025-1001-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing MXenes and MBenes-Supported Composites for Superior Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-9546-2.ch009</link>
      <description>P. Selvakumar, Ritu Dahiya, T. C. Manjunath, Santosh Kumar Nathsharma, IGI Global eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409250446

                The pivotal area of research in the quest for sustainable and efficient methods although highly effective for industrial ammonia production, is energy-intensive and reliant on fossil fuels, contributing significantly to global carbon emissions. NRR offers a promising alternative, enabling ammonia synthesis at ambient temperatures and pressures using renewable energy sources. This reaction, where nitrogen is converted into ammonia through electrochemical means, mitigate environmental demand for green technologies in chemical manufacturing. At the core of NRR is the challenge of nitrogen activation, as molecular Electrocatalysts play a crucial role in facilitating this reaction by lowering the energy barriers associated with nitrogen dissociation and subsequent hydrogenation. Various materials, including precious metals, transition metal compounds, and novel carbon-based nanostructures, have been explored for their catalytic properties.</description>
      <author>P. Selvakumar, Ritu Dahiya, T. C. Manjunath, Santosh Kumar Nathsharma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-9546-2.ch009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic performance of in situ pyrolized iron oxide-embedded carbon composite for sustainable hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.112305</link>
      <description>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, T. Maiyalagan, Khuloud A. Alibrahim, Abdullah N. Alodhayb, Nagaraj P. Shetti, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409250906

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, T. Maiyalagan, Khuloud A. Alibrahim, Abdullah N. Alodhayb, Nagaraj P. Shetti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.112305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformative valorization of semi-coking wastewater: Design of rare earth/nitrogen-codoped porous carbon for efficient water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.436</link>
      <description>Qin Wang, Jin&#8208;Xing Liu, Hong&#8208;Xin Li, Xinglong Zhang, Zheng En-rang, Jian Li, Long Yan, Zhengqing Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 126(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409254453

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qin Wang, Jin&#8208;Xing Liu, Hong&#8208;Xin Li, Xinglong Zhang, Zheng En-rang, Jian Li, Long Yan, Zhengqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving Electrochemical Organic Hydrogenations on Metal Catalysts by Tailoring Hydrogen Surface Coverages</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15821</link>
      <description>Anna Ciotti, Motiar Rahaman, Celine Wing See Yeung, Tengfei Li, Erwin Reisner, Max Garc&#237;a&#8208;Melchor, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409262633

                Electrochemical hydrogenation, powered by renewable electricity, represents a promising sustainable approach for organic synthesis and the valorization of biomass-derived chemicals. Traditional strategies often rely on alkaline conditions to mitigate the competing hydrogen evolution reaction, posing challenges in sourcing hydrogen atoms for hydrogenation, which can be addressed through localized water dissociation on the electrode surface. In this study, we present a computationally guided design of electrochemical hydrogenation catalysts by optimizing hydrogen coverage density and binding strength on the electrode. Our theoretical investigations identify Cu, Au, and Ag - metals with moderate hydrogen coverage - as promising catalysts for electrochemical hydrogenations in alkaline media. These predictions are experimentally validated using a model organic substrate (acetophenone), achieving yields and faradaic efficiencies of up to 90%. Additionally, Cu, a nonprecious metal, is demonstrated to selectively hydrogenate a wide range of unsaturated compounds, including C&#9552;O, C&#9552;C, C&#8801;C, and C&#8801;N bonds, at low potentials with moderate to excellent conversion rates and chemoselectivities. This work highlights the potential of tailoring hydrogen coverage on electrode surfaces to rationally design nonprecious metal electrocatalysts for efficient organic hydrogenations. The insights gained here are expected to inform the development of more effective catalysts for organic hydrogenations and other industrially relevant chemical transformations.</description>
      <author>Anna Ciotti, Motiar Rahaman, Celine Wing See Yeung, Tengfei Li, Erwin Reisner, Max Garc&#237;a&#8208;Melchor</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paired electrochemical synthesis of glycolic acid and ammonia from polyester and nitrate sewage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101336</link>
      <description>Yingxin Ma, Xuyun Guo, Wenfang Yuan, Peinuo Yang, Yu Zhang, Wenxuan Chen, Lejuan Cai, Valeria Nicolosi, Wenlong Wang, Yang Chai, Bocheng Qiu, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409264939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingxin Ma, Xuyun Guo, Wenfang Yuan, Peinuo Yang, Yu Zhang, Wenxuan Chen, Lejuan Cai, Valeria Nicolosi, Wenlong Wang, Yang Chai, Bocheng Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Catalytic Materials for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081656</link>
      <description>M. Tr&#281;bala, Agata &#321;amacz, Molecules. 30(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409265480

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has, in recent years, attracted great interest from scientists because of its prime role in a number of renewable energy technologies. It is one of the reactions that occurs during hydrogen production through water splitting, is used in rechargeable metal&#8211;air batteries, and plays a fundamental role in regenerative fuel cells. Therefore, there is an emerging need to develop new, active, stable, and cost-effective materials for OER. This review presents the latest research on various groups of materials, showing their potential to be used as OER electrocatalysts, as well as their shortcomings. Particular attention has been paid to metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) and their derivatives, as those materials offer coordinatively unsaturated sites, high density of transition metals, adjustable pore size, developed surface area, and the possibility to be modified and combined with other materials.</description>
      <author>M. Tr&#281;bala, Agata &#321;amacz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A molecular design strategy to enhance hydrogen evolution on platinum electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01754-4</link>
      <description>Kaiyue Zhao, N. Xiang, Yuqi Wang, Jinyu Ye, Zihan Jin, Linke Fu, Xiaoxia Chang, Dong Wang, Hai Xiao, Bingjun Xu, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409268246

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaiyue Zhao, N. Xiang, Yuqi Wang, Jinyu Ye, Zihan Jin, Linke Fu, Xiaoxia Chang, Dong Wang, Hai Xiao, Bingjun Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01754-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for predicting enantioselectivity in chiral phosphoric acid-catalyzed naphthyl-indole synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12039-025-02347-0</link>
      <description>R. A. Oshiya, Ayan Datta, Journal of Chemical Sciences. 137(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409269804

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. A. Oshiya, Ayan Datta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12039-025-02347-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Activity and Stability of Pt Nanoparticles Supported on Multiscale Porous Antimony Tin Oxide for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500232</link>
      <description>Li Hao, Muhammad Ajmal, Xinquan Wu, Shishi Zhang, Xiaokang Liu, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Ruijie Gao, Lun Pan, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409270370

                Abstract Pt nanoparticles dispersed on carbon supports (Pt/C) are the benchmark oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts in proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). However, their widespread application is hindered by severe stability degradation under high potentials and acidic environments, primarily due to carbon support corrosion. To address this challenge, a multiscale template&#8208;assisted method is proposed, combined with ethylene glycol reduction, to fabricate Pt nanoparticles supported onto multiscale porous conductive antimony tin oxides (Pt/PT&#8208;SSO). Both theoretical and experimental approaches have shown that the strong interaction between Pt and support markedly accelerates electron transfer and optimizes the adsorption strength of key intermediates on the Pt surface. Furthermore, the unique multiscale porous structure of support not only provides an ideal platform for the uniform dispersion of Pt nanoparticles but also greatly enhances confinement effect, effectively preventing Pt aggregation. As a result, the Pt/PT&#8208;SSO exhibits superior ORR activity and durability compared to commercial Pt/C catalysts. Specifically, its mass activity at 0.9 V (vs RHE) reaches 0.617 A mgPt&#8315;&#185;, which is twice that of Pt/C, while maintaining outstanding stability over 50 h. Notably, PEMFCs utilizing Pt/PT&#8208;SSO achieve a high power density of 1.173 W cm&#8315; 2 and retain 94.9% after 30,000 cycles of accelerated durability testing.</description>
      <author>Li Hao, Muhammad Ajmal, Xinquan Wu, Shishi Zhang, Xiaokang Liu, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Ruijie Gao, Lun Pan, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the prediction of TADF emitter properties using &#916;-machine learning: A hybrid semi-empirical and deep tensor neural network approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0263384</link>
      <description>R. Nikhitha, Anirban Mondal, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409270559

                This study presents a machine learning (ML)-augmented framework for accurately predicting excited-state properties critical to thermally activated delayed fluorescence (TADF) emitters. By integrating the computational efficiency of semi-empirical PPP+CIS theory with a &#916;-ML approach, the model overcomes the inherent limitations of PPP+CIS in predicting key properties, including singlet (S1) and triplet (T1) energies, singlet&#8211;triplet gaps (&#916;EST), and oscillator strength (f). The model demonstrated exceptional accuracy across datasets of varying sizes and diverse molecular features, notably excelling in predicting oscillator strength and &#916;EST values, including negative regions relevant to TADF molecules with inverted S1&#8211;T1 gaps. This work highlights the synergy between physics-inspired models and machine learning in accelerating the design of efficient TADF emitters, providing a foundation for future studies on complex systems and advanced functional materials.</description>
      <author>R. Nikhitha, Anirban Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0263384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial Growth of Molecular Graphene on Metal Surface Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qute.202400621</link>
      <description>Biyu Song, Xiamin Hao, Chenqiang Hua, Meimei Wu, Guoxiang Zhi, Wenjin Gao, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou, Advanced Quantum Technologies. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409270724

                Abstract Molecular graphene provides an attractive man&#8208;made artificial system to realize designer Dirac fermions with exotic properties and significant implications in electronics/spintronics, but its large&#8208;scale fabrication remains a challenge as the available approach involves molecule&#8208;by&#8208;molecule manipulation of CO on a metal surface using a scanning tunneling microscopy tip. Here, we propose the epitaxial growth of molecular graphene on metal surface alloy, where CO molecules could be naturally self&#8208;assembled into a hexagonal lattice. Via high&#8208;throughput first&#8208;principles calculations, the adsorption behaviors of CO on 30 surface alloys Cu 2 M (M represents the alloyed element) with a ()&#8208; R 30&#176; superstructure on Cu(111) is explored. By systematically analyzing the structures, energetic and electronic properties of the adsorbed systems with different CO coverages, three surface alloys, Cu 2 Zn, Cu 2 Ga, and Cu 2 Ge, on which molecular graphene can be spontaneously formed, are successfully screened out. Remarkably, the self&#8208;assembled molecular graphene is featured by an effective four&#8208;band model involving the molecular (, ) orbitals of CO on a hexagonal lattice, leading to quantum spin Hall effect. This work paves an avenue for the large&#8208;scale growth of artificial graphene, which should stimulate immediate interest among experimentalists in the synthesis, characterization, and implementation of topological states for dissipationless transport and quantum computing.</description>
      <author>Biyu Song, Xiamin Hao, Chenqiang Hua, Meimei Wu, Guoxiang Zhi, Wenjin Gao, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qute.202400621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the mechanism of methanol electrooxidation: a potential-dependent DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra01511a</link>
      <description>Wei Zhang, Biyi Huang, Yang Cui, Lifang Shen, Shubin Yan, RSC Advances. 15(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409272922

                GC-DFT simulations reveal that PtCu alloy reduces MER overpotential (0.7 V vs. Pt's 0.9 V) via enhanced methanol adsorption, weakened CO binding, and diversified pathways, advancing CO-tolerant bimetallic catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Wei Zhang, Biyi Huang, Yang Cui, Lifang Shen, Shubin Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra01511a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generator of Neural Network Potential for Molecular Dynamics: Constructing Robust and Accurate Potentials with Active Learning for Nanosecond-Scale Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01613</link>
      <description>Naoki Matsumura, Yuta Yoshimoto, Tamio Yamazaki, Tomohito Amano, Tomoyuki Noda, Naoki Ebata, Takatoshi Kasano, Yasufumi Sakai, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409272958

                Neural network potentials (NNPs) enable large-scale molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of systems containing &gt;10,000 atoms with the accuracy comparable to ab initio methods and play a crucial role in material studies. Although NNPs are valuable for short-duration MD simulations, maintaining the stability of long-duration MD simulations remains challenging due to the uncharted regions of the potential energy surface (PES). Currently, there is no effective methodology to address this issue. To overcome this challenge, we developed an automatic generator of robust and accurate NNPs based on an active learning (AL) framework. This generator provides a fully integrated solution encompassing initial data set creation, NNP training, evaluation, sampling of additional structures, screening, and labeling. Crucially, our approach uses a sampling strategy that focuses on generating unstable structures with short interatomic distances, combined with a screening strategy that efficiently samples these configurations based on interatomic distances and structural features. This approach greatly enhances the MD simulation stability, enabling nanosecond-scale simulations. We evaluated the performance of our NNP generator in terms of its MD simulation stability and physical properties by applying it to liquid propylene glycol (PG) and polyethylene glycol (PEG). The generated NNPs enable stable MD simulations of systems with &gt;10,000 atoms for 20 ns. The predicted physical properties, such as the density and self-diffusion coefficient, show excellent agreement with the experimental values. This work represents a remarkable advance in the generation of robust and accurate NNPs for organic materials, paving the way for long-duration MD simulations of complex systems.</description>
      <author>Naoki Matsumura, Yuta Yoshimoto, Tamio Yamazaki, Tomohito Amano, Tomoyuki Noda, Naoki Ebata, Takatoshi Kasano, Yasufumi Sakai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Water Electrolysis for Green Hydrogen Production with Material Engineering: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400258</link>
      <description>Ying Liu, Yuanyuan Qin, Dawei Yu, Haiyue Zhuo, Churong Ma, Kai Chen, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409273758

                Abstract Water electrolysis, a traditional and highly technology, is gaining significant attention due to the growing demand for renewable energy resources. It stands as a promising solution for energy conversion, offer substantial benefits in environmental protection and sustainable development efforts. The aim of this research is to provide a concise review of the current state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art in the field of water electrolysis, focusing on the principles of water splitting fundamental, recent advancements in catalytic materials, various advanced characterization methods and emerging electrolysis technology improvements. Moreover, the paper delves into the development trends of catalysts engineering for water electrolysis, providing insight on how to enhance the catalytic performance. With the advancement of technology and the reduction of costs, hydrogen production through water electrolysis is expected to assume a more significant role in future energy ecosystem. This paper not only synthesizes existing knowledge but also highlights emerging opportunities and potential advancements in this field, offering a clear roadmap for further research and innovation.</description>
      <author>Ying Liu, Yuanyuan Qin, Dawei Yu, Haiyue Zhuo, Churong Ma, Kai Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eliminating nanometer-scale asperities on metallic thin films through plasma modification processes studied by molecular dynamics and AFM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-92095-5</link>
      <description>Tomoyuki Tsuyama, Tatsuki Oyama, Y. Azuma, Hirotada Ohashi, Masahiro Irie, Ayumi Yamakawa, Shoko Uetake, Takayuki Konno, Takahiro Ukai, Kazuhiko Ochiai, Nobuyuki Iwaoka, Atsushi Hashimoto, Yoshishige Okuno, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409285818

                We report the effects of reducing surface asperity size at the nanometer scale on metallic surfaces by plasma-assisted surface modification processes using simulations and experiments. Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations were conducted by irradiating various inert gas ions (Ne, Ar, Kr, and Xe) onto a cobalt slab with nanoscale asperities on the surface. The MD simulations showed that as the atomic number of the inert gas increased the surface asperity size was reduced more efficiently, while the etching rate decreased. The dependencies of the scattering behaviors on the inert gas ions originated from the mass exchange between the working gas ions and the slab atoms. Atomic force microscopy and X-ray fluorescence measurements were performed on hard disk media subjected to the surface modification processes. These measurements experimentally demonstrated that the density of nanoscale asperities was reduced with a lower etching rate as the atomic number of the inert gas increased, consistent with the simulation results. Through this study, we clarified that heavier working gases were more effective in reducing surface asperity size without significantly reducing the thickness of the material, which can contribute to better control of surface morphologies at the nanometer scale.</description>
      <author>Tomoyuki Tsuyama, Tatsuki Oyama, Y. Azuma, Hirotada Ohashi, Masahiro Irie, Ayumi Yamakawa, Shoko Uetake, Takayuki Konno, Takahiro Ukai, Kazuhiko Ochiai, Nobuyuki Iwaoka, Atsushi Hashimoto, Yoshishige Okuno</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-92095-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-Tuned Surface Reconstruction Promotes Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125356</link>
      <description>Guiling Wu, Qianlin Chen, Jinrong Min, Feng Wang, Yan Zhao, Zhaoyang Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409301686

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guiling Wu, Qianlin Chen, Jinrong Min, Feng Wang, Yan Zhao, Zhaoyang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking design strategies for oxygen evolution reaction catalysts: Insights from a kinetic perspective via constrained ab initio molecular dynamics simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162357</link>
      <description>Dongyup Shin, Sang Soo Han, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409307402

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongyup Shin, Sang Soo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.162357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D Package&#8208;Integrated Platinum Catalyst with Robust Interactions for Enhanced Cathodic Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503111</link>
      <description>Huiting Niu, Yan Liu, Lei Huang, Lebin Cai, Chenfeng Xia, Ruijuan Qi, Yu Mao, Wei Guo, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409308107

                Abstract Durable electrocatalysts and optimal ionomer distribution in cathode catalyst layer (CCL) are crucial for the efficiency and lifetime of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), especially at high currents. This work presents a 1D package&#8208;integrated platinum (Pt) catalyst designed to optimize mass exchange and boost cathodic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The package&#8208;integrated Pt catalyst not only enhances the active site utilization, activity, and stability of Pt alloys but also optimizes the ionomer coverage and oxygen transport within the CCL. It shows superior performance with a mass activity of 1.33 A mg Pt &#8722;1 and only a 12 mV decay in half&#8208;wave potential after 30 000 cycles. Additionally, it delivers impressive catalytic performance (320 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0.8 V), mass transport polarization (0.632 V at 2000 mA cm &#8722;2 ), and low oxygen transport resistance (0.03 s cm &#8722;1 ) in hydrogen&#8208;air fuel cells. This package&#8208;integrated catalyst with robust anti&#8208;ionomer interference and impressive transport capability is of great significance for designing efficient and long&#8208;lasting PEMFC cathodes.</description>
      <author>Huiting Niu, Yan Liu, Lei Huang, Lebin Cai, Chenfeng Xia, Ruijuan Qi, Yu Mao, Wei Guo, Ziyun Wang, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on the recent mechanisms investigation of PFAS electrochemical oxidation degradation: mechanisms, DFT calculation, and pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenve.2025.1568542</link>
      <description>Gengyang Li, Mengyun Peng, Qingguo Huang, Ching&#8208;Hua Huang, Yongsheng Chen, Gary L. Hawkins, Ke Li, Frontiers in Environmental Engineering. 4(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409308265

                Per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) have drawn public concern recently due to their toxic properties and persistence in the environment, making it urgent to eliminate PFAS from contaminated water. Electrochemical oxidation (EO) has shown great promise for the destructive treatment of PFAS with direct electron transfer and hydroxyl radical (&#8901;OH)-mediated indirect reactions. One of the most popular electrodes is Magn&#233;li phase titanium suboxides. However, the degradation mechanisms of PFAS are still unsure and are under investigation now. The main methodology is the first-principal density functional theory (DFT) computation, which is recently used to explore the degradation mechanisms and interpret by-product formation during PFAS mineralization. From the literature review, the main applications of DFT computation for studying PFAS degradation mechanisms by EO include bond dissociation energy, absorption energy, activation energy, and overpotential &#951; for oxygen evolution reactions. The main degradation mechanisms and pathways of PFAS in the EO process include mass transfer, direct electron transfer, decarboxylation, peroxyl radical generation, hydroxylation, intramolecular rearrangement, and hydrolysis. In the recent 4 years, 11 papers performed DFT computation to explore the possible PFAS degradation mechanisms and pathways in the EO process. This paper&#8217;s objectives are to: 1) summarize the main degradation mechanisms of PFAS degradation in EO; 2) review the application of DFT computation for studying PFAS degradation mechanisms during EO; process; 3) review the possible degradation pathways of perfluorooctane sulfonoic acid (PFOS) and per-fluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) during EO process.</description>
      <author>Gengyang Li, Mengyun Peng, Qingguo Huang, Ching&#8208;Hua Huang, Yongsheng Chen, Gary L. Hawkins, Ke Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenve.2025.1568542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering 3d-Printed Molybdenum Carbide Catalysts for Selective Co2 Reduction to Co</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5211448</link>
      <description>Arturo Pajares, Mehmet Tanr&#305;verdi, Eduardo Couti&#241;o&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Jacob Andrade Arvizu, Maxim Guc, Pablo Guardia, H&#232;ctor Prats, Bart Michielsen, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409310095

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arturo Pajares, Mehmet Tanr&#305;verdi, Eduardo Couti&#241;o&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Jacob Andrade Arvizu, Maxim Guc, Pablo Guardia, H&#232;ctor Prats, Bart Michielsen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5211448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of bifunctional oxygen evolution/reduction electrocatalysts on g-C3N3 monolayer by a defect physics method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116135</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Liuming Yan, Chao Yang, Yanyan Qu, Aodi Zhang, Zhenzhen Feng, Wentao Wang, Pengfei Ou, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409315993

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Liuming Yan, Chao Yang, Yanyan Qu, Aodi Zhang, Zhenzhen Feng, Wentao Wang, Pengfei Ou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiSe synergistically enhancing FeNi bimetallic site catalysts for efficient bifunctional water electrolysis catalysts and mechanistic insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115108</link>
      <description>Zhiqiang Peng, H. Li, J. Jenny Li, Feng Ao, Yue Cheng, Kai Huang, Jun Yao, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao, Molecular Catalysis. 580(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409321916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiqiang Peng, H. Li, J. Jenny Li, Feng Ao, Yue Cheng, Kai Huang, Jun Yao, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media: from in situ characterization to rational design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.067</link>
      <description>Bo Sun, Haoyan Cheng, Kexing Song, Zhonghan Jiang, Changrui Shi, Hao Liang, Shuaiyu Ma, Hao Hu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409322908

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Sun, Haoyan Cheng, Kexing Song, Zhonghan Jiang, Changrui Shi, Hao Liang, Shuaiyu Ma, Hao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise modulation of nickel-molybdenum alloy (MoNi4)/molybdenum dioxide nanowires via a ternary nickel-cobalt-iron complex for enhanced electrochemical overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137560</link>
      <description>Peng Zuo, Fanfan Liu, Fuyan Zhao, Xiaofei Zhang, Yun Li, Kaiqin Xu, Fang Xiaowei, Zhi&#8208;wei Zhang, Yun Shen, Jinyun Liu, Yefeng Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409323446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Zuo, Fanfan Liu, Fuyan Zhao, Xiaofei Zhang, Yun Li, Kaiqin Xu, Fang Xiaowei, Zhi&#8208;wei Zhang, Yun Shen, Jinyun Liu, Yefeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Oxides as Promising Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.116550</link>
      <description>Jie Zhang, Junhua You, Yao Zhao, Tong Liu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409327872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Zhang, Junhua You, Yao Zhao, Tong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.116550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogenation of Mixed Ir&#8211;Ti Oxide: A Powerful Concept to Promote the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00588</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Matej Zlatar, Yuejun Wang, Phillip Timmer, Alexander Spriewald-Luciano, Lorena Glatthaar, Serhiy Cherevko, Herbert Over, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409329062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Matej Zlatar, Yuejun Wang, Phillip Timmer, Alexander Spriewald-Luciano, Lorena Glatthaar, Serhiy Cherevko, Herbert Over</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Electrochemical Activity of Pt/C Catalysts through Mild Ultraviolet Pulsed Laser Post Irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00223</link>
      <description>Manuel Matten, Norbert Koch, Adib Caidi, Ivan Radev, Thomas de Lange, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409332699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manuel Matten, Norbert Koch, Adib Caidi, Ivan Radev, Thomas de Lange, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The NOMAD mini-apps: A suite of kernels from ab initio electronic structure codes enabling co-design in high-performance computing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.3</link>
      <description>Isidre Mas Magre, Rogeli Grima Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a, Jos&#233; Julio Guti&#233;rrez Moreno, Open Research Europe. 4(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409333649

                This article introduces a suite of mini-applications (mini-apps) designed to optimise computational kernels in ab initio electronic structure codes. The suite is developed from flagship applications participating in the NOMAD Center of Excellence, such as the ELPA eigensolver library and the GW implementations of the exciting, Abinit, and FHI-aims codes. The mini-apps were identified by targeting functions that significantly contribute to the total execution time in the parent applications. This strategic selection allows for concentrated optimisation efforts. The suite is designed for easy deployment on various High-Performance Computing (HPC) systems, supported by an integrated CMake build system for straightforward compilation and execution. The aim is to harness the capabilities of emerging (post)exascale systems, which necessitate concurrent hardware and software development &#8212; a concept known as co-design. The mini-app suite serves as a tool for profiling and benchmarking, providing insights that can guide both software optimisation and hardware design. Ultimately, these developments will enable more accurate and efficient simulations of novel materials, leveraging the full potential of exascale computing in material science research.</description>
      <author>Isidre Mas Magre, Rogeli Grima Torres, Jos&#233; Mar&#237;a, Jos&#233; Julio Guti&#233;rrez Moreno</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/openreseurope.16920.3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Screening of Molecule/Polymer Photocatalysts for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01785</link>
      <description>Lei Shi, Alessandro Troisi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409335152

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Shi, Alessandro Troisi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Metal Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C Sites with Improved Stability for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500116</link>
      <description>Shiyang Liu, Md Raziun Bin Mamtaz, Jia Chen, Haijiao Lu, Shuhao Wang, Quentin Meyer, Chuan Zhao, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409335837

                Abstract Low&#8208;cost and durable hydrogen fuel cells are crucial for the success of the hydrogen economy. While Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts are amongst the most promising low&#8208;cost alternative to platinum (Pt) for the oxygen reduction reaction, their unsatisfactory durability is the grand challenge faced by the field due to iron demetallation, carbon corrosion and electrode collapse. Herein, a dual&#8208;metal single&#8208;atom Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst with superior stability (49% loss in peak power density) than Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts (66% loss) over 96 h of continuous operations in H 2 &#8211;O 2 fuel cells is reported. Advanced operando electrochemical and post&#8208;mortem physical measurements shed light on the underlying mechanism. The iron&#8211;manganese bond anchors the iron strongly in the Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C centre, which lowers the hydrogen peroxide yield as a result. Operando electrochemical measurements reveal a more stable triple&#8208;phase boundary environment for the Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst than for Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C. Specifically, a combination of cyclic voltammetry and impedance spectroscopy with the distribution of relaxation times reveals that the iron demetallation and carbon corrosion are respectively 20% and 30% slower for the Fe&#8211;Mn&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst than the Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst in hydrogen fuel cells. Altogether, this dual&#8208;metal site strategy paves the way for improving the stability of Pt&#8208;free catalysts for hydrogen fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Shiyang Liu, Md Raziun Bin Mamtaz, Jia Chen, Haijiao Lu, Shuhao Wang, Quentin Meyer, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Water in Green Carbon Science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00347</link>
      <description>Bo Peng, Kun Zhang, Yuhan Sun, Buxing Han, Mingyuan He, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409348887

                Within the context of green chemistry, the concept of green carbon science emphasizes carbon balance and recycling to address the challenge of achieving carbon neutrality. The fundamental processes in this field are oxidation and reduction, which often involve simple molecules such as CO2, CO, CH4, CHx, and H2O. Water plays a critical role in nearly all oxidation-reduction processes, and thus, it is a central focus of research in green carbon science. Water can act as a direct source of dihydrogen in reduction reactions or participate in oxidation reactions, frequently involving O-O coupling to produce hydrogen peroxide or dioxygen. At the atomic level, this coupling involves the statistically unfavorable proximity of two atoms, requiring optimization through a catalytic process influenced by two types of factors, as described by the authors. Extrinsic factors are related to geometrical and electronic criteria associated with the catalytic metal, involving its d-orbitals (or bands in the case of zerovalent metals and electrodes). Intrinsic factors are related to the coupling of oxygen atoms via their p-orbitals. At the mesoscopic or microscopic scale, the reaction medium typically consists of mixtures of lipophilic and hydrophilic phases with water, which may exist under supercritical conditions or as suspensions of microdroplets. These reactions predominantly occur at phase interfaces. A comprehensive understanding of the phenomena across these scales could facilitate improvements and even lead to the development of novel conversion processes.</description>
      <author>Bo Peng, Kun Zhang, Yuhan Sun, Buxing Han, Mingyuan He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monolayer Ytei for Photocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5213974</link>
      <description>Dan Mao, Rundong Wan, Shijie Wang, Ying Lei, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409349545

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Mao, Rundong Wan, Shijie Wang, Ying Lei, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5213974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Selectivity in Oxygen Electrocatalysis Using Chiral Nanoparticles as Electron-Spin Filters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03394</link>
      <description>Zixu Wang, Jinling Wan, Xuehao Sun, Lichao Sun, Shengli Chen, Qingfeng Zhang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409350393

                Controlling the electron spin of oxygen-containing intermediates is crucial for efficient oxygen electrocatalysis toward clean energy technologies such as fuel cells and water electrolysis. Current strategies for controlling the electron spins rely mainly on tuning the chemical structure of the oxygen electrocatalyst, which is often hardly achieved for metal and oxide electrocatalysts. The chiral-induced spin selectivity (CISS) effect, a significant discovery in chiral spintronics, represents an alternative approach for tuning the spin selectivity of oxygen electrocatalysts. Here we demonstrate the use of intrinsic chiral nanoparticles as electron-spin filters to tune the selectivity in oxygen electrocatalytic reactions. Chiral Au nanoparticles with a concave vortex cube structure were employed as the chiral substrate, exhibiting highly tunable optical chirality and intriguing CISS-like effect. As model systems, the catalytically active components such as Pt or Ni(OH)2 are overgrown onto chiral Au nanoparticles to construct the chiral hybrid electrocatalysts. Remarkably, both cases show chirality-dependent tunable activities over oxygen reduction/evolution reactions, respectively. The insights gained from this work not only shed light on the underlying mechanisms dictating the CISS-enhanced oxygen electrocatalysis by chiral nanoparticles but also provide an important knowledge framework that guides the rational design of chiral electrocatalysts toward oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Zixu Wang, Jinling Wan, Xuehao Sun, Lichao Sun, Shengli Chen, Qingfeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles insights into Ta-Nb ratio optimization of (CoCrNiMo)98Ta Nb medium-entropy alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417208</link>
      <description>Wen Deng, Tianyi Zhang, Jianlei Zhang, Hongxing Zheng, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409194816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Deng, Tianyi Zhang, Jianlei Zhang, Hongxing Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous Single-Crystalline Particles as Robust and Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18390</link>
      <description>Yong Wang, Yunpu Qin, Sijia Liu, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Shangqing Zhao, Jianfang Liu, Jie Wang, Yadong Liu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409264530

                The scarcity of iridium (Ir) limits its widespread use in acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, mesoporous single-crystalline spinel Co3O4 with atomically dispersed low-valence-state Ir has been developed to enable Ir's efficient and stable utilization. The surface Pourbaix diagram suggests that under acidic OER conditions, O* fully covers both Co3O4(111) and (110) surfaces, passivating Co sites but enhancing Co3O4's structural stability, a benefit further improved by Ir doping. Mesopores offer numerous loading sites for Ir single atoms (13.8 wt %), which activate the originally O*-passivated Co3O4(111) surface by creating high-intrinsic-activity Co-Ir bridge sites; meanwhile, Ir and Co leaching rates are reduced to about 1/4 and 1/5, respectively, compared to conventional Ir/Co3O4 catalysts. Our catalyst exhibits a low &#951;10 of 248 mV for over 100 h, showcasing its potential in water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Yong Wang, Yunpu Qin, Sijia Liu, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Shangqing Zhao, Jianfang Liu, Jie Wang, Yadong Liu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Material Characteristics with System Properties for Membrane-Based Direct Air Capture (m-DAC) Using Process Operability and Inverse Design Approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04553</link>
      <description>Vitor Gama, Deepanjali Roy, Fernando V. Lima, Oishi Sanyal, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409324074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vitor Gama, Deepanjali Roy, Fernando V. Lima, Oishi Sanyal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge-guided large language model for material science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.revmat.2025.100007</link>
      <description>Guanjie Wang, Jingjing Hu, Jian Zhou, Sen Liu, Qi Li, Zhimei Sun, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409204146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanjie Wang, Jingjing Hu, Jian Zhou, Sen Liu, Qi Li, Zhimei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.revmat.2025.100007</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
