<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 01:19:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally stimulated chirp in a pulsed QCL: Microscopic origins behind Fabry-Perot pattern drift</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2024.109618</link>
      <description>Evgeniia D. Cherotchenko, Ivan I. Vrubel, Alexander A. Pavlov, Anna S. Konanykhina, Ilya E. Rafailov, Roman G. Polozkov, V. V. Dudelev, G. S. Sokolovski&#301;, International Journal of Thermal Sciences. 210(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405632163

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Evgeniia D. Cherotchenko, Ivan I. Vrubel, Alexander A. Pavlov, Anna S. Konanykhina, Ilya E. Rafailov, Roman G. Polozkov, V. V. Dudelev, G. S. Sokolovski&#301;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2024.109618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e232" altimg="si37.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;X&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; reduction mechanism: Thermal vs electrochemical step</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145429</link>
      <description>Mohd Riyaz, Alexander Bagger, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405632928

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohd Riyaz, Alexander Bagger</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali metal cations act as homogeneous cocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction in aqueous electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01241-1</link>
      <description>Sang Gu Ji, Minho M. Kim, Man Ho Han, Junsic Cho, Yoosang Son, Young Yong Kim, Jaeyoung Jeong, Zee Hwan Kim, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, Nature Catalysis. 7(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405636810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sang Gu Ji, Minho M. Kim, Man Ho Han, Junsic Cho, Yoosang Son, Young Yong Kim, Jaeyoung Jeong, Zee Hwan Kim, Keun Hwa Chae, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01241-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alternative Electrocatalysts: Exploring Quantum Dots and Transition Metal MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674664-00447</link>
      <description>Abid Ullah, Shahbaz Ahmad, Muhammad Arif, M. Egilmez, Basharat Hussain, Muhammad Raheel Khan, Amjad Hussain, Ayesha Samreen, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405647175

                Hydrogen emerges as a pivotal clean and versatile energy carrier amid global energy challenges, urging a shift towards renewable hydrogen production. The efficiency of the electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) hinges on catalyst choice, ambient conditions, and electrolyte pH. In transitioning away from costly and scarce catalysts like Pt or Ru, researchers explore Earth-abundant alternatives, notably transition metal-based quantum dots (QDs) and MXenes. QDs offer high surface area and customizable properties, while MXenes demonstrate exceptional conductivity and surface area. QDs, despite challenges such as agglomeration, prove effective when engineered into composites. MXenes, with their unique stacked structure and chemical robustness, hold promise for HER catalysis. As discussed, QDs and MXenes exhibit schematic HER representations, emphasizing their potential as catalysts for sustainable hydrogen production and their adaptability to span diverse fields, offering scalable solutions towards a renewable energy future.</description>
      <author>Abid Ullah, Shahbaz Ahmad, Muhammad Arif, M. Egilmez, Basharat Hussain, Muhammad Raheel Khan, Amjad Hussain, Ayesha Samreen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674664-00447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674664-00423</link>
      <description>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Subrata Kundu, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405647518

                Hydrogen is regarded as a vital resource for the advancement of renewable energy technologies. Electrocatalytic water splitting has emerged as a viable technique for producing ultra-pure hydrogen. The electrocatalyst, which can catalyze the electrochemical process to decrease the overpotential by increasing the current density, is critical to the effectiveness of this approach. Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) have become recognized as possible electrocatalysts in recent years due to their exposed surface active sites, evenly distributed interconnected pore structure, and adjustable shape. Thus, the significance of homogeneous and heterogeneous MOFs and their derivatives for the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution process (HER) is summarized in this chapter. The chapter begins with an overview of the fundamentals of the electrocatalytic HER, after which the importance of various transition metal-based pristine MOFs and their derivatives towards the HER is examined. However, there is still plenty of room for improvement given their sub-par intrinsic activity and weak conductivity. Various MOF-derived composites, as well as new methodologies and procedures, are given to solve intrinsic activity and conductivity issues, emphasizing progress in MOF-based materials for a more effective HER electrocatalyst in large-scale hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674664-00423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insight on the delicate regulation of coordination environments for carbon-nitrogen-supported single-atom metals for OER and ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114784</link>
      <description>Xiao-Kuan Wu, Junan Gao, Zhao Hong, Zhigang Lei, Jie Zhang, Molecular Catalysis. 572(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405660232

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao-Kuan Wu, Junan Gao, Zhao Hong, Zhigang Lei, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigations of hydroxyl-functionalized iron-doped phthalocyanine photocatalyst for efficient CO2 reduction to methanol and methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.121121</link>
      <description>Thangaraj Thiruppathiraja, Baker Rhimi, Na Zhang, Min Zhou, Weidong Shi, Zhifeng Jiang, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405662603

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thangaraj Thiruppathiraja, Baker Rhimi, Na Zhang, Min Zhou, Weidong Shi, Zhifeng Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.121121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surficial Engineering of Cathodic Protection Strategy via P&#8208;Doped NiCuV Monolithic Electrode for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400815</link>
      <description>Huizhen Han, Shiyi Tao, Yu Sun, Yuxin Luo, Yulian Zhao, Somnath Mukherjee, Yi Ma, Xin Bo, Zenglin Wang, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405674677

                Abstract The concentrated alkaline passivates the monolithic electrode for electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in the alkaline water electrolysis (AWE) industry. Herein, a surface engineering of cathodic protection via one&#8208;step co&#8208;electrodeposition of P into NiCuV is presented and the achieved monolithic electrode exhibits an enhanced electrochemical catalytic behavior and constant durability with a feedback potential of &#8722;0.75 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) under an extremely high current density of 1A cm &#8722;2 for more than 270 h in alkaline media. The strategy of cathodic protection optimises the charge density redistribution by forming a phosphate surface layer. This preserves the particular metal (alloy) phase from oxidation while also modulating the heterarchical porous structure through P incorporation. Furthermore, an anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) with the NiCuVP serving as the HER catalyst and the NiFeCr LDH as the OER catalyst is constructed, which exhibits a current density of 912 mA cm &#8722;2 at 2 V at 80 &#176;C with 30 wt.% KOH electrolytes. The resultant factors for activity and durability such as the electrochemical specific area, redox behaviors and surface hydrophilicity are also systematically discussed. This research presents a practical protocol for the anticorrosion and active enhancement of AWE and AEMWE cathodes.</description>
      <author>Huizhen Han, Shiyi Tao, Yu Sun, Yuxin Luo, Yulian Zhao, Somnath Mukherjee, Yi Ma, Xin Bo, Zenglin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400815</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic role of nickel-chromium heterogeneous selenides in the efficient stabilisation of the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178250</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Ruixue Sun, Ting Li, Si Hui, Haoyu Luo, Gang Lv, Jifang Fu, Li Wang, Zhiqin Peng, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405679873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Ruixue Sun, Ting Li, Si Hui, Haoyu Luo, Gang Lv, Jifang Fu, Li Wang, Zhiqin Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing local CO2 availability via amorphous Bi2O3 enable efficient and stable photocatalytic C2H6 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158854</link>
      <description>Qingqing Chen, Jiaxin Jiang, Yan Wu, Jiaojiao Fang, Ning L&#252;, Gang Wang, Junjie Mao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405686146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingqing Chen, Jiaxin Jiang, Yan Wu, Jiaojiao Fang, Ning L&#252;, Gang Wang, Junjie Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Effective Catalysts for Hydrogen Production: A Performance Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.134257</link>
      <description>A. Ya&#287;mur G&#246;ren, Mert Temiz, Do&#287;an Erdemir, &#304;brahim Din&#231;er, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405686151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Ya&#287;mur G&#246;ren, Mert Temiz, Do&#287;an Erdemir, &#304;brahim Din&#231;er</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.134257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The influence of multiple factors on the PtCo3 catalyst characteristics during the ORR process in proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.122263</link>
      <description>Chuanqi Luo, Kechuang Wan, Jue Wang, Bing Li, Daijun Yang, Pingwen Ming, Cunman Zhang, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405695428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuanqi Luo, Kechuang Wan, Jue Wang, Bing Li, Daijun Yang, Pingwen Ming, Cunman Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.122263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wannier-function software ecosystem for materials simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/revmodphys.96.045008</link>
      <description>Antimo Marrazzo, Sophie Beck, Elena R. Margine, Nicola Marzari, Arash A. Mostofi, Junfeng Qiao, Ivo Souza, Stepan S. Tsirkin, Jonathan R. Yates, Giovanni Pizzi, Reviews of Modern Physics. 96(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405717922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Antimo Marrazzo, Sophie Beck, Elena R. Margine, Nicola Marzari, Arash A. Mostofi, Junfeng Qiao, Ivo Souza, Stepan S. Tsirkin, Jonathan R. Yates, Giovanni Pizzi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/revmodphys.96.045008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of electron&#8211;proton correlation functionals for vibrational spectra of shared-proton systems by constrained nuclear-electronic orbital density functional theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0243086</link>
      <description>Yuzhuo Yang, Yuzhe Zhang, Yang Yang, Xi Xu, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405725332

                Proton transfer plays a crucial role in various chemical and biological processes. A major theoretical challenge in simulating proton transfer arises from the quantum nature of the proton. The constrained nuclear-electronic orbital (CNEO) framework was recently developed to efficiently and accurately account for nuclear quantum effects, particularly quantum nuclear delocalization effects, in quantum chemistry calculations and molecular dynamics simulations. In this paper, we systematically investigate challenging proton transfer modes in a series of shared-proton systems using CNEO density functional theory (CNEO-DFT), focusing on evaluating existing electron&#8211;proton correlation functionals. Our results show that CNEO-DFT accurately describes proton transfer vibrational modes and significantly outperforms conventional DFT. The inclusion of the epc17-2 electron&#8211;proton correlation functional in CNEO-DFT produces similar performance to that without electron&#8211;proton correlations, while the epc17-1 functional yields less accurate results, comparable with conventional DFT. These findings hold true for both asymmetrical and symmetrical shared-proton systems. Therefore, until a more accurate electron&#8211;proton correlation functional is developed, we currently recommend performing vibrational spectrum calculations using CNEO-DFT without electron&#8211;proton correlation functionals.</description>
      <author>Yuzhuo Yang, Yuzhe Zhang, Yang Yang, Xi Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0243086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Coordination Environment of Cu-Embedded Mo&lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (&lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; = S, Se, and Te) Monolayers for Electrocatalytic Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;: Unveiling the Origin of Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03564</link>
      <description>Thamarainathan Doulassiramane, R. Padmanaban, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405735995

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is a promising approach to alleviating global warming and emerging energy crises. Yet, the CO2RR efficiency is impeded by the need for electrocatalysts with good selectivity and efficiency. Recently, single-atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted much attention in electrocatalysis and are more efficient than traditional metal-based catalysts. In this study, we modeled a Cu single atom embedded on MoX2 (X = Se and Te) monolayer with a single chalcogen (X) vacancy as SAC. Employing the dispersion-corrected density functional theory (DFT-D3) method, the electrocatalytic CO2RR activity of the Cu-MoX2 SACs is systematically investigated through significant descriptors, such as the Gibbs free energy change, charge density difference, and COHP analysis. The stability of SACs, CO2 adsorption configurations, and all possible reaction pathways for the formation of C1 products (HCOOH, CO, CH3OH, and CH4) were examined. All of the Cu-MoX2 SACs are stable and show high catalytic selectivity for the CO2RR by significantly suppressing the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). We found that the catalytic activity is mainly due to the level of antibonding states filling between the Cu atom and *OCHOH intermediate. Among the C1 products, CH4 is selectively produced in all three SACs. Notably, there is a decrease in the limiting potential (UL) when X changes from S to Te in Cu-MoX2. Among these three SACs, Cu-MoTe2 SAC is the most promising catalyst for reducing CO2 to CH4, with as low as UL of &#8722;0.34 V vs RHE. Our results demonstrate that the local coordination environment in SACs has a significant impact on the catalytic activity of CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Thamarainathan Doulassiramane, R. Padmanaban</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress on noble metal-transition metal carbide support catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118903</link>
      <description>Yang Yang, Huijuan Zhang, Miaomiao Yu, Jiangyu Luo, Yuhua Xue, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405738356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Yang, Huijuan Zhang, Miaomiao Yu, Jiangyu Luo, Yuhua Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual action of non-metal doped C2N and Ti3C2T2 heterojunction enhances the catalytic activity of electrochemical simultaneous oxidation of hydrogen peroxide and peroxymonosulfate:A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120698</link>
      <description>Yuxin Zhou, Yanru Huo, Yuhui Ma, Nuan Wen, Qingyuan Gu, Maoxia He, Environmental Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405738889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Zhou, Yanru Huo, Yuhui Ma, Nuan Wen, Qingyuan Gu, Maoxia He</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.120698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive review on carbon capturing materials and processes for sustainable Development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101783</link>
      <description>Yatish Singla, Avinash Thakur, Dhiraj Sud, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405739733

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yatish Singla, Avinash Thakur, Dhiraj Sud</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A computational study on MNX3 transition metal dichalcogenides for the alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105704</link>
      <description>Y.C. Zhou, Chongchong Liu, Jiacheng Li, Fang Xue, Gang Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405741165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y.C. Zhou, Chongchong Liu, Jiacheng Li, Fang Xue, Gang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105704</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Assisted Screening of Hexagonal 2D van der Waals Bilayers for Photocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05495</link>
      <description>Arooba Kanwal, Abdul Jalil, Syed Raza Ali Raza, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405742458

                From the photoelectric effect to the development of contemporary photocatalysts, the hunt for efficient energy conversion has been a tale of invention and discovery. Since 1972, water-splitting photocatalysis has evolved as an effective strategy for advancing toward sustainable energy. The van der Waals (vdW) heterostructures, formed by the vertical stacking of two distinct 2D materials, exhibit unique electronic properties. The weak vdW interactions tend to provide the benefit of efficient carrier separation, thus making them promising candidates for photocatalysis. However, analyzing all possible combinations of 2D materials is impractical through traditional approaches, necessitating the development of predictive models to automate and accelerate the quest. Herein, we propose a hybrid approach using machine learning (ML) in conjugation with first-principles calculations to predict the properties of hexagonal vdW bilayers for application in photocatalysis. Our ML workflow comprises the following major steps: (1) constructing a vast material space of bilayers and their descriptors using a 2D material database, (2) labeling a diverse set of bilayers using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, (3) training the supervised ML models on a labeled data set for binding energy, interlayer distance, band gap, work function, and band edges of heterostructures, (4) evaluating the performance of models on the validation set, and (5) predicting the properties of the unlabeled data set and screening the bilayers feasible for overall water-splitting (OWS) photocatalysis. The computational framework presented here tends to establish the relationship between 2D monolayers and vdW bilayers. Our findings highlight the potential of this approach in accelerating the search for novel photocatalysts by efficiently and accurately predicting their properties, thereby contributing to the broader goal of sustainable energy production.</description>
      <author>Arooba Kanwal, Abdul Jalil, Syed Raza Ali Raza</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the critical roles of metal dissolution electrodeposition in enhancing oxygen evolution reaction activity of Fe&#8211;NiOOH electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.317</link>
      <description>Jaewon Lee, JeongEun Yoo, Kiyoung Lee, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 100(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405743617

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaewon Lee, JeongEun Yoo, Kiyoung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced efficiency and durability of nickel sulfide catalyst integrated with reduced graphene oxide: Exploring hierarchically porous structures for methanol oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.285</link>
      <description>Mehdi Salmi, Nabil Khossossi, Yousra Boudad, Charafeddine Jama, Fouad Bentiss, Zaina Zaroual, Sanae El Ghachtouli, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 100(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405743802

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mehdi Salmi, Nabil Khossossi, Yousra Boudad, Charafeddine Jama, Fouad Bentiss, Zaina Zaroual, Sanae El Ghachtouli</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous porosity bimetallic phosphide FeP/CoP/CP as an efficient electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.236092</link>
      <description>Meilian Gao, Siwen Tang, Pingping Gao, Ting Lei, Ren Zhong-ping, Geping Yin, Yong Du, Journal of Power Sources. 630(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405744150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meilian Gao, Siwen Tang, Pingping Gao, Ting Lei, Ren Zhong-ping, Geping Yin, Yong Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.236092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Criteria for Active and Selective Catalysts in the Nitrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00058</link>
      <description>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Kai S. Exner, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405746625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the production distribution in Ni-Cu nanoparticle mediated nitrile hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.179</link>
      <description>Zihan Lv, Zeng Hong, Da Ke, Chao Qian, Xinzhi Chen, Shaodong Zhou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405747184

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihan Lv, Zeng Hong, Da Ke, Chao Qian, Xinzhi Chen, Shaodong Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Melamine-Driven Solvation Effect Promotes Oxygen Reduction on a Platinum Catalyst: Machine Learning-Aided Free Energy Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03437</link>
      <description>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Saori Minami, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405749721

                The modification of Pt surfaces with organic compounds like melamine enhances oxygen reduction reaction activity and catalyst durability. Through first-principles free energy calculations utilizing thermodynamic integration and finite-temperature molecular dynamics, enhanced by machine learning force fields for efficient sampling of nanosecond-scale interfacial water fluctuations and incorporating corrections to accurately reproduce first-principles free energies, we demonstrate that melamine destabilizes OH adsorbates, facilitating their removal and enhancing catalytic activity. Unlike alloys, where OH destabilization is driven by changes in electronic structure and surface strain, melamine disrupts hydrogen bonding between OH and interfacial water. Structural and vibrational analyses reveal that melamine alters the water solvation structure, which is evident in modified radial distribution functions and a blue shift in the O&#8211;H stretching vibrations. These findings indicate that manipulating interfacial solvation with organic compounds could be a promising approach to enhance catalytic activity without compromising durability.</description>
      <author>Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Saori Minami</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant-Tuned Restructuring Kinetic for the Formation of Heterophase-Confined Metal-Nonmetal Diatomic Sites for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03060</link>
      <description>Xinyi Li, Feiyan Liu, Wenting Lu, Huafeng Fan, Meiling Xiao, Xiaoqiang Cui, Lu Li, Xiaoxin Zou, Weitao Zheng, Xiao Zhao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405751831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyi Li, Feiyan Liu, Wenting Lu, Huafeng Fan, Meiling Xiao, Xiaoqiang Cui, Lu Li, Xiaoxin Zou, Weitao Zheng, Xiao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The &lt;i&gt;On&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;Off&lt;/i&gt; pH-Dependent Electrocatalytic Activity of the Perfluorinated Iron Phthalocyanine for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Electrochemical Hardness as a Reactivity Descriptor: Experimental and Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06957</link>
      <description>Luis Acu&#241;a-Saavedra, Ana Mar&#237;a M&#233;ndez&#8208;Torres, Gloria C&#225;rdenas&#8208;Jir&#243;n, Rub&#233;n O&#241;ate, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Allende, Ricardo Venegas, Roberto Bernal, Francisco Melo, Elizabeth Imbarack, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Ingrid Ponce, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405755151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luis Acu&#241;a-Saavedra, Ana Mar&#237;a M&#233;ndez&#8208;Torres, Gloria C&#225;rdenas&#8208;Jir&#243;n, Rub&#233;n O&#241;ate, Benjam&#237;n S&#225;nchez-Allende, Ricardo Venegas, Roberto Bernal, Francisco Melo, Elizabeth Imbarack, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Ingrid Ponce</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the influence of coexistence of Zn vacancies (VZn) and H interstices (Hi) on the photoelectrocatalytic performance of wurtzite ZnO (001) monolayer: Li/Na/K</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113981</link>
      <description>Gang Zhang, Qingyu Hou, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma, Riguleng Si, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405757090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gang Zhang, Qingyu Hou, Zhenchao Xu, Wen Ma, Riguleng Si</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating photocatalytic H2O2 rate over inter-molecular Z-scheme heterojunction via dual production paths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115192</link>
      <description>Yaodan Cao, Y. C. Zhai, Wenwen Lv, Hongyan Liu, J. Zhuo, Shouchun Ma, Maoquan Wu, Wanting Hui, Wenqi Ding, Tongjie Yao, Jiaxu Zhang, Jie Wu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405761097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaodan Cao, Y. C. Zhai, Wenwen Lv, Hongyan Liu, J. Zhuo, Shouchun Ma, Maoquan Wu, Wanting Hui, Wenqi Ding, Tongjie Yao, Jiaxu Zhang, Jie Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional metal&#8211;organic frameworks with dual active sites for electrochemical CO2 reduction: A computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131275</link>
      <description>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405775281

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.131275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Ru&#8211;B&#8211;Cr Moieties to Activate the Ru Site for Acidic Water Electrolysis under Industrial-Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c05113</link>
      <description>Weimo Li, Linfeng Zhang, Lipo Ma, Jiawei Wang, Ruikai Qi, Yang Pang, Meijiao Xu, Chengji Zhao, Ce Wang, Mingbin Gao, Xiaofeng Lu, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405775903

                Developing highly efficient non-iridium-based active sites for acidic water splitting is still a huge challenge. Herein, unique Ru&#8211;B&#8211;Cr moieties have been constructed in RuO2 nanofibers (NFs) to activate Ru sites for water electrolysis, which overcomes the bottleneck of RuO2-based catalysts usually possessing low activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and poor stability for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The fabricated Cr, B-doped RuO2 NFs exhibit low overpotentials of 205 and 379 mV for acidic HER and OER at 1 A cm&#8211;2 with outstanding stability lasting 1000 and 188 h, respectively. The assembled acidic electrolyzer also possesses great hydrogen production efficiency and durability at a high current density. Experimental and theoretical explorations reveal that the formation of Ru&#8211;B&#8211;Cr moieties effectively optimizes the atomic configurations and modulates the adsorption/desorption free energy of reaction intermediates to achieve exceptional HER and OER performance.</description>
      <author>Weimo Li, Linfeng Zhang, Lipo Ma, Jiawei Wang, Ruikai Qi, Yang Pang, Meijiao Xu, Chengji Zhao, Ce Wang, Mingbin Gao, Xiaofeng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c05113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A computational survey of layered mixed phases Mn1&#8722;xNixPS3 for water splitting: Modulation of the band gap and the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.364</link>
      <description>Nicol&#225;s Forero-Correa, Carolina Aliaga, Evgenia Spodine, Catalina Cort&#233;s, Tatiana G&#243;mez, Javiera Cabezas-Escares, Francisco Mu&#241;oz, Carlos C&#225;rdenas, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 99(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405782916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicol&#225;s Forero-Correa, Carolina Aliaga, Evgenia Spodine, Catalina Cort&#233;s, Tatiana G&#243;mez, Javiera Cabezas-Escares, Francisco Mu&#241;oz, Carlos C&#225;rdenas</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au atomic clusters on MoS2 nanosheets for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105691</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Tian, Lei Hou, Wei Pei, Xueke Yu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405790966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Tian, Lei Hou, Wei Pei, Xueke Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational studies on transition metal and nitrogen atoms co-doped fullerene as an efficient electrocatalyst for nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-024-02443-w</link>
      <description>Faiza Shafiq, Lei Yang, Weihua Zhu, Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405795555

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faiza Shafiq, Lei Yang, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-024-02443-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing localized surface plasmon resonance and hydrogen spillover effects on AgPt NPs/d-Siloxene heterostructure for enhanced electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134178</link>
      <description>Yixin Yang, Zhi&#8208;Xin Liao, Cuicui Du, Jun&#8208;Feng Qin, Min Hong, Xiaohua Zhang, Jinhua Chen, Fuel. 385(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405800079

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yixin Yang, Zhi&#8208;Xin Liao, Cuicui Du, Jun&#8208;Feng Qin, Min Hong, Xiaohua Zhang, Jinhua Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of In&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ru&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Alloys for Efficient Electrocatalytic Reduction of Nitrate to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06598</link>
      <description>Qingchao Fang, M. T. Nasir, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Xuxin Kang, Yun Han, Cheng Yan, Anthony P. O&#8217;Mullane, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405801950

                The electrochemical reduction of nitrate to ammonia is considered a feasible strategy to address the imbalance of the global nitrogen cycle by eliminating N-containing pollutants in wastewater while producing ammonia in a sustainable way. In this work, we systematically investigate the reduction of nitrate to ammonia on p-block indium (In), noble metal ruthenium (Ru), and their alloys (InRu3, In3Ru). We found that pure In and Ru candidates exhibit various performances for nitrate reduction with low limiting potentials for the potential-determining step of &#8722;0.31 V and &#8722;0.14 V, respectively. However, the incorporation of In into Ru to create alloys leads to excellent activity for the reduction of nitrate to ammonia. Ammonia production on InRu3 and In3Ru alloys demonstrates higher catalytic activity and selectivity as the byproducts of NO2 and NO can be inhibited, while the parasitic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) can also be significantly suppressed. Our work not only proposes efficient electrocatalysts for nitrate reduction but also provides a new strategy for the rational design of alloy catalysts for improved catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Qingchao Fang, M. T. Nasir, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Xuxin Kang, Yun Han, Cheng Yan, Anthony P. O&#8217;Mullane, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electrical Double Layer in Electrocatalytic Reactions: Fundamentals, Characterizations and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actphy.2024.100041</link>
      <description>Xueting Cao, Shuangshuang Cha, Ming Gong, Acta Physico-Chimica Sinica. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405802144

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xueting Cao, Shuangshuang Cha, Ming Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actphy.2024.100041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique Cu+/Cu0 active-site switches in Cu-loaded g-C3N4 nanosheets for efficient photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.12.010</link>
      <description>Dongxiao Wen, Nan Wang, Jiahe Peng, Tetsuro Majima, Jizhou Jiang, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405802199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongxiao Wen, Nan Wang, Jiahe Peng, Tetsuro Majima, Jizhou Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.12.010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights into the adjustable electronic buffering effect of C60 under electric fields for single-atom Cu catalysis in CO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115054</link>
      <description>Lei-Xian Chen, Zi-Yang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, W. P. Wang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405802485

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei-Xian Chen, Zi-Yang Qiu, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, W. P. Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox photocatalysis CuFe-BTC for nitrate reduction and formaldehyde oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158995</link>
      <description>Huang Xu, Kai-Yin Wu, Fei Yang, Rui Fu, Yunfei Ji, Wei Kong, Chao Su, Beibei Xiao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405812911

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huang Xu, Kai-Yin Wu, Fei Yang, Rui Fu, Yunfei Ji, Wei Kong, Chao Su, Beibei Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity-Drop of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in LiNO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Based &#8220;Hydronium-in-Salt&#8221; Acidic Electrolytes on Platinum Enables Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13117</link>
      <description>Cheolmin Park, Min Young Seo, Taesung Kwon, Ji-Yoon Kim, Ki Min Nam, YongJoo Kim, Jinho Chang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405741914

                The electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction (NO3&#8211;RR) involves multiple hydrogenation and deoxygenation steps, which compete with the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Therefore, NO3&#8211;RR driven in acidic media is challenging in spite of advantageous fast hydrogen transfers in its elementary steps. The findings presented in this article first demonstrate that the NO3&#8211;RR is significantly activated even in acidic lithium nitrate solutions at LiNO3 concentrations exceeding 6 m on a Pt electrode (the highly effective catalyst for HER) by the formation of a "hydronium-in-salt" electrolyte (HISE), a new type of aqueous high concentration salt electrolyte. The observed enhancement of NO3&#8211;RR while the suppression of HER-activity in the LiNO3 based HISE was verified by scanning electrochemical microscopy, electrochemical impedance spectroscopy, UV&#8211;vis/IR spectroscopy, and molecular dynamics simulations. The formation of a HISE in acidic LiNO3 solutions contrasts with that of a "water-in-salt" electrolyte in LiTFSI with the same concentration. The mechanism of NO3&#8211;RR activation in a HISE suggests facilitated proton-coupled electron transfers (PCETs) from H3O+ to NO3&#8211; and subsequent reactive intermediates owing to the proximity between the two ions induced by the unique solvation structure blended with all ions together (Li+ + NO3&#8211; + H3O+). In contrast, all the ions are separately hydrated at low concentrations of LiNO3 electrolytes. On the other hand, PCET from H2O to NO3&#8211; in a high concentration LiNO3 electrolyte (e.g., 9 m) is not kinetically preferred, probably owing to the slow dissociation kinetics of H2O, and therefore, H2O reduction is not suppressed by the NO3&#8211;RR.</description>
      <author>Cheolmin Park, Min Young Seo, Taesung Kwon, Ji-Yoon Kim, Ki Min Nam, YongJoo Kim, Jinho Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Thermal Stability Challenges in Top&#8208;Emission OLEDs: The Role of Buffer Layer in Preventing Pixel Shrinkage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202402832</link>
      <description>Seung Ju Ok, Thi Na Le, Ji Hee Son, Seung Yong Song, Min Chul Suh, Advanced Optical Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405820617

                Abstract This study introduces a strategic buffer layer approach to mitigate thermal&#8208;induced pixel shrinkage in top&#8208;emission organic light&#8208;emitting diodes (TEOLEDs), enhancing both thermal stability and efficiency. A new cathode composed of binary alloy from silver (Ag) and copper (Cu) is developed for their moderately high binding energy, improving film uniformity and boosting optical and electrical performance. High surface energy metals, aluminum (Al) and Cu are employed as buffer layers to regulate the growth mechanism, resulting in an exceptionally smooth cathode film. The optimal device is designed by incorporating a bilayer electron injection layer consisting of lithium fluoride (LiF) and ytterbium (Yb) along with the buffer layer. The TEOLEDs achieved an impressive efficiency of 178 cd A &#8722;1 and luminance of 247,000 cd m &#8722; 2 while demonstrating superior thermal stability, with the absence of cathode shrinkage after 240 h at 85 &#176;C. This stability is attributed to the suppression of thermal diffusion and aggregation, facilitated by the high surface energy buffer layer and innovative cathode compositions employed.</description>
      <author>Seung Ju Ok, Thi Na Le, Ji Hee Son, Seung Yong Song, Min Chul Suh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202402832</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
