<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 01:27:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling High&#8208;Entropy Core with Rh Shell for Efficient pH&#8208;Universal Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403353</link>
      <description>Min Wei, Yuyan Sun, Junyu Zhang, Jianrong Zeng, Jike Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401844907

                Abstract Constructing high&#8208;entropy alloys (HEAs) with core&#8211;shell (CS) nanostructure is efficient for enhancing catalytic activity. However, it is extremely challenging to incorporate the CS structure with HEAs. Herein, PtCoNiMoRh@Rh CS nanoparticles (PtCoNiMoRh@Rh) with &#8764;5.7 nm for pH&#8208;universal hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are reported for the first time. The PtCoNiMoRh@Rh just require 9.1, 24.9, and 17.1 mV to achieve &#8722;10 mA cm &#8722;2 in acid, neutral, and alkaline electrolyte, and the corresponding mass activity are 5.8, 2.79, and 91.8 times higher than that of Rh/C. Comparing to PtCoNiMoRh nanoparticles, the PtCoNiMoRh@Rh exhibit excellent HER activity attributed to the decrease of Rh 4d especially 4d 5/2 unoccupied state induced by the multi&#8208;active sites in HEA, as well as the synergistic effect in Rh shell and HEA core. Theorical calculation exhibits that Rh&#8208;d yz , d x2 , and d xz orbitals experience a negative shift with shell thickness increasing. The HEAs with CS structure would facilitate the rational design of high&#8208;performance HEAs catalysts.</description>
      <author>Min Wei, Yuyan Sun, Junyu Zhang, Jianrong Zeng, Jike Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tosr: Create the Tree of Science from WoS and Scopus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5530/jscires.13.2.36</link>
      <description>Sebasti&#225;n Robledo, Luis Eduardo Pel&#225;ez Valencia, Martha Zuluaga, &#211;scar Echeverri, Jorge William Arboleda Valencia, Journal of Scientometric Research. 13(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401845777

                Sebastian Robledo1, Luis Valencia2, Martha Zuluaga1, Oscar Arbelaez Echeverri3 and Jorge W. Arboleda Valencia45 Author informationPDFCitations 1Direcci&#243;n Acad&#233;mica, Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Sede de La Paz, Cesar, COLOMBIA 2Centro de Bioinform&#225;tica y Biolog&#237;a Computacional de Colombia &#8211; BIOS, COLOMBIA 3Core of Science, IRELAND 4FITOBIOL, Instituto de Biolog&#237;a, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales, Universidad de</description>
      <author>Sebasti&#225;n Robledo, Luis Eduardo Pel&#225;ez Valencia, Martha Zuluaga, &#211;scar Echeverri, Jorge William Arboleda Valencia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5530/jscires.13.2.36</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular dynamics of liquid&#8211;electrode interface by integrating &lt;scp&gt;Coulomb&lt;/scp&gt; interaction into universal neural network potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27487</link>
      <description>Kaoru Hisama, Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Michihisa Koyama, Journal of Computational Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401851483

                Abstract Computational understanding of the liquid&#8211;electrode interface faces challenges in efficiently incorporating reactive force fields and electrostatic potentials within reasonable computational costs. Although universal neural network potentials (UNNPs), representing pretrained machine learning interatomic potentials, are emerging, current UNNP models lack explicit treatment of Coulomb potentials, and methods for integrating additional charges on the electrode remain to be established. We propose a method to analyze liquid&#8211;electrode interfaces by integrating a UNNP, known as the preferred potential, with Coulomb potentials using the ONIOM method. This approach extends the applicability of UNNPs to electrode&#8211;liquid interface systems. Through molecular dynamics simulations of graphene&#8211;water and graphene oxide (GO)&#8211;water interfaces, we demonstrate the effectiveness of our method. Our findings emphasize the necessity of incorporating long&#8208;range Coulomb potentials into the water potential to accurately describe water polarization at the interface. Furthermore, we observe that functional groups on the GO electrode influence both polarization and capacitance.</description>
      <author>Kaoru Hisama, Gerardo Valadez Huerta, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key role of nonprecious oxygen-evolving active site in NiOOH electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161066</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Na Song, Ming Fang, Yixing Li, Xuedi Chen, Yue Li, Lei He, Wenbiao Zhang, Xiaoyu Ma, Xianzhang Lei, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401858995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Na Song, Ming Fang, Yixing Li, Xuedi Chen, Yue Li, Lei He, Wenbiao Zhang, Xiaoyu Ma, Xianzhang Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain engineering of CoSAN C catalyst toward enhancing the oxygen reduction reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.165</link>
      <description>Hong Yin, Yuehong Deng, Zhe He, Wenyuan Xu, Zhaohui Hou, Binhong He, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Jo&#227;o Cunha, Maryam Karimi, Zhipeng Yu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401862691

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Yin, Yuehong Deng, Zhe He, Wenyuan Xu, Zhaohui Hou, Binhong He, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Jo&#227;o Cunha, Maryam Karimi, Zhipeng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.165</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallated graphynes as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114489</link>
      <description>Ting Yao, Huohai Yang, Xiaoyue Fu, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Qiang Ke, Xin Chen, Molecular Catalysis. 567(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401844774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Yao, Huohai Yang, Xiaoyue Fu, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Qiang Ke, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site heterogeneity and broad surface-binding isotherms in modern catalysis: Building intuition beyond the Sabatier principle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115725</link>
      <description>James M. Mayer, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401892778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>James M. Mayer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing the competing hydrogen evolution reaction in CO2 electroreduction: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114869</link>
      <description>Munawar Khalil, Grandprix T.M. Kadja, Ferry Anggoro Ardy Nugroho, Laurencia G. Sutanto, Prastika Krisma Jiwanti, Fatwa F. Abdi, Farihahusnah Hussin, Mohamed Kheireddine Aroua, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 206(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401936017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munawar Khalil, Grandprix T.M. Kadja, Ferry Anggoro Ardy Nugroho, Laurencia G. Sutanto, Prastika Krisma Jiwanti, Fatwa F. Abdi, Farihahusnah Hussin, Mohamed Kheireddine Aroua</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Photo/Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400169</link>
      <description>Sheriff A. Balogun, Dina Thole, Daniel Masekela, Kwena D. Modibane, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401957318

                Cobalt phthalocyanine (CoPc)&#8208;based catalysts have garnered significant interest as efficient materials for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) due to their abundant availability, low cost, tunable electronic structures, and unique light absorption performance. This review offers a thorough examination of the latest developments in CoPc&#8208;based catalysts for HER. It entails a wide range of synthesis approaches, intrinsic characteristics, and catalytic mechanisms associated with these catalysts for HER. We also compare the photo/electrocatalytic performance of these catalysts using parameters like Tafel slope, exchange current density, overpotential, hydrogen yield, turnover frequency, stability, specific surface area, etc. The review shows that the commonly used electrolytes for electrocatalytic HER are KOH, LiClO 4 /PBS, and H 2 SO 4 , while for photocatalytic HER, triethylamine, water, and triethanolamine are frequently used. Among all the electrocatalysts understudied, poly[CoOTPc]&#8208;KB and GO/4N&#8208;CoPc are the best, owing to their lowest overpotentials and Tafel slopes. In terms of photocatalytic hydrogen production, CoPc/TiO 2 /Pt has better photocatalytic HER performance compared to its counterparts. This review also highlights the effects of incorporating CoPc with different materials on the photo/electrocatalytic HER performance. Furthermore, the review discusses the challenges and prospects, emphasizing the chances for improving and incorporating CoPc&#8208;based catalysts as a viable option for hydrogen production in the future.</description>
      <author>Sheriff A. Balogun, Dina Thole, Daniel Masekela, Kwena D. Modibane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837674497-part2</link>
      <description>, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401960484

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837674497-part2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Low-Temperature CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis: Current Status and Outlook</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00583</link>
      <description>Hojeong Lee, Seontaek Kwon, Namgyoo Park, Sun Gwan, Eunyoung Lee, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kong, Jihoo Cha, Youngkook Kwon, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401843733

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction (eCO2R) in membrane electrode assemblies (MEAs) has brought e-chemical production one step closer to commercialization because of its advantages of minimized ohmic resistance and stackability. However, the current performance of reported eCO2R in MEAs is still far below the threshold for economic feasibility where low overall cell voltage (&lt;2 V) and extensive stability (&gt;5 years) are required. Furthermore, while the production cost of e-chemicals heavily relies on the carbon capture and product separation processes, these areas have received much less attention compared to CO2 electrolysis, itself. In this perspective, we examine the current status of eCO2R technologies from both academic and industrial points of view. We highlight the gap between current capabilities and commercialization standards and offer future research directions for eCO2R technologies with the hope of achieving industrially viable e-chemical production.</description>
      <author>Hojeong Lee, Seontaek Kwon, Namgyoo Park, Sun Gwan, Eunyoung Lee, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kong, Jihoo Cha, Youngkook Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Embedding Techniques in Multimodal Retrieval Augmented Generation A Comprehensive Study on Cross Modal AI Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/h8wf8vah</link>
      <description>Zhou Ren, Journal of Computing and Electronic Information Management. 13(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402026964

                Our study presents significant advancements in the handling of multimodal data through an extended Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) model. By integrating advanced embedding techniques, efficient retrieval mechanisms, and robust generative capabilities, our model demonstrates notable improvements in retrieval accuracy, real-time efficiency, generative quality, and scalability. The retrieval accuracy of our model reached 85%, showing a 10% improvement over existing benchmarks. Furthermore, the retrieval time was reduced by 40%, enhancing real-time application performance. The model's generative quality was also significantly improved, with BLEU and ROUGE scores increasing by 15% and 12%, respectively. These results validate the effectiveness of our approach and its applicability to various AI applications, including information retrieval, recommendation systems, and content creation. Future research directions include the integration of additional modalities and further optimization of retrieval mechanisms to broaden the applicability of our model.</description>
      <author>Zhou Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/h8wf8vah</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Predictive Control Strategies for Water-Gas Shift Membrane Reactors Using Data-Driven Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33915/etd.12598</link>
      <description>Bernardo de Oliveira Vecchio, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401953006

                As demand for more efficient processes keeps rising and more restrictive environmental legislation requires higher levels of both yield and purity, the process industry has now, more than ever, been looking for new ways to achieve these goals. One approach has been the implementation of Process Intensification (PI). PI aims to combine multiple unit operations into a single one, promoting efficiency gains on multiple levels. This combination, however, leads to complex process dynamics, and controlling such processes, particularly when setup as multi-input-multi-output (MIMO) systems, presents a great challenge due to highly interactive complex process dynamics and the imposition of many operating constraints. The objectives of this research are to generate first-principles and data-driven water-gas shift membrane reactor (WGS-MR) models and to create predictive control schemes to perform effective setpoint tracking under a MIMO framework. The AVEVA Process Simulation platform is chosen for simulating the first-principles model and both Gaussian Processes using a Squared Exponential kernel (GP-SE) and Bayesian Smoothing Spline Analysis of Variance (BSS-ANOVA) are explored as possible frameworks for data-driven models. A Proportional&#8211;Integral&#8211; Derivative (PID) controller is created as a benchmark and a Quadratic Dynamic Matrix Controller (QDMC) is developed for advanced control of the system. The GP model is later used as a digital twin of the plant for calculating a control action trajectory that could be applied to the physical system in case of a desired setpoint change. The results demonstrate the superiority of the BSS-ANOVA model over the GP-SE, especially under open-loop simulation conditions. Also, both PID and QDMC perform well under the tested conditions, but the QDMC is able to deliver smoother control action, specially under noisy signals. Finally, when operating under closed-loop control, the BSS-ANOVA model is capable of providing a good representation of one of the variables being studied, namely carbon capture, with Integral of the Absolute Error (IAE) values ranging from 0.39 to 12.6, while creating a fit for the other variable, namely hydrogen recovery, with IAE measurements ranging from 3.71 to 26.7. These results indicate that the proposed framework is viable, although not universal, as each variable desired to be modeled and controlled should be tested and have its viability carefully assessed.</description>
      <author>Bernardo de Oliveira Vecchio</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33915/etd.12598</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
