<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 01:10:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Rise of machine learning potentials in heterogeneous catalysis: Developments, applications, and prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152757</link>
      <description>Seokhyun Choung, Won Il Park, Jeong Hyun Moon, Jeong Woo Han, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399274810

                The urgency of tackling climate change is driving a global shift towards renewable sources of energy, with a growing contribution from alternative energy sources such as solar, wind and hydroelectric power. With the global push for the sustainable energy, the demand for effective catalysts for sustainable chemical production and energy storage has been rapidly increasing. Computational simulations have contributed to the rational design of catalysts by allowing profound analysis of catalyst properties. Machine learning potential (MLP) has emerged as a potential tool to bridge the gap between quantum mechanical accuracy and computational efficiency, overcoming the computational cost limitations of quantum chemistry-based simulations. This review discusses the development and application of MLP in multiscale simulations of heterogeneous catalysis. It covers the basic concepts of computational catalysis, the construction of MLP focusing on efficient datasets, atomic structure representations, and the process of training and evaluating of ML models. Furthermore, the potential applications of MLP are discussed in addressing computational challenges within the field, as MLP has potential to overcome limitations in simulation time and length scale. Lastly, the prospects for MLP are presented, taking advantage of the rapid advancements in artificial intelligence architectures. It is expected that the integration of MLP will accelerate progress within the catalyst research community and will bridge the gap between theoretical and experimental approaches in catalytic research.</description>
      <author>Seokhyun Choung, Won Il Park, Jeong Hyun Moon, Jeong Woo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduced graphene oxide encapsulated octahedral NiSe2 nanocrystals with dominant {111} crystal facets for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114286</link>
      <description>Yan Liang, Nana Wan, Xiaojian Zhao, Lu Tang, Zongqing Ma, Lin Gu, Yunqian Long, Ting Yu, Yong Yang, Molecular catalysis. 563(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399280768

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Liang, Nana Wan, Xiaojian Zhao, Lu Tang, Zongqing Ma, Lin Gu, Yunqian Long, Ting Yu, Yong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-dependent Kohn&#8722;Sham electron dynamics coupled with nonequilibrium plasmonic response via atomistic electromagnetic model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0205845</link>
      <description>Xunkun Huang, Wenshu Zhang, WanZhen Liang, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399293012

                Computational modeling of plasmon-mediated molecular photophysical and photochemical behaviors can help us better understand and tune the bound molecular properties and reactivity and make better decisions to design and control nanostructures. However, computational investigations of coupled plasmon&#8211;molecule systems are challenging due to the lack of accurate and efficient protocols to simulate these systems. Here, we present a hybrid scheme by combining the real-time time-dependent density functional theory (RT-TDDFT) approach with the time-domain frequency dependent fluctuating charge (TD-&#969;FQ) model. At first, we transform &#969;FQ in the frequency-domain, an atomistic electromagnetic model for the plasmonic response of plasmonic metal nanoparticles (PMNPs), into the time-domain and derive its equation-of-motion formulation. The TD-&#969;FQ introduces the nonequilibrium plasmonic response of PMNPs and atomistic interactions to the electronic excitation of the quantum mechanical (QM) region. Then, we combine TD-&#969;FQ with RT-TDDFT. The derived RT-TDDFT/TD-&#969;FQ scheme allows us to effectively simulate the plasmon-mediated &#8220;real-time&#8221; electronic dynamics and even the coupled electron&#8211;nuclear dynamics by combining them with the nuclear dynamics approaches. As a first application of the RT-TDDFT/TD-&#969;FQ method, we study the nonradiative decay rate and plasmon-enhanced absorption spectra of two small molecules in the proximity of sodium MNPs. Thanks to the atomistic nature of the &#969;FQ model, the edge effect of MNP on absorption enhancement has also been investigated and unveiled.</description>
      <author>Xunkun Huang, Wenshu Zhang, WanZhen Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0205845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure&#8211;spectrum relationship in the calculated Raman spectra of silicates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jrs.6686</link>
      <description>Mohammad Bagheri, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Journal of Raman spectroscopy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399294188

                Abstract Silicate minerals have a rich structural variety consisting of silicon oxide clusters or networks of any dimensionality interdispersed with different types of elements, which is reflected in marked changes in the Raman spectra. Understanding how the changes in the Raman spectra are correlated with the atomic structure would be highly desirable for fast material identification and analysis. Extracting such trends from experimental spectra can be difficult owing to the uncertainties in the structural details of the samples and in ensuring consistency between measurements from different sources. Simulated spectra, however, avoid these problems, making them a good candidate for systematic studies. Here, we study the correlation between the structure and Raman spectral features of 179 silicates derived from a database of Raman spectra simulated using first&#8208;principles calculations. We investigate the spectral similarities with a specific emphasis on materials containing isolated 0D clusters in nesosilicate (SiO 4 ), sorosilicate (Si 2 O 7 ), and cyclosilicate (Si 3 O 9 and Si 4 O 12 ) configurations. While trends identified in the previous reports can be confirmed, we find that the variations within each group of similar structural motifs tend to be larger than the changes across groups, and therefore, developing a reliable automated classification algorithm is likely to be challenging.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Bagheri, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jrs.6686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Harmonious Coexistence of Ruthenium States on a Self&#8208;Standing Electrode for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12766</link>
      <description>Joonhee Ma, Jin Hyuk Cho, Chaehyeon Lee, Moon Sung Kang, Sungkyun Choi, Ho Won Jang, Sanghyun Ahn, Seoin Back, Soo Young Kim, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399296416

                The development of cost&#8208;effective, highly efficient, and durable electrocatalysts has been a paramount pursuit for advancing the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Herein, a simplified synthesis protocol was designed to achieve a self&#8208;standing electrode, composed of activated carbon paper embedded with Ru single&#8208;atom catalysts and Ru nanoclusters (ACP/Ru SAC+C ) via acid activation, immersion, and high&#8208;temperature pyrolysis. Ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) calculations are employed to gain a more profound understanding of the impact of acid activation on carbon paper. Furthermore, the coexistence states of the Ru atoms are confirmed via aberration&#8208;corrected scanning transmission electron microscopy (AC&#8208;STEM), X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS). Experimental measurements and theoretical calculations reveal that introducing a Ru single&#8208;atom site adjacent to the Ru nanoclusters induces a synergistic effect, tuning the electronic structure and thereby significantly enhancing their catalytic performance. Notably, the ACP/Ru SAC+C exhibits a remarkable turnover frequency (TOF) of 18 s &#8722;1 and an exceptional mass activity (MA) of 2.2 A mg &#8722;1 , surpassing the performance of conventional Pt electrodes. The self&#8208;standing electrode, featuring harmoniously coexisting Ru states, stands out as a prospective choice for advancing HER catalysts, enhancing energy efficiency, productivity, and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Joonhee Ma, Jin Hyuk Cho, Chaehyeon Lee, Moon Sung Kang, Sungkyun Choi, Ho Won Jang, Sanghyun Ahn, Seoin Back, Soo Young Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Organic Frameworks for Sustainable Hydrogen Production: Reaction Mechanisms, Performance and Future Aspects in Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129553</link>
      <description>Shahid Alam, M. Imran Jamil, Muhammad Zahir Iqbal, Muhammad Waqas Khan, Asma Khizar, Ahmed M. Fouda, Hosameldin Helmy Hegazyd, Faiz Alam, Zubair Ahmad, Materials chemistry and physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399297402

                Water splitting research has drawn a lot of attention recently due to the exhaustion of fossil fuels reserves and the urgent need for sustainable energy options. A potential method for producing clean, effective hydrogen that can be used as a renewable energy source is water splitting. Metal organic framework-based electrocatalysts have become a potential class of materials in this area because of their distinctive characteristics and tunability in terms of metal ion selection, ligand design, and porosity. This article offers a comprehensive review of the enhancements in MOF-based electrocatalysts, divided into monometallic, multimetallic, their composite and derivative categories and their potential applications in water splitting. It explores the unique qualities of these MOFs, highlighting their catalytic power and potential to improve water splitting processes. Harnessing the extraordinary electrocatalytic attributes of MOFs is a pivotal strategy in accelerating the progression towards a future predominantly powered by renewable energy sources.</description>
      <author>Shahid Alam, M. Imran Jamil, Muhammad Zahir Iqbal, Muhammad Waqas Khan, Asma Khizar, Ahmed M. Fouda, Hosameldin Helmy Hegazyd, Faiz Alam, Zubair Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas-balancing adsorption strategy towards noble-metal-based nanowire electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01167-8</link>
      <description>Jiashun Liang, Shenzhou Li, Xuan Li, Yazhou Wan, Yu Xia, Sue Hao, Siyang Zhang, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang, Gang Lu, Gang Wu, Yunhui Huang, Qing Li, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399299966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiashun Liang, Shenzhou Li, Xuan Li, Yazhou Wan, Yu Xia, Sue Hao, Siyang Zhang, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang, Gang Lu, Gang Wu, Yunhui Huang, Qing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01167-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear magnetoelectricity in the Zintl phase pnictides (Ba, Ca, Sr) &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;Mn&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; (P, As, Sb) &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; from first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.214404</link>
      <description>John Mangeri, Martin Ovesen, Thomas Olsen, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 109(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399302394

                We report a comprehensive set of density functional theory calculations on the family of layered antiferromagnetic manganese pnictides $(\mathrm{Ba},\mathrm{Ca},\mathrm{Sr}){\mathrm{Mn}}_{2}{(\mathrm{P},\mathrm{As},\mathrm{Sb})}_{2}$. We characterize all components to the linear magnetoelectric (ME) tensor $\ensuremath{\alpha}$, which are parsed into their contributions from spin and orbital moments for both lattice-mediated and their clamped-ion electronic analogs. Our main results show that the orbital magnetization components cannot be neglected in these systems. The ME response is dominated by electronic effects with total $\ensuremath{\alpha}$ values exceeding those of the prototypical ${\mathrm{Cr}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{3}$ (i.e., $\ensuremath{\alpha}\ensuremath{\simeq}6.79$ ps/m in ${\mathrm{BaMn}}_{2}{\mathrm{As}}_{2}$). We also identify a strong correlation with the computed ME susceptibility on pnictogen substitution in the trigonal subfamily albeit with weaker amplitudes ($\ensuremath{\alpha}\ensuremath{\approx}0.2$--1.7 ps/m). Additionally, we provide the dependence of these predictions on the Hubbard $+U$ correction, at the level of the local density approximation, which shows large variations on the calculated ME coefficients in the tetragonal compounds highlighting the role of strong correlation in these compounds.</description>
      <author>John Mangeri, Martin Ovesen, Thomas Olsen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.214404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic battle of activated carbon supported transition metal atom towards adsorption and dissociation of molecular hydrogen: Progress towards quantum chemical application on renewable energy resource</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2024.108804</link>
      <description>Abhijit Dutta, Amit Kumar Pradhan, Paritosh Mondal, Journal of molecular graphics &amp; modelling/Journal of molecular graphics and modelling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399318217

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abhijit Dutta, Amit Kumar Pradhan, Paritosh Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2024.108804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constant potential energetics of metallic and semiconducting electrodes: A benchmark study on 2D materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0202849</link>
      <description>Hedda Oschinski, Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Karsten Reuter, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399320804

                Grand-canonical (GC) constant-potential methods within an implicit solvent environment provide a general approach to compute the potential-dependent energetics at electrified solid&#8211;liquid interfaces with first-principles density-functional theory. Here, we use a mindfully chosen set of 27 isostructural 2D metal halides MX2 to analyze the variation of this energetics when the electronic structure changes from metallic to semiconducting and insulating state. Apart from expectable changes due to the opening up of the electronic bandgap, the calculations also show an increasing sensitivity to the numerical Brillouin zone integration and electronic smearing, which imposes computational burdens in practice. We rationalize these findings within the picture of the total interfacial capacitance arising from a series connection of the electrochemical double-layer capacitance and the so-called quantum capacitance resulting from the filling of electronic states inside the electrode. For metals, the electrochemical double-layer capacitance dominates at all potentials, and the entire potential drop takes place in the electrolyte. For semiconductors, the potential drop occurs instead fully or partially inside the electrode at potentials within or just outside the bandgap. For 2D semiconductors, the increased sensitivity to numerical parameters then results from the concomitantly increased contribution of the quantum capacitance that is harder to converge. Fortunately, this understanding motivates a simple extension of the CHE + DL approximation for metals, which provides the approximate GC energetics of 2D semiconductors using only quantities that can be obtained from computationally undemanding calculations at the point of zero charge and a generic double-layer capacitance.</description>
      <author>Hedda Oschinski, Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Karsten Reuter</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0202849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plugin-based interoperability and ecosystem management for the MolSSI Driver Interface Project</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214279</link>
      <description>Taylor Barnes, Sara Ellis, J. Chen, Steven J. Plimpton, Jessica A. Nash, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399321824

                The MolSSI Driver Interface (MDI) Project is an effort to simplify and standardize the process of enabling tight interoperability between independently developed code bases and is supported by numerous software packages across the domain of chemical physics. It enables a wide variety of use cases, including quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics, advanced sampling, path integral molecular dynamics, machine learning, ab initio molecular dynamics, etc. We describe two major developments within the MDI Project that provide novel solutions to key interoperability challenges. The first of these is the development of the MDI Plugin System, which allows MDI-supporting libraries to be used as highly modular plugins, with MDI enforcing a standardized application programming interface across plugins. Codes can use these plugins without linking against them during their build process, and end-users can select which plugin(s) they wish to use at runtime. The MDI Plugin System features a sophisticated callback system that allows codes to interact with plugins on a highly granular level and represents a significant advancement toward increased modularity among scientific codes. The second major development is MDI Mechanic, an ecosystem management tool that utilizes Docker containerization to simplify the process of developing, validating, maintaining, and deploying MDI-supporting codes. Additionally, MDI Mechanic provides a framework for launching MDI simulations in which each interoperating code is executed within a separate computational environment. This eliminates the need to compile multiple production codes within a single computational environment, reducing opportunities for dependency conflicts and lowering the barrier to entry for users of MDI-enabled codes.</description>
      <author>Taylor Barnes, Sara Ellis, J. Chen, Steven J. Plimpton, Jessica A. Nash</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;insulator&#8211;semiconductor photoelectrodes for enhanced photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00820g</link>
      <description>Shice Wei, Xuewen Xia, Bi Shi, Huolin Shen, Xuefeng Wu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Xingli Zou, Kai Huang, David W. Zhang, Qianyi Sun, Allen J. Bard, E. T. Yu, Ji Li, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399326921

                Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting provides a scalable and integrated platform to harness renewable solar energy for green hydrogen production. The practical implementation of PEC systems hinges on addressing three critical challenges: enhancing energy conversion efficiency, ensuring long-term stability, and achieving economic viability. Metal-insulator-semiconductor (MIS) heterojunction photoelectrodes have gained significant attention over the last decade for their ability to efficiently segregate photogenerated carriers and mitigate corrosion-induced semiconductor degradation. This review discusses the structural composition and interfacial intricacies of MIS photoelectrodes tailored for PEC water splitting. The application of MIS heterostructures across various semiconductor light-absorbing layers, including traditional photovoltaic-grade semiconductors, metal oxides, and emerging materials, is presented first. Subsequently, this review elucidates the reaction mechanisms and respective merits of vacuum and non-vacuum deposition techniques in the fabrication of the insulator layers. In the context of the metal layers, this review extends beyond the conventional scope, not only by introducing metal-based cocatalysts, but also by exploring the latest advancements in molecular and single-atom catalysts integrated within MIS photoelectrodes. Furthermore, a systematic summary of carrier transfer mechanisms and interface design principles of MIS photoelectrodes is presented, which are pivotal for optimizing energy band alignment and enhancing solar-to-chemical conversion efficiency within the PEC system. Finally, this review explores innovative derivative configurations of MIS photoelectrodes, including back-illuminated MIS photoelectrodes, inverted MIS photoelectrodes, tandem MIS photoelectrodes, and monolithically integrated wireless MIS photoelectrodes. These novel architectures address the limitations of traditional MIS structures by effectively coupling different functional modules, minimizing optical and ohmic losses, and mitigating recombination losses.</description>
      <author>Shice Wei, Xuewen Xia, Bi Shi, Huolin Shen, Xuefeng Wu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Xingli Zou, Kai Huang, David W. Zhang, Qianyi Sun, Allen J. Bard, E. T. Yu, Ji Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00820g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of adsorption properties and CO oxidation reaction on surfaces of higher tungsten boride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-63676-7</link>
      <description>Aleksandra D. Radina, Viktor S. Baidyshev, Ilya V. Chepkasov, Nikita Matsokin, Tariq Altalhi, Boris I. Yakobson, Alexander G. Kvashnin, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399339614

                Abstract Most modern catalysts are based on precious metals and rear-earth elements, making some of organic synthesis reactions economically insolvent. Density functional theory calculations are used here to describe several differently oriented surfaces of the higher tungsten boride WB 5-x , together with their catalytic activity for the CO oxidation reaction. Based on our findings, WB 5-x appears to be an efficient alternative catalyst for CO oxidation. Calculated surface energies allow the use of the Wulff construction to determine the equilibrium shape of WB 5-x particles. It is found that the (010) and (101) facets terminated by boron and tungsten, respectively, are the most exposed surfaces for which the adsorption of different gaseous agents (CO, CO 2 , H 2 , N 2 , O 2 , NO, NO 2 , H 2 O, NH 3 , SO 2 ) is evaluated to reveal promising prospects for applications. CO oxidation on B-rich (010) and W-rich (101) surfaces is further investigated by analyzing the charge redistribution during the adsorption of CO and O 2 molecules. It is found that CO oxidation has relatively low energy barriers. The implications of the present results, the effects of WB 5-x on CO oxidation and potential application in the automotive, chemical, and mining industries are discussed.</description>
      <author>Aleksandra D. Radina, Viktor S. Baidyshev, Ilya V. Chepkasov, Nikita Matsokin, Tariq Altalhi, Boris I. Yakobson, Alexander G. Kvashnin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-63676-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Charge Transfer Unveils Antideactivation of Ru at High Potentials for the Alkaline Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03622</link>
      <description>H. C. Shi, Yang Yang, Pin Meng, Jiahe Yang, Wei Zheng, Pengcheng Wang, Yunlong Zhang, Xingyan Chen, Zhiyu Cheng, Cichang Zong, Dongdong Wang, Qianwang Chen, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399368506

                The activity of Ru-based alkaline hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) electrocatalysts usually decreases rapidly at potentials higher than 0.1 V (vs a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE)), which significantly limits the lifetime of fuel cells. It is found that this phenomenon is caused by the overadsorption of the O species due to the overcharging of Ru nanoparticles at high potentials. Here, Mn1Ox(OH)y clusters-modified Ru nanoparticles (Mn1Ox(OH)y@Ru/C) were prepared to promote charge transfer from overcharged Ru nanoparticles to Mn1Ox(OH)y clusters. Mn1Ox(OH)y@Ru/C exhibits high HOR activity and stability over a wide potential range of 0&#8211;1.0 V. Moreover, a hydroxide exchange membrane fuel cell with a Mn1Ox(OH)y@Ru/C anode delivers a high peak power density of 1.731 W cm&#8211;2, much superior to that of a Pt/C anode. In situ X-ray absorption fine structure (XAFS) analysis and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that Mn in Mn1Ox(OH)y clusters could receive more electrons from overcharged Ru at higher potentials and significantly decrease the overadsorption of the O species on Ru, thus permitting the HOR on Ru to proceed at high potentials. This study provides guidance for the design of alkaline HOR catalysts without activity decay at high potentials.</description>
      <author>H. C. Shi, Yang Yang, Pin Meng, Jiahe Yang, Wei Zheng, Pengcheng Wang, Yunlong Zhang, Xingyan Chen, Zhiyu Cheng, Cichang Zong, Dongdong Wang, Qianwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atoms on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Can Catalyze Water Oxidation in Photoelectrochemical Experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03319</link>
      <description>Shi Wu, Wu Lu, Nikita Denisov, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Giorgio Zoppellaro, Xiaoyu Yang, Patrik Schmuki, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399380646

                Photoelectrochemical water splitting on n-type semiconductors is highly dependent on catalysis of the rate-determining reaction of O2 evolution. Conventionally, in electrochemistry and photoelectrochemistry O2 evolution is catalyzed by metal oxide catalysts like IrO2 and RuO2, whereas noble metals such as Pt are considered unsuitable for this purpose. However, our study finds that Pt, in its single-atom form, exhibits exceptional cocatalytic properties for photoelectrochemical water oxidation on a TiO2 photoanode, in contrast to Pt in a nanoparticle form. The decoration of Pt single atoms onto TiO2 yields a remarkable current density of 5.89 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.23 VRHE, surpassing bare TiO2 (or Pt nanoparticle decorated TiO2) by 2.52 times. Notably, this enhancement remains consistent over a wide pH range. By accompanying theoretical work, we assign this significant enhancement to an improved charge transfer and separation efficiency along with accelerated kinetics in the oxygen evolution reaction facilitated by the presence of Pt single atoms on the TiO2 surface.</description>
      <author>Shi Wu, Wu Lu, Nikita Denisov, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Giorgio Zoppellaro, Xiaoyu Yang, Patrik Schmuki</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of High Entropy Alloys on a Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Approaching Active Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01278</link>
      <description>Jing Liang, Yanling Ma, Yanjie Li, Wencong Zhang, Hao Hu, Jie Su, Zhenpeng Yao, Wenpei Gao, Wen Shang, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399380880

                High-entropy alloys (HEAs) have garnered considerable attention as promising nanocatalysts for effectively utilizing Pt in catalysis toward oxygen reduction reactions due to their unique properties. Nonetheless, there is a relative dearth of attention regarding the structural evolution of HEAs in response to electrochemical conditions. In this work, we propose a thermal reduction method to synthesize high entropy nanoparticles by leveraging the confinement effect and abundant nitrogen-anchored sites provided by pyrolyzed metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs). Notably, the prepared catalysts exhibit enhanced activity accompanied by structural reconstruction during electrochemical activation, approaching 1 order of magnitude higher mass activity compared to Pt/C in oxygen reduction. Atomic-scale structural characterization reveals that abundant defects and single atoms are formed during the activation process, contributing to a significant boost in the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction reactions. This study provides deep insights into surface reconstruction engineering during electrochemical operations, with practical implications for fuel cell applications.</description>
      <author>Jing Liang, Yanling Ma, Yanjie Li, Wencong Zhang, Hao Hu, Jie Su, Zhenpeng Yao, Wenpei Gao, Wen Shang, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatMOF: an artificial intelligence system for predicting and generating metal-organic frameworks using large language models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48998-4</link>
      <description>Yeonghun Kang, Jihan Kim, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399290669

                Abstract ChatMOF is an artificial intelligence (AI) system that is built to predict and generate metal-organic frameworks (MOFs). By leveraging a large-scale language model (GPT-4, GPT-3.5-turbo, and GPT-3.5-turbo-16k), ChatMOF extracts key details from textual inputs and delivers appropriate responses, thus eliminating the necessity for rigid and formal structured queries. The system is comprised of three core components (i.e., an agent, a toolkit, and an evaluator) and it forms a robust pipeline that manages a variety of tasks, including data retrieval, property prediction, and structure generations. ChatMOF shows high accuracy rates of 96.9% for searching, 95.7% for predicting, and 87.5% for generating tasks with GPT-4. Additionally, it successfully creates materials with user-desired properties from natural language. The study further explores the merits and constraints of utilizing large language models (LLMs) in combination with database and machine learning in material sciences and showcases its transformative potential for future advancements.</description>
      <author>Yeonghun Kang, Jihan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48998-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pourbaix Machine Learning Framework Identifies Acidic Water Oxidation Catalysts Exhibiting Suppressed Ruthenium Dissolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01353</link>
      <description>Jehad Abed, Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Ming Ronnier Luo, Wajdi Alnoush, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Jian Wang, Jigang Zhou, Daojin Zhou, Khalid Fatih, John R. Kitchin, Drew Higgins, Zachary W. Ulissi, Edward H. Sargent, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399305702

                The demand for green hydrogen has raised concerns over the availability of iridium used in oxygen evolution reaction catalysts. We identify catalysts with the aid of a machine learning-aided computational pipeline trained on more than 36,000 mixed metal oxides. The pipeline accurately predicts Pourbaix decomposition energy (Gpbx) from unrelaxed structures with a mean absolute error of 77 meV per atom, enabling us to screen 2070 new metallic oxides with respect to their prospective stability under acidic conditions. The search identifies Ru0.6Cr0.2Ti0.2O2 as a candidate having the promise of increased durability: experimentally, we find that it provides an overpotential of 267 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 and that it operates at this current density for over 200 h and exhibits a rate of overpotential increase of 25 &#956;V h&#8211;1. Surface density functional theory calculations reveal that Ti increases metal&#8211;oxygen covalency, a potential route to increased stability, while Cr lowers the energy barrier of the HOO* formation rate-determining step, increasing activity compared to RuO2 and reducing overpotential by 40 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 while maintaining stability. In situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy and ex situ ptychography-scanning transmission X-ray microscopy show the evolution of a metastable structure during the reaction, slowing Ru mass dissolution by 20&#215; and suppressing lattice oxygen participation by &gt;60% compared to RuO2.</description>
      <author>Jehad Abed, Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Ming Ronnier Luo, Wajdi Alnoush, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Jian Wang, Jigang Zhou, Daojin Zhou, Khalid Fatih, John R. Kitchin, Drew Higgins, Zachary W. Ulissi, Edward H. Sargent</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Electronic Density of States in Guanine-TiO2 Adsorption Model based on Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csbr.2024.100008</link>
      <description>Yark&#305;n A. &#199;etin, Benjam&#237; Martorell, Francesc Serratosa, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399274321

                The electronic density of states is a property of the material that is extensively used in quantum systems in condensed matter physics. It refers to the energy level of the electrons in a solid crystal. One of the most current ways to compute it is by Density Functional Tight Binding (DFTB), given the geometry of the material. Nevertheless, this computation could be very computationally demanding, although applied to some materials with a very reduced number of atoms. This paper presents a method to deduce the electronic density of states, which is based on a neural network, thus, almost linear with respect to the number of atoms in the material. Specifically, we have applied our method to a metal oxide structure interacting with a nucleic base guanine. We have focused on stoichiometric and O-defective anatase TiO2 (101) surfaces. The data set of the electronic density of states needed to train the neural network has been obtained by a DFTB+ numerical solver given an initial molecular geometry model, which computed a track of time-dependent geometry and their associated electronic density of states. We validated that the predicted electronic density of states deduced by our method and by DFTB tends to be very similar, thus, opening the door to other computations such that introducing our method in the process of generating the time-dependent geometry analysis.</description>
      <author>Yark&#305;n A. &#199;etin, Benjam&#237; Martorell, Francesc Serratosa</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csbr.2024.100008</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
