<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 01:26:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Assisted Selection of Catalyst for &#947;-Valerolactone Hydrogenation from Levulinic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05941</link>
      <description>Liu Dongyu, Zhen Jia, Lu Shen, Wenman Liu, Ronald T.K. Pang, Shitao Yu, Shiwei Liu, Lu Li, Yue Liu, Longzhen Yu, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403716968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liu Dongyu, Zhen Jia, Lu Shen, Wenman Liu, Ronald T.K. Pang, Shitao Yu, Shiwei Liu, Lu Li, Yue Liu, Longzhen Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction on Cu-Decorated Biphenylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08499</link>
      <description>Radha N Somaiya, Muhammad Sajjad, Nirpendra Singh, Aftab Alam, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728309

                Developing efficient electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction into value-added products is crucial for a green economy. Inspired by the recent experimental synthesis of biphenylene (BPH) and the excellent catalytic activity of copper dispersed on two-dimensional (2D) materials, we chose to systematically investigate the pristine, defective, and Cu-decorated BPH for the electrocatalytic CO2 reduction to value-added hydrocarbons. It is observed that the CO2 molecules bind weakly to the pristine BPH, indicating their chemical inertness. Carbon single-vacancy defects facilitate CO2 adsorption with a strong binding energy (Eb) of &#8722;3.23 eV, detrimental to the CO2 reduction reaction (CRR) mechanism. We have further investigated the binding energy and kinetic stability of Cu-decorated BPH as a single-atom-catalyst (SAC). The molecular dynamics simulations confirm the kinetic stability, revealing that the Cu-atom avoids agglomeration under low metal dispersal conditions. The CO2 molecule gets adsorbed horizontally on the Cu-BPH surface with a &#916;Eb of &#8722;0.52 eV. The CRR mechanism is investigated using two pathways beginning with two different initial states, formate (*OCOH) and carboxylic (*COOH). The formate pathway confirms the conversion of *OCOH to *HCOOH with the rate-limiting potential (UL) of 0.39 eV for the production of HCOOH, while for the carboxylic pathway, the conversion of *COH to *CHOH has a UL of 0.32 eV, eventually producing CH3OH. Our findings highlight the role of Cu-BPH as an efficient SAC for CO2 catalytic activity to C1 products, as compared to the state-of-the-art Cu, and holds promise as an electrocatalyst for CRR.</description>
      <author>Radha N Somaiya, Muhammad Sajjad, Nirpendra Singh, Aftab Alam</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mild polarization electric field in ultra-thin BN-Fe-graphene sandwich structure for efficient nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60114-2</link>
      <description>Ziyuan Xiu, Wei Mu, Xin Zhou, Xiaojun Han, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyuan Xiu, Wei Mu, Xin Zhou, Xiaojun Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60114-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miniaturized Electrochemical Gas Sensor with a Functional Nanocomposite and Thin Ionic Liquid Interface for Highly Sensitive and Rapid Detection of Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c02561</link>
      <description>Zhuoru Huang, Wenjian Yang, Yanchi Zhang, Jiaxi Yin, Xianyou Sun, Jiaying Sun, Guangqing Ren, Shichao Tian, Ping Wang, Hao Wan, Analytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403732719

                Hydrogen has been widely used in industrial and commercial applications as a carbon-free, efficient energy source. Due to the high flammability and explosion risk of hydrogen&#8211;air mixtures, it is vital to develop sensors featuring fast-responding and high sensitivity for hydrogen leakage detection. This paper presents a miniaturized electrochemical gas sensor by elaborately establishing a nanocomposite and thin ionic liquid interface for highly sensitive and rapid electrochemical detection of hydrogen, in which a remarkable response time and recovery time of approximately 6 s was achieved at room temperature. A screen-printed carbon electrode was modified with a reduced graphene oxide&#8211;carbon nanotube (rGO-CNT) hybrid and platinum&#8211;palladium (Pt&#8211;Pd) bimetallic nanoparticles to realize high sensitivity. To achieve miniaturization and high stability of the sensor, a thin-film room-temperature ionic liquid (RTIL) was employed as the electrolyte with a significantly decreased response time. The fast-responding hydrogen sensor demonstrates excellent performance with high sensitivity, linearity, and repeatability at concentrations below the lower explosive limit of 4 vol %. The engineered high-performance interface and gas sensor provide a promising and effective strategy for gas sensor design and rapid hazardous gas monitoring.</description>
      <author>Zhuoru Huang, Wenjian Yang, Yanchi Zhang, Jiaxi Yin, Xianyou Sun, Jiaying Sun, Guangqing Ren, Shichao Tian, Ping Wang, Hao Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.4c02561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D single-faceted IrO2(101) monolayer enabling high-performing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis beyond 8,000 h stability at 1.5 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</link>
      <description>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745568

                Abstract Both commercially available and laboratory-synthesized IrO2 catalysts typically possess rutile-type structures and diverse facet orientations. According to the theoretical results from density functional theory calculations, distinct IrO2 facets will result in divergent electrocatalytic properties, among which the (101) crystal facet is theoretically predicted as the most energetically favorable for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) owing to its lowest energy barrier. Maintaining a single-unit-cell thickness while exposing a desired facet of 2D IrO2 presents a significant opportunity and challenge for the development of high-performance OER anode catalysts. Herein, we develop an ammonia-induced facet engineering for oriented modulation of crystal facets in the ultimate limit of monolayer thickness, and successfully synthesize 2D monolayer IrO2 exposing unique (101) facet. At the current density of 10 mA cm-2geo, an ultralow overpotential of 230 mV has been achieved on the highly activated (101) facet in a three-electrode system. More importantly, in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, the IrO2 anode reaches a low voltage of 1.74 V at an industrial-level current density of 2 A cm-2geo, much lower than that of all commercial IrO2 electrocatalysts. Though facet engineering primarily contributes to modulating the intrinsic activity rather than stability, the as-prepared IrO2(101) monolayer performs over 8,000 hours of PEM water electrolysis (PEMWE) stability at constant 1.5 A cm-2geo, with a negligible decay rate of 4.0 mV kh-1. Furthermore, even a long-term PEMWE test of 1000 h using the membrane electrode assembly (MEA) with ultra-low Ir loading of 0.2 mgIr cm-2geo under fluctuating operating conditions is performed, ECell remains highly electrochemically stable over time at 1.5 A cm-2geo, without any signs of catalyst degradation. This work proposes that ammonia-induced facet engineering of 2D monolayer IrO2 could represent a novel approach to selectively expose the desired (101) facet, thereby enabling unique facet-dependent OER performance and ultrahigh stability in industrial-scale PEM electrolysis, even under voltage fluctuations generated by solar and wind power.</description>
      <author>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chirality Engineering of Nanostructured Copper Oxide for Enhancing Oxygen Evolution from Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</link>
      <description>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745745

                Abstract The exploration of a new conceptual strategy for improving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) of earth&#8208;abundant electrocatalysts is critical. In this study, chiral copper oxide nanoflower is explored by a self&#8208;assembly method. The characterization suggests the chiral structure originates from the crystal plane&#8208;level helical stack of the secondary nanosheets. Of note, the assembly illustrates a record&#8208;high degree of spin polarization of 96%, indicating the ideal alignment of electron spin. Moreover, density function theory calculations show the chiral structure reducing the reaction energy barrier (REB) while switching the potential&#8208;determining step from *O&#8594;*OOH to *OH&#8594;*O. Together with the enhanced electrochemical active surface area and accelerated charge transfer, the production of ground&#8208;state triplet O 2 is improved via a spin&#8208;forbidden route that involves the singlet H 2 O/OH&#8226;. Consequently, the chiral nanoflower shows a overpotential of 308 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 93.5 mV dec &#8722;1 , which is even superior to the commercial RuO 2 (310 mV, 101 mV dec &#8722;1 ). This study presents a new strategy for improving the OER activity by simultaneously enhancing electronic properties and lowering the REB of an non&#8208;noble electrocatalyst via chirality engineering.</description>
      <author>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Modulation of RuCo Catalysts on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanotubes Promoting Durable Acidic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</link>
      <description>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745765

                Abstract The development of efficient and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts is essential for hydrogen production from acidic water splitting. Herein, a TiO 2 nanotube&#8208;loaded Co&#8208;doped Ru nanoparticle catalyst (RuCo/TiO 2 NTs) is reported that exhibits excellent activity and stability toward acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The Ru&#9472;O&#9472;Ti bonding is enhanced by Co doping, and the metal carrier interaction between Ru nanoparticles and TiO 2 NTs is enhanced, which effectively stabilizes Ru species during OER and initiates hydrogen spillover accelerating HER kinetics. As a result, RuCo/TiO 2 NTs catalyst requires only 156 mV OER overpotential and 17 mV HER overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a stability more than 500 h in acidic conditions. More importantly, benefiting from the excellent bifunctional activities, the proton exchange membrane electrolyte assembled from RuCo/TiO 2 NTs has excellent activity and robust stability (1000 h). This work opens a new avenue for the efficient energy conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Host-guest-induced electronic state triggers two-electron oxygen reduction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53714-3</link>
      <description>Hongni Chen, Chao Wang, Han Wu, Lili Li, Yali Xing, Chuanhui Zhang, Xiaojing Long, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403749872

                Supramolecular polymers possess great potential in catalysis owing to their distinctive molecular recognition and dynamic crosslinking features. However, investigating supramolecular electrocatalysts with high efficiency in oxygen reduction reaction to hydrogen peroxide (ORHP) remains an unexplored frontier. Herein, we present organic polymers for ORHP by introducing cyclodextrin-containing noncovalent building blocks, affording these supramolecules with abundant dynamic bonds. The electronic states and reaction kinetics are further well-modulated via a host-guest strategy, resulting in appropriate regional electron binding force and controllable chemical activity. Notably, integrating supramolecular units into phenyl group-containing model covalent polymer achieves a production rate of 9.14 mol g</description>
      <author>Hongni Chen, Chao Wang, Han Wu, Lili Li, Yali Xing, Chuanhui Zhang, Xiaojing Long</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53714-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom anchored van der Waals heterojunctions for efficient Z-scheme photocatalytic overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.308</link>
      <description>Jie Yang, Nianjun Luo, Wenyi Tang, Min-Quan Kuang, Chunling Tian, Hong Chen, Hongkuan Yuan, Biao Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403753108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Yang, Nianjun Luo, Wenyi Tang, Min-Quan Kuang, Chunling Tian, Hong Chen, Hongkuan Yuan, Biao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Catalyst Screening of Multielement Alloy Catalysts for Ammonia Synthesis Using Machine Learning Potential and Generative Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04018</link>
      <description>Kaoru Hisama, Atsushi Ishikawa, Susan Me&#241;ez Aspera, Michihisa Koyama, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403753284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaoru Hisama, Atsushi Ishikawa, Susan Me&#241;ez Aspera, Michihisa Koyama</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study of Highly Active Bifunctional Double-Atom Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02759</link>
      <description>Wei Zhang, Xueqi Cheng, Xiongyi Liang, Keke Mao, Xiao Cheng Zeng, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757553

                Dual-atom catalysts (DACs) can be very effective for catalyzing both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we present theoretical evidence of a new class of highly active DACs, namely, the double-atom embedded in nitrogen-doped graphene sheet 2M-N-C (M = Mn, Fe) on the basis of density functional theory calculations. Importantly, we find that the double active sites of 2M-N-C DACs entail an unconventional catalytic reaction pathway for ORR and OER. We also show that the local coordination environment of the active sites can significantly affect the stability and oxygen catalytic activity of 2M-N-C DACs. In particular, MnFe-N-C DAC not only exhibits good stability but also possesses outstanding bifunctional ORR/OER catalytic activity with the potential difference (&#916;</description>
      <author>Wei Zhang, Xueqi Cheng, Xiongyi Liang, Keke Mao, Xiao Cheng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and Activity of Organometallic Phthalocyanine Sheets for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999676</link>
      <description>Walter Orellana, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Walter Orellana</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interlayer Hydrogen Recombination from Hydrogen Boride Nanosheets Elucidated by Isotope Labeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01975</link>
      <description>Shin&#8208;ichi Ito, Kurt Irvin M. Rojas, Yukihiro Yasuda, Natsumi Noguchi, Kosei Fukuda, Miwa Hikichi, Zihao Kang, Mei Yuan, Ryuki Tsuji, Osamu Oki, Susmita Roy, Yasuyuki Hikita, Iwao Matsuda, Masahiro Miyauchi, Ikutaro Hamada, Takahiro Kondo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403761453

                In this study, deuterium boride (DB) nanosheets were synthesized as deuterated borophane through the ion exchange of magnesium cations in magnesium diboride with deuterons from a deuterium-type ion-exchange resin in acetonitrile. The Fourier-transform infrared absorption spectrum of DB exhibited clear isotope effects, namely the shift in the absorption peak of the B-H stretching vibrational mode to a lower wavenumber. Temperature-programmed desorption (TPD) from a mixture of DB and hydrogen boride (HB) nanosheets yielded a more intense hydrogen-deuterium (HD) signal compared to the H</description>
      <author>Shin&#8208;ichi Ito, Kurt Irvin M. Rojas, Yukihiro Yasuda, Natsumi Noguchi, Kosei Fukuda, Miwa Hikichi, Zihao Kang, Mei Yuan, Ryuki Tsuji, Osamu Oki, Susmita Roy, Yasuyuki Hikita, Iwao Matsuda, Masahiro Miyauchi, Ikutaro Hamada, Takahiro Kondo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace Ru Incorporation Boosted Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P Nanorods for Superior Water Electrolysis and Substrate&#8208;Paired Electrolysis Toward Value&#8208;Added Chemicals in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405056</link>
      <description>Souradip Ganguly, Pooja Basera, Sahnawaz Ahmed, Sukanta Saha, Arnab Dutta, Chanchal Loha, Sirshendu Ghosh, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776601

                Abstract Electro&#8208;valorization of biomass&#8208;derived chemicals has ensured sustainable production of value&#8208;added products, an effective approach for reducing carbon footprint, through renewable energy. Electrochemical oxidation and reduction reactions in aqueous media using H 2 O as a potential source for active hydrogenated and oxygenated species fulfill the purpose. In this study, Ru&#9472;Co 2 P nanorods are explored as a bifunctional electrocatalyst toward valorization of Organics at basic media. The in&#8208;situ electrogenerated Co 3+ and Co 4+ species act as active oxidants toward product selectivity. An overpotential of 68 mV is found for hydrogen evolution reaction (1 m NaOH) with Ru&#9472;Co 2 P. Further, used as cathode, Ru&#9472;Co 2 P effectively reduces furfuraldehyde to furfuryl alcohol and p &#8208;nitrophenol to p &#8208;aminophenol. Ru doping enables ease of formation of active species both for reduction and oxidation, faster charge transfer between catalyst to absorbates. Density Functional Theory calculation establishes Ru incorporation in Co 2 P surface results in enhanced adsorption of substrates. Ru doping modulates the electronic structure of Co 2 P which changes the density of states resulting in faster water dissociation and water splitting. To reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 current density only 1.6 V is required for water electrolysis, whereas 1.4 V is enough for substrate&#8208;paired electrolysis with simultaneous oxidation of benzyl alcohol and reduction of p &#8208;nitro phenol.</description>
      <author>Souradip Ganguly, Pooja Basera, Sahnawaz Ahmed, Sukanta Saha, Arnab Dutta, Chanchal Loha, Sirshendu Ghosh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threefold Impact on Reaction Coordinate Mapping of Zirconium Based Tri&#8208;Chalcogenide Pseudo&#8208;Monolayers as Emerging Ultrathin Catalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400816</link>
      <description>Ponnappa Kechanda Prasanna, Sudip Chakraborty, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403782112

                Abstract The continuous quest of finding optimum catalysts for photo&#8208;electrocatalytic (PEC) water splitting has been revolving around 2D ultrathin materials because of the fact of exploiting both the surface area. In this work, a threefold impact is envisaged route to enhance the activity both in terms of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in the emerging Zirconium Tri&#8208;sulfides (ZrS 3 ) based pseudo&#8208;monolayers. Due to the unique and distinct electronic properties of the tri&#8208;chalcogenide systems as compared to the di&#8208;chalcogenide counterpart of Zirconium, one could afford to explore the implications of not only single&#8208;atom functionalization and vacancy defect, but also the external strain to expedite the bifunctional catalytic activity in this promising material. Rigorous electronic structure calculations have been performed for the mentioned threefold effect on not only the band&#8208;edge alignment, but going beyond to it by further constructing the reaction coordinate mapping corresponding to HER and OER mechanism. The repercussion of external strain in addition to the single atom functionalization and vacancy defect on the adsorption free energies of the prime intermediates of HER and OER reaction has been further correlated with the work function variation in this pseudo&#8208;monolayer system.</description>
      <author>Ponnappa Kechanda Prasanna, Sudip Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing atomic-scale processes at the ferrihydrite-water interface with reactive molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12932-024-00094-8</link>
      <description>Ardalan Hayatifar, Simon Gravelle, Beatriz D. Moreno, Valerie A. Schoepfer, Matthew B.J. Lindsay, Geochemical Transactions. 25(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403782459

                Interfacial processes involving metal (oxyhydr)oxide phases are important for the mobility and bioavailability of nutrients and contaminants in soils, sediments, and water. Consequently, these processes influence ecosystem health and functioning, and have shaped the biological and environmental co-evolution of Earth over geologic time. Here we employ reactive molecular dynamics simulations, supported by synchrotron X-ray spectroscopy to study the molecular-scale interfacial processes that influence surface complexation in ferrihydrite-water systems containing aqueous</description>
      <author>Ardalan Hayatifar, Simon Gravelle, Beatriz D. Moreno, Valerie A. Schoepfer, Matthew B.J. Lindsay</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12932-024-00094-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Metal&#8208;Support Interactions in Heterogeneous Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407167</link>
      <description>Zhiqian Hou, Chenghao Cui, Yanan Yang, Zhikun Huang, Yu Zhuang, Ye Zeng, Xi Gong, Tao Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403791868

                Molecular oxygen redox electrocatalysis involves oxygen reduction and evolution as core reactions in various energy conversion and environmental technology fields. Strong metal-support interactions (SMSIs) based nanomaterials are regarded as desirable and state-of-the-art heterogeneous electrocatalysts due to their exceptional physicochemical properties. Over the past decades, considerable advancements in theory and experiment have been achieved in related studies, especially in modulating the electronic structure and geometrical configuration of SMSIs to enable activity, selectivity, and stability. In this focuses on the concept of SMSI, explore their various manifestations and mechanisms of action, and summarizes recent advances in SMSIs for efficient energy conversion in oxygen redox electrocatalysis applications. Additionally, the correlation between the physicochemical properties of different metals and supports is systematically elucidated, and the potential mechanisms of the structure-activity relationships between SMSIs and catalytic performance are outlined through theoretical models. Finally, the obstacles confronting this burgeoning field are comprehensively concluded, targeted recommendations and coping strategies are proposed, and future research perspectives are outlined.</description>
      <author>Zhiqian Hou, Chenghao Cui, Yanan Yang, Zhikun Huang, Yu Zhuang, Ye Zeng, Xi Gong, Tao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Non&#8208;Noble Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Focus on Transition and Rare&#8208;Earth Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400151</link>
      <description>Jala Bib Khan, Yuan&#8208;Chang Liang, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403792218

                Abstract The demand for renewable energy sources has become more urgent due to climate change and environmental pollution. The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role in green energy sources. This article primarily explores the potential of using non&#8208;noble metals, such as transition and rare earth metals, to enhance the efficiency of the OER process. Due to their cost&#8208;effectiveness and unique electronic structure, these non&#8208;noble metals could be a game&#8208;changer in the field. &#8242;Doping,&#8242; which is the process of adding a small amount of impurity to a material to alter its properties, and &#8242;synergistic effects,&#8242; which refer to the combined effect of two or more elements that is greater than the sum of their individual effects, are two key concepts in this field. Transition and rare earth metals can reduce the overpotential, a measure of the excess potential required to drive a reaction, thus enhancing the OER process by engineering the electronic and surface molecular structure. This article summarizes the roles of various non&#8208;noble metals in the OER process and highlights opportunities for researchers to propose innovative ways to optimize the OER process.</description>
      <author>Jala Bib Khan, Yuan&#8208;Chang Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achievements and Challenges in Surfactants&#8208;Assisted Synthesis of MOFs&#8208;Derived Transition Metal&#8211;Nitrogen&#8211;Carbon as a Highly Efficient Electrocatalyst for ORR, OER, and HER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408227</link>
      <description>Ru&#8208;Ji Li, Wen&#8208;Jun Niu, Wei&#8208;Wei Zhao, Bing&#8208;Xin Yu, Chen&#8208;Yu Cai, Liyang Xu, Fu&#8208;Ming Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403808262

                Abstract Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) are excellent precursors for preparing transition metal and nitrogen co&#8208;doped carbon catalysts, which have been widely utilized in the field of electrocatalysis since their initial development. However, the original MOFs derived catalysts have been greatly limited in their development and application due to their disadvantages such as metal atom aggregation, structural collapse, and narrow pore channels. Recently, surfactants&#8208;assisted MOFs derived catalysts have attracted much attention from researchers due to their advantages such as hierarchical porous structure, increased specific surface area, and many exposed active sites. This review mainly focuses on the synthesis methods of surfactants&#8208;assisted MOFs derived catalysts and comprehensively introduces the action of surfactants in MOFs derived materials and the structure&#8208;activity relationship between the catalysts and the oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, and hydrogen evolution reaction performance. Apparently, the aims of this review not only introduce the status of surfactants&#8208;assisted MOFs derived catalysts in the field of electrocatalysis but also contribute to the rational design and synthesis of MOFs derived catalysts for fuel cells, metal&#8211;air cells, and electrolysis of water toward hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Ru&#8208;Ji Li, Wen&#8208;Jun Niu, Wei&#8208;Wei Zhao, Bing&#8208;Xin Yu, Chen&#8208;Yu Cai, Liyang Xu, Fu&#8208;Ming Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supplanted by electron-deficient B to form RuN2B-CoN4 moiety as superior catalytic site to further promote urea production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114637</link>
      <description>Ao Yang, Changyan Zhu, Kaile Li, Yun&#8211;Jie Chu, Mengxue Wang, Yun Geng, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Min Zhang, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403813518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ao Yang, Changyan Zhu, Kaile Li, Yun&#8211;Jie Chu, Mengxue Wang, Yun Geng, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave&#8208;assisted control of Pt&#63743;Ni nanoalloy clusters on the nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene oxide for energy conversion with oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12499</link>
      <description>Seung Geun Jo, Gil&#8208;Ryeong Park, Jemin Kim, D. Ahn, Rahul Ramkumar, Sun&#8208;I Kim, Duck Hyun Lee, Jung Woo Lee, EcoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403822209

                Abstract Research on the production and utilization of hydrogen energy is essential to overcome the environmental issues caused by fossil fuels. Herein, we anchor Pt&#63743;Ni nanoalloy clusters (Pt&#8208;Ni NACs) on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene oxide (NrGO) by a facile microwave&#8208;assisted synthesis and analyze the variations of catalyst properties based on the Pt&#63743;Ni composition and the presence of nitrogen. Ni inclusion in the Pt matrix can induce lattice strain and change the electronic structure, while the doped nitrogen into the graphene can enhance electron transfer and improve the durability of the catalyst through strong chemical bonding with the alloy clusters. TEM analysis discovers that the NACs are uniformly decorated in a few&#8208;nanometer&#8208;size on the graphene surface, and the formation of the Pt&#63743;Ni NACs and structural changes according to composition are confirmed through XRD and XPS. In addition, the structural changes due to N&#8208;doping and its bonding with the NACs are observed through Raman spectroscopy and XPS. Electrochemical measurements reveal that Pt 2.6 Ni NACs/NrGO exhibits the highest ORR onset potential (0.893 V) and the lowest HER overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 (22 mV) among other catalysts, and those activities are almost unchanged under long&#8208;term durability tests. From these results, Pt 2.6 Ni NACs/NrGO is utilized in a zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB) system, demonstrating better battery performance than commercial Pt and Ir&#8208;based catalysts. Moreover, it is applied to hydrogen collection, showing linear trend in hydrogen production over time, confirming the catalyst's availability in hydrogen production and utilization. image</description>
      <author>Seung Geun Jo, Gil&#8208;Ryeong Park, Jemin Kim, D. Ahn, Rahul Ramkumar, Sun&#8208;I Kim, Duck Hyun Lee, Jung Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbe-electrode interactions on biocathodes are facilitated through tip-enhanced electric fields during CO2-fed microbial electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102262</link>
      <description>Ning Xue, Limin Liu, Richen Lin, Richard O&#8217;Shea, Chen Deng, Xiaoxu Xuan, Rongxin Xia, David Wall, Jerry D. Murphy, Cell Reports Physical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403825161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Xue, Limin Liu, Richen Lin, Richard O&#8217;Shea, Chen Deng, Xiaoxu Xuan, Rongxin Xia, David Wall, Jerry D. Murphy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Swiss Army Knife of Electrodes: Pillar[6]arene&#8208;Modified Electrodes for Molecular Electrocatalysis Over a Wide pH Range</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413144</link>
      <description>Helena Roithmeyer, Jan B&#252;hler, Olivier Blacque, Isik Tuncay, Thomas Moehl, Cristiano Invernizzi, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, S. David Tilley, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403848771

                Abstract Molecularly&#8208;modified electrode materials that maintain stability over a broad pH range are rare. Typically, each electrochemical transformation necessitates a specifically tuned system to achieve strong binding and high activity of the catalyst. Here, we report the functionalisation of mesoporous indium tin oxide (mITO) electrodes with the macrocyclic host molecule pillar[6]arene (PA[6]). These electrodes are stable within the pH range of 2.4&#8211;10.8 and can be equipped with electrochemically active ruthenium complexes through host&#8211;guest interactions to perform various oxidation reactions. Benzyl alcohol oxidation serves as a model reaction in acidic media, while ammonia oxidation is conducted to assess the systems performance under basic conditions. PA[6]&#8208;modified electrodes demonstrate catalytic activity for both reactions when complexed to different guest molecules and can be reused by reabsorption of the catalyst after its degradation. Furthermore, the system can be employed to perform subsequent reactions in electrolyte with varying pH, enabling the same electrode to be utilised in multiple different electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Helena Roithmeyer, Jan B&#252;hler, Olivier Blacque, Isik Tuncay, Thomas Moehl, Cristiano Invernizzi, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, S. David Tilley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Swiss Army Knife of Electrodes: Pillar[6]arene&#8208;Modified Electrodes for Molecular Electrocatalysis Over a Wide pH Range</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413144</link>
      <description>Helena Roithmeyer, Jan B&#252;hler, Olivier Blacque, Isik Tuncay, Thomas Moehl, Cristiano Invernizzi, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, S. David Tilley, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403848972

                Abstract Molecularly&#8208;modified electrode materials that maintain stability over a broad pH range are rare. Typically, each electrochemical transformation necessitates a specifically tuned system to achieve strong binding and high activity of the catalyst. Here, we report the functionalisation of mesoporous indium tin oxide (mITO) electrodes with the macrocyclic host molecule pillar[6]arene (PA[6]). These electrodes are stable within the pH range of 2.4&#8211;10.8 and can be equipped with electrochemically active ruthenium complexes through host&#8211;guest interactions to perform various oxidation reactions. Benzyl alcohol oxidation serves as a model reaction in acidic media, while ammonia oxidation is conducted to assess the systems performance under basic conditions. PA[6]&#8208;modified electrodes demonstrate catalytic activity for both reactions when complexed to different guest molecules and can be reused by reabsorption of the catalyst after its degradation. Furthermore, the system can be employed to perform subsequent reactions in electrolyte with varying pH, enabling the same electrode to be utilised in multiple different electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Helena Roithmeyer, Jan B&#252;hler, Olivier Blacque, Isik Tuncay, Thomas Moehl, Cristiano Invernizzi, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, S. David Tilley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Ingredients for the Modeling of Single&#8208;Atom Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400476</link>
      <description>Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403849366

                Abstract Single&#8208;atom catalysis is gaining interest also because of its potential applications in a broad spectrum of electrochemical reactions. The reactivity of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) is typically modeled with first principles approaches taking insight from heterogenous catalysis. An increasing number of studies show that the chemistry of SACs is more complex than often assumed, and shares many aspects in common with coordination chemistry. This evidence raises challenges for computational electrocatalysis of SACs. In this perspective we highlight a few fundamental ingredients that one need to consider to provide reliable predictions on the reactivity of SACs for electrochemical applications. We discuss the role of the local coordination of the metal active phase, the need to use self&#8208;interaction corrected functionals, in particular when systems have magnetic ground states. We highlight the formation of unconventional intermediates with respect to classical metal electrodes, the need to include the stability of SACs in electrochemical conditions and the role of solvation in the analysis of new potential catalytic systems. This brief account can be considered as a tutorial underlining the importance of treating the reactivity of SACs. In fact, neglecting some of these aspects could lead to unreliable predictions failing in the design of new electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective and durable H2O2 electrosynthesis catalyst in acid by selenization induced straining and phasing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53607-5</link>
      <description>Zhiyong Yu, Hao Deng, Qing Yao, Liangqun Zhao, Fei Xue, Tianou He, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Xiaoqing Huang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403852415

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyong Yu, Hao Deng, Qing Yao, Liangqun Zhao, Fei Xue, Tianou He, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Xiaoqing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53607-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double-Shell Confinement Strategy Enhancing Durability of PtFeTi Intermetallic Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04779</link>
      <description>Chen Sumin, Lai-Ke Chen, Na Tian, Sheng-Nan Hu, Shuangli Yang, Jun&#8208;Fei Shen, Jing-Xiao Tang, De&#8208;Yin Wu, Mingshu Chen, Zhi&#8208;You Zhou, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403869883

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Sumin, Lai-Ke Chen, Na Tian, Sheng-Nan Hu, Shuangli Yang, Jun&#8208;Fei Shen, Jing-Xiao Tang, De&#8208;Yin Wu, Mingshu Chen, Zhi&#8208;You Zhou, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elastic constants from charge density distribution in FCC high-entropy alloys using CNN and DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229105</link>
      <description>Hossein Mirzaee, Ramin Soltanmohammadi, Nathan Linton, J. FISCHER, Serveh Kamrava, Pejman Tahmasebi, Dilpuneet S. Aidhy, APL Machine Learning. 2(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403871417

                While high-entropy alloys (HEAs) present exponentially large compositional space for alloy design, they also create enormous computational challenges to trace the compositional space, especially for the inherently expensive density functional theory calculations (DFT). Recent works have integrated machine learning into DFT to overcome these challenges. However, often these models require an intensive search of appropriate physics-based descriptors. In this paper, we employ a 3D convolutional neural network over just one descriptor, i.e., the charge density derived from DFT, to simplify and bypass the hunt for the descriptors. We show that the elastic constants of face-centered cubic multi-elemental alloys in the Ni&#8211;Cu&#8211;Au&#8211;Pd&#8211;Pt system can be predicted from charge density. In addition, using our recent PREDICT approach, we show that the model can be trained only on the charge densities of simpler binary and ternary alloys to effectively predict elastic constants in complex multi-elemental alloys, thereby further enabling easier property-tracing in the large compositional space of HEAs.</description>
      <author>Hossein Mirzaee, Ramin Soltanmohammadi, Nathan Linton, J. FISCHER, Serveh Kamrava, Pejman Tahmasebi, Dilpuneet S. Aidhy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Formation of C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Products Steered by Bridge-Bonded *CO Confined by *OH Domains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08755</link>
      <description>Haibin Ma, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez-Al&#233;, Futian You, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z, Boon Siang Yeo, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403879378

                During the electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR) on copper catalysts, linear-bonded CO (*COL) is commonly regarded as the key intermediate for the CO-CO coupling step, which leads to the formation of multicarbon products. In this work, we unveil the significant role of bridge-bonded *CO (*COB) as an active species. By combining in situ Raman spectroscopy, gas and liquid chromatography, and density functional theory (DFT) simulations, we show that adsorbed *OH domains displace *COL to *COB. The electroreduction of a 12CO+13CO2 cofeed demonstrates that *COB distinctly favors the production of acetate and 1-propanol, while *COL favors ethylene and ethanol formation. This work enhances our understanding of the mechanistic intricacies of eCO(2)RR and suggests new directions for designing operational conditions by modifying the competitive adsorption of surface species, thereby steering the reaction toward specific multicarbon products.</description>
      <author>Haibin Ma, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez-Al&#233;, Futian You, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z, Boon Siang Yeo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and compositional optimization of bimetallic NiCo alloy nanoparticles for promotion of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235641</link>
      <description>Bishnupad Mohanty, Lingaraj Pradhan, Biswarup Satpati, Parasmani Rajput, Mahdi Ghorbani&#8208;Asl, Yidan Wei, Prashanth W. Menezes, Arkady V. Krasheninnikov, Bikash Kumar Jena, Journal of Power Sources. 625(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885372

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bishnupad Mohanty, Lingaraj Pradhan, Biswarup Satpati, Parasmani Rajput, Mahdi Ghorbani&#8208;Asl, Yidan Wei, Prashanth W. Menezes, Arkady V. Krasheninnikov, Bikash Kumar Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the limitations of layered LiNiO2: Insights from DFT simulations on its viability as a cathode material for aqueous Lithium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235650</link>
      <description>Gibu George, Artur Brotons&#8208;Rufes, Albert Poater, Miquel Sol&#224;, Sergio Posada&#8208;P&#233;rez, Journal of Power Sources. 625(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885407

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gibu George, Artur Brotons&#8208;Rufes, Albert Poater, Miquel Sol&#224;, Sergio Posada&#8208;P&#233;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated water dissociation kinetics by nickel-nickelous hydroxide epitaxial interfaces for superior alkaline hydrogen generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.141</link>
      <description>Ya-Fei Cheng, Yanlong Li, Zhenyu Qiao, Lulu Hu, Hongbo Geng, Huilong Dong, Fan Liao, Mingwang Shao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya-Fei Cheng, Yanlong Li, Zhenyu Qiao, Lulu Hu, Hongbo Geng, Huilong Dong, Fan Liao, Mingwang Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-space visualization of atomic displacements in a long-wavelength charge density wave using cryogenic 4D-STEM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.104414</link>
      <description>Haoyang Ni, William R. Meier, H. Miao, Andrew F. May, B. C. Sales, Jian&#8208;Min Zuo, Miaofang Chi, Physical Review Materials. 8(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403888133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoyang Ni, William R. Meier, H. Miao, Andrew F. May, B. C. Sales, Jian&#8208;Min Zuo, Miaofang Chi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.104414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid confinement of Pt-Ni-Co spherical core-shells in multibranched nano-dendrites interspersed on N-doped aerogels for enhanced ORR performance and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177307</link>
      <description>Muhammad Umair Mushtaq, Danni Li, Xiang Shao, Khurram Shahzad Ayub, Ali Shan, Limei Cao, Ji Yang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403898069

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Umair Mushtaq, Danni Li, Xiang Shao, Khurram Shahzad Ayub, Ali Shan, Limei Cao, Ji Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electrochemical Synthesis of Urea on Triatomic Cluster/Cu Catalysts: A Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105349</link>
      <description>Qiang Liu, Jingnan Wang, Yongan Yang, Xi Wang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403902171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Liu, Jingnan Wang, Yongan Yang, Xi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional SnS2/ZrSi2N4 van der Waals heterojunction as a spontaneously enhanced hydrogen evolution photocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110816</link>
      <description>Ying Hu, Feilong Xiong, Chaoyi Xin, Sheng Wang, Zhengquan Li, Kai-Wu Luo, Kejun Dong, Liang Xu, Materials Today Communications. 41(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403904649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Hu, Feilong Xiong, Chaoyi Xin, Sheng Wang, Zhengquan Li, Kai-Wu Luo, Kejun Dong, Liang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing 2D PtSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/PtCo Heterojunctions by Partial Selenization for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413916</link>
      <description>Bing Hao, Manyuan Gan, Jingjing Guo, Li Guo, Yanhui Song, Yongqing Shen, Bingshe Xu, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403792023

                Abstract The rational design and fabrication of 2D heterojuctions are proven a promising strategy for boosting the performance of electrocatalysts. Although 2D platinum diselenide (PtSe 2 ) exhibits catalytic activity for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the catalytic performance is still unsatisfactory due to its inert basal plane, wide bandgap, and poor electron transfer ability. Herein, a new strategy is reported to construct PtSe 2 /PtCo heterojunctions by partial selenization of PtCo alloy for high&#8208;efficiency HER electrocatalyst, which exhibits a low overpotential of 38 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , a small Tafel slope of 22 mV dec &#8722;1 , and a superior stability over 24 h and 1000 cycles. The outstanding HER activity of the catalyst arises from the strong electronic interactions between PtSe 2 and PtCo in the heterojunctions, which induce electron transferring from PtSe 2 to PtCo and the d&#8208;band center down shifting, and thus optimize the H * adsorption/desorption. This work provides a novel strategy for constructing highly efficient heterostructure electrocatalysts, which facilitates the applications of hydrogen energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Bing Hao, Manyuan Gan, Jingjing Guo, Li Guo, Yanhui Song, Yongqing Shen, Bingshe Xu, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward AI/ML-assisted discovery of transition metal complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.arcc.2024.10.003</link>
      <description>H.-Q. Jin, Kenneth M. Merz, Annual reports in computational chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403897047

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H.-Q. Jin, Kenneth M. Merz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.arcc.2024.10.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal reduction of CO2 captured by aqueous amine solutions into formate: comparison between in situ generated H2 and gaseous H2 as reductant and evaluation of amine stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100333</link>
      <description>Laura Quintana-G&#243;mez, Luama Ara&#250;jo dos Santos, Fernando Cossio-Cid, V&#237;ctor Ciordia-Asenjo, Miguel Almarza, Alberto Goikoechea, Sergio Ferrero, Celedonio M. &#193;lvarez, Jos&#233; J. Segovia, &#193;ngel Mart&#237;n, M. Dolores Bermejo, Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403901788

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Laura Quintana-G&#243;mez, Luama Ara&#250;jo dos Santos, Fernando Cossio-Cid, V&#237;ctor Ciordia-Asenjo, Miguel Almarza, Alberto Goikoechea, Sergio Ferrero, Celedonio M. &#193;lvarez, Jos&#233; J. Segovia, &#193;ngel Mart&#237;n, M. Dolores Bermejo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2024.100333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of anion exchange membrane-based electrochemical CO2 separation cells for direct air capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.10.049</link>
      <description>Ji Eon Chae, Jiseon Choi, Dongkeun Lee, Sunyoup Lee, Seonyeob Kim, Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403905064

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ji Eon Chae, Jiseon Choi, Dongkeun Lee, Sunyoup Lee, Seonyeob Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.10.049</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
