<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 01:09:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Design, Synthesis, and Electronic Structure Modulation of ORR Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113417</link>
      <description>Muhammad Arif, Ayaz Mahsud, Tahir Muhmood, Francis Leonard Deepak, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399941270

                Due to the environmental deterioration caused by modern industrialization, the key focus of researchers worldwide is diverted toward clean and sustainable energy sources, such as fuel cells and metal-air batteries, where the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at the cathode plays a central role. Unfortunately, the sluggish kinetics at the cathode of the ORR, in which the platinum-based (Pt-based) catalyst plays a critical role, is the principal impediment to commercialization. Pt and Pt-based, cutting-edge ORR electrocatalysts suffer from high cost, low methanol tolerance, and poor stability. Researchers have made tremendous efforts towards substitution of Pt-based catalysts, and significant achievements were accomplished in the form of alternatives such as metal oxides, nitrides, chalcogenides, carbides, metal-free nanocarbon, and metal-nitrogen/carbon (M-N/C) nanocomposites. Among these innumerable substitutes of Pt-based catalysts, M-N/C shows great potential because of their high stability, high methanol tolerance, and admirable ORR activities. In this review, we have summarized the principles and factors determining the rate of ORR, which are related to different surface planes of the crystal, surface area, and electronic structure tunability, where the morphology, multiple heteroatom-doping, and controlled particle size play a vital role. Furthermore, we have also discussed the synthetic protocol of different ORR materials such as Pt-based, metal chalcogenides, metal oxides, and M-N/C nanocomposites and the challenges related to these materials. Hopefully, this review will provide a status update as well as new directions to the scientific community engaged in designing novel catalytic materials for energy and environmental applications.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Arif, Ayaz Mahsud, Tahir Muhmood, Francis Leonard Deepak</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect to unlock the activity and stability for oxygen evolution reaction in spinel LiMn2O4 via d-block metal substitution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124331</link>
      <description>J Li, Linlin Liu, Jianghua Wu, Zhiwei Hu, Yi&#8208;Ying Chin, Hong-Ji Lin, Chien-Te Chen, Xiaoqing Pan, Yu Deng, Nicolas Alonso&#8208;Vante, Lijun Sui, Yu Xie, Jian&#8208;Chun Ma, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399956855

                An effective strategy using d-block metal hybridization was proposed to induce electronic interaction and promote the synergistic effect, aiming to enhance the OER performance of cost-effective spinel LiMn2O4. Indeed, we deploy a series of LiNixMn2-xO4 catalysts substituted with Ni, yielding the increase of Mn valence states from Mn3.5+ to Mn4+. The LiNi0.5Mn1.5O4 catalyst achieved an excellent OER performance in alkaline media, with an overpotential reduction more than 320 mV at 10 mA cm-2 compared to the unsubstituted LiMn2O4, as well as the electrochemical stability. It was shown to be superior to most reported Mn-based oxide OER electrocatalysts. Theoretical calculations demonstrated that Ni dopes holes in the Mn site, leading to an increase in Mn4+, and that the shared covalent network of Ni 3d-O 2p-Mn 3d optimized an easier desorption of intermediates. These results pave a new example for modulating the chemisorption strength, thus enabling activating the activity and stability of the OER process for cost-effective electrocatalysts based on spinel Mn oxides.</description>
      <author>J Li, Linlin Liu, Jianghua Wu, Zhiwei Hu, Yi&#8208;Ying Chin, Hong-Ji Lin, Chien-Te Chen, Xiaoqing Pan, Yu Deng, Nicolas Alonso&#8208;Vante, Lijun Sui, Yu Xie, Jian&#8208;Chun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124331</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial growth of highly atomically ordered Pt-Fe nanoparticles from carbon nanotube bundles as durable oxygen reduction electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.06.009</link>
      <description>Jibao He, Chao Chen, Hailong Yu, Yang Zhao, Maotian Xu, Tao Xiong, Qian Lu, Zhi Gen Yu, Kaiping Tai, Jinting Tan, Chang Liu, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399980742

                Intermetallic Pt-based nanoparticles have displayed excellent activity for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in fuel cells. However, it remains a great challenge to synthesize highly atomically ordered Pt-based nanoparticle catalysts because the formation of an atomically ordered structure usually requires high-temperature annealing accompanied by grain sintering. Here we report the direct epitaxial growth of well-aligned, highly atomically ordered Pt3Fe and PtFe nanoparticles (&lt; 5 nm) on single-walled carbon nanotube (SWCNT) bundle films. The long-range periodically symmetric van der Waals (vdW) interactions between SWCNT bundles and Pt-Fe nanoparticles play an important role in promoting not only the alignment ordering of inter-nanoparticles but also the atomic ordering of intra-nanoparticles. The ordered Pt3Fe/SWCNT hybrid catalyst showed enhanced ORR catalytic performance of 2.3-fold higher mass activity and 3.1-fold higher specific activity than commercial Pt/C. Moreover, the formation of an interlocked interface and strong vdW interaction endow the Pt-Fe/SWCNT catalysts with extreme long-term stability in potential cycling and excellent anti-thermal sintering ability.</description>
      <author>Jibao He, Chao Chen, Hailong Yu, Yang Zhao, Maotian Xu, Tao Xiong, Qian Lu, Zhi Gen Yu, Kaiping Tai, Jinting Tan, Chang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.06.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ar/NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Plasma Etching of Cobalt&#8208;Nickel Selenide Microspheres Rich in Selenium Vacancies Wrapped with Nitrogen Doped Carbon Nanotubes as Highly Efficient Air Cathode Catalysts for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400565</link>
      <description>Yangyang Feng, Weiheng Chen, Lingyan Zhao, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Xiaoning Tian, Zhongqing Jiang, Small methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399983084

                Abstract This work utilizes defect engineering, heterostructure, pyridine N&#8208;doping, and carbon supporting to enhance cobalt&#8208;nickel selenide microspheres' performance in the oxygen electrode reaction. Specifically, microspheres mainly composed of CoNiSe 2 and Co 9 Se 8 heterojunction rich in selenium vacancies (V Se&#183; ) wrapped with nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes (p&#8208;CoNiSe/NCNT@CC) are prepared by Ar/NH 3 radio frequency plasma etching technique. The synthesized p&#8208;CoNiSe/NCNT@CC shows high oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance (half&#8208;wave potential (E 1/2 ) = 0.878 V and limiting current density (J L ) = 21.88 mA cm &#8722;2 ). The J L exceeds the 20 wt% Pt/C (19.34 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and the E 1/2 is close to the 20 wt% Pt/C (0.881 V). It also possesses excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance (overpotential of 324 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), which even exceeds that of the commercial RuO 2 (427 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ). The density functional theory calculation indicates that the enhancement of ORR performance is attributed to the synergistic effect of plasma&#8208;induced V Se&#183; and the CoNiSe 2 &#8208;Co 9 Se 8 heterojunction. The p&#8208;CoNiSe/NCNT@CC electrode assembled Zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) show a peak power density of 138.29 mW cm &#8722;2 , outperforming the 20 wt% Pt/C+RuO 2 (73.9 mW cm &#8722;2 ) and other recently reported catalysts. Furthermore, all&#8208;solid&#8208;state ZAB delivers a high peak power density of 64.83 mW cm &#8722;2 and ultra&#8208;robust cycling stability even under bending.</description>
      <author>Yangyang Feng, Weiheng Chen, Lingyan Zhao, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Xiaoning Tian, Zhongqing Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight on Strain Relaxation Effect in Perovskites for High&#8208;Temperature Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401307</link>
      <description>Hyunmin Kim, Chaesung Lim, Jimin Gu, Hu Young Jeong, Jeong Woo Han, Ji&#8208;Hyun Jang, Yunfei Bu, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399983726

                Abstract The size of in situ exsolved nanoparticles (NPs) significantly affects the electrochemical and electro&#8208;catalytic properties of oxide supports. Unfortunately, the instrumental factor affecting the exsolved NP size in poly&#8208;crystalline perovskite oxides is still unexplored. Herein, the inherent micro&#8208;strain (&#949;) value as an unprecedented factor in controlling the exsolved NP size of Pr 0.5 Ba 0.5&#8208; x Sr x Fe 0.85 Ni 0.15 O 3&#8208; &#948; ( x = 0.3, 0.4, and 0.5) is introduced, wherein smaller NP size is successfully obtained via strain relaxation strategy. The effect of exsolved NP size on the fuel oxidation reaction kinetics at high&#8208;temperature regimes is evaluated in&#8208;depth by using density functional theory (DFT) calculations. In accordance with the insights provided by DFT calculations, the electro&#8208;catalyst featuring the smallest Fe 3 Ni NP size via strain relaxation strategy demonstrates exceptional electrochemical performance along with robust durability toward high&#8208;temperature hydrogen oxidation reaction. This work presents scientific guidance for tailoring the exsolved NP size in perovskites, thereby paving the way for designing rational perovskite electro&#8208;catalysts in various energy&#8208;related applications.</description>
      <author>Hyunmin Kim, Chaesung Lim, Jimin Gu, Hu Young Jeong, Jeong Woo Han, Ji&#8208;Hyun Jang, Yunfei Bu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sodium-assisted MoS2 for boosting CO2 hydrogenation to methanol: The crucial role of sodium in defect evolution and modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115621</link>
      <description>Zhen Zhang, Juan Zuo, Luteng Luo, Xinghua Yang, Zhiyuan Ma, Hongjun Jin, Youzhu Yuan, Qingrong Qian, Qinghua Chen, Yong-Chun Luo, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399986594

                The effective conversion of CO2 to methanol utilizing green hydrogen under moderate conditions represents a promising approach for achieving carbon neutrality. MoS2 demonstrates exceptional catalytic performance at temperatures below 200 &#176;C, however, generating in-plane sulfur defects is challenging due to the intact planar structure. Introducing heteroatoms to induce sulfur vacancy formation and modulate their chemical environment remains a significant obstacle. In this study, we developed a NaCl-assisted method for synthesizing MoS2 and discovered that a small quantity of sodium not only promotes the formation of sulfur vacancies during the induction period, but also encourages CO2 hydrogenation via the carboxylate route, as opposed to the CO2 dissociation to CO* route over non-modified sulfur vacancies. Furthermore, catalysts at various stages throughout the 60 h induction period were characterized, revealing that the increase in sulfur vacancies and enhanced H2 dissociation capability are primary factors contributing to improved methanol yield. The sodium-modified MoS2 achieves a methanol space&#8211;time yield of up to 571 mgMeOH gcat&#8722;1h&#8722;1 at 200 &#176;C and 5 MPa with a 4.8 % CO2 conversion and 96 % methanol selectivity. The turnover frequency based on total sulfur vacancies reaches 170 h&#8722;1. This research is anticipated to offer a new strategy for enhancing the catalytic performance of CO2 hydrogenation to methanol using heteroatom-assisted defect engineering.</description>
      <author>Zhen Zhang, Juan Zuo, Luteng Luo, Xinghua Yang, Zhiyuan Ma, Hongjun Jin, Youzhu Yuan, Qingrong Qian, Qinghua Chen, Yong-Chun Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Electroreduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to C&lt;sub&gt;2+&lt;/sub&gt; Alcohols Using Graphitic Frustrated Lewis Pair Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04275</link>
      <description>Hyun-Tak Kim, Jaehyun Park, Jinhong Mun, HyeonOh Shin, Deok&#8208;Ho Roh, Junhyeok Kwon, Sung&#8208;Tae Kim, Sang-Joon Kim, Geunsik Lee, Seok Ju Kang, Tae&#8208;Hyuk Kwon, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399993700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyun-Tak Kim, Jaehyun Park, Jinhong Mun, HyeonOh Shin, Deok&#8208;Ho Roh, Junhyeok Kwon, Sung&#8208;Tae Kim, Sang-Joon Kim, Geunsik Lee, Seok Ju Kang, Tae&#8208;Hyuk Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c04275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of Z-Scheme Photocatalysis for Total Water Splitting: An Improvised Route to High Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01162</link>
      <description>Atish Ghosh, Anup Pramanik, Sougata Pal, Pranab Sarkar, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399998814

                Photocatalytic water splitting to spontaneously produce H2 and O2 is a long-standing goal in solar energy conversion, presenting a significant challenge without using sacrificial electron donors or external biases. Inspired by natural photosynthesis, the design of artificial Z-scheme photocatalytic systems is at the forefront of this field. These systems achieve higher redox potential by separating photogenerated electrons and holes through a fast interlayer recombination process between valence and conduction band edges. Z-scheme photocatalysis involves using two different semiconductors with distinct bandgap energies. Here, we explore potential systems based on two-dimensional (2D) heterostructures composed of carbon, nitrogen, or similar main group elements. The advantages and disadvantages of these systems are discussed, with a focus on enhancing their efficiency through strategic design. Special emphasis is placed on the dynamics of excited charge carrier transfer and recombination processes, which are crucial for developing efficient photocatalytic systems for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Atish Ghosh, Anup Pramanik, Sougata Pal, Pranab Sarkar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of electrocatalysts for hydrogen oxidation reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.152</link>
      <description>Youze Zeng, Xue Wang, Yang Hu, Wei Qi, Zheng Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, Jianguo Zhu, Carbon neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400000471

                Abstract Anion exchange membrane fuel cells (AEMFCs) have been hailed as a promising hydrogen energy technology due to high energy conversion efficiency, zero carbon emission and the potential independence on scare and expensive noble metal electrocatalysts. A variety of platinum group metal (PGM)&#8208;free catalysts has been developed with superior catalytic performance to noble metal benchmarks toward cathodic oxygen reduction reactions (ORR). However, PGM electrocatalysts still dominate the anodic catalyst research because the kinetics of hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) are two or three orders of magnitude slower than in that acidic media. Therefore, it is urgently desirable to improve noble metal utilization efficiency and/or develop high&#8208;performance PGM&#8208;free electrocatalysts for HOR, thus promoting the real&#8208;world implementation of AEMFCs. In this review, the current research progress of electrocatalysts for HOR in alkaline media is summarized. We start with the discussion on the current HOR reaction mechanisms and existing controversies. Then, methodologies to improve the HOR performance are reviewed. Following these principles, the recently developed HOR electrocatalysts including PGM and PGM&#8208;free HOR electrocatalysts in alkaline media are systematically introduced. Finally, we put forward the challenges and prospects in the field of HOR catalysis.</description>
      <author>Youze Zeng, Xue Wang, Yang Hu, Wei Qi, Zheng Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, Jianguo Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WyCryst: Wyckoff inorganic crystal generator framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2024.05.042</link>
      <description>Ruiming Zhu, Wei Nong, Shuya Yamazaki, Kedar Hippalgaonkar, Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400001790

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruiming Zhu, Wei Nong, Shuya Yamazaki, Kedar Hippalgaonkar</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2024.05.042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From 2e&#8722; to 4e&#8722; pathway in the alkaline oxygen reduction reaction on Au(100): Kinetic circumvention of the volcano curve</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211477</link>
      <description>Yuke Li, Bing-Yu Liu, Yan&#8208;Xia Chen, Zhi-Feng Liu, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400006273

                We report the free energy barriers for the elementary reactions in the 2e&#8722; and 4e&#8722; oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) steps on Au(100) in an alkaline solution. Due to the weak adsorption energy of O2 on Au(100), the barrier for the association channel is very low, and the 2e&#8722; pathway is clearly favored, while the barrier for the O&#8211;O dissociation channel is significantly higher at 0.5 eV. Above 0.7 V reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), the association channel becomes thermodynamically unfavorable, which opens up the O&#8211;O dissociation channel, leading to the 4e&#8722; pathway. The low adsorption energy of oxygenated species on Au is now an advantage, and residue ORR current can be observed up to the 1.0&#8211;1.2 V region (RHE). In contrast, the O&#8211;O dissociation barrier on Au(111) is significantly higher, at close to 0.9 eV, due to coupling with surface reorganization, which explains the lower ORR activity on Au(111) than that on Au(100). In combination with the previously suggested outer sphere electron transfer to O2 for its initial adsorption, these results provide a consistent explanation for the features in the experimentally measured polarization curve for the alkaline ORR on Au(100) and demonstrate an ORR mechanism distinct from that on Pt(111). It also highlights the importance to consider the spin state of O2 in ORR and to understand the activation barriers, in addition to the adsorption energies, to account for the features observed in electrochemical measurements.</description>
      <author>Yuke Li, Bing-Yu Liu, Yan&#8208;Xia Chen, Zhi-Feng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0211477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering and Design of Halide Perovskite Photoelectrochemical Cells for Solar&#8208;Driven Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405414</link>
      <description>Saikiran Khamgaonkar, Anny Leudjo Taka, Vivek Maheshwari, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400008004

                Abstract Photoelectrochemical cells (PEC) use solar energy to generate green hydrogen by water splitting and have an integrated device structure. Achieving high solar&#8208;to&#8208;hydrogen conversion (STH) efficiency along with a long operational lifetime in these cells is crucial for the production of low&#8208;cost green hydrogen as a viable energy source. Several functional components, such as photo absorber, charge transport, and catalyst layers are interfaced in these cells to form a compact monolithic device. In this review, therefore, the engineering and design of the individual components of these cells, the interplay between them, and their interfaces are discussed in detail, as these factors determine the overall performance of the cells. The main emphasis is on halide perovskite (HP) photo absorbers, which have emerged as promising materials for use in these cells due to their superior optoelectronic properties. Recent advances in the development of efficient and stable perovskite&#8208;based cells are highlighted and reviewed. The design of catalysts for water splitting and the effect of factors such as pH and supporting cations are also examined. Finally, the scientific challenges and future directions for designing perovskite&#8208;based photoelectrochemical cells are discussed. This review can help researchers further advance this technology toward commercial production of green hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Saikiran Khamgaonkar, Anny Leudjo Taka, Vivek Maheshwari</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial growth of Pd clusters on N-doped Ag nanowires for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphma.2024.06.004</link>
      <description>Qingxin Guan, Shiwei Sun, Xiao Ge, Fan Zhang, Lijun Qu, Chunrong Yin, Weiyong Yuan, Lian Ying Zhang, ChemPhysMater. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400016345

                Efficient and stable Pt-free electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are indispensable for future fuel cells. Herein, we describe a heterostructure of Pd nanocrystals (PdNCs) on N-doped Ag nanowires (NWs) synthesized using a direct epitaxial growth strategy with a Pd loading of only 9.5 wt.%. The PdAg bimetallic heterostructure showed the highest mass activity among reported PdAg-based ORR electrocatalysts and exhibited excellent stability, with only a 1.5 mV decay in the half-wave potential even after 20000 cycles of continuous testing. The remarkably enhanced activity and durability can be attributed to the distinct advantages of the ultrasmall PdNCs, cocatalysts of N-doped AgNWs, and their heterointerfaces. This work reveals that the epitaxial growth of a heterostructure on a stable support is a promising strategy for promoting catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Qingxin Guan, Shiwei Sun, Xiao Ge, Fan Zhang, Lijun Qu, Chunrong Yin, Weiyong Yuan, Lian Ying Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphma.2024.06.004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat-Induced Aliquation and Phosphating of Nickel as Efficient Catalysts for Hydrogen Evolution in Alkaline Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101635</link>
      <description>Peng&#8208;Jun Deng, Yaxuan Wang, Yang Liu, Jiajia Lu, Han&#8208;Pu Liang, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400016692

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng&#8208;Jun Deng, Yaxuan Wang, Yang Liu, Jiajia Lu, Han&#8208;Pu Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101635</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensitivity Analysis of Electrochemical Double Layer Approximations on Electrokinetic Predictions: Case Study for CO Reduction on Copper</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01457</link>
      <description>Andrew Jark-Wah Wong, Bolton Tran, Naveen Agrawal, Bryan R. Goldsmith, Michael J. Janik, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400017419

                Density functional theory (DFT) modeling has been useful to electrocatalyst research, yet simulating the complexities of the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface hinders progress in understanding reaction mechanisms and the underlying kinetics. Though many approaches to incorporating electrochemical double layer (EDL) features in DFT calculations have been developed, uncertainty in interfacial solvent properties and the distribution of ions leave the impact of the EDL on electrocatalytic kinetics unclear. Elucidating the sensitivity of DFT predictions to the EDL properties and model is crucial. Herein, we use an analytical Grand Canonical DFT framework (aGC-DFT) to quantify the sensitivity of potential-dependent activation energies to parameters of the EDL, incorporating a Helmholtz EDL model with varying dielectric constant (&#949;r) and EDL width (d). We compute the activation barriers for OC&#8211;H, CO&#8211;H, and OC&#8211;CO bond formation from CO* on Cu. These elementary reactions are critical within the heavily debated reaction mechanism of CO2 reduction and are likely to impact overall activity and product selectivity. We show the aGC-DFT method produces consistent results with explicit GC-DFT calculations, while enabling probing of the EDL model sensitivity at a much lower computational cost. Reaction steps with significant dipole moment changes (i.e., CO&#8211;H bond formation) are highly sensitive to the chosen EDL parameters, such that the relative barriers of the OC&#8211;H, CO&#8211;H, and OC&#8211;CO bond formation steps depend significantly on EDL properties. Without knowledge of the interfacial properties of the EDL, there is substantial uncertainty in activation barriers and elementary reaction rates within a DFT analysis of electrocatalytic kinetics.</description>
      <author>Andrew Jark-Wah Wong, Bolton Tran, Naveen Agrawal, Bryan R. Goldsmith, Michael J. Janik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pathways and Enhancement Strategies for Magnesium Hardness Removal in Modified Induced Crystallization Softening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4877890</link>
      <description>c. h. LI, Cheng Liu, Yun Han, Wenjing Xu, Bing Yan, Aijun Du, Qin Li, Yu Qian, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400027614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>c. h. LI, Cheng Liu, Yun Han, Wenjing Xu, Bing Yan, Aijun Du, Qin Li, Yu Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4877890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TSeC: an efficient transition state search tool driven by machine learning potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-28824-1.50560-3</link>
      <description>Kun Tang, Lei Zhang, Qingwei Meng, Jian Du, Qilei Liu, Computer-aided chemical engineering/Computer aided chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400032180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kun Tang, Lei Zhang, Qingwei Meng, Jian Du, Qilei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-28824-1.50560-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin, large area &#946;-Ni(OH)2 crystalline nanosheet as bifunctional electrode material for charge storage and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.167</link>
      <description>Sayali Ashok Patil, Pallavi B. Jagdale, Narad Barman, Asif Iqbal, Amanda Sfeir, S&#233;bastien Royer, Ranjit Thapa, Akshaya K. Samal, Manav Saxena, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400036923

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sayali Ashok Patil, Pallavi B. Jagdale, Narad Barman, Asif Iqbal, Amanda Sfeir, S&#233;bastien Royer, Ranjit Thapa, Akshaya K. Samal, Manav Saxena</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Dynamics Study of the Effect of Grafting Density on Ion Diffusivity in a MARTINI Coarse-Grained Strong Polyelectrolyte Brush</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.macromol.4c01018</link>
      <description>Michael J. Boyle, Ravi Radhakrishnan, Russell J. Composto, Macromolecules. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400042181

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Michael J. Boyle, Ravi Radhakrishnan, Russell J. Composto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.macromol.4c01018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control Over Nitrogen Dopant Sites in Palladium Metallene for Manipulating Catalytic Activity and Stability in the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408264</link>
      <description>Tiantian Zeng, Mang Niu, Binghui Xu, Weiyong Yuan, Chunxian Guo, Dapeng Cao, Chang Ming Li, Lian Ying Zhang, Xin Zhao, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400045429

                Abstract Doping light elements in Pt&#8208;group metals is an effective approach toward improving their catalytic properties for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). However, it is challenging to control dopant sites and to establish the correlation between the doping site and the catalytic property. In this paper, this success is demonstrated in controlling N doping sites in Pd metallene to manipulate electrocatalytic properties toward ORR. A Pd metallene sample with N dopant predominantly located at the atomic vacancy site (V&#8208;N&#8208;Pd metallene) exhibits two times higher mass activity in ORR than a Pd metallene sample with N dopant mainly occupied the interstitial site (I&#8208;N&#8208;Pd metallene). However, the I&#8208;N&#8208;Pd metallene shows improved durability than the V&#8208;N&#8208;Pd metallene, with only a 4 mV decay in half&#8208;wave potential after 20 000 cycles. Computational calculation results reveal that the significantly enhanced ORR activity of V&#8208;N&#8208;Pd metallene arises from the atomic vacancy&#8208;doped N, which modulates the electronic structure of Pd metallene to weaken the adsorption energy of intermediate O * species. This work provides guidelines for manipulating catalytic properties by controlling the doping sites of light elements in metal nanostructures.</description>
      <author>Tiantian Zeng, Mang Niu, Binghui Xu, Weiyong Yuan, Chunxian Guo, Dapeng Cao, Chang Ming Li, Lian Ying Zhang, Xin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking water adsorption on metal surfaces with &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0205552</link>
      <description>Mian-Le Xu, Sihang Liu, Sudarshan Vijay, Thomas Bligaard, Georg Kastlunger, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400045624

                Solid&#8211;water interfaces are ubiquitous in nature and technology. In particular, technologies evolving in the green transition, such as electrocatalysis, heavily rely on the junction of an electrolyte and an electrode as a central part of the device. For the understanding of atomic-scale processes taking place at the electrolyte&#8211;electrode interface, density functional theory (DFT) has become the de facto standard. The validation of DFT&#8217;s ability to simulate the interfacial solid/water interaction is crucial, and ideal simulation setups need to be identified in order to prevent avoidable systematic errors. Here, we develop a rigorous sampling protocol for benchmarking the adsorption/desorption energetics of water on metallic surfaces against experimental temperature programmed desorption, single crystal adsorption calorimetry, and thermal energy atom scattering. We screened DFT&#8217;s quality on a series of transition metal surfaces, applying three of the most common exchange&#8211;correlation approximations: PBE-D3, RPBE-D3, and BEEF-vdW. We find that all three xc-functionals reflect the pseudo-zeroth order desorption of water rooted in the combination of attractive adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate interactions and their saturation at low and intermediate coverages, respectively. However, both RPBE-D3 and BEEF-vdW lead to more accurate water adsorption strengths, while PBE-D3 clearly overbinds near-surface water. We relate the variations in binding strength to specific variations in water&#8211;metal and water&#8211;water interactions, highlighting the structural consequences inherent in an uninformed choice of simulation parameters. Our study gives atomistic insight into water&#8217;s complex adsorption equilibrium. Furthermore, it represents a guideline for future DFT-based simulations of solvated solid interfaces by providing an assessment of systematic errors in specific setups.</description>
      <author>Mian-Le Xu, Sihang Liu, Sudarshan Vijay, Thomas Bligaard, Georg Kastlunger</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0205552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pH-dependent formation potential of OH&#8727; on Pt(111): Double layer effect on water dissociation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.05.009</link>
      <description>Xue Wang, Jiaxin Zhu, Yongbo Kuang, Jun Cheng, Jia&#8208;Bo Le, Nano materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400045888

                The adsorption/desorption of OH&#8727; on electrode surfaces is pivotal in numerous electrocatalytic reactions. To understand the effect of electrolyte pH on that process, in this work, an advanced approach combining ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) with free energy perturbation is employed to calculate the dehydrogenation free energy of water chemisorbed at differently electrified Pt(111)/electrolyte interfaces. Our findings reveal that the onset potential for OH&#8727; formation shifts negatively as the pH increases at low pH condition (pH&lt;4.3), aligning with the cyclic voltammetry curves observed in experimental studies. It indicates the dissociation of chemisorbed water is the primary route for OH&#8727; adsorption at low pH condition. Furthermore, it is also found that the variation in dehydrogenation energy across different pH is primarily due to the local hydrogen bonding network surrounding the chemisorbed water. In addition, it is proposed that at high pH conditions OH&#8722; oxidation emerges as the primary route for OH&#8727; adsorption on Pt(111) constrained by the water chemisorption process. This work provides crucial insights into the pH-dependent adsorption behavior of OH&#8727; on the Pt(111) surface and aims to guide the optimization of electrolytes to boost the efficiency of related reactions.</description>
      <author>Xue Wang, Jiaxin Zhu, Yongbo Kuang, Jun Cheng, Jia&#8208;Bo Le</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.05.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THD-C Sheet: A Novel Nonbenzenoid Carbon Allotrope with Tetra-, Hexa-, and Dodeca-Membered Rings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01870</link>
      <description>Trevor Jenkins, Alexander Silva, Marcos G. Menezes, Timo Thonhauser, Saif Ullah, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400059919

                We propose a novel two-dimensional carbon-based structure with tetra-, hexa-, and dodeca-membered rings, which we refer to by the abbreviated name, THD-C. The structure presents a mixture of sp&#8211;sp2 hybridization and can potentially be synthesized by the topological assembly of 4-ethynyldiphenylacetylene molecules. By employing first-principles calculations, the stability and ease of synthesis of the sheet are investigated and compared with various C-allotropes. We predict its metallic behavior and excellent kinetic and dynamic stability. Due to the crystal structure of the sheet, a strong mechanical anisotropy is observed. The effects of functionalization on the electronic properties of the material are also studied, and different semiconducting systems are obtained. The potential of THD-C for energy storage in metal-based batteries, hydrogen storage, and catalysis is also investigated, and we find a superior performance in comparison to graphite and other allotropes. The quantum confinement effect is investigated by constructing nanoribbons and nanotubes of various sizes. For ribbons, we find that tailor-made electronic and magnetic properties can be obtained and explored in potential spintronic devices. Additionally, we observe that nanotubes are conducting irrespective of their chirality and can potentially be used for capture, storage, and separation of industrially relevant small gas molecules.</description>
      <author>Trevor Jenkins, Alexander Silva, Marcos G. Menezes, Timo Thonhauser, Saif Ullah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron&#8211;Cobalt Phosphide Encapsulated in a N-Doped Carbon Framework as a Promising Low-Cost Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalyst for Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02077</link>
      <description>Jinlong Liu, Ziyu Luo, Jie Wu, Dong Qian, Weixiong Liao, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Xiangxiong Chen, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400060584

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) plays a vital role in many next-generation electrochemical energy conversion and storage devices, motivating the search for low-cost ORR electrocatalysts possessing high activity and excellent durability. In this work, we demonstrate that iron&#8211;cobalt phosphide (FeCoP) nanoparticles encapsulated in a N-doped carbon framework (FeCoP@NC) represent a very promising catalyst for the ORR in alkaline media. The core&#8211;shell structured FeCoP@NC catalyst offered outstanding ORR activity with a half-wave potential (E1/2) of 0.86 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) and excellent stability in a 0.1 M KOH electrolyte, outperforming commercial Pt/C and many recently reported noble-metal-free ORR electrocatalysts. The superiority of FeCoP@NC as an ORR electrocatalyst relative to Pt/C was further verified in prototype zinc-air batteries (ZABs), with the aqueous and flexible ZABs prepared using FeCoP@NC offering excellent stability, impressive open circuit voltages (1.56 and 1.44 V, respectively), and high maximum power densities (183.5 and 69.7 mW cm&#8211;2, respectively). Density functional theory calculations revealed that encapsulating FeCoP nanoparticles in N-doped carbon shells resulted in favorable electron penetration effects, which synergistically regulated the adsorption/desorption of ORR intermediates for optimal ORR performance while also boosting the electronic conductivity. Our findings offer valuable new insights for rational design of transition metal phosphide-based catalysts for the ORR and other electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Jinlong Liu, Ziyu Luo, Jie Wu, Dong Qian, Weixiong Liao, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Xiangxiong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt&#8211;Copper-Embedded Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Nanostructures Derived from Zeolite Imidazolate Frameworks as Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c01667</link>
      <description>Sunguk Noh, Hyejin Oh, Jihyun Kim, Sojin Jung, Jae&#8208;Hyun Shim, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400060752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sunguk Noh, Hyejin Oh, Jihyun Kim, Sojin Jung, Jae&#8208;Hyun Shim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c01667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A deep learning-based energy and force prediction framework for high-throughput quantum chemistry calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-28824-1.50120-4</link>
      <description>Guoxin Wu, Qilei Liu, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Lei Zhang, Computer-aided chemical engineering/Computer aided chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400062440

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoxin Wu, Qilei Liu, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-28824-1.50120-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First principles study on the type-II g-C6N6/PtSSe heterojunction: a potential photocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109685</link>
      <description>Qi Pang, Junjie Qian, Yuxuan Tang, Hui Li, Dangli Gao, You Xie, Yiyun Song, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400077243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Pang, Junjie Qian, Yuxuan Tang, Hui Li, Dangli Gao, You Xie, Yiyun Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Surface Chemistry of Copper Oxides through Annealing Environment for Enhanced Selective HMF Oxidation: A DFT-Electrochemical Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113444</link>
      <description>Nadia Mumtazah, Chen-Hui Chan, Stefani Catherine, Minh-Trang Huynh Pham, Ja&#8208;Yeon Choi, Jong Suk Yoo, Chia&#8208;Ying Chiang, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400080255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nadia Mumtazah, Chen-Hui Chan, Stefani Catherine, Minh-Trang Huynh Pham, Ja&#8208;Yeon Choi, Jong Suk Yoo, Chia&#8208;Ying Chiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering chemical ordering in High Entropy Materials: A machine learning-accelerated high-throughput cluster expansion approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120137</link>
      <description>Guillermo Vazquez, Daniel Sauceda, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave, Acta materialia. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400082110

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guillermo Vazquez, Daniel Sauceda, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2024.120137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective OER activity of rhombohedral nickel sulphide nanoparticles supported via reduced graphene oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111354</link>
      <description>Mohsin Majeed, Albandari W. Alrowaily, B.M. Alotaibi, Haifa A. Alyousef, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Khalid I. Hussein, Zubair Ahmad, Diamond and related materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400088573

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsin Majeed, Albandari W. Alrowaily, B.M. Alotaibi, Haifa A. Alyousef, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Khalid I. Hussein, Zubair Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-to-HCOOH Electroreduction on Graphdiyne-Supported Bimetallic Single-Cluster Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00858</link>
      <description>Bin Chen, Yafei Jiang, Hai Xiao, Jun Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400093530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Chen, Yafei Jiang, Hai Xiao, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical understanding of graphene supported hematite photoanode for solar-driven water splitting applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114912</link>
      <description>Labanya Bhattacharya, Avi Cohen, Maytal Caspary Toroker, Catalysis today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400105511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Labanya Bhattacharya, Avi Cohen, Maytal Caspary Toroker</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Mechanism of the Water&#8211;Gas Shift Reaction Activity Catalyzed by Au Single Atoms Supported on Multicomponent Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01559</link>
      <description>Jungwoo Choi, Hyuk Soon Choi, Ju Hyeok Lee, Eunji Kang, Kihyun Shin, Hyuck Mo Lee, Hyun You Kim, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400109282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jungwoo Choi, Hyuk Soon Choi, Ju Hyeok Lee, Eunji Kang, Kihyun Shin, Hyuck Mo Lee, Hyun You Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Electrocatalytic Activity Unveiled: Cu-Mo Bimetal Sulfo-Selenide Nanocomposite for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100894</link>
      <description>Sumanth Dongre S, Rohit Kumar, Bhubaneswar Paswan, Itika Kainthla, Amitava Banerjee, Jari S. Algethami, Mabkhoot Alsaiari, Farid A. Harraz, R. Shwetharani, R. Geetha Balakrishna, Materials today sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400109398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sumanth Dongre S, Rohit Kumar, Bhubaneswar Paswan, Itika Kainthla, Amitava Banerjee, Jari S. Algethami, Mabkhoot Alsaiari, Farid A. Harraz, R. Shwetharani, R. Geetha Balakrishna</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-step annealing synthesis of MOF-derived Cr-Co-Ru metallic oxides for improving the oxygen evolution reaction in acidic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104695</link>
      <description>Bohan Zhang, Chang Wen, Ming Xu, Qian Liu, Zhi Yong Zhang, Hongbo Huang, Dapeng Wang, Zhengkai Tu, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400109655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bohan Zhang, Chang Wen, Ming Xu, Qian Liu, Zhi Yong Zhang, Hongbo Huang, Dapeng Wang, Zhengkai Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Structural Evolution of Single Atom Catalysts during Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction by in Situ X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00554</link>
      <description>Lingzhe Fang, Mingyu Wan, Yuzi Liu, Benjamin Reinhart, Zehua Jin, Ming Yang, Fanglin Che, Tao Li, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400112845

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingzhe Fang, Mingyu Wan, Yuzi Liu, Benjamin Reinhart, Zehua Jin, Ming Yang, Fanglin Che, Tao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficient, selective, and stable photocatalytic methane coupling to ethane enabled by lattice oxygen looping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado4390</link>
      <description>Gaohong Zhai, Lejuan Cai, Jun Ma, Yihong Chen, Zehua Liu, Shenghe Si, Delong Duan, Shuaikang Sang, Jiawei Li, Xinyu Wang, Ying-Ao Liu, Bei Qian, Chengyuan Liu, Yang Pan, Ning Zhang, Dong Liu, Ran Long, Yujie Xiong, Science advances. 10(26)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400113120

                Light-driven oxidative coupling of methane (OCM) for multi-carbon (C</description>
      <author>Gaohong Zhai, Lejuan Cai, Jun Ma, Yihong Chen, Zehua Liu, Shenghe Si, Delong Duan, Shuaikang Sang, Jiawei Li, Xinyu Wang, Ying-Ao Liu, Bei Qian, Chengyuan Liu, Yang Pan, Ning Zhang, Dong Liu, Ran Long, Yujie Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado4390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient and Selective Nitrogen Reduction Reaction Catalysis of Cluster-Modified MXene Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01369</link>
      <description>Yu Rong, Zhaorui Liu, Dominik Legut, J. Sun, Qianfan Zhang, Joseph S. Francisco, Ruifang Zhang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400119996

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Rong, Zhaorui Liu, Dominik Legut, J. Sun, Qianfan Zhang, Joseph S. Francisco, Ruifang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles and experimental insight of high-entropy materials as electrocatalysts for energy-related applications: Hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, and oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2024.100813</link>
      <description>Jasmin S. Shaikh, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Victor M&#225;rquez, Navajsharif S. Shaikh, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Sumayya C. Pathan, Pongsakorn Kanjanaboos, Toshiaki Taniike, Mohammad Khaja Nazeeruddin, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, Materials science &amp; engineering. R, Reports. 160(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400120264

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jasmin S. Shaikh, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Victor M&#225;rquez, Navajsharif S. Shaikh, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Sumayya C. Pathan, Pongsakorn Kanjanaboos, Toshiaki Taniike, Mohammad Khaja Nazeeruddin, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2024.100813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Research on Iridium&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction from the Origin of Reaction Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403845</link>
      <description>L.-Y. Chen, Wei Zhao, Juntao Zhang, Min Liu, Jun Yin, Ru-Zhi Wang, Maorong Chai, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400122094

                As the anode reaction of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE), the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the main obstacles to the practical application of PEMWE due to its sluggish four-electron transfer process. The development of high-performance acidic OER electrocatalysts has become the key to improving the reaction kinetics. To date, although various excellent acidic OER electrocatalysts have been widely researched, Ir-based nanomaterials are still state-of-the-art electrocatalysts. Hence, a comprehensive and in-depth understanding of the reaction mechanism of Ir-based electrocatalysts is crucial for the precise optimization of catalytic performance. In this review, the origin and nature of the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) and the derived volcanic relationship on Ir-based electrocatalysts for acidic OER processes are summarized and some optimization strategies for Ir-based electrocatalysts based on the AEM are introduced. To further investigate the development strategy of high-performance Ir-based electrocatalysts, several unconventional OER mechanisms including dual-site mechanism and lattice oxygen mediated mechanism, and their applications are introduced in detail. Thereafter, the active species on Ir-based electrocatalysts at acidic OER are summarized and classified into surface Ir species and O species. Finally, the future development direction and prospect of Ir-based electrocatalysts for acidic OER are put forward.</description>
      <author>L.-Y. Chen, Wei Zhao, Juntao Zhang, Min Liu, Jun Yin, Ru-Zhi Wang, Maorong Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Calculations to Increase the Efficiency of Oxygen Electrode Catalysts from Ytterbium Single Atom Catalysts Using Nitrogen Solid Supports</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02434</link>
      <description>Tongtong Xu, Meiling Liu, Kang &#24247; Wu &#21556;, Chao Liu, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400129721

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tongtong Xu, Meiling Liu, Kang &#24247; Wu &#21556;, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02434</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different role of ruthenium and platinum defective sites on the catalytic activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114908</link>
      <description>D&#237;dac A. Fenoll, Mariona Sodupe, Xavier Solans&#8208;Monfort, Catalysis today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400139360

                No abstract</description>
      <author>D&#237;dac A. Fenoll, Mariona Sodupe, Xavier Solans&#8208;Monfort</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of CO2 reduction on two-dimensional porphyrin metal&#8211;organic frameworks modified with various metal paddlewheel clusters or phenyl</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114743</link>
      <description>X. An, Gaofeng Hu, Yueyang Zhang, Shaohui Guo, Xinxin Tian, Zhuxia Zhang, Computational and theoretical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400142737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>X. An, Gaofeng Hu, Yueyang Zhang, Shaohui Guo, Xinxin Tian, Zhuxia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Adsorption on Ordered and Disordered Pt&#8211;Fe and Pt&#8211;Co Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01308</link>
      <description>Andrew N. Okafor, William A. Shelton, Ye Xu, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400145700

                The bulk properties and surface chemical reactivity of compositionally disordered Pt&#8211;Fe and Pt&#8211;Co alloys in the fcc A1 phase have been investigated theoretically in comparison to the ordered alloys of the same compositions. The results are analyzed together with our previously reported findings for Pt&#8211;Ni. Nonlinear variation is observed in lattice constant, d band center, magnetic moment, and hydrogen adsorption energy across the composition range (0&#8211;100 atomic % of Pt, xPt). The Pt 5d states are strongly perturbed by the 3d states of the base metals, leading to notable density of states above the Fermi level and residual magnetic moments at high xPt. Surface reactivity in terms of average H adsorption energy varies continuously with composition between the monometallic Fe&#8211;Pt and Co&#8211;Pt limits, going through a maximum around xPt = 0.5&#8211;0.75. Close inspection reveals a significant variation in site reactivity at xPt &lt; 0.75, particularly with disordered Pt&#8211;Fe alloys due in part to the inherent disparity in chemical reactivity between Fe and Pt. Furthermore, the strong interaction between Fe and Pt causes Pt-rich sites to be less reactive toward H than Pt-rich sites on disordered Pt&#8211;Ni alloy surfaces, despite less compressive strain caused. These results provide theoretical underpinnings for conceptualizing and understanding the performance of these Pt-base metal alloys in key catalytic applications and for efforts to tailor Pt-alloys as catalysts.</description>
      <author>Andrew N. Okafor, William A. Shelton, Ye Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Reactivity Origin of Oxygen Reduction at High-Entropy Alloy Electrocatalysts with a Computational and Data-Driven Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01630</link>
      <description>Yang Huang, Shih&#8208;Han Wang, Xiangrui Wang, Noushin Omidvar, Luke E.K. Achenie, Sara E. Skrabalak, Hongliang Xin, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400147811

                High-entropy alloys (HEAs), characterized as compositionally complex solid solutions with five or more metal elements, have emerged as a novel class of catalytic materials with unique attributes. Because of the remarkable diversity of multielement sites or site ensembles stabilized by configurational entropy, human exploration of the multidimensional design space of HEAs presents a formidable challenge, necessitating an efficient, computational and data-driven strategy over traditional trial-and-error experimentation or physics-based modeling. Leveraging deep learning interatomic potentials for large-scale molecular simulations and pretrained machine learning models of surface reactivity, our approach effectively rationalizes the enhanced activity of a previously synthesized PdCuPtNiCo HEA nanoparticle system for electrochemical oxygen reduction, as corroborated by experimental observations. We contend that this framework deepens our fundamental understanding of the surface reactivity of high-entropy materials and fosters the accelerated development and synthesis of monodisperse HEA nanoparticles as a versatile material platform for catalyzing sustainable chemical and energy transformations.</description>
      <author>Yang Huang, Shih&#8208;Han Wang, Xiangrui Wang, Noushin Omidvar, Luke E.K. Achenie, Sara E. Skrabalak, Hongliang Xin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Outer shell Electron-Nuclear Distant of Transition Metal Atoms (TMA) on Band Gap Reduction and Optical Properties of TiO2 Semiconductor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102479</link>
      <description>Taha Yasin Ahmed, Shujahadeen B. Aziz, Elham M. A. Dannoun, Results in engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400094603

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Taha Yasin Ahmed, Shujahadeen B. Aziz, Elham M. A. Dannoun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically Induced CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Capture Enabled by Aqueous Quinone Flow Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01235</link>
      <description>Yan Jing, Kiana Amini, Dawei Xi, Shijian Jin, Abdulrahman M. Alfaraidi, Emily F. Kerr, Roy G. Gordon, Michael J. Aziz, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400112277

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Jing, Kiana Amini, Dawei Xi, Shijian Jin, Abdulrahman M. Alfaraidi, Emily F. Kerr, Roy G. Gordon, Michael J. Aziz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar fuel generation based on first-row transition metal catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95494-5.00007-0</link>
      <description>Abolfazl Ghaderian, Roghayeh Heiran, Shahzada Ahmad, Samrana Kazim, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400124930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abolfazl Ghaderian, Roghayeh Heiran, Shahzada Ahmad, Samrana Kazim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95494-5.00007-0</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
