<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 01:05:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electron redistribution and proton transfer induced by atomically fully exposed Cu-O-Fe clusters coupled with single-atom sites for efficient oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103410</link>
      <description>Enze Zhu, Zheng Tao, Jiali Yu, Chaoyang Shi, Lei Zhou, Huali Jin, Jun Yang, Guang&#8211;Nan Luo, Danyang Wei, Xianfeng Yang, Mingli Xu, Energy storage materials. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394869502

                Single-atom catalysts have garnered significant attention by showing sparkling performance in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on the air cathode side of energy devices such as metal-air batteries and fuel cells. This work presents a novel catalyst, AC-CuFe-NC, that incorporates Fe-doped CuO atomic clusters (CuOFe) synergistically with single-atom sites. The AC-CuFe-NC demonstrates outstanding ORR performance (half-wave potential of 0.92 V) and an oxygen overpotential gap between ORR and OER as low as 0.61 V, which is among the top reported performances. Combined with in situ ATR-SEIRAS and DFT calculations, it is shown that the synergistic CuOFe atomic clusters are effective in inducing the electronic structure redistribution of the Fe single-atom site, modulating oxygen adsorption energy, and lowering ORR barriers. More importantly, it is revealed that the synergistic adsorption of clusters and single-atom sites establishes hydrogen bonds between the oxygenated intermediates and the electrolyte H2O molecules. The constructed hydrogen bond can provide a pathway for efficient proton transport as supported by kinetic isotope experiments, leading to a substantial enhancement in reaction kinetics. Additionally, the oxygenated intermediates are stabilized, and the Fe-O bond is elongated during the final step of ORR, thereby facilitating the desorption of OH*. The excellent bifunctional electrocatalytic performance of AC-CuFe-NC enable it to show promising application in rechargeable Zn-air batteries. The innovative catalyst structure and synergistic mechanism demonstrated in this study shed light on the development of high-performance catalysts in energy devices.</description>
      <author>Enze Zhu, Zheng Tao, Jiali Yu, Chaoyang Shi, Lei Zhou, Huali Jin, Jun Yang, Guang&#8211;Nan Luo, Danyang Wei, Xianfeng Yang, Mingli Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of a high-entropy oxide as an oxygen carrier for chemical looping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131307</link>
      <description>I&#241;aki Ad&#225;nez-Rubio, M.T. Izquierdo, Joakim Brorsson, Daofeng Mei, Tobias Mattisson, Juan Ad&#225;nez, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394870018

                One mixed oxide with 5 cations in equimolar proportions in the sublattice, to fulfil high-entropy oxide (HEO) criteria, has been developed and investigated as oxygen carrier for chemical looping combustion processes. As far as we know, nobody has explored this class of material for chemical looping combustion. Material is prepared by direct mixing of five metal oxides (CuO, Mn2O3, Fe2O3, TiO2, MgO), followed by calcination at 1000, 1100 and 1200 &#176;C for 6h in air. XRD characterization provides strong evidence that the synthesized oxygen carriers possess the hallmark properties of HEO, and SEM-EDX analysis shows an overall homogeneous metal distribution. Materials have one main cubic phase with the empirical formula MnCuMgFeTiO7, dominating under all conditions. One of the key objectives of this study is achieved, reduce chemical stress during redox cycles. Oxygen transfer capability is investigated by thermogravimetric analysis and batch fluidized bed reactor experiments for different fuels and atmospheres. Mass-based oxygen transport capacities for lattice oxygen and oxygen uncoupling are around 5.5wt% and 1.1wt%, respectively. This work opens up a new dimension for the future preparation of oxygen carriers for chemical looping processes, since the vast compositional space of HEO provides opportunities to tune both chemical and physical characteristics.</description>
      <author>I&#241;aki Ad&#225;nez-Rubio, M.T. Izquierdo, Joakim Brorsson, Daofeng Mei, Tobias Mattisson, Juan Ad&#225;nez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring &lt;scp&gt;Li&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; configuration and orbital structure of &lt;scp&gt;CoS&lt;/scp&gt; to improve catalytic activity and stability for &lt;scp&gt;Li&#8208;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12449</link>
      <description>Rui Mao, Yingqi Liu, Pengfei Shu, Bingyi Lu, Biao Chen, Yanli Chen, Yang Song, Yeyang Jia, Zhong Zheng, Qiong Peng, Guangmin Zhou, EcoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394870765

                Abstract The sluggish reaction kinetics has greatly hampered the development of reversible Li&#8208;CO 2 batteries. Especially during charge, high charge voltage and possible side reactions during Li 2 CO 3 decomposition require both high activity and strong durability of catalysts. Herein, a strategy of introducing rich sulfur vacancies is proposed, which tailors the configuration of Li 2 CO 3 and the orbital structure of CoS to realize the dual enhancement. The calculation results show that charge redistribution by sulfur vacancies on the catalyst stretches the adsorbed Li 2 CO 3 and consequently facilitates its decomposition. Moreover, the induced vacancies lower the S 2p band center, promoting the electrochemical stability of sulfides. Therefore, Li&#8208;CO 2 batteries with sulfur vacancy&#8208;rich CoS exhibit a low overpotential of 1.07 V after 400 h cycling, while batteries with pristine CoS have a short lifespan that the overpotential exceeds 1.75 V after cycling for 200 h. This study not only proposes a strategy to improve both catalytic activity and stability but also paves new avenues for designing advanced catalysts for Li&#8208;CO 2 batteries and beyond. image</description>
      <author>Rui Mao, Yingqi Liu, Pengfei Shu, Bingyi Lu, Biao Chen, Yanli Chen, Yang Song, Yeyang Jia, Zhong Zheng, Qiong Peng, Guangmin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic role of dopant and graphene on BiVO4 photoanode for enhanced photoelectrochemical hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131329</link>
      <description>Mohaseen S. Tamboli, Santosh S. Patil, Dong Kyu Lee, C. S. Praveen, Asiya M. Tamboli, Uk Sim, Ki-Young Lee, Geun Ho Gu, Chinho Park, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394876478

                The development of an efficient and stable electrode remains an attractive challenge for photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting to generate cheaper and green hydrogen (H2). Herein, we have fabricated a novel multicomponent molybdenum (Mo) doped bismuth vanadate/graphene (Mo-doped BiVO4@graphene) photoanode by simple spin coating technique followed by an annealing process. Precise control over Mo and graphene doping concentration (GR3/BVO:Mo-0.5) was attained, enabling excellent photocurrent density (4-fold increase as compared to BVO) with an enhanced rate of H2 production. This is attributed to the synergistic effect between molybdenum and graphene enhancing charge carrier density and suppressing the recombination rate of photo-generated electrons and holes. Our DFT studies indicate a reduction in the band gap value after doping pure BVO with Mo. In addition, we observed that the potential determining step of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the electrochemical adsorption of hydroxyl radical (H2O(l) + * &#8594; HO* + H+(aq) + e-), which is reduced by &#8764;0.8 eV after doping with Mo. This study reports on the unique design of a Mo-doped BiVO4@graphene hybrid electrode, which can be used as a superior electrode for green hydrogen generation under sunlight.</description>
      <author>Mohaseen S. Tamboli, Santosh S. Patil, Dong Kyu Lee, C. S. Praveen, Asiya M. Tamboli, Uk Sim, Ki-Young Lee, Geun Ho Gu, Chinho Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Two&#8208;Dimensional Transition Metal Dichalcogenides for Water Electrolysis: Doping, Defect, Phase, and Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300614</link>
      <description>Ji Hyeon Lim, K Kim, Jong Hun Kang, Ki Chang Kwon, Ho Won Jang, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394878590

                Abstract The demand for hydrogen production technology to replace fossil fuels and address the global climate crisis has become one of the most urgent tasks in the modern era. Among the promising breakthroughs, electrochemical water splitting using renewable energy sources offers a path to green hydrogen production that is both feasible and economically viable. However, the current state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art catalysts for the water&#8208;splitting reaction predominantly rely on scarce and costly noble metals, posing a significant challenge to the mass production of green hydrogen. In this context, two&#8208;dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides (2D TMDs) have emerged as compelling candidates to replace noble metals, owing to their impressive reactivity and cost&#8208;effectiveness. These TMD&#8208;based electrocatalysts demonstrate exceptional reactivity at their active edge sites, while the basal planes remain catalytically inert. Several tailored strategies can activate these basal planes by modifying the chemical bonding nature and electronic band structure of the constituent atoms, thus enhancing the overall reactivity of TMDs. This review summarizes recent advancements in the modulation methodologies of 2D TMDs to enhance their water&#8208;splitting reactivity. We highlight various chemical modification strategies, including heteroatom doping, defect&#8208;engineering, and heterostructure formation, and provide insights into future research directions for the development of advanced 2D TMD&#8208;based water&#8208;splitting catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ji Hyeon Lim, K Kim, Jong Hun Kang, Ki Chang Kwon, Ho Won Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300614</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Charge Effects for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Pt(111) Using a Modified Grand-Canonical Potential Kinetics Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081813</link>
      <description>Shaoyu Kong, Min Ouyang, Yi An, Wei Cao, Xiaobo Chen, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394880897

                Surface charges of catalysts have important influences on the thermodynamics and kinetics of electrochemical reactions. Herein, we develop a modified version of the grand-canonical potential kinetics (GCP-K) method based on density functional theory (DFT) calculations to explore the effect of surface charges on reaction thermodynamics and kinetics. Using the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) on the Pt(111) surface as an example, we show how to track the change of surface charge in a reaction and how to analyze its influence on the kinetics. Grand-canonical calculations demonstrate that the optimum hydrogen adsorption energy on Pt under the standard hydrogen electrode condition (SHE) is around &#8722;0.2 eV, rather than 0 eV established under the canonical ensemble, due to the high density of surface negative charges. By separating the surface charges that can freely exchange with the external electron reservoir, we obtain a Tafel barrier that is in good agreement with the experimental result. During the Tafel reaction, the net electron inflow into the catalyst leads to a stabilization of canonical energy and a destabilization of the charge-dependent grand-canonical component. This study provides a practical method for obtaining accurate grand-canonical reaction energetics and analyzing the surface charge induced changes.</description>
      <author>Shaoyu Kong, Min Ouyang, Yi An, Wei Cao, Xiaobo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First&#8208;Principles Investigations on Effects of B&#8208;Site Substitution (B&#9552;Mn, Fe, and Co) on La&#8208;Based Perovskite Oxides As Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Rechargeable Metal&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202301235</link>
      <description>Siriwimol Somdee, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Annop Ektarawong, Soorathep Kheawhom, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, Advanced theory and simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394890199

                Abstract The effects of B&#8208;site substitution (B&#9552;Mn, Fe, and Co) in La&#8208;based perovskite oxides (LPOs); LaMnO 3 , LaFeO 3 , LaCoO 3 , as bifunctional electrocatalysts during oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in metal&#8211;air batteries (MABs) under an alkaline electrolyte (pH = 13) are investigated using density functional theory (DFT). It is found that LaMnO 3 exhibits higher ORR activity than others with ORR overpotential ( &#951; ORR ) of 0.57 V, but its OER activity is poor with OER overpotential ( &#951; OER ) of 1.12 V. The &#951; ORR (0.59 V) and &#951; OER (1.13 V) of LaMn 0.75 Fe 0.25 O 3 closely resemble those of LaMnO 3 , suggesting that Fe substitution does not yield appreciable enhancements in activity. Fe substitution reduces the ORR and OER activity because the adsorption energies of intermediate species on Fe&#8208;substituted LPOs surfaces are too strong to obtain a potential determining step for ORR and OER. According to Sabatier's principle, the LaMn 0.25 Co 0.75 O 3 demonstrates superior OER activity compared to the other composition, while ORR activity approximates that of LaMnO 3 , evidenced by &#951; ORR of 0.65 V and &#951; OER of 0.53 V. The Co&#8208;terminated LaMn 0.25 Co 0.75 O 3 shows bifunctional activity higher than Mn/Co termination, indicating that Co is an active site for OER and Mn is a promoter for improved ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Siriwimol Somdee, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Annop Ektarawong, Soorathep Kheawhom, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202301235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Ammonia Production via Nitric Oxide Electrochemical Reduction on H-MXenes: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07989</link>
      <description>Yuehong Zhao, Xiangyu Zhang, Lu Liu, Yijing Gao, Xiao&#8208;Shun Zhou, Weidong Zhu, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394890892

                Ammonia has gained more interest as a promising candidate to produce clean and renewable hydrogen energy in recent years. It is crucial to develop a new and efficient method for improving the performance of NH3 synthesis. Nowadays, electrochemical NH3 synthesis by direct NO reduction has become an alternative to the Haber&#8211;Bosch process. Herein, the performance of a NO reduction reaction (NORR) on 33 different H-functionalized MXenes (H-MXenes) has been investigated by the combination of density functional theory (DFT) calculations with the least absolute shrinkage and selection operator (LASSO) regression. Through surface Pourbaix diagrams and Gibbs free-energy calculations, the reaction mechanism and limiting potential (UL) of the NORR on the H-MXenes are investigated. The DFT calculations demonstrate that the surface H could regulate the strength of NO adsorption, lower the free energy of the elemental step, effectively reduce the limiting potential, and hence improve the NORR performance. Furthermore, the results on the LASSO regression indicate a good fitting between the expression consisting of the combined descriptors from 1D to 4D and the UL values from the DFT calculations. Moreover, |Gv&#8722;ENO|2|GNO| is regarded as human-readable NORR performance descriptors with R2 = 0.83. This work not only provides a deep insight into the important role of H-functionalization in NORR but also profits to understand the originals of the NORR activity for the high-throughput screening of NH3 synthesis catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuehong Zhao, Xiangyu Zhang, Lu Liu, Yijing Gao, Xiao&#8208;Shun Zhou, Weidong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined cobalt single&#8208;atom catalysts with strong electronic metal&#8208;support interactions based on a biomimetic self&#8208;assembly strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.554</link>
      <description>Bowen Guo, Zekun Wang, Lei Zheng, Guang Mo, Hongjun Zhou, Dan Luo, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394891223

                Abstract Designing high&#8208;performance and low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical for the conversion and storage of sustainable energy technologies. Inspired by the biomineralization process, we utilized the phosphorylation sites of collagen molecules to combine with cobalt&#8208;based mononuclear precursors at the molecular level and built a three&#8208;dimensional (3D) porous hierarchical material through a bottom&#8208;up biomimetic self&#8208;assembly strategy to obtain single&#8208;atom catalysts confined on carbonized biomimetic self&#8208;assembled carriers (Co SACs/cBSC) after subsequent high&#8208;temperature annealing. In this strategy, the biomolecule improved the anchoring efficiency of the metal precursor through precise functional groups; meanwhile, the binding&#8208;then&#8208;assembling strategy also effectively suppressed the nonspecific adsorption of metal ions, ultimately preventing atomic agglomeration and achieving strong electronic metal&#8208;support interactions (EMSIs). Experimental characterizations confirm that binding forms between cobalt metal and carbonized self&#8208;assembled substrate (Co&#8211;O 4 &#8211;P). Theoretical calculations disclose that the local environment changes significantly tailored the Co d&#8208;band center, and optimized the binding energy of oxygenated intermediates and the energy barrier of oxygen release. As a result, the obtained Co SACs/cBSC catalyst can achieve remarkable OER activity and 24 h durability in 1 M KOH ( &#951; 10 at 288 mV; Tafel slope of 44 mV dec &#8722;1 ), better than other transition metal&#8208;based catalysts and commercial IrO 2 . Overall, we presented a self&#8208;assembly strategy to prepare transition metal SACs with strong EMSIs, providing a new avenue for the preparation of efficient catalysts with fine atomic structures.</description>
      <author>Bowen Guo, Zekun Wang, Lei Zheng, Guang Mo, Hongjun Zhou, Dan Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deactivation mechanism for water splitting: Recent advances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.528</link>
      <description>Yuqing Jia, Y. J. Li, Qiong Zhang, Sohail Yasin, Xinqian Zheng, Kai Ma, Hua Zhong, Jianfeng Shi, Chaohua Gu, Yuhai Dou, Shi Xue Dou, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394891351

                Abstract Hydrogen (H 2 ) has been regarded as a promising alternative to fossil&#8208;fuel energy. Green H 2 produced via water electrolysis (WE) powered by renewable energy could achieve a zero&#8208;carbon footprint. Considerable attention has been focused on developing highly active catalysts to facilitate the reaction kinetics and improve the energy efficiency of WE. However, the stability of the electrocatalysts hampers the commercial viability of WE. Few studies have elucidated the origin of catalyst degradation. In this review, we first discuss the WE mechanism, including anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Then, we provide strategies used to enhance the stability of electrocatalysts. After that, the deactivation mechanisms of the typical commercialized HER and OER catalysts, including Pt, Ni, RuO 2 , and IrO 2 , are summarized. Finally, the influence of fluctuating energy on catalyst degradation is highlighted and in situ characterization methodologies for understanding the dynamic deactivation processes are described.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Jia, Y. J. Li, Qiong Zhang, Sohail Yasin, Xinqian Zheng, Kai Ma, Hua Zhong, Jianfeng Shi, Chaohua Gu, Yuhai Dou, Shi Xue Dou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating electrocatalytic activities of Pt, Pd, Au and Ag-based catalyst on PEMFC performance: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.177</link>
      <description>Zatil Amali Che Ramli, Jagadeesh Pasupuleti, Nik Farah Hanis Nik Zaiman, Tengku Shafazila Tengku Saharuddin, Salma Samidin, Wan Nor Roslam Wan Isahak, A.G.N. Sofiah, Siti Kartom Kamarudin, Sieh Kiong Tiong, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394894659

                This comprehensive review article highlights recent advancements of Pt and Pd-based electrocatalysts, covering Pt and Pd alloys, Pt-M and Pd-M core-shell structures, nanosize/nanostructure effects, addition of support material, doping effects, and post-treatment for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) in Proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC). Additionally, it delves into other precious metals such as Gold (Au) and Silver (Ag) for ORR and HOR in PEMFC. The role and contribution of incorporating other elements or materials such as metal oxides, metal carbides, transition metal oxides, carbon support, and non-carbon support are thoroughly discussed. The most promising methods are also described, with a special emphasis on narrow particle size, nanostructure, and low loading of novel Pt- and Pd-based catalysts. Furthermore, the advantages and shortcomings of these catalysts for electrocatalysis are analyzed, along with the influence of the nanostructure and morphology of the electrocatalyst materials on electrochemical performance.</description>
      <author>Zatil Amali Che Ramli, Jagadeesh Pasupuleti, Nik Farah Hanis Nik Zaiman, Tengku Shafazila Tengku Saharuddin, Salma Samidin, Wan Nor Roslam Wan Isahak, A.G.N. Sofiah, Siti Kartom Kamarudin, Sieh Kiong Tiong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity of IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from Quantum Mechanics and Experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14271</link>
      <description>Soonho Kwon, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger, Reshma R. Rao, Liang Qiao, William A. Goddard, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394907888

                The diversity of chemical environments present on unique crystallographic facets can drive dramatic differences in catalytic activity and the reaction mechanism. By coupling experimental investigations of five different IrO2 facets and theory, we characterize the detailed elemental steps of the surface redox processes and the rate-limiting processes for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The predicted complex evolution of surface adsorbates and the associated charge transfer as a function of applied potential matches well with the distinct redox features observed experimentally for the five facets. Our microkinetic model from grand canonical quantum mechanics (GC-QM) calculations demonstrates mechanistic differences between nucleophilic attack and O&#8211;O coupling across facets, providing the rates as a function of applied potential. These GC-QM calculations explain the higher OER activity observed on the (100), (001), and (110) facets and the lower activity observed for the (101) and (111) facets. This combined study with theory and experiment brings new insights into the structural features that either promote or hinder the OER activity of IrO2, which are expected to provide parallels in structural effects on other oxide surfaces.</description>
      <author>Soonho Kwon, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger, Reshma R. Rao, Liang Qiao, William A. Goddard, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Macrocyclic Precursors Influence the M-N-C Catalysts? Preparation and Their Applications on the Electrochemically Catalyzed Hydrogen Evolutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174518</link>
      <description>Zhen Zhang, Xue Dong, Tingting Gu, Qilong Li, Mengyu Liu, Minzhi Li, Weihua Zhu, Ling Xu, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394912207

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhen Zhang, Xue Dong, Tingting Gu, Qilong Li, Mengyu Liu, Minzhi Li, Weihua Zhu, Ling Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium-based catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109906</link>
      <description>Jiawei Ge, Wang Xian, Heyuan Tian, Hao Wan, Wei Ma, Jiangying Qu, Junjie Ge, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394913003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Ge, Wang Xian, Heyuan Tian, Hao Wan, Wei Ma, Jiangying Qu, Junjie Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additive Manufacturing: A Paradigm Shift in Revolutionizing Catalysis with 3D Printed Photocatalysts and Electrocatalysts Toward Environmental Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401278</link>
      <description>Valerine Khoo, Sue&#8208;Faye Ng, Choon Yian Haw, Wee&#8208;Jun Ong, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394920528

                Semiconductor-based materials utilized in photocatalysts and electrocatalysts present a sophisticated solution for efficient solar energy utilization and bias control, a field extensively explored for its potential in sustainable energy and environmental management. Recently, 3D printing has emerged as a transformative technology, offering rapid, cost-efficient, and highly customizable approaches to designing photocatalysts and electrocatalysts with precise structural control and tailored substrates. The adaptability and precision of printing facilitate seamless integration, loading, and blending of diverse photo(electro)catalytic materials during the printing process, significantly reducing material loss compared to traditional methods. Despite the evident advantages of 3D printing, a comprehensive compendium delineating its application in the realm of photocatalysis and electrocatalysis is conspicuously absent. This paper initiates by delving into the fundamental principles and mechanisms underpinning photocatalysts electrocatalysts and 3D printing. Subsequently, an exhaustive overview of the latest 3D printing techniques, underscoring their pivotal role in shaping the landscape of photocatalysts and electrocatalysts for energy and environmental applications. Furthermore, the paper examines various methodologies for seamlessly incorporating catalysts into 3D printed substrates, elucidating the consequential effects of catalyst deposition on catalytic properties. Finally, the paper thoroughly discusses the challenges that necessitate focused attention and resolution for future advancements in this domain.</description>
      <author>Valerine Khoo, Sue&#8208;Faye Ng, Choon Yian Haw, Wee&#8208;Jun Ong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial Impact of Spin State Evolution in OER/ORR Catalyzed by Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06122</link>
      <description>Mingyuan Yu, Ang Li, Erjun Kan, Caimao Zhan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394925248

                The Fe-embedded N-doped graphene (Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C) is the most representative single atom catalyst (SAC) that has shown great potentiality in electrocatalysis, such as oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the active moiety of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C is still elusive due to contradictory experimental results. Moreover, early simulations mainly focus on the thermodynamic potential of adsorbates, while the effect of spin multiplicity receives little attention. To explore the role of spin multiplicity in electrocatalysis, we employ the constant-potential density functional theory (DFT) to systematically study the structural evolution of the high-spin (HS) and intermediate-spin (IS) FeN4 site (marked by FeN4HS/IS) in OER and ORR processes. With the consideration of spin multiplicity, our simulation shows spontaneous oxidation from Fe(II)N4IS to Fe(III)N4HS at potential U = 0.4 V versus SHE. Further simulation indicates that the FeN4IS site undergoes a sequential adsorption of *OH and *OOH along with U increase, which leads to the spin state transition from IS to HS. According to the constant-potential free energy analysis, the FeN4HS*OOH is confirmed to be the practical active centers of OER, while the FeN4HS*OH and FeN4IS are assigned to the active center of ORR in low and high overpotentials. The predicted ORR activity of FeN4HS*OH agrees with the in situ X-ray absorption near-edge spectroscopy (XANES) and 57Fe M&#246;ssbauer spectroscopy measurement by Xiao et al. [Microporous Framework Induced Synthesis of Single-Atom Dispersed Fe-NC Acidic ORR Catalyst and its In Situ Reduced Fe-N4 Active Site Identification Revealed by X-Ray Absorption Spectroscopy. ACS Catal. 2018, 8, 2824&#8211;2832]. Based on the geometry and orbital analysis, the bond length of Fe&#8211;N and coordination number of Fe center are found to have a significant impact on the d orbital splitting energy and thus induce the turnover of HS/IS stability in the OER/ORR intermediates. Our study brings comprehensive insights into the evolution of coordination and spin state in Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C, which reveals the significance of spin multiplicity in electrocatalysis and benefits further theoretical design of SACs from the perspective of spin effects.</description>
      <author>Mingyuan Yu, Ang Li, Erjun Kan, Caimao Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal complexes of bipyridine-functionalized covalent organic frameworks as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02681-1</link>
      <description>Zhuangzhuang Wu, Tian Xia, Ying Liang, Yongpeng Li, Zhuyin Sui, Lijuan Feng, Daoxiong Wu, Xinlong Tian, Qi Chen, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394927346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuangzhuang Wu, Tian Xia, Ying Liang, Yongpeng Li, Zhuyin Sui, Lijuan Feng, Daoxiong Wu, Xinlong Tian, Qi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02681-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped CoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocages as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01449</link>
      <description>Bo Fang, Yue Li, Jiaqi Yang, Ting Lu, Xinjuan Liu, Xiaohong Chen, Likun Pan, Zhenjie Zhao, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394931309

                Currently, electrochemical water-splitting activity is limited by the slow intrinsic reaction kinetics and energy conversion efficiency, so designing highly efficient electrocatalysts that can facilitate electrochemical reactions remains necessary. Herein, the catalyst architecture consisting of Fe-doped CoS2 nanocages with nitrogen-doped carbon wrapping (CN/Fe-CoS2) was explored as an outstanding bifunctional electrocatalyst. Through density functional theory calculations, the introduction of Fe into CoS2 would modulate the density of states, making the reduced band gap and enhanced intrinsic charge transfer efficiency of CoS2. Simultaneously, the adsorption of intermediates during the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) processes is regulated, leading to an improvement in the intrinsic catalytic activity. The experimental results demonstrate that Fe doping significantly enhances the electron transfer, specific surface area, and electrochemical active area of CoS2, which facilitates the efficient utilization of charge and exposes additional active sites for electrochemical reactions. In addition, the nanocage architecture and nitrogen-doped carbon wrapping in CN/Fe-CoS2 act as a protective layer to prevent CoS2 aggregation, thereby exposing additional active sites and enhancing the interface with the electrolyte. By optimizing the amount of Fe, CN/Fe-CoS2 demonstrates a remarkably superior electrocatalytic performance and stability, as evidenced by the low overpotential (&#951;10) of 186 and 304 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH media for HER and OER, respectively. Overall, combining heteroatom doping and structure designing represents a promising approach to develop high-performance electrocatalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Bo Fang, Yue Li, Jiaqi Yang, Ting Lu, Xinjuan Liu, Xiaohong Chen, Likun Pan, Zhenjie Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism in pH effects of electrochemical reactions: a mini-review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42823-024-00724-2</link>
      <description>Shuzhong Liu, Zhuowen Wang, Shan Qiu, Fengxia Deng, Carbon letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394932255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuzhong Liu, Zhuowen Wang, Shan Qiu, Fengxia Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42823-024-00724-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Model of Carbon Nitride as a Substrate to Support Single Metal Atom</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00975</link>
      <description>Pan Du, Shengwei Deng, Liang Chen, Ziqi Tian, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394933990

                Carbon nitrides are commonly employed as substrates to anchor single metal atoms. Numerous theoretical studies have previously characterized these single-atom systems using the pristine g-C3N4 structure, featuring a C6N7 motif. However, the relatively large pores in g-C3N4 may not effectively coordinate with metal cations, resulting in discordance with the coordination environment determined by experimental characterization. In this study, we introduce a novel model denoted as CN-N4, which preserves the essential g-C3N4 motif, while offering four nitrogen sites for metal binding. Compared with g-C3N4, the binding affinity between the metal and this new substrate model is significantly enhanced, similar to that of a commonly studied nitrogen-doped graphene model (N-gra). Additionally, we have assessed the catalytic performance in various reactions, including the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The CN-N4-supported system exhibits activity comparable to that of the corresponding N-gra-supported species. Fe- and Co-centered SACs can be promising catalysts for ORR, and relatively stable Cu-g-C3N4 is active to HER and CO2RR, consistent with reported experiments. In addition, V-CN-N4 and Rh-CN-N4 are predicted to be candidates to catalyze the HER and ORR, respectively. We suggest that the CN-N4 model aptly captures the local structure of carbon nitride-based materials with a high coordination number, providing an alternative foundation for investigating the reaction mechanisms of these single-atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>Pan Du, Shengwei Deng, Liang Chen, Ziqi Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Heteroatom-Doped Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C Single-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction via Simple Descriptor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01377</link>
      <description>Jin Liu, Jing Zhu, Hanhui Xu, Daojian Cheng, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394934259

                The coordination engineering of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C single-atom catalysts (SACs) through introducing heteroatom dopants has attracted widespread attention in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). However, the common regularity for tuning the ORR activity by coordinated and environmental heteroatoms has not been sufficiently studied. Herein, we study the ORR activity on 100 Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C SACs with S, P, and B heteroatoms in diverse coordination shells by density functional theory calculations. Based on the energy level distribution of frontier orbits and molecular orbital theory, it is found that the origin of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C ORR activity is the hybridization of molecular orbitals of Fe 3dz2, 3dyz (3dxz), and O2*/OH* intermediates, where hybrid orbitals are adjusted by coordinated and environmental S, P, and B heteroatoms, and then the protonation process of O2* or OH* intermediate is determined. Moreover, we found that the Fe&#8211;O bond length, the d-orbital gap of spin states, the d-orbital center, and the valence state of the Fe site can be used as structural descriptors to predict the ORR activity governed by the protonation of O2* or OH* intermediate as potential-determining steps. Our structural descriptors rationalize the superior ORR performance of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C with S or B atoms doped in the second coordination shell to those in the first coordination shell, as well as the fact that the P heteroatom is more suitable as a coordinated atom than the environmental atom to enhance the ORR activity of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C, in available experimental references. Thanks to structural descriptors, the codoping synergistic effect between P in the first coordination shell and S in the second coordination shell is predicted and confirmed to greatly enhance the ORR activity. This study provides a unified mechanistic understanding on the ORR activity trend among Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C SACs regulated by coordinated and environmental heteroatoms.</description>
      <author>Jin Liu, Jing Zhu, Hanhui Xu, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the High-Entropy Oxide Composition Space: Insights through Comparing Experimental with Theoretical Models for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05915</link>
      <description>Vladislav A. Mints, Katrine L. Svane, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394934324

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is key for the transition to a hydrogen-based energy economy. The observed activity of the OER catalysts arises from the combined effects of surface area, intrinsic activity, and stability. Therefore, alloys provide an effective platform to search for catalysts that balance these factors. In particular, high-entropy oxides provide a vast material composition space that could contain catalysts with optimal OER performance. In this work, the OER performance of the AuIrOsPdPtReRhRu composition space was modeled using an experimentally obtained dataset of 350 nanoparticles. This machine-learned model based on experimental data found the optimal catalyst to be a mixture of AuIrOsPdRu. However, as a "black-box model", it cannot explain the underlying chemistry. Therefore, density functional theory (DFT) calculations were performed to provide a complementary theoretical model with defined assumptions and, hence, a physical interpretation through comparison with the experimental model. The DFT calculations suggest that the majority of the activity originates from Ru and Ir active sites and that the addition of Pd improves the performance of these sites. However, the DFT calculation did not find the experimentally observed beneficial effects of Au and Os. Therefore, we hypothesize that the Os contributed to the performance of the tested catalysts by roughening the surface, whereas Au fulfilled the role of a structural support. Overall, it is demonstrated how machine learning can help accelerate catalyst discovery, and combining machine-learned models obtained from experimental data with models based on DFT calculations can provide important insights into the complex chemistry of OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Vladislav A. Mints, Katrine L. Svane, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the landscape of anti-MoS2 monolayers: computational exploration of stability and multifaceted properties across the periodic table</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2861-2</link>
      <description>Fengyu Li, Yu Liu, Linke Yu, Xiaodong Liu, Peng Jin, Zhongfang Chen, Science China. Materials. 67(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394936891

                Inspired by the distinctive structural and electronic properties of two-dimensional (2D) transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs), we conducted comprehensive high-throughput first-principles computations to screen stable 2D chalcogenides X2T (X = transition metals Sc&#8211;Hg, totally 29 and main group elements Li&#8211;Ba, totally 37; T = S, Se, and Te) with anti-MoS2 configurations in both 1T and 2H phases. Among 396 evaluated candidates, the selected X2T monolayers (X = Sc, Fe, Y, Zr, Nb, Hf, Ta, IA elements Li&#8211;Fr, IIA elements Ca&#8211;Ra, N, In, Tl, and Te; T = S, Se, or Te) demonstrate outstanding thermodynamic, dynamic, mechanical properties, and thermal stabilities in 1T/1T&#8242; or 2H phases. These anti-MoS2 variants exhibit diverse characteristics, serving as nonmagnetic/magnetic metals or nonmagnetic/antiferromagnetic semiconductors, often surpassing MoS2 in Young's modulus and/or displaying negative Poisson's ratios. Transition-metal-based monolayers show susceptibility to O2 oxidization, and some show high N2 dissociation activity. Oxygen/nitrogen-terminations can quench TM magnetism and increase band-gaps over their pristine counterparts. Notably, the 2H-Fe2S monolayer maintains robust antiferromagnetism upon O-termination. Moreover, TM-based X2T sheets demonstrate promise as efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reactions. This study expands the diversity of 2D materials with new members and novel functional properties and broadens their potential applications.</description>
      <author>Fengyu Li, Yu Liu, Linke Yu, Xiaodong Liu, Peng Jin, Zhongfang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2861-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomalously low vacancy formation energies and migration barriers at Cu/AlN interfaces from ab initio calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2024.116126</link>
      <description>Yann Muller, Andrej Antu&#353;ek, Lars P. H. Jeurgens, Vladyslav Turlo, Scripta materialia. 248(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394944497

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yann Muller, Andrej Antu&#353;ek, Lars P. H. Jeurgens, Vladyslav Turlo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2024.116126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo4/3B2O2-supported single-atom catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114152</link>
      <description>Yuxiang Wang, Erpeng Wang, Ya Gao, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun, Molecular catalysis. 560(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394945353

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxiang Wang, Erpeng Wang, Ya Gao, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mno2 Nanozyme@Persistent Luminescent Nanoparticles for Dual-Modality Glucose Detection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4796886</link>
      <description>Yue Zhang, Renagul Abdurahman, Yugui Han, Shiji Liu, Rui Zhang, Xue&#8208;Bo Yin, Jie Gao, Shuqi Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394947879

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Yue Zhang, Renagul Abdurahman, Yugui Han, Shiji Liu, Rui Zhang, Xue&#8208;Bo Yin, Jie Gao, Shuqi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4796886</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D Nanomaterials Based for Electrocatalytic Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394167883.ch14</link>
      <description>Anchit Modi, Deepesh Kumar Gupta, Jitendra Malviya, N. K. Gaur, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394950720

                Chapter 14 2D Nanomaterials Based for Electrocatalytic Application Anchit Modi, Anchit Modi Department of Basic Sciences, IITM, IES University, Bhopal (M. P.), IndiaSearch for more papers by this authorD. K. Gupta, D. K. Gupta Department of Basic Sciences, IITM, IES University, Bhopal (M. P.), IndiaSearch for more papers by this authorJitendra Malviya, Jitendra Malviya Department Life Sciences and Biological Sciences IES University, Bhopal (M. P.), IndiaSearch for more papers by this authorN. K. Gaur, N. K. Gaur Department of Physics, Barkatullah University, Bhopal, (M. P.), IndiaSearch for more papers by this author Anchit Modi, Anchit Modi Department of Basic Sciences, IITM, IES University, Bhopal (M. P.), IndiaSearch for more papers by this authorD. K. Gupta, D. K. Gupta Department of Basic Sciences, IITM, IES University, Bhopal (M. P.), IndiaSearch for more papers by this authorJitendra Malviya, Jitendra Malviya Department Life Sciences and Biological Sciences IES University, Bhopal (M. P.), IndiaSearch for more papers by this authorN. K. Gaur, N. K. Gaur Department of Physics, Barkatullah University, Bhopal, (M. P.), IndiaSearch for more papers by this author Book Editor(s):Subhendu Chakroborty, Subhendu Chakroborty Research Coordinator, IES University, Bhopal, IndiaSearch for more papers by this authorKaushik Pal, Kaushik Pal University Centre for Research and Development (UCRD), Chandigarh University, IndiaSearch for more papers by this author First published: 19 April 2024 https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394167883.ch14 AboutPDFPDF ToolsRequest permissionExport citationAdd to favoritesTrack citation ShareShareShare a linkShare onEmailFacebookTwitterLinkedInRedditWechat Summary This chapter comprehensively explores the significance of electrocatalysis and unique properties of 2D nanomaterials. The motivations for the incorporation of 2D nanomaterials into electrocatalytic systems have been thoroughly discussed. This chapter categorizes 2D nanomaterials into three main groups, with a detailed examination of graphene including its distinctive structure, properties, synthesis methods, and electrocatalytic applications. Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) have also been extensively explored, including their structures, properties, synthesis methods, and electrocatalytic applications. Furthermore, this chapter presents a concise overview of other 2D nanomaterials such as black phosphorus and MXenes, showing their potential for electrocatalytic applications. Specific electrocatalytic reactions facilitated by 2D nanomaterials, such as the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR), have been thoroughly examined, emphasizing the role of 2D nanomaterials in enhancing the catalytic performance. Key findings and advancements in these areas have been highlighted. Synthesis and characterization techniques for 2D nanomaterials have been extensively discussed, emphasizing the intricate relationship between the synthesis, structure, and electrocatalytic performance. This chapter addresses the challenges of utilizing 2D nanomaterials for electrocatalysis and proposes strategies to overcome these obstacles. Additionally, future directions and emerging trends in the field of 2D nanomaterials for electrocatalysis are examined, summarizing the key points discussed throughout the chapter and underscoring the importance and potential impact of 2D nanomaterials in enhancing the catalytic performance and driving advancements in energy conversion and storage technologies. References Jaramillo , T.F. , J&#248;rgensen , K.P. , Bonde , J. , Nielsen , J.H. , Horch , S. , Chorkendorff , I. , Identification of active edge sites for electrochemical H2 evolution from MoS2 nanocatalysts . Science , 317 , 5834 , 100 &#8211; 102 , 2007 . https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1141483 . 10.1126/science.1141483 CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Stamenkovic , V.R. , Strmcnik , D. , Lopes , P.P. , Markovic , N.M. , Energy and fuels from electrochemical interfaces . Nat. Mater. , 16 , 1 , 57 &#8211; 69 , 2017 . https://doi.org/10.1038/nmat4738 . 10.1038/nmat4738 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar N&#248;rskov , J.K. , Rossmeisl , J. , Logadottir , A. , Lindqvist , L. , Kitchin , J.R. , Bligaard , T. , Jonsson , H. , Origin of the overpotential for oxygen reduction at a fuel-cell cathode . J. Phys. Chem. B , 108 , 46 , 17886 &#8211; 17892 , 20042004. https://doi.org/10.1021/jp047349j . 10.1021/jp047349j Google Scholar Heldt , F.S. , Kupke , S.Y. , Dorl , S. , Reichl , U. , Frensing , T. , Single-cell analysis and stochastic modelling unveil large cell-to-cell variability in influenza A virus infection . Nat. Commun. , 6 , 8938 , 2015 . https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms9938 . 10.1038/ncomms9938 CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Chen , Z. , Higgins , D. , Yu , A. , Zhang , L. , Zhangb , J. , A review on non-precious metal electrocatalysts for PEM fuel cells . Energy Environ. Sci. , 4 , 3167 , 2011 . https://doi.org/10.1039/c0ee00558d . 10.1039/c0ee00558d CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Li , L. and Xia , Y. , Engineering the architecture of electrocatalysts for efficient water splitting . Nano Today , 11 , 5 , 511 &#8211; 532 , 2016 . https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nantod.2016.08.006 . 10.1016/j.nantod.2016.08.006 Google Scholar Kim , B. , Hillman , F. , Ariyoshi , M. , Fujikawa , S. , Kenis , P.J.A. , Effects of composition of the microporous layer and the substrate on performance in the electrochemical reduction of CO2 to CO . J. Power Sources , 312 , 192 &#8211; 198 , 2016 . https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2016.02.043 . 10.1016/j.jpowsour.2016.02.043 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Kopljar , D. , Wagner , N. , Klemm , E. , Transferring electrochemical CO2 reduction from semi-batch into continuous operation mode using gas diffusion electrodes . Chem. Eng. Technol. , 39 , 2042 &#8211; 2050 , 2016 . https://doi.org/10.1002/ceat.201600198 . 10.1002/ceat.201600198 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Kortlever , R. , Tan , K.H. , Kwon , Y. , Koper , M.T.M. , Electrochemical carbon dioxide and bicarbonate reduction on copper in weakly alkaline media . J. Solid State Electrochem. , 17 , 1843 &#8211; 1849 , 2013 . https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-013-2100-9 . 10.1007/s10008-013-2100-9 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Chhowalla , M. , Shin , H.S. , Eda , G. , Li , L. , Loh , K.P. , Zhang , H. , The chemistry of two-dimensional layered transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets . Nat. Chem. , 5 , 4 , 263 &#8211; 275 , 2013 . https://doi.org/10.1038/nchem.1589 . 10.1038/nchem.1589 PubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Wang , Q.H. , Kalantar-Zadeh , K. , Kis , A. , Coleman , J.N. , Strano , M.S. , Electronics and optoelectronics of two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides . Nat. Nanotechnol. , 7 , 11 , 699 &#8211; 712 , 2012 . https://doi.org/10.1038/nnano.2012.193 . 10.1038/nnano.2012.193 CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Jaramillo , T.F. , J&#248;rgensen , K.P. , Bonde , J. , Nielsen , J.H. , Horch , S. , Chorkendorff , I. , Identification of active edge sites for electrochemical H2 evolution from MoS2 nanocatalysts . Science , 317 , 5834 , 100 &#8211; 102 , 2007 . https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1141483 . 10.1126/science.1141483 CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Liu , Z. , Wu , Z. , Yao , Q. , Cao , Y. , Chaib , O.J.H. , Xie , J. , Correlations between the fundamentals and applications of ultrasmall metal nanoclusters: Recent advances in catalysis and biomedical applications . Nano Today , 36 , 101053 , 2020 . https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nantod.2020.101053 . 10.1016/j.nantod.2020.101053 Google Scholar Voiry , D. , Yang , J. , Chhowalla , M. , Recent strategies for improving the catalytic activity of 2D TMD nanosheets toward the hydrogen evolution reaction . Adv. Mater. , 28 , 29 , 6197 &#8211; 6206 , 2016 . https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.201600038 . 10.1002/adma.201505597 CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Wang , Y. , Zhang , Z. , Mao , Y. , Wang , X. , Two-dimensional nonlayered materials for electrocatalysis . Energy Environ. Sci. , 13 , 3993 &#8211; 4016 , 2020 . https://doi.org/10.1039/D0EE01714 . 10.1039/D0EE01714K CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Duong , K.D.L. , Yun , S.J. , Lee , Y.H. , Van der Waals layered materials: Opportunities and challenges . ACS Nano , 11 , 12 , 11803 &#8211; 11830 , 2017 . https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.7b07436 . 10.1021/acsnano.7b07436 CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Shinde , P.A. , Patil , A.M. , Lee , S. , Junga , E. , Jun , S.C. , Two-dimensional MXenes for electrochemical energy storage applications . J. Mater. Chem. A , 10 , 1105 &#8211; 1149 , 2022 . https://doi.org/10.1039/D1TA04642J . 10.1039/D1TA04642J CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Zhang , Z. , Liu , P. , Song , Y. , Hou , Y. , Xu , B. , Liao , T. , Zhang , H. , Guo , J. , Sun , Z. , Heterostructure engineering of 2D superlattice materials for electrocatalysis . Adv. Sci. , 9 , 2204297 , 2022 . 10.1002/advs.202204297 CASGoogle Scholar Patil , A.M. , Wang , J. , Li , S. , Hao , X. , Du , X. , Wang , Z. , Hao , X. , Abudula , A. , Guan , G. , Bilateral growth of monoclinic WO3 and 2D Ti3C2Tx on 3D free-standing hollow graphene foam for all-solid-state supercapacitor . Chem. Eng. J. , 421 , 2 , 127883 , 2021 . https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2020.127883 . 10.1016/j.cej.2020.127883 CASGoogle Scholar Khan , M. , Assal , M.E. , Tahir , M.N. , Khan , M. , Ashraf , M. , Hatshan , M.R. , Khan , M. , Varala , R. , Badawi , N.M. , Adil , S.F. , Graphene/inorganic nanocomposites: Evolving photocatalysts for solar energy conversion for environmental remediation . J. Saudi Chem. Soc. , 26 , 6 , 101544 , 2022 . https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jscs.2022.101544 . 10.1016/j.jscs.2022.101544 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Priyadharshini , S.D. , Manikandan , S. , Kiruthiga , R. , Rednam , U. , Babu , P.S. , Subbaiya , R. , Karmegam , N. , Kim , W. , Govarthanan , M. , Graphene oxide-based nanomaterials for the treatment of pollutants in the aquatic environment: Recent trends and perspectives-a review . Environ. Pollut. , 306 , 119377 , 2022 . https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2022.119377 . 10.1016/j.envpol.2022.119377 PubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Arul , N.S. and Nithya , V.D. , Two Dimensional Transition Metal Dichalcogenides . Springer , Singapore , 2019 , https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/978-981-13-9045-6 . 10.1007/978-981-13-9045-6 Google Scholar Li , T. and Galli , G. , Electronic properties of MoS2 nanoparticles . J. Phys. Chem. C , 111 , 16192 &#8211; 16196 , 2007 . https://doi.org/10.1021/jp075424v . 10.1021/jp075424v CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Shi , Y. , Li , H. , Li , L. , Recent advances in controlled synthesis of two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides via vapor deposition techniques . Chem. Soc. Rev. , 44 , 2744 &#8211; 2756 , 2015 . https://doi.org/10.1039/C4CS00256C . 10.1039/C4CS00256C CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Huan , Y. , Shi , J. , Zou , X. , Gong , Y. , Xie , C. , Yang , Z. , Zhang , Z. , Gao , Y. , Shi , Y. , Li , M. , Yang , P. , Jiang , S. , Hong , M. , Gu , L. , Zhang , Q. , Yan , X. , Zhang , Y. , Scalable production of two-dimensional metallic transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheet powders using NaCl templates toward electrocatalytic applications . J. Am. Chem. Soc. , 141 , 47 , 18694 &#8211; 18703 , 2019 . https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.9b06044 . 10.1021/jacs.9b06044 CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Elbanna , O. , Zhu , M. , Fujitsuka , M. , Majima , T. , Black phosphorus sensitized TiO2 mesocrystal photocatalyst for hydrogen evolution with visible and near-infrared light irradiation . ACS Catal. , 9 , 4 , 3618 &#8211; 3626 , 2019 . https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.8b05081 . 10.1021/acscatal.8b05081 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Huan , Y. , Shi , J. , Zhao , G. , Yan , X. , Zhang , Y. , 2D metallic transitional metal dichalcogenides for electrochemical hydrogen evolution . Energy Technol. , 7 , 1980333 , 2019 . 10.1002/ente.201980333 Google Scholar Qazi , U.Y. , Future of hydrogen as an alternative fuel for next-generation industrial applications; Challenges and expected opportunities . Energies , 15 , 4741 , 2022 . https://doi.org/10.3390/en15134741 . 10.3390/en15134741 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Song , L. , Li , H. , Zhang , Y. , Shi , J. , Recent progress of two-dimensional metallic transition metal dichalcogenides: Syntheses, physical properties, and applications . J. Appl. Phys. , 131 , 060902 , 2022 . https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0083929 . 10.1063/5.0083929 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Lu , S. , Lou , F. , Yu , Z. , Recent progress in two-dimensional materials for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction . Catalysts , 12 , 2 , 228 , 2022 . https://doi.org/10.3390/catal12020228 . 10.3390/catal12020228 CASGoogle Scholar Li , J.R. , Ma , Y. , McCarthy , M.C. , Sculley , J. , Yu , J. , Jeong , H.K. , Balbuena , P.B. , Zhou , H.C. , Carbon dioxide capture-related gas adsorption and separation in metal-organic frameworks . Coord. Chem. Rev. , 255 , 1791 &#8211; 1823 , 2011 . https://doi.org/10.3390/catal12020228 . 10.1016/j.ccr.2011.02.012 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Keith , D.W. , Holmes , G. , St Angelo , D. , Heidel , K. , A process for capturing CO2 from the atmosphere . Joule , 2 , 1573 &#8211; 1594 , 2018 . https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2018.05.006 . 10.1016/j.joule.2018.05.006 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Back , S. , Lim , J. , Kim , N. , Kim , Y. , Jung , Y. , Single-atom catalysts for CO2 electroreduction with significant activity and selectivity improvements . Chem. Sci. , 8 , 1090 &#8211; 1096 , 2017 . https://doi.org/10.1039/C6SC03911A . 10.1039/C6SC03911A CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Cui , H. , Guo , Y. , Guo , L. , Wang , L. , Zhou , Z. , Peng , Z. , Heteroatom-doped carbon materials and their composites as electrocatalysts for CO2 reduction . J. Mater. Chem. A , 6 , 18782 &#8211; 18793 , 2018 . https://doi.org/10.1039/C8TA07430E . 10.1039/C8TA07430E CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Li , F. , Sun , S. , Chen , Y. , Naka , T. , Hashishin , T. , Maruyama , J. , Abe , H. , Bottom-up synthesis of 2D layered high-entropy transition metal hydroxides . Nanoscale Adv. , 4 , 2468 &#8211; 2478 , 2022 . https://doi.org/10.1039/D1NA00871D . 10.1039/D1NA00871D CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Ling , X. , Lee , Y. , Lin , Y. , Fang , W. , Yu , L. , Dresselhaus , M.S. , Kong , J. , Role of the seeding promoter in MoS2 growth by chemical vapor deposition . Nano Lett. , 15 , 2 , 1402 &#8211; 1409 , 2015 . https://doi.org/10.1021/nl4033704 . 10.1021/nl4033704 Google Scholar Kang , T. , Tang , T.W. , Pan , B. , Liu , H. , Zhang , K. , Luo , Z. , Strategies for controlled growth of transition metal dichalcogenides by chemical vapor deposition for integrated electronics . ACS Mater. , 2 , 6 , 665 &#8211; 685 , 2022 . https://doi.org/1021/acsmaterialsau.2c00029. 10.1021/acsmaterialsau.2c00029 CASPubMedGoogle Scholar Kang , T.W. , Pan , B. , Liu , H. , Zhang , K. , Luo , Z. , Strategies for controlled growth of transition metal dichalcogenides by chemical vapor deposition for integrated electronics . ACS Mater. , 2 , 6 , 665 &#8211; 685 , 2022 . 10.1021/acsmaterialsau.2c00029 CASPubMedGoogle Scholar Chhowalla , M. , Shin , H.S. , Eda , G. , Li , L. , Loh , K.P. , Zhang , H. , The chemistry of two-dimensional layered transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets . Nat. Chem. , 5 , 263 &#8211; 275 , 2013 . https://doi.org/10.1038/nchem.1589 . 10.1038/nchem.1589 PubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Zhang , Y. , Tang , T. , Girit , C. , Hao , Z. , Martin , M.C. , Zettl , A. , Crommie , M.F. , Shen , Y.R. , Wang , F. , Direct observation of a widely tunable bandgap in bilayer grapheme . Nature , 459 , 820 &#8211; 823 , 2009 . https://doi.org/10.1038/nature08105 . 10.1038/nature08105 CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Laursen , L.B. , Kegn&#230;s , S. , Dahla , S. , Chorkendorff , I. , Molybdenum sulfides efficient and viable materials for electro- and photoelectrocatalytic hydrogen evolution . Energy Environ. Sci. , 5 , 5577 &#8211; 5591 , 2012 . https://doi.org/10.1039/c2ee02618j . 10.1039/c2ee02618j CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Dubey , K. , Dubey , S. , Sahu , V. , Modi , A. , Bamne , J. , Haque , F.Z. , Gaur , N.K. , Defects and oxygen vacancies modified properties of transition metal doped Ce0.95X0.05O2 (X = Fe, Co, Ni) nanoparticles . Mater. Sci. Eng. B , 288 , 116154 , 2023 . https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2022.116154 . 10.1016/j.mseb.2022.116154 CASGoogle Scholar Wang , T. , Zhang , X. , Mei , L. , Ma , D. , Liao , Y. , Zu , Y. , Xu , P. , Yin , W. , Gu , Z. , A two-step gas/liquid strategy for the production of N-doped defect-rich transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets and their antibacterial applications . Nanoscale , 12 , 8415 &#8211; 8424 , 2020 . https://doi.org/10.1039/D0NR00192A . 10.1039/D0NR00192A CASPubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Zaman , M.B. , Poolla , R. , Khandy , S.A. , Modi , A. , Tiwari , R.K. , Thioglycolic acid assisted hydrothermal growth of SnS 2D nanosheets as catalysts for photodegradation of industrial dyes . Nanotechnology , 32 , 245706 , 2021 . https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/abec09 . 10.1088/1361-6528/abec09 CASWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar Bano , A. , Pandey , D.K. , Modi , A. , Gaur , N.K. , MoB2 driven metallic behavior and interfacial charge transport mechanism in MoS2/MoB2 heterostructure: A first-principles study . Sci. Rep. , 8 , 14444 , 2018 . https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-32850-z . 10.1038/s41598-018-32850-z PubMedWeb of Science&#174;Google Scholar 2D Nanomaterials: Synthesis, Properties and Applications ReferencesRelatedInformation</description>
      <author>Anchit Modi, Deepesh Kumar Gupta, Jitendra Malviya, N. K. Gaur</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394167883.ch14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H2O2-mediated electrosynthesis of nitrate from air</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00522-8</link>
      <description>Kai Dong, Yongchao Yao, Haobo Li, Huangjingwei Li, Shengjun Sun, Xun He, Yan Wang, Yongsong Luo, Dongdong Zheng, Qian Liu, Quan Li, Dongwei Ma, Xuping Sun, Bo Tang, Nature synthesis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394955448

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Dong, Yongchao Yao, Haobo Li, Huangjingwei Li, Shengjun Sun, Xun He, Yan Wang, Yongsong Luo, Dongdong Zheng, Qian Liu, Quan Li, Dongwei Ma, Xuping Sun, Bo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00522-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deprotonated 2-thiolimidazole serves as a metal-free electrocatalyst for selective acetylene hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-024-01480-6</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, Rui Bai, Jin Lin, Jun Bu, Zhenpeng Liu, Siying An, Zhihong Wei, Jian Zhang, Nature chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394955902

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, Rui Bai, Jin Lin, Jun Bu, Zhenpeng Liu, Siying An, Zhihong Wei, Jian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-024-01480-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JEDI: A versatile code for strain analysis of molecular and periodic systems under deformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0199247</link>
      <description>Henry Wang, Sanna Benter, Wilke Dononelli, Tim Stauch, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394955973

                Stretching or compression can induce significant energetic, geometric, and spectroscopic changes in materials. To fully exploit these effects in the design of mechano- or piezo-chromic materials, self-healing polymers, and other mechanoresponsive devices, a detailed knowledge about the distribution of mechanical strain in the material is essential. Within the past decade, Judgement of Energy DIstribution (JEDI) analysis has emerged as a useful tool for this purpose. Based on the harmonic approximation, the strain energy in each bond length, bond angle, and dihedral angle of the deformed system is calculated using quantum chemical methods. This allows the identification of the force-bearing scaffold of the system, leading to an understanding of mechanochemical processes at the most fundamental level. Here, we present a publicly available code that generalizes the JEDI analysis, which has previously only been available for isolated molecules. Now, the code has been extended to two- and three-dimensional periodic systems, supramolecular clusters, and substructures of chemical systems under various types of deformation. Due to the implementation of JEDI into the Atomic Simulation Environment, the JEDI analysis can be interfaced with a plethora of program packages that allow the calculation of electronic energies for molecular systems and systems with periodic boundary conditions. The automated generation of a color-coded three-dimensional structure via the Visual Molecular Dynamics program allows insightful visual analyses of the force-bearing scaffold of the strained system.</description>
      <author>Henry Wang, Sanna Benter, Wilke Dononelli, Tim Stauch</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0199247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-performance Bi2S3/ZnO photoanode enabled by interfacial engineering with oxyanion for efficient photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6653-y</link>
      <description>Ying-Chu Chen, Hsiang-Yu Jui, Yichen Feng, Yong Lu, Yu&#8208;Kuei Hsu, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394962932

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying-Chu Chen, Hsiang-Yu Jui, Yichen Feng, Yong Lu, Yu&#8208;Kuei Hsu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6653-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface exsolved NiFeOx nanocatalyst for enhanced alkaline oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160134</link>
      <description>Hyerin Jeong, Hyunwoo Jang, Yo Han Kim, Minwoo Kim, Youngho Kang, Jae&#8208;ha Myung, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394984906

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyerin Jeong, Hyunwoo Jang, Yo Han Kim, Minwoo Kim, Youngho Kang, Jae&#8208;ha Myung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling synergy of strain and ligand effects in metallic aerogel for electrocatalytic polyethylene terephthalate upcycling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2318853121</link>
      <description>J.T. Chen, Fangzhou Zhang, Min Kuang, Li Wang, Huaping Wang, Wei Li, Jianping Yang, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394892556

                Recently, there has been a notable surge in interest regarding reclaiming valuable chemicals from waste plastics. However, the energy-intensive conventional thermal catalysis does not align with the concept of sustainable development. Herein, we report a sustainable electrocatalytic approach allowing the selective synthesis of glycolic acid (GA) from waste polyethylene terephthalate (PET) over a Pd 67 Ag 33 alloy catalyst under ambient conditions. Notably, Pd 67 Ag 33 delivers a high mass activity of 9.7 A mg Pd &#8722;1 for ethylene glycol oxidation reaction (EGOR) and GA Faradaic efficiency of 92.7 %, representing the most active catalyst for selective GA synthesis. In situ experiments and computational simulations uncover that ligand effect induced by Ag incorporation enhances the GA selectivity by facilitating carbonyl intermediates desorption, while the lattice mismatch-triggered tensile strain optimizes the adsorption of *OH species to boost reaction kinetics. This work unveils the synergistic of strain and ligand effect in alloy catalyst and provides guidance for the design of future catalysts for PET upcycling. We further investigate the versatility of Pd 67 Ag 33 catalyst on CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) and assemble EGOR//CO 2 RR integrated electrolyzer, presenting a pioneering demonstration for reforming waste carbon resource (i.e., PET and CO 2 ) into high-value chemicals.</description>
      <author>J.T. Chen, Fangzhou Zhang, Min Kuang, Li Wang, Huaping Wang, Wei Li, Jianping Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2318853121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Expectations and Imbalanced Training Data in Reactive Force Field Development: An Application to Water Adsorption on Alumina</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01009</link>
      <description>L. Dumortier, C&#233;line Chizallet, Beno&#238;t Creton, Theodorus de Bruin, Toon Verstraelen, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394953177

                ReaxFF is a computationally efficient model for reactive molecular dynamics simulations, which has been applied to a wide variety of chemical systems. When ReaxFF parameters are not yet available for a chemistry of interest, they must be (re)optimized, for which one defines a set of training data that the new ReaxFF parameters should reproduce. ReaxFF training sets typically contain diverse properties with different units, some of which are more abundant (by orders of magnitude) than others. To find the best parameters, one conventionally minimizes a weighted sum of squared errors over all data in the training set. One of the challenges in such numerical optimizations is to assign weights so that the optimized parameters represent a good compromise between all the requirements defined in the training set. This work introduces a new loss function, called Balanced Loss, and a workflow that replaces weight assignment with a more manageable procedure. The training data is divided into categories with corresponding "tolerances", i.e. acceptable root-mean-square errors for the categories, which define the expectations for the optimized ReaxFF parameters. Through the Log-Sum-Exp form of Balanced Loss, the parameter optimization is also a validation of one's expectations, providing meaningful feedback that can be used to reconfigure the tolerances if needed. The new methodology is demonstrated with a non-trivial parameterization of ReaxFF for water adsorption on alumina. This results in a new force field that reproduces both rare and frequent properties of a validation set not used for training. We also demonstrate the robustness of the new force field with a molecular dynamics simulation of water desorption from a $\gamma$-Al$_2$O$_3$ slab model.</description>
      <author>L. Dumortier, C&#233;line Chizallet, Beno&#238;t Creton, Theodorus de Bruin, Toon Verstraelen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a Pt&#8208;CeO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Interface for the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402966</link>
      <description>Shen&#8208;Wei Yu, Soonho Kwon, Yizhen Chen, Zhenhua Xie, Xiner Lu, Kui He, Sooyeon Hwang, Jingguang G. Chen, William A. Goddard, Sen Zhang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394961595

                Abstract The creation of metal&#8208;metal oxide interfaces is an important approach to fine&#8208;tuning catalyst properties through strong interfacial interactions. This article presents the work on developing interfaces between Pt and CeO x that improve Pt surface energetics for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) within an alkaline electrolyte. The Pt&#8208;CeO x interfaces are formed by depositing size&#8208;controlled Pt nanoparticles onto a carbon support already coated with ultrathin CeO x nanosheets. This interface structure facilitates substantial electron transfer from Pt to CeO x , resulting in decreased hydrogen binding energies on Pt surfaces, and water dissociation for the HER, as predicted by the density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Electrochemical testing indicates that both Pt specific activity and mass activity are improved by a factor of 2 to 3 following the formation of Pt&#8208;CeO x interfaces. This study underscores the significance and potential of harnessing robust interfacial effects to enhance electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Shen&#8208;Wei Yu, Soonho Kwon, Yizhen Chen, Zhenhua Xie, Xiner Lu, Kui He, Sooyeon Hwang, Jingguang G. Chen, William A. Goddard, Sen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402966</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-Economic and Environmental Impact of Biomass Co-Firing with Carbon Capture and Storage in Indonesian Power Plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16083423</link>
      <description>Mujammil Asdhiyoga Rahmanta, Almas Aprilana, Ruly Bayu Sitanggang, Nur Cahyo, Tiva Winahyu Dwi Hapsari, Eko Supriyanto, Sustainability. 16(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394962739

                This research aims to analyze the techno-economic and environmental aspects of retrofitting carbon capture and storage (CCS) technology on the existing 330 MWe pulverized coal (PC) power plant. Modeling simulations on existing PC and retrofitting PC CCS with variations in biomass co-firing (wood pellet) were carried out using the Integrated Environment Control Model (IECM) version 11.5 software. An amine-based post-combustion capture was used in this study. Coal and biomass co-firing at PC CCS reduce the net power output and thermal efficiency. Carbon neutrality occurs at 10% biomass co-firing on PC CCS. There was a 164% increase in the levelized cost of electricity (LCOE), from 0.0487 USD/kWh on PC to 0.1287 USD/kWh on PC CCS. A sensitivity analysis of fuel prices shows that at a fuel price of 25 USD/t, the LCOE of PC CCS is 0.0953 USD/kWh or higher than Indonesia&#8217;s national weighted LCOE of 0.0705 USD/kWh. The LCOE of PC CCS can be lower than the national weighted LCOE when the carbon price is higher than 80 USD/t CO2.</description>
      <author>Mujammil Asdhiyoga Rahmanta, Almas Aprilana, Ruly Bayu Sitanggang, Nur Cahyo, Tiva Winahyu Dwi Hapsari, Eko Supriyanto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16083423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study of Punctual Defects in Monolayer WS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Evidence of Correlations Between Raman and Photoluminescence Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00511</link>
      <description>Let&#237;cia Mara Vieira Ildefonso, Erika Lira Buthers, Br&#225;ulio S. Archanjo, Cristiano Legnani, Welber G. Quirino, Daniel V. P. Massote, Indhira O. Maciel, Benjamin Fragneaud, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394963737

                The investigation of defects in transition-metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) are of capital interest for future applications because they strongly change the optical, electronic, or vibrational properties of such materials. In this sense, spectroscopic techniques, such as Raman and photoluminescence, are powerful tools to investigate the optoelectronic properties of crystal defects in two-dimensional TMDs. In this work, we observed that defect-activated Raman modes and bound exciton emissions can be strongly correlated. Specifically, we investigated the impact that sulfur vacancies, produced by focused helium ion beam, have on the electronic and phononic properties of WS2 grown by chemical vapor deposition. The photoluminescence spectra show two new emission peaks related to defects in the crystal structure. The defective nature of these bands were corroborated by density functional theory calculations, which showed new electronic states in the band gap associated with sulfur vacancies. Furthermore, by monitoring the evolution of the Raman spectra as a function of the defect concentration, we observed two new defect activated modes. These bands are explained by a second-order double resonant Raman process, similar to the D band of graphene. Finally, we found out that the defect-related Raman peaks become fully resonant for high defect concentrations. It turns out that degenerate electronic states split in two separated levels for high defect concentrations that are involved in the resonance of the Raman processes.</description>
      <author>Let&#237;cia Mara Vieira Ildefonso, Erika Lira Buthers, Br&#225;ulio S. Archanjo, Cristiano Legnani, Welber G. Quirino, Daniel V. P. Massote, Indhira O. Maciel, Benjamin Fragneaud</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution of MoS2 enabled by electrochemical cation implantation for simultaneous surface-defect and phase engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124037</link>
      <description>Mun Kyoung Kim, Bipin Lamichhane, Baozhen Song, Sunhyeong Kwon, Benzhi Wang, Shyam Kattel, Ji Hoon Lee, Hyung Mo Jeong, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. 352(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394987326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mun Kyoung Kim, Bipin Lamichhane, Baozhen Song, Sunhyeong Kwon, Benzhi Wang, Shyam Kattel, Ji Hoon Lee, Hyung Mo Jeong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic H2 generation and CO2 reduction by WB5-x cocatalyst of TiO2 catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160095</link>
      <description>Anna Yu. Kurenkova, Aleksandra D. Radina, V. S. Baidyshev, Pavel Povalyaev, Egor E. Aidakov, E. Yu. Gerasimov, Denis D. Mishchenko, Angelina V. Zhurenok, A. Ya. Pak, Ekaterina A. Kozlova, Alexander G. Kvashnin, Applied surface science. 661(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394992243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anna Yu. Kurenkova, Aleksandra D. Radina, V. S. Baidyshev, Pavel Povalyaev, Egor E. Aidakov, E. Yu. Gerasimov, Denis D. Mishchenko, Angelina V. Zhurenok, A. Ya. Pak, Ekaterina A. Kozlova, Alexander G. Kvashnin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards atom-level understanding of metal oxide catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01273-y</link>
      <description>Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jessica Karaguesian, Hoje Chun, Jiayu Peng, Yitong Tseo, Chunhui Shan, Byungchan Han, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394996236

                Abstract Green hydrogen production is crucial for a sustainable future, but current catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) suffer from slow kinetics, despite many efforts to produce optimal designs, particularly through the calculation of descriptors for activity. In this study, we develop a dataset of density functional theory calculations of bulk and surface perovskite oxides, and adsorption energies of OER intermediates, which includes compositions up to quaternary and facets up to (555). We demonstrate that per-site properties of perovskite oxides such as Bader charge or band center can be tuned through element substitution and faceting, and develop a machine learning model that accurately predicts these properties directly from the local chemical environment. We leverage these per-site properties to identify promising perovskites with high theoretical OER activity. The identified design principles and promising materials provide a roadmap for closing the gap between current artificial catalysts and biological enzymes such as photosystem II.</description>
      <author>Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jessica Karaguesian, Hoje Chun, Jiayu Peng, Yitong Tseo, Chunhui Shan, Byungchan Han, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01273-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient OER catalysis on Ir-doped Co3O4: Understanding Double and Quadruple Oxygen Coupling Mechanisms on Bimetallic sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04683-1</link>
      <description>Zheheng Jiang, Xu Wang, Yaping Li, Xiaoming Sun, Catalysis letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394996745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheheng Jiang, Xu Wang, Yaping Li, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04683-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur Doping Triggers Charge Redistribution at the Heterointerface of Fe-N-C Supported Ultralow-Pt-loading Electrocatalysts for Efficient Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134055</link>
      <description>Qian Liu, Chenye Zhang, Ming&#8208;Xun Ren, Jinyi Wang, Li Feng, Yixuan Wang, Chuang Liu, Ningru Xiao, Haiming Zhang, Colloids and surfaces. A, Physicochemical and engineering aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394997719

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Liu, Chenye Zhang, Ming&#8208;Xun Ren, Jinyi Wang, Li Feng, Yixuan Wang, Chuang Liu, Ningru Xiao, Haiming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local CO2 reservoir layer promotes rapid and selective electrochemical CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47498-9</link>
      <description>Subhabrata Mukhopadhyay, Muhammad Saad Naeem, G. Shiva Shanker, Arnab Ghatak, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Ran Shimoni, Liat Avram, Itamar Liberman, Rotem Balilty, Raya Ifraemov, Illya Rozenberg, Menny Shalom, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Idan Hod, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395001584

                Abstract Electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction in aqueous electrolytes is a promising route to produce added-value chemicals and decrease carbon emissions. However, even in Gas-Diffusion Electrode devices, low aqueous CO 2 solubility limits catalysis rate and selectivity. Here, we demonstrate that when assembled over a heterogeneous electrocatalyst, a film of nitrile-modified Metal-Organic Framework (MOF) acts as a remarkable CO 2 -solvation layer that increases its local concentration by ~27-fold compared to bulk electrolyte, reaching 0.82 M. When mounted on a Bi catalyst in a Gas Diffusion Electrode, the MOF drastically improves CO 2 -to-HCOOH conversion, reaching above 90% selectivity and partial HCOOH currents of 166 mA/cm 2 (at &#8722;0.9 V vs RHE). The MOF also facilitates catalysis through stabilization of reaction intermediates, as identified by operando infrared spectroscopy and Density Functional Theory. Hence, the presented strategy provides new molecular means to enhance heterogeneous electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction, leading it closer to the requirements for practical implementation.</description>
      <author>Subhabrata Mukhopadhyay, Muhammad Saad Naeem, G. Shiva Shanker, Arnab Ghatak, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Ran Shimoni, Liat Avram, Itamar Liberman, Rotem Balilty, Raya Ifraemov, Illya Rozenberg, Menny Shalom, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Idan Hod</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47498-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mechanism of water oxidation using transition metal-based heterogeneous electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01031g</link>
      <description>Shujiao Yang, Xiaohan Liu, Siqi Li, Wanming Yuan, Luna Yang, Ting Wang, Haoquan Zheng, Rui Cao, Wei Zhang, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395003921

                The water oxidation reaction, a crucial process for solar energy conversion, has garnered significant research attention. Achieving efficient energy conversion requires the development of cost-effective and durable water oxidation catalysts. To design effective catalysts, it is essential to have a fundamental understanding of the reaction mechanisms. This review presents a comprehensive overview of recent advancements in the understanding of the mechanisms of water oxidation using transition metal-based heterogeneous electrocatalysts, including Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, and Cu-based catalysts. It highlights the catalytic mechanisms of different transition metals and emphasizes the importance of monitoring of key intermediates to explore the reaction pathway. In addition, advanced techniques for physical characterization of water oxidation intermediates are also introduced, for the purpose of providing information for establishing reliable methodologies in water oxidation research. The study of transition metal-based water oxidation electrocatalysts is instrumental in providing novel insights into understanding both natural and artificial energy conversion processes.</description>
      <author>Shujiao Yang, Xiaohan Liu, Siqi Li, Wanming Yuan, Luna Yang, Ting Wang, Haoquan Zheng, Rui Cao, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01031g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemically Reversible CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Uptake by Dendrimer-Impregnated Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00885</link>
      <description>Rebecca B. Goncalves, Carlos Cuadrado Collados, Christos D. Malliakas, Zhiwei Wang, Matthias Thommes, Randall Q. Snurr, Joseph T. Hupp, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395010584

                Industrialization over the past two centuries has resulted in a continuous rise in global CO2 emissions. These emissions are changing ecosystems and livelihoods. Therefore, methods are needed to capture these emissions from point sources and possibly from our atmosphere. Though the amount of CO2 is rising, it is challenging to capture directly from air because its concentration in air is extremely low, 0.04%. In this study, amines installed inside metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) are investigated for the adsorption of CO2, including at low concentrations. The amines used are polyamidoamine dendrimers that contain many primary amines. Chemically reversible adsorption of CO2 via carbamate formation was observed, as was enhanced uptake of carbon dioxide, likely via dendrimer-amide-based physisorption. Limiting factors in this initial study are comparatively low dendrimer loadings and slow kinetics for carbon dioxide uptake and release, even at 80 &#176;C.</description>
      <author>Rebecca B. Goncalves, Carlos Cuadrado Collados, Christos D. Malliakas, Zhiwei Wang, Matthias Thommes, Randall Q. Snurr, Joseph T. Hupp</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00885</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium&#8208;Induced High Covalent Co&#8211;O Bonds for Efficient Anodic Catalysts in PEM Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402356</link>
      <description>Qisheng Yan, Jie Feng, Wen&#8208;Juan Shi, Weixin Niu, Zhuorong Lu, Kai Sun, Xiao Yang, Liangyao Xue, Yi Liu, Youyong Li, Bo Zhang, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395011558

                Abstract The proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE), crucial for green hydrogen production, is challenged by the scarcity and high cost of iridium&#8208;based materials. Cobalt oxides, as ideal electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), have not been extensively applied in PEMWE, due to extremely high voltage and poor stability at large current density, caused by complicated structural variations of cobalt compounds during the OER process. Thus, the authors sought to introduce chromium into a cobalt spinel (Co 3 O 4 ) catalyst to regulate the electronic structure of cobalt, exhibiting a higher oxidation state and increased Co&#8211;O covalency with a stable structure. In&#8208;depth operando characterizations and theoretical calculations revealed that the activated Co&#8211;O covalency and adaptable redox behavior are crucial for facilitating its OER activity. Both turnover frequency and mass activity of Cr&#8208;doped Co 3 O 4 (CoCr) at 1.67 V (vs RHE) increased by over eight times than those of as&#8208;synthesized Co 3 O 4 . The obtained CoCr catalyst achieved 1500 mA cm &#8722;2 at 2.17 V and exhibited notable durability over extended operation periods &#8211; over 100 h at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 and 500 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , demonstrating promising application in the PEMWE industry.</description>
      <author>Qisheng Yan, Jie Feng, Wen&#8208;Juan Shi, Weixin Niu, Zhuorong Lu, Kai Sun, Xiao Yang, Liangyao Xue, Yi Liu, Youyong Li, Bo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-NC Catalyst with Rich Coordinated Nitrogen and Hierarchical Porous Structure for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174599</link>
      <description>Ji&#8208;Rui Bai, Kai Zhang, Jia-Yao Gao, Zeng-Yu Han, Yang Zhu, Xiaoqi Yuan, Wenfang Cai, Xiaohe Liu, Qing&#8208;Yun Chen, Yun&#8208;Hai Wang, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395014634

                Cobalt nitrogen-doped carbon (Co-NC) catalysts are synthesized for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) via the pyrolysis of zinc-mediated and SiO2-templated 2,6-diaminopyridine (DAP) composites. The resulting Co-NC(Zn12-SiO2[20])-900 demonstrates exceptional ORR activities, with half-wave and onset potentials of 0.835 V and 0.875 V, respectively, which is similar to Pt/C catalyst. In long-term durability test, the Co-NC(Zn12-SiO2[20])-900 catalyst exhibits a negligible E1/2 shift, and in methanol tolerance tests, it displays significantly better performance than commercial Pt/C catalyst. The superior performance can be attributed to the hierarchical porous structure, dense and highly accessible Co-N4 and graphitic nitrogen (g-N) sites. The high content of Co-N4 and g-N sites enhances 3d-orbital filling and reduces the Co centers' on-site magnetic moment, as calculated by density functional theory. This may lead to a decrease in the energy barrier of the rate-determining step (RDS), which in turn enhances the intrinsic activity of the ORR.</description>
      <author>Ji&#8208;Rui Bai, Kai Zhang, Jia-Yao Gao, Zeng-Yu Han, Yang Zhu, Xiaoqi Yuan, Wenfang Cai, Xiaohe Liu, Qing&#8208;Yun Chen, Yun&#8208;Hai Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in understanding the regulation effect of carbon dots on intrinsic activity of metal and metal-free catalysts for electrocatalysis reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151544</link>
      <description>Bo Meng, Zimei Fu, Chunmei Liu, Peipei Zhao, Jiamin Ma, Wenxiang Wang, He Xiao, Junwei Wu, Man Zhao, Jianfeng Jia, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395014721

                Electrochemical energy conversion and storage devices support a promising green, efficient renewable way to solve energy-supply shortages and environmental problems. To promote reaction rates of involved electrochemical reactions, non-metal or noble metal electrocatalysts are elaborately designed. For optimizing the intrinsic structure and decreasing the cost, functional carbon dots (CDs) are chosen to add into these metal or metal-free materials, benefitting from their unique advantages of abundant surface functional groups, excellent electron acceptor/donor properties and high specific surface area. This review aims to support a summary of recent breakthrough in the application of CDs to regulate intrinsic structure of metal or metal-free materials including dispersibility, utilization efficiency, electronic state, partial charge distribution, and coordination environment of active atom-sites. Moreover, electrocatalytic performances (including stability, conductivity and antitoxicity, etc.) are also systematically investigated. Except that, the potential opportunities and challenges for application of CDs-based materials in the future are also discussed to promote the development of this field.</description>
      <author>Bo Meng, Zimei Fu, Chunmei Liu, Peipei Zhao, Jiamin Ma, Wenxiang Wang, He Xiao, Junwei Wu, Man Zhao, Jianfeng Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal nitride catalysts for selective conversion of oxygen-containing molecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01314j</link>
      <description>William N. Porter, Kevin K. Turaczy, Marcus Yu, Hansen Mou, Kuan Chang, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395016795

                Transition metal nitrides are promising catalysts for a variety of reactions. This work outlines their use for C 1 molecule upgrading, biomass valorization, and hydrogen evolution, and presents challenges and future opportunities for these catalysts.</description>
      <author>William N. Porter, Kevin K. Turaczy, Marcus Yu, Hansen Mou, Kuan Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01314j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Electrocatalytic Activities of Dealloyed Nanoporous Catalysts by Macroscopic Strain Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c00781</link>
      <description>Qite Li, Qite Li, Akira Kudo, Jinling Ma, Ryuichi Kawashima, Koji Toyama, Wence Xu, Zhonghui Gao, Yanqin Liang, Hui Jiang, Zhaoyang Li, Zhenduo Cui, Shengli Zhu, Luyang Chen, Luyang Chen, Luyang Chen, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395029045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qite Li, Qite Li, Akira Kudo, Jinling Ma, Ryuichi Kawashima, Koji Toyama, Wence Xu, Zhonghui Gao, Yanqin Liang, Hui Jiang, Zhaoyang Li, Zhenduo Cui, Shengli Zhu, Luyang Chen, Luyang Chen, Luyang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c00781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Stable Mo-NiO@NiFe-Layered Double Hydroxide Heterojunction Anode Catalyst for Alkaline Electrolyzers with Porous Membrane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00974</link>
      <description>Jianwei Ye, Jianwei Ye, Bin Yuan, Bin Yuan, Bin Yuan, Weiliang Peng, Weiliang Peng, Jia Liang, Jia Liang, Han Qin, Han Qin, Renzong Hu, Renzong Hu, Renzong Hu, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395029639

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianwei Ye, Jianwei Ye, Bin Yuan, Bin Yuan, Bin Yuan, Weiliang Peng, Weiliang Peng, Jia Liang, Jia Liang, Han Qin, Han Qin, Renzong Hu, Renzong Hu, Renzong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of transition metal subphthalocyanine molecules (TM@C24H12N6) as highly active electrocatalysts for the nitrogen reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141284</link>
      <description>Daomei Wu, Shuang Sun, Ye Xiang, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395033081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daomei Wu, Shuang Sun, Ye Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Activation of H&#8211;H Bonds by Platinum in Dilute Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00886</link>
      <description>Tongxin Han, Yuanyuan Li, Tao Wu, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Shuting Xiang, Yueqiang Cao, Yueqiang Cao, Ilkeun Lee, Xinggui Zhou, De&#8208;en Jiang, Anatoly I. Frenkel, Anatoly I. Frenkel, Francisco Zaera, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395037408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tongxin Han, Yuanyuan Li, Tao Wu, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Shuting Xiang, Yueqiang Cao, Yueqiang Cao, Ilkeun Lee, Xinggui Zhou, De&#8208;en Jiang, Anatoly I. Frenkel, Anatoly I. Frenkel, Francisco Zaera</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00886</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embracing data science in catalysis research</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01150-3</link>
      <description>Manu Suvarna, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395041397

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manu Suvarna, Javier P&#233;rez&#8208;Ram&#237;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01150-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphor-Doping Modulates the D-Band Center of Fe Atoms in Fe-N4 Catalytic Sites to Boost the Activity of Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4803771</link>
      <description>Yuan Qin, Chaozhong Guo, Zihao Ou, Yao Liu, Rong Jin, Chuanlan Xu, Haifeng Chen, Yujun Si, HongLin Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395046567

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan Qin, Chaozhong Guo, Zihao Ou, Yao Liu, Rong Jin, Chuanlan Xu, Haifeng Chen, Yujun Si, HongLin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4803771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Nitrogen for Electrochemical Ammonia Synthesis via an Electrified Transition-Metal Dichalcogenide Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08230</link>
      <description>Taylor J. Aubry, Jacob M. Clary, Elisa M. Miller, Derek Vigil&#8208;Fowler, Jao van de Lagemaat, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395048705

                The complex interplay between local chemistry, the solvent microenvironment, and electrified interfaces frequently present in electrocatalytic reactions has motivated the development of quantum chemical methods that can accurately model these effects. Here, we predict the thermodynamics of the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) at sulfur vacancies in 1T&#8242;-phase MoS2 and highlight how the realistic treatment of potential within grand canonical density functional theory (GC-DFT) seamlessly captures the multiple competing effects of applied potential on a catalyst interface interacting with solvated molecules. In the canonical approach, the computational hydrogen electrode is widely used and predicts that adsorbed N2 structure properties are potential-independent. In contrast, GC-DFT calculations show that reductive potentials activate N2 toward electroreduction by controlling its back-bonding strength and lengthening the N&#8211;N triple bond while decreasing its bond order. Similar trends are observed for another classic back-bonding ligand in CO, suggesting that this mechanism may be broadly relevant to other electrochemistries involving back-bonded adsorbates. Furthermore, reductive potentials are required to make the subsequent N2 hydrogenation steps favorable but simultaneously destabilizes the N2 adsorbed structure resulting in a trade-off between the favorability of N2 adsorption and the subsequent reaction steps. We show that GC-DFT facilitates modeling all these phenomena and that together they can have important implications in predicting electrocatalyst selectivity for the NRR and potentially other reactions.</description>
      <author>Taylor J. Aubry, Jacob M. Clary, Elisa M. Miller, Derek Vigil&#8208;Fowler, Jao van de Lagemaat</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08230</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Helmholtz model describes capacitance profiles of ionic liquids and concentrated aqueous electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0194360</link>
      <description>Suehyun Park, Jesse G. McDaniel, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395049125

                In this work, we propose and validate a generalization of the Helmholtz model that can account for both &#8220;bell-shaped&#8221; and &#8220;camel-shaped&#8221; differential capacitance profiles of concentrated electrolytes, the latter being characteristic of ionic liquids. The generalization is based on introducing voltage dependence of both the dielectric constant &#8220;&#1013;r(V)&#8221; and thickness &#8220;L(V)&#8221; of the inner Helmholtz layer, as validated by molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. We utilize MD simulations to study the capacitance profiles of three different electrochemical interfaces: (1) graphite/[BMIm+][BF4&#8722;] ionic liquid interface; (2) Au(100)/[BMIm+][BF4&#8722;] ionic liquid interface; (3) Au(100)/1M [Na+][Cl&#8722;] aqueous interface. We compute the voltage dependence of &#1013;r(V) and L(V) and demonstrate that the generalized Helmholtz model qualitatively describes both camel-shaped and bell-shaped differential capacitance profiles of ionic liquids and concentrated aqueous electrolytes (in lieu of specific ion adsorption). In particular, the camel-shaped capacitance profile that is characteristic of ionic liquid electrolytes arises simply from combination of the voltage-dependent trends of &#1013;r(V) and L(V). Furthermore, explicit analysis of the inner layer charge density for both concentrated aqueous and ionic liquid double layers reveal similarities, with these charge distributions typically exhibiting a dipolar region closest to the electrode followed by a monopolar peak at larger distances. It is appealing that a generalized Helmholtz model can provide a unified description of the inner layer structure and capacitance profile for seemingly disparate aqueous and ionic liquid electrolytes.</description>
      <author>Suehyun Park, Jesse G. McDaniel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0194360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Struktura ionno-molekulyarnykh kompleksov H+(H2O)n dlya n = 2 &#8722; 6 i termodinamicheskie kharakteristiki gidratatsii protonov v gazovoy srede</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044451023070015</link>
      <description>V. V. Reshetnyak, O. B. Reshetnyak, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1060;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080;&#1087;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074;, &#381;&#200;TF. Pis&#697;ma v redakci&#251;. 164(1)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394922242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>V. V. Reshetnyak, O. B. Reshetnyak, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1060;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080;&#1087;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044451023070015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vzaimodeystvie atomov na mezhfaznoy granitse Al-TiC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044451023120131</link>
      <description>V. V. Reshetnyak, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1086;&#1088;&#1082;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1060;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080;&#1087;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074;, &#381;&#200;TF. Pis&#697;ma v redakci&#251;. 164(6)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394922785

                The interaction of a titanium carbide nanoparticle with aluminum (100), (110), and (111) substrates is investigated within the density functional theory. The nanoparticle&#8211;substrate interaction energies are determined; the electron density distribution and the electron localization function between aluminum, titanium, and carbon atoms are analyzed. It has been established that the atoms in the upper layers of the aluminum (100) and (110) substrates are significantly displaced relative to their initial positions as a result of the interaction with the nanoparticle, whereas a minor displacement of atoms is typical for the (111) substrate. The interaction between aluminum and carbon atoms at the Al&#8211;TiC interface is due to the formation of covalent Al&#8211;C chemical bonds. The aluminum atoms forming carbide bonds do not form chemical bonds with titanium atoms. The aluminum atoms that are adjacent to the titanium atoms and are not involved in the formation of carbide bonds form metallic Al&#8211;Ti bonds.</description>
      <author>V. V. Reshetnyak, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1086;&#1088;&#1082;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1060;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080;&#1087;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044451023120131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#1058;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080;&#1082;&#1072; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1086;&#1089;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1082;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; &#1085;&#1072; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1076;&#1086;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084; &#1075;&#1088;&#1072;&#1092;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044453723110158</link>
      <description>&#1042;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1055;&#1072;&#1074;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1057;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#381;urnal fizi&#269;eskoj himii. 97(11)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394967632

                &#1057; &#1087;&#1086;&#1084;&#1086;&#1097;&#1100;&#1102; DFT-&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1095;&#1080;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1099; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1092;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080; &#1089;&#1074;&#1086;&#1073;&#1086;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1086;&#1089;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1082;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; &#1074; &#1082;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1080; &#1097;&#1077;&#1083;&#1086;&#1095;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1089;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1072;&#1093; &#1085;&#1072; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1076;&#1086;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084; &#1075;&#1088;&#1072;&#1092;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072; &#1074; &#1089;&#1088;&#1072;&#1074;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1089; &#1073;&#1077;&#1079;&#1076;&#1077;&#1092;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084; &#1075;&#1088;&#1072;&#1092;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084;. &#1056;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1099; &#1082;&#1072;&#1082; &#1095;&#1077;&#1090;&#1099;&#1088;&#1077;&#1093;-, &#1090;&#1072;&#1082; &#1080; &#1076;&#1074;&#1091;&#1093;&#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1086;&#1094;&#1080;&#1072;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1084;&#1077;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1084; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080;. &#1056;&#1072;&#1089;&#1095;&#1077;&#1090;&#1099; &#1074;&#1099;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1099; &#1074; &#1073;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1096;&#1086;&#1084; &#1082;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1085;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1084; &#1072;&#1085;&#1089;&#1072;&#1084;&#1073;&#1083;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1092;&#1080;&#1082;&#1089;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; &#1087;&#1086;&#1090;&#1077;&#1085;&#1094;&#1080;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077; &#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1095;&#1077;&#1090;&#1099; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1092;&#1080;&#1082;&#1089;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; &#1087;&#1086;&#1090;&#1077;&#1085;&#1094;&#1080;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077; &#1076;&#1072;&#1102;&#1090; &#1089;&#1091;&#1097;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1077; &#1086;&#1090;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1080;&#1077; &#1086;&#1090; &#1086;&#1073;&#1097;&#1077;&#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1085;&#1103;&#1090;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1095;&#1077;&#1090;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1092;&#1080;&#1082;&#1089;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;. &#1054;&#1073;&#1085;&#1072;&#1088;&#1091;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077; &#1076;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1080;&#1077; &#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1089;&#1080; &#1089;&#1074;&#1103;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086; &#1089; &#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1093;&#1077;&#1084;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1088;&#1073;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1080;&#1085;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1077;&#1076;&#1080;&#1072;&#1090;&#1072; OOH, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1089;&#1085;&#1080;&#1078;&#1072;&#1077;&#1090; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1102; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1084;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083;&#1099; &#1082;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1082;&#1078;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1074; &#1097;&#1077;&#1083;&#1086;&#1095;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1089;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077; &#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1090;&#1085;&#1072;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1089;&#1100; &#1080;&#1085;&#1075;&#1080;&#1073;&#1080;&#1088;&#1091;&#1077;&#1090; &#1076;&#1074;&#1091;&#1093;&#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1084;&#1077;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1084; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080;.</description>
      <author>&#1042;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1055;&#1072;&#1074;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1057;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044453723110158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#1069;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1089;&#1074;&#1086;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1072; N-&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1083;-2,2'-&#1073;&#1080;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072; &#1080; N,N'-&#1076;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1083;-2,2'-&#1073;&#1080;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044453723100060</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1044;&#1086;&#1083;&#1075;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1051;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1083;&#1080;&#1084;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1045;. &#1045;. &#1052;&#1091;&#1088;&#1102;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1057;. &#1043;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1088;&#1102;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1040;. &#1064;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1079;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1054;. &#1042;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1085;&#1103;&#1079;&#1077;&#1074;, &#381;urnal fizi&#269;eskoj himii. 97(10)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394967767

                &#1057; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077;&#1084; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; &#1094;&#1080;&#1082;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1081; &#1074;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1090;&#1072;&#1084;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1080; (&#1062;&#1042;&#1040;) &#1074;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1074;&#1099;&#1077; &#1080;&#1079;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1099; &#1080; &#1086;&#1087;&#1080;&#1089;&#1072;&#1085;&#1099; &#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1089;&#1074;&#1086;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1072; N-&#1079;&#1072;&#1084;&#1077;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1089;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1081; 2,2'-&#1073;&#1080;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072; &#8211; N-&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1083;-2,2'-&#1073;&#1080;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072; &#1080; N,N'-&#1076;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1083;-2,2'-&#1073;&#1080;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1079;&#1072;&#1084;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080; &#1091; &#1072;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084;&#1072; &#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072; &#1074; &#1084;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083;&#1077; &#1086;&#1088;&#1090;&#1086; -&#1073;&#1080;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072; &#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072;&#1102;&#1090; &#1089;&#1080;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1077; &#1074;&#1083;&#1080;&#1103;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1085;&#1072; &#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1089;&#1074;&#1086;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1072;. &#1044;&#1083;&#1103; N,N'-&#1076;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1083;-2,2'-&#1073;&#1080;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072; &#1073;&#1099;&#1083;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1095;&#1080;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1099; &#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1090;&#1099; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1094;&#1080;&#1086;&#1085;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1087;&#1086;&#1079;&#1074;&#1086;&#1083;&#1080;&#1083;&#1086; &#1089;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1072;&#1090;&#1100; &#1074;&#1099;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076; &#1086; &#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1087;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080; &#1083;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1101;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072; &#1074; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1091;&#1077;&#1084;&#1099;&#1093; &#1089;&#1080;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1084;&#1072;&#1093;.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1042;. &#1044;&#1086;&#1083;&#1075;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1051;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1083;&#1080;&#1084;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1045;. &#1045;. &#1052;&#1091;&#1088;&#1102;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;, &#1057;. &#1043;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1088;&#1102;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1040;. &#1064;. &#1050;&#1086;&#1079;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1054;. &#1042;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1040;. &#1042;. &#1050;&#1085;&#1103;&#1079;&#1077;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044453723100060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EFFECT OF HEAT TREATMENT ON THE STRUCTURE AND FUNCTIONAL CHARACTERISTICS OF A PtCo/C CATALYST</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0424857023120083</link>
      <description>A. K. Nevelskaya, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, N. V. Toporkov, A. Yu. Nikulin, &#200;lektrohimi&#226;. 59(12)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4395003648

                The PtCo/C electrocatalyst obtained by the method of simultaneous reduction of metal precursors using sodium borohydride was treated at a temperature of 350 &#730;C in an argon atmosphere for 1 hour. The results of X-ray phase analysis and transmission electron microscopy indicate an increase in the average size of crystallites and the formation of nanoparticle agglomerates after heat treatment. The shift in the reflection of Pt (111) after treatment indicates the possible segregation of metal components during the heating of the sample. An increase in the catalyst activity after heat treatment is shown, both mass activity and specific activity. The stability of the sample after heat treatment, according to the results of the stress test in the potential range of 0.6&#8211;1.4 V, showed a higher value than the material in the &#8220;as prepared&#8221; state.</description>
      <author>A. K. Nevelskaya, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, N. V. Toporkov, A. Yu. Nikulin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0424857023120083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coverage- and Facet-Dependent Multiscale Modeling of O* and H* Adsorption on Pt Catalytic Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08335</link>
      <description>Ayodeji Omoniyi, Alyssa J. R. Hensley, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394880245

                Within computational heterogeneous catalysis, two critical factors exist&#9472;coverage and multifaceted effects&#9472;which are challenging to incorporate and contribute to differences between the results obtained from computational and experimental studies. Such disparities exist when significant adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate interactions are present, particularly when coupled with computationally limited facet sampling. Here, we designed a study to demonstrate the significance of coverage and facet effects on the predicted coverages for O* and H* on Pt nanoparticles. This is accomplished by employing multiscale modeling techniques using a three-pronged approach consisting of density functional theory (DFT), ab initio phase diagrams, and mean-field microkinetic models. Overall, adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate interactions are repulsive and far stronger for O*/Pt than for H*/Pt. For O* on Pt(111), repulsive interactions are both two- and three-body, but on Pt(100) and Pt(110), they are predominantly three-body. Through benchmarks to existing experimental literature, we demonstrate that experimentally observed coverages and desorption temperatures can be accurately estimated by computational models when the adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate interactions are included. Finally, by combining microkinetic models at the equilibrium limit with kubic harmonic interpolation, we model the impacts of the treatment of adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate interactions on the predicted O* and H* coverages over multifaceted Pt nanoparticles. Omitting adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate interactions over Pt nanoparticles leads to an overestimation of equilibrium coverages of the adsorbates (maximum of 0.29 and 0.11 ML for O* and H*, respectively) across a wide range of temperatures and pressures relevant to heterogeneous catalysis. Altogether, our work demonstrates that the inclusion of coverage and facet effects increases the accuracy of computational models for heterogeneous catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ayodeji Omoniyi, Alyssa J. R. Hensley</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Asymmetrical TMN4 Sites via Phosphorus or sulfur Dual Coordination as High-Performance Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.095</link>
      <description>Zhe Xue, Rui Tan, Jinzhong Tian, Hua Hou, Xinyu Zhang, Yuhong Zhao, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394980238

                The development of highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts based on more cost-effective and earth-abundant elements is of great significance and still faces a huge challenge. In this work, a series of transition metal (TM) embedding a newly-defined monolayer carbon nitride phase is theoretically profiled and constructed as a catalytic platform for OER studies. Typically, a four-step screening strategy was proposed to rapidly identified high performance candidates and the coordination structure and catalytic performance relationship was thoroughly analyzed. Moreover, the eliminating criterion was established to condenses valid range based on the Gibbs free energy of OH*. Our results reveal that the as-constructed 2FeCN/P exhibits superior activity toward OER with an ultralow overpotential of 0.25 V, at the same time, the established 3FeCN/S configuration performed well as a bifunctional OER/ORR electrocatalysis with extremely low overpotential &#951;OER/&#951;ORR of 0.26/0.48 V. Overall, this work provides an effective framework for screening advanced OER catalysts, which can also be extended to other complex multistep catalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Zhe Xue, Rui Tan, Jinzhong Tian, Hua Hou, Xinyu Zhang, Yuhong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of CO2 capture plants with surrogate model uncertainties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108709</link>
      <description>A. Pedrozo, C. M. Valderrama-R&#237;os, Miguel Zamarripa, Josh Morgan, Juan-Pablo Osorio-Su&#225;rez, Ariel Uribe-Rodr&#237;guez, M. Soledad Diaz, Lorenz T. Biegler, Computers &amp; chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4395033023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Pedrozo, C. M. Valderrama-R&#237;os, Miguel Zamarripa, Josh Morgan, Juan-Pablo Osorio-Su&#225;rez, Ariel Uribe-Rodr&#237;guez, M. Soledad Diaz, Lorenz T. Biegler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compchemeng.2024.108709</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
