<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 01:45:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-Stabilized Core@Shell NiFe2O4@CoFe2O4 Nanocages for the Integrated Energy and Electroreduction of Nitrate-to-Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125775</link>
      <description>Kasiviswanathan Muthusamy, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Athis Watwiangkham, Ahreum Min, Siriporn Jungsuttiwong, Myong Yong Choi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412980661

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kasiviswanathan Muthusamy, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Athis Watwiangkham, Ahreum Min, Siriporn Jungsuttiwong, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B and Sr co-doping suppressed Pt oxidative passivation enables fast water oxidation in PEMWE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111657</link>
      <description>Jiawei Ge, Hao Wan, Feng Gao, Heyuan Tian, Jiangying Qu, Wang Xian, Junjie Ge, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412981064

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Ge, Hao Wan, Feng Gao, Heyuan Tian, Jiangying Qu, Wang Xian, Junjie Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Formic Acid and Hydrogen Co-electrosynthesis via Engineering Atom Arrangement in Nickel-Boron Interstitials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125773</link>
      <description>Qiuju Li, Hao Sun, Qiaoyu Liu, Guang Yang, Yijing Pian, Xiaotian Li, Zexuan Zheng, Shurong Li, Zhenyu Li, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Haibin Chu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412988531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiuju Li, Hao Sun, Qiaoyu Liu, Guang Yang, Yijing Pian, Xiaotian Li, Zexuan Zheng, Shurong Li, Zhenyu Li, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Haibin Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-dimensional decoupling local electron spin and inner Helmholtz layer roles in MoS2/MoSe2 superlattice photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166707</link>
      <description>Guoliang Zhu, Jagadeesh Suriyaprakash, Guangri Chen, Dapeng Hong, Jiajun Gu, Yanyang Zhang, Lianwei Shan, Huanyan Xu, Xiaojing Li, Haitao Wu, Limin Dong, Shuyan Qi, Xinxin Jin, Gang Liu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412988940

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoliang Zhu, Jagadeesh Suriyaprakash, Guangri Chen, Dapeng Hong, Jiajun Gu, Yanyang Zhang, Lianwei Shan, Huanyan Xu, Xiaojing Li, Haitao Wu, Limin Dong, Shuyan Qi, Xinxin Jin, Gang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomimetic design for zinc-based energy storage devices: principles, challenges and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cs00093a</link>
      <description>Jian Song, Qian Zhang, Guangjie Yang, Kai Qi, Xue Li, Zhenlu Liu, Haoqi Yang, Ho Seok Park, Shaohua Jiang, Jingquan Han, Shuijian He, Bao Yu Xia, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412995324

                An overview summarizes the research status and progress of biomimetic design for zinc-based energy storage devices, analyzes the challenges and proposes future prospects in this field.</description>
      <author>Jian Song, Qian Zhang, Guangjie Yang, Kai Qi, Xue Li, Zhenlu Liu, Haoqi Yang, Ho Seok Park, Shaohua Jiang, Jingquan Han, Shuijian He, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cs00093a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical High-Throughput Screening of Single-Atom CO2 Electroreduction Catalysts to Methanol Using Active Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eng.2025.03.039</link>
      <description>Honghao Chen, Jun Yin, Jiali Li, Xiaonan Wang, Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412999375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Honghao Chen, Jun Yin, Jiali Li, Xiaonan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eng.2025.03.039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of Zero-Dimensional Carbon Allotrope-Encapsulated Ni&#8211;Co Nanoparticles as a Water Splitting Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01627</link>
      <description>Adyasa Priyadarsini, Bhabani S. Mallik, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412999515

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adyasa Priyadarsini, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient separation of CO2/H2 gas mixtures via hydrate-based method driven by tetrafluoroethane and calcium hydroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.134631</link>
      <description>Chuanxiao Cheng, Qianhao Zhang, Yanqiu Xiao, Cheng Yan, Haoran Zhu, Hongjin He, Zhi Shang, Yifei Hou, Zihan Li, Jinhai Zhang, Yunpeng Shang, Fan Wang, Wenfeng Hu, Shiquan Zhu, Hongsheng Dong, Wei Zhang, Lunxiang Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. 378(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413000671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuanxiao Cheng, Qianhao Zhang, Yanqiu Xiao, Cheng Yan, Haoran Zhu, Hongjin He, Zhi Shang, Yifei Hou, Zihan Li, Jinhai Zhang, Yunpeng Shang, Fan Wang, Wenfeng Hu, Shiquan Zhu, Hongsheng Dong, Wei Zhang, Lunxiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.134631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Investigation of Single-Atom Catalysts Anchored on Nitrogen-Doped Two-Dimensional NbSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Highly Selective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c01839</link>
      <description>Hao Wang, Wei Jin, De-Chuan Sun, Tong Liu, Chang&#8208;Chun Ding, Junshan Hu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413001881

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) is a promising approach for CO2 emission reduction, but the development of efficient catalysts remains a major challenge. Here, a series of transition metal/nitrogen-doped NbSe2 (TM@N3-NbSe2) catalysts were selected to systematically investigate the reaction process and catalytic mechanism involved in the conversion of CO2 to methane (CH4) through density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The results indicate that CO2 has two possible adsorption configurations on TM@N3-NbSe2 surfaces, namely, physisorption and chemisorption. During the CO2 chemical adsorption process, a significant amount of charge is transferred from the substrate to CO2, thereby activating the formation of CO2 into a bent structure. In contrast, physically adsorbed CO2 cannot accept electrons from the substrate, resulting in minimal interaction between CO2 and the TM@N3-NbSe2. According to the reaction pathway and limiting potentials, the catalytic activity of TM@N3-NbSe2 for CO2-to-CH4 conversion can be ranked in the following order: Co &gt; Ir &gt; Pd &gt; Cu &gt; Os &gt; Fe &gt; Rh &gt; Pt &gt; Ag &gt; Ru &gt; Ni &gt; Au. Among them, Co@N3-NbSe2 exhibited more prominent catalytic properties, and the free energy change required to be overcome during the conversion of CO2 to CH4 is only 0.22 eV. Most TM@N3-NbSe2 systems exhibit higher selectivity for the CO2RR compared to the hydrogen evolution reaction, making them promising candidates as CO2RR catalysts. This study reveals the mechanism of transition metal and nitrogen codoped two-dimensional materials in CO2RR, which will help to screen high-efficiency catalysts to improve efficiency and selectivity.</description>
      <author>Hao Wang, Wei Jin, De-Chuan Sun, Tong Liu, Chang&#8208;Chun Ding, Junshan Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c01839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomass-Derived Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Supported Mo/Mo2C Heterojunctions with Interfacial Electronic-Activated Carbon Matrix for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182829</link>
      <description>Junjie Gong, Beibei Xiao, Zhenzhen Wang, Pengyue Wang, Yuhang Liu, Shijie Shen, Wenwu Zhong, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413002243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junjie Gong, Beibei Xiao, Zhenzhen Wang, Pengyue Wang, Yuhang Liu, Shijie Shen, Wenwu Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-regulated Schiff base complexes for efficient electrocatalytic carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116356</link>
      <description>Siying Wang, Shuaiqi Wang, Qiangwei Li, Leqing Deng, Lidong Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413008181

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siying Wang, Shuaiqi Wang, Qiangwei Li, Leqing Deng, Lidong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work function-induced spontaneous built-in electric field in Ir/MoSe2 for efficient PEM water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64685-7</link>
      <description>Bingjie Zhang, Chunyan Wang, Fulin Yang, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 75(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413011897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingjie Zhang, Chunyan Wang, Fulin Yang, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64685-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous Surface Charging and Janus Nature of the Hexagonal Boron Nitride&#8211;Water Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07827</link>
      <description>Yongkang Wang, Haojian Luo, Xavier R. Advincula, Zhengpu Zhao, Ali Esfandiar, Da Wu, Kara D. Fong, Lei Gao, Arsh S. Hazrah, Takashi Taniguchi, Christoph Schran, Yuki Nagata, Lyd&#233;ric Bocquet, Marie&#8208;Laure Bocquet, Ying Jiang, Angelos Michaelides, Mischa Bonn, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413013444

                Boron, nitrogen, and carbon are neighbors in the periodic table and can form strikingly similar twin structures&#9472;hexagonal boron nitride (hBN) and graphene&#9472;yet nanofluidic experiments demonstrate drastically different water friction on them. We investigate this discrepancy by probing the interfacial water and atomic-scale properties of hBN using surface-specific vibrational spectroscopy, atomic-resolution atomic force microscopy (AFM), and machine learning-based molecular dynamics. Spectroscopy reveals that pristine hBN acquires significant negative charges upon contacting water at neutral pH, unlike hydrophobic graphene, leading to interfacial water alignment and stronger hydrogen bonding. AFM supports that this charging is not defect-induced. pH-dependent measurements suggest OH- chemisorption and physisorption, which simulations validate as two nearly equally stable states undergoing dynamic exchange. These findings challenge the notion of hBN as chemically inert and hydrophobic, revealing its spontaneous surface charging and Janus nature, and providing molecular insights into its higher water friction compared to carbon surfaces.</description>
      <author>Yongkang Wang, Haojian Luo, Xavier R. Advincula, Zhengpu Zhao, Ali Esfandiar, Da Wu, Kara D. Fong, Lei Gao, Arsh S. Hazrah, Takashi Taniguchi, Christoph Schran, Yuki Nagata, Lyd&#233;ric Bocquet, Marie&#8208;Laure Bocquet, Ying Jiang, Angelos Michaelides, Mischa Bonn</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing precious metal concentration in PEMWE anodes catalyst layer through synergistic optimization of morphology and structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150838</link>
      <description>Zeyi Chen, F. M. Zhang, Xuechang Zhou, Haibo Liu, Xiongbo Duan, Zhiqiang Sun, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 164(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413014874

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyi Chen, F. M. Zhang, Xuechang Zhou, Haibo Liu, Xiongbo Duan, Zhiqiang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic study of C1 product formation from CO2 reduction using transition metal clusters-embedded C2N</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147061</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Jiali Liu, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413019478

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Jiali Liu, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating chemical and electronic structure of Ni-based catalysts via introducing heteroatoms for boosting electrochemical oxidation of borohydride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166900</link>
      <description>Ying Yang, Zhihong Cui, Caini Yi, Meilin Chen, Hang Yang, Xiaolong Hou, Guimiao Wang, Shuo Wang, Yuping Liu, Guozhong Cao, Danmei Yu, Xiaoyuan Zhou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413020290

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Yang, Zhihong Cui, Caini Yi, Meilin Chen, Hang Yang, Xiaolong Hou, Guimiao Wang, Shuo Wang, Yuping Liu, Guozhong Cao, Danmei Yu, Xiaoyuan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166900</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Approach to the Free&#8208;Energy Diagram of the Nitrogen Reduction Reaction on Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500196</link>
      <description>Diwakar Singh, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413020893

                Accurate free&#8208;energy landscapes are essential for understanding electrocatalytic processes, especially those involving proton&#8211;coupled electron transfer. While density functional theory (DFT) is widely used to model such reactions, it often introduces significant errors in the computed free energies of gas&#8208;phase reference molecules, leading to inconsistencies in the derivation of the free&#8208;energy changes of the elementary reaction steps. This study presents and compares different correction schemes to address gas&#8208;phase DFT errors. Unlike conventional methods that rely on bond&#8211;order&#8211;based adjustments, this approach reconstructs the formation free energy of target molecules as a linear combination of theoretically determined formation free energies of carefully selected reference molecules. This framework ensures consistency across the reaction network while avoiding dependence on the bond order. This methodology applies to the nitrogen reduction reaction on Mo 2 C(0001) MXene using dispersion&#8211;corrected DFT calculations. The incorporation of gas&#8208;phase corrections significantly reshapes the free&#8208;energy profile and alters catalytic activity descriptors, including the largest free&#8208;energy span of the G max ( U ) descriptor. Findings highlight the importance of thermodynamic accuracy in computational electrocatalysis and provide a generalizable framework that improves the reliability of DFT&#8208;based predictions across a wide range of electrochemical systems for energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Diwakar Singh, Ebrahim Tayyebi, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202500196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-faceted IrO2 monolayer enabling high-performing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis beyond 10,000 h stability at 1.5 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62665-2</link>
      <description>Deren Yang, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Yue Yang, Yubo Liu, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Shouwei Zuo, Abdullah Tan, Jianguo Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413023898

                Both commercial and laboratory-synthesized IrO2 catalysts typically possess rutile-type structures with multiple facets. Theoretical results predict the (101) facet is the most energetically favorable for oxygen evolution reaction owing to its lowest energy barrier. Achieving monolayer thickness while exposing this desired facet is a significant opportunity for IrO2. Herein, we develop an ammonia-induced facet engineering for the synthesis of single-faceted IrO2(101) monolayer. It achieves 230 mV overpotential at 10 mA cmgeo-2 in a three-electrode system and 1.70 V at 2 A cmgeo-2 in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer. Though facet engineering primarily contributes to modulating the intrinsic activity rather than stability, single-faceted IrO2 monolayer performs over 10,000-hour stability at constant 1.5 A cmgeo-2 (3.95 mV kh-1 decay) and 1000-hour stability at 0.2 mgIr cmgeo-2 under fluctuating conditions. This work proposes that ammonia-induced facet engineering of IrO2 monolayer enables facet-dependent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance and high stability in industrial-scale PEM electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Deren Yang, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Yue Yang, Yubo Liu, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Shouwei Zuo, Abdullah Tan, Jianguo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-62665-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volcano&#8208;Type Behavior in Spatially Resolved Electron Transfer and Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Mapping over 2D Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202501169</link>
      <description>Septia Kholimatussadiah, Mohammad Qorbani, Yu&#8208;Chen Liu, R. Raman, Ying&#8208;Ren Lai, Chih&#8208;Yang Huang, Mario Hofmann, Michitoshi Hayashi, Kuei&#8208;Hsien Chen, Li&#8208;Chyong Chen, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413024582

                Abstract In situ mapping of interfacial electron transfer dynamics to reveal electrocatalytic activity with high spatial resolution is crucial for developing efficient electrochemical devices. While emerging 2D materials for catalysis have attracted substantial attention, there is still a notable lack of studies examining their electrochemical properties at the nanoscale, particularly in a layer&#8208;by&#8208;layer context. Here, both outer&#8208;sphere and inner&#8208;sphere electron transfer at a 2D semiconducting WSe 2 electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface are spatially resolved and quantified in high resolution. The investigations reveal that WSe 2 exhibits a volcano&#8208;type behavior in its electrochemical activity, with a peak performance observed at a specific thickness of four layers. This phenomenon is attributed to the interplay between the layer&#8208;specific electronic density of states and the tunneling of charge carriers across the interlayer regions. This observation is further exemplified by micro&#8208;electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction measurements.</description>
      <author>Septia Kholimatussadiah, Mohammad Qorbani, Yu&#8208;Chen Liu, R. Raman, Ying&#8208;Ren Lai, Chih&#8208;Yang Huang, Mario Hofmann, Michitoshi Hayashi, Kuei&#8208;Hsien Chen, Li&#8208;Chyong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202501169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMPERE-2: an open-hardware, robotic platform for automated electrodeposition and electrochemical validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5dd00180c</link>
      <description>Nis Fisker&#8208;B&#248;dker, Daniel Persaud, Yang Bai, Mark Kozdras, Tejs Vegge, Jason Hattrick&#8208;Simpers, Jin Hyun Chang, Digital Discovery. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413027967

                AMPERE-2 automates electrodeposition and in situ OER catalyst testing. The open-hardware workflow yields reproducible multi-metal catalysts in 65 min per sample.</description>
      <author>Nis Fisker&#8208;B&#248;dker, Daniel Persaud, Yang Bai, Mark Kozdras, Tejs Vegge, Jason Hattrick&#8208;Simpers, Jin Hyun Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5dd00180c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Single&#8208;Atom Catalyst for Efficient C&#9472;S Coupling in Thioether Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202510632</link>
      <description>Theodore A. Gazis, Santi R. Palit, Luis A. Cipriano, Nicol&#242; Allasia, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Martin Sterrer, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413028711

                Abstract Carbon&#8208;heteroatom cross&#8208;coupling reactions have become indispensable tools in synthetic chemistry. However, the formation of carbon&#8211;sulfur (C&#9472;S) bonds, which are essential for producing thioethers used in pharmaceuticals, agrochemicals, and advanced materials, remains significantly underdeveloped. Industrial C&#9472;S coupling methods still rely on expensive, homogeneous catalysts that suffer from poor recyclability and are susceptible to sulfur&#8208;induced deactivation. In this work, we report a copper single&#8208;atom catalyst, where Cu sites are atomically dispersed on mesoporous graphitic carbon nitride, to enable efficient, selective, and recyclable C&#9472;S cross&#8208;coupling reactions under mild conditions and on a gram scale. The catalyst exhibits excellent resistance to thiol poisoning and maintains high performance over multiple catalytic cycles. Advanced characterization techniques, including aberration&#8208;corrected electron microscopy, X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, and single&#8208;atom&#8208;sensitive electron energy loss spectroscopy, confirm the atomic dispersion and stable coordination environment of Cu sites. Combined with density functional theory simulations and radical scavenging experiments, our mechanistic investigations support a concerted oxidative addition pathway, which excludes radical intermediates. These results provide key insights into heterogeneous C&#9472;S coupling and demonstrate the power of single&#8208;atom catalysts in addressing long&#8208;standing challenges in sulfur chemistry, paving the way toward greener and more scalable processes for fine chemical and pharmaceutical synthesis.</description>
      <author>Theodore A. Gazis, Santi R. Palit, Luis A. Cipriano, Nicol&#242; Allasia, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Martin Sterrer, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianvito Vil&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202510632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Single&#8208;Atom Catalyst for Efficient C&#9472;S Coupling in Thioether Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202510632</link>
      <description>Theodore A. Gazis, Santi R. Palit, Luis A. Cipriano, Nicol&#242; Allasia, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Martin Sterrer, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianvito Vil&#233;, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413028712

                Abstract Carbon&#8208;heteroatom cross&#8208;coupling reactions have become indispensable tools in synthetic chemistry. However, the formation of carbon&#8211;sulfur (C&#9472;S) bonds, which are essential for producing thioethers used in pharmaceuticals, agrochemicals, and advanced materials, remains significantly underdeveloped. Industrial C&#9472;S coupling methods still rely on expensive, homogeneous catalysts that suffer from poor recyclability and are susceptible to sulfur&#8208;induced deactivation. In this work, we report a copper single&#8208;atom catalyst, where Cu sites are atomically dispersed on mesoporous graphitic carbon nitride, to enable efficient, selective, and recyclable C&#9472;S cross&#8208;coupling reactions under mild conditions and on a gram scale. The catalyst exhibits excellent resistance to thiol poisoning and maintains high performance over multiple catalytic cycles. Advanced characterization techniques, including aberration&#8208;corrected electron microscopy, X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, and single&#8208;atom&#8208;sensitive electron energy loss spectroscopy, confirm the atomic dispersion and stable coordination environment of Cu sites. Combined with density functional theory simulations and radical scavenging experiments, our mechanistic investigations support a concerted oxidative addition pathway, which excludes radical intermediates. These results provide key insights into heterogeneous C&#9472;S coupling and demonstrate the power of single&#8208;atom catalysts in addressing long&#8208;standing challenges in sulfur chemistry, paving the way toward greener and more scalable processes for fine chemical and pharmaceutical synthesis.</description>
      <author>Theodore A. Gazis, Santi R. Palit, Luis A. Cipriano, Nicol&#242; Allasia, Sean M. Collins, Quentin M. Ramasse, Ik Seon Kwon, Martin Sterrer, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianvito Vil&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202510632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indirect Heteroatom Doping of TMN4 Single Atom Catalysts for Bifunctional ORR/OER Electrocatalysis: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113505</link>
      <description>Zeyu Wang, Lili Sun, Wolong Li, Junda Qin, Yongcun Li, Yong Wang, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413031099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyu Wang, Lili Sun, Wolong Li, Junda Qin, Yongcun Li, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular bridge-reshaped interfacial water configuration on oxygen-deficient silica for robust electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166863</link>
      <description>Minxia Jiang, Yingjie Hu, Jie Zhu, Wen Wei, Shuaifeng Wang, Zhen Yang, Jie Wang, Xiaowan Zhan, Ying Wang, Minhua Cao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413031474

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minxia Jiang, Yingjie Hu, Jie Zhu, Wen Wei, Shuaifeng Wang, Zhen Yang, Jie Wang, Xiaowan Zhan, Ying Wang, Minhua Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into electrocatalytic urea synthesis on graphdiyne-supported transition metal-boron triatomic clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164202</link>
      <description>Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Aling Ma, Yukun Han, Zhenzhen Wang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413032259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongpeng Ding, YuShan Pang, Aling Ma, Yukun Han, Zhenzhen Wang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Synergism in Boron Interstitial Doping Ordered Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co Nanoparticles Enhances the Protonation Process: Application to Efficient Oxygen Reduction in Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503590</link>
      <description>Guangrui Xu, Xinyuan Zhou, Miao Yu, Baolin Jiang, Qiyan Sun, Zexing Wu, Bin Li, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413038207

                Abstract Ordered intermetallic Pt 3 Co compounds are highly promising alloy materials for oxygen electrocatalysis, while the sluggish kinetics and high cost of Pt still hinder their wide use in practical applications. In this work, boron atom gap&#8208;doped Pt 3 Co nanoparticles loaded on carbon nanobowls (B&#8208;Pt 3 Co/CNBs) are obtained to enhance the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance. The introduction of B atoms is responsible for the negative shift of the d&#8208;band center compared to Pt 3 Co, and the subsequent reduction process leads to the uniform loading of B&#8208;Pt 3 Co nanoparticles on hollow carbon nanobowls. It is demonstrated that B&#8208;Pt 3 Co/CNBs exhibit the best electrocatalytic performance for ORR with an onset potential of 1.095 V versus RHE and a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.985 versus RHE, as well as robust electrocatalytic stability with negligible activity decay even after 50 000 cycles. Experimental and theoretical calculations show that the introduction of the highly electronegative metalloid B leads the Pt atoms to lose electrons, which changes the electronic structure of Pt 3 Co that can weaken the bonding strength of Pt&#8208;O and accelerate the protonation and desorption of O* on the surface of the B&#8208;Pt 3 Co/ CNB, reducing the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step during the ORR process.</description>
      <author>Guangrui Xu, Xinyuan Zhou, Miao Yu, Baolin Jiang, Qiyan Sun, Zexing Wu, Bin Li, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pH&#8208;Dependent Electroreduction of Nitrate on Fe Single&#8208;Atom Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202500717</link>
      <description>Zhen Meng, Adyasa Priyadarsini, Kaige Shi, Zhuanghe Ren, Deepak Prasad Subedi, Daniel W. Israel, William E. Kaden, Xiaofeng Feng, Shyam Kattel, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413044311

                Electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) has received considerable attention due to its potential for the denitrification of wastewater and sustainable NH 3 production. Among various catalysts for NO 3 RR, Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C single&#8208;atom catalyst has attracted significant interest due to its well&#8208;defined active sites and high stability across various media. Here, we investigate the pH dependence of NO 3 RR on Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C by combining experiments and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C catalyst achieves high activity and &gt;80% Faradaic efficiency for NH 3 production in the NO 3 RR across acidic, neutral, and alkaline electrolytes, while the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) exhibits the strongest competition with NO 3 RR in alkaline electrolyte. DFT calculations identify the NHO*&#8208;mediated pathway as the most favorable for NO 3 RR on Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C and further reveal the pH dependence of the potential&#8208;determining steps for both NO 3 RR and HER, elucidating the origin of the pH&#8208;dependent selectivity. Our studies provide new mechanistic insights into the NO 3 RR on single&#8208;atom catalysts and guide the design of broad pH&#8208;range electrocatalysts for efficient and versatile nitrate recycling.</description>
      <author>Zhen Meng, Adyasa Priyadarsini, Kaige Shi, Zhuanghe Ren, Deepak Prasad Subedi, Daniel W. Israel, William E. Kaden, Xiaofeng Feng, Shyam Kattel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202500717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the built-in electric field in two-dimensional p-2H-MSiN3 (M = Cr, Mo, W) for optimized photocarrier dynamics and enhanced overall water splitting activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136468</link>
      <description>Yanli Chang, Pucun Bai, Xueping Zhao, Xiaoming Cui, Fuel. 405(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413049265

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanli Chang, Pucun Bai, Xueping Zhao, Xiaoming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field-Driven Interface Hydroxylation via the Vibrational Stark Effect Boosts Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00585</link>
      <description>Xiayan Yao, Jianwei Guo, Zhi Wang, Guoyu Qian, X.P. Wang, Dong Wang, Xuzhong Gong, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413052677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiayan Yao, Jianwei Guo, Zhi Wang, Guoyu Qian, X.P. Wang, Dong Wang, Xuzhong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Activity and Stability of Ba0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3-&#948; Cathode by Surface Engineering with SrCoO3-&#948; Nanoparticles in Protonic Ceramic Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.08.038</link>
      <description>Chenxiao Wang, Guangjun Zhang, Qiang Xue, Xiaoyu Zhang, Ting Chen, Lang Xu, Shaorong Wang, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413053103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenxiao Wang, Guangjun Zhang, Qiang Xue, Xiaoyu Zhang, Ting Chen, Lang Xu, Shaorong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.08.038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cycloaddition of CO2 to epoxides catalyzed by homogeneous metalorganic complexes under ambient conditions: an update</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2025.123799</link>
      <description>Suthida Kaewsai, Valerio D&#8217;Elia, Journal of Organometallic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413053188

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suthida Kaewsai, Valerio D&#8217;Elia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2025.123799</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling d-band synergy in anti-sandwich dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction: High-throughput DFT screening and machine learning insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164256</link>
      <description>Wentao Liang, Wenjun Xiao, Linxing Meng, Jinshun Bi, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xiaofeng Rong, Degui Wang, Xuefei Liu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413052776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wentao Liang, Wenjun Xiao, Linxing Meng, Jinshun Bi, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xiaofeng Rong, Degui Wang, Xuefei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164256</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training a Machine Learned Potential on the Cerebras Wafer Scale Engine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3708035.3736081</link>
      <description>Dana O&#8217;Connor, Wissam A. Saidi, Paola A. Buitrago, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413059244

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dana O&#8217;Connor, Wissam A. Saidi, Paola A. Buitrago</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1145/3708035.3736081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semiempirical and interpretable machine learning of the oxygen interaction barriers in thousands of the two-dimensional materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1140/epjb/s10051-025-01001-5</link>
      <description>Raphael M. Tromer, The European Physical Journal B. 98(7)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413064406

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Raphael M. Tromer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1140/epjb/s10051-025-01001-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Literature-Based Machine Learning Framework for Yield Prediction in Cyclohexene Epoxidation: Toward a Digital Catalyst Concept</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5355788</link>
      <description>Alfonso Enrique Ram&#237;rez Sanabria, Fabian Ramirez, Juli&#225;n Mu&#241;oz-Ord&#243;&#241;ez, Cristian Mu&#241;oz, Nelson J. Castellanos, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413075752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alfonso Enrique Ram&#237;rez Sanabria, Fabian Ramirez, Juli&#225;n Mu&#241;oz-Ord&#243;&#241;ez, Cristian Mu&#241;oz, Nelson J. Castellanos</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5355788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core&#8208;Shell Structured V&#8208;Doped CoPx@FeOOH for Efficient Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500850</link>
      <description>Gai Li, Yanhui Yu, Chongtai Wang, Daoxiong Wu, Yingjie Hua, Peng Rao, Xinlong Tian, Jing Li, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413078233

                Abstract As a renewable energy conversion method, the hydrogen from seawater electrolysis needs to overcome problems such as chlorination reaction and corrosion resistance. Considering these questions, it is vital to design a highly efficient and corrosion&#8208;resistant catalyst. Here, we developed a vanadium&#8208;doped cobalt phosphide encapsulated within an iron oxyhydroxide shell (V&#8208;CoPx@FeOOH) as an efficient core&#8208;shell electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in seawater electrolytes. In particular, the OER overpotential of the V&#8208;CoPx@FeOOH catalyst at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 was 270 mV. Notably, V&#8208;CoPx||V&#8208;CoPx@FeOOH was able to operate in alkaline seawater at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for more than 1000 h, showing excellent stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that the enhanced HER activity is attributed to the introduction of V, which strengthens the bonding between Co sites and H atoms, and the optimized OER activity results from the presence of both V and Fe, which together optimize the bonding strength between Co sites and OOH intermediates. The highly efficient catalyst of the core&#8208;shell structure has great prospects for overall water/seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Gai Li, Yanhui Yu, Chongtai Wang, Daoxiong Wu, Yingjie Hua, Peng Rao, Xinlong Tian, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production via 2e&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; ORR on Alkalinized Tubular C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; from Melamine Waste Integrating with Fenton Wastewater Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.5c00228</link>
      <description>Hongyu Song, Huijing Ma, Haifei Wang, Yichan Wen, Chengcheng Cai, Jiyi Sun, Xufang Qian, Yixin Zhao, ACS Sustainable Resource Management. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413084227

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongyu Song, Huijing Ma, Haifei Wang, Yichan Wen, Chengcheng Cai, Jiyi Sun, Xufang Qian, Yixin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.5c00228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton&#8208;Driven Multistage System Enables Selective Recovery of Gold and Palladium from Electronic Waste Leachate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70085</link>
      <description>Ziwen Chang, Yingying Zhou, Penghui Shao, Liming Yang, Bo Li, Dewei Li, Lingrong Zeng, Yi Gong, Xubiao Luo, Shenglian Luo, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413084471

                Selective extraction of precious metals from urban mines plays a crucial role in mitigating the risk of depletion of precious metal resources and reducing waste pollution. However, a major obstacle in precious metal extraction lies in the difficulty of distinguishing the subtle differences in the physicochemical characteristics between them, especially gold and palladium. Herein, a proton&#8208;driven separation system was presented for cascade recovery of gold and palladium from waste&#8208;printed circuit boards (W&#8208;PCBs) leachate using poly(amidoxime) (PAO) hydrogel. This exhibits an ultra&#8208;high capacity, extra&#8208;fast rate, and excellent selectivity for the extraction of Au(III) and Pd(II). Notably, the separation of Au(III) and Pd(II) can be achieved with high selectivity at pH = 0, resulting in a remarkable separation factor of k Au(III)/Pd(II) = 36.5. This was demonstrated to originate from the differential mechanism of PAO hydrogel for the capture of Au(III) and Pd(II) under proton&#8208;mediated conditions. Drawing inspiration from the mechanism, the proton&#8208;driven cascade recovery system demonstrates remarkable efficiency in sequentially recovering 99.92% of gold and 99.05% of palladium from W&#8208;PCBs acid leachate. This research opens up a strategy to precisely separate and recover precious metals from e&#8208;waste of urban mines.</description>
      <author>Ziwen Chang, Yingying Zhou, Penghui Shao, Liming Yang, Bo Li, Dewei Li, Lingrong Zeng, Yi Gong, Xubiao Luo, Shenglian Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Outlook of Nickel&#8208;Based MOFs&#8211;LDHs Materials for Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500483</link>
      <description>Lincoln Einstein Kengne Fotso, Saad Mehmood, Vatsala Rani Jetti, Joydeep Dutta, Ujjwal Pal, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413087547

                Abstract This review focuses on the advances and outlook of integrated Ni&#8208;based MOFs (Metal&#8208;Organic Framework) and LDHs (Layered Double Hydroxides) photo(electro) catalysts, and addresses the pivotal gap in water splitting for sustainable energy generation application. MOFs and LDHs are two classes of materials with high potential for applications in photo(electro)catalytic water splitting reaction. However, challenges such as limited intrinsic activity, low electrical conductivity of a single material, lack of more exposed active sites, weak mass transport ability, and poor crystalline structure remain. State&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art strategies including doping, the development of composites, nano&#8208;structuration are used to solve these issues. Machine learning and artificial intelligence&#8208;assisted advanced in situ characterization techniques are proposed as unavoidable tools to address these challenges and optimize the catalyst design. This review outlines the key parameters involved in the assessment of the electrocatalytic and photocatalytic performance of water&#8208;splitting catalysts. The importance of density functional theory in Ni&#8208;based MOFs and LDHs for electrocatalytic water splitting is emphasized. Details about the balance of high activity along with long&#8208;term stability as a crucial requirement for large&#8208;scale applications are provided. This review will propel the knowledge and know&#8208;how in using Ni&#8208;based MOFs/LDHs as electro(photo)catalysts for hydrogen (H 2 ) production, and guide the researchers in the field.</description>
      <author>Lincoln Einstein Kengne Fotso, Saad Mehmood, Vatsala Rani Jetti, Joydeep Dutta, Ujjwal Pal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening of chalcogenides for intermediate band solar cells surpassing the Shockley-Queisser limit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/adf095</link>
      <description>Matteo Cagnoni, Journal of Physics Energy. 7(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413090529

                Abstract Intermediate band solar cells offer a promising avenue to surpass the Shockley&#8211;Queisser limit of    &#8764;  30   %    that constrains conventional single-junction devices, with the potential to approach an efficiency limit of    &#8764;  45   %    in terrestrial environments by incorporating a metallic band within the valence-conduction gap. Yet, their practical realization is challenged by difficulties in developing suitable intermediate band (IB) materials. Current approaches, which involve adding inclusions or utilizing highly mismatched alloys, often degrade material quality or present significant technological hurdles. A possible solution that remains underexplored, is to identify crystalline materials that inherently possess an IB and fine-tune their properties. In this work, thousands of crystalline chalcogenides are analyzed using a detailed balance model to quantitatively evaluate their expected efficacy as IB materials. Notably, orthorhombic     VB   1     VIA   2     and     IA   4     VIA   6     compounds, such as     Ta   1     Se   2     and     Cs   4     S   6     , are projected to achieve maximum efficiencies exceeding 35%, that is, surpassing the Shockley&#8211;Queisser limit. The interplay of IB filling and chemical substitution on the properties of these systems is analyzed, to unravel the impact on performance. This study not only identifies new material candidates for IB solar cells, but also provides insights into efficiency-property relations, hence advancing the understanding of these systems.</description>
      <author>Matteo Cagnoni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/adf095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the catalytic versatility of transition metal-doped coal char systems for hydrogen evolution reaction: a first-principles approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112882</link>
      <description>Abosede A. Badeji, Kowthaman Pathmanathan, Hewa Y. Abdullah, Ismail Hossain, Musa Runde, Chemical Physics. 599(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413097198

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abosede A. Badeji, Kowthaman Pathmanathan, Hewa Y. Abdullah, Ismail Hossain, Musa Runde</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics in enabling 2D materials: Optimization, predictive modelling, and data-driven discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2025.101814</link>
      <description>Johnson Kehinde Abifarin, Yuerui Lu, Materials Today Physics. 57(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413097860

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Johnson Kehinde Abifarin, Yuerui Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2025.101814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunability of Carbon Nitrides for Enhanced Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04006</link>
      <description>Shanping Liu, Valent&#237;n Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Haijian Tong, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Christian Mark Pelicano, Guillaume Maurin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413098894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shanping Liu, Valent&#237;n Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Haijian Tong, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Christian Mark Pelicano, Guillaume Maurin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPR_calculator: An on-the-fly surrogate model to accelerate massive nudged elastic band calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109781</link>
      <description>Isaac G. Onyango, Byungkyun Kang, Qiang Zhu, Computer Physics Communications. 316(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413099346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Isaac G. Onyango, Byungkyun Kang, Qiang Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of carboxymethyl chitosan chain length on its interaction with vitamin C and curcumin: molecular docking and molecular dynamic approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06458-w</link>
      <description>Nabela Audryna Amalia Insani, Nurwarrohman Andre Sasongko, Suci Zulaikha Hildayani, Dwi Hudiyanti, Khairul Anam, Daniel Sethio, Vivitri Dewi Prasasty, Parsaoran Siahaan, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 31(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413029349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nabela Audryna Amalia Insani, Nurwarrohman Andre Sasongko, Suci Zulaikha Hildayani, Dwi Hudiyanti, Khairul Anam, Daniel Sethio, Vivitri Dewi Prasasty, Parsaoran Siahaan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06458-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CO&#8322; adsorption kinetics in direct air capture: The role of steam desorption in amine-based anion exchange sorbents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2025.103184</link>
      <description>Florian M. Chimani, Josef Fuchs, Andreas Wallm&#252;ller, Jean Pierre Matriciani, Gerhard Sch&#246;ny, Stefan M&#252;ller, Journal of CO2 Utilization. 100(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413046267

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Florian M. Chimani, Josef Fuchs, Andreas Wallm&#252;ller, Jean Pierre Matriciani, Gerhard Sch&#246;ny, Stefan M&#252;ller</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcou.2025.103184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy-driven coordination field modulating electron spin state for enhanced bidirectional polysulfide conversion in lithium-sulfur batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.065</link>
      <description>Kangdong Tian, Ruifeng Li, Miaofa Yuan, Jiafeng Li, Chengxiang Wang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412980381

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kangdong Tian, Ruifeng Li, Miaofa Yuan, Jiafeng Li, Chengxiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dual Subsurface Hydrogen (2H&#8217;) Mechanism for Ethylene Hydrogenation on Pd</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02240</link>
      <description>Nicholas Golio, Andrew J. Gellman, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4413040709

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicholas Golio, Andrew J. Gellman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02240</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
