<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:25:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>N, S Coordination in Co Single Atom Catalyst Promoting Co2rr Towards Hcooh at Negative Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5163414</link>
      <description>H. L. Zhang, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Siyuan Liu, Hongyu Chen, Yi-tong Yin, Zhongyuan Yue, Shuxian Wei, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408093060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. L. Zhang, Maohuai Wang, Shoufu Cao, Zengxuan Chen, Siyuan Liu, Hongyu Chen, Yi-tong Yin, Zhongyuan Yue, Shuxian Wei, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5163414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Catalysis for H2o2 Reduction Using Cu(Ii) Complexes with Nitrogen Donor Tetradentate Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5163265</link>
      <description>Janet Ocampo-Hern&#225;ndez, &#193;ngel Mendoza, Gilberto Rocha&#8208;Ortiz, Juan Pablo F. Rebolledo&#8208;Ch&#225;vez, Lillian G. Ram&#237;rez&#8208;Palma, Fernando Cort&#233;s&#8208;Guzm&#225;n, Marisela Cruz-Ram&#237;rez, Luis Ortiz&#8208;Frade, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408097789

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Janet Ocampo-Hern&#225;ndez, &#193;ngel Mendoza, Gilberto Rocha&#8208;Ortiz, Juan Pablo F. Rebolledo&#8208;Ch&#225;vez, Lillian G. Ram&#237;rez&#8208;Palma, Fernando Cort&#233;s&#8208;Guzm&#225;n, Marisela Cruz-Ram&#237;rez, Luis Ortiz&#8208;Frade</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5163265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Structure Prediction Meets Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03727</link>
      <description>Zian Chen, Zijun Meng, Tao He, Haichao Li, Jian Cao, Lina Xu, Hong&#8208;Ping Xiao, Yueyu Zhang, Xiao He, Guoyong Fang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408098824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zian Chen, Zijun Meng, Tao He, Haichao Li, Jian Cao, Lina Xu, Hong&#8208;Ping Xiao, Yueyu Zhang, Xiao He, Guoyong Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-to-Metal Charge Transfer Controls the Photophysical Properties and HER Activity of Ag&lt;sub&gt;13&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters Depends on the Hydrogen Adsorption Energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00101</link>
      <description>Aarti Devi, Harshita Seksaria, Rashi, Abir De Sarkar, Amitava Patra, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408099309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aarti Devi, Harshita Seksaria, Rashi, Abir De Sarkar, Amitava Patra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of water impurities on promoted and unpromoted cobalt-catalysts during the ammonia decomposition reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116054</link>
      <description>Zahra Almisbaa, Philippe Sautet, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408103035

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahra Almisbaa, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Outer- and Inner-Sphere Electrosynthesis from Biomass-Derived Furfural Using Single Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00468</link>
      <description>Sihang Liu, Zamaan Mukadam, Angus Pedersen, Jes&#250;s Barrio, J.V. Parker, Helen E.J. Tyrrell, Sarah J. Haigh, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Georg Kastlunger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408105894

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sihang Liu, Zamaan Mukadam, Angus Pedersen, Jes&#250;s Barrio, J.V. Parker, Helen E.J. Tyrrell, Sarah J. Haigh, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Georg Kastlunger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel&#8211;Antimony Electrocatalyst for Durable Acidic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Proton Exchange Membrane Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00233</link>
      <description>Cheng Cai, Husileng Lee, Weili Shi, Y.H. Liu, Biaobiao Zhang, Licheng Sun, Tao Wang, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408106746

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Cai, Husileng Lee, Weili Shi, Y.H. Liu, Biaobiao Zhang, Licheng Sun, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Alkaline Water Electrolysis by the Rational Decoration of RuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; with the In Situ-Grown CoFe Nanolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c16691</link>
      <description>Sang&#8208;Woo Kim, Jeongah Lee, Yong Beom Kim, DongHwan Oh, Jun Kyu Kim, Bonjae Koo, Hyunseung Kim, Gi hong Jung, MinJoong Kim, Gisu Doo, Jongsu Seo, Tae Jin Lim, Kyeounghak Kim, Jeong Woo Han, WooChul Jung, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408113042

                Rational engineering of the surfaces of heterogeneous catalysts (especially the surfaces of supported metals) can endow intriguing catalytic functionalities for electrochemical reactions. However, it often requires complicated steps, and even if it does not, breaking the trade-off between activity and stability is quite challenging. Herein, we present a strategy for reconstructing supported catalysts via in situ growth of metallic nanolayers from the perovskite oxide support. When Ru-coated LaFe0.9Co0.1O3 is thermally reduced, the CoFe nanoalloy spontaneously migrates onto the Ru and greatly increases the physicochemical stability of Ru in alkaline water electrolysis. Benefiting from an 81% reduction in Ru dissolution after decoration, it operates for over 200 h without noticeable degradation. Furthermore, the underlying Ru modifies the electronic structure and surface adsorption properties of the CoFe overlayer toward reaction intermediates, synergistically catalyzing both the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction. Specifically, the mass activity of the oxygen evolution reaction is 64.1 times greater than that of commercial RuO2. Our work highlights a way to protect inherently unstable Ru from dissolution while allowing it to influence surface kinetics from the subsurface sites in heterogeneous catalysts.</description>
      <author>Sang&#8208;Woo Kim, Jeongah Lee, Yong Beom Kim, DongHwan Oh, Jun Kyu Kim, Bonjae Koo, Hyunseung Kim, Gi hong Jung, MinJoong Kim, Gisu Doo, Jongsu Seo, Tae Jin Lim, Kyeounghak Kim, Jeong Woo Han, WooChul Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c16691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrutinization of late first-row transition metals decorated octagonal boron (B8) ring complexes as single-atom catalysts for green hydrogen and oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra07274j</link>
      <description>Naveen Kosar, Tariq Mahmood, Muhammad Arshad, Muhammad Imran, Utkirjon Holikulov, RSC Advances. 15(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408117028

                DFT-driven design of late TM@B8 for enhanced SACs in HER.</description>
      <author>Naveen Kosar, Tariq Mahmood, Muhammad Arshad, Muhammad Imran, Utkirjon Holikulov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra07274j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced transition metal phosphide&#8211;based materials for hydrogen evolution reactions: a comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06166-8</link>
      <description>Bheema Divya, Manjunatha Kumara K S, Sunilkumar P Sunilkumar P, Srinivasa Budagumpi, Sumanjali Kota, M. B. Madhusudana Reddy, D. H. Nagaraju, Ionics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408118259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bheema Divya, Manjunatha Kumara K S, Sunilkumar P Sunilkumar P, Srinivasa Budagumpi, Sumanjali Kota, M. B. Madhusudana Reddy, D. H. Nagaraju</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06166-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom M/GDY catalysts for electrochemical ethylene conversion via tandem water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162865</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Sun, Wen Zhao, Wei Cai, Yuhua Chi, Hao Ren, Zhongtao Li, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408122811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Sun, Wen Zhao, Wei Cai, Yuhua Chi, Hao Ren, Zhongtao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P-NiMoN/NF Heterostructure Nanorod Arrays as Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Urea Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c22180</link>
      <description>Zixuan Zhang, Dongxing Tan, Jing Wang, Dan Zhang, Qingkun Kong, Weiqing Kong, Xiaowei Yin, Yuanyuan Feng, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408124543

                Electrolysis of water represents an effective method for the generation of high-purity hydrogen. Nevertheless, the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) exhibits slow kinetics, which leads to a high electrolytic potential and induces excessive energy consumption. In this work, nickel foam-supported 3D phosphide/bimetal nitride (Co2P-NiMoN/NF) nanorod array catalyst is prepared by calcination of NiMoO4, followed by phosphatization of Co(OH)2. The heterostructure catalyst exhibits excellent catalytic activity for cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER: &#951;100 = 98 mV, &#951;1000 = 297 mV) and anodic OER (&#951;100 = 277 mV, &#951;1000 = 382 mV) of water electrolysis in alkaline electrolyte, indicating its feasibility as a bifunctional catalyst for overall water splitting (OWS). Additionally, at a current density of 100 mA cm-2, the associated oxidation potential is decreased by roughly 160 mV when the anodic OER is replaced with the urea oxidation process (UOR), which has a far lower thermodynamic equilibrium potential. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the heterointerface between Co2P and NiMoN enriches the density of electronic states near the Fermi level, thereby enhancing electron transfer and promoting charge redistribution. This modulation precisely tunes the adsorption strengths of reactants during the reaction process, ultimately boosting the electrocatalytic performance. A current density of 100 mA cm-2 can be attained at a cell voltage of 1.51 V when Co2P-NiMoN/NF is used as the anode and cathode in the urea electrolysis cell. Notably, this cell potential is significantly lower compared to that of the water electrolysis cell (1.65 V), as well as the previously published values. The findings demonstrate that the Co2P-NiMoN/NF heterostructure can be used as a bifunctional catalyst for water and urea electrolysis and demonstrate an efficient strategy for the energy-efficient production of hydrogen through substituting UOR for OER at the anode of water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Zixuan Zhang, Dongxing Tan, Jing Wang, Dan Zhang, Qingkun Kong, Weiqing Kong, Xiaowei Yin, Yuanyuan Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c22180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Saturation: A Fundamental Principle for Single-Atom-Site Catalyst Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00643</link>
      <description>Chunjin Ren, Yu Cui, Qiang Li, Chongyi Ling, Jinlan Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408128326

                Single-atom alloys (SAAs), with twin advantages of alloys and single-atom catalysts, have emerged as an innovative class of electrocatalysts. This uniqueness is expected to achieve unattainable catalytic performance but simultaneously gives rise to the absence of guidelines for designing desired SAAs. Herein, we proposed a fundamental principle, single-atom saturation (SSA), to quantify the binding strength of different intermediates on SAAs, enabling the rapid and qualitative evaluation of the catalytic activity across various reactions. SSA is rationalized by combining the variation of electronic structure (d electron occupancy saturation) and geometrical structure (coordination saturation) of the single guest atom as well as the effect of the host atom type and the intermediate adsorption configuration. Based on the insights given by SSA, Pd1Cu(111), Ru1Cu(111), Ir1Ag(111), Pt1Ag(111), and Pt1Cu(111) are predicted to possess excellent activity for CO2 reduction, N2 reduction, O2 evolution, O2 reduction, and H2 evolution reactions, respectively, most of which are supported by reported experiments. Moreover, SSA is also applicable to nitrogen-doped graphene-supported single-atom catalysts (SACs) with ultrahigh accuracy. In general, single-atom saturation is a concise, interpretable, and universal descriptor that deciphers the structure-activity relation of SAAs across various reactions, where the insights revealed also offer a simple and fundamental principle for the design of excellent single-atom-site catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chunjin Ren, Yu Cui, Qiang Li, Chongyi Ling, Jinlan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c00643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced ORR and OER bifunctional performance of Co-N-C single atom catalyst by interlayer covalent interaction of graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162879</link>
      <description>Depeng Meng, Hongpeng Chen, Jinshuo Pang, Chunnian He, Chunsheng Shi, Naiqin Zhao, Enzuo Liu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408129206

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Depeng Meng, Hongpeng Chen, Jinshuo Pang, Chunnian He, Chunsheng Shi, Naiqin Zhao, Enzuo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design principles of non-noble metal catalysts for high-performance rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104155</link>
      <description>Pengxiang Liu, Yaqian Wang, Ruitao Lv, Guangying Zhang, Xu Liu, Lei Wang, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408129674

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengxiang Liu, Yaqian Wang, Ruitao Lv, Guangying Zhang, Xu Liu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrocatalytic N2 fixation over BC3N2 monolayer: A computational screening of single-atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114931</link>
      <description>Chaozheng He, Ye Shen, Long Lin, Kun Xie, Songshan Gao, Yaowei Liu, Molecular Catalysis. 577(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408131851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaozheng He, Ye Shen, Long Lin, Kun Xie, Songshan Gao, Yaowei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Aqueous and Electrochemical Stability of 2D Materials from Extended Pourbaix Analyses</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00178</link>
      <description>Stefano Americo, Ivano E. Castelli, Kristian S. Thygesen, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408132151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefano Americo, Ivano E. Castelli, Kristian S. Thygesen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Polymer Electrolyte Membrane Water Electrolyzer Stack Development Studies: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10147</link>
      <description>Murat K&#305;st&#305;, Bulut H&#252;ner, Abdelmola Albadwi, Emre &#214;zdo&#287;an, &#304;layda Nur Uzg&#246;ren, S&#252;leyman Uysal, Marise Cona&#287;as&#305;, Yakup Og&#252;n S&#252;zen, Nesrin Dem&#239;r, Mehmet Fatih Kaya, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408132242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Murat K&#305;st&#305;, Bulut H&#252;ner, Abdelmola Albadwi, Emre &#214;zdo&#287;an, &#304;layda Nur Uzg&#246;ren, S&#252;leyman Uysal, Marise Cona&#287;as&#305;, Yakup Og&#252;n S&#252;zen, Nesrin Dem&#239;r, Mehmet Fatih Kaya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study of UMCM-9 Polymorphs: Structural, Dynamic, and Hydrogen Storage Properties via Atomistic Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07872</link>
      <description>Josef M. Gallmetzer, Jakob Gamper, Stefanie Kr&#246;ll, Thomas S. Hofer, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408138893

                The structural and dynamic properties of two polymorphs of the metal&#8211;organic framework UMCM-9 (UMCM-9-&#945; and -&#946;) have been studied via molecular dynamics (MD) simulations in conjunction with density functional tight binding (DFTB) as well as the newly developed MACE&#8211;MP neural network potential (NNP). Based on these calculations, a novel UMCM-9-&#946; polymorph is proposed that exhibits reduced linker strain and increased flexibility compared to UMCM-9-&#945;, which is shown to be energetically less stable. UMCM-9-&#946; exhibits enhanced diffusion of molecular hydrogen due to weaker host&#8211;guest interactions, whereas UMCM-9-&#945; exhibits stronger interactions, leading to improved hydrogen adsorption. The results suggest that synthesis conditions may control the formation of both polymorphs: UMCM-9-&#946; is likely to be the thermodynamic product, forming under stable conditions, while UMCM-9-&#945; may be the kinetic product, forming under accelerated synthesis conditions. This study highlights the potential for optimizing MOFs for specific gas storage applications to achieve the desired structural and associated gas storage properties.</description>
      <author>Josef M. Gallmetzer, Jakob Gamper, Stefanie Kr&#246;ll, Thomas S. Hofer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orientation-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Catalytic Performance and Mechanistic Insights of Epitaxial Co&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; Thin Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00074</link>
      <description>Yong Wang, Yi Chen, Hongyuan Zhou, Zhao Yang, Shulong Li, Liang Qiao, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408142326

                Cobalt sulfide (Co9S8) nanomaterials exhibit an efficient electrochemical catalytic performance due to their unique properties and electronic structure. The preparation of epitaxial Co9S8 thin films with varying crystal orientations and the study of their catalytic kinetics and mechanisms remain significant gaps. This study addresses the preparation of epitaxial Co9S8 thin films with orientations of (100), (110), and (111) on yttrium-doped zirconia (YSZ) substrates using pulsed laser deposition. Characterization confirmed their single-crystalline nature and consistent thickness. Electrochemical measurements revealed a similar hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance across all films but significant differences in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. The (111) orientation showed the best OER activity, with a current density of 24.2 mA cm-2 at 1.8 V vs RHE, outperforming the (100) and (110) orientations, which achieved 14.5 and 6.7 mA cm-2, respectively. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicated that the (100) orientation favored the traditional four-electron transfer mechanism, with a lower theoretical overpotential (0.37 V). In contrast, the (110) and (111) orientations demonstrated more complex adsorption behaviors, resulting in a higher overpotential of 0.49 V and a lower overpotential of 0.29 V, respectively. These results highlight the unique reactivity of different Co9S8 crystal orientations and provide valuable insights for optimizing the catalyst design to enhance the OER performance.</description>
      <author>Yong Wang, Yi Chen, Hongyuan Zhou, Zhao Yang, Shulong Li, Liang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00074</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of the Different Trends of Experimental Activity on Perovskite Catalysts between OER and ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c03003</link>
      <description>Anran Hou, Runhai Ouyang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408143741

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anran Hou, Runhai Ouyang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c03003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targeted construction of high-performance single-atom platinum-based electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60199-3</link>
      <description>Jing Liu, Xiandi Ma, JeongHan Roh, Dongwon Shin, Ara Cho, Jeong Woo Han, Jianping Long, Zhen Zhou, Menggai Jiao, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, EunAe Cho, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 69(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408143969

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Liu, Xiandi Ma, JeongHan Roh, Dongwon Shin, Ara Cho, Jeong Woo Han, Jianping Long, Zhen Zhou, Menggai Jiao, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, EunAe Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60199-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the C&#8211;C coupling mechanism in electrochemical CO reduction at low CO coverage: Dynamic change in site preference matters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60180-4</link>
      <description>Zhe Chen, Tao Wang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 69(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408143973

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhe Chen, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60180-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative photocatalytic C&#8211;C coupling with Cu and P dual sites to produce C2H4 over Cu P/g-C3N4 heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60183-x</link>
      <description>Dongxiao Wen, Nan Wang, Jiahe Peng, Tetsuro Majima, Jizhou Jiang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 69(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408143976

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongxiao Wen, Nan Wang, Jiahe Peng, Tetsuro Majima, Jizhou Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60183-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge-constrained atomic cluster expansion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.033802</link>
      <description>Matteo Rinaldi, Anton Bochkarev, Yury Lysogorskiy, Ralf Drautz, Physical Review Materials. 9(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408150315

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matteo Rinaldi, Anton Bochkarev, Yury Lysogorskiy, Ralf Drautz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.033802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in lanthanide-based materials for oxygen evolution reaction: Challenges and future prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216573</link>
      <description>Sheraz Muhammad, Lixia Wang, Zhiyang Huang, Aling Zhou, Hazrat Bilal, Tayirjan Taylor Isimjan, Xiulin Yang, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 534(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408152230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sheraz Muhammad, Lixia Wang, Zhiyang Huang, Aling Zhou, Hazrat Bilal, Tayirjan Taylor Isimjan, Xiulin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compressive-strained rutile TiO2 enables O2 mono-hydrogenation for singlet oxygen electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00756-0</link>
      <description>R. F. Wang, Jie Dai, Long Zhao, Zhiwei Hu, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Chang&#8208;Yang Kuo, Guangming Zhan, Yanbiao Shi, Jiaxian Wang, Yunjie Zou, Mingkai Xu, Xingyue Zou, Qian Zheng, B. Zhou, Kaiyuan Wang, Rui Zhao, Yan Zhang, Y. Shen, Yancai Yao, Lizhi Zhang, Nature Synthesis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408156981

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. F. Wang, Jie Dai, Long Zhao, Zhiwei Hu, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Chang&#8208;Yang Kuo, Guangming Zhan, Yanbiao Shi, Jiaxian Wang, Yunjie Zou, Mingkai Xu, Xingyue Zou, Qian Zheng, B. Zhou, Kaiyuan Wang, Rui Zhao, Yan Zhang, Y. Shen, Yancai Yao, Lizhi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00756-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic potential of bare and OH-functionalized co-N-doped pyrene for ORR and HER: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115167</link>
      <description>Angappan Kausalya, Thangaraj Thiruppathiraja, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408160127

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angappan Kausalya, Thangaraj Thiruppathiraja, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study of oxygen reduction reaction catalyzed by Fe&#8211;Zn dual-atom Co-anchored on N doped carbon structures decorated with axial ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.447</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Jialu Li, Siyu Gan, Xihao Chen, Guangzhao Wang, Bingke Li, Tianhang Zhou, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 113(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408164157

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Jialu Li, Siyu Gan, Xihao Chen, Guangzhao Wang, Bingke Li, Tianhang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational catalyst design for N2 electro-reduction: Regulation strategies and quick screen towards enhanced conversion efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111056</link>
      <description>Jinzhou Zheng, Chaozheng He, Chenxu Zhao, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408168060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinzhou Zheng, Chaozheng He, Chenxu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monoatomic metalloporphyrinoid catalysts for efficient oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03151-4</link>
      <description>Yao Ying, Xiaoting Chen, Xinyuan Zhang, Shangbin Jin, Zhihong Tian, Guoliang Li, Liming Yang, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408175409

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Ying, Xiaoting Chen, Xinyuan Zhang, Shangbin Jin, Zhihong Tian, Guoliang Li, Liming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03151-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From waste to fuel cells. In situ preparation of an atomically precise Pd(II)-catalyst by selective extraction of Pd(II) from a mixture of metal ions using modified multi walled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) and its implementation in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in alkaline solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236661</link>
      <description>Marco Bonechi, Carlotta Cappanni, Pietro Gentilesca, Carla Bazzicalupi, Walter Giurlani, Massimo Innocenti, Leonardo Lari, Francesco Montanari, Matteo Savastano, Mirko Severi, Antonio Bianchi, Journal of Power Sources. 639(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408177228

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marco Bonechi, Carlotta Cappanni, Pietro Gentilesca, Carla Bazzicalupi, Walter Giurlani, Massimo Innocenti, Leonardo Lari, Francesco Montanari, Matteo Savastano, Mirko Severi, Antonio Bianchi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236661</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Pt/C and PtCu/C electrocatalysts for improved oxygen reduction reaction in proton-exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10757-1</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Kirill Paperzh, Angelina Pavlets, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, A. K. Nevelskaya, Yulia Bayan, M. V. Danilenko, Ilya Pankov, &#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408181426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1089;&#1077;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Kirill Paperzh, Angelina Pavlets, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1095;&#1080;&#1093;, A. K. Nevelskaya, Yulia Bayan, M. V. Danilenko, Ilya Pankov, &#1042;. &#1045;. &#1043;&#1091;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1072;&#1085;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10757-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single metal atom anchored graphitic carbon nitride monolayers as promising multifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162840</link>
      <description>Shan Peng, Xiaolin Wu, Wengang Cheng, Xinhua Li, Zihao Cheng, De&#8208;Bing Long, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408185444

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shan Peng, Xiaolin Wu, Wengang Cheng, Xinhua Li, Zihao Cheng, De&#8208;Bing Long</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Three-Tiered Hierarchical Computational Framework Bridging Molecular Systems and Junction-Level Charge Transport</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01711</link>
      <description>Xuan Ji, Qiang Qi, Yueqi Chen, Chen Zhou, Xi Yu, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408186192

                The nonequilibrium Green's function (NEGF) method combined with ab initio calculations has been widely used to study charge transport in molecular junctions. However, the significant computational demands of high-resolution calculations for all device components pose challenges in simulating junctions with complex molecular junction structures and understanding the functionality of molecular devices. In this study, we developed a series of computational methods capable of effectively handling the molecular Hamiltonian, electrode electronic structures, and their interfacial coupling at different theoretical levels. As three-tiered hierarchical levels, they enable efficient charge transport computations ranging from individual molecules to complete junction systems, achieving an optimal balance between computational cost and accuracy. Moreover, integrated into a Question-Driven Hierarchical Computation (QDHC) framework, we show this three-tiered framework is able to address specific research objectives by isolating and analyzing the dominant factors governing charge transport, thus significantly enhancing the efficiency of analyzing charge transport mechanisms, as validated through a series of benchmark studies on diverse molecular junction systems.</description>
      <author>Xuan Ji, Qiang Qi, Yueqi Chen, Chen Zhou, Xi Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01711</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of the Electronic Properties of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; through Bi Octahedral Doping for Enhanced Activity in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07911</link>
      <description>Damian Gorylewski, Filip Zasada, Grzegorz S&#322;owik, Magdalena Lofek, Gabriela Grzybek, Katarzyna Tyszczuk&#8208;Rotko, Andrzej Kotarba, Pawe&#322; Stelmachowski, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408190039

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Damian Gorylewski, Filip Zasada, Grzegorz S&#322;owik, Magdalena Lofek, Gabriela Grzybek, Katarzyna Tyszczuk&#8208;Rotko, Andrzej Kotarba, Pawe&#322; Stelmachowski</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07911</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Accelerated Interfacial Fluxionality in Ni-Supported Metal Nitride Ammonia Synthesis Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168150</link>
      <description>Pranav Roy, Brandon C. Bukowski, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408190436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pranav Roy, Brandon C. Bukowski</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Exploration of Codoped Fe and Ru Single-Atom Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168151</link>
      <description>Haojun Jia, Chenru Duan, Gianmarco Terrones, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408190457

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haojun Jia, Chenru Duan, Gianmarco Terrones, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Imaging of Chirality Transfer Induced by Glycosidic Bond Stereochemistry in Carbohydrate Self-Assemblies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16088</link>
      <description>Shuning Cai, Joakim S. Jestil&#228;, Peter Liljeroth, Adam S. Foster, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408192153

                Carbohydrates, essential biological building blocks, exhibit functional mechanisms tied to their intricate stereochemistry. Subtle stereochemical differences, such as those between the anomers maltose and cellobiose, lead to distinct properties due to their differing glycosidic bonds; the former is digestible by humans, while the latter is not. This underscores the importance of precise structural determination of individual carbohydrate molecules for deeper functional insights. However, their structural complexity and conformational flexibility, combined with the high spatial resolution needed, have hindered direct imaging of carbohydrate stereochemistry. Here, we employ noncontact atomic force microscopy integrated with a data-efficient, multifidelity structure search approach accelerated by machine learning integration to determine the precise 3D atomic coordinates of two carbohydrate anomers on Au(111). We observe that the stereochemistry of the glycosidic bond regulates on-surface chiral selection in carbohydrate self-assemblies. The reconstructed models, validated against experimental data, provide reliable atomic-scale structural evidence, uncovering the origin of the on-surface chirality from carbohydrate anomerism. Our study confirms that nc-AFM is a reliable technique for real-space discrimination of carbohydrate stereochemistry at the single-molecule level, providing a pathway for bottom-up investigations into the structure-property relationships of carbohydrates in biological research and materials science.</description>
      <author>Shuning Cai, Joakim S. Jestil&#228;, Peter Liljeroth, Adam S. Foster</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning assisted screening of non-metal doped MXenes catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.469</link>
      <description>Mei Yang, Changxin Wang, Minhui Song, Lu Xie, Ping Qian, Yanjing Su, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 113(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408194232

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mei Yang, Changxin Wang, Minhui Song, Lu Xie, Ping Qian, Yanjing Su</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.02.469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface hydrogen migration significantly promotes electroreduction of acetonitrile to ethylamine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57462-w</link>
      <description>Yulong Tang, J. Li, Yichao Lin, Miaomiao Cheng, Shuibo Wang, Ziqi Tian, Junjie Zhou, H. M. Zhang, Yunan Wang, Liang Chen, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408196546

                The electrochemical reduction of acetonitrile (AN) to ethylamine (EA) is an attractive yet challenging process, primarily due to the competing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This study demonstrates the ability to halt the HER at Volmer step, where protons migrate to the unsaturated bond of AN on a self-supported CuO@Cu heterostructure. The CuO@Cu catalyst exhibits nearly 100% Faradaic efficiency (FE) over the entire range of potentials tested from -0.1 to -0.4 V vs. RHE, demonstrating remarkable stability over 1000 h at a constant current density of 0.2 A cm-2. CuO is identified as the active component driving the reaction, while the metallic Cu facilitates efficient electron transfer. Theoretical simulations and experimental evidences indicate that a synergistic hydrogenation process contributes to the AN reduction reaction (ARR), which involves both surface hydrogen migration and proton addition from solution. This study provides an insight into understanding of ARR process, and suggests an efficient strategy to enhance the electrochemical hydrogenation of organic molecules by regulating the Volmer step.</description>
      <author>Yulong Tang, J. Li, Yichao Lin, Miaomiao Cheng, Shuibo Wang, Ziqi Tian, Junjie Zhou, H. M. Zhang, Yunan Wang, Liang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57462-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom alloys 2.0: Exploiting undercoordination for stronger dissociative CH4 chemisorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122735</link>
      <description>Debtanu Maiti, Michael P. Harold, Lars C. Grabow, Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408200122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Debtanu Maiti, Michael P. Harold, Lars C. Grabow</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights of nitrate reduction to ammonia on partially reduced In2O3 surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114991</link>
      <description>Qingchao Fang, M. T. Nasir, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Yun Han, Xuxin Kang, Cheng Yan, Anthony P. O&#8217;Mullane, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du, Molecular Catalysis. 577(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408202856

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingchao Fang, M. T. Nasir, Dimuthu Wijethunge, Yun Han, Xuxin Kang, Cheng Yan, Anthony P. O&#8217;Mullane, Hanqing Yin, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114991</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature dependent mechanism transition effect stabilized ruthenium-based oxides for water oxidation in proton exchange membrane electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4097038/v1</link>
      <description>Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, Rui Wu, Heng Liu, Sihua Feng, Sheng Zhu, Jie Xu, Hengli Duan, Ruiqi Liu, Yingkang Qin, Wensheng Yan, Xiaozhi Su, Hao Li, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408203568

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER), as the anodic reaction of many electrochemical devices, plays a crucial role in such energy conversion process. However, the poor OER stability of non-iridium-based materials has tremendously limited the large-scale application of related devices. Here, using a novel home-made operando differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy, for the first time we report a temperature dependent mechanism transition (TDMT) effect of RhRu3Ox, a non-iridium-based electrocatalyst, in OER process, which makes us realize the important role of temperature in triggering OER mechanism transition, and further enriches our toolbox for manipulating OER kinetics. To evaluate the potential of RhRu3Ox for practical applications, we assembled it as an anode in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, demonstrating its stability at room temperature for over 1000 hours at 200 mA cm-2 compared with the unstable pristine RuO2. Techno-economic analysis shows that the cost of H2 production using solar photovoltaic and onshore wind as power sources is already lower than the global average levelized cost of H2 from coal. Density functional theory studies reveal that the existence of kinetic barrier related to lattice oxygen activation might be the reason for the OER TDMT of RhRu3Ox at elevated temperature.</description>
      <author>Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, Rui Wu, Heng Liu, Sihua Feng, Sheng Zhu, Jie Xu, Hengli Duan, Ruiqi Liu, Yingkang Qin, Wensheng Yan, Xiaozhi Su, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4097038/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ion Irradiation Engineered Defect Formation and Hydrogen Evolution on Two-Dimensional Mos2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5167848</link>
      <description>Jiahua Xu, Tianzhao Li, Wenjin Gao, Miaogen Chen, Jinge Wu, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408204590

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahua Xu, Tianzhao Li, Wenjin Gao, Miaogen Chen, Jinge Wu, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5167848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial metal&#8211;coordinated bifunctional PtCo for practical fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adt4914</link>
      <description>Zhongliang Huang, Qi Xiao, Tianyi Ding, Jing Xia, Changhong Zhan, Xiangmin Meng, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Y Wang, Nanjun Chen, Liang Cao, Xiaoqing Huang, Science Advances. 11(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408223155

                Platinum (Pt) has been documented as the top-tier fuel cell catalyst, yet it faces a notable challenge regarding its poor CO tolerance and sluggish oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), particularly when using CO-contaminated blue and gray H 2 . Here, we present an interfacial metal coordination strategy to design a bifunctional platinum-cobalt (PtCo) intermetallic catalyst integrated with a tin-nitrogen-carbon (Sn&#8211;N&#8211;C) support, which forms Pt&#8211;Sn&#8211;N bonds that substantially boost both ORR activity and CO tolerance. The PtCo/Sn&#8211;N&#8211;C-made fuel cell achieves a topmost peak power density of 2.11 watts per square centimeter in 100 parts per million (ppm) of CO-containing H 2 , surpassing all previously reported PEMFCs. In addition, it operates stably at a rated voltage for over 710 hours in 100 ppm of CO/H 2 -air. This work demonstrates the feasibility of fuel cells directly using CO-contaminated gray &amp; blue H 2 , paving the way for PEMFC-driven energy vehicles.</description>
      <author>Zhongliang Huang, Qi Xiao, Tianyi Ding, Jing Xia, Changhong Zhan, Xiangmin Meng, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Zhiwei Hu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Y Wang, Nanjun Chen, Liang Cao, Xiaoqing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adt4914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Dichroism in Strong-Coupled Chiral Molecule-Plasmon Nanoparticle System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00721</link>
      <description>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yurui Fang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408223641

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yurui Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of alkali and alkaline earth defects on the Electronic, magnetic properties and work function of 2H-CrS2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113822</link>
      <description>Xuejiao Wang, Xintao Li, Longhua Li, Computational Materials Science. 253(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408225487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuejiao Wang, Xintao Li, Longhua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2025.113822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Descriptor toward Optimizing Electrocatalytic N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxidation to HNO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Performance over Graphene-Based Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00234</link>
      <description>Chuang Zhi, Shouyu Cai, Dengning Sun, Juan Yang, Zhongti Sun, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408226563

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) exhibit tremendous advantages in the electrochemical N2 oxidation reaction (EN2OR) to HNO3, which is an eco-friendly alternative to the synthesis of conventional industrial nitric acid and nitrates, but methods to rationally design and rapidly screen high-efficiency EN2OR SACs are unclear. Herein, taking pyridinic nitrogen-doped graphene-supported SACs as an example, a simple descriptor has been proposed to evaluate the EN2OR performance through systematically constructing a surface reaction phase diagram. This descriptor is comprised of merely the geometric information and inherent atomic properties (occupied d electron number, electronegativity, and coordinate number) that can accurately predict the activity and selectivity of EN2OR, independent of DFT simulations. Based on this descriptor, high-throughput screening has been executed on partially N/C/O coordinated SACs, including 160 candidates; 13 candidates with the overpotential of less than 1.0 V are selected and then validated by DFT calculations with a mean absolute error (MAE) as low as 0.09 V, indicating the reliability of the descriptor. Meanwhile, the screened CoO2N2-G and RhO2N2-G SACs exhibit lower EN2OR overpotential of 0.64 and 0.68 V and more negative UL(EN2OR) - UL(OER) values of -0.34 and -0.44 V in comparison to other candidates, respectively, demonstrating the excellent activity and selectivity of EN2OR. This work offers a route to rapid discovery of high-performance SACs for EN2OR.</description>
      <author>Chuang Zhi, Shouyu Cai, Dengning Sun, Juan Yang, Zhongti Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quasi Fe MIL-53 nanozyme inducing ferroptosis and immunogenic cell death for cancer immunotherapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57542-x</link>
      <description>Zhaoxiong Yan, Yang Bai, Songtao Zhang, Lingyi Kong, Yu Wang, Han Sun, Yi Li, Lin Qiu, Ruijie Zhang, Pengju Jiang, Donghui Zhao, Zhongyan Chen, Yafei Li, Huan Pang, Jianhao Wang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408229481

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaoxiong Yan, Yang Bai, Songtao Zhang, Lingyi Kong, Yu Wang, Han Sun, Yi Li, Lin Qiu, Ruijie Zhang, Pengju Jiang, Donghui Zhao, Zhongyan Chen, Yafei Li, Huan Pang, Jianhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57542-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-efficient construction of high-fidelity graph deep learning interatomic potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01550-4</link>
      <description>Tsz Wai Ko, Shyue Ping Ong, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408231448

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tsz Wai Ko, Shyue Ping Ong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01550-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupled Differential Electrochemical Mass Spectrometry and Surface-Enhanced Infrared Absorption Spectroscopic Studies Unravel the Mechanism of Nitric Oxide Electroreduction on Platinum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16057</link>
      <description>Hongsen Wang, H&#232;ctor D. Abru&#241;a, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408231674

                The nitric oxide electroreduction reaction (NORR) has received considerable attention due to its importance in electrochemical denitrification of nitrogen oxides in groundwater and industrial waste gases and electrochemical ammonia synthesis. However, the detailed mechanism and the factors that affect product selectivity are far less understood. Employing coupled differential electrochemical mass spectrometry (DEMS) and attenuated total reflection-surface-enhanced infrared absorption (ATR-SEIRA) spectroscopy, adsorbed species and volatile solution products, during the adsorption of NO and NORR on Pt in both alkaline and acidic media, have been simultaneously studied, enabling us to correlate the potential-dependent product selectivity with the surface ad-species. NOad,M, NOad,B, NOad,L, and NO2,ad were identified using SEIRA spectroscopy as surface ad-species, with their potential-dependent intensities having a strong correlation with the product selectivity. N2O is the only reduction product at potentials beyond the hydrogen region and is attributed to the reduction of weakly adsorbed NO. In contrast, the formation of NH3 and NH2OH occurs only in the hydrogen region and is ascribed to the reaction between strongly adsorbed NO and adsorbed H. N2 is a minor product, and is formed through further reduction of N2O by adsorbed H. The formation of N2 is significantly suppressed in acidic media due to the fast kinetics of NO reduction to NH3/NH2OH, and thus lowering of NO coverage in the hydrogen region. To achieve the selective reduction of NO to NH3/NH2OH, the potential should remain at 0.1-0.2 V (vs RHE) in both acidic and alkaline media while a slow NO supply, and acidic media are preferred over alkaline media due to the faster kinetics. These new spectroscopic results and insights about the NORR could advance the design of more effective NORR catalysts and help develop optimal conditions for selective ammonia synthesis.</description>
      <author>Hongsen Wang, H&#232;ctor D. Abru&#241;a</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Engineering the Optoelectronic and HER Behavior of MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/ZnO Heterojunction: A DFT Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03605</link>
      <description>Jian Yang, LI Xiao-wen, Yu Yang, Ruifen Dou, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408236348

                The rational design of heterojunctions by coupling two or more two-dimensional (2D) materials is regarded as a feasible strategy to efficiently enhance photocatalytic-hydrogen performance by capturing solar energy to address the increasing global energy crisis. In this work, a functional MoS2/ZnO heterojunction is proposed based on first-principles simulation. Our results reveal that the photogenerated electrons and holes in the MoS2/ZnO heterojunction follow a specific Z-scheme pathway, highly facilitating redox reactions and optimizing optical properties in the visible-light region. Under external strain, the MoS2/ZnO heterojunction demonstrates improved HER performance and remarkable optical-harvesting capabilities. Interestingly, the HER free energy for the heterojunction is only -0.04 eV under -5% compressive strain, highlighting its promising potential for photocatalytic hydrogen production. We observe that the absorption edge of the spectrum shifts gradually to the infrared region with increasing tensile biaxial strains, whereas compressive biaxial strains result in a blue-shift absorption spectrum. Additionally, all heterojunctions achieve excellent solar-to-hydrogen (STH) efficiencies exceeding 10%, demonstrating their capability to store sufficient solar energy. Our work offers a novel strategy for exploring highly efficient photocatalysts in the field of hydrogen energy with the ability to modulate their activity through external strain.</description>
      <author>Jian Yang, LI Xiao-wen, Yu Yang, Ruifen Dou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-defined monolayers, bilayers and trilayers of two-dimensional Janus MoSSe and Ga2SSe van der Waals homojunctions as potential photocatalysts for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122829</link>
      <description>Fan Yang, Marie&#8208;Christine Record, Pascal Boulet, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408236886

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan Yang, Marie&#8208;Christine Record, Pascal Boulet</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin and scarcity of breathing pyrochlore lattices in spinel oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.033602</link>
      <description>Valentina Mazzotti, Solveig S. Aamlid, Abraham A. Mancilla, Janna Machts, Megan Rutherford, J&#246;rg Rottler, Kenji Kojima, Alannah M. Hallas, Physical Review Materials. 9(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408241532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Valentina Mazzotti, Solveig S. Aamlid, Abraham A. Mancilla, Janna Machts, Megan Rutherford, J&#246;rg Rottler, Kenji Kojima, Alannah M. Hallas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.033602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The QCML dataset, Quantum chemistry reference data from 33.5M DFT and 14.7B semi-empirical calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-025-04720-7</link>
      <description>Stefan Ganscha, Oliver T. Unke, Daniel Ahlin, Hartmut Maennel, Sergii Kashubin, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller, Scientific Data. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408246939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefan Ganscha, Oliver T. Unke, Daniel Ahlin, Hartmut Maennel, Sergii Kashubin, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-025-04720-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation to explore PdSnSe2-n/PdPSe (n = 0, 1, 2) heterostructures as advanced photocatalysts for water splitting applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162899</link>
      <description>Jia-Yi Lin, Chia&#8208;Ying Wu, Chen&#8208;Hao Yeh, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408248170

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia-Yi Lin, Chia&#8208;Ying Wu, Chen&#8208;Hao Yeh</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the catalytic performance of rare earth single atom catalysts for electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136591</link>
      <description>Yongmao Hu, Ruochen Zhu, Xinyuan Yang, Haoyu Wang, Chunyi Lv, Xiaolong Zhou, Yanan Yu, Riming Hu, Shengqiang Zhang, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408252177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongmao Hu, Ruochen Zhu, Xinyuan Yang, Haoyu Wang, Chunyi Lv, Xiaolong Zhou, Yanan Yu, Riming Hu, Shengqiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition tuning and heterostructure construction of Fe-doped Co-Ni hydroxide nanosheets for boosting oxygen electrocatalysis in rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161248</link>
      <description>Zihan Zhang, Zhicheng Zheng, Nattapol Ma, Emmanuel Picheau, Nobuyuki Sakai, Yoshiyuki Sugahara, Takayoshi Sasaki, Renzhi Ma, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408258101

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihan Zhang, Zhicheng Zheng, Nattapol Ma, Emmanuel Picheau, Nobuyuki Sakai, Yoshiyuki Sugahara, Takayoshi Sasaki, Renzhi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.161248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168152</link>
      <description>Gbolagade Olajide, Khagendra Baral, Sophia Ezendu, Ademola Soyemi, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408190752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gbolagade Olajide, Khagendra Baral, Sophia Ezendu, Ademola Soyemi, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5168152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operability for Process Flowsheet Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100229</link>
      <description>Ulysses Guilherme Ferreira, S&#233;rgio Mauro da Silva Neiro, Lu&#237;s Cl&#225;udio Oliveira-Lopes, Thiago V. Costa, Heleno Bispo, Fernando V. Lima, Digital Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408186083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ulysses Guilherme Ferreira, S&#233;rgio Mauro da Silva Neiro, Lu&#237;s Cl&#225;udio Oliveira-Lopes, Thiago V. Costa, Heleno Bispo, Fernando V. Lima</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dche.2025.100229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic Assessment of Ligand-Exchanging Catalytic Cycles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00348</link>
      <description>Orkhan Abdullayev, Diego Garay&#8208;Ruiz, Berta Bori-Bru, Carles B&#243;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408192594

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Orkhan Abdullayev, Diego Garay&#8208;Ruiz, Berta Bori-Bru, Carles B&#243;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inferring the cross-sectional area profile of an unseen solid in a draining tank from liquid level dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121488</link>
      <description>Gbenga Fabusola, Cory M. Simon, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408240913

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gbenga Fabusola, Cory M. Simon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121488</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
