<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 01:20:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Transformation of Copper-Coordinated COFs Drives Enhanced Multi-Carbon Selectivity in CO2 Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125131</link>
      <description>Jian Yu, Yang Zheng, Bo Lv, Aiming Huang, Junjun Zhang, Zizi Wang, Yifan Zhang, Yang Wu, Yanan Zhou, Yong Wang, Wen Luo, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407164905

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Yu, Yang Zheng, Bo Lv, Aiming Huang, Junjun Zhang, Zizi Wang, Yifan Zhang, Yang Wu, Yanan Zhou, Yong Wang, Wen Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A first-principles study into the development of a bifunctional, single-atom catalyst for nickel loading on melon carbon nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162640</link>
      <description>Xiao-Kuan Wu, Xinying Teng, Zhao Hong, Zhigang Lei, Jie Zhang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407165140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao-Kuan Wu, Xinying Teng, Zhao Hong, Zhigang Lei, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cathode materials and novel strategies for improving bioenergy production in microbial electrolysis cell: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115718</link>
      <description>Miaomiao Yang, Shuai Luo, Rongfang Yuan, Rongrong Hou, Beihai Zhou, Huilun Chen, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407171832

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miaomiao Yang, Shuai Luo, Rongfang Yuan, Rongrong Hou, Beihai Zhou, Huilun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microkinetic Modelling of Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Ir(111)@N&#8208;Graphene Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400907</link>
      <description>Adyasa Priyadarsini, Bhabani S. Mallik, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407172985

                Abstract We have explored the thermodynamics and microkinetic aspects of oxygen evolution catalysis on low loading of Ir(111) on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene at constant potential. The electronic modification induced by N&#8208;doping is the reason for the reduced overpotential of OER. The N&#8208;induced defect in the charge density is observed with increasing charge&#8208;depleted region around the Ir atoms. The lattice contraction shifts the d&#8208;band center away from the Fermi level, which increases the barrier for OH* and O* formation on Ir(111) supported on NGr (Ir(111)@NGr). Thus, highly endothermic O* formation reduces the OOH* formation, which is the potential determining step. For comparison, all electronic and binding energy calculations were also performed against Ir NP supported on Gr (Ir(111)@Gr). The stepwise potential&#8208;dependent activation barrier ( ) was obtained using the charge extrapolation method. The third step remains the RDS in all ranges of water oxidation potentials. The potential dependent is further applied to the Eyring rate equation to obtain the current density ( ) and correlation between and pH dependence, i. e., OH &#8722; concentration. The microkinetic progression leads to a Tafel slope value of 30 mV dec &#8722;1 at pH=14.0, requiring .</description>
      <author>Adyasa Priyadarsini, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Speeds Up the Discovery of Efficient Porphyrinoid Electrocatalysts for Ammonia Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12888</link>
      <description>Wenfeng Hu, Bingyi Song, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407178198

                Two&#8208;dimensional transition metal porphyrinoid materials (2DTMPoidMats), due to their unique electronic structure and tunable metal active sites, have the potential to enhance interactions with nitrogen molecules and promote the protonation process, making them promising electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR) electrocatalysts. Experimentally screening a large number of catalysts for eNRR catalytic performance would consume considerable time and economic resources. First&#8208;principles calculations and machine learning (ML) algorithms could greatly improve the efficiency of catalyst screening. Using this approach, we selected 86 candidates capable of catalyzing eNRR from 1290 types of 2DTMPoidMats, and verified the results with density functional theory (DFT) computations. Analysis of the full reaction pathway shows that MoPp&#8208;meso&#8208;F&#8208;&#946;&#8208;Py, MoPp&#8208;&#946;&#8208;Cl&#8208;meso&#8208;Diyne, MoPp&#8208;meso&#8208;Ethinyl, and WPp&#8208;&#946;&#8208;Pz exhibit the best catalytic performance with the onset potential of &#8722;0.22, &#8722;0.19, &#8722;0.23, and &#8722;0.35 V, respectively. This work provides valuable insights into efficient design and screening of eNRR catalysts and promotes the application of ML algorithmic models in the field of catalysis.</description>
      <author>Wenfeng Hu, Bingyi Song, Li&#8208;Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite Oxides for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen/Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400648</link>
      <description>Lu Lu, Mingzi Sun, Tong Wu, Qiuyang Lu, Baian Chen, Cheuk Hei Chan, Hon Ho Wong, Zikang Li, Bolong Huang, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407179736

                Abstract Since the excessive exploitation of fossil fuels will cause wars for oil, developing sustainable and eco&#8208;friendly energy resources to solve the energy crisis and realize the carbon&#8208;neutrality goal has been a hot issue. Water electrolysis has been acknowledged as a promising technology for hydrogen (H 2 )/oxygen (O 2 ) evolution reaction (HER/OER) since the overall water splitting reaction rates can be well controlled by applying appropriate electrode voltage. Whereas the sluggish electrochemical reactions kinetics on both the cathode and anode have greatly restricted the energy conversion efficiency. Thus, developing highly active electrocatalysts to reduce the overpotentials required for electrolytic HER/OER is of great significance in increasing the utilization rates of electrical power and lowering production costs. ABO 3 &#8208;structured perovskite&#8208;oxides based electrocatalysts possess the merits of low cost, high structural stability, and lattice compatibility, and thus they have attracted intense research attention in recent decays. To inspire both theoretical and experimental researchers to design novel perovskite&#8208;oxide electrocatalysts for efficient HER/OER, the fundamental electrode reaction mechanisms, the effects of synthetic methods on material morphologies, recently reported perovskite&#8208;oxide electrocatalysts and effective tuning strategies on enhancing the electrocatalytic activities of existing perovskite&#8208;oxides have been fully discussed in this review.</description>
      <author>Lu Lu, Mingzi Sun, Tong Wu, Qiuyang Lu, Baian Chen, Cheuk Hei Chan, Hon Ho Wong, Zikang Li, Bolong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced theoretical modeling methodologies for electrocatalyst design in sustainable energy conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235572</link>
      <description>Tianyi Wang, Qilong Wu, Yun Han, Zhongyuan Guo, Jun Chen, Chuangwei Liu, Applied Physics Reviews. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407191563

                Electrochemical reactions are pivotal for energy conversion and storage to achieve a carbon-neutral and sustainable society, and optimal electrocatalysts are essential for their industrial applications. Theoretical modeling methodologies, such as density functional theory (DFT) and molecular dynamics (MD), efficiently assess electrochemical reaction mechanisms and electrocatalyst performance at atomic and molecular levels. However, its intrinsic algorithm limitations and high computational costs for large-scale systems generate gaps between experimental observations and calculation simulation, restricting the accuracy and efficiency of electrocatalyst design. Combining machine learning (ML) is a promising strategy to accelerate the development of electrocatalysts. The ML-DFT frameworks establish accurate property&#8211;structure&#8211;performance relations to predict and verify novel electrocatalysts' properties and performance, providing a deep understanding of reaction mechanisms. The ML-based methods also accelerate the solution of MD and DFT. Moreover, integrating ML and experiment characterization techniques represents a cutting-edge approach to providing insights into the structural, electronic, and chemical changes under working conditions. This review will summarize the DFT development and the current ML application status for electrocatalyst design in various electrochemical energy conversions. The underlying physical fundaments, application advancements, and challenges will be summarized. Finally, future research directions and prospects will be proposed to guide novel electrocatalyst design for the sustainable energy revolution.</description>
      <author>Tianyi Wang, Qilong Wu, Yun Han, Zhongyuan Guo, Jun Chen, Chuangwei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0235572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additively Manufactured High Surface Area 3D Cathodes for Efficient and Productive Electro-Bio-Methanation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00109</link>
      <description>Buddhinie Srimali Jayathilake, Swetha Chandrasekaran, J&#246;rg S. Deutzmann, Frauke Kracke, C. Allin Cornell, Matthew A. Worthington, Megan C. Freyman, Melinda L. Jue, Alfred M. Spormann, Simon H. Pang, Sarah E. Baker, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407200148

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Buddhinie Srimali Jayathilake, Swetha Chandrasekaran, J&#246;rg S. Deutzmann, Frauke Kracke, C. Allin Cornell, Matthew A. Worthington, Megan C. Freyman, Melinda L. Jue, Alfred M. Spormann, Simon H. Pang, Sarah E. Baker</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anisotropic Janus monolayers BXY (X = P, as or Sb, Y = S, Se or Te) for photocatalytic water splitting: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solener.2025.113320</link>
      <description>Yanfu Zhao, Bofeng Zhang, Jiahe Lin, Solar Energy. 288(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407203428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanfu Zhao, Bofeng Zhang, Jiahe Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solener.2025.113320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-dimensional Pd@PtIrM ( M = Mn, Fe, Co, Ni) core&#8211;shell nanowires for efficient oxygen reduction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134581</link>
      <description>Hong Pan, Qian Liu, Jiabo Geng, Luo Sheng-quan, Xiaoxuan Ren, Faming Gao, Fuel. 389(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407203532

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Pan, Qian Liu, Jiabo Geng, Luo Sheng-quan, Xiaoxuan Ren, Faming Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134581</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand canonical view on electrochemical energetics at applied potential in a nutshell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101656</link>
      <description>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407204775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Sensitivity of N 1s Excitations in &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;-Methylacetamide Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03487</link>
      <description>Eemeli A. Eronen, Anton Vladyka, Christoph J. Sahle, Jyrki Niskanen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407206267

                Interpreting the X-ray spectra of liquids is complicated by their selective structural sensitivity and ensemble averaging. We report nitrogen K-edge spectra of liquid N-methylacetamide and its water solutions at temperatures of 305 and 350 K. The pre-peak in the spectrum shows a shift with an increase in the temperature or N-methylacetamide concentration. The effect is reproduced by our classical molecular dynamics simulations and subsequent spectrum calculations using density functional theory. We apply a data-driven method, emulator-based component analysis, to the computational data to identify the decisive structural degrees of freedom behind spectral variation. This representation in reduced dimensions accounts for the involved loss of structural information and reveals that the effect is indicative of weakening of the hydrogen bonds.</description>
      <author>Eemeli A. Eronen, Anton Vladyka, Christoph J. Sahle, Jyrki Niskanen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Thiocarbonate Cocatalyst Promoting ZnIn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution via Built-In Electric Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04874</link>
      <description>Bo Yan, Haoran Shi, Haiyuan Li, Dingxin Liu, Guowei Yang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407220335

                Cocatalysts play an important role in the field of photocatalysis by providing active sites and reducing reaction barriers to increase the reaction rates. However, efficient cocatalysts usually contain expensive noble metals, such as platinum. It is thus of great significance for practical applications in developing low-cost cocatalysts in photocatalysis. In this contribution, we reported a new cocatalyst nickel thiocarbonate (NiCS3) of ZnIn2S4 photocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). It was found that the hydrogen production rate of the NiCS3/ZnIn2S4 composite can reach 15.4 mmol&#183;h-1&#183;g-1 under visible light when NiCS3 is composited with ZnIn2S4, which is more than three times that of the HER performance of ZnIn2S4 alone. The theoretical calculations suggested that the improvement of HER performance is rooted in the built-in electric fields in the NiCS3/ZnIn2S4 composite. The abundant Ni active sites in the NiCS3/ZnIn2S4 composite not only promote the separation and migration of photoinduced carriers but also allow a suitable Gibbs free energy of adsorbed H* (&#916;GH*). This study indicated that NiCS3 has great potential to replace noble metals as a promising cocatalyst of ZnIn2S4 for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Bo Yan, Haoran Shi, Haiyuan Li, Dingxin Liu, Guowei Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Photocatalytic Reduction Pathways of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by Catalyst PbBiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Br Using In-Situ Raman Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06401</link>
      <description>Kang-Yu Hsiao, Fuyu Liu, Chiing&#8208;Chang Chen, I&#8208;Chia Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407224837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kang-Yu Hsiao, Fuyu Liu, Chiing&#8208;Chang Chen, I&#8208;Chia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in CO2 Reduction on Bulk and Two-Dimensional Electrocatalysts: From First Principles to Experimental Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101668</link>
      <description>Raghavan Rajagopalan, S Chaturvedi, Neeru Chaudhary, Abhijit Gogoi, Tej S. Choksi, Ananth Govind Rajan, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407229595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Raghavan Rajagopalan, S Chaturvedi, Neeru Chaudhary, Abhijit Gogoi, Tej S. Choksi, Ananth Govind Rajan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Surface Reconstruction and Transformation of 3d Transition&#8208;Metal (oxy)Hydroxides and Spinel&#8208;Type Oxides during the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411479</link>
      <description>Biao He, Fan Bai, Priya Jain, Tong Li, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407233790

                Abstract Developing efficient and sustainable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for advancing energy conversion and storage technologies. 3d transition&#8208;metal (oxy)hydroxides and spinel&#8208;type oxides have emerged as promising candidates due to their structural flexibility, oxygen redox activity, and abundance in earth's crust. However, their OER performance can be changed dynamically during the reaction due to surface reconstruction and transformation. Essentially, multiple elementary processes occur simultaneously, whereby the electrocatalyst surfaces undergo substantial changes during OER. A better understanding of these elementary processes and how they affect the electrocatalytic performance is essential for the OER electrocatalyst design. This review aims to critically assess these processes, including oxidation, surface amorphization, transformation, cation dissolution, redeposition, and facet and electrolyte effects on the OER performance. The review begins with an overview of the electrocatalysts&#8217; structure, redox couples, and common issues associated with electrochemical measurements of 3d transition&#8208;metal (oxy)hydroxides and spinels, followed by recent advancements in understanding the elementary processes involved in OER. The challenges and new perspectives are presented at last, potentially shedding light on advancing the rational design of next&#8208;generation OER electrocatalysts for sustainable energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Biao He, Fan Bai, Priya Jain, Tong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving the Coverage Dependence of Surface Reaction Kinetics with Machine Learning and Automated Quantum Chemistry Workflows</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06636</link>
      <description>Matthew S. Johnson, David H. Bross, Judit Z&#225;dor, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407238622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matthew S. Johnson, David H. Bross, Judit Z&#225;dor</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed bimetallic single-atom Cu, Fe/NC as pH-universal ORR electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160400</link>
      <description>Weiming Gong, Peng Guo, Lan Zhang, Rao Fu, Minglei Yan, Chun Yi Wu, Mengmeng Sun, Gehong Su, Yanying Wang, Jianshan Ye, Hanbing Rao, Zhiwei Lu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407242211

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiming Gong, Peng Guo, Lan Zhang, Rao Fu, Minglei Yan, Chun Yi Wu, Mengmeng Sun, Gehong Su, Yanying Wang, Jianshan Ye, Hanbing Rao, Zhiwei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating the Basal Plane of 2D Transition Metal Dichalcogenides via High-Entropy Alloying</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13863</link>
      <description>Mohammad Amin Akhound, Karsten W. Jacobsen, Kristian S. Thygesen, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407243054

                Two-dimensional materials, such as transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDCs) in the 2H or 1T crystal phases, are promising (electro)catalyst candidates due to their high surface-to-volume ratio and composition of low-cost, abundant elements. While the edges of elemental TMDC nanoparticles, such as MoS2, can show significant catalytic activity, the basal plane of the pristine materials is notoriously inert, which limits their normalized activity. Here, we show that high densities of catalytically active sites can be formed on the TMDC basal plane by alloying elements that prefer the 2H (1T) phase into a 1T (2H) structure. The global stability of the alloy, in particular, whether it crystallizes in the 2H or 1T phase, can be controlled by ensuring a majority of elements prefer the target phase. We further show that the mixing entropy plays a decisive role in stabilizing the alloy, implying that high-entropy alloying becomes essential. Our calculations point to a number of interesting nonprecious hydrogen evolution catalysts, including (CrTaVHfZr)S2 and (CrNbVTiZr)S2 in the 1T-phase and (MoNbTaVTi)S2 in the 2H-phase. Our work opens new directions for designing catalytic sites via high-entropy alloy stabilization of locally unstable structures.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Amin Akhound, Karsten W. Jacobsen, Kristian S. Thygesen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the energy landscape of aluminas through machine learning interatomic potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.023801</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, W. D. Luo, Renxi Liu, Mohan Chen, Zhongbo Yan, Kun Cao, Physical Review Materials. 9(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407252667

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, W. D. Luo, Renxi Liu, Mohan Chen, Zhongbo Yan, Kun Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.023801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo2N nanoclusters and FeMo dual atomic active sites confined in N-doped hollow carbon nanocages for synergistic improvement in oxygen reduction and Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160442</link>
      <description>Chenyang Wang, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407284110

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenyang Wang, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.160442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Catalytic Performance of Oxygen-Coordinated Single-Atom Catalysts for Nitric Oxide Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07612</link>
      <description>Shiya Zhu, Yu Zhang, Wenbin Liu, Deshuai Yang, Guobing Zhou, Zhen Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407292269

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiya Zhu, Yu Zhang, Wenbin Liu, Deshuai Yang, Guobing Zhou, Zhen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Weak-Binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C Single-Atom Catalysts Possess Anomalously High Oxygen Reduction Activity?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16733</link>
      <description>Di Zhang, Fangxin She, Jiaxiang Chen, Li Wei, Hao Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407293609

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) with metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) structures are widely recognized as promising candidates in oxygen reduction reactions (ORR). According to the classical Sabatier principle, optimal 3d metal catalysts, such as Fe/Co&#8211;N&#8211;C, achieve superior catalytic performance due to the moderate binding strength. However, the substantial ORR activity demonstrated by weakly binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts such as Ni/Cu&#8211;N&#8211;C challenges current understandings, emphasizing the need to explore new underlying mechanisms. In this work, we integrated a pH-field coupled microkinetic model with detailed experimental electron state analyses to verify a novel key step in the ORR reaction pathway of weak-binding SACs&#9472;the oxygen adsorption at the metal&#8211;nitrogen bridge site. This step significantly altered the adsorption scaling relations, electric field responses, and solvation effects, further impacting the key kinetic reaction barrier from HOO* to O* and pH-dependent performance. Synchrotron spectra analysis further provides evidence for the new weak-binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C model, showing an increase in electron density on the antibonding &#960; orbitals of N atoms in weak-binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts and confirming the presence of N&#8211;O bonds. These findings redefine the understanding of weak-binding M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalyst behavior, opening up new perspectives for their application in clean energy.</description>
      <author>Di Zhang, Fangxin She, Jiaxiang Chen, Li Wei, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c16733</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Heterojunction Construction and Interaction Mechanism of Ru1-LaOx-NiMnOx Nanocomposite for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.179115</link>
      <description>Qianzuo Liu, Yunping Ma, Nan Ma, Yingyi Wang, Sifan Sun, Binqi He, Ting Zhang, Xuehua Yan, Tie Li, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407302411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianzuo Liu, Yunping Ma, Nan Ma, Yingyi Wang, Sifan Sun, Binqi He, Ting Zhang, Xuehua Yan, Tie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.179115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of direct ammonia solid oxide fuel cells: Low temperature cell structure and ammonia decomposition strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115350</link>
      <description>Yuchen Ya, Ying Xu, Ahmed Mohammed Elbanna, Yimin Liu, Boyu Sun, Xiaobei Cheng, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 213(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407308347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuchen Ya, Ying Xu, Ahmed Mohammed Elbanna, Yimin Liu, Boyu Sun, Xiaobei Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet Engineering of Weyl Semimetals for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100091</link>
      <description>Ting Wai Lau, Qiong Lei, Jun Yin, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407309182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Wai Lau, Qiong Lei, Jun Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Numerical Energy Hessians with Graph Neural Network Potentials and Their Application in Heterogeneous Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07477</link>
      <description>Brook Wander, Joseph Musielewicz, Raffaele Cheula, John R. Kitchin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407310889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brook Wander, Joseph Musielewicz, Raffaele Cheula, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crash testing machine learning force fields for molecules, materials, and interfaces: model analysis in the TEA Challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06529h</link>
      <description>Igor Poltavsky, Anton Charkin-Gorbulin, Mirela Puleva, Gr&#233;gory Fonseca, Ilyes Batatia, Nicholas J. Browning, Stefan Chmiela, Mengnan Cui, J. Thorben Frank, Stefan Heinen, Bing Huang, Silvan K&#228;ser, Adil Kabylda, Danish Khan, Carolin M&#252;ller, Alastair J. A. Price, Kai Riedmiller, Kai T&#246;pfer, Tsz Wai Ko, Markus Meuwly, Matthias Rupp, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Johannes T. Margraf, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407320154

                Assessing the performance of modern machine learning force fields across diverse chemical systems to identify their strengths and limitations within the TEA Challenge 2023.</description>
      <author>Igor Poltavsky, Anton Charkin-Gorbulin, Mirela Puleva, Gr&#233;gory Fonseca, Ilyes Batatia, Nicholas J. Browning, Stefan Chmiela, Mengnan Cui, J. Thorben Frank, Stefan Heinen, Bing Huang, Silvan K&#228;ser, Adil Kabylda, Danish Khan, Carolin M&#252;ller, Alastair J. A. Price, Kai Riedmiller, Kai T&#246;pfer, Tsz Wai Ko, Markus Meuwly, Matthias Rupp, G&#225;bor C&#347;anyi, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Johannes T. Margraf, Klaus&#8208;Robert Mueller, Alexandre Tkatchenko</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06529h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical prediction of disulfide defects (S22&#8722;) in molybdenum disulfide monolayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06306-x</link>
      <description>Maxim R. Ryzhikov, S. G. Kozlova, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 31(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407340873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maxim R. Ryzhikov, S. G. Kozlova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-025-06306-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Surface Reconstruction and Metal Dissolution on Ru&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ti&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Acidic Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08119</link>
      <description>Francisco Ospina&#8208;Acevedo, Jos&#233; Fernando God&#237;nez-Salom&#243;n, Zachary G. Naymik, Kevin C. Matthews, Jamie H. Warner, Christopher P. Rhodes, Perla B. Balbuena, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407340979

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Francisco Ospina&#8208;Acevedo, Jos&#233; Fernando God&#237;nez-Salom&#243;n, Zachary G. Naymik, Kevin C. Matthews, Jamie H. Warner, Christopher P. Rhodes, Perla B. Balbuena</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-layer group III-IV-VI semiconductors: potential photocatalysts for water splitting with high carrier mobilities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08157a</link>
      <description>Qiu Yang, Qi-Dong Hao, Cui-E Hu, Hua-Yun Geng, Xiang-Rong Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407341215

                Strong optical absorption, high carrier mobility, and potential photocatalytic water splitting properties of MSiX (M = Ga, In; X = S, Se, Te) monolayers.</description>
      <author>Qiu Yang, Qi-Dong Hao, Cui-E Hu, Hua-Yun Geng, Xiang-Rong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08157a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Scanning Microwave Microscopy Reveals Ion Intercalation Dynamics and Maps Active Sites in 2D Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500043</link>
      <description>Mohamed Awadein, Abhishek Kumar, Yuqing Wang, Mingdong Dong, Stefan M&#252;llegger, Georg Gramse, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4407348632

                The accelerated demand for electrochemical energy storage urges the need for new, sustainable, and lightweight materials able to store high energy densities rapidly and efficiently. Development of these functional materials requires specialized techniques that can provide a close insight into the electrochemical properties at the nanoscale. For this reason, the electrochemical scanning microwave microscopy (EC-SMM) enabling local measurement of electrochemical properties with nanometer spatial resolution and sensitivity down to atto-Ampere electrochemical currents is introduced. Its power is demonstrated by studying NiCo-layered double hydroxide flakes, revealing active site locations and providing atomistic insights into the catalytic process. EC-SMM's spatial resolution of 16 &#177; 1 nm allows detailed analysis of edge effects in this 2D material, including localized electrochemical impedance spectroscopy and cyclic voltammetry. Coupled with advanced numerical modeling of diffusion and migration dynamics at the material interface, the findings elucidate the previously hypothesized processes responsible for localized enhancements in electrochemical activity, while pinpointing essential parameters for tuning the thermodynamics of ion intercalation and optimizing surface adsorption.</description>
      <author>Mohamed Awadein, Abhishek Kumar, Yuqing Wang, Mingdong Dong, Stefan M&#252;llegger, Georg Gramse</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202500043</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
