<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 01:12:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Single-, Double-, and Triple-atom Catalysts on PC6 for Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia: A Computational Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144915</link>
      <description>Jinrui Huang, Shixiang Hu, Mengran Liu, Zhichao Ma, Tianfang Yang, Yingjie Yang, Yang Liu, Shuyan Gao, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401599093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinrui Huang, Shixiang Hu, Mengran Liu, Zhichao Ma, Tianfang Yang, Yingjie Yang, Yang Liu, Shuyan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy-efficient CO(2) conversion to multicarbon products at high rates on CuGa bimetallic catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51466-8</link>
      <description>Lei Chen, Junmei Chen, Wei&#8208;Wei Fu, Jiayi Chen, Di Wang, Yukun Xiao, Shibo Xi, Yongfei Ji, Lei Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401605999

                Electrocatalytic CO</description>
      <author>Lei Chen, Junmei Chen, Wei&#8208;Wei Fu, Jiayi Chen, Di Wang, Yukun Xiao, Shibo Xi, Yongfei Ji, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51466-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand canonically optimized grain boundary phases in hexagonal close-packed titanium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51330-9</link>
      <description>Enze Chen, Tae Wook Heo, Brandon C. Wood, Mark Asta, Timofey Frolov, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401606990

                Abstract Grain boundaries (GBs) profoundly influence the properties and performance of materials, emphasizing the importance of understanding the GB structure and phase behavior. As recent computational studies have demonstrated the existence of multiple GB phases associated with varying the atomic density at the interface, we introduce a validated, open-source GRand canonical Interface Predictor (GRIP) tool that automates high-throughput, grand canonical optimization of GB structures. While previous studies of GB phases have almost exclusively focused on cubic systems, we demonstrate the utility of GRIP in an application to hexagonal close-packed titanium. We perform a systematic high-throughput exploration of tilt GBs in titanium and discover previously unreported structures and phase transitions. In low-angle boundaries, we demonstrate a coupling between point defect absorption and the change in the GB dislocation network topology due to GB phase transformations, which has important implications for the accommodation of radiation-induced defects.</description>
      <author>Enze Chen, Tae Wook Heo, Brandon C. Wood, Mark Asta, Timofey Frolov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51330-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonlocal machine-learned exchange functional for molecules and solids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.075130</link>
      <description>Kyle Bystrom, Boris Kozinsky, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401612695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kyle Bystrom, Boris Kozinsky</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.075130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mamonca: magnetic Monte Carlo code</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.06194</link>
      <description>Osamu Waseda, Tilmann Hickel, J&#246;rg Neugebauer, The Journal of Open Source Software. 9(100)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401613037

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Osamu Waseda, Tilmann Hickel, J&#246;rg Neugebauer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.06194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Lattice Nitrogen Coordination to Break the Performance Limitation of Metal Nitrides for Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00377</link>
      <description>Haiyang Yuan, Chen Zhu, Yu Hou, Hua Gui Yang, Haifeng Wang, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401627407

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haiyang Yuan, Chen Zhu, Yu Hou, Hua Gui Yang, Haifeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of transition metals (Ni and Co) in the methanol oxidation reaction electrocatalytic activity on Mo2C/MWCNT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114455</link>
      <description>Liping Mao, Lin Fu, Xinyu Zhang, Zhifeng Yan, Zhihua Gao, Lei Zhu, Wei Huang, Zhijun Zuo, Molecular Catalysis. 567(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401633928

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liping Mao, Lin Fu, Xinyu Zhang, Zhifeng Yan, Zhihua Gao, Lei Zhu, Wei Huang, Zhijun Zuo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114455</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Efficient Ru@NiMoCu Porous Electrode for High Current Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303623</link>
      <description>Songhu Bi, Zhen Geng, Luyu Yang, Linyi Zhao, Chenxu Qu, Zijian Gao, Liming Jin, Mingzhe Xue, Cunman Zhang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401654459

                Abstract Alkaline water electrolysis is the promising technical pathway of large&#8208;scale green hydrogen production. However, its hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is hindered by the alkaline environment, leading to slow H 2 O splitting kinetics, especially for NiMoCu alloy catalysts which are considered potential alkaline HER catalysts. In this work, the Ru&#8208;substrate modified NiMoCu 20 porous electrode is designed by a continuous multistep electrodeposition method. It shows the good alkaline HER performance at the high current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is attributed to the synergistic charge&#8208;reconfiguration effects between Ru&#8208;substrate and NiMoCu alloy by density functional theory (DFT) calculations and in situ Raman spectra analysis. It indicates that the Ru&#8208;substrate is capable of encouraging H&#8208;OH* bond breakage and optimizing transition&#8208;state H* adsorption. Further, the overall water electrolysis results of the alkaline water electrolysis cell (30 wt% KOH) at 70 &#176;C show that it has good performance at the large current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 with 2.05 V and good stability at 600 mA cm &#8722;2 up to 500 h. It provides the possibility of designing the high&#8208;performance HER electrode from the view of industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Songhu Bi, Zhen Geng, Luyu Yang, Linyi Zhao, Chenxu Qu, Zijian Gao, Liming Jin, Mingzhe Xue, Cunman Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New global minimum conformers for the Pt$$_{19}$$ and Pt$$_{20}$$ clusters: low symmetric species featuring different active sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-024-06099-5</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Manuel Guevara&#8208;Vela, Miguel Gallegos, Tom&#225;s Rocha&#8208;Rinza, &#193;lvaro Mu&#241;oz-Castro, P. Ke&#223;ler, &#193;ngel Mart&#237;n Pend&#225;s, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 30(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401664223

                Abstract Context The study of platinum (Pt) clusters and nanoparticles is essential due to their extensive range of potential technological applications, particularly in catalysis. The electronic properties that yield optimal catalytic performance at the nanoscale are significantly influenced by the size and structure of Pt clusters. This research aimed to identify the lowest-energy conformers for Pt $$_{18}$$    18    , Pt $$_{19}$$    19    , and Pt $$_{20}$$    20    species using Density Functional Theory (DFT). We discovered new low-symmetry conformers for Pt $$_{19}$$    19    and Pt $$_{20}$$    20    , which are 3.0 and 1.0 kcal/mol more stable, respectively, than previously reported structures. Our study highlights the importance of using density functional approximations that incorporate moderate levels of exact Hartree-Fock exchange, alongside basis sets of at least quadruple-zeta quality. The resulting structures are asymmetric with varying active sites, as evidenced by sigma hole analysis on the electrostatic potential surface. This suggests a potential correlation between electronic structure and catalytic properties, warranting further investigation. Methods An equivariant graph neural network interatomic potential (NequIP) within the Atomic Simulation Environment suite (ASE) was used to provide initial geometries of the aggregates under study. DFT calculations were performed with the ORCA 5 package, using functional approximations that included Generalized Gradient Approximation (PBE), meta-GGA (TPSS, M06-L), hybrid (PBE0, PBEh), meta-GGA hybrid (TPSSh), and range-separated hybrid ( $$\omega $$  &#969;  B97x) functionals. Def2-TZVP and Def2-QZVP as well as members of the cc-pwCVXZ-PP family to check basis set convergence were used. QTAIM calculations were performed using the AIMAll suite. Structures were visualized with the AVOGADRO code.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Manuel Guevara&#8208;Vela, Miguel Gallegos, Tom&#225;s Rocha&#8208;Rinza, &#193;lvaro Mu&#241;oz-Castro, P. Ke&#223;ler, &#193;ngel Mart&#237;n Pend&#225;s</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-024-06099-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janus NbOBrI monolayer for efficient photocatalytic overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104980</link>
      <description>Xue Deng, Tie Zhou, Xiao Long, Jing Xie, Bing Lv, Yangfang Liao, Wenzhong Wang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401675459

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Deng, Tie Zhou, Xiao Long, Jing Xie, Bing Lv, Yangfang Liao, Wenzhong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for High-Throughput Configuration Sampling of Li&#8722;La&#8722;Ti&#8722;O Disordered Solid-State Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01221</link>
      <description>Mohamad Ataya, Eric McCalla, Rustam Z. Khaliullin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401684476

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohamad Ataya, Eric McCalla, Rustam Z. Khaliullin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects of the Electric Field Induced by Imidazolium Rotation and Hydrogen Bonding in Electrocatalysis of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05172</link>
      <description>Oguz Kagan Coskun, Zeynep Bagbudar, Vaishali Khokhar, Saudagar Dongare, Robert E. Warburton, Burcu Gurkan, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401618125

                The roles of the ionic liquid (IL), 1-ethyl-3-methylimidazolium tetrafluoroborate ([EMIM][BF4]), and water in controlling the mechanism, energetics, and electrocatalytic activity of CO2 reduction to CO on silver in nonaqueous electrolytes were investigated. The first electron transfer occurs to CO2 at reduced overpotentials when it is trapped between the planes of the [EMIM]+ ring and the electrode surface due to cation reorientation as determined from voltammetry, in situ surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy, and density functional theory calculations. Within this interface, water up to 0.5 M does not induce significant Faradaic activity, opposing the notion of it being a free proton source. Instead, water acts as a hydrogen bond donor, and the proton is sourced from [EMIM]+. Furthermore, this study demonstrates that alcohols with varying acidities tune the hydrogen bonding network in the interfacial microenvironment to lower the energetics required for CO2 reduction. The hydrogen bonding suppresses the formation of inactive carboxylate species, thus preserving the catalytic activity of [EMIM]+. The ability to tune the hydrogen bonding network opens new avenues for advancing IL-mediated electrocatalytic reactions in nonaqueous electrolytes.</description>
      <author>Oguz Kagan Coskun, Zeynep Bagbudar, Vaishali Khokhar, Saudagar Dongare, Robert E. Warburton, Burcu Gurkan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small basis set density functional theory method for cost-efficient, large-scale condensed matter simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0222649</link>
      <description>E. Keller, Jack Morgenstein, Karsten Reuter, Johannes T. Margraf, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401626986

                We present an efficient first-principles based method geared toward reliably predicting the structures of solid materials across the Periodic Table. To this end, we use a density functional theory baseline with a compact, near-minimal min+s basis set, yielding low computational costs and memory demands. Since the use of such a small basis set leads to systematic errors in chemical bond lengths, we develop a linear pairwise correction, available for elements Z = 1&#8211;86 (excluding the lanthanide series), parameterized for use with the Perdew&#8211;Burke&#8211;Ernzerhof exchange&#8211;correlation functional. We demonstrate the reliability of this corrected approach for equilibrium volumes across the Periodic Table and the transferability to differently coordinated environments and multi-elemental crystals. We examine relative energies, forces, and stresses in geometry optimizations and molecular dynamics simulations.</description>
      <author>E. Keller, Jack Morgenstein, Karsten Reuter, Johannes T. Margraf</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0222649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flat-Bottom Elastic Network Model for Generating Improved Plausible Reaction Paths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00792</link>
      <description>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401628311

                Rapid generation of a plausible reaction path connecting a given reactant and product in advance is crucial for the efficient computation of precise reaction paths or transition states. We propose a computationally efficient potential energy based on the molecular structure to generate such paths. This potential energy has a flat bottom consisting of structures without atomic collisions while preserving nonreactive chemical bonds, bond angles, and partial planar structures. By combining this potential energy with the direct MaxFlux method, a recently developed reaction-path/transition-state search method, we can find the shortest plausible path passing within the bottom. Numerical results show that this combination yields lower energy paths compared to the paths obtained by the well-known image-dependent pair potential. We also theoretically investigate the differences between these two potential energies. The proposed potential energy and path generation routine are implemented in our Python version of the direct MaxFlux method, available on GitHub.</description>
      <author>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Machine Learned Force Fields for Complex Fluids through Enhanced Sampling: A Liquid Crystal Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c01546</link>
      <description>Yezhi Jin, Gustavo R. P&#233;rez-Lemus, Pablo F. Zubieta Rico, Juan Pablo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401628476

                Machine learned force fields offer the potential for faster execution times while retaining the accuracy of traditional DFT calculations, making them promising candidates for molecular simulations in cases where reliable classical force fields are not available. Some of the challenges associated with machine learned force fields include simulation stability over extended periods of time and ensuring that the statistical and dynamical properties of the underlying simulated systems are correctly captured. In this work, we propose a systematic training pipeline for such force fields that leads to improved model quality, compared to that achieved by traditional data generation and training approaches. That pipeline relies on the use of enhanced sampling techniques, and it is demonstrated here in the context of a liquid crystal, which exemplifies many of the challenges that are encountered in fluids and materials with complex free energy landscapes. Our results indicate that, whereas the majority of traditional machine learned force field training approaches lead to molecular dynamics simulations that are only stable over hundred-picosecond trajectories, our approach allows for stable simulations over tens of nanoseconds for organic molecular systems comprising thousands of atoms.</description>
      <author>Yezhi Jin, Gustavo R. P&#233;rez-Lemus, Pablo F. Zubieta Rico, Juan Pablo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c01546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning&#8208;Based Assessment and Optimization of Electrode Materials for Supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527838851.ch25</link>
      <description>Srikanta Moharana, Bibhuti B. Sahu, Jayakishan Meher, Rozalin Nayak, Srikanta Moharana, Karthik Dhandapani, Kalim Deshmukh, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401631133

                In the past few years, supercapacitors (SCs) have received remarkable attention in the field of energy conversion and storage systems in sustainable nanotechnologies because of their unique properties such as better cycling life, low processing cost, and excellent specific power than that of batteries. The carbon material, metal oxide, and conductive polymers are three electrode materials that have been utilized for processing the SCs owing to their superior electrochemical performances. However, machine learning (ML) techniques have placed great significance on quickly developing applications in a number of domains, including physics, chemistry, and material science, where vast amounts of data are available, to estimate the capacitance of electrode materials for SCs. In order to discover and tailor the energy storage material for electrochemical performance, ML plays an imperative role and also optimizes the properties of electrode materials in terms of high specific capacitance for SC applications. This chapter is intended to portray the contemporary technological applications, fundamental key concepts, and prospective domain of ML, in order to predict the electrode materials for design, development, and applications of SCs. Also, it will provide a platform for in-depth insight into ML to study the relationship between various parameters of electrode materials linked to SC performance, such as charge&#8211;discharge cycle, power, energy density, and specific surface area.</description>
      <author>Srikanta Moharana, Bibhuti B. Sahu, Jayakishan Meher, Rozalin Nayak, Srikanta Moharana, Karthik Dhandapani, Kalim Deshmukh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527838851.ch25</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Upcycling of Polyolefins</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00943</link>
      <description>Jia&#8208;Kai Sun, Jinhu Dong, Lijun Gao, Yu&#8208;Quan Zhao, Hyunjin Moon, Susannah L. Scott, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401631518

                The large production volumes of commodity polyolefins (specifically, polyethylene, polypropylene, polystyrene, and poly(vinyl chloride)), in conjunction with their low unit values and multitude of short-term uses, have resulted in a significant and pressing waste management challenge. Only a small fraction of these polyolefins is currently mechanically recycled, with the rest being incinerated, accumulating in landfills, or leaking into the natural environment. Since polyolefins are energy-rich materials, there is considerable interest in recouping some of their chemical value while simultaneously motivating more responsible end-of-life management. An emerging strategy is catalytic depolymerization, in which a portion of the C-C bonds in the polyolefin backbone is broken with the assistance of a catalyst and, in some cases, additional small molecule reagents. When the products are small molecules or materials with higher value in their own right, or as chemical feedstocks, the process is called upcycling. This review summarizes recent progress for four major catalytic upcycling strategies: hydrogenolysis, (hydro)cracking, tandem processes involving metathesis, and selective oxidation. Key considerations include macromolecular reaction mechanisms relative to small molecule mechanisms, catalyst design for macromolecular transformations, and the effect of process conditions on product selectivity. Metrics for describing polyolefin upcycling are critically evaluated, and an outlook for future advances is described.</description>
      <author>Jia&#8208;Kai Sun, Jinhu Dong, Lijun Gao, Yu&#8208;Quan Zhao, Hyunjin Moon, Susannah L. Scott</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00943</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Effect of Dopants in Zirconia-Based Catalysts for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03206</link>
      <description>Raffaele Cheula, Tuan Anh Tran, Mie Andersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401631981

                The doping of zirconia to enhance its activity and selectivity for the hydrogenation of CO2 to methanol has been studied intensively in experiments, but a thorough theoretical understanding of the factors that decide whether a dopant has a positive or negative influence on the reactivity is lacking. In this work, we conduct a mechanistic investigation using density functional theory and microkinetic modeling, considering the ZrO2(101) surface doped with 16 different metals. This analysis elucidates the following two criteria for enhanced reactivity. One, the ability of the surface to facilitate the dissociation of H2 and provide the H* species necessary for the catalytic reaction is deemed a necessary but not sufficient criterion. Two, dopants that are thermodynamically stable under reaction conditions in a 2+ or 3+ oxidation state are beneficial, since this entails the introduction of O vacancies, which stabilize O-containing reaction intermediates such as formate and lower key transition states. We construct linear scaling relations that can reliably predict transition state energies in terms of less computationally costly adsorption energies. It is revealed that dopants that are stable in the 4+ state (e.g., Ti), and thereby lack O vacancies, follow a different scaling relation with a higher intercept for formate formation, which can explain their reduced reactivity. Overall, our microkinetic models can successfully predict the trends for dopants that have been found active in experiments (Zn2+, Cd2+, Ga3+, In3+) and not. Together with the established reactivity criteria, this paves the way for computational screening of oxides for the important CO2-to-methanol process.</description>
      <author>Raffaele Cheula, Tuan Anh Tran, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Properties of Ni&lt;sub&gt;1+&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;A&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;N (A = Mo, W): The Effect of Mo and W in the Oxygen Evolution and Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/nano.202400051</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Antonio Coca Clemente, Isabel Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, P. Oc&#243;n, M. Retuerto, Sergio Rojas, Nano Select. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401638572

                ABSTRACT Ni, Fe&#8208;based nitrides have been widely studied for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, displaying electrocatalytic activities similar to Pt and other noble metal electrocatalysts. The incorporation of small amounts of Mo or W on these Ni, Fe&#8208;based nitrides is expected to have a significant effect on the electrocatalytic performance of these materials, especially for the HER activity. In this work, transition metal nitrides (TMNs) with the empirical formula Ni 1+ x Fe 3&#8722; x &#8722; y A y N (A = Mo, W), were obtained in two steps: synthesis of the transition metal oxide precursors by an easy, one&#8208;pot sol&#8211;gel polymerization method followed by nitridation under ammonia atmosphere to obtain the final TMNs. Their HER and OER catalytic performances in alkaline electrolyte (0.1 M KOH solution) were studied and it was observed that the incorporation of small quantities of Mo or W in these Ni, Fe&#8208;based nitrides (Ni 1+ x Fe 3&#8722; x &#8722; y A y N, where y = 0.1) results in improved HER and OER activities, especially in the TMN that contains W (i.e., Ni 1+ x Fe 2.9&#8722; x W 0.1 N), where the overpotentials were 348 mV for OER and 269 mV for HER. These values are lower than those obtained for Ni 1+ x Fe 3&#8722; x N, which are 395 mV for OER and 368 mV for HER.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Antonio Coca Clemente, Isabel Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, P. Oc&#243;n, M. Retuerto, Sergio Rojas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/nano.202400051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Dispersed Cu Atoms Induce Alternating Surface Microstrain in PtCu Concave Octahedral Nanoparticles Accelerating Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02973</link>
      <description>Xiashuang Luo, Cehuang Fu, Shuiyun Shen, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang, Junliang Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401643081

                A comprehensive understanding of the intricate surface environments of practical nanocatalysts at the atomic level is essential for advancing our knowledge of catalytic mechanisms. In this study, we investigate PtCu octahedral nanoparticles with varying microstrains engineered by Cu dispersion. A detailed analysis of the atom configuration and corresponding microstrain is conducted. The intimate mixing of Cu and Pt results in increased randomness in atom displacement within the lattice and a more pronounced distribution of alternating microstrain on the surfaces. Specifically, we observe that the PtCu concave octahedral nanoparticles with alternating microstrain demonstrate a substantial oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity of 3.95 mA cm&#8211;2 in area-specific activity. The significant impact of shear microstrain is further underscored, as evidenced by an 86.9% decrease in the ORR activity upon the removal of the alternating shear microstrain. This study sheds light on the effects of microstrain toward the ORR and provides valuable insights into designing advanced Pt-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiashuang Luo, Cehuang Fu, Shuiyun Shen, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu-P@silica-CNT-based catalyst for effective electrolytic water splitting in an alkaline medium with hydrazine assistance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03998j</link>
      <description>Nezar H. Khdary, Asmaa R.M. El-Gohary, Ahmed Galal, Ahmed M. Alhassan, Sami D. Alzahrain, RSC Advances. 14(35)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647384

                In this study, we prepared a potential catalyst as an electrode modifier for electrolytic water splitting.</description>
      <author>Nezar H. Khdary, Asmaa R.M. El-Gohary, Ahmed Galal, Ahmed M. Alhassan, Sami D. Alzahrain</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03998j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing heterointerface of NiCoP&#8211;Co/MXene with regulated charge distribution via built-in electric field for efficient overall water-splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02950-z</link>
      <description>Yan Liang, Yonghang Chen, Juan Xie, Hao Li, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401660767

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Liang, Yonghang Chen, Juan Xie, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02950-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalyst for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR): towards an active and stable electrocatalyst for low-temperature PEM fuel cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05767-z</link>
      <description>K.P. Jithul, B. Tamilarasi, Jay Pandey, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401664259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K.P. Jithul, B. Tamilarasi, Jay Pandey</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05767-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning&#8208;Assisted Design of Nitrogen&#8208;Rich Covalent Triazine Frameworks Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413453</link>
      <description>Mingliang Wu, Zhilong Song, Yu Cui, Zhanzhao Fu, Kunquan Hong, Qiang Li, Zhiyang Lyu, Wei Wang, Jinlan Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401686058

                Abstract Covalent triazine frameworks (CTFs), noted for their rich nitrogen content, have attracted significant attention as promising photocatalysts. However, the structural complexity introduced by the diversity of nitrogen atoms in nitrogen&#8208;rich CTFs poses a substantial challenge in discovering high&#8208;performance CTFs. To address this challenge, a machine&#8208;learning approach is developed to rationally design nitrogen&#8208;rich CTFs, which is subsequently validated through experimental methods. A framework is employed based on the special orthogonal group in three dimensions (SO(3))&#8208;invariant graph neural networks to predict photocatalytic properties of CTFs structures. This approach achieves exceptionally high accuracies with R 2 scores exceeding 0.98. From a dataset of 14920 CTFs structures, this framework identifies 45 high&#8208;performance candidates. Guided by these predictions, a novel CTF structure, pyridine&#8208;2,5&#8208;dicarbaldehyde (CTF&#8208;DCPD) is selected and successfully synthesized, which exhibits an ultrahigh hydrogen evolution rate of 17.70 mmol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 . This rate significantly surpasses that of the widely studied CTF&#8208;1,4&#8208;dicyanobenzene (CTF&#8208;DCB, 10.41 mmol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 ). This work provides a new paradigm for machine learning to accelerate materials development, which can be generalized to the development of other functional materials.</description>
      <author>Mingliang Wu, Zhilong Song, Yu Cui, Zhanzhao Fu, Kunquan Hong, Qiang Li, Zhiyang Lyu, Wei Wang, Jinlan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413453</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structurally optimized rosette-like microspheres carbon with Fe-Ni single atom sites for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis in Zinc-Air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154963</link>
      <description>Chaoyang Liu, Shang Wu, Shuo Tian, Jincai Yang, Jiankun Li, Guan Quan, Fenping Yin, Xiang Xiao-ming, Yanbin Wang, Xiaoyi Meng, Quanlu Yang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401689594

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoyang Liu, Shang Wu, Shuo Tian, Jincai Yang, Jiankun Li, Guan Quan, Fenping Yin, Xiang Xiao-ming, Yanbin Wang, Xiaoyi Meng, Quanlu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton&#8208;Coupled Electron Transfer on Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O/Ti&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; MXene for Propane (C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;) Synthesis from Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202405154</link>
      <description>Jun Young Kim, Won Tae Hong, Thi Kim Cuong Phu, Seong Chan Cho, Byeongkyu Kim, Unbeom Baeck, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Jai Hyun Koh, Xu Yu, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jongwook Park, Sang Uck Lee, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Jung Kyu Kim, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401694444

                Electrochemical CO</description>
      <author>Jun Young Kim, Won Tae Hong, Thi Kim Cuong Phu, Seong Chan Cho, Byeongkyu Kim, Unbeom Baeck, Hyung&#8208;Suk Oh, Jai Hyun Koh, Xu Yu, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jongwook Park, Sang Uck Lee, Chan&#8208;Hwa Chung, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202405154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Negative Reaction Order for CO during CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction on Au</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c06232</link>
      <description>Zhihao Cui, Andrew Jark-Wah Wong, Michael J. Janik, Anne C. Co, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401695552

                The potential-dependent negative fractional reaction orders with respect to the CO partial pressures were measured for CO</description>
      <author>Zhihao Cui, Andrew Jark-Wah Wong, Michael J. Janik, Anne C. Co</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c06232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous Structure of Ni&#8211;Mo Nanoalloys Decorated on MoO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; for an Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Using Hydrogen Spillover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202403752</link>
      <description>DongHoon Song, JeongHan Roh, Jungwoo Choi, Hyein Lee, Gou Young Koh, YongKeun Kwon, Joohee Lee, Hyuck Mo Lee, MinJoong Kim, EunAe Cho, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401696400

                Herein, a heterogeneous structure of Ni-Mo catalyst comprising Ni</description>
      <author>DongHoon Song, JeongHan Roh, Jungwoo Choi, Hyein Lee, Gou Young Koh, YongKeun Kwon, Joohee Lee, Hyuck Mo Lee, MinJoong Kim, EunAe Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202403752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices of modeling complex materials in electrocatalysis, exemplified by oxygen evolution reaction on pentlandites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01792g</link>
      <description>Maksim Sokolov, Katharina Doblhoff-Dier, Kai S. Exner, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401697196

                Estimating the catalytic activity of a complex material in the oxygen evolution reaction is associated with several pitfalls, which are summarized in the present work.</description>
      <author>Maksim Sokolov, Katharina Doblhoff-Dier, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01792g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The promise of chiral electrocatalysis for efficient and sustainable energy conversion and storage: a comprehensive review of the CISS effect and future directions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00316g</link>
      <description>Kyunghee Chae, Nur Aqlili Riana Che Mohamad, J. A. Kim, Dong&#8208;Il Won, Zhiqun Lin, Jeongwon Kim, Dong Ha Kim, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401698107

                The integration of chirality, specifically through the chirality-induced spin selectivity (CISS) effect, into electrocatalytic processes represents a pioneering approach for enhancing the efficiency of energy conversion and storage systems.</description>
      <author>Kyunghee Chae, Nur Aqlili Riana Che Mohamad, J. A. Kim, Dong&#8208;Il Won, Zhiqun Lin, Jeongwon Kim, Dong Ha Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00316g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibrational study of CO, O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, and H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Adsorbed on the CoCrFeNi (110) High Entropy Alloy Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03938</link>
      <description>Frank McKay, Andrew N. Okafor, David P. Young, Ye Xu, Phillip Sprunger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401698811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Frank McKay, Andrew N. Okafor, David P. Young, Ye Xu, Phillip Sprunger</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03938</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms and selectivity of methanol oxidation on PtRuM&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/C-MWCNT (M = Fe and Co) electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04493b</link>
      <description>&#272;&#7863;ng Long Qu&#226;n, Soong&#8208;Hyuck Suh, Do Ngoc Son, RSC Advances. 14(36)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401705941

                Methanol oxidation efficiency and resistance to CO poisoning are the most challenging issues associated with direct methanol fuel cells. Much experimental effort has been undertaken, such as generating Pt-based binary and ternary nanoparticles, creating composite substrates, and fabricating nanoparticles with special shapes, to overcome these drawbacks. Our previous experiment showed that ternary PtRuM</description>
      <author>&#272;&#7863;ng Long Qu&#226;n, Soong&#8208;Hyuck Suh, Do Ngoc Son</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04493b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation on Enhanced HER Electrocatalytic Activities of SiC Monolayers through Nonmetal Doping and Strain Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00633j</link>
      <description>Bingwen Li, Hongrui Shi, Zeyun Ni, Haifeng Zheng, Kehao Chen, Yuting Yan, Huimin Qi, Yu Xue, Xinfang Wang, Liming Fan, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401717241

                Efficient hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalysts are crucial for renewable energy storage and conversion.</description>
      <author>Bingwen Li, Hongrui Shi, Zeyun Ni, Haifeng Zheng, Kehao Chen, Yuting Yan, Huimin Qi, Yu Xue, Xinfang Wang, Liming Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00633j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Study and Mitigation Methods of Bias in LLM-Based Robots</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/re9qp070</link>
      <description>Zhou Ren, Academic Journal of Science and Technology. 12(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401684575

                Our study provides a comprehensive analysis of biased behaviors exhibited by robots utilizing large language models (LLMs) in real-world applications, focusing on five experimental scenarios: customer service, education, healthcare, recruitment, and social interaction. The analysis reveals significant differences in user experiences based on race, health status, work experience, and social status. For instance, the average satisfaction score for white customers is 4.2, compared to 3.5 for black customers, and the response accuracy for white students is 92%, versus 85% for black students. To address these biases, we propose several mitigation methods, including data resampling, model regularization, post-processing techniques, diversity assessment, and user feedback mechanisms. These methods aim to enhance the fairness and inclusivity of robotic systems, promoting healthy human-robot interactions. By combining our quantitative data analysis with existing research, we affirm the importance of bias detection and mitigation, and propose various improvement strategies. Future research should further explore data balancing strategies, fairness-constrained models, real-time monitoring and adjustment mechanisms, and cross-domain studies to comprehensively evaluate and improve the performance of LLM-based robotic systems across various tasks.</description>
      <author>Zhou Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/re9qp070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Vanadium Redox Flow Process for Carbon Capture and Energy Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4770270/v1</link>
      <description>Mohammad Rahimi, Mohsen Afshari, Abdelrahman Refaie, Prince Aleta, Ahmad Hassan, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401652180

                Abstract Climate change mitigation by decreasing worldwide CO2 emissions is an urgent and demanding challenge that requires innovative technical solutions. This work, inspired by vanadium redox flow batteries (VRFB), introduces an integrated electrochemical process for carbon capture and energy storage. It utilizes established vanadium and ferricyanide redox couples for pH modulation for CO2 desorption and absorbent regeneration. The developed process consumes electricity during the daytime&#8212;when renewable electricity is available&#8212;to desorb CO2 and charge the cell, and it can regenerate the absorbent for further CO2 absorption while releasing electricity to the grid during nighttime when solar power is unavailable. This research explores the process fundamentals and scalability potential, through an extensive study of the system's thermodynamics, transport phenomena, kinetics, and bench-scale operations. Cyclic voltammetry (CV) was utilized to study the thermodynamics of the process, mapping the redox profiles to identify ideal potential windows for operation. The CV results pinpointed a 0.3 V Nernstian overpotential as the thermodynamic minimum required for cell operation. Additionally, polarization studies were conducted to select the practical operating potential, identifying 0.5 V as optimal for the CO2 desorption cycle to provide sufficient polarity to overcome activation barriers in addition to the Nernstian potential. Mass transfer analysis balanced conductivity and desorption efficiency, with a 1:1 ratio identified as optimal for redox-active species and background electrolyte concentration. To further enhance the kinetics of the redox reactions, plasma treatment of electrode surfaces was implemented, resulting in a 43% decrease in charge transfer resistance, as measured by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) analysis. Finally, a bench-scale operation of the system demonstrated an energy consumption of 54 kJ/mol CO2, which is competitive with other electrochemical carbon capture technologies. Besides its energy competitiveness, the process offers multiple additional advantages, including the elimination of precious metal electrodes, oxygen insensitivity in flue gas, scalability inspired by VRFB technology, and the unique ability to function as a battery during the absorbent regeneration process, enabling efficient day-night operation.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Rahimi, Mohsen Afshari, Abdelrahman Refaie, Prince Aleta, Ahmad Hassan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4770270/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fraud Detection in Credit Risk Assessment Using Supervised Learning Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/qw9j1892</link>
      <description>Tianyi Xu, No host. 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401667087

                Our study systematically evaluates the performance of various supervised learning algorithms in credit risk assessment and fraud detection, including Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Support Vector Machine, Random Forest, Gradient Boosting Tree, and Neural Network. The results show that in credit risk assessment, the Gradient Boosting Tree performed best with an accuracy of 90.5% and a ROC-AUC of 0.84, followed by Random Forest and Neural Network, with accuracies of 89.2% and 88.8%, and ROC-AUCs of 0.82 and 0.81, respectively. In the fraud detection task, the Neural Network performed best with an accuracy of 97.5% and a ROC-AUC of 0.88, while Gradient Boosting Tree and Random Forest achieved accuracies of 97.1% and 96.3%, and ROC-AUCs of 0.87 and 0.85, respectively. Feature importance analysis indicates that repayment history, credit limit, bill amount, and repayment amount are key features in credit risk assessment, while transaction amount, transaction time, and location are crucial for fraud detection. Data preprocessing and feature engineering played critical roles in enhancing model performance. Further optimization of model hyperparameters and addressing data imbalance issues will help improve model performance. In conclusion, ensemble learning methods and Neural Networks exhibit significant advantages in credit risk assessment and fraud detection. By employing scientific data preprocessing and feature engineering, combined with advanced machine learning algorithms, financial institutions can significantly enhance their risk management effectiveness.</description>
      <author>Tianyi Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/qw9j1892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risks of Discrimination Violence and Unlawful Actions in LLM-Driven Robots</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54097/taqbjh83</link>
      <description>Zhou Ren, No host. 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401667091

                The integration of Large Language Models (LLMs) into robotics heralds significant advancements in human-robot interaction, enabling robots to perform complex tasks involving natural language understanding, common sense reasoning, and human modeling. However, despite their impressive capabilities, LLMs pose substantial ethical and safety concerns, particularly the risk of enacting discrimination, violence, and unlawful actions. This study conducts a comprehensive Human-Robot Interaction (HRI)-based evaluation of several highly-rated LLMs, focusing on their bias and safety criteria. Our findings reveal that LLMs exhibit significant biases across diverse demographic groups and frequently produce unsafe or unlawful responses when faced with unconstrained natural language inputs. These results underscore the urgent need for systematic risk assessments and robust ethical guidelines to ensure the responsible deployment of LLM-driven robots. We propose detailed strategies for mitigating these risks, including advanced bias detection techniques, robust safety mechanisms, and collaborative standards development. By addressing these critical issues, we aim to pave the way for the development of safer, fairer, and more reliable robotic systems.</description>
      <author>Zhou Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54097/taqbjh83</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen, Oxygen, and Lead Adsorbates on Al&lt;sub&gt;13&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;(100): Accurate Potential Energy Surfaces at Low Computational Cost by Machine Learning and DFT-Based Data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00367</link>
      <description>Nathan Boulangeot, Florian Brix, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Sur, &#201;milie Gaudry, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401699978

                Intermetallic compounds are promising materials in numerous fields, especially those involving surface interactions, such as catalysis. A key factor to investigate their surface properties lies in adsorption energy maps, typically built using first-principles approaches. However, exploring the adsorption energy landscapes of intermetallic compounds can be cumbersome, usually requiring huge computational resources. In this work, we propose an efficient method to predict adsorption energies, based on a Machine Learning (ML) scheme fed by a few Density Functional Theory (DFT) estimates performed on</description>
      <author>Nathan Boulangeot, Florian Brix, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Sur, &#201;milie Gaudry</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00367</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
