<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:43:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible Hydrogen Electrode (RHE) Scale Dependent Surface Pourbaix Diagram at Different pH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00298</link>
      <description>Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Wang Yuan, Hao Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393301713

                In the analysis of electrocatalysis mechanisms and the design of catalysts, the effect of electrochemistry-induced surface coverage is a critical consideration that should not be overlooked. The surface Pourbaix diagram emerges as a fundamental tool in this context, providing essential insights into the surface coverage of adsorbates generated via electrochemical potential-driven water activation. A classic surface Pourbaix diagram considers the pH effects by correcting the free energy of H+ ions by the concentration-dependent term: &#8722;kBT ln(10) &#215; pH, which is independent of the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) scale. However, this is sometimes inconsistent with the experimentally observed potential-dependent surface coverage at an RHE scale, especially under high-pH conditions. Here, we derived the pH-dependent surface Pourbaix diagram at an RHE scale by considering the energetics computed by density functional theory with the Bayesian Error Estimation Functional with van der Waals corrections (BEEF-vdW), the electric field effects, the derived adsorption-induced dipole moment and polarizability, and the potential of zero-charge. Using Pt(111) as the typical example, we found that the surface coverage predicted by the proposed RHE-dependent surface Pourbaix diagram can significantly minimize the discrepancy between theory and experimental observations, especially under neutral-alkaline, moderate-potential conditions. This work provides a new methodology and establishes guidelines for the precise analysis of the surface coverage prior to the evaluation of the activity of an electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Wang Yuan, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid Electrolyte Anions Adsorption Effects on IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08103</link>
      <description>S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393302584

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis is a promising technology merging the usage of intermittent renewable energy sources with the production of green hydrogen. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction remains the bottleneck of the efficiency of these devices due to sluggish reaction kinetics, high cost, and the scarcity of state-of-the-art catalytic materials. Though most research is focused on the discovery of new catalytic materials, understanding the effects of acid electrolyte anions is crucial to designing and optimizing existing electrocatalysts in diverse electrochemical microenvironments. Herein, we systematically study the effects of acid electrolytes on the IrO2(110) surface under OER reaction conditions using density functional theory. The potential-dependent anion adsorption results show that HPO42&#8211; adsorbs the strongest, followed by SO42&#8211;, NO3&#8211;, and ClO4&#8211; respectively at 1.6 V (vs RHE). HPO42&#8211; and SO42&#8211; block the Ir-active sites by competitively adsorbing with the OER intermediates while ClO4&#8211; does not interfere with OER performance. By evaluating dipole-field interactions, surface work function changes, Bader charges of adsorbed anions, and the effects of adsorbed electrolyte anions on the adsorption of the OER intermediates, we provide further insights into acid anion electrolyte effects under the OER conditions. This expansion of fundamental understanding of the effects of acid electrolyte anion adsorption on IrO2 assists in engineering better-performing catalysts with integrated electrolyte microenvironment for OER.</description>
      <author>S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The reduction mechanism of C1 product from carbon dioxide catalyzed by Ni-doped g-C3N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Molecular catalysis (Online). 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393305887

                This work employs density functional theory (DFT) to scrutinize the catalytic efficacy of nano nickel (Ni) clusters supported by graphitic carbon nitride (Nin@g-C3N4, where n ranges from 1 to 6) in the context of the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Structural examination revealed that Nin@g-C3N4 possesses a substantial binding energy (-1.63 eV to -7.72 eV), confirming the structural stability of the catalyst in the CO2RR. Electronic structure analysis revealed a pronounced orbital overlap near the Fermi level between the 3d orbital of Ni atoms and the 2p orbital of adjacent cavity nitrogen atoms in Nin@g-C3N4. Further insights are gleaned from the calculations of the Bader charge and energy band, indicating significant charge transfer and band gap alteration, suggesting enhanced conductivity due to Ni doping on g-C3N4. The catalytic performance in the CO2RR is predominantly influenced by the size of the doped Ni clusters. The Ni4@g-C3N4 cluster demonstrated optimal efficiency in producing formic acid (HCOOH) with a limiting potential of -0.12 V. In contrast, the Ni5@g-C3N4 cluster excels in methane (CH4) formation, with a limiting potential of -0.35 V. Additionally, these catalysts exhibit marked inhibition of the hydrogen evolution reaction, further underscoring their potential in CO2RR applications.</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Hai Feng, Chenyu Li, Xihua Cao, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous confined Pt-based intermetallic compound with wrinkled carbon to enhance the performance towards oxygen reduction reaction for proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234357</link>
      <description>Ferng Chun Ke, Qian Cheng, Dong Ge Tong, Deyou Liu, Xu Xiang, Yubin Chen, Hui Yang, Hui Yang, Journal of power sources (Print). 603(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393307875

                The formation of small-sized (&lt;5 nm) and high-loading (&gt;50 wt%) Pt-based intermetallic compound structures commonly requires thermal treatment to conquer the atom-ordering barrier, which inevitably causes severe nanoparticle agglomeration and hence reduces oxygen reduction reaction activity. Herein, we provided a synthetic wrinkled carbon support by vapor deposition from methane (CH4), and then we utilized the carbon to synthesize sub-5 nm high-loading (50.6 wt%) Pt3Co1 intermetallic compound by mesoporous confinement effect. Structural characterizations reveal that the nanoparticles are mainly located in the pores of the mesoporous carbon with an average size of ca. 4.1 nm, corroborating the confinement effect of the mesoporous structure. As a consequence, the Pt3Co1 intermetallic compound catalyst exhibits superior oxygen reduction reaction activity with a mass activity (@0.9V) of 0.35 A/mgPt and satisfactory durability with a mass activity decline by 22% after 40k-cycles accelerated durability test. Membrane electrode assembly with the resultant catalyst delivers the desirable performance with the peak power density of ca. 1.0 W/cm2 while lowering the Pt loading to 0.1 mg/cm2, suggesting the practical application potential in low-Pt proton exchange membrane fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Ferng Chun Ke, Qian Cheng, Dong Ge Tong, Deyou Liu, Xu Xiang, Yubin Chen, Hui Yang, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directional multiobjective optimization of metal complexes at the billion-system scale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00616-5</link>
      <description>Hannes Kneiding, Ainara Nova, David Balcells, Nature computational science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393309150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hannes Kneiding, Ainara Nova, David Balcells</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-024-00616-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study of Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Mechanism on Typical MXenes under Realistic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00072</link>
      <description>Xueli Liu, Libo Yao, Sijia Zhang, Chuanqi Huang, Wenshao Yang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393316898

                MXenes are a revolutionary class of two-dimensional materials that have been recently demonstrated to exhibit promising capability of electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) in theory and experiment. In electrocatalytic reactions, the active phases, the mechanism, and the performance can be greatly influenced by electrochemical conditions such as applied electrode potential, pH, and electrolyte. Therefore, in this first-principles study, the stable surface structures of three typical MXenes (V2C, Mo2C, and Ti3C2) with variation of electrocatalytic conditions were determined by the Pourbaix phase diagrams. Additionally, the reaction mechanism for CO2RR toward C1 products was investigated based on the thermal dynamically stable phases. The computation revealed that surfaces of all three MXenes are dominated by H* termination throughout the practical CO2RR electrochemical condition ranges. Meanwhile, the bicarbonate ions, which serve as the major electrolyte in CO2RR, show thermal dynamic unfavorability to adsorb on the surfaces. Among the three types of MXenes, V2CH exhibits higher activity in generating CO and HCOOH through the CO2RR, while Mo2CH exhibits higher activity in producing HCHO, CH3OH, and CH4. This comprehensive study provides crucial insights into the mechanism of electrocatalytic CO2RR on MXenes under realistic electrochemical conditions.</description>
      <author>Xueli Liu, Libo Yao, Sijia Zhang, Chuanqi Huang, Wenshao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Review of Bimetallic Nanoparticle&#8211;Graphene Oxide and Bimetallic Nanoparticle&#8211;Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Nanocomposites as Photo-, Electro-, and Photoelectrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071646</link>
      <description>Mogwasha D. Makhafola, Sheriff A. Balogun, Kwena D. Modibane, Energies (Basel). 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317710

                This review extensively discusses current developments in bimetallic nanoparticle&#8211;GO and bimetallic nanoparticle&#8211;MOF nanocomposites as potential catalysts for HER, along with their different synthesis methodologies, structural characteristics, and catalytic mechanisms. The photoelectrocatalytic performance of these catalysts was also compared based on parameters such as Tafel slope, current density, onset potential, turnover frequency, hydrogen yield, activation energy, stability, and durability. The review shows that the commonly used metal alloys in the bimetallic nanoparticle&#8211;GO-based catalysts for HERs include Pt-based alloys (e.g., PtNi, PtCo, PtCu, PtAu, PtSn), Pd-based alloys (e.g., PdAu, PdAg, PdPt) or other combinations, such as AuNi, AuRu, etc., while the most used electrolyte sources are H2SO4 and KOH. For the bimetallic nanoparticle MOF-based catalysts, Pt-based alloys (e.g., PtNi, PtCu), Pd-based alloys (e.g., PdAg, PdCu, PdCr), and Ni-based alloys (e.g., NiMo, NiTi, NiAg, NiCo) took the lead, with KOH being the most frequently used electrolyte source. Lastly, the review addresses challenges and prospects, highlighting opportunities for further optimization and technological integration of the catalysts as promising alternative photo/electrocatalysts for future hydrogen production and storage.</description>
      <author>Mogwasha D. Makhafola, Sheriff A. Balogun, Kwena D. Modibane</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17071646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Double Perovskites in the Dion&#8211;Jacobson Phase Alleviate Parity Forbidden Transitions for Photovoltaic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03276</link>
      <description>Robert V. Stanton, Dhara Trivedi, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317812

                Two-dimensional double perovskites have recently been identified as a potential class of materials for the improvement of halide-perovskite-based solar cell technology. The expanded set of utilizable B- and B&#8242;-site cations afforded to double perovskites, combined with tunable structural and electronic properties in two-dimensional perovskites, leads to a highly modifiable set of materials, which have yet to be explored. In this study, we investigate the structural, electronic, and thermoelectric properties of these materials and identify a number of key structure&#8211;property relationships governing their performance. In the process, we demonstrate a link between the relative electronegativities of the building components and the resultant geometric structures. Furthermore, we provide insights aimed toward alleviating concerns associated with parity forbidden transitions which plague many double perovskite systems. In addition, we identify a number of two-dimensional double perovskites including the mixed-oxidation state In25Tl75Cl-based system which displays optically active transitions as low as 1.41 eV across the Brillouin zone and indicators pointing toward stable experimental synthesis.</description>
      <author>Robert V. Stanton, Dhara Trivedi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects of Carbon Vacancies in Conjunction with Phosphorus Dopant across Bilayer Graphene for the Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c00495</link>
      <description>Huimin Hu, Jin Ho Choi, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393318016

                Bilayer graphene (BLG) exhibits distinct physical properties under external influences, such as torsion and structural defects, setting it apart from monolayer graphene. In this study, we explore the synergistic effects of carbon vacancies, in conjunction with phosphorus dopants, across BLG, focusing on their impact on structural, magnetic, electrical, and hydrogen adsorption properties. Our findings reveal that the substitutional doping of a phosphorus atom into a single carbon vacancy in a graphene layer induces substantial structural distortion in BLG. In contrast, doping phosphorus into a double vacancy maintains the flat structure of graphene layers. These distinct layer structures affect the electron distribution and spin arrangement, leading to varied electronic configurations and intriguing magnetic behaviors. Furthermore, the presence of abundant unsaturated electrons around the vacancy promotes the capture and bonding of hydrogen atoms. Hydrogen adsorption on BLG results in substantial orbital hybridization, accompanied by significant charge transfer. The calculated Gibbs free energies for hydrogen adsorption on BLG range from &#8722;0.08 to 0.09 eV, indicating exceptional catalytic activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction. These findings carry implications for optimizing the properties of graphene layers, making them highly desirable for applications such as catalysis.</description>
      <author>Huimin Hu, Jin Ho Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c00495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effects of Fe and P doping in WS2 monolayers for enhanced bifunctional electrocatalysis in water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.261</link>
      <description>Sampath Prabhakaran, Getasew Mulualem Zewdie, Hong Seok Kang, Do Hwan Kim, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393332697

                The quest for efficient dual-purpose electrocatalysts to facilitate water splitting is an ongoing challenge in materials science. In this study, we introduce a novel approach involving the incorporation of Fe and P atoms into WS2 monolayers (MLs) through rigorous first-principle calculations. The introduction of Fe and P atoms brings about remarkable enhancements in the electronic properties of the WS2 MLs, significantly boosting the catalytic performance of the 1T' phase. The doping-induced changes in energy levels lead to the formation of a spin-polarized density of states, which exhibits superior conductivity in the vicinity of the d-band center and Fermi level. These electronic alterations are intricately governed by the valence and conduction bands. In addition to this, the introduced dopants elevate the charge transfer rate while simultaneously reducing interfacial resistance. Furthermore, the strong bonding of the dopants plays a pivotal role in reducing the energy barrier during adsorption. This, in turn, leads to a substantial decrease in the Gibbs free energy (0.101 eV) for the hydrogen evolution reaction and a lowered overpotential (0.36 V) for the oxygen evolution reaction. These findings collectively offer a promising avenue for the development of advanced bifunctional catalysts in the context of water splitting, suggesting that substitutional heteroatom doping of 1T&#8242;-WS2 MLs holds substantial potential in this field.</description>
      <author>Sampath Prabhakaran, Getasew Mulualem Zewdie, Hong Seok Kang, Do Hwan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pivotal role of Ce3+ polarons on promoting oxygen reduction reaction activity of Pt1/CeO2 catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234393</link>
      <description>Yan Jiang, Wei Xiao, Rong Zeng, Qi&#8208;Jun Hong, Xiaowu Li, Ligen Wang, Journal of power sources (Print). 603(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393337631

                The Pt1/CeO2 single-atom catalyst excels across catalytic fields, promising applications in the oxygen reduction reactions (ORRs). Here, we employ first-principles calculations to systematically investigate the ORR mechanism catalyzed by Pt1/CeO2 systems and the activity regulated by Ce3+ polarons. We determine the reaction pathways of different Pt1/CeO2 systems by evaluating four critical factors: O2 adsorption energy, O2 dissociation Gibbs barrier, Gibbs free energy change for O2&#8594;OOH*, and H2O2 adsorption structure. Notably, most Pt1/CeO2 systems tend to react through the 4e&#8722; associative path. Theoretical activity calculations reveal that PtOH/CeO2(110) system show low overpotential of 0.47 V comparable to pure Pt. The excellent ORR activity is attributed to the synergistic mechanism of Pt and surrounding Ce3+ polarons, where the polaron regulation mechanism dominates the reaction. The quantity of Ce3+ polarons not only affects the reaction active sites but also regulates the radical adsorption state. With an elevated Ce3+ polarons concentration, the ORR overpotential in Pt1/CeO2 system can decrease from 0.47 to 0.16 V, leading to a substantial enhancement in activity. This work first underscores the crucial involvement of Ce3+ polarons in catalyzing the ORR, reducing the significance of Pt in catalysis, inspiring a new way to design active non-platinum electrocatalysts for ORR in experiments.</description>
      <author>Yan Jiang, Wei Xiao, Rong Zeng, Qi&#8208;Jun Hong, Xiaowu Li, Ligen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photochemical reduction of ultrasmall Pt nanoparticles on single-layer transition-metal dichalcogenides for hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2023.101487</link>
      <description>Liang Mei, Yuefeng Zhang, Ting Ying, W. Zheng, Honglu Hu, Ruijie Yang, Ruixin Yan, Yue Zhang, Chong Cheng, Bilu Liu, Shuang Li, Zhiyuan Zeng, Materials today energy. 42(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393337653

                Single-layer TaS2 and TiS2 nanosheets were meticulously synthesized through an electrochemical lithium-intercalation-based exfoliation method. Subsequently, ultrasmall Pt nanoparticles, finely sized between 1.2 and 1.6 nm, were expertly deposited onto these monolayer nanosheets via an environmentally friendly photochemical reduction process. The resulted Pt-TaS2 and Pt-TiS2 composites exhibit hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity comparable with commercial Pt/C. Density functional theory calculations reveal that the introduced Pt (111) plane energetically promotes the adsorption of &#8727;H with an optimal &#916;G value of 0.09 eV. Furthermore, these composite materials demonstrate outstanding cycle stability, far exceeding that of Pt/C. This compelling performance underscores the potential of Pt-TaS2 and Pt-TiS2 hybrids as promising alternatives for HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Liang Mei, Yuefeng Zhang, Ting Ying, W. Zheng, Honglu Hu, Ruijie Yang, Ruixin Yan, Yue Zhang, Chong Cheng, Bilu Liu, Shuang Li, Zhiyuan Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2023.101487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles modeling of corrosion potential/current and its application in AZ and AZ-RE Magnesium Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108771</link>
      <description>Yuhao Huang, Xumin Zhang, Jiawei Wang, Y. Zeng, Xi Zhang, Luo Li, Yong Liu, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393346570

                First-principles modeling for magnesium corrosion potential/current has been established in this work. The corrosion potential formulation should be UaSHE=ln10RTlgnFkTh+Gv+NAN&#215;S&#215;Esurf+(10ln10)RT+0.65&#955;2nF&#8722;(&#955;1+&#955;2)nF(the intersection point of anodic and cathodic branch). And the one for the corrosion current density should belgJtot=lgJm+km&#215;&#8721;(fm&#215;&#8710;Em)+ki&#215;&#8721;(fi&#215;&#8710;Ei)(including matrix corrosion lgJm, matrix interplane galvanic corrosion km&#215;&#8721;(fm&#215;&#8710;Em), second phase galvanic corrosionki&#215;&#8721;(fi&#215;&#8710;Ei) and &#8710;E is the intergranular potential difference between phase/matrix planes and Mg(0001)). Applied the modeling to simulate AZ and AZ-RE electrochemical corrosion, the predicted potential/current values are quite coherent with the experimental polarization ones. The role of alloying element on corrosion have also been discussed at atomic level. The main alloying element (such as Al or Zn in AZ, or AZ-RE) would affect work function &#934;, surface energy density Esurf/&#961;, and hydrogen atom adsorption free energy &#8710;GH*, so it influences anode/cathode reaction greatly and works a lot on Ua and lgJm. Furthermore, main alloy and minor alloy (such as RE in AZ-RE) would make their own contribution on galvanic corrosion by holding the potential difference &#8710;Em or &#8710;Ei and keeping mole fraction fm or fi. The work provide the modeling which could predict the corrosion potential/current values for magnesium alloy, which are directly correspond to the polarization curves. It also could give a theoretical understanding for alloying effect on corrosion. It suggests a more flexible way for seeking corrosion-resistant alloys.</description>
      <author>Yuhao Huang, Xumin Zhang, Jiawei Wang, Y. Zeng, Xi Zhang, Luo Li, Yong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum&#8211;Tellurium Heterojunction Nanosheet Assemblies for Efficient Direct Formic Acid Electrooxidation Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c11523</link>
      <description>Dong Chen, Biao Zhang, Huijun Song, Shiyuan Zhou, Jinyu Ye, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Lisha Dong, Bolong Huang, Lingzheng Bu, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393317391

                Two-dimensional (2D) heterojunction nanomaterials offer exceptional physicochemical and catalytic properties, thanks to their special spatial electronic structure. However, synthesizing morphologically uniform 2D platinum (Pt)-based metallic nanomaterials with diverse crystalline phases remains a formidable challenge. In this study, we have achieved the successful synthesis of advanced 2D platinum&#8211;tellurium heterojunction nanosheet assemblies (Ptx&#8211;PtTe2 HJNSAs, x = 0, 1, 2), seamlessly integrating both trigonal PtTe2 (t-PtTe2) and cubic Pt (c-Pt) phases. By enabling efficient electron transport and leveraging the specific electron density present at the heterojunction, the Pt2&#8211;PtTe2 HJNSAs/C demonstrated exceptional formic acid oxidation reaction (FAOR) activity and stability. Specifically, the specific and mass activities reached 8.4 mA cm&#8211;2 and 6.1 A mgPt&#8211;1, which are 46.7 and 50.8 times higher than those of commercial Pt/C, respectively. Impressively, aberration-corrected high-angle annular dark field scanning transmission electron microscopy (AC-HAADF-STEM) revealed a closely packed arrangement of atomic layers and a coherent intergrowth heterogeneous structure. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations further indicated that rearrangement of electronic structure occurred on the surface of Pt2&#8211;PtTe2 HJNSAs resulting in a more favorable dehydrogenation pathway and excellent CO tolerance, beneficial for performance improvement. This work inspires the targeted exploration of Pt-based nanomaterials through 2D heterostructure design, leading to an important impact on fuel cell catalysis and beyond.</description>
      <author>Dong Chen, Biao Zhang, Huijun Song, Shiyuan Zhou, Jinyu Ye, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Lisha Dong, Bolong Huang, Lingzheng Bu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c11523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum/Tantalum Carbide Core&#8211;Shell Nanoparticles with Sub&#8208;Monolayer Shells for Methanol and Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304092</link>
      <description>Zhenshu Wang, Jin Soo Kang, Daniel G&#246;hl, Paul Paciok, Douglas Gon&#231;alves, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim, Daniela Zanchet, Marc Heggen, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Marc Ledendecker, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Advanced energy materials (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393334644

                Abstract Core&#8211;shell architectures provide great opportunities to improve catalytic activity, but achieving nanoparticle stability under electrochemical cycling remains challenging. Herein, core&#8211;shell nanoparticles comprising atomically thin Pt shells over earth&#8208;abundant TaC cores are synthesized and used as highly durable electrocatalysts for the methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) needed to drive direct methanol fuel cells (DMFCs). Characterization data show that a thin oxidic passivation layer protects the TaC core from undergoing dissolution in the fuel cell&#8208;relevant potential range, enabling the use of partially covered Pt/TaC core&#8211;shell nanoparticles for MOR and ORR with high stability and enhanced catalytic performance. Specifically, at the anode the surface&#8208;oxidized TaC further enhances MOR activity compared to conventional Pt nanoparticles. At the cathode, the Pt/TaC catalyst feature increases tolerance to methanol crossover. These results show unique synergistic advantages of the core&#8211;shell particles and open opportunities to tailor catalytic properties for electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Zhenshu Wang, Jin Soo Kang, Daniel G&#246;hl, Paul Paciok, Douglas Gon&#231;alves, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim, Daniela Zanchet, Marc Heggen, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Marc Ledendecker, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methanol&#8208;Facilitated Surface Reconstruction Catalysts for Near 200% Faradaic Efficiency in a Coupled System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314596</link>
      <description>Xia Qin, Chengkai Jin, Yu Lun Huang, Yanjie Zhai, Wenkai Han, Cheng Cheng, Chuan Xia, Chun Che Lin, Xunhua Zhao, Xiao Zhang, Advanced functional materials (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393345338

                Abstract The coupling of the carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) and methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) holds great promise for the energy&#8208;efficient production of HCOO &#8722; . However, anode catalysts' limited selectivity (&lt;80%) and stability (&lt;15 h) have impeded electron utilization and HCOO &#8722; production rates. To overcome it, copper&#8208;copper(I) oxide&#8208;copper(II) oxide nanowires (Cu&#9472;CuO&#9472;Cu 2 O NWs) catalysts have been developed, which exhibit exceptional performance in promoting the MOR with a faradic efficiency of nearly 100% at commercially viable current densities, and long stability over 100 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Interestingly, the unique structure of the catalysts, when exposed to methanol, facilitates a transition from Cu/CuO to Cu 2 O. This phenomenon promotes the MOR while inhibiting the competitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER). By coupling the anodic reaction with cathodic CO 2 reduction, the system demonstrates exceptional performance in HCOO &#8722; production, achieving an overall faradic efficiency of nearly 200% at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 with a low cell voltage of 2.382 V. Techno&#8208;economic analysis indicates that the production costs of HCOOH are &#8776;US$0.37 and 0.35 kg &#8722;1 at 100 and 150 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively, significantly lower than those associated with traditional electrochemical methods.</description>
      <author>Xia Qin, Chengkai Jin, Yu Lun Huang, Yanjie Zhai, Wenkai Han, Cheng Cheng, Chuan Xia, Chun Che Lin, Xunhua Zhao, Xiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Cu-Doped Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Aqueous Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00571</link>
      <description>Ashis Kumar Behera, Deepak Seth, Manish Agarwal, M. Ali Haider, Aninda J. Bhattacharyya, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393363876

                The efficiency of oxygen electrocatalysis is a key factor in diverse energy domain applications, including the performance of metal&#8211;air batteries, such as aqueous Zinc (Zn)&#8211;air batteries. We demonstrate here that the doping of cobalt oxide with optimal amounts of copper (abbreviated as Cu-doped Co3O4) results in a stable and efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction (ORR) and evolution (OER) reactions in aqueous Zn&#8211;air batteries. At high Cu-doping concentrations (&#8805;5%), phase segregation occurs with the simultaneous presence of Co3O4 and copper oxide (CuO). At Cu-doping concentrations &#8804;5%, the Cu ion resides in the octahedral (Oh) site of Co3O4, as revealed by X-ray diffraction (XRD)/Raman spectroscopy investigations and molecular dynamics (MD) calculations. The residence of Cu@Oh sites leads to an increased concentration of surface Co3+-ions (at catalytically active planes) and oxygen vacancies, which is beneficial for the OER. Temperature-dependent magnetization measurements reveal favorable d-orbital configuration (high eg occupancy &#8776; 1) and a low &#8594; high spin-state transition of the Co3+-ions, which are beneficial for the ORR in the alkaline medium. The influence of Cu-doping on the ORR activity of Co3O4 is additionally accounted in DFT calculations via interactions between solvent water molecules and oxygen vacancies. The application of the bifunctional Cu-doped (&#8804;5%) Co3O4 electrocatalyst resulted in an aqueous Zn&#8211;air battery with promising power density (=84 mW/cm2), stable cyclability (over 210 cycles), and low charge/discharge overpotential (=0.92 V).</description>
      <author>Ashis Kumar Behera, Deepak Seth, Manish Agarwal, M. Ali Haider, Aninda J. Bhattacharyya</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Surface Reconstruction During Oxygen Evolution Reaction on the Defined Spinel Oxide Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401095</link>
      <description>Kyungbeen Yeom, Jung Hyun Jo, Hyun-Seop Shin, Hyunsoo Ji, Sun-Young Moon, Ji&#8208;Eun Park, Seongbeom Lee, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Dong Hyeon Mok, Megalamane S. Bootharaju, Seoin Back, Taeghwan Hyeon, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Advanced functional materials (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393364585

                Abstract The reconstructed surface structure of Co&#8208;based spinel oxides serves as the active site for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the structural complexity of spinel oxides and surface dynamics during the OER hinder the understanding of the reconstruction mechanism and electronic structure of the active site. In this study, spinel Co 3 O 4 @(CoFeV) 3 O 4 nanocube (CoFeV) is reported, a (001) facet&#8208;defined spinel oxide comprising Co, Fe, and V deposited on the Co 3 O 4 nanocube template to exclude facet&#8208;dependent factors. Introducing highly dissoluble V cations accelerates the reconstruction process to enhance the electrocatalytic activity. CoFeV exhibited enhanced electrocatalytic activity (266 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 M KOH) and durability (maintained stable electrocatalytic activity during a 200 h chronopotentiometry (CP) test at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ) with significantly enlarged electrochemically active surface area (ECSA). The experimental and theoretical results demonstrated that V dissolution during catalysis induced oxygen vacancies, accelerating the surface reconstruction to highly active oxyhydroxide. Consequently, the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) of CoFeV as the anode exhibited a remarkable performance of 6.19 A cm &#8722;2 at 2.0 V cell in 1 M KOH and robust durability for 96 h at a constant current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Kyungbeen Yeom, Jung Hyun Jo, Hyun-Seop Shin, Hyunsoo Ji, Sun-Young Moon, Ji&#8208;Eun Park, Seongbeom Lee, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Dong Hyeon Mok, Megalamane S. Bootharaju, Seoin Back, Taeghwan Hyeon, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Data-Driven Discovery and Screening of Two-Dimensional Magnets Using Graph Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07246</link>
      <description>Ahmed Elrashidy, James Della-Giustina, Jia-An Yan, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393378496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ahmed Elrashidy, James Della-Giustina, Jia-An Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and lifetime of diffusion-trapped oxygen in oxide-derived copper CO2 reduction electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01132-5</link>
      <description>Zan Lian, Federico Dattila, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393379673

                Abstract Oxide-derived Cu has an excellent ability to promote C&#8211;C coupling in the electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction. However, these materials largely rearrange under reaction conditions; therefore, the nature of the active site remains controversial. Here we study the reduction process of oxide-derived Cu via large-scale molecular dynamics with a precise neural network potential trained on first-principles data and introducing experimental conditions. The oxygen concentration in the most stable oxide-derived Cu increases with an increase of the pH, potential or specific surface area. In long electrochemical experiments, the catalyst would be fully reduced to Cu, but removing all the trapped oxygen takes a considerable amount of time. Although the highly reconstructed Cu surface provides various sites to adsorb oxygen more strongly, the surface oxygen atoms are not stable under common experimental conditions. This work provides insight into the evolution of oxide-derived Cu catalysts and residual oxygen during reaction and also a deep understanding of the nature of active sites.</description>
      <author>Zan Lian, Federico Dattila, N&#250;ria Lop&#233;z</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01132-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Search and Theoretical Study of Silicene Grain Boundaries&#8217; Mechanical Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07294</link>
      <description>Jianan Zhang, Aditya Koneru, Subramanian K. R. S. Sankaranarayanan, Carmen M. Lilley, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393380298

                Defects such as grain boundaries (GBs) are almost inevitable during the synthesis process of 2D materials. To take advantage of the fascinating properties of 2D materials, understanding the nature and impact of various GB structures on pristine 2D sheets is crucial. In this work, using an evolutionary algorithm search, we predict a wide variety of silicene GB structures with very different atomic structures compared with those found in graphene or hexagonal boron-nitride. Twenty-one GBs with the lowest energy were validated by density functional theory (DFT), a majority of which were previously unreported to our best knowledge. Based on the diversity of the GB predictions, we found that the formation energy and mechanical properties can be dramatically altered by adatom positions within a GB and certain types of atomic structures, such as four-atom rings. To study the mechanical behavior of these GBs, we apply strain to the GB structures stepwise and use DFT calculations to investigate the mechanical properties of 9 representative structures. It is observed that GB structures based on pentagon-heptagon pairs are likely to have similar or higher in-plane stiffness and strength compared to the zigzag orientation of pristine silicene. However, an adatom located at the hollow site of a heptagon ring can significantly deteriorate the mechanical strength. For all of the structures, the in-plane stiffness and strength were found to decrease with increasing formation energy. For the failure behavior of GB structures, it was found that GB structures based on pentagon-heptagon pairs have failure behavior similar to that of graphene. We also found that the GB structures with atoms positioned outside of the 2D plane tend to experience phase transitions before failure. Utilizing the evolutionary algorithm, we locate diverse silicene GBs and obtain useful information about their mechanical properties.</description>
      <author>Jianan Zhang, Aditya Koneru, Subramanian K. R. S. Sankaranarayanan, Carmen M. Lilley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment Regulation Breaks the Trade-Off between the Faradaic Efficiency and the Current Density for Electrocatalytic Deuteration Using D2O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4023036/v1</link>
      <description>Bin Zhang, Meng He, Rui Li, Chuanqi Cheng, Cuibo Liu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393381349

                Abstract The high Faradaic efficiency (FE) of the deuteration of organics with D 2 O at large current densities is significant for developing a feasible and promising room-temperature deuteration strategy. However, the FE and current density are the two ends of a seesaw because of the severe D 2 evolution side reaction at nearly industrial current densities (&#8722; 100 mA cm &#8722; 2 ). Herein, we report a combined scenario of a nanotip-enhanced electric field and surfactant-modified interface microenvironment to enable electrocatalytic deuteration of arylacetonitrile in D 2 O with an 80% FE at &#8722; 100 mA cm &#8722; 2 , which are both the best records for electrocatalytic deuteration. The increased reactant concentration with low activation energy due to the large electric field along the tips and the accelerated reactant transfer and suppressed D 2 evolution by the surfactant-created deuterophobic microenvironment contribute to breaking the trade-off between high FE and current density. Furthermore, the application of our strategy in other deuteration reactions with improved FE at &#8722; 100 mA cm &#8722; 2 rationalizes the design concept.</description>
      <author>Bin Zhang, Meng He, Rui Li, Chuanqi Cheng, Cuibo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4023036/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing d Electrons&#8217; Delocalization of the Single-Atom Ni&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Site to Boost Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to CO by Axial d&#8211;d Orbital Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00493</link>
      <description>Xiaohang Wang, Zhongzheng Mao, Guanghua Wei, Lingli Liu, Hao Tang, Baolei Li, Ling Zhu, Simin Xu, Shaobin Tang, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393381512

                Atomically dispersed nitrogen-coordinated transition metal (TM) anchored on graphene (TM&#8211;Nx&#8211;C) provides a promising potential for an electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). However, it is still a challenge to precisely control the electronic structures of TM single-atom catalysts (SACs) for optimizing the catalytic performance. Using first-principles calculations, we propose a novel strategy to regulate the electronic structure of the Ni&#8211;N4&#8211;C site by vertically coupling the 3-fold N atom-coordinated TM atom on graphene (TM&#8211;N3&#8211;C) for promoting CO2 reduction to CO. In contrast to the traditional TM&#8211;N4&#8211;C substrate that is weakly coupled with the N&#8211;N4&#8211;C site, the raised TM atoms on the TM&#8211;N3&#8211;C substrate relative to the basal plane of graphene shorten the distance from TM to Ni atoms and strengthen d orbital hybridization between them, thus leading to more delocalized charge distribution of the Ni active site. As a result, the improved axial d&#8211;d orbital coupling largely enhances the adsorption of the key *COOH intermediate on Ni SACs and, more importantly, maintains the facile desorption of adsorbed *CO. In particular, these Ni&#8211;N4&#8211;C SACs with axial coupling of Tc&#8211; and Ru&#8211;N3&#8211;C substrates not only exhibit high catalytic activity toward CO production, with low limiting potentials of &#8722;0.68 and &#8722;0.61 V, respectively, but also effectively suppress the competing hydrogen evolution (HER).</description>
      <author>Xiaohang Wang, Zhongzheng Mao, Guanghua Wei, Lingli Liu, Hao Tang, Baolei Li, Ling Zhu, Simin Xu, Shaobin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of electrocatalytic urea synthesis through CO2 and N2 on metal cluster decorated C2N</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09547-y</link>
      <description>Wenxi Zhang, Mengnan Qu, Aijun Du, Qiao Sun, Journal of materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393386671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenxi Zhang, Mengnan Qu, Aijun Du, Qiao Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09547-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretically Insight into Co and S Pairs Dispersed on N&#8208;Doped Graphene: Promising Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400076</link>
      <description>Ji Zhang, Aimin Yu, Dongsheng Li, Chenghua Sun, Advanced theory and simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393388274

                Abstract Single atom catalysts (SACs) are considered as efficient catalysts for hydrogen&#8208;based energy conversion and storage because of their excellent catalytic performance for oxygen evolution reactions (OER) and oxygen reduction reactions (ORR). In the present work, a new concept of SACs is proposed with the capacity to form d &#8208; p orbital hybridization. These computationally designed SACs contain a metal and non&#8208;metal pair embedded in the N&#8208;doped graphene framework (MX@N 6 ). Based on the overpotential evaluation by the first principle theory calculations, CoS@N 6 containing Co and S atom pair possessed a low overpotential of 0.37 V/0.29 V when used as a bifunctional ORR/OER catalyst. These overpotentials are much lower than Co@N 6 without S atom. The electronic structure analysis revealed that non&#8208;metal atoms of the catalyst can regulate the electronic structure of active metal sites and facilitate the adsorption and charge transfer between intermediates and the catalyst resulting in enhanced catalytic performance. This work demonstrates an alternative way to further improve the catalytic activity of SACs by introducing a non&#8208;metal atom that may shed light on the rational design of advanced SACs for ORR/OER with high efficiency and stability.</description>
      <author>Ji Zhang, Aimin Yu, Dongsheng Li, Chenghua Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validation workflow for machine learning interatomic potentials for complex ceramics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</link>
      <description>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash, Computational materials science. 239(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393373529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing lithium-silver alloy phases for enhanced energy density and electrochemical performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</link>
      <description>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu, Next materials. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393925878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolytic Regeneration of Spent Caustic Soda from CO2 Capture Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</link>
      <description>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho, Processes. 12(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393866132

                The traditional electrochemical caustic soda recovery system uses the generated pH gradient across the ion exchange membrane for the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent from CO2 capture. This electrochemical CO2 capture system releases the by-products H2 and O2 at the cathode and anode, respectively. Although effective for capturing CO2, the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limit the energy efficiency of this technique. Hence, this study proposed and validated a hybrid electrochemical cell based on the H2-cycling from the cathode to the anode to eliminate the reliance on anodic oxygen generation. The results show that our lab-scale prototype enabled effective spent caustic soda recovery with an electron utilisation efficiency of 90%, and a relative carbonate/bicarbonate diffusional flux of approximately 40%. The system also enabled the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent with a minimum electrochemical energy input of 0.19 kWh/kg CO2 at a CO2 recovery rate of 0.7 mol/m2/h, accounting for 30% lower energy demand than a control system without H2-recycling, making this technique a promising alternative to the conventional thermal regeneration technology.</description>
      <author>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenges of hydrogen production from biomass gasification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13613-9.00005-2</link>
      <description>Jingwei Chen, Yilin Guo, Xiaomin Wu, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393323912

                With the development of alternative energy sources, biomass gasification for hydrogen production technology has attracted high attentions from researchers. This chapter introduces three main aspects: biomass gasification for hydrogen production technology, enhancement strategies for hydrogen production from biomass gasification, and hydrogen purification technology. The physical and chemical processes of hydrogen production from traditional biomass gasification, the effects of various key parameters on the performance of hydrogen production from biomass gasification, and the advantages and disadvantages of existing hydrogen purification technologies are introduced in details. Although the technology of hydrogen production from biomass gasification has been studied for many years, there are still challenges that hinder the commercialization and industrialization of hydrogen production technology from biomass gasification. The challenges including the detailed gasification evolution mechanisms of biomass, the gasification interactions between biomass components, the development of new catalysts and purification technologies, and the antiaging of catalytic and purification materials have been proposed in this chapter. In particular, there is a lack of precise and detailed descriptions of the gasification evolution mechanism of biomass macromolecules, catalytic and deactivation mechanisms of catalysts, which provide a theoretical basis for precise manipulation of the direction of hydrogen production reactions from biomass gasification. Finally, it is hoped that by overcoming the challenges presented, the technical barriers of hydrogen production from biomass gasification can be broken through, and the hydrogen production technology from biomass gasification can be commercialized and industrialized.</description>
      <author>Jingwei Chen, Yilin Guo, Xiaomin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13613-9.00005-2</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
