<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 01:41:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxide-mediated asymmetric Ni-O-Mn electron channels in MnOx@Ni(OH)2@NF monolithic catalyst for efficient and stable catalytic ozonation of methyl mercaptan</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163417</link>
      <description>Zhangnan Yao, Tao P. Zhong, Chenghua Wang, Fang Zhong, Jun Du, Wenbin Huang, Huinan Zhao, Shuanghong Tian, Dong Shu, Chun He, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410083474

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhangnan Yao, Tao P. Zhong, Chenghua Wang, Fang Zhong, Jun Du, Wenbin Huang, Huinan Zhao, Shuanghong Tian, Dong Shu, Chun He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.163417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation on diatomic copper catalysts coordinated with nitrogen, boron, and sulfur for electrocatalytic CO&#8322; reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142149</link>
      <description>Hui Li, Chenyu Li, Xindi Cao, Jiali Liu, Jing Zhang, Zhiqiang Xing, Junfeng Zhao, Yang Wu, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410083912

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Li, Chenyu Li, Xindi Cao, Jiali Liu, Jing Zhang, Zhiqiang Xing, Junfeng Zhao, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heyrovsky&#8208;Driven Hydrogen Evolution on Pt&#8208;Rh/FePS&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;: A Theoretical Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202500018</link>
      <description>Ravi Trivedi, Brahmananda Chakraborty, ChemistrySelect. 10(17)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410085785

                Abstract We explored the HER activity of FePS 3 monolayers in combination with various metals and metal alloys, including Pt, Pd, Ir, Ag, Au, Fe, P, Rh, as well as Pt&#8208;Rh, Ir&#8208;Pt, and Ir&#8208;Rh using state of the art density functional theory for the advantages for electrocatalytic applications. Among these metal and alloy combinations, PtRh/FePS 3 exhibited the lowest Gibbs free energy ( &#916;G = 0.06 eV), indicating the highest HER performance. Furthermore, our calculations suggest that hydrogen evolution on Pt&#8208;Rh/FePS 3 follows the Heyrovsky mechanism, supported by a lower energy barrier for the Volmer&#8211;Heyrovsky step (0.37 eV) compared to the Volmer&#8211;Tafel step. These theoretical findings provide valuable insights for experimentalists aiming to electrocatalyst for efficient HER applications.</description>
      <author>Ravi Trivedi, Brahmananda Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202500018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic regulation of sulfides and carbon in Fe-doped CoS2@MOF-based nanocomposites for enhanced catalytic performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180769</link>
      <description>Yihua Wang, Zi Ouyang, Xiaolu Liu, Siwei Liang, Weipeng Lai, Xiaoshuang Li, Chengqun Xu, Qi Feng, Donghua Fan, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410089387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yihua Wang, Zi Ouyang, Xiaolu Liu, Siwei Liang, Weipeng Lai, Xiaoshuang Li, Chengqun Xu, Qi Feng, Donghua Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensively evaluating and unraveling the electrical conductivity, corrosion resistance and mechanical properties of metal carbide coatings for metal bipolar plates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.112713</link>
      <description>Lijie Zhang, Xiaohua Hong, Zonglun Li, Jian Song, Zan Yang, Jiansheng Liu, Jihui Huang, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410089945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lijie Zhang, Xiaohua Hong, Zonglun Li, Jian Song, Zan Yang, Jiansheng Liu, Jihui Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.112713</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying the Liouville&#8211;Lanczos method of time-dependent density-functional theory to warm dense matter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0263947</link>
      <description>Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Sebastian Schwalbe, Thomas Gawne, Thomas R. Preston, Jan Vorberger, Tobias Dornheim, Matter and Radiation at Extremes. 10(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410092768

                Ab initio modeling of dynamic structure factors (DSF) and related density response properties in the warm dense matter (WDM) regime is a challenging computational task. The DSF, convolved with a probing X-ray beam and instrument function, is measured in X-ray Thomson scattering (XRTS) experiments, which allow the study of electronic structure properties at the microscopic level. Among the various ab initio methods, linear-response time-dependent density-functional theory (LR-TDDFT) is a key framework for simulating the DSF. The standard approach in LR-TDDFT for computing the DSF relies on the orbital representation. A significant drawback of this method is the unfavorable scaling of the number of required empty bands as the wavenumber increases, making LR-TDDFT impractical for modeling XRTS measurements over large energy scales, such as in backward scattering geometry. In this work, we consider and test an alternative approach to LR-TDDFT that employs the Liouville&#8211;Lanczos (LL) method for simulating the DSF of WDM. This approach does not require empty states and allows the DSF at large momentum transfer values and over a broad frequency range to be accessed. We compare the results obtained from the LL method with those from the solution of Dyson&#8217;s equation using the standard LR-TDDFT within the projector augmented-wave formalism for isochorically heated aluminum and warm dense hydrogen. Additionally, we utilize exact path integral Monte Carlo results for the imaginary-time density-density correlation function (ITCF) of warm dense hydrogen to rigorously benchmark the LL approach. We discuss the application of the LL method for calculating DSFs and ITCFs at different wavenumbers, the effects of pseudopotentials, and the role of Lorentzian smearing. The successful validation of the LL method under WDM conditions makes it a valuable addition to the ab initio simulation landscape, supporting experimental efforts and advancing WDM theory.</description>
      <author>Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Sebastian Schwalbe, Thomas Gawne, Thomas R. Preston, Jan Vorberger, Tobias Dornheim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0263947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulation of Electrochemical Surface Reconstruction on Spinel Oxides for Boosted Water Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01964</link>
      <description>Yuxin Li, Zhe Zhang, Yilin Yang, Chunguang Li, Zhan Shi, Shouhua Feng, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410093002

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Li, Zhe Zhang, Yilin Yang, Chunguang Li, Zhan Shi, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Efficiency Electrochemical Ammonia Synthesis at Co-Catalytic Fe&#8211;Mo Dual-Atom Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c01741</link>
      <description>Ruonan Li, Runlin Ma, Lili Zhang, Wei Ma, Gonglei Shao, Xu Zhang, Yun Tian, Menggai Jiao, Zhen Zhou, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410096201

                To tackle the challenge in electrochemical nitrogen fixing and reduction in aqueous electrolytes, the conventional approach has been to suppress the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction. Nonetheless, proton provision is a crucial step in the nitrogen reduction pathway to produce ammonia, and a single active site faces the daunting task in striking a balance between high nitrogen fixation efficiency and fast protonation kinetics. This work presents a harmonic strategy featuring atomically dispersed dual Fe-Mo sites anchored in an N-doped carbon (FeMoNC) substrate, where a low-spin Fe center with enriched empty d orbitals aids in nitrogen fixation and activation, and the adjacent Mo site accelerates the protonation kinetics of N-containing intermediates at the Fe site via a distal associative mechanism. Driven by this co-catalytic mechanism, the FeMoNC catalyst achieves a Faradaic efficiency of 37.42%, marking a significant improvement of 7.8- and 10.6-fold over Fe or Mo single-atom catalysts, respectively. Furthermore, an excellent NH3 yield of 54.40 &#956;g h-1 mgcat.-1 is realized in a flow cell by enhancing mass transfer. This study provides valuable insights into diatomic co-catalytic mechanisms for electrochemical ammonia synthesis.</description>
      <author>Ruonan Li, Runlin Ma, Lili Zhang, Wei Ma, Gonglei Shao, Xu Zhang, Yun Tian, Menggai Jiao, Zhen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c01741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable Charge Distribution in Self&#8208;Supported NiCoP Through V and Mo Incorporation for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution in all pH Ranges and Alkaline Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503368</link>
      <description>Tanu Bagaria, Taranga Borgohain, Swati Jadhav, Tisita Das, Bharati Debnath, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410098559

                Abstract Developing electrocatalysts with high activity and durability remains a key challenge in water electrolysis, essential for advancing sustainable hydrogen fuel production. Efficient electrocatalysts capable of functioning across diverse pH conditions and in alkaline seawater for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) are crucial for the future of clean energy. In this study, a dual incorporation of vanadium (V) and molybdenum (Mo) into NiCoP [V, M (x,y)&#8208;NCP] catalyst is successfully fabricated via electrodeposition, offering an effective method for enhancing HER activity. Exhibiting low impedance and a high electrochemically active surface area, the material achieved overpotentials of 24 mV in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 , 85 mV in 1 m PBS, and 32 mV in 1 m KOH at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Impressively, V, M (3,6)&#8208;NCP demonstrated excellent electrocatalytic performance in alkaline seawater, achieving 41 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . The catalyst exhibited remarkable corrosion resistance, maintaining stable performance for over 100 h. Theoretical calculations revealed that Mo and V incorporation into NiCoP enhances electron transfer efficiency by modifying the local electronic structure, promoting the HER process effectively. These findings highlight the significant impact of dual metal incorporation in enhancing HER technology, offering a straightforward, efficient, and cost&#8208;effective method for developing advanced electrocatalysts for diverse energy applications.</description>
      <author>Tanu Bagaria, Taranga Borgohain, Swati Jadhav, Tisita Das, Bharati Debnath</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202503368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable&#8208;Photocorrosion Balance Endows ZnCdS Stable Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202506159</link>
      <description>Xinlong Zheng, Yiming Song, Qizhi Gao, Jiaxin Lin, J.P. Zhai, Zhongyun Shao, Jing Li, Daoxiong Wu, Xinlong Tian, Weifeng Liu, Xinlong Tian, Yuhao Liu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410098877

                Abstract Metal sulfide (MS) photocatalysts are highly attracted for visible&#8208;light photocatalytic hydrogen evolution (PHE), yet the ubiquitous issue of photocorrosion significantly undermines their photostability, often viewed as a detrimental effect. In this study, the positive impact of controllable&#8208;photocorrosion is highlighted on enhancing the PHE activity of MS photocatalysts. Specifically, it establish a clear structure&#8208;activity relationship for ZnCdS solid solutions fabricated via a unique sulfur&#8208;rich butyldithiocarbamic acid solution process. During the PHE process, the sulfur&#8208;rich surface of ZnCdS not only efficiently scavenges excess photogenerated holes but also facilitates the accumulation of sulfur produced from the surface layer photocorrosion of CdS. Leveraging the robust Zn&#9472;S chemical bonds, the photocorrosion of the ZnCdS photocatalyst is effectively confined to the Zn&#8208;subsurface region after the fifth cycle in long&#8208;term photostability tests, thus substantially delaying the internal destruction of ZnCdS. Consequently, the PHE rate of ZnCdS reaches 30.12 mmol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 after a long&#8208;term photostability test, representing a 2.5&#8208;fold increase compared to the initial rate.</description>
      <author>Xinlong Zheng, Yiming Song, Qizhi Gao, Jiaxin Lin, J.P. Zhai, Zhongyun Shao, Jing Li, Daoxiong Wu, Xinlong Tian, Weifeng Liu, Xinlong Tian, Yuhao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202506159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into Pd-Nb@In2Se3 Electrocatalyst for High-Performance and Selective CO2 Reduction Reaction from DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics13050146</link>
      <description>Lin Ju, Xiao Tang, Yixin Zhang, Mengya Chen, Shuli Liu, Long Chen, Inorganics. 13(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410099588

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (eCO2RR), driven by renewable energy, represents a promising strategy for mitigating atmospheric CO2 levels while generating valuable fuels and chemicals. Its practical implementation hinges on the development of highly efficient electrocatalysts. In this study, a novel dual-metal atomic catalyst (DAC), composed of niobium and palladium single atoms anchored on a ferroelectric &#945;-In2Se3 monolayer (Nb-Pd@In2Se3), is proposed based on density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The investigation encompassed analyses of structural and electronic characteristics, CO2 adsorption configurations, transition-state energetics, and Gibbs free energy changes during the eCO2RR process, elucidating a synergistic catalytic mechanism. The Nb-Pd@In2Se3 DAC system demonstrates enhanced CO2 activation compared to single-atom counterparts, which is attributed to the complementary roles of Nb and Pd sites. Specifically, Nb atoms primarily drive carbon reduction, while neighboring Pd atoms facilitate oxygen species removal through proton-coupled electron transfer. This dual-site interaction lowers the overall reaction barrier, promoting efficient CO2 conversion. Notably, the polarization switching of the In2Se3 substrate dynamically modulates energy barriers and reaction pathways, thereby influencing product selectivity. Our work provides theoretical guidance for designing ferroelectric-supported DACs for the eCO2RR.</description>
      <author>Lin Ju, Xiao Tang, Yixin Zhang, Mengya Chen, Shuli Liu, Long Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics13050146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Carbon Dioxide Reduction Activity via Local Charge Environment Regulation of Active Sites with Rational Functionalization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01212</link>
      <description>Xinxia Li, Zhou Fang, Xinliang Feng, Zihan Wang, Ya Xu, Yan He, Huifang Li, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410106548

                Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are a new emerging class of electrochemical catalysts for the CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) with fascinating structural tunability. In this work, to dig more detailed information about the effect of local charge environment regulation of active sites via structure modification on the catalytic performance of COFs for CO2RR, the Gibbs free-energy change (&#916;G) of each elementary reaction step involved in the CO2RR and competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) on COF366-Co and its derivatives were examined theoretically. It is observed that the valence band maximum (VBM) energy level of the COFs is increased by incorporation of electron-donating groups, and then the charge distribution on the Co center of COF366-Co is increased due to the increased charge-transfer amount from the electron-occupied N sp2 hybrid orbitals to the empty Co3d orbitals. For incorporating electron-withdrawing groups, the VBM energy level and the d-band center (&#958;d) of the Co atom are downshifted, and the d-band center gets closer to the occupied VBM energy level as the VBM is decreased to a larger extent than the &#958;d. As a result, electrosorption of the intermediate is facilitated and the CO2RR performance is enhanced by such a linker functionalization strategy, especially for electron-withdrawing groups. Our study highlights the key role that controlled local electrical environment via chemical structure modification of COFs can play in regulating the catalytic activity for its CO2RR applications.</description>
      <author>Xinxia Li, Zhou Fang, Xinliang Feng, Zihan Wang, Ya Xu, Yan He, Huifang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemistry of Materials Underpinning Photoelectrochemical Solar Fuel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00258</link>
      <description>Zebulon G. Schichtl, O. Quinn Carvalho, Jeiwan Tan, Simran S. Saund, Debjit Ghoshal, Logan M. Wilder, Melissa K. Gish, Adam C. Nielander, Michaela Burke Stevens, Ann L. Greenaway, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410106879

                Since its inception, photoelectrochemistry has sought to power the generation of fuels, particularly hydrogen, using energy from sunlight. Efficient and durable photoelectrodes, however, remain elusive. Here we review the current state of the art, focusing our discussion on advances in photoelectrodes made in the past decade. We open by briefly discussing fundamental photoelectrochemical concepts and implications for photoelectrode function. We next review a broad range of semiconductor photoelectrodes broken down by material class (oxides, nitrides, chalcogenides, and mature photovoltaic semiconductors), identifying intrinsic properties and discussing their influence on performance. We then identify innovative in situ and operando techniques to directly probe the photoelectrode|electrolyte interface, enabling direct assessment of structure-property relationships for catalytic surfaces in active reaction environments. We close by considering more complex photoelectrochemical fuel-forming reactions (carbon dioxide and nitrogen reduction, as well as alternative oxidation reactions), where product selectivity imposes additional criteria on electrochemical driving force and photoelectrode architecture. By contextualizing recent literature within a fundamental framework, we seek to provide direction for continued progress toward achieving efficient and stable fuel-forming photoelectrodes.</description>
      <author>Zebulon G. Schichtl, O. Quinn Carvalho, Jeiwan Tan, Simran S. Saund, Debjit Ghoshal, Logan M. Wilder, Melissa K. Gish, Adam C. Nielander, Michaela Burke Stevens, Ann L. Greenaway</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can scientists remain internationally visible after the return to their home country? A study of Chinese scientists</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/13662716.2025.2499535</link>
      <description>Ying Zhang, Cornelia Lawson, Liangping Ding, Industry and Innovation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410111374

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Zhang, Cornelia Lawson, Liangping Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/13662716.2025.2499535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphization Induces High-Density Undercoordinated Indium Sites for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Urea Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01055</link>
      <description>Chuhao Liu, Tongtong Yang, Shiyun Li, Yue Wu, Qinyu Jiang, Jisheng Xie, Yifei Xu, Yifan Bu, Cheng Peng, Lipeng Tang, Azhar Mahmood, Jihan Zhou, Bingjun Xu, Hai Xiao, Mufan Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410114519

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chuhao Liu, Tongtong Yang, Shiyun Li, Yue Wu, Qinyu Jiang, Jisheng Xie, Yifei Xu, Yifan Bu, Cheng Peng, Lipeng Tang, Azhar Mahmood, Jihan Zhou, Bingjun Xu, Hai Xiao, Mufan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Design of 1D MOFs as Tunable Single-Atom Catalysts for Water Splitting Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08151</link>
      <description>Mridusmita Sarma, Chandra N. Patra, K. Srinivasu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410115970

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mridusmita Sarma, Chandra N. Patra, K. Srinivasu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial Ligand-Modified PdN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; as Efficient Electrocatalysts for the Two-Electron Oxygen Reduction Reaction: Insights from DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07352</link>
      <description>Zhenze Wang, Weijian Wang, Sanam Attique, Haiyan Zhang, Guiqiu Huang, Wenlin Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410125571

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenze Wang, Weijian Wang, Sanam Attique, Haiyan Zhang, Guiqiu Huang, Wenlin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyrrole Nitrogen Coordination Activates Intrinsically Catalytically Inert Mo for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00970</link>
      <description>L&#252; Shaojie, Shuwen Niu, Jun&#8208;Dong Yi, Jian Zhang, Ge Meng, Yun Yang, Wei Chen, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410127489

                Electronic structure modulation is a promising approach to enhance the properties of intrinsically inert metals in an electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction. Herein, a molybdenum (Mo) single atom (Mo SAs) catalyst with pyrrole-rich nitrogen/oxygen double coordination has been designed and synthesized (defined as Mo SAs/N-C). The pyrrole-nitrogen (Pyrr-N) coordination was shown to effectively regulate the metal-centered electronic structure of Mo. This coordination strategy enables Mo SAs/N-C to exhibit superior catalytic activity and enhanced 4e- transfer selectivity. The electrochemical performance evaluations revealed that Mo SAs/N-C exhibit exceptional durability (with only a 2.0 mV half-wave potential decay after 5000 cycles) and resistance to methanol toxicity, outperforming commercial Pt/C (20%). Notably, as an air-cathode catalyst for zinc-air batteries, Mo SAs/N-C achieved a peak power density of 242 mW cm-2. Combining experimental results with density functional theory calculations, it was found that Pyrr-N effectively modulates the adsorption of OOH* intermediates on Mo atoms, promoting the 4e- transfer pathway and significantly enhancing the performance of the ORR. This study provides valuable insights into the role of Pyrr-N coordination in improving the performance of single-atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>L&#252; Shaojie, Shuwen Niu, Jun&#8208;Dong Yi, Jian Zhang, Ge Meng, Yun Yang, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Molecular Dynamics with Potential and Charge Fluctuations Applied to Au(111) in Alkaline Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00406</link>
      <description>Renata Sechi, Georg Kastlunger, Arghya Bhowmik, Heine Anton Hansen, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410131315

                Electrified solid-liquid interfaces play a crucial role in energy conversion, storage, photoconversion, sensors, and corrosion processes. While computational chemistry simulations can provide detailed insights into reaction mechanisms, aligning experimental and simulation results remains a significant challenge. In this work, we introduce the FDT-SJM method for ab initio molecular dynamics simulations under potential control, where the electrode charge fluctuates around an average value following the fluctuation-dissipation theorem (FDT), and electrode charges are screened by the solvated jellium method (SJM). The FDT-SJM is developed in GPAW, a Python-based open-source DFT code. We validate this approach by simulating the Au(111) interface in pure water, KOH, LiOH, Li, and K solutions at several electrode potentials. We analyze water reorientation in response to changes in the electrode surface charge and demonstrate that the method enables the estimation of interface capacitance and the potential of zero charge, yielding values consistent with experimental data.</description>
      <author>Renata Sechi, Georg Kastlunger, Arghya Bhowmik, Heine Anton Hansen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binding Energies of Molecules Grafted onto Calcium Surfaces: A Periodic DFT Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01160</link>
      <description>Pierre Beaujean, Beno&#305;&#770;t Champagne, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410131339

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pierre Beaujean, Beno&#305;&#770;t Champagne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Mesopores on Ultrathin Hollow Carbon Nanoarchitecture with N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Coordinated Ni Single-Atom Catalysts for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03118</link>
      <description>Donggyun Kim, Ko-Eun Ryou, Godeung Park, Seonghyeon Jung, Jinhyeon Park, Minjun Kim, Ji Eun Jang, Myeongjun Song, Semi Kim, Juyeong Kim, Hyunsoo Lim, Yusuke Yamauchi, Xueyan Feng, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jeonghun Kim, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410131545

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) offer exceptional atomic utilization and catalytic efficiency, particularly in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), where effective mass transport and electronic structure control are critical. However, many SACs suffer from suboptimal hydrogen adsorption energies and limited synergy with the support matrix, which restrict their intrinsic activity and durability. Overcoming these limitations requires an integrated strategy that simultaneously optimizes both the atomic coordination environment and the support architecture. Here, we present a dual-template strategy for synthesizing ultrathin mesoporous hollow carbon (MHC) with tunable mesopores, which enhances ion transport and structural accessibility. Ni single atoms are stabilized within the MHC framework via a tailored N2O2 coordination environment, which fine-tunes the electronic structure of Ni and facilitates efficient hydrogen adsorption and HER kinetics. This coordination environment and the hierarchical porous framework collectively enhance HER activity, significantly reducing the overpotential to 68 mV at 10 mA cm-2 and resulting in remarkable mass activity (5 A mgNi-1 at 50 mV) and enhanced durability over 5000 cycles. Spectroscopic analyses and density functional theory calculations reveal that the N2O2 coordination fine-tunes the electronic structure of Ni, promoting efficient hydrogen adsorption and evolution. These findings highlight the synergistic effects of atomic-level Ni dispersion and tailored support, offering a robust strategy for fabricating single-atom electrocatalysts for sustainable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Donggyun Kim, Ko-Eun Ryou, Godeung Park, Seonghyeon Jung, Jinhyeon Park, Minjun Kim, Ji Eun Jang, Myeongjun Song, Semi Kim, Juyeong Kim, Hyunsoo Lim, Yusuke Yamauchi, Xueyan Feng, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jeonghun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c03118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Activity of Ecofriendly and Earth-Abundant (Zn,Cu)Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; + CuO Nanocomposites for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03062</link>
      <description>Navid Attarzadeh, Keerthi Haritha, Paul Gaurav Nalam, Francelia Sanchez, Kavish Saini, Sreeprasad T. Sreenivasan, Susheng Tan, V. Shutthanandan, Debabrata Das, C.V. Ramana, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410131605

                The projection of sustainable, low-cost, and environmentally friendly energy technologies demands innovation of electrocatalysts utilizing earth-abundant materials. The current study aims to improve the catalytic activity of spinel zinc ferrite (ZF), which is an earth-abundant and economically viable material, via a doping strategy. The spinel ZF shows a weak catalytic activity for water splitting, whereas the substitution of Cu ions at octahedral sites results in improving the catalytic performance in both acidic and basic electrolytes. Structural characterization using high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM) and X-ray diffraction demonstrates that, depending on the Cu concentration, Cu ions either incorporate into spinel Zn-ferrite oxide as doping agents or form CuO nanocomposites, where Cu-induced construction of a composite containing ZCF nanoparticles and CuO nanophase coexists. Substituting Zn with Cu in the octahedral sites of the ZF crystal structure leads to a decrease in the unit cell lattice parameter, and the crystal symmetry is impacted, including the creation of strain and dislocation density. HRTEM analyses provide evidence that the ZF particles nucleate and grow randomly due to the asymmetric reaction dynamics of spinel oxide and the lack of surfactant, while the ZCF nanoparticles are elongated in preferential orientation, forming oriented nanoparticles with a greater surface-to-volume ratio. To attain the current density of 10 mA cm-2, the nanocomposite of the ZCF-50 electrode shows the lowest overpotential of 280 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) among other electrodes. The Tafel slope also decreases significantly in which the nanocomposite of ZCF-50 shows the lowest value of 80 mV dec-1. The measured double-layer capacitance (Cdl) for the nanocomposite structure of ZCF-50 offers the highest value of 27 mF cm-2, which indicates that the nanocomposite contains the largest electrochemically active surface area (ECSA). The catalytic activity of Cu-doped spinel ZCF for hydrogen evolution reaction is also evaluated. The nanocomposite of ZCF-50 shows the lowest onset overpotential of 60 mV compared to 200 mV for the ZF electrode. The obtained Cdl over cathodic potentials for the ZCF-50 electrode shows the highest value of 11.3 mF cm-2 compared with other electrodes. These results confirm that ZCF-50 contains the largest ECSA and highest electrochemical activity. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy studies also demonstrate that the ZCF-50 electrode shows the lowest charge-transfer resistance, indicating that the catalytic OER is improved significantly at its interfaces. We realize that Cu doping into the ferrite structure and the formation of the CuO semishells synergistically can improve interparticle and transparticle charge transfer.</description>
      <author>Navid Attarzadeh, Keerthi Haritha, Paul Gaurav Nalam, Francelia Sanchez, Kavish Saini, Sreeprasad T. Sreenivasan, Susheng Tan, V. Shutthanandan, Debabrata Das, C.V. Ramana</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Confined Fe and Co Atoms Enhances Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503549</link>
      <description>Yunlong Zhang, Jia Zhao, Xiangyu Meng, Xin Bo, Shizheng Zhou, Mingrun Li, Xiaowei Liu, Wei Liu, Jingting Hu, Liang Yu, Dehui Deng, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410132860

                Abstract MoS 2 has emerged as a promising low&#8208;cost candidate for the acidic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, its catalytic performance is limited by the chemical inertness of the dominating MoS 2 &#8208;basal plane. Herein, it is reported that the catalytic activity of MoS 2 for HER can be significantly boosted by the synergy of MoS 2 lattice&#8208;confined Fe and Co atoms (FeCo&#8208;MoS 2 ). The catalyst exhibits a superior activity with a low overpotential of 356 mV at an industrial&#8208;level high current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 , markedly surpassing those of the commercial Pt/C catalyst and previously reported MoS 2 &#8208;based non&#8208;noble metal catalysts, and works stably for over 350 h. Multiple characterizations combined with theoretical calculations demonstrate that the co&#8208;confinement of Fe and Co atoms synergistically optimizes the energy levels of valence electronic states of neighboring sulfur atoms compared with the situations of solely confining Fe or Co, thereby improving the adsorption of protons and facilitating the electron&#8208;transfer kinetics in the Volmer and Heyrovsky steps of HER.</description>
      <author>Yunlong Zhang, Jia Zhao, Xiangyu Meng, Xin Bo, Shizheng Zhou, Mingrun Li, Xiaowei Liu, Wei Liu, Jingting Hu, Liang Yu, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into C&#8211;N Bond Formation through the Coreduction of Nitrite and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Guiding Selectivity Toward C&#8211;N Bond</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07724</link>
      <description>Mohammadreza Karamad, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410138308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammadreza Karamad</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Refilling for Stable Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01382</link>
      <description>Hongzhi Liu, Qiang Zhou, Jun Yu, Mamiko Nakabayashi, Ying-Tsung Lee, Naoya Shibata, Yanbo Li, Jean&#8208;Jacques Delaunay, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410138315

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongzhi Liu, Qiang Zhou, Jun Yu, Mamiko Nakabayashi, Ying-Tsung Lee, Naoya Shibata, Yanbo Li, Jean&#8208;Jacques Delaunay</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying In Situ Activity and Selectivity of Oxygen Reduction Catalysts at the Subparticle Level</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c01902</link>
      <description>Yufei Yao, Hongyang Qu, Zehui Sun, Yequan Chen, Shenglong Yang, Wei Ma, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410138325

                Oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) plays a crucial role in both the chemical and energy industries. Despite substantial advancements in theoretical, computational, and experimental studies, identifying both the in situ activity and selectivity in ORR electrocatalysis remains a major challenge. Here, using a suite of correlative operando scanning electrochemical probe and electrochemiluminescence microscopy techniques, we establish a link between the morphological structure and the local ORR activity and selectivity of single Au and Au@Pt platelets at the subparticle level. It is clearly shown that the edge facets of Au and Au@Pt platelets exhibit higher activity for 4e- ORR compared to basal planes, whereas the basal planes of both Au and Au@Pt platelets demonstrate superior 2e- selectivity relative to the edge facets. These findings deepen our understanding of ORR activity and selectivity across different facets at the subparticle level, which offers valuable guidance for the rational design of highly efficient ORR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yufei Yao, Hongyang Qu, Zehui Sun, Yequan Chen, Shenglong Yang, Wei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c01902</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single&#8208;Atom Iridium Catalysts on Covalent Frameworks: Structural Tuning for Superior Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500045</link>
      <description>Leila Bahri, Fekadu Tsegaye Dajan, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Karim Harrath, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410153879

                Abstract The rational design of active and stable electrodes is crucial for the development of efficient and durable water electrolyzers. However, theoretical studies exploring the structural factors that dictate catalytic activity and dissolution stability remain scarce. This study investigates several factors by examining the trends in activity, stability, and the oxidation state of Ir single atoms during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Using computational methods such as Density Functional Theory (DFT) and Molecular Dynamics (MD) simulations, the structure of Ir single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) is analyzed across a range of oxidation states, which is influenced by electrode potential and environmental pH. The findings indicate that applying potential to Ir SAC&#8208;supported covalent organic framework (COF) in the range of 0.5 &#8764; &lt; U &#8764; &lt; 1.1 can lead to the formation of an OIrOH structure, resulting in outstanding OER activity. Importantly, while applying the electrode potential is not necessary to overcome the potential&#8208;limiting step, it is crucial for the formation and stabilization of the highly active Ir SAC structure. This work offers valuable insights to guide experimental efforts in designing high&#8208;performance Ir SACs with enhanced OER activity.</description>
      <author>Leila Bahri, Fekadu Tsegaye Dajan, Marshet Getaye Sendeku, Karim Harrath</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Synergistic Catalysis in NiP: Dual Role of Electronic Structure and Lewis Acidity for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15050457</link>
      <description>Jiazhou Liang, Jiawei Li, Junrong Yan, Andrew M. Rappe, Jing Yang, Catalysts. 15(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410156533

                Nickel phosphides (NixPy) are recognized as promising alternatives to noble-metal catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). NiP, consisting of the equal stoichiometric ratio of Ni and P, could help quantify the catalytic effect of P and Ni. In this work, density functional theory (DFT) is employed to investigate the OER mechanism on NiP surfaces. We found that P atoms help stabilize O* at the adsorption sites. The rich electron donation from the Ni atom can alter the local charge distribution and enhance the interaction between O* and P atoms. Both oxygen intermediate adsorption energy and OER overpotential exhibit linear correlations with the charge of adsorption sites. Electron loss at the site induces the overall system to exhibit Lewis acidic characteristics, facilitating the OER and leading to a substantial overpotential reduction of up to 0.61 V compared to Lewis basic structures. Leveraging electronic structure theory and Lewis acid&#8211;base theory, we offer a new insight into the OER mechanism on the NiP surface, demonstrating that the catalytic activity of bulk metallic surface materials like NiP can be optimized by tailoring the local surface chemical environment.</description>
      <author>Jiazhou Liang, Jiawei Li, Junrong Yan, Andrew M. Rappe, Jing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15050457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the role of potassium in methane steam reforming using first-principles-based kinetic Monte Carlo simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116203</link>
      <description>Sai Sharath Yadavalli, Glenn Jones, Carlos Fonte, Michail Stamatakis, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410177224

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sai Sharath Yadavalli, Glenn Jones, Carlos Fonte, Michail Stamatakis</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Reconfigured Heterostructure Active Sites on Transition Metal Sulfides Heterojunction for Accelerated Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00902</link>
      <description>Li Huang, Rui Gao, Yunsheng Qiu, Jian Zheng, Wenjing Zhang, Lirong Zheng, Yunfeng Bai, Zhongbo Hu, Tianran Zhang, Xiangfeng Liu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410188613

                Transition metal sulfides (TMSs) are promising noble-metal-free electrocatalysts for electrochemical water splitting due to their distinctive physical and chemical properties, but they usually undergo complicated structure reconfiguration during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Precisely controlling the in situ reconfiguration of TMSs for in situ generation of high-activity real active sites still remains a great challenge. Herein, we propose to in situ reconfigure heterostructure active-sites on transition metal sulfides via heterojunction engineering and achieve high OER performances on (Ni,Fe)S2/MoS2 catalysts. The continuous leaching of Mo and S during electrooxidation induces the reconfiguration, and the strong electronic interaction of (Ni,Fe)S2 and MoS2 generates the special Ni(OH)2/NiOOH/FeOOH heterostructure sites via an asynchronous reconfiguration of Fe and Ni. The (Ni,Fe)S2/MoS2 heterostructure catalyst therefore exhibits excellent OER activity (a small overpotential of 228 mV at 100 mA cm-2) and a low voltage in an alkaline water electrolyzer (1.44 V at 10 mA cm-2), outperforming the homogeneous Mo-free NiFe sulfide catalysts with conventional reconfiguration of Ni-doped FeOOH. This work sheds light on the precise structures design under complicated electrochemical reconstruction and broadens the horizon of reconstruction chemistry to design low-cost and efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Li Huang, Rui Gao, Yunsheng Qiu, Jian Zheng, Wenjing Zhang, Lirong Zheng, Yunfeng Bai, Zhongbo Hu, Tianran Zhang, Xiangfeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00902</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Micro-environments to Macroscopic Effects: How the Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Drives Cu Cathodic Corrosion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07768</link>
      <description>Hori Pada Sarker, Anshuman Goswami, Michael T. Tang, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410192466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hori Pada Sarker, Anshuman Goswami, Michael T. Tang, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07768</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible photo-assisted zinc-air battery achieved by heterojunction structure between oxygen-vacancy-rich CoFe2O4 and nitrogen-doped hollow carbon spheres</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137788</link>
      <description>Xue Liu, Jie Song, Hao Song, H. Zhuo, Wenmiao Chen, Yuexing Zhang, Yanli Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410194916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Liu, Jie Song, Hao Song, H. Zhuo, Wenmiao Chen, Yuexing Zhang, Yanli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable and cost-efficient hydrogen production using platinum clusters at minimal loading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59450-6</link>
      <description>Hongliang Zeng, Zheng Chen, Qiu Jiang, Qiu Zhong, Yuan Ji, Yizhen Chen, Jiawei Li, Chunxiao Liu, Runhao Zhang, Jialin Tang, Xiaoxia Xiong, Zhongyue Zhang, Zhaoyang Chen, Yizhou Dai, Chengbo Li, Yinfang Chen, Donghao Zhao, Xu Li, Tingting Zheng, Xin Xu, Chuan Xia, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410195245

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis stands as a promising technology for sustainable hydrogen production, although its viability hinges on minimizing platinum (Pt) usage without sacrificing catalytic efficiency. Central to this challenge is enhancing the intrinsic activity of Pt while ensuring the stability of the catalyst. We herein present a Mo2TiC2 MXene-supported Pt nanocluster catalyst (Mo2TiC2-PtNC) that requires a minimal Pt content (36 &#956;g cm-2) to function, yet remains highly active and stable. Operando spectroscopy and theoretical simulation provide evidence for anomalous charge transfer from the MXene substrate to PtNC, thus generating highly efficient electron-rich Pt sites for robust hydrogen evolution. When incorporated into a proton exchange membrane electrolyzer, the catalyst affords more than 8700 h at 200 mA cm-2 under ambient temperature with a decay rate of just 2.2 &#956;V h-1. All the performance metrics of the present Mo2TiC2-PtNC catalysts are on par with or even surpass those of current hydrogen evolution electrocatalysts under identical operation conditions, thereby challenging the monopoly of high-loading Pt/C-20% in the current electrolyzer design.</description>
      <author>Hongliang Zeng, Zheng Chen, Qiu Jiang, Qiu Zhong, Yuan Ji, Yizhen Chen, Jiawei Li, Chunxiao Liu, Runhao Zhang, Jialin Tang, Xiaoxia Xiong, Zhongyue Zhang, Zhaoyang Chen, Yizhou Dai, Chengbo Li, Yinfang Chen, Donghao Zhao, Xu Li, Tingting Zheng, Xin Xu, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59450-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bio- and Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Neutral Media: From Mechanisms to Practical Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237267</link>
      <description>Angelo Tricase, Mohsin Muhyuddin, Benjamin Erable, Plamen Atanassov, Deepak Pant, Carlo Santoro, Paolo Bollella, Journal of Power Sources. 646(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410195383

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angelo Tricase, Mohsin Muhyuddin, Benjamin Erable, Plamen Atanassov, Deepak Pant, Carlo Santoro, Paolo Bollella</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of NiMnFeOx Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction Using Galvanic Exchange</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00958-2</link>
      <description>Madis L&#252;si, Heiki Erikson, Helle&#8208;Mai Piirsoo, Arvo Kikas, Vambola Kisand, Kaupo Kukli, Kaido Tammeveski, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410197043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Madis L&#252;si, Heiki Erikson, Helle&#8208;Mai Piirsoo, Arvo Kikas, Vambola Kisand, Kaupo Kukli, Kaido Tammeveski</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00958-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving metal-organic frameworks for highly active oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2025.102046</link>
      <description>Pengqi Yang, Caoyu Yang, Zhengyan Wu, Zhiyong Tang, Matter. 8(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410201973

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengqi Yang, Caoyu Yang, Zhengyan Wu, Zhiyong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2025.102046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#916;-model correction of foundation model based on the model&#8217;s own understanding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0268264</link>
      <description>Mads-Peter V. Christiansen, Bj&#248;rk Hammer, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(18)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410212317

                Foundation models of interatomic potentials, the so called universal potentials, may require fine-tuning or residual corrections when applied to specific subclasses of materials. In the present work, we demonstrate how such an augmentation can be accomplished via &#916;-learning based on the representation already embedded in the universal potentials. The &#916;-model introduced is a Gaussian Process Regression (GPR) model, and various types of aggregation (global, species-separated, and atomic) of the representation vector are discussed. Employing a specific universal potential, CHGNet [Deng et al., Nat. Mach. Intell. 5, 1031 (2023)], in a global structure optimization setting, we find that it correctly describes the energetics of the &#8220;8&#8221; Cu oxide, which is an ultra-thin oxide film on Cu(111). The universal potential model even predicts a more favorable structure compared with that discussed in recent density functional theory-based literature. Moving to sulfur adatom overlayers on Cu(111), Ag(111), and Au(111), the CHGNet model, however, requires corrections. We demonstrate that these are efficiently provided via the GPR-based &#916;-model formulated on CHGNet&#8217;s own internal atomic embedding representation. The need for corrections is tracked to the scarcity of metal&#8211;sulfur atomic environments in the materials project database that CHGNet is trained on, leading to an overreliance on sulfur&#8211;sulfur atomic environments. Other universal potentials trained on the same data, MACE-MP0, SevenNet-0, and ORB-v2-only-MPtrj, show a similar behavior but with varying degrees of error, demonstrating the general need for augmentation schemes for universal potential models.</description>
      <author>Mads-Peter V. Christiansen, Bj&#248;rk Hammer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0268264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials Learning Algorithms (MALA): Scalable machine learning for electronic structure calculations in large-scale atomistic simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109654</link>
      <description>Attila Cangi, Lenz Fiedler, Bartosz Brzoza, Karan Shah, Timothy J. Callow, Daniel Kotik, Steve Schmerler, Matthew C. Barry, James Goff, Andrew Rohskopf, Dayton J. Vogel, Normand A. Modine, Aidan P. Thompson, Sivasankaran Rajamanickam, Computer Physics Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410218316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Attila Cangi, Lenz Fiedler, Bartosz Brzoza, Karan Shah, Timothy J. Callow, Daniel Kotik, Steve Schmerler, Matthew C. Barry, James Goff, Andrew Rohskopf, Dayton J. Vogel, Normand A. Modine, Aidan P. Thompson, Sivasankaran Rajamanickam</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the regulation of ScCl2 electrocatalytic activity through functionalization with H, O, and F</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.027</link>
      <description>Yusheng Wang, Yongqi Zhang, Nahong Song, Juanjuan Wang, Bin Xu, Fei Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 136(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410218655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yusheng Wang, Yongqi Zhang, Nahong Song, Juanjuan Wang, Bin Xu, Fei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.05.027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing the Overall H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Selectivity of Metal Dichalcogenide Electrocatalysts for the Two-Electron Oxygen Reduction Reaction Using Microkinetic Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01079</link>
      <description>Ipsita Mondal, Hongyuan Sheng, Kwanpyung Lee, Song Jin, J. R. Schmidt, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410226531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ipsita Mondal, Hongyuan Sheng, Kwanpyung Lee, Song Jin, J. R. Schmidt</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom Pd boosted Cu catalysts for ethanol dehydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actphy.2025.100100</link>
      <description>Lele Feng, Xueying Bai, Jifeng Pang, Hongchen Cao, Xiaoyan Liu, Wenhao Luo, Xiaofeng Yang, Pengfei Wu, Mingyuan Zheng, Acta Physico-Chimica Sinica. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410230321

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lele Feng, Xueying Bai, Jifeng Pang, Hongchen Cao, Xiaoyan Liu, Wenhao Luo, Xiaofeng Yang, Pengfei Wu, Mingyuan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actphy.2025.100100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing the understanding and prediction accuracy of molecular adsorption energy with artificial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.195413</link>
      <description>Wen Liu, Ning Xu, Zheng Li, Meiliang Ma, Xiaojuan Hu, Zhongkang Han, Ying Jiang, Wentao Yuan, Hangsheng Yang, Sergey V. Levchenko, Yong Wang, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(19)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410233178

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Liu, Ning Xu, Zheng Li, Meiliang Ma, Xiaojuan Hu, Zhongkang Han, Ying Jiang, Wentao Yuan, Hangsheng Yang, Sergey V. Levchenko, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.195413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halide Perovskite Photocatalysts for Clean Fuel Production and Organic Synthesis: Opportunities and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202419603</link>
      <description>Siddharth Singh, Zeinab Hamid, Ramavath Babu, Sergio G&#243;mez&#8208;Gra&#241;a, Xiaowen Hu, Iain McCulloch, Robert L. Z. Hoye, Vishal Govind Rao, Lakshminarayana Polavarapu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410240350

                Abstract The need to constrain the use of fossil fuels causing global warming is motivating the development of a variety of photocatalysts for solar&#8208;to&#8208;fuel generation and chemical synthesis. In particular, semiconductor&#8208;based photocatalysts have been extensively exploited in solar&#8208;driven organic synthesis, carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) conversion into value&#8208;added products, and hydrogen (H 2 ) generation from water (H 2 O) splitting. Recently, metal halide perovskites (MHPs) have emerged as an important class of semiconductors for heterogeneous photocatalysis owing to their interesting properties. Despite key issues with long&#8208;term stability and degradation in polar solvents due to their ionic character, there has been significant progress in halide perovskite&#8208;based photocatalysts with improving their stability and performance in the gas and liquid phases. This review discusses the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art for using halide perovskite&#8208;based photocatalysts and photoelectrocatalysis in hydrogen production from water and halogen acid solutions, CO 2 reduction into value&#8208;added chemicals, and various organic chemical transformations. The different types of halide perovskites used, design strategies to overcome the instability issues in polar solvents, and the efficiencies achieved are discussed. Furthermore, the outstanding challenges associated with the use of polar electrolytes and how the stability and performance can be improved are discussed.</description>
      <author>Siddharth Singh, Zeinab Hamid, Ramavath Babu, Sergio G&#243;mez&#8208;Gra&#241;a, Xiaowen Hu, Iain McCulloch, Robert L. Z. Hoye, Vishal Govind Rao, Lakshminarayana Polavarapu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202419603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum Nanoparticles on Metalloid Antimony Functionalized Graphitic Nanoplatelets for Enhanced Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501408</link>
      <description>Do Hyung Kweon, Jaehoon Baek, Sung O Park, Hyuk&#8208;Jun Noh, Jong&#8208;Pil Jeon, Jeong Hyeon Lee, Tae Joo Shin, Sang Kyu Kwak, In&#8208;Yup Jeon, Jong&#8208;Beom Baek, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410240741

                Abstract Platinum (Pt) nanoparticles are considered to be the most efficient catalyst for acidic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, they are expensive and unstable, because of agglomeration and Ostwald ripening. It is critically necessary for developing a better catalytic support to stabilize the Pt nanoparticles at low loading amounts. One efficient route to improving both catalytic activity and durability is metal catalysts stably anchored on heteroatom functionalized carbon supports via their strong interactions. Nevertheless, the interactions between &#8220;metallic&#8221; catalysts and &#8220;nonmetallic&#8221; heteroatom functionalized carbon supports are still unsatisfactory. Here, &#8220;metalloid&#8221; antimony (Sb) functionalized graphitic nanoplatelets (SbGnP) are reported to stably anchor Pt nanoparticles. The resulting Pt@SbGnP catalyst shows a record high acidic HER performance, attributable to the unique nature of Sb functional groups on SbGnP. Unlike typical low&#8208;period nonmetallic heteroatoms on carbon supports, high&#8208;period metalloid Sb with various oxidation states of SbO x provided strong binding sites to stably anchor Pt nanoparticles, suppressing particle aggregation, and thus sustaining catalytic activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Do Hyung Kweon, Jaehoon Baek, Sung O Park, Hyuk&#8208;Jun Noh, Jong&#8208;Pil Jeon, Jeong Hyeon Lee, Tae Joo Shin, Sang Kyu Kwak, In&#8208;Yup Jeon, Jong&#8208;Beom Baek</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging generative models with periodicity-aware, invertible and invariant representations for crystalline materials design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00797-7</link>
      <description>Zhilong Wang, Fengqi You, Nature Computational Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410242322

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhilong Wang, Fengqi You</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00797-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity&#8208;Selectivity Trends in Electrochemical Urea Synthesis: Co&#8208;Reduction of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Nitrates Over Single&#8208;Site Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202501882</link>
      <description>Qinglan Zhao, Yushen Liu, Yuan Zhang, Shangqian Zhu, Hongming Xu, Mohammad Farhadpour, Fei Xiao, Minghui Xing, Dapeng Cao, Xueping Qin, Tejs Vegge, Minhua Shao, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410246678

                Abstract Electrochemical co&#8208;reduction of carbon dioxide and nitrates (CO 2 NO 3 RR) holds promise for sustainable urea production. However, the sluggish kinetics of the sixteen&#8208;electron transfer and unclear mechanistic understanding strongly impede its development. Here, combined experimental and computational approaches are employed to screen a series of metal phthalocyanine as model catalysts (MPcs, M = Zn, Co, Ni, Cu, and Fe) to uncover the activity&#8208;selectivity trends in electrochemical CO 2 NO 3 RR. The theoretical simulations reveal that the thermodynamics of urea synthesis is significantly influenced by key intermediates, where the enhanced adsorption of *HOOCNO, coupled with reduced adsorptions of *N and *COOH, and moderate adsorption of *H 2 O, can significantly promote the urea production. &#916;G *HOOCNO &#8722;&#916;G *N &#8722;&#916;G *COOH +&#916;G *H2O as a potential descriptor is proposed for predicting the efficiency of CO 2 NO 3 RR toward urea formation. The findings provide systematic guidance for the future design of high&#8208;efficiency catalysts for urea electrosynthesis, addressing a crucial need for sustainable nitrogen fixation.</description>
      <author>Qinglan Zhao, Yushen Liu, Yuan Zhang, Shangqian Zhu, Hongming Xu, Mohammad Farhadpour, Fei Xiao, Minghui Xing, Dapeng Cao, Xueping Qin, Tejs Vegge, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202501882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Study of Axial Coordination Cu-porphyrin for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40242-025-5035-7</link>
      <description>Z. Xu, Yifan Zhang, Yaqiong Su, Chemical Research in Chinese Universities. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410252352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Z. Xu, Yifan Zhang, Yaqiong Su</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40242-025-5035-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and chemistry of uranium dioxide (UO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1045" altimg="si83.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;2&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;) in water from first-principles molecular dynamics simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136827</link>
      <description>G. Rodrik, Yann Foucaud, Bertrand Siboulet, Magali Duvail, St&#233;phanie Szenknect, Jean&#8208;Fran&#231;ois Dufr&#234;che, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410255792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. Rodrik, Yann Foucaud, Bertrand Siboulet, Magali Duvail, St&#233;phanie Szenknect, Jean&#8208;Fran&#231;ois Dufr&#234;che</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of local coordination microenvironment in regulating CO2 electroreduction catalyzed by Cr-corrole-based single-atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137856</link>
      <description>Lei Yang, Bin Li, Ruoya Wang, Meng Yang, Yuling Tang, Haiyan Wang, Chun Zhu, Jinxia Liang, Jun Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410255807

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Yang, Bin Li, Ruoya Wang, Meng Yang, Yuling Tang, Haiyan Wang, Chun Zhu, Jinxia Liang, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin-state-regulated dual-metal orbital engineering in heterostructured nanosheets for d-band center-optimized electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137850</link>
      <description>Mengmeng Guo, Xianda Han, Hui Feng, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Wenzhi Zhang, Yue Li, Guohua Dong, Dongxuan Guo, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410255898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengmeng Guo, Xianda Han, Hui Feng, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Wenzhi Zhang, Yue Li, Guohua Dong, Dongxuan Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137850</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Co and Mn Doping on the Surface Reconstruction of Faceted NiO(111) Nanosheets after the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00493</link>
      <description>Konstantin K. R&#252;cker, Dereje H. Taffa, Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Marcel Risch, Darius Hayes, Elliot Brim, Ryan M. Richards, Corinna Harms, Michael Wark, Julian Lorenz, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410258698

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Konstantin K. R&#252;cker, Dereje H. Taffa, Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Marcel Risch, Darius Hayes, Elliot Brim, Ryan M. Richards, Corinna Harms, Michael Wark, Julian Lorenz</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine&#8208;Learning&#8208;Based Design of Metallocene Catalysts for Controlled Olefin Copolymerization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202500316</link>
      <description>Yongjun Kim, Yeonjoon Kim, Hyeonsu Kim, Sungwoo Kang, Jaewook Kim, Kyung-Hoon Lee, Wook Jeong, Won Jong Lee, Ho Ryu, Kyungwoo Kim, Woo Youn Kim, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410168918

                Abstract Polyolefins are versatile materials for various purposes, but their functionality should be fine&#8208;tuned for target applications including the mitigation of adverse environmental impacts. Producing such polymers with desired properties requires catalysts that can control polymerization at an atomistic level. However, complex reaction mechanisms and very limited experimental data make it difficult to design new efficient catalysts using conventional computational and data&#8208;driven approaches. Here, we present a pragmatic strategy based on data&#8208;efficient predictive models combined with a genetic algorithm to design new catalysts for controlled ethylene/hexene copolymerization. By deriving the chemically intuitive descriptors from the mechanistic analysis of the polymerization, we achieved the promising predictive models with small data applicable to various core structures and different experimental conditions, respectively. We screened catalysts through a virtual screening scheme combining a genetic algorithm and predictive models using chemically intuitive descriptors and considered their synthesizability through the manual inspections of experts. As a result, we successfully designed nine catalysts with desired comonomer ratios and diverse core structures.</description>
      <author>Yongjun Kim, Yeonjoon Kim, Hyeonsu Kim, Sungwoo Kang, Jaewook Kim, Kyung-Hoon Lee, Wook Jeong, Won Jong Lee, Ho Ryu, Kyungwoo Kim, Woo Youn Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202500316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrifying amine carbon capture with robust redox-tunable acids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59732-z</link>
      <description>Xing Li, Charles B. Musgrave, Andong Liu, Junyang Meng, Jihan Zhang, William A. Goddard, Yayuan Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410224916

                Electrochemically mediated carbon capture presents an energy-efficient and cost-effective strategy to combat climate change due to its ability to utilize renewable energy and operate at ambient conditions. However, many current approaches suffer from operational instability and limited scalability potential due to a lack of reliable, low-cost redox-active absorbent materials. Here, we introduce a class of chemically robust and economical redox-tunable Br&#248;nsted acids to electrify amine carbon capture. The redox-tunable acids exhibit a reversible tunability in pKa spanning over 20 units in organic solvents in response to electrochemical potential, thereby enabling the regeneration of classic amines for CO2 separation via proton-coupled electron transfer. Remarkably, the RAs maintain their chemical integrity for over 400 h of operation in a symmetric carbon capture flow cell under 10% CO2 and 21% O2 at ambient temperature and pressure. By harnessing electrification, our approach can effectively mitigate shortcomings inherent to thermochemical carbon capture processes, facilitating a more sustainable drop-in replacement for incumbent amine scrubbing.</description>
      <author>Xing Li, Charles B. Musgrave, Andong Liu, Junyang Meng, Jihan Zhang, William A. Goddard, Yayuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-59732-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular catalyst and co-catalyst systems based on transition metal complexes for the electrochemical oxidation of alcohols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cc01497b</link>
      <description>M. Morrow, Charles W. Machan, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410242301

                Selected molecular catalyst systems for electrochemical alcohol oxidation are highlighted, including co-catalyst systems with redox mediators. Structural and activity trends are examined, with a focus on future catalyst system development principles.</description>
      <author>M. Morrow, Charles W. Machan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cc01497b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of machine learning interatomic potentials in heterogeneous catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116202</link>
      <description>Gbolagade Olajide, Khagendra Baral, Sophia Ezendu, Ademola Soyemi, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410246182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gbolagade Olajide, Khagendra Baral, Sophia Ezendu, Ademola Soyemi, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological Descriptors for the Electron Density of Inorganic Solids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c00390</link>
      <description>Nathan J. Szymanski, Alexander Smith, Pr&#243;dromos Daoutidis, Christopher J. Bartel, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410124237

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nathan J. Szymanski, Alexander Smith, Pr&#243;dromos Daoutidis, Christopher J. Bartel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c00390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Fluorescence Imaging of Oxygen Evolution on Epitaxial Perovskite Films with Composition Gradients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00702</link>
      <description>Daniel J. Zheng, Haldrian Iriawan, Rohit Pant, C. John Eom, Hongbin Xu, Jiayu Peng, Cat Arase, Ichiro Takeuchi, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410231358

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel J. Zheng, Haldrian Iriawan, Rohit Pant, C. John Eom, Hongbin Xu, Jiayu Peng, Cat Arase, Ichiro Takeuchi, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and dynamics of CO2 absorption in aqueous potassium lysinate solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.127749</link>
      <description>Uttama Mukherjee, Prabhat Prakash, Arun Venkatnathan, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4410230237

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Uttama Mukherjee, Prabhat Prakash, Arun Venkatnathan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.127749</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
