<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 01:28:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature-dependent kinetic analysis of direct air capture using a gravimetric approach in porous environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10450-025-00615-6</link>
      <description>Yongqiang Wang, Dan Zhao, Gang Kevin Li, Adsorption. 31(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409128746

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongqiang Wang, Dan Zhao, Gang Kevin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10450-025-00615-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering cobalt coordination environment with dual heteroatom doping for boosting urea-assisted hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135161</link>
      <description>Xueqing Pan, Jiaxiang Qiu, Siyuan Tang, Quanjiang Lv, Jianling Dong, Nan Jiang, Luyu Liu, Yangyang Wan, Xinchun Yang, Jian Han, Fuzhan Song, Fuel. 395(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409132377

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xueqing Pan, Jiaxiang Qiu, Siyuan Tang, Quanjiang Lv, Jianling Dong, Nan Jiang, Luyu Liu, Yangyang Wan, Xinchun Yang, Jian Han, Fuzhan Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Enhancement of the Activity and Durability of the Oxygen Reduction Reaction via Pd&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Mo@Pt/C Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c19839</link>
      <description>Jaeyoung Yoo, Chen&#8208;Hui Chan, Su-Yeon Choi, Doosun Hong, Sae Yane Paek, Kihoon Bang, Jong Min Kim, Dong-Hun Kim, Sang Soo Han, Hyuck Mo Lee, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409140722

                To overcome the limitations of conventional bimetallic catalysts in facilitating the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), we employed density functional theory (DFT) screening to evaluate ternary Pd3X@Pt core@shell catalysts (X = transition metals), with the objective of increasing both the ORR activity and durability. Among the 25 candidates, Pd3Mo@Pt emerges as the most promising catalyst, showing a combination of a low limiting potential and a high dissolution potential. Experimental validation reveals that the carbon-supported Pd3Mo@Pt/C catalysts clearly exhibit exceptional mass activity (3.76 A mgPt-1) and specific activity (1.67 mA cm-2); these activities significantly surpass those of their Pt/C counterparts by factors of 10.2 and 3.18, respectively. Furthermore, these core@shell catalysts exhibit robust durability, while also exhibiting enhanced CO tolerance, as evidenced by CO stripping voltammetry. DFT calculations show that the superior activity and stability of Pd3Mo@Pt/C are attributed to the optimal modulation of the Pt surface electronic structures by the core elements, particularly Mo.</description>
      <author>Jaeyoung Yoo, Chen&#8208;Hui Chan, Su-Yeon Choi, Doosun Hong, Sae Yane Paek, Kihoon Bang, Jong Min Kim, Dong-Hun Kim, Sang Soo Han, Hyuck Mo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c19839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation on the photocatalytic properties of SiI2/InSe and SiI2/InTe heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solener.2025.113487</link>
      <description>Ruyang Yan, Yuqi Wang, Yan Cong, Xumin Yang, Nan Zhang, Xiaobo Ma, Jie Wang, Xugang Huang, Zhaogang Liu, Qing Lv, Hongsheng Zhao, Huanming Chen, Solar Energy. 293(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409146356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruyang Yan, Yuqi Wang, Yan Cong, Xumin Yang, Nan Zhang, Xiaobo Ma, Jie Wang, Xugang Huang, Zhaogang Liu, Qing Lv, Hongsheng Zhao, Huanming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solener.2025.113487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Activity of Transition Metal Oxides for the Electrochemical N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxidation to Nitrate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07924</link>
      <description>Haldrian Iriawan, Graham Leverick, Bar&#305;&#351; Alkan, Daniel Delgado, John Eom, Hongbin Xu, Sunmoon Yu, Livia Giordano, Annette Trunschke, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409146723

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haldrian Iriawan, Graham Leverick, Bar&#305;&#351; Alkan, Daniel Delgado, John Eom, Hongbin Xu, Sunmoon Yu, Livia Giordano, Annette Trunschke, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing machine learning for high-entropy alloy catalysis: a focus on adsorption energy prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01579-5</link>
      <description>Qi Wang, Yonggang Yao, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409150968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Wang, Yonggang Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01579-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging data mining, active learning, and domain adaptation for efficient discovery of advanced oxygen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adr9038</link>
      <description>Rui Ding, Jianguo Liu, Kang Hua, Xuebin Wang, Xiaoben Zhang, Minhua Shao, Yuxin Chen, Junhong Chen, Science Advances. 11(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409157280

                Developing advanced catalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for sustainable hydrogen production. This study presents a multistage machine learning (ML) approach to streamline the discovery and optimization of complex multimetallic catalysts. Our method integrates data mining, active learning, and domain adaptation throughout the materials discovery process. Unlike traditional trial-and-error methods, this approach systematically narrows the exploration space using domain knowledge with minimized reliance on subjective intuition. Then, the active learning module efficiently refines element composition and synthesis conditions through iterative experimental feedback. The process culminated in the discovery of a promising Ru-Mn-Ca-Pr oxide catalyst. Our workflow also enhances theoretical simulations with domain adaptation strategy, providing deeper mechanistic insights aligned with experimental findings. By leveraging diverse data sources and multiple ML strategies, we demonstrate an efficient pathway for electrocatalyst discovery and optimization. This comprehensive, data-driven approach represents a paradigm shift and potentially benchmark in electrocatalysts research.</description>
      <author>Rui Ding, Jianguo Liu, Kang Hua, Xuebin Wang, Xiaoben Zhang, Minhua Shao, Yuxin Chen, Junhong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adr9038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the linear scaling limit in multi-electron-transfer electrocatalysis through intermediate spillover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01323-8</link>
      <description>Qilun Wang, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Kejie Lao, Xiang Huang, Fuhua Li, Hua Bing Tao, Hong Bin Yang, Wei Liu, Weijue Wang, Yaqi Cheng, Nozomu Hiraoka, Liping Zhang, Junming Zhang, Yuhang Liu, Jiazang Chen, Yinghua Xu, Chenliang Su, Jingguang G. Chen, Bin Liu, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409162162

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qilun Wang, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Kejie Lao, Xiang Huang, Fuhua Li, Hua Bing Tao, Hong Bin Yang, Wei Liu, Weijue Wang, Yaqi Cheng, Nozomu Hiraoka, Liping Zhang, Junming Zhang, Yuhang Liu, Jiazang Chen, Yinghua Xu, Chenliang Su, Jingguang G. Chen, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01323-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic, Photoelectrocatalytic, and Photocatalytic Performance Parameters and Their Measurement Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837675838-00068</link>
      <description>Narinder Singh, Sonika Sonika, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409162166

                In this chapter, key parameters, such as specific surface area, porosity, energy density (E), power density (P), cyclic stability, coulombic efficiency, power conversion efficiency (PCE, &#951;), short circuit current (ISC), open circuit voltage (VOC), fill factor (FF), external quantum efficiency (EQE), internal quantum efficiency (IQE), apparent quantum efficiency (AQE), band gap, solar energy to H2 conversion efficiency (STH), and solar energy to ammonia conversion efficiency (STA) are explained. The characterization techniques used for measuring these parameters are discussed in detail.</description>
      <author>Narinder Singh, Sonika Sonika</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837675838-00068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-4 nm Ru-RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Schottky Nanojunction as a Catalyst for Durable Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c01876</link>
      <description>Yuxiang Song, Wanghui Zhao, Zhi Wang, Weili Shi, Feiyang Zhang, Zhuoming Wei, Xin Cui, Yihan Zhu, Tao Wang, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409162565

                RuO2 with high intrinsic activity for water oxidation is a promising alternative to IrO2 in proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, but it suffers from long-term stability issues due to overoxidation. Here, we report a sub-4 nm Ru-RuO2 Schottky nanojunction (Ru-RuO2-SN) prepared by a microwave reaction that exhibits high activity and long-term stability in both three-electrode systems and PEM devices. The lattice strain and charge transfer induced by the metal-oxide SN increase the work function of the Ru-RuO2-SN, optimize the local electronic structure, and reduce the desorption energy of the metal site to the oxygen-containing intermediates; as a result, it leads to the oxide path mechanism (OPM) and inhibits the excessive oxidation of surface ruthenium. The Ru-RuO2-SN requires only 165 mV overpotential to obtain 10 mA&#183;cm-2 with 1400 h stability without obvious activity degradation, achieving a stability number (6.7 &#215; 106) matching iridium-based catalysts. In a PEM electrolyzer with Ru-RuO2-SN as an anode catalyst, only 1.6 V is needed to reach 1.0 A&#183;cm-2 and it shows long-term stability at 100 mA&#183;cm-2 for 1100 h and at 500 mA&#183;cm-2 for 100 h. The reaction mechanism for the high stability of Ru-RuO2-SN was analyzed by density functional theory calculations. This work reports a durable, pure Ru-based water-oxidation catalyst and provides a new perspective for the development of efficient Ru-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuxiang Song, Wanghui Zhao, Zhi Wang, Weili Shi, Feiyang Zhang, Zhuoming Wei, Xin Cui, Yihan Zhu, Tao Wang, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c01876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EFFECT OF Rh DOPING ON THE ACTIVITY OF THE OXYGEN RELEASE REACTION ON BaTiO3(001) SURFACES</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52676/1729-7885-2025-1-140-147</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, U. Zh. Tolegen, &#1060;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Talgat M. Inerbaev, S. A. Nurkenov, Zh. Ye. Zakiyeva, G. A. Kaptagay, NNC RK Bulletin. None(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409162859

                Photoinduced splitting of water using photocatalysts in the form of nanoparticles is a promising and simple way to produce environmentally friendly hydrogen. In this paper, we investigate the potential of modified barium titanate (BaTiO 3 ), an inexpensive perovskite oxide obtained from precursors widely distributed on earth, to develop effective electrocatalysts for water oxidation using first-principles calculations. It has been shown that the BaTiO 3 (001) surface terminated with TiO 2 is more promising in terms of its use as a catalyst. After replacing Ti with Rh, the dopant ion can take over part of the electron density from neighboring oxygen ions. As a result, during the oxidation reaction of water, rhodium ions can be in an intermediate oxidation state between 3+ and 4+. This affects the adsorption energy of the reaction intermediates on the surface of the catalyst, reducing the excess potential.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, U. Zh. Tolegen, &#1060;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Talgat M. Inerbaev, S. A. Nurkenov, Zh. Ye. Zakiyeva, G. A. Kaptagay</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52676/1729-7885-2025-1-140-147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The competitive influence of the intramolecular electric field and hydrophilic active sites of D&#8211;A conjugated porous polymers on photocatalytic hydrogen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta00518c</link>
      <description>Yongzhen Yang, Fei Zhao, Xinyi Feng, Jinsheng Zhao, Zhen Xu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409165647

                Conjugated porous polymers (CPPs) with a donor&#8211;acceptor (D&#8211;A) molecular structure usually exhibit good photocatalytic hydrogen evolution (PHE).</description>
      <author>Yongzhen Yang, Fei Zhao, Xinyi Feng, Jinsheng Zhao, Zhen Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta00518c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon cloth-supported high-entropy transition metal selenides as high-performance oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136819</link>
      <description>Changyu Hu, Xiaoyu Liu, Guoping Han, Cheng Chen, Hu Liu, Wen&#8208;Hao Zhou, Huidong Xie, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409166333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changyu Hu, Xiaoyu Liu, Guoping Han, Cheng Chen, Hu Liu, Wen&#8208;Hao Zhou, Huidong Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wavelength-Resolving Catalytic Turnover Frequencies and Identifying Alternate Proton Donors in Solar-Fuel-Forming Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07140</link>
      <description>Daiki Nishiori, Lillian K. Hensleigh, Nghi P. Nguyen, I. R. Peterson, Gary F. Moore, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409168141

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daiki Nishiori, Lillian K. Hensleigh, Nghi P. Nguyen, I. R. Peterson, Gary F. Moore</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal-decorated Zr12O12 nanocages as single-atom catalysts for water splitting: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.403</link>
      <description>Sajjad Hussain, Abdulaziz A. Al&#8208;Saadi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 122(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409169946

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajjad Hussain, Abdulaziz A. Al&#8208;Saadi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrical Dynamics and Havriliak-Negami Dielectric Relaxation Behavior of FeNi2O4 Electromagnetic Spinel Nickelate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.04.025</link>
      <description>Muhammad Javed, Y. Moualhi, Naeem Akbar, Asad Masood, Thamer Alomayri, S.A. Muhammed Ali, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409171226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Javed, Y. Moualhi, Naeem Akbar, Asad Masood, Thamer Alomayri, S.A. Muhammed Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2025.04.025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melting, Bubblelike Expansion, and Explosion of Superheated Plasmonic Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.136101</link>
      <description>Simon Dold, Thomas Reichenbach, Alessandro Colombo, Jakob Jordan, Ingo Barke, Patrick Behrens, Nils Bernhardt, Jonathan Correa, S. D&#776;usterer, Benjamin Erk, Thomas Fennel, Linos Hecht, Andrea Heilrath, Robert Irsig, N. Iwe, Patrice Kolb, Bj&#246;rn Kruse, Bruno Langbehn, Bastian Manschwetus, Philipp Marienhagen, Franklin Martinez, K.&#8208;H. Meiwes&#8208;Broer, Kevin R. Oldenburg, Christopher Passow, Christian Peltz, Mario Sauppe, Fabian Seel, Rico Mayro P. Tanyag, R. Treusch, Anatoli Ulmer, Saida Walz, Michael Moseler, Thomas M&#246;ller, Daniela Rupp, Bernd von Issendorff, Physical Review Letters. 134(13)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409177514

                We report on time-resolved coherent diffraction imaging of gas-phase silver nanoparticles, strongly heated via their plasmon resonance. The x-ray diffraction images reveal a broad range of phenomena for different excitation strengths, from simple melting over strong cavitation to explosive disintegration. Molecular dynamics simulations fully reproduce this behavior and show that the heating induces rather similar trajectories through the phase diagram in all cases, with the very different outcomes resulting solely from whether and where the stability limit of the metastable superheated liquid is crossed. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>Simon Dold, Thomas Reichenbach, Alessandro Colombo, Jakob Jordan, Ingo Barke, Patrick Behrens, Nils Bernhardt, Jonathan Correa, S. D&#776;usterer, Benjamin Erk, Thomas Fennel, Linos Hecht, Andrea Heilrath, Robert Irsig, N. Iwe, Patrice Kolb, Bj&#246;rn Kruse, Bruno Langbehn, Bastian Manschwetus, Philipp Marienhagen, Franklin Martinez, K.&#8208;H. Meiwes&#8208;Broer, Kevin R. Oldenburg, Christopher Passow, Christian Peltz, Mario Sauppe, Fabian Seel, Rico Mayro P. Tanyag, R. Treusch, Anatoli Ulmer, Saida Walz, Michael Moseler, Thomas M&#246;ller, Daniela Rupp, Bernd von Issendorff</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.136101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the ORR performance of rice husk carbon-supported iron porphyrin catalyst through synergistic effects of doped secondary heteroatoms (S, P) in whole pH range</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.352</link>
      <description>Chen Ling, Kun Fang, Y. X. Lv, Shi-Fu He, Guo&#8208;Chao Liang, Xinyan Xiao, Haiyang Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 123(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409181221

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Ling, Kun Fang, Y. X. Lv, Shi-Fu He, Guo&#8208;Chao Liang, Xinyan Xiao, Haiyang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction Activates Non&#8208;Noble Metal Cathode for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202405846</link>
      <description>Rui Wu, Heng Liu, Jie Xu, Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, You&#8208;Yi Qin, Xusheng Zheng, Junfa Zhu, Hao Li, Xiaozhi Su, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409181257

                Abstract Hydrogen generation via a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer manifests the vertex of fundamental and practical studies on technology transferring electricity into hydrogen fuels. However, the harsh working conditions, especially the strong reductive acidic electrolyte&#8208;catalyst interface, make non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based cathodes unsuitable for PEM electrolyzer. Here, a scale&#8208;up application of F modified CoP (CoP|F) cathode is demonstrated from 0.2 cm 2 lab&#8208;scale three&#8208;electrode setup to a commercial 38 cm 2 PEM electrolyzer. The operando X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and Raman results confirm that F modification can promote the breakage of Co&#9472;P bonds, reconstructed to amorphous metallic Co as true HER active sites. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the presence of F in the CoP 1&#8208;x lattice would lead to a more facile formation of P&#8208;vacancy under HER conditions, leading to more active zerovalent Co active sites for HER. This reconstructed surface shows high activity and tolerance in the reductive acidic electrolyte&#8208;catalyst interface. When used as a cathode in a commercial PEM electrolyzer, its performance is comparable to the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art Pt/C catalyst, with a calculated hydrogen cost to be 2.17 $ kg H2 &#8722;1 . This work suggests a surface&#8208;reconstruction pathway to fabricate cost&#8208;saving and durable non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based cathodes for commercial PEM electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Rui Wu, Heng Liu, Jie Xu, Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, You&#8208;Yi Qin, Xusheng Zheng, Junfa Zhu, Hao Li, Xiaozhi Su, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202405846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkages conversion of imine to amide promotes photocatalytic overall water splitting in Two-Dimensional covalent organic frameworks: The role of polarity effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116118</link>
      <description>Liqun Song, Zhonghai Lin, Zhihua Zhang, Yingcai Fan, Mingwen Zhao, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409186973

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liqun Song, Zhonghai Lin, Zhihua Zhang, Yingcai Fan, Mingwen Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serrated Leaf&#8208;Like N&#8208;Doped Copper Sulfide Enabling Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction/Evolution via Dual&#8208;Mode Cathode Reactions for High Energy Density and Cycle Stability in Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202413425</link>
      <description>Do Hwan Jung, Yong Hak Park, Dong Won Kim, Jong Hui Choi, Sung June Cho, Keon&#8208;Han Kim, Dong Gyu Park, Byungchan Han, Jeung Ku Kang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409187498

                Abstract Zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) are promising electrochemical energy storages, but inefficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) during discharging and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) during charging at their cathodes impede achieving high energy density and stable cycling. We report a serrated leaf&#8208;like nitrogen&#8208;doped copper sulfide (N&#8208;CuS) cathode with conductive N 2p&#8208;S 3p hybridized orbitals, oxygen&#8208;transporting mesopores, and about fivefold larger surface area than Cu. A ZAB with the N&#8208;CuS cathode exhibits a 788 mAh g &#8722;1 capacity (96% of theoretical) and a hitherto highest energy density of 916.0 Wh kg &#8722;1 , surpassing one with the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art Pt/C+RuO&#8322; cathode (712.43 mAh g &#8722;1 and 874 Wh kg &#8722;1 ). Density functional theory calculations elucidate that O&#9552;O bond dissociation is 0.97 eV more favorable on N&#8208;CuS than CuS. Subsequently, protonation of surface&#8208;adsorbed *O to *OH occurs via dissociate (0.55 V), non&#8208;spit associate (1.05 V), and split associate (1.05 V) pathways, with *OH then desorbing as OH &#8208; . Under anaerobic conditions, copper oxide transitions from CuO to Cu 2 O (1.05 V) and eventually to Cu (0.75 V) releasing oxygen to sustain ORR. Additionally, a ZAB with the N&#8208;CuS cathode achieves about threefold longer cyclability than one with the Pt/C+IrO&#8322; cathode, and about six&#8208;fold longer cyclability than one with the Pt/C+RuO&#8322; cathode.</description>
      <author>Do Hwan Jung, Yong Hak Park, Dong Won Kim, Jong Hui Choi, Sung June Cho, Keon&#8208;Han Kim, Dong Gyu Park, Byungchan Han, Jeung Ku Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202413425</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Definition of Important Terms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527853205.ch4</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409187927

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527853205.ch4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New insights into Rh-Pt electrocatalysts with low Pt content for ethanol electro-oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146084</link>
      <description>Nelson A. Galiote, Camilo A. Angelucci, Vin&#237;cius Del Colle, Germano Tremiliosi&#8208;Filho, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409191806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nelson A. Galiote, Camilo A. Angelucci, Vin&#237;cius Del Colle, Germano Tremiliosi&#8208;Filho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a molecular-scale picture of water electrolysis: mechanistic insights, fundamental kinetics and electrocatalyst dynamic evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216651</link>
      <description>Man Chen, Yingju Yang, Yuandong Ding, Jing Liu, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 536(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409197050

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Man Chen, Yingju Yang, Yuandong Ding, Jing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of structural modulation of B2 phase on the deformation mechanism in FeNiCrCoAl high entropy alloy: an atomistic insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130840</link>
      <description>K. Vijay Reddy, Punit Kumar, Saurabh Vashistha, Snehanshu Pal, Shailesh K. Singh, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409199255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Vijay Reddy, Punit Kumar, Saurabh Vashistha, Snehanshu Pal, Shailesh K. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Hypervalent Ru Sites in RuO2 Catalysts by Synergistic Bimetal Codoping for Long-Lasting Ampere-Level PEM Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110960</link>
      <description>Pengfei Li, Shupeng Wang, Hongpu Huang, Linrui Wen, Junlin Cai, Yuhang Peng, Zhiyu Zou, Xiaohong Wang, Xiaoliang Fang, Fang Lei, Xue Wang, Zhaoxiong Xie, Shuifen Xie, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409201280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Li, Shupeng Wang, Hongpu Huang, Linrui Wen, Junlin Cai, Yuhang Peng, Zhiyu Zou, Xiaohong Wang, Xiaoliang Fang, Fang Lei, Xue Wang, Zhaoxiong Xie, Shuifen Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts with three-dimensional porous structure for electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01392</link>
      <description>Yuchen Liu, Yanning Zhang, Zulin Sun, Liming Dai, Bin Liu, Wenxian Li, Sustainable materials and technologies. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409201428

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuchen Liu, Yanning Zhang, Zulin Sun, Liming Dai, Bin Liu, Wenxian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen radical induced Zn transfer to Ru film surfaces and influence of ambient atmosphere exposure on Zn adsorbates on Ru</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2025.114316</link>
      <description>Ilias Gaffarov, Jacobus Marinus Sturm, Marcelo Ackermann, Igor A. Makhotkin, Vacuum. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409201606

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ilias Gaffarov, Jacobus Marinus Sturm, Marcelo Ackermann, Igor A. Makhotkin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2025.114316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction-Driven Varieties of Active Sites on Cu(100) in Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07168</link>
      <description>Shuoqi Zhang, Qingli Tang, Beien Zhu, Yi Gao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409206316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuoqi Zhang, Qingli Tang, Beien Zhu, Yi Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroelectric Polarization Effects of Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts on Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500285</link>
      <description>Hao Ma, Xinyu Ye, Xiaoning Li, Zhichuan J. Xu, Yuanmiao Sun, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409208207

                Abstract The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) heavily depends on their substrates. However, heterojunctions with traditional substrate materials often fail to provide the desired dynamic interface effects. Here, through a systematic study of the ferroelectric heterostructure In 2 Se 3 /C&#8208;N&#8208;M, the feasibility of using ferroelectric materials to achieve dynamic optimization of the OER activity on SACs is demonstrated. The ferroelectric In 2 Se 3 is confirmed to be an effective substrate for improving the stability of various SACs, supported by theoretical results of their negative formation energy and positive dissolution potential. Activity analysis indicates that among these In 2 Se 3 /C&#8208;N&#8208;M systems, the In 2 Se 3 /C&#8208;N&#8208;Ir can achieve near&#8208;ideal catalytic activities through polarization switching. It can unprecedentedly catalyze OER via a hybrid pathway of adsorbate evolution mechanism and O&#8208;O coupling mechanism under different pH conditions (from pH = 1 to pH = 13). Machine learning models have been developed to conduct feature analysis and make ultrafast predictions of OER activity, which identify that the interfacial charge transfer triggered by ferroelectric polarization is the key to fine&#8208;tuning the OER performance of SACs. This work provides a theoretical framework that utilizes ferroelectric polarization as a powerful approach to navigate the design of efficient SACs.</description>
      <author>Hao Ma, Xinyu Ye, Xiaoning Li, Zhichuan J. Xu, Yuanmiao Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202500285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-free two-dimensional nanomaterials supported single atom catalysts for energy conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180261</link>
      <description>Yong Wan, Mingming Zhang, Cui Lai, Fuhang Xu, Shiyu Liu, Yukui Fu, Ling Li, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409211302

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Wan, Mingming Zhang, Cui Lai, Fuhang Xu, Shiyu Liu, Yukui Fu, Ling Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.180261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antisite defect unleashes catalytic potential in high-entropy intermetallics for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58679-5</link>
      <description>Tao Chen, Xinkai Zhang, Hangchao Wang, Chonglin Yuan, Yuxuan Zuo, Chuan Gao, Wukun Xiao, Yue Yu, Junfei Cai, Tie Luo, Yan Xiang, Dingguo Xia, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409211400

                Developing highly active, low-cost, and durable catalysts for efficient oxygen reduction reactions remain a challenge, hindering the commercial viability of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). In this study, an ordered PtZnFeCoNiCr high-entropy intermetallic electrocatalyst with Pt antisite point defects (PD-PZFCNC-HEI) is synthesized. The electrocatalyst shows high mass activity of 4.12 A mgPt-1 toward the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), which is 33 times that of the commercial Pt/C. PEMFC, assembled with PD-PZFCNC-HEI as the cathode (0.05 mgPt cm-2), exhibits a peak power density of 1.9 W cm-2 and a high mass activity of 3.0 A mgPt-1 at 0.9 V. Theoretical calculations combined with in situ X-ray absorption fine structure results reveal that defect engineering optimizes Pt's electronic structure and activates non-noble metal site active centers, achieving exceptionally high ORR catalytic activity. This study provides guidance for the development of nanostructured ordered high-entropy intermetallic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Chen, Xinkai Zhang, Hangchao Wang, Chonglin Yuan, Yuxuan Zuo, Chuan Gao, Wukun Xiao, Yue Yu, Junfei Cai, Tie Luo, Yan Xiang, Dingguo Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58679-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate classification of materials with elEmBERT: Element embeddings for chemical benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232529</link>
      <description>Shokirbek Shermukhamedov, Dilorom Mamurjonova, Michael Probst, APL Machine Learning. 3(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409216061

                We introduce the elEmBERT model for chemical classification tasks. It is based on deep learning techniques, such as a multilayer encoder architecture. We demonstrate the opportunities offered by our approach on sets of organic, inorganic, and crystalline compounds. In particular, we developed and tested the model using the Materials Project and MoleculeNet benchmarks, which include crystal properties and drug design-related benchmarks. We also conduct an analysis of vector representations of chemical compounds, shedding light on the underlying patterns in structural data. Our model exhibits exceptional predictive capabilities and proves universally applicable to molecular and material datasets. For instance, on the Tox21 dataset, we achieved an average precision of 96%, surpassing the previously best result by 10%.</description>
      <author>Shokirbek Shermukhamedov, Dilorom Mamurjonova, Michael Probst</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Coverage Carbon Monoxide Adsorption on a ZnAl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Surface: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00722</link>
      <description>Chunyan Sun, Lihong Cheng, Runping Ye, Rongbin Zhang, Qiang Li, Gang Feng, Shi Liu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409219696

                ZnAl2O4 spinel is widely used as a support in various reactions due to its thermal stability. Investigating the interaction between CO and ZnAl2O4 is essential for understanding the surface reaction mechanisms. In the present work, density functional theory (DFT) and ab initio atomistic thermodynamics were employed to investigate the adsorption of CO on perfect and O-defective ZnAl2O4 surfaces at varying CO coverages. The results reveal the formation of C* species and the subsequent aggregation can be hindered by the concentration of surface oxygen vacancy (Ovac) at low CO coverages. Notably, at high CO coverages, carbon deposition (CD) occurs on the ZnAl2O4 surfaces. &#916;&#956;CO is regulated below its threshold based on surface Ovac concentrations to control CO coverage and thereby suppress CD. At 523 K, the CO partial pressures should be maintained below 100, 10-3, 100, and 10-6 atm for surface with Ovac concentrations of 0, 12.5, 25, and 37.5%, respectively, to prevent CD on the surface. DFT-simulated IR spectra show that varying Ovac concentrations significantly affects the CO adsorption peak types and shifts, causing red shifts in vibrational frequencies for linearly adsorbed CO. These findings provide guidance for synthesizing ZnAl2O4 with varying Ovac concentrations to enhance catalyst efficiency and durability while mitigating CD.</description>
      <author>Chunyan Sun, Lihong Cheng, Runping Ye, Rongbin Zhang, Qiang Li, Gang Feng, Shi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c00722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From lab to market: Economic viability of modern hydrogen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135227</link>
      <description>Margarita Ryabicheva, Yaroslav Zhigalenok, Saken Abdimomyn, &#1052;&#1072;zhyn Skakov, &#1040;. Zh. Miniyazov, Gainiya Zhanbolatova, Nuriya Mukhamedova, Zhanar Ospanova, Thierry Djenizian, Fyodor Malchik, Fuel. 395(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409228929

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Margarita Ryabicheva, Yaroslav Zhigalenok, Saken Abdimomyn, &#1052;&#1072;zhyn Skakov, &#1040;. Zh. Miniyazov, Gainiya Zhanbolatova, Nuriya Mukhamedova, Zhanar Ospanova, Thierry Djenizian, Fyodor Malchik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.135227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Review on Revisiting Marcus Theory and Novel Understanding Heterogeneous Electron Transfer by Programing Tools</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elan.12045</link>
      <description>Xuanze Wang, Jie Deng, Kulika Pithaksinsakul, Yachao Zhu, Jiaxin Ren, Jiangfeng Qian, Olivier Fontaine, Electroanalysis. 37(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409229211

                Electron transfer is always the spotlight in electrochemistry, especially electrochemical energy storage. However, the current understanding of electron transfer, particularly in heterogeneous systems as explained by Marcus theory, faces challenges in accurately accounting for surface effects, solvent reorganization, and quantum tunneling, which are critical to real&#8208;world applications. Here, this review presents a comprehensive analysis of the heterogeneous electron transfer processes within the framework of Marcus theory, focusing on computing approaches using Python and Wolfram Language. The introduction outlines the significance of Marcus theory in explaining electron transfer reactions and sets the stage for the subsequent discussions. In the results and discussions section, the electron distribution in heterogeneous systems is explored, comparing the effects of different formalisms on electron transfer. A detailed comparison of the computational approaches using Python and Mathematica underscores the essential role of programing in tackling complex electron transfer models. These tools offer powerful, complementary capabilities for simulating the nuanced behavior of heterogeneous electron transfer processes, providing researchers with the flexibility and precision necessary to address the limitations of traditional theoretical methods. Finally, the work delves into the law of conservation of energy within the context of Marcus theory, offering a nuanced discussion of its implications for electron transfer studies. This review aims to equip researchers with practical insights and computing tools to enhance their understanding and application of Marcus theory in heterogeneous systems.</description>
      <author>Xuanze Wang, Jie Deng, Kulika Pithaksinsakul, Yachao Zhu, Jiaxin Ren, Jiangfeng Qian, Olivier Fontaine</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elan.12045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curvature-Influenced Electrocatalytic NRR Reactivity by Heme-like FeN4-Site on Carbon Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081670</link>
      <description>Yajie Meng, Ziyue Huang, Xi Chen, Yingqi Li, Xueyuan Yan, Jiawei Xu, Hai&#8208;Yan Wei, Molecules. 30(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409245179

                Two-dimensional carbon materials and their derivatives are widely applied as promising electrocatalysts and supports of single-atom sites. Theoretical investigations of 2D carbon materials are usually based on planar models, yet ignore local curvature brought on by possible surface distortion, which can be significant to the exact catalytic performance as has been realized in latest research. In this work, the curvature-influenced electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) reactivity of heme-like FeN4 single-atom site was predicted by a first-principle study, with FeN4-CNT(m,m) (m = 5~10) models adopted as local curvature models. The results showed that a larger local curvature is favored for NRR, with a lower limiting potential and higher N2 adsorption affinity, while a smaller local curvature shows lower NH3 desorption energy and is beneficial for catalyst recovery. Using electronic structures and logarithm fitting, we also found that FeN4-CNT(5,5) shows an intermediate-spin state, which is different from the high-spin state exhibited by other FeN4-CNT(m,m) (m = 6~10) models with a smaller local curvature.</description>
      <author>Yajie Meng, Ziyue Huang, Xi Chen, Yingqi Li, Xueyuan Yan, Jiawei Xu, Hai&#8208;Yan Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction by tuning the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface in nickel-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-025-01508-z</link>
      <description>Ben Wang, Tomohiro Fukushima, Hiro Minamimoto, Andrey Lyalin, Kei Murakoshi, Tetsuya Taketsugu, Communications Chemistry. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409246364

                A comprehensive understanding of the electrode-electrolyte interface in energy conversion systems remains challenging due to the complex and multifaceted nature of interfacial processes. This complexity hinders the development of more efficient electrocatalysts. In this work, we propose a hybrid approach to the theoretical description of the OER process on nickel-iron-based oxyhydroxides (&#947;-Ni1-xFexOOH) electrodes in alkaline media as a model system. Multiple reaction pathways represented by the single- and dual-site mechanisms were investigated by taking into account the realistic structure of the catalyst, the doping, and the solvation effects using a simple and computationally feasible strategy. Accounting for the variable solvation effects considerably affects the predicted overpotential in a roughly linear relationship between overpotential and dielectric constant. By incorporating quantum chemical simulations with kinetic modeling, we demonstrate that tuning the local solvation environment can significantly enhance the OER activity, opening new routine ways for elucidation of the emerging issues of OER processes on transition metal oxide surfaces and design of cost-effective, efficient electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Ben Wang, Tomohiro Fukushima, Hiro Minamimoto, Andrey Lyalin, Kei Murakoshi, Tetsuya Taketsugu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42004-025-01508-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy alloy enables multi-path electron synergism and lattice oxygen activation for enhanced oxygen evolution activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58648-y</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Hui-Feng Zhao, Zheng&#8208;Jie Chen, Qun Yang, Niu Gao, Li Li, Na Luo, Jian Zheng, Shanhu Bao, Jing Peng, Peng Xu, Xinwang Liu, Hai&#8208;Bin Yu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409246456

                Electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is key to several energy technologies but suffers from low activity. Leveraging the lattice oxygen activation mechanism (LOM) is a strategy for boosting its activity. However, this approach faces significant thermodynamic challenges, requiring high-valent oxidation of metal ions without compromising their stability. We reveal that high-entropy alloys (HEAs) can efficiently activate the LOM through synergistic multi-path electron transfer. Specifically, the oxidation of nickel is enhanced by this electron transfer, aided by the integration of weaker Co-O bonds, enabling effective LOM at the Ni-Co dual-site. These insights allow the design of a NiFeCoCrW0.2 HEA that exhibits improved activity, achieving an overpotential of 220 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm-2. It also demonstrates good stability, maintaining the potential with less than 5% variation over 90 days at 100 mA cm-2 current density. This study sheds light on the synergistic effects that confer high activity in HEAs and contribute to the advancement of high-performance OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Hui-Feng Zhao, Zheng&#8208;Jie Chen, Qun Yang, Niu Gao, Li Li, Na Luo, Jian Zheng, Shanhu Bao, Jing Peng, Peng Xu, Xinwang Liu, Hai&#8208;Bin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58648-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationally Designing Efficient Biomass Carbon Electrocatalysts for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis and Near-Neutral Zn&#8211;Air Batteries with Preliminary Machine Learning Guidance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00377</link>
      <description>Jiawei He, Zijun Shen, Shengchun Hu, Yuying Zhao, Qixin Yuan, Yuhan Wu, Kang Sun, Shule Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Mengmeng Fan, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409248983

                Biomass-based carbon materials are considered promising metal-free catalysts for the 2e- oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) to synthesize H2O2 and act as air electrodes in Zn-air batteries. However, optimization of the catalyst structure is a complex process due to the diversity of biomass precursors and synthesis parameters. Machine learning, a new artificial intelligence technology, has recently been used in various fields owing to its ability to rapidly analyze large amounts of data and guide material synthesis. Consequently, we constructed a machine learning model based on previously reported experimental data and guided the fabrication of a boron-doped biomass carbon catalyst for the 2e- ORR. The achieved catalytic performance exceeded most reported ORR catalysts in terms of H2O2 selectivity (90-95% in broad potentials of 0.30-0.68 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode), stability (maintaining over 90% selectivity for 12 h), yield (3450 mmol gcatalyst-1 h-1), and Faraday efficiency (over 90%). We applied the catalysts to Zn-air batteries and showed a high capacity (2856 mAh g-1) and stability twice that of traditional commercial metal catalysts. Therefore, this study proposed an effective machine learning model to guide the fabrication of biomass-based catalysts in the field of electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Jiawei He, Zijun Shen, Shengchun Hu, Yuying Zhao, Qixin Yuan, Yuhan Wu, Kang Sun, Shule Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Mengmeng Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular iron phthalocyanines anchoring onto ZIF-67-derived cobalt-carbon nanomaterials as bifunctional oxygen catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-025-1001-9</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Lin, Danna Lin, Weiwu Zhang, Jie Liu, Yanqiong Shen, Jinjie Qian, Frontiers in Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409250226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Lin, Danna Lin, Weiwu Zhang, Jie Liu, Yanqiong Shen, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11708-025-1001-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing MXenes and MBenes-Supported Composites for Superior Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-9546-2.ch009</link>
      <description>P. Selvakumar, Ritu Dahiya, T. C. Manjunath, Santosh Kumar Nathsharma, IGI Global eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409250446

                The pivotal area of research in the quest for sustainable and efficient methods although highly effective for industrial ammonia production, is energy-intensive and reliant on fossil fuels, contributing significantly to global carbon emissions. NRR offers a promising alternative, enabling ammonia synthesis at ambient temperatures and pressures using renewable energy sources. This reaction, where nitrogen is converted into ammonia through electrochemical means, mitigate environmental demand for green technologies in chemical manufacturing. At the core of NRR is the challenge of nitrogen activation, as molecular Electrocatalysts play a crucial role in facilitating this reaction by lowering the energy barriers associated with nitrogen dissociation and subsequent hydrogenation. Various materials, including precious metals, transition metal compounds, and novel carbon-based nanostructures, have been explored for their catalytic properties.</description>
      <author>P. Selvakumar, Ritu Dahiya, T. C. Manjunath, Santosh Kumar Nathsharma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3693-9546-2.ch009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic performance of in situ pyrolized iron oxide-embedded carbon composite for sustainable hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.112305</link>
      <description>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, T. Maiyalagan, Khuloud A. Alibrahim, Abdullah N. Alodhayb, Nagaraj P. Shetti, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409250906

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, T. Maiyalagan, Khuloud A. Alibrahim, Abdullah N. Alodhayb, Nagaraj P. Shetti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.112305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformative valorization of semi-coking wastewater: Design of rare earth/nitrogen-codoped porous carbon for efficient water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.436</link>
      <description>Qin Wang, Jin&#8208;Xing Liu, Hong&#8208;Xin Li, Xinglong Zhang, Zheng En-rang, Jian Li, Long Yan, Zhengqing Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 126(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409254453

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qin Wang, Jin&#8208;Xing Liu, Hong&#8208;Xin Li, Xinglong Zhang, Zheng En-rang, Jian Li, Long Yan, Zhengqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving Electrochemical Organic Hydrogenations on Metal Catalysts by Tailoring Hydrogen Surface Coverages</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15821</link>
      <description>Anna Ciotti, Motiar Rahaman, Celine Wing See Yeung, Tengfei Li, Erwin Reisner, Max Garc&#237;a&#8208;Melchor, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409262633

                Electrochemical hydrogenation, powered by renewable electricity, represents a promising sustainable approach for organic synthesis and the valorization of biomass-derived chemicals. Traditional strategies often rely on alkaline conditions to mitigate the competing hydrogen evolution reaction, posing challenges in sourcing hydrogen atoms for hydrogenation, which can be addressed through localized water dissociation on the electrode surface. In this study, we present a computationally guided design of electrochemical hydrogenation catalysts by optimizing hydrogen coverage density and binding strength on the electrode. Our theoretical investigations identify Cu, Au, and Ag - metals with moderate hydrogen coverage - as promising catalysts for electrochemical hydrogenations in alkaline media. These predictions are experimentally validated using a model organic substrate (acetophenone), achieving yields and faradaic efficiencies of up to 90%. Additionally, Cu, a nonprecious metal, is demonstrated to selectively hydrogenate a wide range of unsaturated compounds, including C&#9552;O, C&#9552;C, C&#8801;C, and C&#8801;N bonds, at low potentials with moderate to excellent conversion rates and chemoselectivities. This work highlights the potential of tailoring hydrogen coverage on electrode surfaces to rationally design nonprecious metal electrocatalysts for efficient organic hydrogenations. The insights gained here are expected to inform the development of more effective catalysts for organic hydrogenations and other industrially relevant chemical transformations.</description>
      <author>Anna Ciotti, Motiar Rahaman, Celine Wing See Yeung, Tengfei Li, Erwin Reisner, Max Garc&#237;a&#8208;Melchor</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c15821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paired electrochemical synthesis of glycolic acid and ammonia from polyester and nitrate sewage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101336</link>
      <description>Yingxin Ma, Xuyun Guo, Wenfang Yuan, Peinuo Yang, Yu Zhang, Wenxuan Chen, Lejuan Cai, Valeria Nicolosi, Wenlong Wang, Yang Chai, Bocheng Qiu, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409264939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingxin Ma, Xuyun Guo, Wenfang Yuan, Peinuo Yang, Yu Zhang, Wenxuan Chen, Lejuan Cai, Valeria Nicolosi, Wenlong Wang, Yang Chai, Bocheng Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Catalytic Materials for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081656</link>
      <description>M. Tr&#281;bala, Agata &#321;amacz, Molecules. 30(8)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409265480

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has, in recent years, attracted great interest from scientists because of its prime role in a number of renewable energy technologies. It is one of the reactions that occurs during hydrogen production through water splitting, is used in rechargeable metal&#8211;air batteries, and plays a fundamental role in regenerative fuel cells. Therefore, there is an emerging need to develop new, active, stable, and cost-effective materials for OER. This review presents the latest research on various groups of materials, showing their potential to be used as OER electrocatalysts, as well as their shortcomings. Particular attention has been paid to metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) and their derivatives, as those materials offer coordinatively unsaturated sites, high density of transition metals, adjustable pore size, developed surface area, and the possibility to be modified and combined with other materials.</description>
      <author>M. Tr&#281;bala, Agata &#321;amacz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30081656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A molecular design strategy to enhance hydrogen evolution on platinum electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01754-4</link>
      <description>Kaiyue Zhao, N. Xiang, Yuqi Wang, Jinyu Ye, Zihan Jin, Linke Fu, Xiaoxia Chang, Dong Wang, Hai Xiao, Bingjun Xu, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409268246

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaiyue Zhao, N. Xiang, Yuqi Wang, Jinyu Ye, Zihan Jin, Linke Fu, Xiaoxia Chang, Dong Wang, Hai Xiao, Bingjun Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01754-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for predicting enantioselectivity in chiral phosphoric acid-catalyzed naphthyl-indole synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12039-025-02347-0</link>
      <description>R. A. Oshiya, Ayan Datta, Journal of Chemical Sciences. 137(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409269804

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. A. Oshiya, Ayan Datta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12039-025-02347-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Activity and Stability of Pt Nanoparticles Supported on Multiscale Porous Antimony Tin Oxide for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500232</link>
      <description>Li Hao, Muhammad Ajmal, Xinquan Wu, Shishi Zhang, Xiaokang Liu, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Ruijie Gao, Lun Pan, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409270370

                Abstract Pt nanoparticles dispersed on carbon supports (Pt/C) are the benchmark oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts in proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs). However, their widespread application is hindered by severe stability degradation under high potentials and acidic environments, primarily due to carbon support corrosion. To address this challenge, a multiscale template&#8208;assisted method is proposed, combined with ethylene glycol reduction, to fabricate Pt nanoparticles supported onto multiscale porous conductive antimony tin oxides (Pt/PT&#8208;SSO). Both theoretical and experimental approaches have shown that the strong interaction between Pt and support markedly accelerates electron transfer and optimizes the adsorption strength of key intermediates on the Pt surface. Furthermore, the unique multiscale porous structure of support not only provides an ideal platform for the uniform dispersion of Pt nanoparticles but also greatly enhances confinement effect, effectively preventing Pt aggregation. As a result, the Pt/PT&#8208;SSO exhibits superior ORR activity and durability compared to commercial Pt/C catalysts. Specifically, its mass activity at 0.9 V (vs RHE) reaches 0.617 A mgPt&#8315;&#185;, which is twice that of Pt/C, while maintaining outstanding stability over 50 h. Notably, PEMFCs utilizing Pt/PT&#8208;SSO achieve a high power density of 1.173 W cm&#8315; 2 and retain 94.9% after 30,000 cycles of accelerated durability testing.</description>
      <author>Li Hao, Muhammad Ajmal, Xinquan Wu, Shishi Zhang, Xiaokang Liu, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Ruijie Gao, Lun Pan, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the prediction of TADF emitter properties using &#916;-machine learning: A hybrid semi-empirical and deep tensor neural network approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0263384</link>
      <description>R. Nikhitha, Anirban Mondal, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409270559

                This study presents a machine learning (ML)-augmented framework for accurately predicting excited-state properties critical to thermally activated delayed fluorescence (TADF) emitters. By integrating the computational efficiency of semi-empirical PPP+CIS theory with a &#916;-ML approach, the model overcomes the inherent limitations of PPP+CIS in predicting key properties, including singlet (S1) and triplet (T1) energies, singlet&#8211;triplet gaps (&#916;EST), and oscillator strength (f). The model demonstrated exceptional accuracy across datasets of varying sizes and diverse molecular features, notably excelling in predicting oscillator strength and &#916;EST values, including negative regions relevant to TADF molecules with inverted S1&#8211;T1 gaps. This work highlights the synergy between physics-inspired models and machine learning in accelerating the design of efficient TADF emitters, providing a foundation for future studies on complex systems and advanced functional materials.</description>
      <author>R. Nikhitha, Anirban Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0263384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxial Growth of Molecular Graphene on Metal Surface Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qute.202400621</link>
      <description>Biyu Song, Xiamin Hao, Chenqiang Hua, Meimei Wu, Guoxiang Zhi, Wenjin Gao, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou, Advanced Quantum Technologies. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409270724

                Abstract Molecular graphene provides an attractive man&#8208;made artificial system to realize designer Dirac fermions with exotic properties and significant implications in electronics/spintronics, but its large&#8208;scale fabrication remains a challenge as the available approach involves molecule&#8208;by&#8208;molecule manipulation of CO on a metal surface using a scanning tunneling microscopy tip. Here, we propose the epitaxial growth of molecular graphene on metal surface alloy, where CO molecules could be naturally self&#8208;assembled into a hexagonal lattice. Via high&#8208;throughput first&#8208;principles calculations, the adsorption behaviors of CO on 30 surface alloys Cu 2 M (M represents the alloyed element) with a ()&#8208; R 30&#176; superstructure on Cu(111) is explored. By systematically analyzing the structures, energetic and electronic properties of the adsorbed systems with different CO coverages, three surface alloys, Cu 2 Zn, Cu 2 Ga, and Cu 2 Ge, on which molecular graphene can be spontaneously formed, are successfully screened out. Remarkably, the self&#8208;assembled molecular graphene is featured by an effective four&#8208;band model involving the molecular (, ) orbitals of CO on a hexagonal lattice, leading to quantum spin Hall effect. This work paves an avenue for the large&#8208;scale growth of artificial graphene, which should stimulate immediate interest among experimentalists in the synthesis, characterization, and implementation of topological states for dissipationless transport and quantum computing.</description>
      <author>Biyu Song, Xiamin Hao, Chenqiang Hua, Meimei Wu, Guoxiang Zhi, Wenjin Gao, Tianchao Niu, Miao Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qute.202400621</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the mechanism of methanol electrooxidation: a potential-dependent DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra01511a</link>
      <description>Wei Zhang, Biyi Huang, Yang Cui, Lifang Shen, Shubin Yan, RSC Advances. 15(14)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409272922

                GC-DFT simulations reveal that PtCu alloy reduces MER overpotential (0.7 V vs. Pt's 0.9 V) via enhanced methanol adsorption, weakened CO binding, and diversified pathways, advancing CO-tolerant bimetallic catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Wei Zhang, Biyi Huang, Yang Cui, Lifang Shen, Shubin Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra01511a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generator of Neural Network Potential for Molecular Dynamics: Constructing Robust and Accurate Potentials with Active Learning for Nanosecond-Scale Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01613</link>
      <description>Naoki Matsumura, Yuta Yoshimoto, Tamio Yamazaki, Tomohito Amano, Tomoyuki Noda, Naoki Ebata, Takatoshi Kasano, Yasufumi Sakai, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409272958

                Neural network potentials (NNPs) enable large-scale molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of systems containing &gt;10,000 atoms with the accuracy comparable to ab initio methods and play a crucial role in material studies. Although NNPs are valuable for short-duration MD simulations, maintaining the stability of long-duration MD simulations remains challenging due to the uncharted regions of the potential energy surface (PES). Currently, there is no effective methodology to address this issue. To overcome this challenge, we developed an automatic generator of robust and accurate NNPs based on an active learning (AL) framework. This generator provides a fully integrated solution encompassing initial data set creation, NNP training, evaluation, sampling of additional structures, screening, and labeling. Crucially, our approach uses a sampling strategy that focuses on generating unstable structures with short interatomic distances, combined with a screening strategy that efficiently samples these configurations based on interatomic distances and structural features. This approach greatly enhances the MD simulation stability, enabling nanosecond-scale simulations. We evaluated the performance of our NNP generator in terms of its MD simulation stability and physical properties by applying it to liquid propylene glycol (PG) and polyethylene glycol (PEG). The generated NNPs enable stable MD simulations of systems with &gt;10,000 atoms for 20 ns. The predicted physical properties, such as the density and self-diffusion coefficient, show excellent agreement with the experimental values. This work represents a remarkable advance in the generation of robust and accurate NNPs for organic materials, paving the way for long-duration MD simulations of complex systems.</description>
      <author>Naoki Matsumura, Yuta Yoshimoto, Tamio Yamazaki, Tomohito Amano, Tomoyuki Noda, Naoki Ebata, Takatoshi Kasano, Yasufumi Sakai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c01613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Water Electrolysis for Green Hydrogen Production with Material Engineering: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400258</link>
      <description>Ying Liu, Yuanyuan Qin, Dawei Yu, Haiyue Zhuo, Churong Ma, Kai Chen, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409273758

                Abstract Water electrolysis, a traditional and highly technology, is gaining significant attention due to the growing demand for renewable energy resources. It stands as a promising solution for energy conversion, offer substantial benefits in environmental protection and sustainable development efforts. The aim of this research is to provide a concise review of the current state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art in the field of water electrolysis, focusing on the principles of water splitting fundamental, recent advancements in catalytic materials, various advanced characterization methods and emerging electrolysis technology improvements. Moreover, the paper delves into the development trends of catalysts engineering for water electrolysis, providing insight on how to enhance the catalytic performance. With the advancement of technology and the reduction of costs, hydrogen production through water electrolysis is expected to assume a more significant role in future energy ecosystem. This paper not only synthesizes existing knowledge but also highlights emerging opportunities and potential advancements in this field, offering a clear roadmap for further research and innovation.</description>
      <author>Ying Liu, Yuanyuan Qin, Dawei Yu, Haiyue Zhuo, Churong Ma, Kai Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eliminating nanometer-scale asperities on metallic thin films through plasma modification processes studied by molecular dynamics and AFM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-92095-5</link>
      <description>Tomoyuki Tsuyama, Tatsuki Oyama, Y. Azuma, Hirotada Ohashi, Masahiro Irie, Ayumi Yamakawa, Shoko Uetake, Takayuki Konno, Takahiro Ukai, Kazuhiko Ochiai, Nobuyuki Iwaoka, Atsushi Hashimoto, Yoshishige Okuno, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409285818

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tomoyuki Tsuyama, Tatsuki Oyama, Y. Azuma, Hirotada Ohashi, Masahiro Irie, Ayumi Yamakawa, Shoko Uetake, Takayuki Konno, Takahiro Ukai, Kazuhiko Ochiai, Nobuyuki Iwaoka, Atsushi Hashimoto, Yoshishige Okuno</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-92095-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAPF-DFT: A graph-based alchemical perturbation density functional theory for catalytic high-entropy alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01567-9</link>
      <description>Mohamed Hendy, Okan K. Orhan, Homin Shin, Ali Malek, Mauricio Ponga, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409177553

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohamed Hendy, Okan K. Orhan, Homin Shin, Ali Malek, Mauricio Ponga</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01567-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles insights into Ta-Nb ratio optimization of (CoCrNiMo)98Ta Nb medium-entropy alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417208</link>
      <description>Wen Deng, Tianyi Zhang, Jianlei Zhang, Hongxing Zheng, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409194816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen Deng, Tianyi Zhang, Jianlei Zhang, Hongxing Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2025.417208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous Single-Crystalline Particles as Robust and Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18390</link>
      <description>Yong Wang, Yunpu Qin, Sijia Liu, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Shangqing Zhao, Jianfang Liu, Jie Wang, Yadong Liu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409264530

                The scarcity of iridium (Ir) limits its widespread use in acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, mesoporous single-crystalline spinel Co3O4 with atomically dispersed low-valence-state Ir has been developed to enable Ir's efficient and stable utilization. The surface Pourbaix diagram suggests that under acidic OER conditions, O* fully covers both Co3O4(111) and (110) surfaces, passivating Co sites but enhancing Co3O4's structural stability, a benefit further improved by Ir doping. Mesopores offer numerous loading sites for Ir single atoms (13.8 wt %), which activate the originally O*-passivated Co3O4(111) surface by creating high-intrinsic-activity Co-Ir bridge sites; meanwhile, Ir and Co leaching rates are reduced to about 1/4 and 1/5, respectively, compared to conventional Ir/Co3O4 catalysts. Our catalyst exhibits a low &#951;10 of 248 mV for over 100 h, showcasing its potential in water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Yong Wang, Yunpu Qin, Sijia Liu, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Shangqing Zhao, Jianfang Liu, Jie Wang, Yadong Liu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c18390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Al&#8208;doped SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cores on hydrogen evolution from SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; core&#8210;shell catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20542</link>
      <description>Wenjia Song, A. Salvador, Gregory S. Rohrer, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409151028

                Abstract The hydrogen produced by Al&#8208;doped SrTiO 3 /TiO 2 core&#8210;shell catalysts with a range of Al&#8208;doped SrTiO 3 cores and the same TiO 2 shell are compared. The study included SrTiO 3 cores doped with different amounts of Al (0, 1, 2, or 3 mol%) added at different points in the synthesis (prior to or during the molten salt treatment) and at different temperatures (900&#176;C, 1000&#176;C, and 1100&#176;C). It was found that core&#8210;shell catalysts with different cores had hydrogen generation rates that varied by a factor of more than 40 and varied with the processing parameters in the same way as the hydrogen generation rates of the cores alone. The best catalysts had 2 or 3 mol% added Al, added during treatment in a SrCl 2 molten salt at 1000&#176;C or 1100&#176;C. Because the core absorbs most of the light, its ability to separate and transport photogenerated charge carriers dominates the properties of the core&#8210;shell catalyst. This indicates that, to optimize the properties of core&#8210;shell catalysts, it is essential to optimize the properties of the core. While the shell can be important to protect the core from degradation, it is not as important to the overall reactivity as the core.</description>
      <author>Wenjia Song, A. Salvador, Gregory S. Rohrer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the temperature-driven microkinetic processes of NH3 decomposition on the Co(111) surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.428</link>
      <description>Tian Tang, Penghui Ren, Jinfei Chen, Heyuan Zhang, Wenyun Qiao, Linhan Yu, Xinbao Li, Xuesen Du, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 123(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409169471

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tian Tang, Penghui Ren, Jinfei Chen, Heyuan Zhang, Wenyun Qiao, Linhan Yu, Xinbao Li, Xuesen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge-guided large language model for material science</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.revmat.2025.100007</link>
      <description>Guanjie Wang, Jingjing Hu, Jian Zhou, Sen Liu, Qi Li, Zhimei Sun, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409204146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanjie Wang, Jingjing Hu, Jian Zhou, Sen Liu, Qi Li, Zhimei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.revmat.2025.100007</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
