<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 01:56:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in computational design of van der Waals heterostructures for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02722e</link>
      <description>Ramandeep Singh, Pooja Jamdagni, Ashok Kumar, K. Tankeshwar, Ravindra Pandey, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412706704

                Light-driven photocatalytic water splitting is a promising approach to renewable hydrogen production, driven by the increasing global energy demand.</description>
      <author>Ramandeep Singh, Pooja Jamdagni, Ashok Kumar, K. Tankeshwar, Ravindra Pandey</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta02722e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering 3D-printed molybdenum carbide catalysts for selective CO2 reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166134</link>
      <description>Arturo Pajares, Mehmet Tanr&#305;verdi, Eduardo Couti&#241;o&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Jacob Andrade&#8208;Arvizu, Maxim Guc, Pablo Guardia, H&#232;ctor Prats, Bart Michielsen, Chemical Engineering Journal. 520(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412711710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arturo Pajares, Mehmet Tanr&#305;verdi, Eduardo Couti&#241;o&#8208;Gonz&#225;lez, Jacob Andrade&#8208;Arvizu, Maxim Guc, Pablo Guardia, H&#232;ctor Prats, Bart Michielsen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.166134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid carbothermic shock synthesis of high-entropy oxides as highly stable oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237967</link>
      <description>Changyu Hu, Huidong Xie, Cheng Chen, Xiaoyu Liu, Hao Chen, Lingyi Meng, Hu Liu, Journal of Power Sources. 655(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412711831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changyu Hu, Huidong Xie, Cheng Chen, Xiaoyu Liu, Hao Chen, Lingyi Meng, Hu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening and mechanistic study of transition metal and non-metal mono-/co-doped WS2 with anti-site defects as nitrogen reduction electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136349</link>
      <description>Huaping Xiong, Yue Meng, Bo Xie, Zheming Ni, Shengjie Xia, Fuel. 404(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412715582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaping Xiong, Yue Meng, Bo Xie, Zheming Ni, Shengjie Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient Surface Degradation of LSCO and LSFO during OER in Alkaline Electrolyte under Dynamic Cycling Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02273</link>
      <description>Anton Kaus, Bixian Ying, Zhenjie Teng, Muzaffar Maksumov, Lisa Heymann, Michael Merz, S. Schuppler, Peter Nagel, Florian Hausen, Karin Kleiner, Felix Gunkel, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412716932

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anton Kaus, Bixian Ying, Zhenjie Teng, Muzaffar Maksumov, Lisa Heymann, Michael Merz, S. Schuppler, Peter Nagel, Florian Hausen, Karin Kleiner, Felix Gunkel</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02273</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Estimation of Inter-atomic Potentials in Plasma Material Interaction Molecular Dynamic Modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-97992-7_13</link>
      <description>Alper Pahsa, Lecture notes in networks and systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412719240

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alper Pahsa</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-97992-7_13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: beyond the surface&#8212;exploring the complexities of 2D materials with density functional theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-11190-0</link>
      <description>Mehedi Hasan, Heider A. Abdulhussein, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412722169

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mehedi Hasan, Heider A. Abdulhussein</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-11190-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward data-driven predictive modeling of electrocatalyst stability and surface reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0271797</link>
      <description>Jiayu Peng, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412726279

                Catalyst dissolution and surface restructuring are ubiquitous in electrocatalysis, often leading to formidable activity&#8211;stability trade-offs and obscure electrochemically induced surface species that severely hinder the understanding and optimization of electrocatalysts under diverse harsh operating conditions. As even state-of-the-art characterization techniques lack the resolution and efficiency for the unambiguous elucidation of decomposition kinetics and reconstruction dynamics at electrocatalytic interfaces, many atomistic modeling approaches&#8212;following the recent advances in physics-driven machine learning&#8212;have been widely used to facilitate the atom-by-atom understanding and rational engineering of electrocatalyst stability and dynamics. This Perspective systematically assesses classical and data-driven approaches in theoretical surface science and computational catalysis, recognizing their achievements and highlighting their limitations in throughput, efficiency, accuracy, bias, transferability, and scalability toward enabling realistic and predictive modeling of electrocatalyst degradation and reconstruction. By examining different methods spanning first-principle simulations, surface sampling, neural network interatomic potentials, and generative deep learning models, it is underscored how such data-driven computational techniques help elucidate the precise nature of various key interfacial atomistic processes to address existing technical challenges in surface modeling and provide a new paradigm to optimize dissolution kinetics and restructuring dynamics for electrocatalyst design.</description>
      <author>Jiayu Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0271797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promising two-dimensional Janus &#946;-PdXO (X = S/Se) for photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150617</link>
      <description>Yue Hao, Shuo Jiang, Xi Sun, Zihan Qu, Zuyu Xu, Yunlai Zhu, Yihong Dai, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 161(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412730454

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue Hao, Shuo Jiang, Xi Sun, Zihan Qu, Zuyu Xu, Yunlai Zhu, Yihong Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A state-of-the-art review of digital twin-enabled human-robot collaboration in smart energy management systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2025.106524</link>
      <description>S. Q. Fu, Maxwell Fordjour Antwi&#8208;Afari, Shahnawaz Anwer, Zhiqiang Chen, Heng Li, Results in Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412739116

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Q. Fu, Maxwell Fordjour Antwi&#8208;Afari, Shahnawaz Anwer, Zhiqiang Chen, Heng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2025.106524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface structural engineering of self-supported HER electrodes: Multiscale micro/nanostructure regulation and their roles in HER process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01570</link>
      <description>Yaxin Wen, Zhaoyang Zhang, Hao Zhu, Yang Liu, Tian Wen, Lizhuo Ma, Jingtao Wang, Kun Xu, Sustainable materials and technologies. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412739183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaxin Wen, Zhaoyang Zhang, Hao Zhu, Yang Liu, Tian Wen, Lizhuo Ma, Jingtao Wang, Kun Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2025.e01570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen evolution reaction by goldene/Janus-MSSe (M=Mo, W) heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150744</link>
      <description>Kourosh Rahimi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 161(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412740343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kourosh Rahimi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectro-Microscopy of Individual Pt&#8211;Rh Core&#8211;Shell Nanoparticles during Competing Oxidation and Alloying</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c07668</link>
      <description>Jagrati Dwivedi, Lydia J. Bachmann, Arno Jeromin, Satishkumar Kulkarni, Heshmat Noei, Liviu C. T&#259;nase, Aarti Tiwari, Lucas de Souza Caldas, Thomas Schmidt, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Andreas Stierle, Thomas F. Keller, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412741690

                The surface chemical composition of supported single Pt-Rh core-shell nanoparticles was studied to understand the Rh behavior in oxidizing and reducing gas environments using spectro-microscopy with high spatial resolution. We combined in situ X-ray photoemission electron microscopy with ex situ scanning electron-, atomic force-, and scanning Auger-microscopy to distinguish Rh oxidation-reduction, dewetting-sintering, and alloying-segregation during the course of the experiment. A more than 20% higher Rh 3d5/2 oxide to metal photoemission intensity ratio for the Rh layer on top of the Pt-core was found as compared to the bare strontium titanate (STO) oxide catalyst support in close vicinity, where Rh/RhOx nanoparticles are forming. At elevated temperatures, Rh diffuses into the Pt particle, and this alloying at the Pt metal surface competes with Rh oxidation, whereas the Rh/RhOx nanoparticles on the STO support are observed to sinter under identical oxidizing and temperature environments. A nanoparticle facet-dependent analysis of selected Pt-core nanoparticles suggests that Rh oxidation is most advanced on a small nanoparticle with a low coordination top facet that we indexed by electron backscatter diffraction, demonstrating the strength of our correlative approach.</description>
      <author>Jagrati Dwivedi, Lydia J. Bachmann, Arno Jeromin, Satishkumar Kulkarni, Heshmat Noei, Liviu C. T&#259;nase, Aarti Tiwari, Lucas de Souza Caldas, Thomas Schmidt, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Andreas Stierle, Thomas F. Keller</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c07668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carburization-Assisted Conversion of N-Doped Mo to N-Doped Mo2c for Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5372834</link>
      <description>Stefanos Chaitoglou, Subrata Ghosh, Shubhadeep Majumdar, Roger Amade, E. Bertr&#225;n, Carlo S. Casari, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412743023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Stefanos Chaitoglou, Subrata Ghosh, Shubhadeep Majumdar, Roger Amade, E. Bertr&#225;n, Carlo S. Casari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5372834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stereochemical Control of Cocrystal and Hybrid Salt&#8211;Cocrystal Formation in the Baclofen&#8211;Mandelic Acid System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00779</link>
      <description>Sarita Songsermsawad, Kajjana Boonpalit, Oleksii Shemchuk, Koen Robeyns, Tom Leyssens, Adrian E. Flood, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412743394

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarita Songsermsawad, Kajjana Boonpalit, Oleksii Shemchuk, Koen Robeyns, Tom Leyssens, Adrian E. Flood</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c00779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-engineered molybdenum Diboride and tungsten Diboride monolayers as efficient catalysts for sustainable ammonia production via nitric oxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138597</link>
      <description>Rongjian Sa, Qingyu Li, Weiguo Li, Helong Wu, De&#8208;Jing Li, Zuju Ma, Diwen Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412746358

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rongjian Sa, Qingyu Li, Weiguo Li, Helong Wu, De&#8208;Jing Li, Zuju Ma, Diwen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138597</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Accelerated Computational Screening of Pt-Modified Cantor Alloys as High-Entropy Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00063-5</link>
      <description>Wiljar Lobjakas, Christian M. Clausen, Jaak Nerut, Jan Rossmeisl, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412746629

                Abstract High-entropy alloys are increasingly recognised as promising catalyst materials due to their highly tunable compositions. In particular, the Cantor alloy, CrCoFeMnNi, has attracted significant interest as a low-cost, earth-abundant alternative to Pt-group catalysts. However, the Cantor alloy is susceptible to degradation in acidic environments. To address this, Pt has been proposed as an addition to the Cantor alloy to leverage the high catalytic activity and surface stability of Pt. In this study, we identify and elucidate the catalytic activity trend for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) by screening CrCoFeMnNiPt alloys containing 50&#8211;100 at.% Pt and up to 50 at.% of each 3d element at 10 at.% resolution using a purely computational, machine learning-accelerated density-functional-theory workflow. Assuming the formation of a Pt skin through surface reconfiguration, a machine learning-accelerated simulation protocol infers the strain-corrected adsorption strengths of key reaction intermediates and uses them as descriptors for kinetic modelling. Our results show that Pt-modification of the Cantor alloy is a potentially viable strategy towards active and durable ORR catalysts. However, the simulations also predict binary Pt-rich alloys with approximately 80 at.% Pt to exhibit the highest ORR activity due to synergistic ligand and strain effects. As this model identifies known alloys with high ORR performance, we suggest that this framework contributes to a clear understanding of how bulk composition affects the reaction kinetics of complex surface alloys.</description>
      <author>Wiljar Lobjakas, Christian M. Clausen, Jaak Nerut, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44210-025-00063-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Templated Engineering of W&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Active Sites on CTF-Derived Tungsten Catalysts: Synergistic Regulation of Mass Transfer, Reaction Pathway, and Oxygen Reduction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c08970</link>
      <description>Huan Ye, Yuanzhi Zhu, Qicheng Zhang, Jiawen Wu, Xiaobin Fan, Wenchao Peng, Xiaoxia Chang, Yang Li, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412754301

                The urgent demand for Pt-free oxygen reduction catalysts drives exploration of tungsten-based alternatives, motivated by its Pt-mimetic valence electron configuration and optimal oxygen binding energy (&#916;EO &#8776; - 2.05 eV) revealed in oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) volcano plots. Herein, a hierarchical W3N4-doped catalyst has been engineered through dual-stage thermal activation of covalent triazine framework (CTF)-tungstate complexes, where W precursors serve dual roles as self-sacrificing templates and active site generators. In-depth discussions via distribution of relaxation time (DRT) analysis elucidates that the hierarchical pore structure and active sites of WNNP-C demonstrate &#8764;90% reduction in relaxation time (&#964; = 0.18 vs 1.6 s of WNOSAC-C) at half potential and achieve a 0.83 V half-wave potential (E1/2) approaching Pt/C (0.865 V) in 0.1 M KOH coupled with exceptional methanol tolerance. The mechanistic analysis demonstrates that the enhanced electrical conductivity of the catalyst support facilitates the desorption of *OH intermediates by overcoming their elevated energy barrier, which preferentially promotes the 4e- ORR pathway and consequently improves the overall ORR performance. Moreover, the WNNP-C assembled zinc-air battery delivers 839 mAh gZn-1 specific capacity and over 140 h of stability at a discharge current density of 5 mA/cm2, validating the strategy's effectiveness in synchronizing porous architectures with W3N4 active centers. This work provides a paradigm for unlocking catalytic potential in traditionally inert transition metals through synergistic coordination pyrolysis engineering.</description>
      <author>Huan Ye, Yuanzhi Zhu, Qicheng Zhang, Jiawen Wu, Xiaobin Fan, Wenchao Peng, Xiaoxia Chang, Yang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c08970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xtalopt Version 14: Variable-Composition Crystal Structure Search for Functional Materials Through Pareto Optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5372187</link>
      <description>Samad Hajinazar, Eva Zurek, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412754436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samad Hajinazar, Eva Zurek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5372187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable machine learned predictions of adsorption energies at the metal&#8211;oxide interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0282674</link>
      <description>Michael S. Nielsen, L. Kempen, J&#244;rgen Ravn, Raffaele Cheula, Mie Andersen, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412757774

                The conversion of CO2 to value-added compounds is an important part of the effort to store and reuse atmospheric CO2 emissions. Here, we focus on CO2 hydrogenation over so-called inverse catalysts: transition metal oxide clusters supported on metal surfaces. The conventional approach for computational screening of such candidate catalyst materials involves a reliance on density functional theory (DFT) to obtain accurate adsorption energies at a significant computational cost. Here, we present a machine learning (ML)-accelerated workflow for obtaining adsorption energies at the metal&#8211;oxide interface. We enumerate possible binding sites at the clusters and use DFT to sample a subset of these with diverse local adsorbate environments. The dataset is used to explore interpretable and black-box ML models with the aim of revealing the electronic and structural factors controlling adsorption at metal&#8211;oxide interfaces. Furthermore, the explored ML models can be used for low-cost prediction of adsorption energies on structures outside of the original training dataset. The workflow presented here, along with the insights into trends in adsorption energies at metal&#8211;oxide interfaces, will be useful for identifying active sites, predicting parameters required for microkinetic modeling of reactions on complex catalyst materials, and accelerating data-driven catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Michael S. Nielsen, L. Kempen, J&#244;rgen Ravn, Raffaele Cheula, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0282674</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Stabilization Mechanism of Electron-Enriched PtNiCo Catalysts in Practical Direct Methanol Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c01144</link>
      <description>Min Chen, Yichi Guan, Zhengpei Miao, Shuo Zhang, Chunxia Wu, Yu Zhou, Hongxian Luo, Daoxiong Wu, Ruisong Li, Junming Luo, Xinlong Tian, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412761595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Chen, Yichi Guan, Zhengpei Miao, Shuo Zhang, Chunxia Wu, Yu Zhou, Hongxian Luo, Daoxiong Wu, Ruisong Li, Junming Luo, Xinlong Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c01144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Efficiency Electrochemical Nitrogen Fixation by Noble&#8208;Metal&#8208;Free Metallic Glasses</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503400</link>
      <description>Xue Chen, Xin&#8208;Jie Peng, Dongdong Xiao, Y. T. Sun, Kailing Zhou, Xiaoyong Yang, Yong&#8208;Zheng Zhang, Weihua Wang, Zhen Lu, Hong-Yang Bai, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412765121

                Abstract The electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) represents an energy&#8208;efficient alternative to the traditional Haber&#8208;Bosch process for industrial ammonia synthesis. However, the cleavage of the strong N&#8801;N bond hinders the practical application of NRR. Herein, an innovative design strategy is proposed based on a Fe 76 Si 8 B 13 Nb 3 metallic glass (MG&#8208;FeSiBNb) catalyst, featuring a unique amorphous structure with endogenous nanoscale compositional heterogeneity. This catalyst achieves an impressive ammonia yield rate of 92.1 &#181;g h &#8722;1 mg &#8722;1 cat. in 0.1 m Na 2 SO 4 solution, surpassing most state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art NRR electrocatalysts. Extended X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure analysis reveals that MG&#8208;FeSiBNb provides abundant unsaturated coordination sites, essential for effective N 2 adsorption. Furthermore, electronic structural characterizations and density functional theory calculations demonstrate that the incorporation of Si, B, and Nb atoms into the Fe&#8208;based matrix precisely tailors the local electronic environment, effectively shifting the Fe d&#8208;band center toward the Fermi level. This electronic modulation enhances electron transfer efficiency, thus promoting the hydrogenation of * NH 2 to * NH 3 . Additionally, the amorphous nature of MG&#8208;FeSiBNb suppresses hydrogen adsorption by eliminating well&#8208;defined crystal facets, thereby selectively mitigating the hydrogen evolution reaction and enhancing NRR selectivity. This work offers not only a high&#8208;performing NRR catalyst but also a generalizable strategy for sustainable electrocatalysis beyond conventional crystalline systems.</description>
      <author>Xue Chen, Xin&#8208;Jie Peng, Dongdong Xiao, Y. T. Sun, Kailing Zhou, Xiaoyong Yang, Yong&#8208;Zheng Zhang, Weihua Wang, Zhen Lu, Hong-Yang Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structurally Ordered High&#8208;Entropy Intermetallics for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503306</link>
      <description>Lu Fan, Guang Feng, Huimin Qi, Qichang Li, Lina Su, Z X Kang, Yuying Hou, Zhiqi Huang, Dingguo Xia, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412765439

                Abstract Structurally ordered high&#8208;entropy intermetallics (HEIs) have garnered increased attention due to their unique physicochemical properties. The ordered atomic configuration and compositional diversity of HEIs contribute to optimal active&#8208;site isolation, broad tunability of catalytic activity, and remarkable electrochemical stability. These advantages have enabled HEIs to achieve exceptional catalytic performance in various energy&#8208;related applications, positioning them as promising candidates for next&#8208;generation catalytic materials. However, comprehensive reviews on HEIs are scarce. This work provides a systematic overview of recent advances in HEIs research, encompassing innovative synthesis strategies, advanced characterization techniques, and catalytic applications such as the oxygen reduction reaction, hydrogen evolution reaction, electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction, and small&#8208;molecule oxidation reactions. Furthermore, the unique catalytic properties of HEIs are thoroughly elucidated, while discussing the challenges and future research opportunities for HEI&#8208;based catalysts. This work highlights the transformative potential of HEIs in driving the development of energy&#8208;related catalytic technologies and provides valuable insights for designing next&#8208;generation high&#8208;performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Lu Fan, Guang Feng, Huimin Qi, Qichang Li, Lina Su, Z X Kang, Yuying Hou, Zhiqi Huang, Dingguo Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma-synthesized NiFe-layered double hydroxides/amorphous MoWSx featuring synergistic effect of hydrogen spillover and vacancy engineering for highly efficient high-current-density overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtadv.2025.100601</link>
      <description>Dai Zhang, Feilong Wang, Shiting Ou, Ying Guo, Rongqing Liang, Shuyu Zhang, Xijiang Chang, Materials Today Advances. 27(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412772329

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dai Zhang, Feilong Wang, Shiting Ou, Ying Guo, Rongqing Liang, Shuyu Zhang, Xijiang Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtadv.2025.100601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annealing Effects on Cu Migration in the Colloidal Synthesis of Pd-Chalcogenides Nanoheterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c02469</link>
      <description>Suvodeep Sen, Niraj Nitish Patil, Ajitabh Bora, Manoj Palabathuni, Temilade Esther Adegoke, Kevin M. Ryan, Kevin Rossi, Shalini Singh, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412776019

                Heterostructuring nanocrystals into a modular metal-semiconductor configuration enables tunable and novel functionalities. Such combinations at the nanoscale equip hybrid structures with unique electronic, optical, and catalytic properties unobserved in single-phase materials. Here, we report the hot-injection synthesis of Pd-Cu3Pd13S6.65Te0.35 nanoheterostructures (NHCs) from PdCu nanoalloy seeds. First, the growth of Pd-rich chalcogenide nanocrystals was initiated over the preformed PdCu surface through simultaneous sulfidation and tellurization, followed by their transformation into Pd-Cu3Pd13S6.65Te0.35 NHCs. By strategically employing moderate-temperature annealing, we achieved the complete migration of Cu+ due to the higher reactivity of Cu in comparison to Pd at that temperature, establishing a novel mechanistic relationship between cation mobility and temperature. This strategy enables controlled semiconductor domain formation and targeted metal migration. The NHCs showed efficient and stable electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution with low Tafel values in acidic media, outperforming conventional nanoelectrocatalysts. Computational analysis identified the active sites responsible for the observed catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Suvodeep Sen, Niraj Nitish Patil, Ajitabh Bora, Manoj Palabathuni, Temilade Esther Adegoke, Kevin M. Ryan, Kevin Rossi, Shalini Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c02469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Evolution on Mechanically Strained TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/NiTi: Implications of Compositional Heterogeneity at (Photo)electrocatalytic Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.5c00228</link>
      <description>O. Quinn Carvalho, Nikita S. Dutta, Debjit Ghoshal, Steven P. Harvey, Ross A. Kerner, Shuya Li, Zebulon G. Schichtl, Patrick Walker, Logan M. Wilder, Gustavo Z. Girotto, Maximilian Jaugstetter, Slavom&#237;r Nem&#353;&#225;k, Ethan J. Crumlin, Elisa M. Miller, Ann L. Greenaway, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412777392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>O. Quinn Carvalho, Nikita S. Dutta, Debjit Ghoshal, Steven P. Harvey, Ross A. Kerner, Shuya Li, Zebulon G. Schichtl, Patrick Walker, Logan M. Wilder, Gustavo Z. Girotto, Maximilian Jaugstetter, Slavom&#237;r Nem&#353;&#225;k, Ethan J. Crumlin, Elisa M. Miller, Ann L. Greenaway</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.5c00228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in Interdisciplinary Research: Evidence From the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/21582440251361767</link>
      <description>Shufang Huang, SAGE Open. 15(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412781126

                Although the COVID-19 pandemic has largely subsided, it remains crucial to reflect on past experiences and shortcomings to better prepare for potential future outbreaks. Effective outbreak management is a complex scientific challenge that demands robust interdisciplinary collaboration. However, there is currently a lack of quantitative and objective assessments of progress in interdisciplinary research on coronaviruses, particularly measures that directly evaluate the extent of such collaborations. In this study, we employed Python-based algorithms to analyze 156,674 publications from the Web of Science database, tracing the development of coronavirus research and interdisciplinary collaboration. Our findings reveal a significant upward trend in both the volume of coronavirus research and the intensity of interdisciplinary collaboration over the past 5 decades. Notably, major outbreaks have acted as critical catalysts, driving substantial advancements in this field. The past 2 decades, marked by three major coronavirus outbreaks, have seen dramatic growth in the scale and depth of interdisciplinary studies. Nevertheless, achieving seamless cross-disciplinary integration remains a persistent challenge. This study offers valuable insights for fostering interdisciplinary collaboration and optimizing academic discipline structures in universities.</description>
      <author>Shufang Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/21582440251361767</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon-Induced Degradation of Short-Chain PFAS by Noble Metal Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01683</link>
      <description>Samir Kumar Nayak, Khushboo Bhardwaj, Pramod Kumar Verma, Sharma S. R. K. C. Yamijala, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412786954

                Per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) are widely used in industry and consumer products due to their unique physical and chemical properties. However, due to their toxicity and environmental persistence, the production of long-chain PFAS such as perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) and perfluorooctanesulfonic acid (PFOS) has been systematically phased out. Instead, short-chain PFAS have been widely used as replacements for long-chain PFAS. However, recent studies indicate that even short-chain PFAS can be toxic to the environment. Despite numerous attempts, complete degradation of these short-chain PFAS has not yet been achieved, leaving room for further exploration. In this work, we explored the potential of plasmonic silver (Ag) and gold (Au) nanoclusters (NCs) in the complete degradation of short-chain PFAS. By considering icosahedral Ag55 and Au55 NCs, as well as different types of PFAS, we present a thorough study of plasmon-induced processes for NC-PFAS complexes. Among different decay channels, our study focuses on plasmon decay through the direct hot electron transfer (DHET) and direct hot hole transfer (DHHT) pathways from NC to PFAS. Our calculations reveal that DHET is more probable in Ag-PFAS complexes and DHHT is more probable in Au-PFAS complexes. Furthermore, among all complexes, the Ag-PFBS complex exhibits the highest DHET with a total probability of 10%. Our Ehrenfest molecular dynamics simulations show that the PFAS in Ag-PFAS complexes undergo efficient degradation in the presence of these hot carriers, albeit at different rates.</description>
      <author>Samir Kumar Nayak, Khushboo Bhardwaj, Pramod Kumar Verma, Sharma S. R. K. C. Yamijala</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c01683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MS25: Materials Science-Focused Benchmark Data Set for Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01262</link>
      <description>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Xinglong Zhang, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412789389

                We present MS25, a benchmark data set for evaluating machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) across diverse materials-relevant systems including MgO surfaces, liquid water, zeolites, a catalytic Pt surface reaction, high-entropy alloys (HEAs), and disordered Zr-oxides. Five MLIP architectures (MACE, NequIP, Allegro, MTP, and Torch-ANI) are trained and tested, focusing not only on traditional metrics (energies, forces, and stresses) but also explicitly validating derived physical observables such as lattice constants, volumes, and reaction barriers. We find that most models reach comparable accuracy on standard error metrics across the simple systems, although equivariant MLIPs offer 1.5-2&#215; improvements over nonequivariant MLIPs in energy and force error for structurally complex or compositionally disordered environments such as HEAs and Zr-O systems. Our analysis highlights that low errors in energy and force predictions do not guarantee reliable observables, emphasizing the necessity of explicit validation. We demonstrate limitations in cross-framework transferability, as models trained on one zeolite framework (CHA) fail to reliably generalize to predictions of structurally distinct frameworks (e.g., MFI). Size-extensive tests show some dependence on system size for MgO, resulting from forced periodicity. The HEA and Zr-O data sets are identified as challenging tests for future benchmarks and MLIP model architecture developments as they show significant differentiation in error between MLIP architectures and are still relatively difficult at 1000 training images. Moving forward, we recommend that benchmarking efforts shift their focus from marginal accuracy improvements in energy and force errors toward identifying and understanding model failure modes, rigorously assessing transferability, and evaluating how their errors affect observable predictions. For researchers looking to choose an MLIP architecture, we suggest selecting equivariant MLIP architectures if the complexity of the system is a challenge. For simple materials problems, auxiliary features such as integration with molecular dynamics engines, trade-offs between computational data set generation cost vs MLIP inference speed, and framework integration may play a more important decision factor than small differences in error metrics that are unlikely to matter for production-level research.</description>
      <author>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Xinglong Zhang, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-metal content optimization strategy based on density functional theory and machine learning: enhancing the hydrogen evolution reaction performance of metal-doped catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113463</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Xiong, Jianhang Feng, Shengjun Huo, Yu Liu, Meng Yu, Xin Zhang, Meiling Hou, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412792607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Xiong, Jianhang Feng, Shengjun Huo, Yu Liu, Meng Yu, Xin Zhang, Meiling Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-driven predictive design of catalytic oxygen carriers for chemical looping processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43937-025-00081-9</link>
      <description>Zhuo Cheng, Qichang Meng, Xiaofeng Jiang, Sudeshna Gun, Liang&#8208;Shih Fan, Discover Energy. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412793742

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuo Cheng, Qichang Meng, Xiaofeng Jiang, Sudeshna Gun, Liang&#8208;Shih Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43937-025-00081-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Electrochemistry of Pt&#8211;Ni Thin-Film Formations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03762</link>
      <description>Alasdair Fairhurst, Benjamin J. Ransom, Dominik Haering, Chaewon Lim, Ethan J. Schoettler, Vojislav R. Stamenkovi&#263;, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412800488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alasdair Fairhurst, Benjamin J. Ransom, Dominik Haering, Chaewon Lim, Ethan J. Schoettler, Vojislav R. Stamenkovi&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03762</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tip&#8208;Enhanced Oxygen Reduction on Pt@Ni Cones via Concentrated Electric and Magnetic Fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500684</link>
      <description>Guojun Han, Mohamed Ait Tamerd, Ling Gao, Guo Qingsheng, Cong Feng, Menghao Yang, Guo&#8208;Xing Miao, Jing Fu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412812727

                Abstract Efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for energy conversion technologies, yet its sluggish kinetics remain a significant challenge. Beyond optimizing the catalyst's intrinsic properties, field effects can also profoundly impact the microenvironment at the catalyst/electrolyte interface, thereby affecting electrocatalytic performance. This study explores the tip&#8208;enhanced ORR by leveraging the coupled effects of electric and magnetic fields at the reaction interface. The Pt&#8208;loaded ferromagnetic Ni cone electrode generates strong localized electric fields that reorganize interfacial water molecules into a more ordered structure. This strengthens hydrogen bonding between the electrolyte and reaction intermediates, which in turn facilitates proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer and accelerates the rate&#8208;limiting *OH desorption into interfacial water matrix. Additionally, the amplified electric fields at tips accelerate OH &#8722; electromigration away from the catalyst surface, while the migration current couples with the concentrated magnetic fields near tips to drive strong magnetohydrodynamic flows. These intensified flows effectively enhance O 2 molecule delivery to wider electrode surface and facilitate better OH &#8722; product removal, thus improving the overall reaction efficiency. This strategy of concentrating both E/M fields using the field&#8208;effect catalyst optimizes the ORR kinetics at the interface as well as the mass transport dynamics near interface, offering an effective approach for advancing ORR performance.</description>
      <author>Guojun Han, Mohamed Ait Tamerd, Ling Gao, Guo Qingsheng, Cong Feng, Menghao Yang, Guo&#8208;Xing Miao, Jing Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202500684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Amorphous Ni Core&#8211;N&#8208;Doped Carbon Shell Nanoparticles for Efficient Bifunctional Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70103</link>
      <description>Haoran Cheng, Hong Seok Kim, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412812879

                Amorphous metal&#8208;based catalysts are highly promising for water splitting due to their abundance of unsaturated active sites. Herein, we report a one&#8208;step, surfactant&#8208;free synthesis of amorphous nickel nanoparticles (NPs) encapsulated in nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon shells (A&#8208;Ni@NC) via pulsed laser ablation in liquid (PLAL). The synergistic integration of the amorphous Ni core and a defect&#8208;rich N&#8208;doped carbon shell markedly enhanced the catalytic activities for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), with low overpotentials of 182 mV for HER and 288 mV for OER at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1.0 m KOH. Furthermore, the bifunctional catalyst achieved a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.63 V and retained 98.9% of its initial performance after 100 h of operation. The nitrogen&#8208;rich carbon shell not only offered abundant active sites and structural protection but also promoted charge transport. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed that N&#8208;doping optimized intermediate adsorption energies, while the amorphous Ni core facilitated efficient electron transfer. This green and scalable synthesis strategy provides a promising platform for developing a wide range of transition metal@N&#8208;doped carbon hybrid catalysts for sustainable energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Haoran Cheng, Hong Seok Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction of PtRhNiMoPd Nanocrystals Facilitates Hydrogen Evolution from Acidic Electrolytic Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c05884</link>
      <description>Ziting Li, Pei Xiong, Min Wei, Jike Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412818028

                The development and design of Pt-based alloy catalysts with high activity and stability are important for the hydrogen evolution reaction, especially in acidic media. Here, we report a mild acid-impregnated reconfiguration strategy to construct defects and strain effect (PtRhNiMoPd NCs-80&#176;C-6h) by removing unstable Ni atoms in acetic acid treatment. Only 5.6 mV is required to achieve a current density of -10 mA cm-2 for PtRhNiMoPd NCs-80&#176;C-6h in an acid electrolyte. Meanwhile, PtRhNiMoPd NCs-80&#176;C-6h exhibits negligible degradation after 10,000 cycles, which is superior to commercial Pt/C. This suggests that surface reconstruction can expose more efficient active sites and improve the adsorption of intermediates on the active sites, enhancing the catalytic performance. This study provides a new perspective for the rational design of high-entropy alloy nanomaterials with an efficient hydrogen evolution performance.</description>
      <author>Ziting Li, Pei Xiong, Min Wei, Jike Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c05884</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox chemistry meets semiconductor defect physics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0270226</link>
      <description>Jian Gu, Jun Huang, Jun Cheng, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412824011

                Understanding how the electronic structure of electrodes influences electrocatalytic reactions has been a longstanding topic in the electrochemistry community, with predominant attention paid to metallic electrodes. In this work, we present a defect physics perspective on the effect of semiconductor band structure on electrochemical redox reactions. Specifically, the Haldane&#8211;Anderson model, originally developed to study multiple charge states of transition-metal defects in semiconductors, is extended to describe electrochemical redox reactions by incorporating the solvent effect, inspired by the Holstein model. The solvent coordinate and the actual charge on the redox species in reduced and oxidized states are assumed to be in instant equilibrium, and the transitions between these states are defined by the framework of Green&#8217;s function. With these treatments, the charge state transitions are handled in a self-consistent manner, and the implications of charge self-consistency (or, equivalently, charge self-regulation) on electrocatalysis can be investigated explicitly. We first confirm that this self-consistent approach is essential to accurately depict the hybridization effect of band structure by comparing the model-calculated ionization potential and electron affinity, as well as the redox potential of the species, with those obtained from density functional theory calculations. Next, we illustrate that the effect of charge self-consistency is key to obtaining a fuller understanding of the catalytic activities of semiconductor electrodes and the source of asymmetry in reorganization energies, which is often observed in prior ab initio molecular dynamics simulations. In addition, we discuss how band structure impacts redox reactions in the strong coupling limit. Finally, we compare our work with other relevant studies in the literature.</description>
      <author>Jian Gu, Jun Huang, Jun Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0270226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPmoire: a tool for constructing accurate machine learning force fields in moir&#233; systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01740-0</link>
      <description>J.D. Liu, Fang Zhong, Hongming Weng, Quansheng Wu, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412825031

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J.D. Liu, Fang Zhong, Hongming Weng, Quansheng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01740-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Generation of Chlorine and Hydrogen from Waste Poly(vinyl chloride)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c04559</link>
      <description>Bertrand J. Neyhouse, Grace Cook, Rahul Kant Jha, Anne J. McNeil, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412826285

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bertrand J. Neyhouse, Grace Cook, Rahul Kant Jha, Anne J. McNeil</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c04559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anion-Exchange-Membrane Electrolysis with Alkali-Free Water Feed</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00466</link>
      <description>Mohsin Muhyuddin, Carlo Santoro, Luigi Osmieri, Valerio C.A. Ficca, Ariel Friedman, Karam Yassin, Gioele Pagot, Enrico Negro, Anastasiia Konovalova, Grace Lindquist, Liam Twight, Minkyoung Kwak, Enrico Berretti, Vito Di Noto, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Lior Elbaz, Dario R. Dekel, Piercarlo Mustarelli, Shannon W. Boettcher, Alessandro Lavacchi, Plamen Atanassov, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412829789

                Hydrogen is a green and sustainable energy vector that can facilitate the large-scale integration of intermittent renewable energy, renewable fuels for heavy transport, and deep decarbonization of hard-to-abate industries. Anion-exchange-membrane water electrolyzers (AEM-WEs) have several achieved or expected competitive advantages over other electrolysis technologies, including the use of precious metal-free electrocatalysts at both electrodes, fluorine-free hydrocarbon-based ionomeric membranes and bipolar plates based on inexpensive materials. Contrasting the analogous proton-exchange-membrane system (PEM-WE), where pure water is circulated (no support electrolyte), the current generation of AEM-WEs necessitates the circulation of a dilute aqueous alkaline electrolyte for reaching high energy efficiency and durability. For several reasons, including but not limited to lower cost of balance-of-plant, lower operating cost and improved device's lifetime, achieving high cell efficiency and performance using an alkali-free water feed is highly desirable. In this review, we develop and build a foundational understanding of AEM-WEs operating with pure water, as well as discuss the effects of operating with natural water feeds like seawater. After a discussion of the possible advantages of pure-water-fed AEM-WEs, we cover the thermodynamic and kinetic processes involved in AEM-WE, followed by a detailed review of materials and components and their integration in the device. We highlight the influence of electrolyte composition and alkali/electrolyte-free feed on the membrane-electrode assembly, ionomers, electrocatalysts, porous transport layer, bipolar plates and operating configuration. We provide evidence for how the pure water feed engenders several issues related to the degradation of device components and propose mitigation strategies.</description>
      <author>Mohsin Muhyuddin, Carlo Santoro, Luigi Osmieri, Valerio C.A. Ficca, Ariel Friedman, Karam Yassin, Gioele Pagot, Enrico Negro, Anastasiia Konovalova, Grace Lindquist, Liam Twight, Minkyoung Kwak, Enrico Berretti, Vito Di Noto, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Lior Elbaz, Dario R. Dekel, Piercarlo Mustarelli, Shannon W. Boettcher, Alessandro Lavacchi, Plamen Atanassov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton-Relaying Adsorbates Induce Non-Nernstian Behavior in Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01767</link>
      <description>Lulu Zhang, Donghui Zhao, Weiqiang Tang, Yanxia Chen, Jun Huang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412839552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lulu Zhang, Donghui Zhao, Weiqiang Tang, Yanxia Chen, Jun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c01767</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells: Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-9845-5_5</link>
      <description>Yinshi Li, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412845495

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yinshi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-9845-5_5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and Theoretical Investigations on Magneto&#8208;Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction of CoFeP Nanorods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500321</link>
      <description>Mohammed Arkham Belgami, Afsal S. Shajahan, Erdenebayar Baasanjav, Vishwanath Ankalgi, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Sang Mun Jeong, Chandra Sekhar Rout, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412845647

                Abstract The pursuit of low&#8208;cost, efficient, and durable electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution in alkaline media is vital for water&#8208;splitting applications. Herein, the hydrothermal&#8208;based synthesis of a multiphase ferromagnetic catalyst CoFeP, comprising FeP, CoP, and Fe 2 P is reported. Structural analyses confirm the coexistence of phases, and electrochemical studies reveal excellent OER activity. CoFeP exhibits an overpotential of 335 mV at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 116 mV dec &#8722;1 without a magnetic field, whereas under the magnetic field of 2000 G, these values lowered to 235 mV and 93 mV dec &#8722;1 , respectively. The enhancement is attributed to magnetic&#8208;field&#8208;induced spin polarization, surface reconstruction, and increased ECSA from 70 to 110 mF cm &#8722;2 , highlighting the potential of magnetic modulation for boosting catalytic performance. Through spin&#8208;polarized Density Functional Theory (DFT) simulations, the structural and electronic features of CoFeP, providing theoretical insights into its role in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) is elucidated. This investigation demonstrates that the application of an external magnetic field significantly reduces the overpotential required for OER as the adsorption of intermediate species becomes stronger due to more charge transfer, aligning with experimental observations. These findings highlight the interplay between magnetic fields and electrocatalytic performance, offering a pathway to enhance energy conversion efficiency.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Arkham Belgami, Afsal S. Shajahan, Erdenebayar Baasanjav, Vishwanath Ankalgi, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Sang Mun Jeong, Chandra Sekhar Rout</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast synthesis of V8C7 catalysts for efficient chemical hydrogen evolution via decoupled water electrolysis in a dual-circuit redox flow battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150665</link>
      <description>Ying Ma, Huimei Yuan, Guanghui Zhang, Shengliang Qi, Shumin Liu, Xiaofei Lei, Xu Zong, Weiguang Ma, Xiangkun Ma, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 162(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412848627

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Ma, Huimei Yuan, Guanghui Zhang, Shengliang Qi, Shumin Liu, Xiaofei Lei, Xu Zong, Weiguang Ma, Xiangkun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric hydrogenation-driven enhancement of activity and selectivity in V-anchored N3-doped graphene catalysts for nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150787</link>
      <description>Wenming Lu, Kai Guo, Daifei Ye, Xiaxia Gong, Wei Liu, Jing Xu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 162(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412860694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenming Lu, Kai Guo, Daifei Ye, Xiaxia Gong, Wei Liu, Jing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Empirical Energy Functions Using Physics&#8208; and Machine Learning&#8208;Based Extensions: Structure, Dynamics and Spectroscopy of Modified Benzenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70162</link>
      <description>Kham Lek Chaton, Markus Meuwly, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(21)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412861632

                The effects of replacing individual contributions to an empirical energy function are assessed for halogenated benzenes (X-Bz, X = H, F, Cl, Br) and chlorinated phenols (Cl-PhOH). Introducing electrostatic models based on minimal distributed charges (MDCM) instead of usual atom-centered point charges (PCs) to realistically describe features such as &#963;-holes yields overestimated hydration free energies unless the van der Waals parameters are reparametrized. Scaling van der Waals ranges by 10% to 20% for three Cl-PhOH and most X-Bz yield results within experimental error bars, which is encouraging, whereas for benzene (H-Bz) PC-based models are sufficient. Replacing the bonded terms by a neural network-trained energy function featuring fluctuating atom-centered PCs also yields qualitatively correct hydration free energies, which can be brought into agreement with experiments within error bars after adaptation of the van der Waals parameters. The infrared spectroscopy of Cl-PhOH is rather well captured by all models, although the ML-based energy function performs somewhat better in the region of the framework modes. The present work finds that refinements of empirical energy functions for targeted applications are a meaningful way toward more quantitative and physics-based simulations. At the same time, empirical energy functions have matured to a remarkable degree, at least for the species considered in the present work.</description>
      <author>Kham Lek Chaton, Markus Meuwly</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of Hydrogen Storage in MOF-5 and Li-MOF-5 by Ring Polymer Molecular Dynamics on Self-Consistently Fine-Tuned Machine-Learned Interatomic Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01522</link>
      <description>Julien Steffen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. 129(30)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412865197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Julien Steffen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A sustainable Ru catalyzed aerobic oxidation based on high loading magnetic ionic nanoparticles network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-07505-5</link>
      <description>Sepideh Asgari, Mina Ghahremani, Sepideh Najafvand-Derikvandi, Hesamodin Moradi, Mina Tavakolian, Fariborz Mansouri, Babak Karimi, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412867463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sepideh Asgari, Mina Ghahremani, Sepideh Najafvand-Derikvandi, Hesamodin Moradi, Mina Tavakolian, Fariborz Mansouri, Babak Karimi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-07505-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Dynamics of Amorphous Phase in Sriro3 Catalyst During Oxygen Evolution Reaction Revealed by Operando Total X-Ray Scattering Measurements and Pair Distribution Function Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5358492</link>
      <description>Kentaro Kobayashi, Satoshi Hiroi, Koji Ohara, Neha Thakur, Mukesh Kumar, Weijie Cao, Kengo Nakada, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Hiroki Yamada, Seiya Shimono, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yoshiharu Uchimoto, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412873697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kentaro Kobayashi, Satoshi Hiroi, Koji Ohara, Neha Thakur, Mukesh Kumar, Weijie Cao, Kengo Nakada, Jo&#8208;Chi Tseng, Hiroki Yamada, Seiya Shimono, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yoshiharu Uchimoto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5358492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal-Doped Mo-Vacancy Defects at MoS2 Basal Plane for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-025-00515-z</link>
      <description>Donghwi Kim, Sangheon Lee, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim, Korean Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412874275

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Donghwi Kim, Sangheon Lee, Hyung&#8208;Kyu Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-025-00515-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Enhancement of Charge Transfer and Friction at the Interfaces between Defected h-BN and Water: a Density-Functional-Theory-Based Machine Learning Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10338-025-00628-2</link>
      <description>Yu Zhong, Hao Li, Yufeng Guo, Acta Mechanica Solida Sinica. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412787133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Zhong, Hao Li, Yufeng Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10338-025-00628-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping uncertainty using differentiable programming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18940</link>
      <description>Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird, Fernando V. Lima, John R. Kitchin, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412788564

                Abstract Uncertainty quantification (UQ) and propagation is a ubiquitous challenge in science, permeating our field in a general fashion, and its importance cannot be overstated. Recently, the commoditization of differentiable programming, motivated by the development of machine learning, has allowed easier access to tools for evaluating derivatives of complex systems, of implicit and nonlinear nature. Motivated by this, we develop a UQ mapping approach based on differentiable programming principles. The approach is novel, faster, and yields equally accurate results when compared against the current state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art approaches for the UQ problem, which is to quantify and map uncertainty using linear methods or expensive Monte Carlo simulations. Three case studies&#8212;namely a continuous stirred tank reactor, a membrane reactor, and a fed&#8208;batch bioreactor&#8212;are assessed and compared against typical uncertainty mapping techniques. Lastly, the method allows the use of a single model implementation to perform forward and inverse uncertainty maps, easily switching mapping directions.</description>
      <author>Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird, Fernando V. Lima, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic modeling of kinetic surface segregation mechanisms in CuAu binary alloys: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113413</link>
      <description>Nadia Ait Labyad, Abdallah El-asri, Moussa Amrani, Andrew J. Gellman, Herv&#233; Mart&#237;nez, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412792535

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nadia Ait Labyad, Abdallah El-asri, Moussa Amrani, Andrew J. Gellman, Herv&#233; Mart&#237;nez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113413</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
