<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:43:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15742-4.00038-7</link>
      <description>Bilal Ni&#351;anc&#305;, Ramazan Ko&#231;ak, Fatma B. Ni&#351;anc&#305;, Sefa U&#231;ar, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393184127

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bilal Ni&#351;anc&#305;, Ramazan Ko&#231;ak, Fatma B. Ni&#351;anc&#305;, Sefa U&#231;ar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15742-4.00038-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Surface Transformations of Lanthanum Nickelate Electrocatalysts during Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c00863</link>
      <description>Yi&#8208;Hsuan Wu, Marcel Jan&#225;k, Paula M. Abdala, Camelia N. Borca, Anna Wach, Agnieszka M. Kierzkowska, Felix Donat, Thomas Huthwelker, Denis A. Kuznetsov, Christoph R. M&#252;ller, Journal of the American Chemical Society (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393187140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi&#8208;Hsuan Wu, Marcel Jan&#225;k, Paula M. Abdala, Camelia N. Borca, Anna Wach, Agnieszka M. Kierzkowska, Felix Donat, Thomas Huthwelker, Denis A. Kuznetsov, Christoph R. M&#252;ller</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c00863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical inspection of high-efficiency single-atom catalysts based on &#960;-&#960; conjugated holey graphitic g-C7N3 monolayer: marvelous water-splitting and oxygen reduction reactions activities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.087</link>
      <description>Chunyao Fang, Xihang Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Di Liu, Xiaomeng Cui, Jingcheng Xu, Chenglong Shi, Rongshan Qin, Journal of Materials Science and Technology (Shenyang). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393189834

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunyao Fang, Xihang Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Di Liu, Xiaomeng Cui, Jingcheng Xu, Chenglong Shi, Rongshan Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and Electrocatalytic Applications of Noble Metal Chalcogenides Nanomaterials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300686</link>
      <description>Zhenya Hu, Lei Huang, Lin Xu, Hui Liu, Shaonan Tian, Jun Yang, ChemElectroChem (Weinheim). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393191730

                Abstract In this review, we first focus on summarizing recent advances in effective and facile strategies for the ration synthesis of noble metal chalcogenide nanomaterials (NMCNs), and then, we systematically introduce their applications in catalyzing typical electrochemical reactions. Finally, we make some perspectives on the challenges for using NMCNs in electrocatalysis with respect to further enhancement of their electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Zhenya Hu, Lei Huang, Lin Xu, Hui Liu, Shaonan Tian, Jun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing active sites and regulating electron distribution to design Mo and P co-doped Ni for efficient alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114069</link>
      <description>Wei Xu, Shijie Li, J. Wang, Bo Peng, Wenjie Yin, Xiaohu Tang, Yu Shen, Molecular catalysis (Online). 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393192829

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Xu, Shijie Li, J. Wang, Bo Peng, Wenjie Yin, Xiaohu Tang, Yu Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D Monoclinic Ir&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Ru&lt;sub&gt;1&#8208;x&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Solid Solution with Ru&#8208;Enhanced Electrocatalytic Activity for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402226</link>
      <description>Keyang Qin, Hao Yu, Wenxiang Zhu, Yunjie Zhou, Zhiyong Guo, Qi Shao, Yangbo Wu, Xuepeng Wang, Youyong Li, Yujin Ji, Fan Liao, Yang Liu, Zhenhui Kang, Mingwang Shao, Advanced functional materials (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393198977

                Abstract The rutile phase IrO 2 , as a promising catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), still falls short of satisfactory activity. Here, a novel 1D monoclinic phase iridium&#8208;ruthenium oxide solid solution (m&#8208;Ir x Ru 1&#8208;x O 2 ) is reported. For m&#8208;Ir x Ru 1&#8208;x O 2 with different metal proportions, the optimal m&#8208;Ir 0.91 Ru 0.09 O 2&#8208;&#948; catalyst exhibits excellent OER activity under acidic conditions with an overpotential of 180 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . As an anode catalyst in a proton exchange membrane electrolyzer, m&#8208;Ir 0.91 Ru 0.09 O 2&#8208;&#948; with a low catalyst loading (0.1 mg cm &#8722;2 ) can operate &#8776;256 h at 1.8 V with a high current density over 900 mA cm &#8722;2 at room temperature. Such a satisfied stability may have originated from the specific morphology and crystal structure, which is confirmed by the transient potential scanning test. Density functional theory calculations show that the Ru in the m&#8208;Ir x Ru 1&#8208;x O 2 facilitates decreasing the OER overpotentials due to the electron transfer from Ru to Ir.</description>
      <author>Keyang Qin, Hao Yu, Wenxiang Zhu, Yunjie Zhou, Zhiyong Guo, Qi Shao, Yangbo Wu, Xuepeng Wang, Youyong Li, Yujin Ji, Fan Liao, Yang Liu, Zhenhui Kang, Mingwang Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Zr dopants on properties of PtNi nanoparticles for ORR catalysis: A DFT modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0193848</link>
      <description>Riccardo Farris, Boris V. Merinov, Albert Bruix, Konstantin M. Neyman, &#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics. 160(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393200358

                Pt-based alloys, such as Pt3Ni, are among the best electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells. Doping of PtNi alloys with Zr was shown to enhance the durability of the operating ORR catalysts. Rationalizing these observations is hindered by the absence of atomic-level data for these tri-metallic materials, even when not exposed to the fuel cell operation conditions. This study aims at understanding structure&#8211;property relations in Zr-doped PtNi nanoparticles as a key to their ORR function. In particular, we calculated, using a method based on density functional theory, the most stable chemical orderings of pristine and Zr-doped Pt3Ni particles containing over 400 atoms. We thus clarify (i) preferential location and charge states of Zr atoms in the Pt3Ni NPs; (ii) effect of doping Zr atoms on the stability of the Pt skin of the Pt3Ni NPs; (iii) charge redistribution induced by Zr dopants; (iv) layer-by-layer atomic ordering in the Pt3Ni/Zr NPs with the increasing Zr content; and (v) effect of Zr atoms on the adsorption energies of O and OH species as indicators of the ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Riccardo Farris, Boris V. Merinov, Albert Bruix, Konstantin M. Neyman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0193848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni&#9472;Co&#9472;O&#9472;S Derived Catalysts on Hierarchical N&#8208;doped Carbon Supports with Strong Interfacial Interactions for Improved Hybrid Water Splitting Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310087</link>
      <description>Yunfeng Qiu, Yongxia Zhang, Ye Sun, Xinghua Li, Yanxia Wang, Zhuangzhuang Ma, Shaoqin Liu, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393200548

                Abstract Simultaneously improving electrochemical activity and stability is a long&#8208;term goal for water splitting. Herein, hierarchical N&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes on carbon nanowires derived from PPy are grown on carbon cloth, serving as a support for NiCo oxides/sulfides. The hierarchical electrodes annealed in N 2 or H 2 /N 2 display improved intrinsic activity and stability for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and glucose oxidation reaction. Compared with Pt/C||Ir/C in alkaline media, the glucose electrolysis assembled with electrodes exhibits a cell voltage of 1.38 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , durability for &gt;12 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 , and resistance to glucose/gluconic acid poisoning. In addition, electrocatalysts can also be applied in ethanol oxidation reactions. Systematic characterizations reveal the strong interactions between NiCo and N&#8208;doped carbon support&#8208;induced partial charge transfer at the interface and regulate the local electronic structure of active sites. Density functional theory calculations demonstrate that the synergistic effect between N&#8208;doped carbon supports, metallic NiCo, and NiCo oxides/sulfides optimize the adsorption energy of H 2 O and the H* free energy for HER. The energy barrier of the dehydrogenation of glucose effectively decreased. This work will attract attention to the role of metal&#8208;support interactions in enhancing the intrinsic activity and stability of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yunfeng Qiu, Yongxia Zhang, Ye Sun, Xinghua Li, Yanxia Wang, Zhuangzhuang Ma, Shaoqin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of O and OH Adsorption on Transition Metal Oxide Surfaces from Bulk Descriptors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00111</link>
      <description>Benjamin M. Comer, Neha Bothra, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Michal Bajdich, Kirsten T. Winther, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393200658

                In the search for stable and active catalysts, density functional theory and machine learning-based models can accelerate the screening of materials. While stability is conveniently addressed on the bulk level of computation, the modeling of catalytic activity requires expensive surface simulations. In this work, we develop models for the surface adsorption energy of O and OH intermediates across a consistent and extensive data set of pure transition metal oxide surfaces. We show that adsorption energies across metal oxidation states of +2 to +6 are well captured from the metal&#8211;oxygen bond strength extracted from the bulk level calculation. Specifically, we calculate the integrated crystal orbital Hamiltonian population (ICOHP) of the metal&#8211;oxygen bond in the bulk oxide and employ a simple normalization scheme to obtain a strong correlation with the adsorption energetics. By combining our ICOHP descriptor with non-DFT features in a Gaussian Process regression (GPR) model, we achieve a high model accuracy with mean absolute errors of 0.166 and 0.219 eV for OH and O adsorption, respectively. By targeting the adsorption energy difference of the OH&#8211;OH adsorption with our GPR model, we predict the oxygen evolution reaction activity from bulk descriptors only. Furthermore, we utilize the strong correlation between the COHP and metal&#8211;oxygen bond lengths to rapidly predict the adsorption energetics and catalytic activity from the optimized bulk geometry. Our approach can enable an efficient search for active catalysts by eliminating the need for surface calculations in the initial screening phase.</description>
      <author>Benjamin M. Comer, Neha Bothra, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Michal Bajdich, Kirsten T. Winther</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving high selectivity and activity of CO2 electroreduction to formate by in-situ synthesis of single atom Pb doped Cu catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.137</link>
      <description>Yurui Xu, Xiao Liu, Minghui Jiang, Bichuan Chi, Yue Lu, Jinjun Guo, Ziming Wang, Suping Cui, Journal of colloid and interface science (Print). 665(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393210611

                Exploring highly selective and stable electrocatalysts is of great significance for the electrochemical conversion of CO2 into fuel. Herein, a three-dimensional (3D) nanostructure catalyst was developed by doping Pb single-atom (PbSA) in-situ on carbon paper (PbSA100-Cu/CP) through a low-energy and economical method. The designed catalyst exhibited abundant active sites and was beneficial to CO2 adsorption, activation, and subsequent conversion to fuel. Interestingly, PbSA100-Cu/CP showed a prominent Faraday efficiency (FE) of 97 % at &#8211;0.9 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs. RHE) and a high partial current density of 27.9 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 for formate. Also, the catalyst remained significantly stable for 60 h during the durability test. The reaction mechanism was investigated by density functional theory (DFT), demonstrating that the doping PbSA induced the electrons redistribution, promoted the formate generation, reduced the rate-determining step (RDS) energy barrier, and inhibited the hydrogen evolution reaction. The study aims to provide a new strategy for developing of single-atom catalysts with high selectivity and stability, which will help reduce environmental pressure and alleviate energy problems.</description>
      <author>Yurui Xu, Xiao Liu, Minghui Jiang, Bichuan Chi, Yue Lu, Jinjun Guo, Ziming Wang, Suping Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen generation via water splitting with hexagonal silicon monolayers as (photo)catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114081</link>
      <description>Riri Jonuarti, Wilson Agerico Di&#241;o, Hikaru Kobayashi, Suprijadi, - Ratnawulan, Rahmat Hidayat, Molecular catalysis (Online). 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393216663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Riri Jonuarti, Wilson Agerico Di&#241;o, Hikaru Kobayashi, Suprijadi, - Ratnawulan, Rahmat Hidayat</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated atomistic simulations of dissociated dislocations with &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; accuracy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.094120</link>
      <description>Laura Mismetti, Max Hodapp, Physical review. B. 109(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393222082

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Laura Mismetti, Max Hodapp</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.094120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Cooperative Mechanisms in Ultralow Copper-Loaded WC@NGC for Enhanced CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to Acetic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c00405</link>
      <description>Debabrata Bagchi, Mohd Riyaz, Jithu Raj, Soumyabrata Roy, Ashutosh Kumar Singh, Arjun Cherevotan, C. P. Vinod, Sebastian C. Peter, Chemistry of materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393225487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Debabrata Bagchi, Mohd Riyaz, Jithu Raj, Soumyabrata Roy, Ashutosh Kumar Singh, Arjun Cherevotan, C. P. Vinod, Sebastian C. Peter</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c00405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum Surface Water Orientation Dictates Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Kinetics in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c12934</link>
      <description>Aamir Hassan Shah, Zisheng Zhang, Chunru Wan, Sibo Wang, Ao Zhang, Laiyuan Wang, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Yu Huang, Xiangfeng Duan, Journal of the American Chemical Society (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393225502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aamir Hassan Shah, Zisheng Zhang, Chunru Wan, Sibo Wang, Ao Zhang, Laiyuan Wang, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Yu Huang, Xiangfeng Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c12934</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable electronic coupling of Fe-doped CoS2/reduced graphene oxide composites for boosting bifunctional water splitting activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174281</link>
      <description>Bo Fang, Yue Li, Jiaqi Yang, Ting L&#252;, Xinjuan Liu, Xiaohong Chen, Likun Pan, Zhenjie Zhao, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393227029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Fang, Yue Li, Jiaqi Yang, Ting L&#252;, Xinjuan Liu, Xiaohong Chen, Likun Pan, Zhenjie Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical regulating the M-site composition of Janus MXenes enables the tailoring design for highly active bifunctional ORR/OER catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.093</link>
      <description>Shuang Luo, Ninggui Ma, Jun Zhao, Yuhang Wang, Yaqin Zhang, Yan Xiong, Jun Fan, Journal of Materials Science and Technology (Shenyang). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393227083

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuang Luo, Ninggui Ma, Jun Zhao, Yuhang Wang, Yaqin Zhang, Yan Xiong, Jun Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly area-selective atomic layer deposition of device-quality Hf1-xZrxO2 thin films through catalytic local activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150760</link>
      <description>Hyo&#8208;Bae Kim, Jeong&#8208;Min Lee, Dong Jun Sung, Ji&#8208;Hoon Ahn, Woo&#8208;Hee Kim, Chemical engineering journal (1996. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393227170

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyo&#8208;Bae Kim, Jeong&#8208;Min Lee, Dong Jun Sung, Ji&#8208;Hoon Ahn, Woo&#8208;Hee Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced manufacturing in heterogeneous catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837672035-00001</link>
      <description>Swarom Kanitkar, Biswanath Dutta, Ashraf Abedin, Xue Bai, Daniel Haynes, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393232922

                Heterogeneous catalysis is one of the major pillars of the chemical and refining industry that has evolved significantly from the need for more efficient and sustainable industrial processes. Advanced manufacturing will play an important role in driving this evolution through its ability to create or design more favourable interactions with catalytic components that can result in more active and stable catalysts, efficient catalytic processes, and sustainable reaction systems. This chapter provides an overview of recent progress that covers various catalyst coating methods, application of 3D printing in catalytic supports and reactor components, and process intensification through additive manufacturing. The work also provides a brief overview on artificial intelligence/machine learning in heterogeneous catalysis that is helping to make/screen catalysts more efficiently. The work further highlights the impacts and challenges of implementing advanced manufacturing methods.</description>
      <author>Swarom Kanitkar, Biswanath Dutta, Ashraf Abedin, Xue Bai, Daniel Haynes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/bk9781837672035-00001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exceptional Performance of &lt;scp&gt;3D&lt;/scp&gt; Additive Manufactured &lt;scp&gt;NiFe&lt;/scp&gt; Phosphite Oxyhydroxide Hollow Tubular Lattice Plastic Electrode for Large&#8208;Current&#8208;Density Water Oxidization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12740</link>
      <description>Liping Ding, Lin Zhang, Gaoyuan Li, Shuyan Chen, Han Yan, Haibiao Tu, Jianmin Su, Qi Li, Yanfeng Tang, Yanqing Wang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393233209

                In this article, we report a 3D NiFe phosphite oxyhydroxide plastic electrode using high&#8208;resolution digital light processing (DLP) 3D&#8208;printing technology via induced chemical deposition method. The as&#8208;prepared 3D plastic electrode exhibits no template requirement, freedom design, low&#8208;cost, robust, anticorrosion, lightweight, and micro&#8208;nano porous characteristics. It can be drawn to the conclusion that highly oriented open&#8208;porous 3D geometry structure will be beneficial for improving surface catalytic active area, wetting performance, and reaction&#8211;diffusion dynamics of plastic electrodes for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysis process. Density functional theory (DFT) calculation interprets the origin of high activity of NiFe(PO 3 )O(OH) and demonstrates that the implantation of the &#8211;PO 3 can effectively bind the 3d orbital of Ni in NiFe(PO 3 )O(OH), lead to the weak adsorption of intermediate, make electron more active to improve the conductivity, thereby lowing the transform free energy of *O to *OOH. The water oxidization performance of as&#8208;prepared 3D NiFe(PO 3 )O(OH) hollow tubular (HT) lattice plastic electrode has almost reached the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art level compared with the as&#8208;reported large&#8208;current&#8208;density catalysts or 3D additive manufactured plastic/metal&#8208;based electrodes, especially for high current OER electrodes. This work breaks through the bottleneck that plagues the performance improvement of low&#8208;cost high&#8208;current electrodes.</description>
      <author>Liping Ding, Lin Zhang, Gaoyuan Li, Shuyan Chen, Han Yan, Haibiao Tu, Jianmin Su, Qi Li, Yanfeng Tang, Yanqing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding pH-Dependent Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Metal Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00461</link>
      <description>Xinnan Mao, Lu Wang, Youyong Li, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393234212

                Exploring low-cost and high-efficiency catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) kinetics in both acidic and alkaline environments could dramatically improve the efficiency of hydrogen fuel cells and their industrial applications. During the electrochemical process, the effect of pH is a complicating factor and is of great importance in identifying high-efficiency electrocatalysts. In this work, we conducted systematic computations to gain a deep understanding of the pH-dependent ORR activity on Pt, Pd, and their near-surface alloys (NSAs). The effects of pH were calculated by employing the double-reference method, and our calculated pH-dependent current densities are in good agreement with the experimental results. High-throughput calculations identified a series of NSA catalysts with superior ORR performance under acidic or alkaline conditions, and we have developed a pH-corrected theoretical model to efficiently estimate the ORR activity on metal catalysts. This work underscores the importance of considering pH effects when evaluating ORR activity from calculations and provides a strategy for designing superior ORR electrocatalysts in acidic and alkaline solutions.</description>
      <author>Xinnan Mao, Lu Wang, Youyong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cr dopants and S vacancies in ZnS to trigger efficient photocatalytic H2 evolution and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.094</link>
      <description>Linping Bao, Yushuai Jia, Xiaohui Ren, Xin Liu, Chunhui Dai, Sajjad Ali, M. Bououdina, Zhang&#8208;Hui Lu, Chao Zeng, Journal of Materials Science and Technology (Shenyang). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393238252

                Driven by endless solar energy, photocatalytic H2 evolution from water splitting and CO2 conversion to hydrocarbon fuels over semiconductor photocatalysts are of great potential to simultaneously settle the greenhouse effect and energy shortage. Herein, Cr-doped zinc sulfide (ZnS) with accompanying sulphur vacancies (Vs) photocatalytic materials is developed by a facile hydrothermal method. The Cr dopants centralize photoinduced holes and Vs trap electrons, forming a synergistic effect for accelerating charge separation and transfer. The reaction energy barrier for both H2 evolution and CO2 reduction has been optimized. Therefore, in the absence of a cocatalyst, the optimal catalyst (Zn0.94Cr0.06S) achieves an outstanding H2 evolution activity of 20.3 mmol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1, which is approximately 2.9 times higher than 6.9 mmol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 for pristine ZnS. In addition, in the gas-solid reaction system without co-catalysts or sacrificial agents, the Zn0.94Cr0.06S exhibits a considerable CO evolution rate of 19.56 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1, about 10.1 times higher than ZnS (1.94 &#956;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1). Both the performances for H2 evolution and CO2 reduction of Zn0.94Cr0.06S outperform most of the previously reported photocatalysts. Particularly, the Zn0.94Cr0.06S possesses superior stability, the photoactivity of which exhibits no noticeable deactivation after six cycles' reactions. This work may shed light on the rational design and fabrication of highly efficient materials via combining individual element doping and defect engineering.</description>
      <author>Linping Bao, Yushuai Jia, Xiaohui Ren, Xin Liu, Chunhui Dai, Sajjad Ali, M. Bououdina, Zhang&#8208;Hui Lu, Chao Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.01.094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SMATool: Strength of Materials Analysis Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109189</link>
      <description>Chinedu Ekuma, Computer physics communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393254202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chinedu Ekuma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances on Computational Modeling of Supported Single-Atom and Cluster Catalysts: Characterization, Catalyst&#8211;Support Interaction, and Active Site Heterogeneity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14040224</link>
      <description>Jiayi Xu, Colton J. Lund, Prajay Patel, Yu Lim Kim, Cong Liu, Catalysts. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393254287

                To satisfy the need for catalyst materials with high activity, selectivity, and stability for energy conversion, material design and discovery guided by theoretical insights are a necessity. In the past decades, the rise in theoretical investigations into the properties of catalyst materials, reaction mechanisms, and catalyst design principles has shed light on the catalysis field. Quantitative structure&#8211;activity relationships have been developed through incorporating spectroscopic simulations, electronic structure calculations, and reaction mechanistic studies. In this review, we report the state-of-the-art computational approaches to catalyst materials characterization for supported single-atom and cluster catalysts utilizing spectroscopic simulations, i.e., XANES simulation, and material properties investigation via electronic-structure calculations. Furthermore, approaches regarding reaction mechanisms, focusing on active site heterogeneity, are also discussed.</description>
      <author>Jiayi Xu, Colton J. Lund, Prajay Patel, Yu Lim Kim, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14040224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical bonding dictates drastic critical temperature difference in two seemingly identical superconductors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2316101121</link>
      <description>Robert H. Lavroff, Julen Mun&#225;rriz, Claire E. Dickerson, Francisco Mu&#241;oz, Anastassia N. Alexandrova, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393255486

                Though YB 6 and LaB 6 share the same crystal structure, atomic valence electron configuration, and phonon modes, they exhibit drastically different phonon-mediated superconductivity. YB 6 superconducts below 8.4 K, giving it the second-highest critical temperature of known borides, second only to MgB 2 . LaB 6 does not superconduct until near-absolute zero temperatures (below 0.45 K), however. Though previous studies have quantified the canonical superconductivity descriptors of YB 6 &#8217;s greater Fermi-level (E f ) density of states and higher electron&#8211;phonon coupling (EPC), the root of this difference has not been assessed with full detail of the electronic structure. Through chemical bonding, we determine low-lying, unoccupied 4f atomic orbitals in lanthanum to be the key difference between these superconductors. These orbitals, which are not accessible in YB 6 , hybridize with &#960; B&#8211;B bonds and bring this &#960;-system lower in energy than the &#963; B&#8211;B bonds otherwise at E f . This inversion of bands is crucial: the optical phonon modes we show responsible for superconductivity cause the &#963;-orbitals of YB 6 to change drastically in overlap, but couple weakly to the &#960;-orbitals of LaB 6 . These phonons in YB 6 even access a crossing of electronic states, indicating strong EPC. No such crossing in LaB 6 is observed. Finally, a supercell (the M k-point) is shown to undergo Peierls-like effects in YB 6 , introducing additional EPC from both softened acoustic phonons and the same electron-coupled optical modes as in the unit cell. Overall, we find that LaB 6 and YB 6 have fundamentally different mechanisms of superconductivity, despite their otherwise near-identity.</description>
      <author>Robert H. Lavroff, Julen Mun&#225;rriz, Claire E. Dickerson, Francisco Mu&#241;oz, Anastassia N. Alexandrova</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2316101121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Electrocatalytic Activity in HMF Oxidation to FDCA by Fine&#8208;Tuning the Degree of NiOOH Phase Over Ni Nanoparticles Supported on Graphene Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400779</link>
      <description>Sorasak Klinyod, Nuttapon Yodsin, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Zikkawas Pasom, Sunpet Assavapanumat, Marisa Ketkaew, Pinit Kidkhunthod, Tetsu Yonezawa, Supawadee Namuangruk, Chularat Wattanakit, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393259803

                Abstract The development of an efficient electrocatalyst for HMF oxidation to FDCA has been in the early stages. Herein, the NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam is fabricated as an electrocatalyst for FDCA production. However, the electrocatalytic performance of the untreated NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam is observed with moderate Faradaic efficiency (FE) (73.0%) and FDCA yield (80.2%). By electrochemically treating the NiNPs/GO&#8208;Ni&#8208;foam in an alkaline solution with positive potential at different treatment durations, the degree of NiOOH on metal surfaces is changed. The distinctive electrocatalytic activity obtained when using the different NiOOH degrees allows to understand the crucial impact of NiOOH species in HMF electrooxidation. Enhancing the portion of the NiOOH phase on the electrocatalyst surface improves electrocatalytic activity in terms of FE and FDCA yield up to 94.8&#177;4.8% and 86.9&#177;4.1%, respectively. Interestingly, as long as the NiOOH portion on the electrocatalyst surface is preserved or regenerated, the electrocatalyst performance can be intact even after several catalytic cycles. The theoretical study via density functional theory (DFT) also agrees with the experimental observations and confirms that the NiOOH phase facilitates the electrochemical transformation of HMF to FDCA through the HMFCA pathway, and the potential limiting step of the overall reaction is the oxidation of FFCA to FDCA.</description>
      <author>Sorasak Klinyod, Nuttapon Yodsin, Mai Thanh Nguyen, Zikkawas Pasom, Sunpet Assavapanumat, Marisa Ketkaew, Pinit Kidkhunthod, Tetsu Yonezawa, Supawadee Namuangruk, Chularat Wattanakit</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible Hydrogen Electrode (RHE) Scale Dependent Surface Pourbaix Diagram at Different pH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00298</link>
      <description>Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Wang Yuan, Hao Li, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393301713

                In the analysis of electrocatalysis mechanisms and the design of catalysts, the effect of electrochemistry-induced surface coverage is a critical consideration that should not be overlooked. The surface Pourbaix diagram emerges as a fundamental tool in this context, providing essential insights into the surface coverage of adsorbates generated via electrochemical potential-driven water activation. A classic surface Pourbaix diagram considers the pH effects by correcting the free energy of H+ ions by the concentration-dependent term: &#8722;kBT ln(10) &#215; pH, which is independent of the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) scale. However, this is sometimes inconsistent with the experimentally observed potential-dependent surface coverage at an RHE scale, especially under high-pH conditions. Here, we derived the pH-dependent surface Pourbaix diagram at an RHE scale by considering the energetics computed by density functional theory with the Bayesian Error Estimation Functional with van der Waals corrections (BEEF-vdW), the electric field effects, the derived adsorption-induced dipole moment and polarizability, and the potential of zero-charge. Using Pt(111) as the typical example, we found that the surface coverage predicted by the proposed RHE-dependent surface Pourbaix diagram can significantly minimize the discrepancy between theory and experimental observations, especially under neutral-alkaline, moderate-potential conditions. This work provides a new methodology and establishes guidelines for the precise analysis of the surface coverage prior to the evaluation of the activity of an electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Heng Liu, Di Zhang, Wang Yuan, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validation workflow for machine learning interatomic potentials for complex ceramics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</link>
      <description>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash, Computational materials science. 239(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393373529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kimia Ghaffari, Salil Bavdekar, Douglas E. Spearot, Ghatu Subhash</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.112983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process Operability Analysis of Membrane-Based Direct Air Capture for Low-Purity CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsengineeringau.3c00069</link>
      <description>Vitor V. Gama, Beatriz Dantas, Oishi Sanyal, Fernando V. Lima, ACS Engineering Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393277124

                Addressing climate change constitutes one of the major scientific challenges of this century, and it is widely acknowledged that anthropogenic CO2 emissions largely contribute to this issue. To achieve the "net-zero" target and keep the rise in global average temperature below 1.5 &#176;C, negative emission technologies must be developed and deployed at a large scale. This study investigates the feasibility of using membranes as direct air capture (DAC) technology to extract CO2 from atmospheric air to produce low-purity CO2. In this work, a two-stage hollow fiber membrane module process is designed and modeled using the AVEVA Process Simulation platform to produce a low-purity (&#8776;5%) CO2 permeate stream. Such low-purity CO2 streams could have several possible applications such as algae growth, catalytic oxidation, and enhanced oil recovery. An operability analysis is performed by mapping a feasible range of input parameters, which include membrane surface area and membrane performance metrics, to an output set, which consists of CO2 purity, recovery, and net energy consumption. The base case for this simulation study is generated considering a facilitated transport membrane with high CO2/N2 separation performance (CO2 permeance = 2100 GPU and CO2/N2 selectivity = 1100), when tested under DAC conditions. With a constant membrane area, both membranes' intrinsic performances are found to have a considerable impact on the purity, recovery, and energy consumption. The area of the first module plays a dominant role in determining the recovery, purity, and energy demands, and in fact, increasing the area of the second membrane has a negative impact on the overall energy consumption, without improving the overall purities. The CO2 capture capacity of DAC units is important for implementation and scale-up. In this context, the performed analysis showed that the m-DAC process could be appropriate as a small-capacity system (0.1&#8211;1 Mt/year of air), with reasonable recoveries and overall purity. Finally, a preliminary CO2 emissions analysis is carried out for the membrane-based DAC process, which leads to the conclusion that the overall energy grid must be powered by renewable sources for the technology to qualify within the negative emissions category.</description>
      <author>Vitor V. Gama, Beatriz Dantas, Oishi Sanyal, Fernando V. Lima</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsengineeringau.3c00069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenges of hydrogen production from biomass gasification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13613-9.00005-2</link>
      <description>Jingwei Chen, Yilin Guo, Xiaomin Wu, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393323912

                With the development of alternative energy sources, biomass gasification for hydrogen production technology has attracted high attentions from researchers. This chapter introduces three main aspects: biomass gasification for hydrogen production technology, enhancement strategies for hydrogen production from biomass gasification, and hydrogen purification technology. The physical and chemical processes of hydrogen production from traditional biomass gasification, the effects of various key parameters on the performance of hydrogen production from biomass gasification, and the advantages and disadvantages of existing hydrogen purification technologies are introduced in details. Although the technology of hydrogen production from biomass gasification has been studied for many years, there are still challenges that hinder the commercialization and industrialization of hydrogen production technology from biomass gasification. The challenges including the detailed gasification evolution mechanisms of biomass, the gasification interactions between biomass components, the development of new catalysts and purification technologies, and the antiaging of catalytic and purification materials have been proposed in this chapter. In particular, there is a lack of precise and detailed descriptions of the gasification evolution mechanism of biomass macromolecules, catalytic and deactivation mechanisms of catalysts, which provide a theoretical basis for precise manipulation of the direction of hydrogen production reactions from biomass gasification. Finally, it is hoped that by overcoming the challenges presented, the technical barriers of hydrogen production from biomass gasification can be broken through, and the hydrogen production technology from biomass gasification can be commercialized and industrialized.</description>
      <author>Jingwei Chen, Yilin Guo, Xiaomin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-13613-9.00005-2</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
