<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 01:20:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Direct Methane to Methanol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15740-0.00130-0</link>
      <description>Ebrahim Ghanbari, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402559239

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ebrahim Ghanbari, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15740-0.00130-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equivariance is essential, local representation is a need: A comprehensive and critical study of machine learning potentials for tobermorite phases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113363</link>
      <description>Keming Zhu, Zhijuan Zhang, Computational Materials Science. 246(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402565410

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Keming Zhu, Zhijuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rigidly Axial O Coordination-Induced Spin Polarization on Single Ni&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;C Site by MXene Coupling for Boosting Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09592</link>
      <description>Guanping Wei, Zongchang Mao, Lingli Liu, Tiantian Hao, Ling Zhu, Simin Xu, Xijun Wang, Shaobin Tang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402567430

                Regulating the spin states in transition-metal (TM)-based single-atom catalysts (SACs), such as the TM-N</description>
      <author>Guanping Wei, Zongchang Mao, Lingli Liu, Tiantian Hao, Ling Zhu, Simin Xu, Xijun Wang, Shaobin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concave Grain Boundaries Stabilized by Boron Segregation for Efficient and Durable Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404839</link>
      <description>Xin Geng, Miquel Vega&#8208;Paredes, Xiaolong Lu, P. Chakraborty, Yue Li, Christina Scheu, Zhenyu Wang, Baptiste Gault, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402567530

                Abstract The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is a critical process that limits the efficiency of fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries due to its slow kinetics, even when catalyzed by platinum (Pt). To reduce Pt usage, enhancing both the specific activity and electrochemically active surface area (ECSA) of Pt catalysts is essential. Here, ultrafine, grain boundary (GB)&#8208;rich Pt nanoparticle assemblies are proposed as efficient ORR catalysts. These nanowires offer a large ECSA and a high density of concave GB sites, which improve specific activity. Atoms at these GB sites exhibit increased coordination and lattice distortion, leading to a favorable reduction in oxygen binding energy and enhanced ORR performance. Furthermore, boron segregation stabilizes these GBs, preserving active sites during catalysis. The resulting boron&#8208;stabilized Pt nanoassemblies demonstrate ORR specific and mass activities of 9.18 mA cm &#8722;2 and 6.40 A mg &#8722;1 Pt (at 0.9 V vs. RHE), surpassing commercial Pt/C catalysts by over 35&#8208;fold, with minimal degradation after 60 000 potential cycles. This approach offers a versatile platform for optimizing the catalytic performance of a wide range of nanoparticle systems.</description>
      <author>Xin Geng, Miquel Vega&#8208;Paredes, Xiaolong Lu, P. Chakraborty, Yue Li, Christina Scheu, Zhenyu Wang, Baptiste Gault</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of catalytic activity of BSCF towards electrochemical oxygen reactions using different synthetic approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.138</link>
      <description>Sachin Bhagat, Nandita Singh, Monika Singh, Ashish Kumar Singh, Suryabhan Singh, Uday Pratap Azad, Akhilesh Kumar Singh, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 88(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sachin Bhagat, Nandita Singh, Monika Singh, Ashish Kumar Singh, Suryabhan Singh, Uday Pratap Azad, Akhilesh Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Selective Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Formic Acid Conversion: A First-Principles Study of Single-Atom and Dual-Atom Catalysts on Tin Disulfide Monolayers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02283</link>
      <description>Guan-Ming Chen, Margherita Buraschi, Rashid Al-Heidous, Satyanarayana Bonakala, Fedwa El&#8208;Mellouhi, Clotilde S. Cucinotta, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402573649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guan-Ming Chen, Margherita Buraschi, Rashid Al-Heidous, Satyanarayana Bonakala, Fedwa El&#8208;Mellouhi, Clotilde S. Cucinotta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure phase change induced by nonequilibrium effects in molecular-scale junctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.l121405</link>
      <description>Hao Wang, Kah Meng Yam, Zhuoling Jiang, Na Guo, Chun Zhang, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402576387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Wang, Kah Meng Yam, Zhuoling Jiang, Na Guo, Chun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.l121405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced ORR Kinetics and Stability Through Synergy of Pt-Ni Clustering and Porous N-doped C/Ca Aerogel Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cep.2024.109999</link>
      <description>Muhammad Umair Mushtaq, Lin Zhu, Danni Li, Khurram Shahzad Ayub, Zain Abbas, Waqas Qamar Zaman, Ji Yang, Chemical Engineering and Processing - Process Intensification. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402577767

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Umair Mushtaq, Lin Zhu, Danni Li, Khurram Shahzad Ayub, Zain Abbas, Waqas Qamar Zaman, Ji Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cep.2024.109999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural, Optical, and Magnetic Studies of Nickel-Doped &#946;-Ga2O3 Monoclinic and Spinel Polycrystalline Powders</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11452-8</link>
      <description>A. R. Suresh Babu, N. Madhusudhana Rao, Journal of Electronic Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402592270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. R. Suresh Babu, N. Madhusudhana Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11452-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen spillover enhances the selective hydrogenation of &#945;,&#946;-unsaturated aldehydes on the Cu-O-Ce interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100438</link>
      <description>Jinyun Cui, Jing Wang, Teng Xu, Jiabao Lin, Kunlong Liu, Pengxin Liu, Chinese Journal of Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402557608

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinyun Cui, Jing Wang, Teng Xu, Jiabao Lin, Kunlong Liu, Pengxin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100438</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
