<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 01:08:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Constant potential energetics of metallic and semiconducting electrodes: A benchmark study on 2D materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0202849</link>
      <description>Hedda Oschinski, Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Karsten Reuter, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399320804

                Grand-canonical (GC) constant-potential methods within an implicit solvent environment provide a general approach to compute the potential-dependent energetics at electrified solid&#8211;liquid interfaces with first-principles density-functional theory. Here, we use a mindfully chosen set of 27 isostructural 2D metal halides MX2 to analyze the variation of this energetics when the electronic structure changes from metallic to semiconducting and insulating state. Apart from expectable changes due to the opening up of the electronic bandgap, the calculations also show an increasing sensitivity to the numerical Brillouin zone integration and electronic smearing, which imposes computational burdens in practice. We rationalize these findings within the picture of the total interfacial capacitance arising from a series connection of the electrochemical double-layer capacitance and the so-called quantum capacitance resulting from the filling of electronic states inside the electrode. For metals, the electrochemical double-layer capacitance dominates at all potentials, and the entire potential drop takes place in the electrolyte. For semiconductors, the potential drop occurs instead fully or partially inside the electrode at potentials within or just outside the bandgap. For 2D semiconductors, the increased sensitivity to numerical parameters then results from the concomitantly increased contribution of the quantum capacitance that is harder to converge. Fortunately, this understanding motivates a simple extension of the CHE + DL approximation for metals, which provides the approximate GC energetics of 2D semiconductors using only quantities that can be obtained from computationally undemanding calculations at the point of zero charge and a generic double-layer capacitance.</description>
      <author>Hedda Oschinski, Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Karsten Reuter</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0202849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plugin-based interoperability and ecosystem management for the MolSSI Driver Interface Project</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214279</link>
      <description>Taylor Barnes, Sara Ellis, J. Chen, Steven J. Plimpton, Jessica A. Nash, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399321824

                The MolSSI Driver Interface (MDI) Project is an effort to simplify and standardize the process of enabling tight interoperability between independently developed code bases and is supported by numerous software packages across the domain of chemical physics. It enables a wide variety of use cases, including quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics, advanced sampling, path integral molecular dynamics, machine learning, ab initio molecular dynamics, etc. We describe two major developments within the MDI Project that provide novel solutions to key interoperability challenges. The first of these is the development of the MDI Plugin System, which allows MDI-supporting libraries to be used as highly modular plugins, with MDI enforcing a standardized application programming interface across plugins. Codes can use these plugins without linking against them during their build process, and end-users can select which plugin(s) they wish to use at runtime. The MDI Plugin System features a sophisticated callback system that allows codes to interact with plugins on a highly granular level and represents a significant advancement toward increased modularity among scientific codes. The second major development is MDI Mechanic, an ecosystem management tool that utilizes Docker containerization to simplify the process of developing, validating, maintaining, and deploying MDI-supporting codes. Additionally, MDI Mechanic provides a framework for launching MDI simulations in which each interoperating code is executed within a separate computational environment. This eliminates the need to compile multiple production codes within a single computational environment, reducing opportunities for dependency conflicts and lowering the barrier to entry for users of MDI-enabled codes.</description>
      <author>Taylor Barnes, Sara Ellis, J. Chen, Steven J. Plimpton, Jessica A. Nash</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;insulator&#8211;semiconductor photoelectrodes for enhanced photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00820g</link>
      <description>Shice Wei, Xuewen Xia, Bi Shi, Huolin Shen, Xuefeng Wu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Xingli Zou, Kai Huang, David W. Zhang, Qianyi Sun, Allen J. Bard, E. T. Yu, Ji Li, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399326921

                Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting provides a scalable and integrated platform to harness renewable solar energy for green hydrogen production. The practical implementation of PEC systems hinges on addressing three critical challenges: enhancing energy conversion efficiency, ensuring long-term stability, and achieving economic viability. Metal-insulator-semiconductor (MIS) heterojunction photoelectrodes have gained significant attention over the last decade for their ability to efficiently segregate photogenerated carriers and mitigate corrosion-induced semiconductor degradation. This review discusses the structural composition and interfacial intricacies of MIS photoelectrodes tailored for PEC water splitting. The application of MIS heterostructures across various semiconductor light-absorbing layers, including traditional photovoltaic-grade semiconductors, metal oxides, and emerging materials, is presented first. Subsequently, this review elucidates the reaction mechanisms and respective merits of vacuum and non-vacuum deposition techniques in the fabrication of the insulator layers. In the context of the metal layers, this review extends beyond the conventional scope, not only by introducing metal-based cocatalysts, but also by exploring the latest advancements in molecular and single-atom catalysts integrated within MIS photoelectrodes. Furthermore, a systematic summary of carrier transfer mechanisms and interface design principles of MIS photoelectrodes is presented, which are pivotal for optimizing energy band alignment and enhancing solar-to-chemical conversion efficiency within the PEC system. Finally, this review explores innovative derivative configurations of MIS photoelectrodes, including back-illuminated MIS photoelectrodes, inverted MIS photoelectrodes, tandem MIS photoelectrodes, and monolithically integrated wireless MIS photoelectrodes. These novel architectures address the limitations of traditional MIS structures by effectively coupling different functional modules, minimizing optical and ohmic losses, and mitigating recombination losses.</description>
      <author>Shice Wei, Xuewen Xia, Bi Shi, Huolin Shen, Xuefeng Wu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Xingli Zou, Kai Huang, David W. Zhang, Qianyi Sun, Allen J. Bard, E. T. Yu, Ji Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00820g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study of adsorption properties and CO oxidation reaction on surfaces of higher tungsten boride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-63676-7</link>
      <description>Aleksandra D. Radina, Viktor S. Baidyshev, Ilya V. Chepkasov, Nikita Matsokin, Tariq Altalhi, Boris I. Yakobson, Alexander G. Kvashnin, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399339614

                Abstract Most modern catalysts are based on precious metals and rear-earth elements, making some of organic synthesis reactions economically insolvent. Density functional theory calculations are used here to describe several differently oriented surfaces of the higher tungsten boride WB 5-x , together with their catalytic activity for the CO oxidation reaction. Based on our findings, WB 5-x appears to be an efficient alternative catalyst for CO oxidation. Calculated surface energies allow the use of the Wulff construction to determine the equilibrium shape of WB 5-x particles. It is found that the (010) and (101) facets terminated by boron and tungsten, respectively, are the most exposed surfaces for which the adsorption of different gaseous agents (CO, CO 2 , H 2 , N 2 , O 2 , NO, NO 2 , H 2 O, NH 3 , SO 2 ) is evaluated to reveal promising prospects for applications. CO oxidation on B-rich (010) and W-rich (101) surfaces is further investigated by analyzing the charge redistribution during the adsorption of CO and O 2 molecules. It is found that CO oxidation has relatively low energy barriers. The implications of the present results, the effects of WB 5-x on CO oxidation and potential application in the automotive, chemical, and mining industries are discussed.</description>
      <author>Aleksandra D. Radina, Viktor S. Baidyshev, Ilya V. Chepkasov, Nikita Matsokin, Tariq Altalhi, Boris I. Yakobson, Alexander G. Kvashnin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-63676-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Charge Transfer Unveils Antideactivation of Ru at High Potentials for the Alkaline Hydrogen Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03622</link>
      <description>H. C. Shi, Yang Yang, Pin Meng, Jiahe Yang, Wei Zheng, Pengcheng Wang, Yunlong Zhang, Xingyan Chen, Zhiyu Cheng, Cichang Zong, Dongdong Wang, Qianwang Chen, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399368506

                The activity of Ru-based alkaline hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) electrocatalysts usually decreases rapidly at potentials higher than 0.1 V (vs a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE)), which significantly limits the lifetime of fuel cells. It is found that this phenomenon is caused by the overadsorption of the O species due to the overcharging of Ru nanoparticles at high potentials. Here, Mn1Ox(OH)y clusters-modified Ru nanoparticles (Mn1Ox(OH)y@Ru/C) were prepared to promote charge transfer from overcharged Ru nanoparticles to Mn1Ox(OH)y clusters. Mn1Ox(OH)y@Ru/C exhibits high HOR activity and stability over a wide potential range of 0&#8211;1.0 V. Moreover, a hydroxide exchange membrane fuel cell with a Mn1Ox(OH)y@Ru/C anode delivers a high peak power density of 1.731 W cm&#8211;2, much superior to that of a Pt/C anode. In situ X-ray absorption fine structure (XAFS) analysis and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that Mn in Mn1Ox(OH)y clusters could receive more electrons from overcharged Ru at higher potentials and significantly decrease the overadsorption of the O species on Ru, thus permitting the HOR on Ru to proceed at high potentials. This study provides guidance for the design of alkaline HOR catalysts without activity decay at high potentials.</description>
      <author>H. C. Shi, Yang Yang, Pin Meng, Jiahe Yang, Wei Zheng, Pengcheng Wang, Yunlong Zhang, Xingyan Chen, Zhiyu Cheng, Cichang Zong, Dongdong Wang, Qianwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atoms on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Can Catalyze Water Oxidation in Photoelectrochemical Experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03319</link>
      <description>Shi Wu, Wu Lu, Nikita Denisov, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Giorgio Zoppellaro, Xiaoyu Yang, Patrik Schmuki, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399380646

                Photoelectrochemical water splitting on n-type semiconductors is highly dependent on catalysis of the rate-determining reaction of O2 evolution. Conventionally, in electrochemistry and photoelectrochemistry O2 evolution is catalyzed by metal oxide catalysts like IrO2 and RuO2, whereas noble metals such as Pt are considered unsuitable for this purpose. However, our study finds that Pt, in its single-atom form, exhibits exceptional cocatalytic properties for photoelectrochemical water oxidation on a TiO2 photoanode, in contrast to Pt in a nanoparticle form. The decoration of Pt single atoms onto TiO2 yields a remarkable current density of 5.89 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.23 VRHE, surpassing bare TiO2 (or Pt nanoparticle decorated TiO2) by 2.52 times. Notably, this enhancement remains consistent over a wide pH range. By accompanying theoretical work, we assign this significant enhancement to an improved charge transfer and separation efficiency along with accelerated kinetics in the oxygen evolution reaction facilitated by the presence of Pt single atoms on the TiO2 surface.</description>
      <author>Shi Wu, Wu Lu, Nikita Denisov, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Giorgio Zoppellaro, Xiaoyu Yang, Patrik Schmuki</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of High Entropy Alloys on a Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Approaching Active Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01278</link>
      <description>Jing Liang, Yanling Ma, Yanjie Li, Wencong Zhang, Hao Hu, Jie Su, Zhenpeng Yao, Wenpei Gao, Wen Shang, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399380880

                High-entropy alloys (HEAs) have garnered considerable attention as promising nanocatalysts for effectively utilizing Pt in catalysis toward oxygen reduction reactions due to their unique properties. Nonetheless, there is a relative dearth of attention regarding the structural evolution of HEAs in response to electrochemical conditions. In this work, we propose a thermal reduction method to synthesize high entropy nanoparticles by leveraging the confinement effect and abundant nitrogen-anchored sites provided by pyrolyzed metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs). Notably, the prepared catalysts exhibit enhanced activity accompanied by structural reconstruction during electrochemical activation, approaching 1 order of magnitude higher mass activity compared to Pt/C in oxygen reduction. Atomic-scale structural characterization reveals that abundant defects and single atoms are formed during the activation process, contributing to a significant boost in the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction reactions. This study provides deep insights into surface reconstruction engineering during electrochemical operations, with practical implications for fuel cell applications.</description>
      <author>Jing Liang, Yanling Ma, Yanjie Li, Wencong Zhang, Hao Hu, Jie Su, Zhenpeng Yao, Wenpei Gao, Wen Shang, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-support spin orders: Crucial effect on electrocatalytic oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0207891</link>
      <description>Yi-jie Chen, Jun Wen, Zhenlin Luo, Fu-li Sun, Wenxian Chen, Gui&#8722;Lin Zhuang, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399494915

                Magnetic property (e.g. spin order) of support is of great importance in the rational design of heterogeneous catalysts. Herein, we have taken the Ni-supported ferromagnetic (FM) CrBr3 support (Nix/CrBr3) to thoroughly investigate the effect of spin-order on electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) via spin-polarized density functional theory calculations. Specifically, Ni loading induces anti-FM coupling in Ni-Cr, leading to a transition from FM-to-ferrimagnetic (FIM) properties, while Ni-Ni metallic bonds create a robust FM direct exchange, benefiting the improvement of the phase transition temperature. Interestingly, with the increase in Ni loading, the easy magnetic axis changes from out-of-plane (2D-Heisenberg) to in-plane (2D-XY). The adsorption properties of Nix/CrBr3, involving O2 adsorption energy and configuration, are not governed by the d-band center but strongly correlate with magnetic anisotropy. It is noteworthy that the applied potential and electrolyte acidity triggers spin-order transition phenomena during the ORR and induces the catalytic pathway change from 4e- ORR to 2e- ORR with the excellent onset potential of 0.93 V/reversible hydrogen electrode, comparable to the existing most excellent noble-metal catalysts. Generally, these findings offer new avenues to understand and design heterogeneous catalysts with magnetic support.</description>
      <author>Yi-jie Chen, Jun Wen, Zhenlin Luo, Fu-li Sun, Wenxian Chen, Gui&#8722;Lin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0207891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seawater electrolysis for fuels and chemicals production: fundamentals, achievements, and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00822c</link>
      <description>Changjian Lin, Chang Yu, Junting Dong, Yingnan Han, Hongling Huang, Wenbin Li, Yafang Zhang, Xin Tan, Jieshan Qiu, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399500181

                The production of value-added fuels and chemicals via seawater electrolysis is a promising step or support towards sustainable energy development and carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Changjian Lin, Chang Yu, Junting Dong, Yingnan Han, Hongling Huang, Wenbin Li, Yafang Zhang, Xin Tan, Jieshan Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00822c</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
