<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:18:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing the &#8220;anomalous&#8221; electrochemical Stark shift of CO at Pt(111) through vibrational spectroscopy and density-functional theory calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122694</link>
      <description>Elias Diesen, Mehmet Ugur Coskun, S. D&#237;az-Coello, Vanessa J. Bukas, Julia Kunze&#8208;Liebh&#228;user, Karsten Reuter, Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406160174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elias Diesen, Mehmet Ugur Coskun, S. D&#237;az-Coello, Vanessa J. Bukas, Julia Kunze&#8208;Liebh&#228;user, Karsten Reuter</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2025.122694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/crystalline NiZr heterojunction nanorods for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction prepared by magnetron sputtering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178575</link>
      <description>Jinsen Tian, Junhao Qin, Han Zhang, Mingwei Tang, Jing Wu, Jiahua Zhu, Jun Shen, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406161078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinsen Tian, Junhao Qin, Han Zhang, Mingwei Tang, Jing Wu, Jiahua Zhu, Jun Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights into tunable photocatalytic water splitting performance of black phosphorus quantum dots through doping different nonmetallic heteroatoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.503</link>
      <description>Song Xu, Jianguang Feng, Xiaoning Wang, Qiong Sun, Hongzhou Dong, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406165308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Song Xu, Jianguang Feng, Xiaoning Wang, Qiong Sun, Hongzhou Dong, Liyan Yu, Lifeng Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of transition-metal-cluster-anchored g-C3N4 for the electrochemical catalytic hydrogenation of carbon dioxide to C1 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115076</link>
      <description>Shuwei Zhang, Huining Feng, Ruiyang Tang, Hui Li, Yang Wu, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406167755

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuwei Zhang, Huining Feng, Ruiyang Tang, Hui Li, Yang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning covalent bonding of single transition metal atom doped in S vacant MoS2 for catalytic CO2 reduction reaction product selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162339</link>
      <description>Poobodin Mano, Thanadol Jitwatanasirikul, Thantip Roongcharoen, Kaito Takahashi, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;, Applied Surface Science. 688(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406168446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Poobodin Mano, Thanadol Jitwatanasirikul, Thantip Roongcharoen, Kaito Takahashi, Supawadee Namuangruk&#8236;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Reduction of Nitric Oxide on Alumina-Supported Ultra-Small Nickel Particles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/surfaces8010006</link>
      <description>Ramazan T. Magkoev, Yong Men, Reza Behjatmanesh&#8208;Ardakani, Mohammadreza Elahifard, N. Pukhaeva, Aleksandr A. Takaev, Ramazan A. Khekilaev, &#1058;. &#1058;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1075;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077;&#1074;, &#1054;. &#1043;. &#1040;&#1096;&#1093;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;, Surfaces. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406169609

                The adsorption and reaction of nitric oxide (NO) molecules on the surface of the model-supported metal/oxide system, consisting of Ni nanoparticles deposited on &#945;-Al2O3 (0001) in ultra-high vacuum, have been studied using in situ surface-sensitive techniques and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. As a combination of X-ray and Auger electron spectroscopy (XPS, AES), Fourier-transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy, and temperature-programmed desorption (TPD) techniques reveals, there is a threshold of Ni particle mean size (&lt;d&gt;) of c.a. 2 nm, differentiating the electron state of adsorbed NO molecules and their reaction. The main feature of Ni particles normally not exceeding 2 nm is that the NO adsorbs in the form of (NO)2 dimers, whereas, for larger particles, the NO molecules adsorb in the form of monomers, usually characteristic for the bulk Ni substrate. This difference is demonstrated to be the main reason for the different reaction of NO molecules on the surface of Ni/alumina. The striking feature is that, in the case of ultra-small Ni particles (&lt;d&gt; &#8804; 2 nm), the nitrous oxide (N2O) molecules are formed upon heating as a result of the NO self-reduction mechanism, which are otherwise not formed in the case of larger Ni particles. According to DFT results, this is due to the significant synergistic impact of NO co-adsorption on the neighboring NO dissociation reaction over ultra-small Ni particles, mediated by the metal/oxide perimeter interface. The observed molecular conversion effects offer an opportunity to tune the catalytic selectivity of this and related metal/oxide systems via varying the supported metal particle size.</description>
      <author>Ramazan T. Magkoev, Yong Men, Reza Behjatmanesh&#8208;Ardakani, Mohammadreza Elahifard, N. Pukhaeva, Aleksandr A. Takaev, Ramazan A. Khekilaev, &#1058;. &#1058;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1075;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077;&#1074;, &#1054;. &#1043;. &#1040;&#1096;&#1093;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/surfaces8010006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same FeN4 Active Site, Different Activity: How Redox Peaks Control Oxygen Reduction on Fe Macrocycles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00146</link>
      <description>Silvia Favero, Ruixuan Chen, Jacob C. H. Cheung, Luke Higgins, Hui Luo, Mengnan Wang, Jes&#250;s Barrio, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Alexander Bagger, Ifan E. L. Stephens, ACS electrochemistry.. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406172700

                Macrocycles show high activity for the electrochemical reduction of oxygen in alkaline media. However, even macrocycles with the same metal centers and MN4 active site can vary significantly in activity and selectivity, and to this date, a quantitative insight into the cause of these staggering differences has not been unambiguously reached. These macrocycles form a fundamental platform, similarly to platinum alloys for metal ORR catalyst, to unravel fundamental properties of FeNx catalysts. In this manuscript, we present a systematic study of several macrocycles, with varying active site motif and ligands, using electrochemical techniques, operando spectroscopy, and density functional theory (DFT) simulations. Our study demonstrates the existence of two families of Fe macrocycles for oxygen reduction in alkaline electrolytes: (i) weak *OH binding macrocycles with one peak in the voltammogram and high peroxide selectivity and (ii) macrocycles with close to optimal *OH binding, which exhibit two voltametric peaks and almost no peroxide production. Here, we also propose three mechanisms that would explain our experimental findings. Understanding what differentiates these two families could shed light on how to optimize the activity of pyrolyzed FeNx catalysts.</description>
      <author>Silvia Favero, Ruixuan Chen, Jacob C. H. Cheung, Luke Higgins, Hui Luo, Mengnan Wang, Jes&#250;s Barrio, Maria&#8208;Magdalena Titirici, Alexander Bagger, Ifan E. L. Stephens</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acselectrochem.4c00146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling Multiple pH-Dependent Factors on the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction at Au(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00081</link>
      <description>Er-Fei Zhen, Bing-Yu Liu, Mengke Zhang, Lulu Zhang, Chenyu Zhang, Jun Cai, Marko Melander, Jun Huang, Yanxia Chen, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406175469

                Understanding how the electrolyte pH affects electrocatalytic activity is a topic of crucial importance in a large variety of systems. However, unraveling the origin of the pH effects is complicated often by the fact that both the reaction driving forces and reactant concentrations in the electric double layer (EDL) change simultaneously with the pH value. Herein, we employ the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at Au(111)-aqueous solution interfaces as a model system to disentangle different pH-dependent factors. In 0.1 M NaOH, the HER current density at Au(111) in the potential range of &#8722;0.4 V &lt; ERHE &lt; 0 V is up to 60 times smaller than that in 0.1 M HClO4. A reaction model with proper consideration of the local reaction conditions within the EDL is developed. After correcting for the EDL effects, the rate constant for HER is only weakly pH-dependent. Our analysis unambiguously reveals that the observed pH effects are mainly due to the pH-dependent reorganization free energy, which depends on the electrostatic potential and the local reaction conditions within the EDL. Possible origins of the pH and temperature dependence of the activation energy and the electron transfer coefficients are discussed. This work suggests that factors influencing the intrinsic pH-dependent kinetics are easier to understand after proper corrections of EDL effects.</description>
      <author>Er-Fei Zhen, Bing-Yu Liu, Mengke Zhang, Lulu Zhang, Chenyu Zhang, Jun Cai, Marko Melander, Jun Huang, Yanxia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of CNTs composites with mono and bimetallic oxides for the oxygen evolution reactions in water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.111961</link>
      <description>Muhammad Khurram, Nadiah Y. Aldaleeli, Muhammad Yasir, Abid Ali, Sheza Muqaddas, Muhammad Naveed Arshad, Rizwan Shoukat, Diamond and Related Materials. 152(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406185824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Khurram, Nadiah Y. Aldaleeli, Muhammad Yasir, Abid Ali, Sheza Muqaddas, Muhammad Naveed Arshad, Rizwan Shoukat</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.111961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of High Purity Ethylene Using High-Index Facet Cu2O Nanocrystals Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125053</link>
      <description>Ahmad M. Harzandi, Seyed Parsa Amouzesh, Jiayi Xu, Taha Baghban-Ronaghi, Sahar Shadman, Fiona Collins, Gayoon Kim, Werner Kaminsky, Larry A. Curtiss, Cong Liu, Mohammad Asadi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406194395

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ahmad M. Harzandi, Seyed Parsa Amouzesh, Jiayi Xu, Taha Baghban-Ronaghi, Sahar Shadman, Fiona Collins, Gayoon Kim, Werner Kaminsky, Larry A. Curtiss, Cong Liu, Mohammad Asadi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focus on the catalysts to resist the phosphate poisoning in high-temperature proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60162-2</link>
      <description>Liyuan Gong, Li Tao, Lei Wang, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Shuangyin Wang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 68(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406199714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liyuan Gong, Li Tao, Lei Wang, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Shuangyin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60162-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect-Induced Bimetallic Cubic-Spinel NiO/NiCo2O4 heterostructures via Na-Incorporation towards efficient electrochemical water splitting performances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162352</link>
      <description>Sebastian Cyril Jesudass, Subramani Surendran, Gnanaprakasam Janani, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kim, Yong Il Park, Uk Sim, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406205422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sebastian Cyril Jesudass, Subramani Surendran, Gnanaprakasam Janani, Tae&#8208;Hoon Kim, Yong Il Park, Uk Sim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disclosure of the hydrogen evolution mechanism on [FeFe]-hydrogenases-inspired molecular catalysts &#8211; a DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1071/ch24137</link>
      <description>Siyao Qiu, Aimin Yu, Cheng E. Sun, Australian Journal of Chemistry. 78(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406211325

                The FeFe bio-inspired molecular catalysts that mimic the [FeFe] hydrogenases have been widely studied. However, the hydrogen evolution mechanism on the molecular catalysts is still not fully understood. In this work, the theoretical calculation was linked with experimental catalytic performance to reveal the possible reaction mechanism of FeFe molecular catalysts. The Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations on the FeFe molecular catalysts exhibited a good match with the experimental overpotential data, with a R2 of 0.592. The detailed DFT study indicated that the first H+/e&#8722; injection was the largest thermodynamic impediment in the whole hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) cycle which follows a proton transfer &#8211; electron transfer (PT-ET) mechanism. The injected hydrogen binds to the bridging position between FeFe centre (&#181;-H) and then transfers to a terminal hydrogen on Fe (t-H). Later, the t-H combines with the second injected hydrogen to form a H2 molecule which is then released from the catalyst. The effect of different ligands on HER was also studied. It was found that different ligands around the FeFe centre could significantly change the PT and ET energy, and some could provide additional binding sites for protons.</description>
      <author>Siyao Qiu, Aimin Yu, Cheng E. Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1071/ch24137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic asymmetric C-C coupling for CO2 reduction on dynamically reconstructed Ru&#948;+-O/Ru0-O sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55885-z</link>
      <description>Hongguang Zhang, Asfaw G. Yohannes, Heng Zhao, Li Zheng, Yejun Xiao, Xi Cheng, Hui Wang, Zhangkang Li, Samira Siahrostami, Md Golam Kibria, Jinguang Hu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406218936

                Solar-driven CO2 reduction to value-added C2 chemicals is thermodynamically challenging due to multiple complicated steps. The design of active sites and structures for photocatalysts is necessary to improve solar energy efficiency. In this work, atomically dispersed Ru-O sites in RuxIn2-xO3 are constructed by interior lattice anchoring of Ru. This results in the dynamic reconstruction of Ru&#948;+-O/Ru0-O sites upon photoexcitation, which facilitates the CO2 activation, *CO intermediates adsorption, and C-C coupling as demonstrated by varied in situ techniques. A SiO2 core in RuxIn2-xO3/SiO2 construction further enhances the solar energy utilization and individual RuxIn2-xO3 nanocrystals dispersion for photocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction. It results in the maximum ethanol production rate up to 31.6 &#956;mol/g/h with over 90% selectivity. DFT simulation reveals that the C2 dimer formation primarily underwent an asymmetric *CO-*CHO coupling route via a low-energy precedence ladder of *CHO. This work provides an insightful understanding of active sites with dynamic reconstruction towards asymmetric C-C coupling for CO2RR at the atomic scale. Understanding the role of atomic sites in photocatalytic CO2 reduction remains challenging. This study provides insights into dynamic Ru&#948;+-O/Ru0-O pair reconstruction and explores approaches to enhancing intermediate regulation and asymmetric *CO-*CHO coupling for producing C2+ products.</description>
      <author>Hongguang Zhang, Asfaw G. Yohannes, Heng Zhao, Li Zheng, Yejun Xiao, Xi Cheng, Hui Wang, Zhangkang Li, Samira Siahrostami, Md Golam Kibria, Jinguang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55885-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering highly selective NO3RR electrocatalysts: Integrating 2D materials with Nb-doped TiN for sustainable ammonia synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131524</link>
      <description>Guoning Feng, Yujie Sun, Ling Ren, Zehui Fang, Xin Chen, Rongjian Sa, Qiaohong Li, Chenghua Sun, Zuju Ma, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406229862

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoning Feng, Yujie Sun, Ling Ren, Zehui Fang, Xin Chen, Rongjian Sa, Qiaohong Li, Chenghua Sun, Zuju Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic electrolyte cations promote non-aqueous CO2 reduction by mediating interfacial electric fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01278-2</link>
      <description>Jon-Marc McGregor, Jay T. Bender, Amanda Schramm Petersen, Louise M. Ca&#241;ada, Jan Rossmeisl, Joan F. Brennecke, Joaquin Resasco, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406231824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jon-Marc McGregor, Jay T. Bender, Amanda Schramm Petersen, Louise M. Ca&#241;ada, Jan Rossmeisl, Joan F. Brennecke, Joaquin Resasco</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01278-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverse catalysts: tuning the composition and structure of oxide clusters through the metal support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01507-z</link>
      <description>L. Kempen, Mie Andersen, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406233749

                Computational modeling of metal&#8211;oxide interfaces is challenging due to the large search space of compositions and structures and the complexity of catalyst materials under operating conditions in general. In this work, we develop an efficient structure search workflow to discover chemically unique and relevant nanocluster geometries of inverse catalysts and apply it to ZnyOx and InyOx on Cu(111), Pd(111), and Au(111). We show that the workflow is successful in obtaining a large range of chemically distinct structures. Structural geometry trends are identified, including stable motifs such as tripod, rhombus, and pyramidal motifs. Using ab initio thermodynamics, we explore the in situ stability of the structures, including single-atom alloys, at a range of oxygen availabilities. This approach allows us to find trends such as the susceptibility to oxidation of the different systems and the range of stability of different cluster motifs. Our analysis highlights the importance of taking the diversity of sites exposed by metal&#8211;oxide interfaces into account in catalyst design studies.</description>
      <author>L. Kempen, Mie Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01507-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Metal Nanoclusters at the Atomic Level for Effective Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smm2.1317</link>
      <description>Chuan Mu, Zhihe Liu, Qiaofeng Yao, Qian He, Jianping Xie, SmartMat. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406234847

                ABSTRACT With the advances of nanochemistry in the past several decades, a diverse set of nanomaterials has been developed as electrocatalysts with enhanced activity, selectivity, and durability for electrocatalytic reactions. However, it has remained as a long challenge to systematically understand the mechanism of electrocatalytic reactions, which involves multiple protons&#8208;coupled electron transfer processes and varied products at the atomic level, intrinsically because of the complexity and polydispersity of the traditional nanomaterials. By sharp contrast, ligand&#8208;protected metal nanoclusters (NCs) possess atomically precise structures and abundant active sites, facilitating their applications as effective model electrocatalysts for revealing the mechanism of electrocatalytic reactions. This review summarizes recent progress in atom&#8208;level engineering of metal NCs as model catalysts for electrocatalytic reactions. Specifically, we first discuss the effects of metal composition engineering, including doping and size effects, on the electrocatalytic performance of metal NCs. Then similar electrocatalytic discussion extends to ligand effects of metal NCs, where ligand type and coverage engineering are deciphered. Moreover, we discuss how the overall charge and morphology of NCs modify their electrocatalytic performance. The fundamental and methodological insights summarized in this review should serve as useful references guiding the future development of effective metal electrocatalysts in diverse sectors of industry.</description>
      <author>Chuan Mu, Zhihe Liu, Qiaofeng Yao, Qian He, Jianping Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smm2.1317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonprecious Triple-Atom Catalysts with Ultrahigh Activity for Electrochemical Reduction of Nitrate to Ammonia: A DFT Screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17726</link>
      <description>Xiangyi Zhou, Mohsen Tamtaji, Weijun Zhou, William A. Goddard, GuanHua Chen, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406242426

                Electrochemical nitrate reduction to ammonia (NO3RR) is promising to not only tackle environmental issues caused by nitrate but also produce ammonia at room temperatures. However, two critical challenges are the lack of effective electrocatalysts and the understanding of related reaction mechanisms. To overcome these challenges, we employed first-principles calculations to thoroughly study the performance and mechanisms of triple-atom catalysts (TACs) composed of transition metals (including 27 homonuclear TACs and 4 non-noble bimetallic TACs) anchored on N-doped carbon (NC). We found five promising candidates possessing not only thermodynamic and electrochemical stability, but also high activity and selectivity for ammonia production. Among them, non-noble homonuclear Ni3@NC TAC show high activity with low theoretical limiting potential of &#8722;0.31 VRHE. Surprisingly, bimetallic Co2Ni@NC, Co2Cu@NC, and Fe2Ni@NC TACs show ultrahigh activity with theoretical limiting potentials of 0.00 VRHE, without a potential determining step in the whole reaction pathways, representing the best theoretical activity been reported up to date. These promising candidates are facilitated by circumventing the limit of scaling relationships, a well-known obstacle for single-atom catalysts. This study indicates that designing suitable TACs can be a promising strategy for efficiently electro-catalyzing NO3RR and breaking the limit of the scaling relationship.</description>
      <author>Xiangyi Zhou, Mohsen Tamtaji, Weijun Zhou, William A. Goddard, GuanHua Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic Selenide NiCo&#8208;Se/CFP as Effective Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalyst for Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405201</link>
      <description>Yajie Guo, Mengwei Wang, Cong Zhang, Kelun Jia, F. Niu, Ke Wang, ChemistrySelect. 10(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406243837

                Abstract The industrial application of green hydrogen production from water electrolysis strongly depends on the invention of low&#8208;cost, highly&#8208;active, and stable nonprecious electrocatalysts for an oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this work, a two&#8208;step process is developed to prepare a NiCo&#8208;Se/CFP bimetallic electrocatalyst by a low&#8208;temperature selenization of NiCo&#8208;PBA precursors electro&#8208;deposited on carbon fibre paper. The NiCo&#8208;Se/CFP bimetallic electrocatalyst exhibits good catalytic activity for the OER, with an overpotential of 307 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a Tafel slope of only 39.94 mV dec &#8722;1 in 1 M KOH. The steady current density and well&#8208;preserved microscopic morphology during the 20 h electrolysis proves its outstanding stability. The high inherent activity of the electrocatalyst is attributed to the 3D porous structure, the synergistic effects of Ni, and Co active components doping, and low&#8208;temperature selenization. The results provide an insightful reference for further improving composition and structure design while investigating nonprecious metal electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yajie Guo, Mengwei Wang, Cong Zhang, Kelun Jia, F. Niu, Ke Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valence Electron: A Descriptor of Spinel Sulfides for Sulfur Reduction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418090</link>
      <description>Zihan Shen, Pengfei Song, Wen Xie, Leonhard Tannesia, Kai Tang, Yuanmiao Sun, Shibo Xi, Zhichuan J. Xu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406247049

                Abstract Catalysts are essential for achieving high&#8208;performance lithium&#8211;sulfur batteries. The precise design and regulation of catalytic sites to strengthen their efficiency and robustness remains challenging. In this study, spinel sulfides and catalyst design principles through element doping are investigated. This research highlights the distinct role of lattice sulfur sites in lithium polysulfide conversion and emphasizes the differences in catalytic activity between metal and anion sites. The valence electron model as a descriptor can characterize catalytic performance, guiding the design of a (FeCo) 3 (PS) 4 catalyst co&#8208;doped with cation and anion. The (FeCo) 3 (PS) 4 exhibits the highest catalytic performance among spinel catalysts to data, particularly under high sulfur loading conditions. It achieves an initial specific capacity of 1205.9 mAh g &#8722;1 (6.1 mAh cm &#8722;2 ) at a sulfur loading of 5 mg cm &#8722;2 and 1192.7 mAh g &#8722;1 (11.9 mAh cm &#8722;2 ) at 10 mg cm &#8722;2 , demonstrating excellent electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Zihan Shen, Pengfei Song, Wen Xie, Leonhard Tannesia, Kai Tang, Yuanmiao Sun, Shibo Xi, Zhichuan J. Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion or inhibition? The effects of adsorbed oxygen species on methane activation over dilute alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162358</link>
      <description>Shuyun Zhou, Xin-Ying Lin, Juan Li, Rong Jiang, Sen Lin, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406269143

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuyun Zhou, Xin-Ying Lin, Juan Li, Rong Jiang, Sen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-modified multicomponent-doped Cr2O3 oxide: An efficient and ultra stable electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction and water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118937</link>
      <description>Zeyu Jin, Yuelin Wang, Linshan Zhu, Jingzi Zhang, Xi Lin, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406270045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyu Jin, Yuelin Wang, Linshan Zhu, Jingzi Zhang, Xi Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise Modulation of Moni4/Moo2 Nanowires Via a Ternary Nicofe Complex for Enhanced Electrochemical Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5093560</link>
      <description>Peng Zuo, Fanfan Liu, Fuyan Zhao, Xiaofei Zhang, Yun Li, Kaiqin Xu, Fang Xiaowei, Zhiwei Zhang, Yun Shen, Jinyun Liu, Yefeng Liu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406275085

                Developing clean and renewable energy technologies requires the design of efficient bifunctional catalysts that do not rely on inert metals for electrochemical water splitting. This study introduced a novel three-step strategy to fabricate NiCoFe-modified MoNi4/MoO2 nanowires supported on nickel foam substrates (denoted as NiCoFe-MoNi4/MoO2/NF), which demonstrate excellent catalytic performance with an impressively low overpotential of just 13 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 current density for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 230 mV at 50 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Notably, its performance greatly exceeded that of many noble-metal catalysts, requiring only 1.51 V for overall water splitting at 50 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 current density. The exceptional catalytic efficiency is ascribed to the unique one-dimensional (1D) nanostructure and the synergistic interactions between the NiCoFe complex and the MoNi4/MoO2 framework, which improve mass transfer, increase active site exposure, and enhance intrinsic catalytic activity. The incorporation of cobalt (Co) and iron (Fe) into the ternary complex significantly enhanced the efficiencies of both HER and OER, offering a promising route for developing high-performance, low-cost bifunctional electrocatalysts and advancing sustainable energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Peng Zuo, Fanfan Liu, Fuyan Zhao, Xiaofei Zhang, Yun Li, Kaiqin Xu, Fang Xiaowei, Zhiwei Zhang, Yun Shen, Jinyun Liu, Yefeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5093560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of single-atomic catalysts loaded on two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides for electrocatalytic oxygen reduction via high throughput ab initio calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.060</link>
      <description>Hao Sun, Liyao Gao, Yizhe Li, Qingzhen Xu, Yaping Li, Wenjun Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406276034

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Sun, Liyao Gao, Yizhe Li, Qingzhen Xu, Yaping Li, Wenjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress on NiCo-LDH electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.035</link>
      <description>Yubo Zhang, Zhe Zhang, Xiaoxuan Zhang, Jinsheng Li, Rui Guo, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406279417

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yubo Zhang, Zhe Zhang, Xiaoxuan Zhang, Jinsheng Li, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical prediction of metal-doped high C/N-ratio C N3 (x=7, 10, 13, 19) as single-atom catalysts for CO2RR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114808</link>
      <description>Haoyang Qiu, Huohai Yang, Qigang Chen, Manxi Leng, Xu Yang, Xin Chen, Molecular Catalysis. 573(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoyang Qiu, Huohai Yang, Qigang Chen, Manxi Leng, Xu Yang, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114808</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Role of Alkyl-Substituted Phosphonic Acids on Oxygen Reduction Reaction on Platinum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02609</link>
      <description>Honghong Lin, Chen Ling, Hongfei Jia, Liang Wang, Gaohua Zhu, Siwen Wang, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406283156

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Honghong Lin, Chen Ling, Hongfei Jia, Liang Wang, Gaohua Zhu, Siwen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02609</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EOSnet: Embedded Overlap Structures for Graph Neural Networks in Predicting Material Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03179</link>
      <description>Shuo Tao, Li Zhu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406283532

                Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) have emerged as powerful tools for predicting material properties, yet they often struggle to capture many-body interactions and require extensive manual feature engineering. Here, we present EOSnet (Embedded Overlap Structures for Graph Neural Networks), a novel approach that addresses these limitations by incorporating Gaussian Overlap Matrix (GOM) fingerprints as node features within the GNN architecture. Unlike models that rely on explicit angular terms or human-engineered features, EOSnet efficiently encodes many-body interactions through orbital overlap matrices, providing a rotationally invariant and transferable representation of atomic environments. The model demonstrates superior performance across various prediction tasks of materials' properties, achieving particularly notable results in properties sensitive to many-body interactions. For band gap prediction, EOSnet achieves a mean absolute error of 0.163 eV, surpassing previous state-of-the-art models. The model also excels in predicting mechanical properties and classifying materials, with 97.7% accuracy in metal/nonmetal classification. These results demonstrate that embedding GOM fingerprints into node features enhances the ability of GNNs to capture complex atomic interactions, making EOSnet a powerful tool for materials' discovery and property prediction.</description>
      <author>Shuo Tao, Li Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Gap-State Engineering of MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Alkaline Water and Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c13736</link>
      <description>Tao Sun, Tong Yang, Wenjie Zang, Jing Li, Xiaoyu Sheng, Enzhou Liu, Jiali Li, Xiao Hai, Huihui Lin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Chenliang Su, Maohong Fan, Ming Yang, Ming Lin, Shibo Xi, Ruqiang Zou, Jiong Lu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406283545

                Transition-metal dichalcogenides (TMDs), such as molybdenum disulfide (MoS2), have emerged as a generation of nonprecious catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), largely due to their theoretical hydrogen adsorption energy close to that of platinum. However, efforts to activate the basal planes of TMDs have primarily centered around strategies such as introducing numerous atomic vacancies, creating vacancy&#8211;heteroatom complexes, or applying significant strain, especially for acidic media. These approaches, while potentially effective, present substantial challenges in practical large-scale deployment. Here, we report a gap-state engineering strategy for the controlled activation of S atom in MoS2 basal planes through metal single-atom doping, effectively tackling both efficiency and stability challenges in alkaline water and seawater splitting. A versatile synthetic methodology allows for the fabrication of a series of single-metal atom-doped MoS2 materials (M1/MoS2), featuring widely tunable densities with each dopant replacing a Mo site. Among these (Mn1, Fe1, Co1, and Ni1), Co1/MoS2 demonstrates outstanding HER performance in both alkaline and seawater alkaline media, with overpotentials at a mere 159 and 164 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2, and Tafel slopes at 41 and 45 mV dec&#8211;1, respectively, which surpasses all reported TMD-based nonprecious materials and benchmark Pt/C catalysts in HER efficiency and stability during seawater splitting, which can be attributed to an optimal gap-state modulation associated with sulfur atoms. Experimental data correlating doping density and dopant identity with HER performance, in conjunction with theoretical calculations, also reveal a descriptor linked to near-Fermi gap state modulation, corroborated by the observed increase in unoccupied S 3p states.</description>
      <author>Tao Sun, Tong Yang, Wenjie Zang, Jing Li, Xiaoyu Sheng, Enzhou Liu, Jiali Li, Xiao Hai, Huihui Lin, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Chenliang Su, Maohong Fan, Ming Yang, Ming Lin, Shibo Xi, Ruqiang Zou, Jiong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c13736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weakening Pd&#9472;O Bonds by an Amorphous Pd Layer to Promote Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409404</link>
      <description>Lian Ying Zhang, Weiyong Yuan, Jinghao Lu, Maoxia He, Chunxian Guo, Haijie Cao, Chang Ming Li, Xin Zhao, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406288033

                Abstract Construction of core&#8211;shell structured electrocatalysts with a thin noble metal shell is an effective strategy for lowering the usage of the noble metal and improving electrocatalytic properties because of the structure&#8208;induced geometric and electronic effects. Here, the synthesis of a novel core&#8211;shell structured nanocatalyst consisting of a thin amorphous Pd shell and a crystalline PdCu core and its significantly improved electrocatalytic properties for both formic acid oxidation and oxygen reduction reactions are shown. The electrocatalyst exhibits 4.1 times higher catalytic peak current density and better stability in the formic acid oxidation compared to both a PdCu nanoalloy catalyst and a Commercial Pd&#8211;C catalyst. An excellent electrocatalytic performance of the core&#8211;shell nanocatalyst is also observed in the oxygen reduction reaction. Computational calculation results reveal that tuning of the electronic state of Pd by the amorphous shell and the Cu in the PdCu core weaken the binding strength of surface Pd&#9472;O bonds, leading to a bond elongation to facilitate bond breaking. As a result, the electrocatalytic activity in both formic acid oxidation and oxygen reduction reactions is enhanced.</description>
      <author>Lian Ying Zhang, Weiyong Yuan, Jinghao Lu, Maoxia He, Chunxian Guo, Haijie Cao, Chang Ming Li, Xin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically doped carbon on highly porous nickel sulfide for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.480</link>
      <description>Sung&#8208;Jin Kim, Yongheum Choi, Hyun-Jong Kim, Tae Joo Park, Young Min Park, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406290075

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sung&#8208;Jin Kim, Yongheum Choi, Hyun-Jong Kim, Tae Joo Park, Young Min Park</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning in electrocatalysis - living up to the hype?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101649</link>
      <description>&#193;rni Bj&#246;rn H&#246;skuldsson, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406291098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#193;rni Bj&#246;rn H&#246;skuldsson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2025.101649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XYZ2 (X/Y = Ge, Pb, Sn; Z = Se, S, Te) Two-Dimensional Janus Monolayers for Photocatalytic Water Splitting: A First-Principles Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136172</link>
      <description>Yu Zhigang, F. R. Xu, Songli Dai, Heng Wang, Shiyu Xiao, Zean Tian, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406291846

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Zhigang, F. R. Xu, Songli Dai, Heng Wang, Shiyu Xiao, Zean Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A roadmap from the bond strength to the grain-boundary energies and macro strength of metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55921-y</link>
      <description>Xin Li, Hao Wu, Wang Gao, Qing Jiang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406300203

                Abstract Correlating the bond strength with the macro strength of metals is crucial for understanding mechanical properties and designing multi-principal-element alloys (MPEAs). Motivated by the role of grain boundaries in the strength of metals, we introduce a predictive model to determine the grain-boundary energies and strength of metals from the cohesive energy and atomic radius. This scheme originates from the d-band characteristics and broken-bond spirit of tight-binding models, and demonstrates that the repulsive/attractive effects play different roles in the variation of bond strength for different metals. Importantly, our framework not only applies to both pure metals and MPEAs, but also unravels the distinction of the bond strength caused by elemental compositions, lattice structures, high-entropy, and amorphous effects. These findings build a physical picture across bond strength, grain-boundary energies and strength of metals by using easily accessible material properties and provide a robust method for the design of high-strength alloys.</description>
      <author>Xin Li, Hao Wu, Wang Gao, Qing Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55921-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforming Detrimental Crystalline Zinc Hydroxide Sulfate to Homogeneous Fluorinated Amorphous Solid&#8211;Electrolyte Interphase on Zinc Anode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04795</link>
      <description>Siyu Tian, Taesoon Hwang, Zhuoxun Zhang, Shiwen Wu, Amirarsalan Mashhadian, Renzheng Zhang, Tye Milazzo, Tengfei Luo, Ruda Jian, Tianyi Li, Kyeongjae Cho, Guoping Xiong, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406313143

                The formation of non-ion conducting byproducts on zinc anode is notoriously detrimental to aqueous zinc-ion batteries (AZIBs). Herein, we successfully transform a representative detrimental byproduct, crystalline zinc hydroxide sulfate (ZHS) to fast-ion conducting solid-electrolyte interphase (SEI) via amorphization and fluorination induced by suspending CaF2 nanoparticles in dilute sulfate electrolytes. Distinct from widely reported nonhomogeneous organic&#8211;inorganic hybrid SEIs that exhibit structural and chemical instability, the designed single-phase SEI is homogeneous, mechanically robust, and chemically stable. These characteristics of the SEI facilitate the prevention of zinc dendrite growth and reduction of capacity loss during long-term cycling. Importantly, AZIB full cells based on this SEI-forming electrolyte exhibit exceptional stability over 20,000 cycles at 3 A/g with a charging voltage of 2.2 V without short circuits and electrolyte dry-out. This work suggests avenues for designing SEIs on a metal anode and provides insights into associated SEI chemistry.</description>
      <author>Siyu Tian, Taesoon Hwang, Zhuoxun Zhang, Shiwen Wu, Amirarsalan Mashhadian, Renzheng Zhang, Tye Milazzo, Tengfei Luo, Ruda Jian, Tianyi Li, Kyeongjae Cho, Guoping Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening and an interpretable machine learning model of single-atom hydrogen evolution catalysts with an asymmetric coordination environment constructed from heteroatom-doped graphdiyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08095e</link>
      <description>Ying Zhao, Shuaishuai Gao, Penghui Ren, Lishuang Ma, Xuebo Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406314790

                Exploring high-activity and low-cost electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction is the key to developing new energy sources, but it faces major challenges.</description>
      <author>Ying Zhao, Shuaishuai Gao, Penghui Ren, Lishuang Ma, Xuebo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08095e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced delocalization and separation of charge carriers of D-&#960;-A type conjugated porous polymers by inserting fused thiophene derivative as &#960; bridge for improved photocatalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134347</link>
      <description>Xin Liu, Weiqiang Zhang, Fanpeng Meng, Jinsheng Zhao, Yuchang Du, Fei Zhao, Fuel. 387(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406316797

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Liu, Weiqiang Zhang, Fanpeng Meng, Jinsheng Zhao, Yuchang Du, Fei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in improving utilization efficiency of precious metal catalysts for hydrogen generation from hydrolysis of ammonia borane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216445</link>
      <description>Wenjing Xu, Mei Liu, Kexin Xu, Baojun Li, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 529(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406325967

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjing Xu, Mei Liu, Kexin Xu, Baojun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated and Efficient Sampling of Chemical Reaction Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409009</link>
      <description>Minhyeok Lee, Umit Volkan Ucak, Jinyoung Jeong, Islambek Ashyrmamatov, Juyong Lee, Eunji Sim, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406330162

                Machine learning interatomic potentials (MLIPs) promise quantum-level accuracy at classical force field speeds, but their performance hinges on the quality and diversity of training data. An efficient and fully automated approach to sample chemical reaction space without relying on human intuition, addressing a critical gap in MLIP development is presented. The method combines the speed of tight-binding calculations with selective high-level refinement, generating diverse datasets that capture both equilibrium and reactive regions of potential energy surfaces. By employing single-ended growing string and nudged elastic band methods, reaction pathways previously underrepresented in MLIP training sets, particularly near transition states are systematically explored. This approach yields datasets with rich structural and chemical diversity, essential for robust MLIP development. Open-source code is provided for the entire workflow, facilitating the integration of the approach into existing MLIP development pipelines.</description>
      <author>Minhyeok Lee, Umit Volkan Ucak, Jinyoung Jeong, Islambek Ashyrmamatov, Juyong Lee, Eunji Sim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dry Reforming of Methane Over Ru&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Dynamic Behavior of Lattice Oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06174</link>
      <description>Pengfei Qu, Dong Fu, Gui&#8208;Chang Wang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406335145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Qu, Dong Fu, Gui&#8208;Chang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Amino Acid Synthesis with WO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Sub&#8208;Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418233</link>
      <description>Guanzheng Wu, Zengying Ma, Tobias Heil, Leting Zhang, Wangcheng Hu, Guoqing Wu, Wenhui He, Lei Dai, Yucheng Huang, Qing Qin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406336851

                Abstract The conversion of nitrate&#8208;rich wastewater and biomass&#8208;derived blocks into high&#8208;value products using renewably generated electricity is a promising approach to modulate the artificial carbon and nitrogen cycle. Here, a new synthetic strategy of WO x sub&#8208;nanoclusters is reported and supported on carbon materials as novel efficient electrocatalysts for nitrate reduction and its coupling with &#945;&#8208;keto acids. In acidic solutions, the NH 3 &#8208;NH 2 OH selectivity can also optimized by adjusting the potential, with the total FE exceeding 80% over a wide potential range. After introducing &#945;&#8208;keto acids, the WO x /D&#8208;CB electrode achieves remarkable activity and selectivity toward C 2 &#8208;C 6 amino acids. For glycine and alanine, impressive FEs of 49.34% and 38.22% based on transitional metal oxides can be obtained, surpassing those of WO x nanoclusters with larger size. In situ analysis and mechanistic studies reveal the critical role of WO x sub&#8208;nanoclusters in reducing the energy barriers of key steps in alanine synthesis. This work opens up new insights into the rational design of cluster catalysts to promote electrochemical amino acid synthesis.</description>
      <author>Guanzheng Wu, Zengying Ma, Tobias Heil, Leting Zhang, Wangcheng Hu, Guoqing Wu, Wenhui He, Lei Dai, Yucheng Huang, Qing Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202418233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Oxidative Desorption of Adsorbed Sulfur Species on (111) Surfaces of Single Crystals of Pure Pt and Pt-Based Bimetallic Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06652</link>
      <description>Makoto Aoki, Tamao Shishido, Tetsuro Morooka, Takuya Nakanishi, Takuya Masuda, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406351662

                The adsorption/desorption behavior of sulfur species at the (111) surfaces of pure Pt and various Pt-based bimetallic alloys, denoted as Pt3M (M = Co, Cu, Fe, Pd), was investigated by electrochemical measurements and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). After the adsorption of elemental sulfur, the current responses characteristic of the adsorption/desorption of hydrogen and hydroxyl species at the sulfur-free bare (111) surfaces completely disappeared, and a doublet peak corresponding to the elemental sulfur appeared in the S 2p region of XPS spectra. The characteristic current responses gradually recovered, simultaneously with the decrease of the S 2p peak, by repeating the potential cycling between &#8722;0.2 and 0.8 V vs Ag/AgCl, indicating the oxidative desorption of S species. Except for the Pt3Pd(111) surface, in which Pd has a similar atomic radius to Pt and fully occupied 4d orbitals, the Pt3M(111) surfaces showed higher oxidative desorption capability than those of the pure Pt(111) surface; electrochemically active surface area recovered at the Pt3M(111) surfaces by fewer potential cycles than at the Pt(111) surface. Among the various factors, the downshift of the d-band center due to the ligand effect of foreign metal and the electronic interaction between adsorbed S and Pt are the dominant factors promoting the oxidative desorption of sulfur as well as the strain effect of foreign metal with an atomic radius smaller than Pt.</description>
      <author>Makoto Aoki, Tamao Shishido, Tetsuro Morooka, Takuya Nakanishi, Takuya Masuda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06652</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Impact of Trace SO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on Amine Absorbents for Chemical Absorption of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04163</link>
      <description>Songtao Zheng, Shaojun Jia, Yan Wu, Qi Wang, Yao Jiang, Peng Cui, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406188239

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Songtao Zheng, Shaojun Jia, Yan Wu, Qi Wang, Yao Jiang, Peng Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c04163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances on Carbon Capture and Electrochemical CO2 Reduction with Amphiphile Surfactants and Polymers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115394</link>
      <description>Fentahun Wondu Dagnaw, Ruiqi Li, Yilin Xie, Qing&#8208;Xiao Tong, Jing&#8208;Xin Jian, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406213677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fentahun Wondu Dagnaw, Ruiqi Li, Yilin Xie, Qing&#8208;Xiao Tong, Jing&#8208;Xin Jian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning research advances in energy storage polymer-based dielectrics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113651</link>
      <description>Qixin Yuan, Yue Dong, Zhe Zhang, Yu Feng, Qingguo Chen, Computational Materials Science. 249(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406275531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qixin Yuan, Yue Dong, Zhe Zhang, Yu Feng, Qingguo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113651</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
