<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:50:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>New approach to produce cubic-WC at low temperature for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.107</link>
      <description>Elvis O. L&#243;pez, Ofelia M. Arias-Pinedo, Rub&#233;n Soria-Mart&#237;nez, Antony Bazan-Aguilar, Gonzalo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Pablo L. Bernardo, N.R. Checca, Alexandre Mello, Ang&#233;lica M. Baena&#8208;Moncada, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392876346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elvis O. L&#243;pez, Ofelia M. Arias-Pinedo, Rub&#233;n Soria-Mart&#237;nez, Antony Bazan-Aguilar, Gonzalo Garc&#305;&#769;a, Pablo L. Bernardo, N.R. Checca, Alexandre Mello, Ang&#233;lica M. Baena&#8208;Moncada</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First-Principles Study of the Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity of Pt with Tm-N-C Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4761893</link>
      <description>Haining Wang, Jiashuo Fu, Liting Cui, Sian Chen, Wen Lei, Xinrui Liu, Jin Zhang, Shanfu Lu, Yan Xiang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392876465

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Haining Wang, Jiashuo Fu, Liting Cui, Sian Chen, Wen Lei, Xinrui Liu, Jin Zhang, Shanfu Lu, Yan Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4761893</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace Fe activates perovskite nickelate OER catalysts in alkaline media via redox-active surface Ni species formed during electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115443</link>
      <description>Liam Twight, Ally Tonsberg, Samji Samira, Kunal Velinkar, Kora Dumpert, Yingqing Ou, Le Wang, Eranda Nikolla, Shannon W. Boettcher, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392878220

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liam Twight, Ally Tonsberg, Samji Samira, Kunal Velinkar, Kora Dumpert, Yingqing Ou, Le Wang, Eranda Nikolla, Shannon W. Boettcher</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D Ferromagnetic M&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;GeTe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (M = Ni/Fe) for Boosting Intermediates Adsorption toward Faster Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202310115</link>
      <description>Guyue Bo, Peng Li, Yuhang Fan, Xiaobo Zheng, Mengting Zhao, Qiang Zhu, Fu Yang, Yitong Li, Wei Pang, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Bernt Johannessen, Lars Thomsen, Bruce C. C. Cowie, Tianyi Ma, Zhidong Chen, Guan Heng Yeoh, Yi Du, Shi Xue Dou, Xiaojing Xu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392880944

                Abstract In this work, 2D ferromagnetic M 3 GeTe 2 (MGT, M = Ni/Fe) nanosheets with rich atomic Te vacancies (2D&#8208;MGT v ) are demonstrated as efficient OER electrocatalyst via a general mechanical exfoliation strategy. X&#8208;ray absorption spectra (XAS) and scanning transmission electron microscope (STEM) results validate the dominant presence of metal&#8208;O moieties and rich Te vacancies, respectively. The formed Te vacancies are active for the adsorption of OH* and O* species while the metal&#8208;O moieties promote the O* and OOH* adsorption, contributing synergistically to the faster oxygen evolution kinetics. Consequently, 2D&#8208;Ni 3 GeTe 2v exhibits superior OER activity with only 370 mV overpotential to reach the current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and turnover frequency (TOF) value of 101.6 s &#8722;1 at the overpotential of 200 mV in alkaline media. Furthermore, a 2D&#8208;Ni 3 GeTe 2v &#8208;based anion&#8208;exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolysis cell (1 cm 2 ) delivers a current density of 1.02 and 1.32 A cm &#8722;2 at the voltage of 3 V feeding with 0.1 and 1 m KOH solution, respectively. The demonstrated metal&#8208;O coordination with abundant atomic vacancies for ferromagnetic M 3 GeTe 2 and the easily extended preparation strategy would enlighten the rational design and fabrication of other ferromagnetic materials for wider electrocatalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Guyue Bo, Peng Li, Yuhang Fan, Xiaobo Zheng, Mengting Zhao, Qiang Zhu, Fu Yang, Yitong Li, Wei Pang, Wei&#8208;Hong Lai, Bernt Johannessen, Lars Thomsen, Bruce C. C. Cowie, Tianyi Ma, Zhidong Chen, Guan Heng Yeoh, Yi Du, Shi Xue Dou, Xiaojing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202310115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuSe2 nanoparticles loaded MoSe2 hybrid rods via interface engineering as an efficient electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159916</link>
      <description>Manzhou Zhu, Huijun Yu, Cheng&#8208;Han Yang, Qinghua Deng, Huan Liu, Jinqiang Huang, Yiwei Zhang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392881530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manzhou Zhu, Huijun Yu, Cheng&#8208;Han Yang, Qinghua Deng, Huan Liu, Jinqiang Huang, Yiwei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in two-dimensional metallenes and their potential application as electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.068</link>
      <description>Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Muhammad Fazle Rabbee, Hadi M. Marwani, Jehan Y. Al&#8208;Humaidi, Muhammad Altaf, Raed H. Althomali, Kwang-Hyun Baek, Md. Rabiul Awual, Mohammed M. Rahman, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392883430

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Muhammad Fazle Rabbee, Hadi M. Marwani, Jehan Y. Al&#8208;Humaidi, Muhammad Altaf, Raed H. Althomali, Kwang-Hyun Baek, Md. Rabiul Awual, Mohammed M. Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of nitrogen reduction reaction activity of sp-B-doped &#947;-graphyne nanotubes through curvature effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114044</link>
      <description>Renzhi Ma, Yipin Lv, Yaqiong Yang, Xinru Wei, Jin Yong Lee, Shaul Mukamel, Baotao Kang, Molecular Catalysis. 558(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392890465

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Renzhi Ma, Yipin Lv, Yaqiong Yang, Xinru Wei, Jin Yong Lee, Shaul Mukamel, Baotao Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phenol as proton shuttle and buffer for lithium-mediated ammonia electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46803-w</link>
      <description>Xiujun Fu, Aoni Xu, Jakob B. Pedersen, Shaofeng Li, Rokas Sa&#382;inas, Yuanyuan Zhou, Suzanne Zamany Andersen, Mattia Saccoccio, Niklas H. Deissler, Jon Bjarke Valb&#230;k Mygind, Jakob Kibsgaard, Peter Christian Kj&#230;rgaard Vesborg, Jens K. N&#248;rskov, Ib Chorkendorff, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392897390

                Abstract Ammonia is a crucial component in the production of fertilizers and various nitrogen-based compounds. Now, the lithium-mediated nitrogen reduction reaction (Li-NRR) has emerged as a promising approach for ammonia synthesis at ambient conditions. The proton shuttle plays a critical role in the proton transfer process during Li-NRR. However, the structure-activity relationship and design principles for effective proton shuttles have not yet been established in practical Li-NRR systems. Here, we propose a general procedure for verifying a true proton shuttle and established design principles for effective proton shuttles. We systematically evaluate several classes of proton shuttles in a continuous-flow reactor with hydrogen oxidation at the anode. Among the tested proton shuttles, phenol exhibits the highest Faradaic efficiency of 72 &#177; 3% towards ammonia, surpassing that of ethanol, which has been commonly used so far. Experimental investigations including operando isotope-labelled mass spectrometry proved the proton-shuttling capability of phenol. Further mass transport modeling sheds light on the mechanism.</description>
      <author>Xiujun Fu, Aoni Xu, Jakob B. Pedersen, Shaofeng Li, Rokas Sa&#382;inas, Yuanyuan Zhou, Suzanne Zamany Andersen, Mattia Saccoccio, Niklas H. Deissler, Jon Bjarke Valb&#230;k Mygind, Jakob Kibsgaard, Peter Christian Kj&#230;rgaard Vesborg, Jens K. N&#248;rskov, Ib Chorkendorff</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46803-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal-based nanozymes: Classification, catalytic mechanisms and emerging biomedical applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215771</link>
      <description>Dandan Zhang, Qing Chen, Qunxiang Ren, Zhong Wang, Hongjin Zhang, Guannan Wang, Yang Zhang, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 508(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392898345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dandan Zhang, Qing Chen, Qunxiang Ren, Zhong Wang, Hongjin Zhang, Guannan Wang, Yang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biologically Templated Formation of Cobalt-Phosphide-Graphene Hybrid with Charge Redistribution for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4762336</link>
      <description>Xingchen Zhou, Lanqian Gong, Chen Wu, Yanfang Peng, Bin Cao, Xueliang Jiang, Huan Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Bao Yu Xia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392899183

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Xingchen Zhou, Lanqian Gong, Chen Wu, Yanfang Peng, Bin Cao, Xueliang Jiang, Huan Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4762336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoporous Nickel Cathode with an Electrostatic Chlorine-Resistant Surface for Industrial Seawater Electrolysis Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00392</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Yanqi Li, Xu Tian, Jie Zheng, Kaiwen Xiao, Bingbing Sun, Ming Ge, Xiaolei Yuan, Chenggang Zhou, Zhao Cai, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392900270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Yanqi Li, Xu Tian, Jie Zheng, Kaiwen Xiao, Bingbing Sun, Ming Ge, Xiaolei Yuan, Chenggang Zhou, Zhao Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Coordination Environment of Ir Single Atoms with Surface Titanium Oxide Amorphization for Superior Chlorine Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13834</link>
      <description>Jiaxian Wang, Long Zhao, Yunjie Zou, Jie Dai, Qiuling Zheng, Xingyue Zou, Lufa Hu, Wei Hou, Ruizhao Wang, Kaiyuan Wang, Yanbiao Shi, Guangming Zhan, Yancai Yao, Lizhi Zhang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392907480

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaxian Wang, Long Zhao, Yunjie Zou, Jie Dai, Qiuling Zheng, Xingyue Zou, Lufa Hu, Wei Hou, Ruizhao Wang, Kaiyuan Wang, Yanbiao Shi, Guangming Zhan, Yancai Yao, Lizhi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural regulation of amorphous molybdenum sulfide by atomic palladium doping for hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.113</link>
      <description>Yao Xiao, Chee Kiang Ivan Tan, Fangui Zeng, Xinyang Wang, Jian Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392907943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Xiao, Chee Kiang Ivan Tan, Fangui Zeng, Xinyang Wang, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-level charge separation boosting the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150536</link>
      <description>Jingwen Pan, Dongbo Wang, Bingke Zhang, Chenchen Zhao, Donghao Liu, Sihang Liu, Zhi Zeng, Tianyuan Chen, Gang Liu, Shujie Jiao, Zhikun Xu, Tongling Liu, Taifeng Liu, Xuan Fang, Liancheng Zhao, Jinzhong Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392914099

                The synergistic implementation of atomic-level charge separation strategies for bulk&#8211;surfaces is a meaningful study that fundamentally addresses the shortcomings of single materials. Here, we report for the first time the atomic-level engineering of atomic doping in combination with surface ion grafting, which can be coordinated to significantly facilitate photocatalytic H2 evolution. More impressively, the study systematically investigated the atomic doping effects of Fe, Co, Ni and Cu atoms, and analyzed the conditions for optimal doping with experimental and theoretical calculations. Electrons from the Cu were transferred to Zn0.67Cd0.33S or adsorbed H atoms on its surface, effectively enhancing the surface charge density and electron transport capacity. The X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) results verified the precise coordination environments of the doped Cu atoms, as well as confirmed the solid grafting of Ni ions on the catalyst surface. Furthermore, the hydrogen production rate of 1.2 % Cu&#8211;Zn0.67Cd0.33S&#8211;0.5 wt% Ni reached 38.17 mmol/g/h, corresponding to an apparent quantum efficiency of 35.5 %, which is 82.8 times higher than that of pure ZCS. Besides, the H2 production rate can reached 118.73 mmol/g/h without cooling. Meanwhile, the synergistic strategy of manipulating the bulk and surface photo-charges of Zn0.67Cd0.33S also effectively enhances the photothermal effect and further improves its photocatalytic performance. This work provides different inspirations for bottom-up design of efficient photocatalysts to achieve synergistic facilitation strategies.</description>
      <author>Jingwen Pan, Dongbo Wang, Bingke Zhang, Chenchen Zhao, Donghao Liu, Sihang Liu, Zhi Zeng, Tianyuan Chen, Gang Liu, Shujie Jiao, Zhikun Xu, Tongling Liu, Taifeng Liu, Xuan Fang, Liancheng Zhao, Jinzhong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergent high-temperature insulating ferromagnetism in Sr4Fe5CoO13-&lt;b&gt; &lt;i&gt;&#948;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/b&gt; epitaxial thin films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0190376</link>
      <description>Xinhai Han, Jianlin Wang, Nanqi Gong, Zheling Shan, Wei Shi, Z. Liu, Xuguang Liu, Jiefeng Cao, Ranran Peng, Qiuping Huang, Zhengping Fu, Yalin Lu, Applied Physics Letters. 124(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392915039

                High-temperature ferromagnetic insulators play a crucial role in a wide range of emerging magnetoelectricity phenomena and hold the potential to become fundamental components of upcoming spintronic devices. However, the strong interaction between ferromagnetism and metallic properties presents a challenge, impeding the development of high-temperature ferromagnetic insulators based on oxides. Heterostructures or superlattice materials, especially those containing perovskite layers, offer a forward-looking solution. In this work, high-quality Sr4Fe6O13 (SFO) and cobalt-doped SFO (Sr4Fe5CoO13-&#948;, SFCO) thin films were grown on Nb-SrTiO3(001) substrates using pulsed laser deposition technology. The grown SFO films exhibit paramagnetism, possibly due to the transition of their film structure from the orthorhombic to the tetragonal phase. In contrast to SFO films, high-quality SFCO thin films exhibit significant ferromagnetism at room temperature, with Curie transition temperature as high as 800 K. This phenomenon is mainly attributed to the formed Dzyaloshinskii&#8211;Moriya interactions between Fe&#8211;O&#8211;Co and increased lattice distortions caused by Co-doping. In contrast, the Curie transition temperature of the SFCO film is slightly higher than that of the SFCO ceramics. This enhancement is likely due to surface effects, where an increase in surface energy introduces additional energy barriers at the film surface and interface, thereby enhancing the thermal stability of the film. These characteristics advance the research of high-temperature magnetic insulators and broaden the operating temperature range of spintronic devices based on ferromagnetic insulators.</description>
      <author>Xinhai Han, Jianlin Wang, Nanqi Gong, Zheling Shan, Wei Shi, Z. Liu, Xuguang Liu, Jiefeng Cao, Ranran Peng, Qiuping Huang, Zhengping Fu, Yalin Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0190376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Design Strategies for M&#8208;N&#8208;C Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts in Oxygen Reduction: An Entropy Increase Perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401027</link>
      <description>Wei Yan, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392918007

                Abstract Recently, a diverse array of novel metal&#8208;nitrogen&#8208;carbon (M&#8208;N&#8208;C) single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have rapidly evolve, particularly in the realm of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Despite the plethora of proposed design and improvement strategies for SACs, a comprehensive review systematically compiling the components in M&#8208;N&#8208;C from a unified perspective is notably absent. For the first time, a thorough examination of each component in M&#8208;N&#8208;C is conducted, focusing on the perspective of entropy increase in the active sites of SACs. For the single M&#8208;N 4 sites and the whole M&#8208;N&#8208;C system, an increase in entropy implies an elevated degree of disorder and chaos. Broadly, the entropy&#8208;increasing modification of M (single mental sites) and guest groups entails an augmentation of chaos, with the most effective co&#8208;catalytic synergy achieved by establishing multiple active sites through a &#8220;cocktail effect&#8221;. Concerning N (nitrogen and other heteroatoms) and C (carbon supports), the entropy increase modification induces heightened disorder, with symmetry breaking more likely to drive M&#8208;N 4 toward adsorbing oxygen molecules to attain an equilibrium symmetric structure. All these innovative design strategies have led to a remarkable improvement in the ORR activity and stability and offer a guiding criterion for the future preparation of SACs.</description>
      <author>Wei Yan, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox Engineering of Fe&#8208;Rich Disordered Rock&#8208;Salt Li&#8208;Ion Cathode Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400402</link>
      <description>Richie Fong, Nauman Mubarak, Sang&#8208;Wook Park, Gregory Lazaris, Yiwei Liu, Rahul Malik, Dong&#8208;Hwa Seo, Jinhyuk Lee, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392918991

                Abstract The pursuit of high&#8208;performance and cost&#8208;effective Li&#8208;ion batteries emphasizes the need for cathode materials composed of abundant elements, such as Fe. Disordered rock&#8208;salt (DRX) cathode materials, known for their high compositional flexibility, offer a unique opportunity in this regard. However, Fe&#8208;rich DRX (Fe&#8208;DRX) cathodes, potentially the most cost&#8208;effective among all DRXs, have seen limited research interest due to their comparatively restrained performance. This limitation stems from the inaccessibility of the Fe 3+ /Fe 4+ redox in the DRX structure, prompting the need for redox engineering to enable Fe&#8208;DRXs with readily utilizable redox mechanisms. In this work, utilizing both experiments and theoretical study, reversible Fe 2+ /Fe 3+ redox in an Fe 2+ &#8208;based DRX cathode is demonstrated. This design minimizes the reliance on O redox, resulting in a high capacity (&#8776;290 mAh g &#8722;1 ) and energy density (&#8776;700 Wh kg &#8722;1 ), as opposed to an Fe 3+ &#8208;based DRX operating on the limited Fe 3+ /Fe 4+ redox and extensive O redox upon cycling. Overall, the study introduces a novel approach to redox engineering to develop low&#8208;cost, high&#8208;performing Fe&#8208;rich cathode materials.</description>
      <author>Richie Fong, Nauman Mubarak, Sang&#8208;Wook Park, Gregory Lazaris, Yiwei Liu, Rahul Malik, Dong&#8208;Hwa Seo, Jinhyuk Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Activity Prediction of &#945;-Diimino Nickel Precatalysts toward Ethylene Polymerization by Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14030195</link>
      <description>Zainab Hashim Abbas, Md Mostakim Meraz, Wenhong Yang, Weishen Yang, Wen&#8208;Hua Sun, Catalysts. 14(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392926061

                The present study explored machine learning methods to predict the catalytic activities of a dataset of 165 &#945;-diimino nickel complexes in ethylene polymerization. Using 25 descriptors as the inputs, the XGBoost model presented the optimal performance among six different algorithms (R2 = 0.999, Rt2 = 0.921, Q2 = 0.561). The results of the analysis indicate that high activity is related to the presence of polarizable atoms and less bulky substituents within the N-aryl group. This approach offers valuable insights on the variation principle of catalytic activity as a function of complex structure, helping to effectively design and optimize &#945;-diimino Ni catalysts with desirable performance.</description>
      <author>Zainab Hashim Abbas, Md Mostakim Meraz, Wenhong Yang, Weishen Yang, Wen&#8208;Hua Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14030195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Alkali Metal Cations on the Oxygen Reduction Activity of Pt&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;Y and Pt&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;Gd Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00531</link>
      <description>Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Alexandra Zagalskaya, Christian Schott, Peter M. Schneider, Batyr Garlyyev, Vitaly Alexandrov, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392927386

                Electrolyte species can significantly influence the electrocatalytic performance. In this work, we investigate the impact of alkali metal cations on the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) on active Pt5Gd and Pt5Y polycrystalline electrodes. Due to the strain effects, Pt alloys exhibit a higher kinetic current density of ORR than pure Pt electrodes in acidic media. In alkaline solutions, the kinetic current density of ORR for Pt alloys decreases linearly with the decreasing hydration energy in the order of Li+ &gt; Na+ &gt; K+ &gt; Rb+ &gt; Cs+, whereas Pt shows the opposite trend. To gain further insights into these experimental results, we conduct complementary density functional theory calculations considering the effects of both electrode surface strain and electrolyte chemistry. The computational results reveal that the different trends in the ORR activity in alkaline media can be explained by the change in the adsorption energy of reaction intermediates with applied surface strain in the presence of alkali metal cations. Our findings provide important insights into the effects of the electrolyte and the strain conditions on the electrocatalytic performance and thus offer valuable guidelines for optimizing Pt-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Alexandra Zagalskaya, Christian Schott, Peter M. Schneider, Batyr Garlyyev, Vitaly Alexandrov, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of technological tendencies in the carbon capture process: a review.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1757-899x/1299/1/012012</link>
      <description>Brayan Eduardo Tarazona Romero, N. Y. Castillo-Leon, A. J. Rodriguez-Nieves, Y. P. Quizena-Fernandez, Y. C. Villabona-Ni&#241;o, O. Forero-Caceres, IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering. 1299(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392932149

                Abstract This paper evaluates the technological trends in the carbon sequestration process. For this purpose, these systems have been classified into two subsystems: conventional technologies subsystem and emerging technologies subsystem. Each is explored for its suitability for meeting a set of six attributes. A bibliometric analysis process was developed using the Scopus database and VOSviewer Software to present the potential of each subsystem evaluated, through an evaluation matrix. The analysis of the subsystems and attributes was performed through the formal concept analysis methodology (8FCA). To facilitate the processing of the information, the open access software concept Explorer was used. The analysis shows that conventional technologies, despite their cost, will be maintained and advance in their implementation process. The bibliometric analysis integrated with the applied FCA methodology has proven to be useful for the evaluation of technological typologies and serves as an alternative to develop theoretical studies that group and link different options as a model to evaluate a deterministic set of attributes.</description>
      <author>Brayan Eduardo Tarazona Romero, N. Y. Castillo-Leon, A. J. Rodriguez-Nieves, Y. P. Quizena-Fernandez, Y. C. Villabona-Ni&#241;o, O. Forero-Caceres</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1757-899x/1299/1/012012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micromechanical Dilution of PLA/PETG&#8211;Glass/Iron Nanocomposites: A More Efficient Molecular Dynamics Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c08264</link>
      <description>William A. Pisani, Dane N. Wedgeworth, Jedadiah F. Burroughs, Travis L. Thornell, Jennifer F. Newman, Manoj K. Shukla, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392934927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>William A. Pisani, Dane N. Wedgeworth, Jedadiah F. Burroughs, Travis L. Thornell, Jennifer F. Newman, Manoj K. Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c08264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Activity and Electrochemical Stability of Ru&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (M = Zr, Nb, Ta): Computational and Experimental Study of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01408</link>
      <description>Francisco Ospina&#8208;Acevedo, Luis A Albiter, Kathleen O. Bailey, Jos&#233; Fernando God&#237;nez-Salom&#243;n, Christopher P. Rhodes, Perla B. Balbuena, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392939927

                We use computations and experiments to determine the effect of substituting zirconium, niobium, and tantalum within rutile RuO2 on the structure, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) mechanism and activity, and electrochemical stability. Calculated electronic structures altered by Zr, Nb, and Ta show surface regions of electron density depletion and accumulation, along with anisotropic lattice parameter shifts dependent on the substitution site, substituent, and concentration. Consistent with theory, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy experiments show shifts in binding energies of O-2s, O-2p, and Ru-4d peaks due to the substituents. Experimentally, the substituted materials showed the presence of two phases with a majority phase that contains the metal substituent within the rutile phase and a second, smaller-percentage RuO2 phase. Our experimental analysis of OER activity shows Zr, Nb, and Ta substituents at 12.5 atom % induce lower activity relative to RuO2, which agrees with computing the average of all sites; however, Zr and Ta substitution at specific sites yields higher theoretical OER activity than RuO2, with Zr substitution suggesting an alternative OER mechanism. Metal dissolution predictions show the involvement of cooperative interactions among multiple surface sites and the electrolyte. Zr substitution at specific sites increases activation barriers for Ru dissolution, however, with Zr surface dissolution rates comparable to those of Ru. Experimental OER stability analysis shows lower Ru dissolution from synthesized RuO2 and Zr-substituted RuO2 compared to commercial RuO2 and comparable amounts of Zr and Ru dissolved from Zr-substituted RuO2, aligned with our calculations.</description>
      <author>Francisco Ospina&#8208;Acevedo, Luis A Albiter, Kathleen O. Bailey, Jos&#233; Fernando God&#237;nez-Salom&#243;n, Christopher P. Rhodes, Perla B. Balbuena</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of the effects of Li/Na/K doping and point defects on the magnetic and photocatalytic properties of monolayer GaN (0 0 1)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113156</link>
      <description>Jianxiao Si, Qingyu Hou, Weiya Li, Yanxia Zhang, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392946948

                In the experimental preparation of monolayer GaN (0 0 1) by chemical-vapor deposition, H impurities inevitably remain, and the intrinsic defect VGa inevitably forms. In this research, generalized gradient approximation + U plane-wave ultrasoft pseudopotentials are computed using the density-functional theory framework. The effects of Li/Na/K doping and point defect (Hi-VGa) coexistence on the magnetic properties and photocatalytic properties of monolayer GaN (0 0 1) surfaces are investigated. Results show that the monolayer Ga34MN36 (M = Li/Na/K) (0 0 1) surfaces are magnetic, and the source of its magnetism is primarily the itinerant electrons of N2&#8722; ions. The monolayer Ga34MHiN36 (0 0 1) surfaces are relatively more stable, and the separation degree of carriers is better than the monolayer Ga34MN36 (0 0 1) surfaces. In particular, the monolayer Ga34LiHiN36 (0 0 1) surface has a large electric-dipole moment, strong carrier activity, strong absorption efficiency, and strong oxidation-reduction properties. Therefore, the monolayer Ga34LiHiN36 (0 0 1) surface is the most suitable photocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Jianxiao Si, Qingyu Hou, Weiya Li, Yanxia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of transition metal dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction based on high-throughput calculation and searching surrogate prediction model using simple features</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159942</link>
      <description>J. Wang, Wei Xu, Jun He, Hao Ma, Wanglai Cen, Yu Shen, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392948917

                Dual-atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction have received widespread attention, but precise screening and prediction of high-performance catalysts through simple methods remains a challenge. In this study, we perform high-throughput density functional theory (DFT) calculation and machine learning (ML) to screen and predict the transition metal dual-atom catalysts with N-doped graphene support (TMDACs) for acidic hydrogen evolution reaction. The Fe_Zn and V_Fe DACs were proposed to be the most promising candidates for Pt-based catalyst toward acidic HER from 406 TMDACs, based on the characteristics of HER activity, formation, thermodynamic stability, abundance, environmental friendliness. The Fe_Zn and V_Fe DACs with excellent HER performance is due to the synergistic effect deriving from the interaction between H and dual metal atoms in TMDACs. By determining 6 different ML models with four kind of input features, we find the artificial neural networks (ANN) model can predict the HER performance of TMDACs most accurately only using simple input features, including one-hot-encoding of atomic number and Gibbs free energy of transition metal single-atom catalyst. This work not only proposed the potential TMDACs with high HER performance, but also verified that the ANN model can accurately predict the HER activity of diatomic catalysts with simple input features.</description>
      <author>J. Wang, Wei Xu, Jun He, Hao Ma, Wanglai Cen, Yu Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF/MXene Composites: Synthesis, Application and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400011</link>
      <description>Sakina Bibi, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, Mamona Nazir, Mohamed H. Helal, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, Sultan Ullah, Muhammad Ahmad Wattoo, Aziz ur Rehman, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392951886

                Abstract 2D MXenes family creates an interest in environmental cleaning and energy conversion. It shows large surface functional groups, electronic transmission, and electrical conductivity. This research focuses on Metal Organic Framework&#8208;based Ti 3 C 2 heterojunctions, directing on surface morphology control, customizable electrical structure, high performance in Ti 3 C 2 &#8208;based electrocatalytic devices, and energy storage as a supercapacitor. In addition, future development obstacles and viable research possibilities are presented. MXene detailed analysis reveals a fundamental study, structure&#8208;activity connections, and potential research paths for environmental applications. Specially developed MOF/MXene nanoarchitectures with remarkable features are highlighted in several study fields, including the chemical sciences, environmental engineering, physics, catalysis, and nanotechnology. They represent a new class of cutting&#8208;edge developing materials. Mainly, the presented review describes multiple synthesis approaches by adjusting conditions for MOF/MXene nanoarchitectures with varying morphologies, and intriguing properties can also be developed for electrochemical energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Sakina Bibi, Syed Shoaib Ahmad Shah, Mamona Nazir, Mohamed H. Helal, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, Sultan Ullah, Muhammad Ahmad Wattoo, Aziz ur Rehman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Quality and Reliability of Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials through Better Reporting Practices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00028</link>
      <description>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393002362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Neural Network Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00004</link>
      <description>Timothy T. Duignan, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393037991

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timothy T. Duignan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on Advancing Sustainable CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion Processes: Trinomial Technology, Environment, and Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07133</link>
      <description>Lourdes F. Vega, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Ismail I.I. Alkhatib, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393097423

                CO2 can be converted into value-added products such as fuels, chemicals, and building materials, adding an economic incentive for CO2 capture and green economy, while also reducing the environmental footprint of hard-to-abate industries such as aviation, construction, and metallurgy. Nonetheless, most available technologies for direct CO2 conversion, while promising, are still in early development stages, facing technical and economic challenges for their scale-up, questioning their viability to truly instill a timely impact on global CO2 emissions. Furthermore, a clear environmental benefit should be obtained for the new processes versus the traditional ones they are replacing in the market. In this perspective, we examine the range of available technologies for direct CO2 conversion using thermal, electrical, and photochemical routes and mineralization including the advancements in their role in synthesizing a range of resulting products from methanol, methane, carbon monoxide, and solid carbonates. We offer insights on the trends in current research and development and the required direction to expedite the technological readiness of attractive CO2 conversion technologies in terms of catalytic material and reactor design. We also highlight the important role of modeling (molecular and process levels) as an enabling tool to deploy these technologies at the commercial scale originating from understanding their behavior at the molecular level. Lastly, we highlight the significance of carrying out reliable life cycle analysis in identifying the environmental hotspots as well as gaps in the technology that allows improving their environmental footprint and economic attractiveness.</description>
      <author>Lourdes F. Vega, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Ismail I.I. Alkhatib</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a 3D Ni-Mn Binary Oxide Anode for Energy-Efficient Electro-Oxidation of Organic Pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112562</link>
      <description>Keyvan Mirehbar, Jaime S. Sanchez, Sergio Pinilla, Freddy E. Oropeza, Ignasi Sir&#233;s, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Jes&#250;s Palma, Julio J. Lado, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392974422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Keyvan Mirehbar, Jaime S. Sanchez, Sergio Pinilla, Freddy E. Oropeza, Ignasi Sir&#233;s, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Jes&#250;s Palma, Julio J. Lado</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112562</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
