<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 01:24:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Isotope-dependent Tafel analysis probes proton transfer kinetics during electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01934-5</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Ran Wang, Hongyuan Sheng, Xiaorong Zhu, R. Dominic Ross, Daxing Hua, Lin Lei, Yafei Li, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Xianjie Wang, Ping Xu, Jun L&#252;, Sida Jiang, Jiecai Han, Bo Song, Song Jin, Nature Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414083407

                Proton transfer plays an important role in both hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions during electrocatalytic water splitting to produce green hydrogen. However, directly adapting the conventional proton/deuterium kinetic isotope effect to study proton transfer in heterogeneous electrocatalytic processes is challenging. Here we propose using the shift in the Tafel slope between protic and deuteric electrolytes, or the Tafel slope isotope effect, as an effective probe of proton transfer characteristics. Comparison of the Tafel slope isotope effect for diverse hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts in different pH environments reveals that proton transfer is both pH and structure dependent. Using ruthenium oxide as an example, we show that local structure modification can change the rate-determining step from an electrochemical, concerted proton-electron transfer step to a chemical step and improve the oxygen evolution activity in acid. The isotope-dependent Tafel analysis will facilitate a better understanding of the proton transfer behaviours during electrocatalytic processes and provide guidance for designing efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Ran Wang, Hongyuan Sheng, Xiaorong Zhu, R. Dominic Ross, Daxing Hua, Lin Lei, Yafei Li, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Xianjie Wang, Ping Xu, Jun L&#252;, Sida Jiang, Jiecai Han, Bo Song, Song Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01934-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient, Hierarchical, and Object-Oriented Electronic Structure Interfaces for Direct Nonadiabatic Dynamics Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00878</link>
      <description>Sascha Mausenberger, Severin Polonius, Sebastian Mai, Leticia Gonz&#225;lez, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414084320

                We present a novel, flexible framework for electronic structure interfaces designed for nonadiabatic dynamics simulations, implemented in Python 3 using concepts of object-oriented programming. This framework streamlines the development of new interfaces by providing a reusable and extendable code base. It supports the computation of energies, gradients, various couplings&#9472;like spin-orbit couplings, nonadiabatic couplings, and transition dipole moments&#9472;and other properties for an arbitrary number of states with any multiplicities and charges. A key innovation within this framework is the introduction of hybrid interfaces, which can use other interfaces in a general hierarchical manner. Hybrid interfaces are capable of using one or more child interfaces to implement multiscale approaches, such as quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics where different child interfaces are assigned to different regions of a system. The concept of hybrid interfaces can be extended through nesting, where hybrid parent interfaces use hybrid child interfaces to easily setup complex workflows without the need for additional coding. We demonstrate the versatility of hybrid interfaces with two examples: one at the method level and one at the workflow level. The first example showcases the numerical differentiation of wave function overlaps, implemented as a hybrid interface and used to optimize a minimum-energy conical intersection with numerical nonadiabatic couplings. The second example presents an adaptive learning workflow, where nested hybrid interfaces are used to iteratively refine a machine learning model. This work lays the groundwork for more modular, flexible, and scalable software design in excited-state dynamics.</description>
      <author>Sascha Mausenberger, Severin Polonius, Sebastian Mai, Leticia Gonz&#225;lez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00878</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Transition State Search and Ligand Screening for Organometallic Catalysis with Reactive Machine Learning Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01047</link>
      <description>Kun Tang, Yujing Zhao, Lei Zhang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Qilei Liu, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414084992

                Organometallic catalysis lies at the heart of numerous industrial processes that produce bulk and fine chemicals. The search for transition states and screening for organic ligands are vital in designing highly active organometallic catalysts with efficient reaction kinetics. However, identifying accurate transition states necessitates computationally intensive quantum chemistry calculations. In this work, a reactive machine learning potential (RMLP) model is developed to accelerate transition state optimizations and ligand screening for organometallic catalysis based on an automated transition state database construction method and a higher-order equivariant message passing neural network. In case studies involving the ethylene hydrogenation reaction catalyzed by organometallic catalysts, RMLP rapidly predicts potential energy surfaces along intrinsic reaction coordinate paths, achieving speeds nearly 3 orders of magnitude faster than those of rigorous quantum chemistry calculations. Meanwhile, it maintains comparable accuracy with a root-mean-square deviation of 0.307 &#197; for transition state geometries and a mean absolute error of 0.871 kJ&#183;mol-1 for reaction barriers on the external test set, significantly outperforming semiempirical quantum chemistry methods. Our RMLP model offers an effective alternative to both rigorous and semiempirical quantum chemistry approaches for rapid and precise transition state optimizations, facilitating high-throughput screening of advanced organometallic catalyst ligands.</description>
      <author>Kun Tang, Yujing Zhao, Lei Zhang, Jian Du, Qingwei Meng, Qilei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain for Credentialing and Academic Record-Keeping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3373-2185-1.ch014</link>
      <description>B. Subashini, Anna Anbumozhi, S. Praveenkumar, N. Vasudevan, Venkatesh Kaliamoorthy, Advances in computational intelligence and robotics book series. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414089994

                In the digital era, ensuring the security, authenticity, and accessibility of academic credentials is crucial. Traditional credentialing and academic record-keeping systems suffer from inefficiencies, security vulnerabilities, and verification issues. Blockchain technology offers a decentralized, tamper-proof, and transparent solution to these challenges. This chapter explores blockchain's potential in academic credentialing, examining its benefits, challenges, and real-world applications. Academic institutions currently rely on centralized authorities, which can be inefficient and susceptible to fraud. Blockchain provides an immutable ledger that enables secure issuance, decentralized verification, and fraud prevention. By leveraging cryptographic security and smart contracts, institutions can issue digital diplomas and certificates that are instantly verifiable, eliminating the need for intermediary verification. Blockchain also enhances lifelong learning records by allowing students to consolidate academic achievements into a single digital identity. This improves global mobility.</description>
      <author>B. Subashini, Anna Anbumozhi, S. Praveenkumar, N. Vasudevan, Venkatesh Kaliamoorthy</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3373-2185-1.ch014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The augmented potential method: Multiscale modeling toward a spectral defect genome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2025.116969</link>
      <description>Nutth Tuchinda, Changle Li, Christopher A. Schuh, Scripta Materialia. 271(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414090801

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nutth Tuchinda, Changle Li, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2025.116969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretation of X-ray Photoelectron Spectra of Ge(111), GeO2/Ge(111), and C60F18/Ge(111) Samples Using Quantum Chemical Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1027451025700685</link>
      <description>E. A. Shramkov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, Ratibor G. Chumakov, V. G. Stankevich, &#1051;. &#1055;. &#1057;&#1091;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Journal of Surface Investigation X-ray Synchrotron and Neutron Techniques. 19(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414095106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. A. Shramkov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1040;&#1085;&#1076;&#1088;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;, Ratibor G. Chumakov, V. G. Stankevich, &#1051;. &#1055;. &#1057;&#1091;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1027451025700685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Hexagonal &lt;scp&gt;V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; Monolayer as a Promising Nonprecious Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction: Insights from First&#8208;Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70137</link>
      <description>Ziqi Li, Xue Li, Sheng Wang, Siyu Lu, Guochun Yang, Zhiyong Tang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100023

                The development of efficient, cost&#8208;effective, and durable electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is critical for advancing sustainable energy systems and enabling the widespread adoption of hydrogen&#8208;based energy technologies. In this study, we discover a stable hexagonal V 2 B 2 monolayer that serves as a promising HER catalyst via an unbiased swarm&#8208;intelligence structural method as implemented in CALYPSO code. First&#8208;principles calculations show that the predicted V 2 B 2 monolayer exhibits excellent metallic properties and promising catalytic activity for HER, suggesting CALYPSO's utility for accelerating the discovery of efficient electrocatalysts. Further doping engineering, incorporating transition metals (TM&#8242; = Sc, Y, Ti, Zr, Hf), reveals that the introduction of Sc, Y, and Zr significantly enhances the catalytic performance. Bader charge analysis reveals a linear correlation between the electron gain by the hydrogen atom and &#916; G H* , suggesting that this relationship could serve as an effective descriptor for HER activity in TM'&#8208;doped V 2 B 2 systems. Our findings provide valuable insights into nonprecious HER electrocatalysts and contribute to a deeper understanding of high catalytic performance in newly proposed 2D HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ziqi Li, Xue Li, Sheng Wang, Siyu Lu, Guochun Yang, Zhiyong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.70137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin State Modulation in M&#8211;N&#8211;C Single-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04591</link>
      <description>Hyeonjung Jung, Roman Fanta, Md Delowar Hossain, Michal Bajdich, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyeonjung Jung, Roman Fanta, Md Delowar Hossain, Michal Bajdich</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering enhanced high mass specific activity and robust Pt/PtSe2 electrode for large current hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136750</link>
      <description>Bing Hao, Jingjing Guo, Feng Chen, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Yanhui Song, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo, Fuel. 405(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414100876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Hao, Jingjing Guo, Feng Chen, Hai&#8208;Xia Zhang, Yanhui Song, Peizhi Liu, Junjie Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure optimization of transition metal dichalcogenides via Cu doping for enhanced nitrate reduction reaction efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107649</link>
      <description>Jiacheng Li, Wei Lang, Lei Rao, Peifang Wang, Chongchong Liu, Y.C. Zhou, Yi Chen, Gang Zhou, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414106340

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiacheng Li, Wei Lang, Lei Rao, Peifang Wang, Chongchong Liu, Y.C. Zhou, Yi Chen, Gang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Study to Assess the Influence of Elastic Strains on the Catalytic Activity of Au Surfaces for the HER and ORR Including the Effect of Coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01962</link>
      <description>Diego Schaefer-Dalmau, Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Javier LLorca, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414111269

                The influence of different surface coverages and the effect of biaxial elastic strains on the catalytic properties for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) were analyzed using the example of a Au fcc(111) surface. The adsorption energies of H, O, and OH for the corresponding intermediate reactions were obtained by density functional theory calculations. While for H and O, the adsorption energy increased with coverage, for OH, the lowest adsorption energy was observed at 0.5 ML. Then, after elastic strains were applied, the trends observed for the unstrained slab were maintained for the three adsorbates. Although neither tension nor compression modified the optimum coverage, they did change the differences in relative energies. This is considered to be a consequence of the deformations promoted on the surface. Finally, the catalytic activity of the HER and ORR was computed for the distinct coverages and elastic strains. Catalytic activity plots confirmed for both reactions that the more favorable adsorption energy promoted by tensile strains leads to an increment of the activity and that the most active coverage is 0.25 ML. Furthermore, an analysis of the free energies of each step of the dissociative mechanism of the ORR unveils that both coverage and elastic strains can modify the rate-limiting step and, therefore, the catalytic activity of a material. The results presented in this work provide ample characterization of the Au fcc(111) surface as a catalyst for the HER and ORR and offer, for the first time, an analysis of the influence of both coverage and elastic strain engineering on the catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Diego Schaefer-Dalmau, Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Javier LLorca, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c01962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Hydroxylated Mn-Doped RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as an Efficient and Stable Electrocatalyst for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04487</link>
      <description>Qian Dang, Zhe Shang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414112879

                The role of surface hydroxylation in the performance of RuO2-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial but still unclear. Using first-principles calculations, we comprehensively studied the impact of surface hydroxylation states on the activity and stability of Mn-doped RuO2-based electrocatalysts (denoted as nOH-Mn0.1Ru0.9O2, n = 1&#8211;5) in acidic OER. It was revealed that the moderately hydroxylated Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 demonstrates better performance than the fully hydroxylated structure, and 4OH-Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 holds the lowest reaction barrier of 0.14 eV in solvation under the constant potential of 1.5 V, which is lower than those of both pure RuO2 (0.28 eV) and Mn0.1Ru0.9O2 (0.23 eV). Such an increase in catalytic activity stems from the nonstrong-and-nonweak charge transfer of reaction sites. In addition, the synergistic effect of doping and hydroxylation can also increase the stability of RuO2 through inhibition of structure collapse caused by the dissolution of Ru and the loss of lattice oxygen. The present study has provided a novel strategy for the design of efficient and stable RuO2-based acidic OER catalysts through surface hydroxylation.</description>
      <author>Qian Dang, Zhe Shang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Hydrogenationof Lignin Derivatives For Sustainable Synthesis of Value-Added Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00981-3</link>
      <description>Ning L&#252;, Congxin Chen, Xiaokang Zhao, Xinxin Li, Dehua Xiong, Zan Li, Guangyuan Yang, Lei Wang, Li Guo, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414116679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning L&#252;, Congxin Chen, Xiaokang Zhao, Xinxin Li, Dehua Xiong, Zan Li, Guangyuan Yang, Lei Wang, Li Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00981-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy, exergy, environmental, and exergoeconomic (4E) analysis of a fossil fuel power plant with carbon capture unit for a sustainable future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2025.08.056</link>
      <description>Tahir Abdul Hussain Ratlamwala, Khurram Kamal, Hafsa Javed, Sheikh Muhammad Ali Haider, &#1052;uhammad Abid, Sayem Zafar, Mohammed Alkahtani, Alexandria Engineering Journal. 130(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414116771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tahir Abdul Hussain Ratlamwala, Khurram Kamal, Hafsa Javed, Sheikh Muhammad Ali Haider, &#1052;uhammad Abid, Sayem Zafar, Mohammed Alkahtani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2025.08.056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing carbon capture and storage (CCS) infrastructure development using a python tool for source-sink matching and cluster formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146563</link>
      <description>Amina Togay, Gaini Serik, Woojin Lee, Journal of Cleaner Production. 525(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414118433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amina Togay, Gaini Serik, Woojin Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel Janus InN/PtSSe heterostructure for highly efficient overall water splitting via a third-generation Z-scheme: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151360</link>
      <description>Khawla Chaoui, Ali Hamidani, Kamel Zanat, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 174(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414120014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Khawla Chaoui, Ali Hamidani, Kamel Zanat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable optoelectronic and hydrogen evolution reaction properties of decorated 2D materials (Ga2O3 monolayer, ZnO monolayer and borophene)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2025.116372</link>
      <description>Rongzhi Wang, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng, Physica E Low-dimensional Systems and Nanostructures. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414120360

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rongzhi Wang, Jin&#8208;Cheng Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2025.116372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced stability catalytic performance: a strategy for stability enhancement of Ru-based catalysts in acidic OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/01614940.2025.2556094</link>
      <description>Bin Liu, Yong Zhao, Yuhao Wu, Yanxuan Wen, Zonglin Liu, Pengfei Wang, Jie Shu, Ting-Feng Yi, Catalysis Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414123085

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Liu, Yong Zhao, Yuhao Wu, Yanxuan Wen, Zonglin Liu, Pengfei Wang, Jie Shu, Ting-Feng Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/01614940.2025.2556094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Electrolyte Ions on Iridium Oxide-Based Water Oxidation Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03970</link>
      <description>Boqiang Chen, Pengpeng Wang, Dongyoon Shin, Wei Li, Tianying Liu, Matthias M. Waegele, Dunwei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414125155

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boqiang Chen, Pengpeng Wang, Dongyoon Shin, Wei Li, Tianying Liu, Matthias M. Waegele, Dunwei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tandem amine scrubbing and CO2 electrolysis via direct piperazine carbamate reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01869-8</link>
      <description>Peng Li, Yu Mao, Heejong Shin, Qi Yang, Xuan Cheng, Yitong Li, Kangkang Li, Hai Yu, Roger J. Mulder, Wei Kong Pang, Huanyu Jin, Yong Zhao, Zhifeng Zheng, E. P. Finch, Kyle N. Hearn, Baohua Jia, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Ziyun Wang, Tianyi Ma, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414131647

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Li, Yu Mao, Heejong Shin, Qi Yang, Xuan Cheng, Yitong Li, Kangkang Li, Hai Yu, Roger J. Mulder, Wei Kong Pang, Huanyu Jin, Yong Zhao, Zhifeng Zheng, E. P. Finch, Kyle N. Hearn, Baohua Jia, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Ziyun Wang, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01869-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of monoatomic boron electronic structure to improve catalytic activity for electrocatalytic acetonitrile reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151428</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Song, Liang Yu, Yi Yang, Xiaoqing Gong, Mingqiang Liu, Kai Xu, Daming Sun, Kefeng Xie, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 174(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414141625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Song, Liang Yu, Yi Yang, Xiaoqing Gong, Mingqiang Liu, Kai Xu, Daming Sun, Kefeng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-engineered Ga2SSe/SnS2 van der Waals heterojunction as an efficient S-scheme photocatalyst for solar water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107637</link>
      <description>Junhao Zhu, Zhengdong Sun, Jiaxin Ma, Yifei Shen, Xiao Wang, Meng Zhang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414148250

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junhao Zhu, Zhengdong Sun, Jiaxin Ma, Yifei Shen, Xiao Wang, Meng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials Engineering for High Performance and Durability Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01989</link>
      <description>Pablo A. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Salaberri, Lonneke van Eijk, William Bangay, Kara J. Ferner, M.H. Ha, M. S. Moore, Ivan Perea, Ahmet Kusoglu, Fei Wei, Prodip K. Das, Nausir Firas, Svitlana Pylypenko, Melissa Novy, Michael Yandrasits, Suvash C. Saha, Ali Bayat, Shawn Litster, Iryna V. Zenyuk, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414155218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pablo A. Garc&#237;a&#8208;Salaberri, Lonneke van Eijk, William Bangay, Kara J. Ferner, M.H. Ha, M. S. Moore, Ivan Perea, Ahmet Kusoglu, Fei Wei, Prodip K. Das, Nausir Firas, Svitlana Pylypenko, Melissa Novy, Michael Yandrasits, Suvash C. Saha, Ali Bayat, Shawn Litster, Iryna V. Zenyuk</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c01989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non&#8208;oxide High&#8208;Entropy Ceramics for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.70048</link>
      <description>Gang Wang, Xuguang Guo, Lihua Lyu, Ruihui Gan, Yongping Zheng, Hyoyoung Lee, Xiaodong Shao, Carbon Neutralization. 4(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414155426

                ABSTRACT As fossil energy resources deplete and environmental challenges escalate, the development of clean energy technologies has gained global consensus. Among emerging strategies, electrochemical water splitting for hydrogen production stands out due to its zero&#8208;carbon emissions. However, the oxygen evolution reaction suffers from sluggish kinetics and typically depends on precious metal catalysts. Recently, non&#8208;oxygen anion (e.g., S, P, N, F, C, etc.) high&#8208;entropy ceramics (NOHECs), a subclass of high&#8208;entropy materials doped with diverse elements, have demonstrated significant OER potential, offering a cost&#8208;effective solution with high activity and excellent stability. This review delineates the synthesis methods for NOHECs from two distinct perspectives: liquid&#8208;phase synthesis routes and gas&#8208;phase synthesis routes. Subsequently, the catalytic mechanisms and performance breakthroughs of various NOHECs are reviewed in detail, which are categorized by the types of coordinated non&#8208;oxygen anions. Importantly, this review critically explores future research directions for these materials from multiple perspectives, including innovative synthetic routes, novel NOHEC designs, theoretical simulations, advanced material characterization techniques, industrial feasibility, and expanded applications. Ultimately, it aims to provide a theoretical foundation and technical references for the integration of NOHECs in energy conversion systems while highlighting promising pathways for further advancement in this rapidly evolving field.</description>
      <author>Gang Wang, Xuguang Guo, Lihua Lyu, Ruihui Gan, Yongping Zheng, Hyoyoung Lee, Xiaodong Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.70048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-optimized copper dual-atom sites for selective electroreduction of carbon dioxide to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ads0609</link>
      <description>Xuewei Huang, Xinwei Li, Shuhao Yan, Dawei Wang, Chang Long, Ying Yue, Pengfei An, Zhiyu Guo, Qun Li, Caoyu Yang, Sheng Chen, Jianyu Han, Lin Chang, Siyu Lu, Yin Zhang, Science Advances. 11(37)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414161983

                Electrocatalytic carbon dioxide (CO2) reduction holds the great potential to convert excess emissions of carbon footprint into high value-added chemicals, but its activity, selectivity, stability, and reproducibility are still far away from satisfactory. The molecular catalysts with precise structures are unique platform to decipher the electrocatalytic mechanism, but they usually suffer from low performance. Herein, we report a strain-optimized dual copper complex immobilized in mesoporous carbon, which exhibits remarkable ethylene (C2H4) Faradaic efficiency (FE) up to 49.9% along with a multicarbon (C2+) product's FE up to 65.2% at -1.19 volts versus reversible hydrogen electrode. Concurrently, the catalyst displays considerable stability for 15 hours at a full cell potential of -3.1 volts. The density functional theory calculation reveals that the strain effect imposed by mesoporous carbon regulates the neighboring dual copper sites in the electrocatalyst to decrease the energy barrier of rate-determining step (*COCO &#8594; *COCOH), thus significantly promoting ethylene production.</description>
      <author>Xuewei Huang, Xinwei Li, Shuhao Yan, Dawei Wang, Chang Long, Ying Yue, Pengfei An, Zhiyu Guo, Qun Li, Caoyu Yang, Sheng Chen, Jianyu Han, Lin Chang, Siyu Lu, Yin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ads0609</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C2N supported single Fe3 cluster for efficient electrocatalytic urea synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168128</link>
      <description>Zhongwei Wang, Nan Xia, Yan Gao, Hongsheng Liu, Junfeng Gao, Haifeng Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. 522(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414164336

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongwei Wang, Nan Xia, Yan Gao, Hongsheng Liu, Junfeng Gao, Haifeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-Level Insight into Ni Clusters Supported on N-Terminated Diamond (111) Surface for HER, OER, and ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02155</link>
      <description>Wei Cheng, Nan Gao, Shaoheng Cheng, Hongdong Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414166732

                Single-cluster catalysts (SCCs), an emerging frontier between single-atom catalysts and conventional metal nanoparticle catalysts, have attracted significant attention due to their unique geometric and electronic structures. Herein, we systematically investigate the structural models and the hydrogen-evolution reaction (HER), oxygen-evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen-reduction reaction (ORR) performances for Nix clusters (x = 2-9) anchored on a N-terminated diamond (111) surface (Nix@ND) through Crystal structure AnaLYsis by Particle Swarm Optimization (CALYPSO)-based structural prediction and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The Ni-H bonding strength serves as a critical descriptor for HER activity, where a balanced relative strength of ad-/desorption is beneficial for enhancing it. The Gibbs free energy change (&#916;G*H) of the Ni7@ND catalyst is -0.25 eV, demonstrating optimal HER performance with an efficiency approaching that of highly efficient Pt-based catalysts. Furthermore, Ni4@ND and Ni2@ND catalysts demonstrate superior OER and ORR performance with low overpotentials (&#951;), which are significantly lower than those of single-atom catalyst Ni1@ND. Volcano curve analysis reveals that the OER performance is maximized at the intermediate adsorption strength of key reaction species (*O, *OH). A pronounced linear correlation is found between &#951;ORR and adsorption energies of intermediate *OH. Furthermore, size effects in SCCs narrow the band gap and increase the number of active sites, thus promoting the catalytic performance (optimizing charge redistribution and reducing the rate-determining step barrier). This design strategy provides atomic-level insights into highly efficient diamond-based SCCs for HER, OER, and ORR.</description>
      <author>Wei Cheng, Nan Gao, Shaoheng Cheng, Hongdong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Tuning of Carbon-Based Nanostructure Surfaces Toward Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction Reaction: Inquiry to Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41061-025-00521-z</link>
      <description>Y. Anjali, Rijo Rajeev, Manoj Balachandran, Tom Cherian, Anitha Varghese, Topics in Current Chemistry. 383(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414167248

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y. Anjali, Rijo Rajeev, Manoj Balachandran, Tom Cherian, Anitha Varghese</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41061-025-00521-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of spin states and electronic excitation via molecular doping with Fe(II)-porphyrin in 2D gallium nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0285574</link>
      <description>Yachao Zhang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414169291

                2D gallium nitride possesses distinctive electronic states, making it ideal for future optoelectronic devices because of the quantum confinement and enhanced many-body interactions inherent in its atomically thin form. This study explores the impact of molecular doping with Fe(II)-porphyrin (FeP) on these characteristics using first-principle calculations. Contact of the magnetic center Fe with the nitrogen site causes a 17% decrease in the energy barrier for the transition from intermediate spin (S = 1) to high spin (S = 2) state, highlighting the sensitivity of spin dynamics to doping sites. Molecular diffusion barriers increase by 9.6 kJ/mol upon spin transition, suggesting that the spin state influences molecular mobility within the material. Exploring spectral functions reveals that FeP doping introduces spin-dependent molecule levels within the bandgap, which may play a role in electron-hole separation and spin injection. In addition, we show that the molecule-substrate coupling lowers the exciton binding energy by 0.1 eV, with further reduction during spin transitions. This weakening is attributed to increased electron mobility, quantified by static polarizability. These results indicate that the molecular spin state can control electronic excitations within substrate materials, presenting a promising strategy for designing spintronic devices.</description>
      <author>Yachao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0285574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface and Interface Engineering of Noble Metal Heterostructures for Superior ORR Performance: Unlocking Ultralow Loading and Maximum Catalyst Utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202506018</link>
      <description>Dinesh Bhalothia, Amisha Beniwal, Hariom Gurjar, Khushabu Shekhawat, Ashima Bagaria, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414169444

                The quest for sustainable and high-efficiency energy conversion technologies has driven intense research into oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts, particularly those based on noble metals, due to the harsh redox environment of these devices. Despite their unparalleled activity, the scarcity and high cost of noble metals like platinum remain significant bottlenecks for large-scale application. Recent advances in surface and interface engineering of noble metal heterostructures offer a promising pathway to address these challenges. By precisely tailoring surface atomic arrangements, modulating interfacial electronic structures, and constructing synergistic heterojunctions, researchers have unlocked unprecedented catalytic efficiencies with dramatically reduced metal loading. This review systematically explores the latest strategies in designing surface- and interface-optimized noble metal heterostructures for ORR, highlighting how these innovations enable maximum utilization of active sites while enhancing activity and durability. We delve into various synthesis techniques, structural modulation approaches, and mechanistic insights gained from advanced characterization and theoretical modeling. Special emphasis is placed on understanding the critical role of heterointerfaces in tuning adsorption energies, charge transfer dynamics, and reaction pathways. Finally, we outline current challenges and propose future directions for the rational design of next-generation ORR catalysts that combine minimal noble metal usage with exceptional performance.</description>
      <author>Dinesh Bhalothia, Amisha Beniwal, Hariom Gurjar, Khushabu Shekhawat, Ashima Bagaria, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202506018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reserved charges in a long-lived NiOOH phase drive catalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01942-5</link>
      <description>Xin Cui, Yunxuan Ding, Feiyang Zhang, Xing Cao, Yu Guo, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang, Nature Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414183253

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Cui, Yunxuan Ding, Feiyang Zhang, Xing Cao, Yu Guo, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01942-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Hydrogen/Liquid Fuel Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch08</link>
      <description>Ran Wang, Huan Pang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414186089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ran Wang, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch08</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch07</link>
      <description>Yifan Ma, Junhua Li, Ying Tang, Hang An, Xiaopeng Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414186120

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Ma, Junhua Li, Ying Tang, Hang An, Xiaopeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch07</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch09</link>
      <description>An&#8208;Liang Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414186224

                No abstract</description>
      <author>An&#8208;Liang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch09</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constant&#8208;potential Modeling in Electrochemical CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch03</link>
      <description>Yaqiong Su, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414186330

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaqiong Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch03</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of hydrogen diffusion mechanism and enhanced catalytic activity in monolayer &#946;12-type borophene for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168499</link>
      <description>Jiahao Gao, Yong Pan, I.P. Jain, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414187843

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahao Gao, Yong Pan, I.P. Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;Orbitals Modulation for Tailoring Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P Interfacial Adsorption Behavior: Boosting Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202504036</link>
      <description>Lei Wang, Xian&#8208;Wei Lv, Haoyu Wang, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Yi Feng, Minglei Sun, Zhong&#8208;Yong Yuan, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414188929

                Abstract Rational design of an efficient catalyst that simultaneously accelerates water splitting, promotes hydroxyl conversion, and facilitates hydrogen desorption presents a significant challenge for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). To address this challenge, a series of coordinating metals selected from elements of the 4th&#8208; and 5th&#8208;period is incorporated into dicobalt phosphide (Co 2 P), thereby tuning the interfacial adsorption. Among these elements&#8208;coordinated catalysts, simultaneously considering both d &#8208;band filling and spin polarization, the iron&#8208;coordinated catalyst (Fe&#8208;CPNCF) exhibits appropriate adsorption energy, activates interfacial inert H 2 O molecules and locates at the optimal position on the volcano plot for the H 2 O dissociation barrier, owing to the rational d &#8208;orbitals modulation of active sites by Fe coordination. Thus, the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzers based on Fe&#8208;CPNCF achieve a current density of 2 A cm &#8722;2 at a low cell voltage of 2.04 V and maintain stable electrolysis for 1160 h, demonstrating great potential in commercial applications. This work underscores the importance of rationally tuning the d&#8208; orbitals of active sites for modulating interfacial adsorption behavior, providing relevant insights for the development of efficient hydrogen evolution catalysts.</description>
      <author>Lei Wang, Xian&#8208;Wei Lv, Haoyu Wang, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Yi Feng, Minglei Sun, Zhong&#8208;Yong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202504036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized selectivity in CO2 electrochemical reduction using amorphous CuNi catalysts: insights from density functional theory and machine learning simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.08.089</link>
      <description>Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Enrico Pedretti, Maria Clelia Righi, Devis Di Tommaso, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414189857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Enrico Pedretti, Maria Clelia Righi, Devis Di Tommaso</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.08.089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weighted active space protocol for multireference machine-learned potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2513693122</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Seal, Simone Perego, Matthew R. Hennefarth, Umberto Raucci, Luigi Bonati, Andrew L. Ferguson, Michele Parrinello, Laura Gagliardi, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(38)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414195114

                Multireference methods such as multiconfiguration pair-density functional theory accurately capture electronic correlation in systems with strong multiconfigurational character, but their cost precludes direct use in molecular dynamics. Combining these methods with machine-learned interatomic potentials (MLPs) can extend their reach. However, the sensitivity of multireference calculations to the choice of the active space complicates the consistent evaluation of energies and gradients across structurally diverse nuclear configurations. To overcome this limitation, we introduce the weighted active space protocol (WASP), a systematic approach to assign a consistent active space for a given system across uncorrelated configurations. By integrating WASP with MLPs and enhanced sampling techniques, we propose a data-efficient active learning cycle that enables the training of an MLP on multireference data. We demonstrated the approach on the TiC+-catalyzed C-H activation of methane, a reaction that poses challenges for Kohn-Sham density functional theory due to its significant multireference character. This framework enables accurate and efficient modeling of catalytic dynamics, establishing a paradigm for simulating complex reactive processes beyond the limits of conventional electronic-structure methods.</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Seal, Simone Perego, Matthew R. Hennefarth, Umberto Raucci, Luigi Bonati, Andrew L. Ferguson, Michele Parrinello, Laura Gagliardi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2513693122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibrational Energy Dissipation in Noncontact Single-Molecule Junctions Governed by Local Geometry and Electronic Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00931</link>
      <description>Lukas H&#246;rmann, Reinhard J. Maurer, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414199780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lukas H&#246;rmann, Reinhard J. Maurer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Surface Engineering of RuPd Nanocatalysts: Orchestrating Reactive Hydrogen Formation, and 2-Chlorophenol Adsorption Dynamics for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Hydrodechlorination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestengg.5c00535</link>
      <description>Hehe Qian, T. Ma, Lili Shi, Shu Yan, Huijuan Cui, Xueqing Luo, Fang Chen, Yuetan Su, Zhongbiao Wu, Xiaole Weng, ACS ES&amp;T Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414200201

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hehe Qian, T. Ma, Lili Shi, Shu Yan, Huijuan Cui, Xueqing Luo, Fang Chen, Yuetan Su, Zhongbiao Wu, Xiaole Weng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestengg.5c00535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Platinum FePt Nanoalloys with Nanoconfinement Effects for Durable Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02931</link>
      <description>Wei Liu, Guangxu Bao, Yihan Xu, Xiaoyi Chen, Jianlong Lin, Zhanpeng Liang, Xiao Wang, Wenquan Cui, Sheng Zhang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414205033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Liu, Guangxu Bao, Yihan Xu, Xiaoyi Chen, Jianlong Lin, Zhanpeng Liang, Xiao Wang, Wenquan Cui, Sheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge&#8208;Deficient PtCu Clusters&#8208;Stabilized Vacancy&#8208;Engineered Mo&lt;sub&gt;4/3&lt;/sub&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;z&lt;/sub&gt; MBene Flake Synergistically Boosts Efficient Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202515741</link>
      <description>Penghao Zhu, Jinhai Yang, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Xichan He, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414205353

                Abstract In this work, a robust method is presented for synthesizing homogeneously distributed, ultrafine PtCu atomic clusters supported on Cu&#8208;modified, vacancy&#8208;engineered Mo 4/3 B 2 T z MBene nanosheets (PtCu AC @Cu&#8208;Mo 4/3 B 2 T z ). The material serves as highly efficient pH&#8208;universal hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalyst, which demonstrates impressively low overpotentials of 4 and 15 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 and 1.0 M KOH, respectively, as well as sustained operational stability. Through comprehensive analysis of in situ Raman spectroscopy and density functional theory, it is realizes that Cu incorporation optimizes the electronic configuration of Pt sites and significantly enhances proton transfer and interfacial water activation. In addition, the active metal&#8208;MBene interactions also leads to modulation in the d&#8208;band center of Pt d&#8208;orbitals, fine&#8208;tuning the adsorption energy of H * and reducing the energy barrier for water dissociation, thus promoting H 2 evolution. The practical tests demonstrate high&#8208;performance anion exchange membrane single&#8208;cell stack based on PtCu AC @Cu&#8208;Mo 4/3 B 2 T z(&#8722;) ||RuO 2(+) configuration, reaching current densities of 0.5/1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.75/1.86 V and stable performance for over 600 h at 0.5 A cm &#8722;2 in 1.0 M KOH at 60 &#176;C. This research underscores the importance of active metal&#8208;supported MBene in enhancing catalytic functions and demonstrates the key role of next&#8208;generation MBene&#8208;based hybrid materials as durable support for electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Penghao Zhu, Jinhai Yang, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Xichan He, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202515741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isopotential Electron Titration: Hydrogen Adsorbate-Metal Charge Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c00851</link>
      <description>J. Hopkins, Benjamin Page, Shengguang Wang, Jesse Canavan, Jason Chalmers, Susannah L. Scott, Lars C. Grabow, James R. McKone, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Omar Abdelrahman, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414206588

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Hopkins, Benjamin Page, Shengguang Wang, Jesse Canavan, Jason Chalmers, Susannah L. Scott, Lars C. Grabow, James R. McKone, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Omar Abdelrahman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c00851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Decomposition over Carbon for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Free Hydrogen Production: A Combined DFT and Experimental Investigation on the Role of Carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04541</link>
      <description>Peng Zhao, Chee Kok Poh, Jiajian Gao, Jiren Zeng, Saifudin Abubakar, Guang Sheng Cao, Lili Zhang, Jia Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414213810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Zhao, Chee Kok Poh, Jiajian Gao, Jiren Zeng, Saifudin Abubakar, Guang Sheng Cao, Lili Zhang, Jia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive multiscale modeling to bridge atomic properties and electrochemical performance in Li-CO2 battery design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126693</link>
      <description>Mohammed Lemaalem, S. Selva Chandrasekaran, Ilias Papailias, Naveen Dandu, Arash Namaeighasemi, Larry A. Curtiss, Amin Salehi&#8208;Khojin, Anh T. Ngo, Applied Energy. 401(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414223727

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammed Lemaalem, S. Selva Chandrasekaran, Ilias Papailias, Naveen Dandu, Arash Namaeighasemi, Larry A. Curtiss, Amin Salehi&#8208;Khojin, Anh T. Ngo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing charge equilibration-based machine learning potentials to their limits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01791-3</link>
      <description>Martin Vondr&#225;k, Karsten Reuter, Johannes T. Margraf, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414224048

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Martin Vondr&#225;k, Karsten Reuter, Johannes T. Margraf</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01791-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallic bismuth-embedded mesoporous carbon hollow spheres for highly selective electrocatalytic hydrogen peroxide production via two-electron oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136799</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Wang, Kun Li, Junling Hu, Meixin Wang, Yanzhi Sun, Pingyu Wan, Yang Tang, Haomin Jiang, Yongmei Chen, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414225638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Wang, Kun Li, Junling Hu, Meixin Wang, Yanzhi Sun, Pingyu Wan, Yang Tang, Haomin Jiang, Yongmei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136799</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing for cooperative grain boundary segregation in multicomponent alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2511930122</link>
      <description>Malik Wagih, Yannick Naunheim, Tianjiao Lei, Christopher A. Schuh, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(38)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414229049

                Tailoring the nanoscale distribution of chemical species at grain boundaries is a powerful method to dramatically influence the properties of polycrystalline materials. However, classical approaches to the problem have tacitly assumed that only competition is possible between solute species. In this paper, we show that solute elements can cooperate in the way they segregate to grain boundaries: In properly targeted alloys, the different chemical species cooperate to each fill complementary grain boundary sites disfavored by the other. By developing a theoretical &#8220;spectral&#8221; approach to this problem based on quantum-accurate grain boundary site distributions, we show how grain boundaries can be cooperatively alloyed, whether by depletion or enrichment. We provide machine-learned cosegregation information for over 700 ternary aluminum-based alloys and experimentally validate the concept in one ternary alloy where cosegregation is not expected by prior models but is expected based on the cooperative model.</description>
      <author>Malik Wagih, Yannick Naunheim, Tianjiao Lei, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2511930122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface synergy engineering in CoFe@NiFe LDH hierarchical heterostructures for bifunctional water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.183765</link>
      <description>Yu Zhong, Zhaoyue Zhang, Xiaoying Chen, Qi Chen, Le Chen, Huanan Wang, Jili Wen, Xiaying Kuang, Peixin Zhang, Jiang Wu, Jia Lin, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1041(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414229888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Zhong, Zhaoyue Zhang, Xiaoying Chen, Qi Chen, Le Chen, Huanan Wang, Jili Wen, Xiaying Kuang, Peixin Zhang, Jiang Wu, Jia Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.183765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning-Driven Mechanism Prediction and New Electrocatalyst Generation for Metal-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/227654-ms</link>
      <description>Maimuna U. Zarewa, Tawfik A. Saleh, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414232856

                Abstract In this work, copper-doped Electrocatalyst was synthesized via pyrolysis, and the electrocatalyst was characterized by XRD, FTIR, and XPS, followed by electrochemical testing. Also, a new electrocatalyst for metal-air batteries was designed, and reaction processes are predicted using large language models (LLMs) such as ChemBERT and ChemGPT. To train the models, RDKit was used to process SMILES representations of functional groups, doping techniques, and electrolyte media. While ChemGPT produced new electrocatalysts with an accuracy of 0.83, ChemBERT, which had been optimized to 0.8, was used to predict mechanisms. To speed up catalyst identification, the methodology incorporates reaction pathway predictions.</description>
      <author>Maimuna U. Zarewa, Tawfik A. Saleh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/227654-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion of Reversible Fuel-Power Generation in Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cell via Water-Mediated Ex-Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02146</link>
      <description>Sejong Ahn, Dongyeon Kim, Incheol Jeong, HeeChan Kang, Ivy Lim, GaEun Heo, Dae&#8208;Kwang Lim, Jun Kyu Kim, Ki&#8208;Min Roh, Bonjae Koo, Jun Hyuk Kim, Kang Taek Lee, WooChul Jung, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414245341

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sejong Ahn, Dongyeon Kim, Incheol Jeong, HeeChan Kang, Ivy Lim, GaEun Heo, Dae&#8208;Kwang Lim, Jun Kyu Kim, Ki&#8208;Min Roh, Bonjae Koo, Jun Hyuk Kim, Kang Taek Lee, WooChul Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Reaction Kinetics of Highly Selective Oxidation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural to 2,5-Furandicarboxylic Acid over NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c04048</link>
      <description>Linlin Wang, Lin Chen, Ruirui Xu, Mohd Adnan Khan, Jun Zhao, Xinti Yu, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jinguang Hu, Zhangxin Chen, Heng Zhao, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414245687

                Selective valorization of biomass feedstocks and their derivatives, using renewable electricity to produce value-added chemicals, is a promising route to decarbonize the chemical industry. Herein, we demonstrate the selective production of 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) from the electrocatalytic oxidation of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF). NiCo2S4 as an anode electrode exhibits almost 100% yield of FDCA with &gt;90% Faradaic efficiency (FE) and high stability at optimized conditions, which outperforms pure NiSx and CoSx. Theoretical calculations reveal that the enhanced reaction kinetics for HMF conversion to FDCA on NiCo2S4 arises from an optimal OH coverage and a more exergonic rate-limiting step compared with its monometallic counterparts. A techno-economic analysis (TEA) for a 100-ton/day FDCA industrial scale production facility reveals that the NiCo2S4 catalyst could drive economic feasibility of the process. This work provides an economically feasible approach to sustainably produce FDCA from HMF oxidation by electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Linlin Wang, Lin Chen, Ruirui Xu, Mohd Adnan Khan, Jun Zhao, Xinti Yu, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jinguang Hu, Zhangxin Chen, Heng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c04048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-Free Doping Strategies in Two-Dimensional Carbon Nitride C&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05773</link>
      <description>Bruno Ipaves, Jo&#227;o F. Justo, J. Almeida, L. V. C. Assali, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414249256

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bruno Ipaves, Jo&#227;o F. Justo, J. Almeida, L. V. C. Assali, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into the Enhanced OER Activity of Single-Atom Iron Catalysts Compared to Metal Clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c02119</link>
      <description>Partha Pratim Borah, Kalishankar Bhattacharyya, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414250168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Partha Pratim Borah, Kalishankar Bhattacharyya</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c02119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Relations and Catalytic Descriptor for the Nitrogen Reduction on Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147389</link>
      <description>Matteo Spotti, Kevin Maineri, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414255615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matteo Spotti, Kevin Maineri, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147389</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NepTrain and NepTrainKit: Automated Active Learning and Visualization Toolkit for Neuroevolution Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109859</link>
      <description>Chengbing Chen, Yutong Li, Rui Zhao, Zhoulin Liu, Zheyong Fan, Gang Tang, Zhiyong Wang, Computer Physics Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414255949

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chengbing Chen, Yutong Li, Rui Zhao, Zhoulin Liu, Zheyong Fan, Gang Tang, Zhiyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Perspective On Materials, Electrochemistry, and Cell Concepts for Redox&#8208;Mediated CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Direct Air Capture Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ceur.202500236</link>
      <description>Tilmann J. Neubert, Martin Oschatz, ChemistryEurope. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414128369

                Anthropogenic emissions of previously sequestered carbon continue to disrupt the natural carbon cycle, driving atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) concentrations beyond 420 ppm. This has resulted in global temperatures rising beyond 1.5 &#176;C above the pre&#8208;industrial level. Direct air capture (DAC) of CO 2 has emerged as a complementary mitigation strategy. However, current DAC technologies are limited by the high energy requirements inherent to the thermal release of captured CO 2 , which are caused by the low thermodynamic efficiency of heat&#8208;driven processes, as constrained by Carnot principles. Redox&#8208;mediated electrochemical carbon capture (RMECC) offers a promising pathway to overcome these limitations. RMECC with DAC application remains in an early developmental stage and requires further optimization to enable energy&#8208;efficient, cost&#8208;effective, and scalable deployment. In this perspective the design of sorbents, electrolytes, and electrochemical cell configurations in the field of RMECC are discussed with an emphasis on sustainable approaches for the demands of DAC applications. The challenges arising from the atmospheric dilution of CO 2 within the more abundant and disruptive competitor oxygen are highlighted as a critical factor influencing sorbent performance. Recent advancements in RMECC are reviewed, key challenges are identified, and future directions are outlined to accelerate electrochemically mediated DAC towards practical implementation.</description>
      <author>Tilmann J. Neubert, Martin Oschatz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ceur.202500236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic reconstruction unlocks concurrent ultra-auxeticity and platinum-competing catalysis in MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111807</link>
      <description>Yucheng Zhu, Miao Pan, Shuaijun Yang, Jianbo Zhu, Ruidong Li, Zhong Chen, Jun Hu, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414220983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yucheng Zhu, Miao Pan, Shuaijun Yang, Jianbo Zhu, Ruidong Li, Zhong Chen, Jun Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali Metal Cations Induce Pseudo-outer-sphere Oxygen Reduction Reaction Mechanism in Electrolyte-Catalyst Synergy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12947</link>
      <description>Yumiao Tian, Pengfei Hou, Yuanyuan Zhou, Quan Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414168040

                Alkali metal cations (AMCs) are known to play pivotal roles in modulating electrocatalytic systems, significantly affecting the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). While their macroscopic effects are well recognized, the molecular-level interactions of AMCs at the electrochemical interface remain poorly understood. Here, using constant-potential ab initio molecular dynamics simulations, we uncover that AMCs (Li+, Na+, and K+) act as molecular switches that trigger a pseudo-outer-sphere ORR mechanism. In this mechanism, surface-adsorbed water molecules serve as dynamic bridges that simultaneously mediate interfacial electron transfer and proton transport. As a result, the reactive zone extends beyond the catalyst surface, overcoming the spatial constraints of traditional inner-sphere pathways. Crucially, H2O2 is generated directly within the outer Helmholtz plane via reduction of AMC-O2 complexes, effectively bypassing the catalyst surface and avoiding over-reduction. This results in significantly enhanced selectivity and production efficiency. Our results demonstrate that AMCs activate interfacial coupling to unlock alternative reaction pathways, while concurrently elucidating the critical yet often overlooked role of solute molecules in governing electrocatalytic behavior. This work establishes a framework for the understanding of electrolyte-catalyst coupling and provides principles for designing next-generation electrochemical systems.</description>
      <author>Yumiao Tian, Pengfei Hou, Yuanyuan Zhou, Quan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A double-U approach to more accurate metal adsorption energies on ceria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0279619</link>
      <description>Ye Xu, Nusrat Jahan Rifat, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414168252

                An empirical approach based on density functional theory (DFT)+U is proposed to provide adsorption energies for atoms of transition metals adsorbed on ceria that are more accurate than those found in the existing DFT literature. It involves applying an intermediate Hubbard U value to the Ce 4f states and another U value to the d states of the metal adatom that is optimized for each metal to match its calculated bulk cohesive energy with the experimental value. The results compare favorably with Campbell's calorimetric measurements of metal adsorption heats on CeO2(111). Thus, this approach produces metal adsorption energies on ceria that are more accurate in both the single-atom and the bulk limits. Furthermore, it preserves a common reference for Ce so that calculations involving different metals adsorbed on ceria, e.g., bimetallic and multimetallic clusters, can be analyzed on the same footing.</description>
      <author>Ye Xu, Nusrat Jahan Rifat</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0279619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SurFF: a foundation model for surface exposure and morphology across intermetallic crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00839-0</link>
      <description>Jun Yin, Honghao Chen, Ju Qiu, Wentao Li, Peng He, Jiali Li, Iftekhar A. Karimi, Xiaocheng Lan, Tiefeng Wang, Xiaonan Wang, Nature Computational Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414083590

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Yin, Honghao Chen, Ju Qiu, Wentao Li, Peng He, Jiali Li, Iftekhar A. Karimi, Xiaocheng Lan, Tiefeng Wang, Xiaonan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00839-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of CO2/N2 separation capabilities for various amine-functionalized organosilica membranes: synthesis and sorption study evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-025-06933-z</link>
      <description>Ufafa Anggarini, Devi Rahayu, Fauzul Azizah Oktaviola, Ndaru Candra Sukmana, Weiwei Yan, Hiroki Nagasawa, Toshinori Tsuru, Masakoto Kanezashi, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414166625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ufafa Anggarini, Devi Rahayu, Fauzul Azizah Oktaviola, Ndaru Candra Sukmana, Weiwei Yan, Hiroki Nagasawa, Toshinori Tsuru, Masakoto Kanezashi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-025-06933-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical multilayer perceptron for lithium batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238334</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Yang, Daniel M. Tartakovsky, Journal of Power Sources. 659(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414223961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Yang, Daniel M. Tartakovsky</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemistry of Bis(trifluoromethyl)amines: Synthesis, Properties, and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.5c00154</link>
      <description>Nikolai V. Ignat&#8217;ev, Maik Finze, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414239925

                Fluorinated groups are widely applied substituents in medicinal and agricultural chemistry as well as materials sciences because the introduction of per- and polyfluorinated substituents allow the targeted tuning of molecules and materials properties, in general. In addition to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substituents, especially trifluoromethylheteroatom substituents have attracted increasing interest in recent years. The bis(trifluoromethyl)amino group (CF3)2N is an example for a trifluoromethylheteroatom substituent. It has been known since the middle of the last century and it has been used and tested in different fields of applications. This review summarizes the chemistry of the bis(trifluoromethyl)amino group since its beginning up to the end of 2024. It focuses on the synthesis of (CF3)2N-containing compounds, precursors for the introduction of the (CF3)2N group, and follow-up reactions of (CF3)2N-containing molecules. The physicochemical properties of the (CF3)2N group and of bis(trifluoromethyl)amines are collected and potential applications that have been described are summarized, as well.</description>
      <author>Nikolai V. Ignat&#8217;ev, Maik Finze</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.5c00154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetically responsive intelligent fibers: nano-engineered materials and multifunctional integration for advanced applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5mh01383f</link>
      <description>Wenping Cheng, Jie Dong, Wei Liang, Guodong Shen, Qiushi Wang, Runjun Sun, Materials Horizons. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414251551

                Magnetically responsive intelligent fibers represent a new class of smart materials that integrate magnetic components into flexible fiber systems, enabling remote actuation, real-time sensing, and self-powered operation under external magnetic fields. With advantages in flexibility, adaptability, and multifunctionality, they hold promise for wearable electronics, soft robotics, biomedical devices, and energy harvesting. This review highlights recent progress in their design, fabrication, and applications. We summarize magnetic materials used in fiber integration-including ferrites, metal alloys, rare-earth compounds, and 2D materials-focusing on structural and magnetic properties. Multi-physics coupling mechanisms such as magneto-mechanical, magnetoelectric, and magneto-optical effects are discussed as the basis of intelligent responses. Fabrication strategies, including extrusion-based printing, magnetic-field-assisted alignment, and surface modification, are evaluated for scalability, resolution, and material integration. Key challenges for commercialization, such as dispersion, biocompatibility, and mechanical stability under dynamic conditions, are also addressed. Finally, future directions are outlined, emphasizing multifunctional fibers with combined stimuli-responsiveness and integration into adaptive systems. This review aims to provide a framework for advancing magnetically responsive fibers and inspiring future innovations in smart fiber technologies.</description>
      <author>Wenping Cheng, Jie Dong, Wei Liang, Guodong Shen, Qiushi Wang, Runjun Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5mh01383f</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
