<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 01:15:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of Fe2O3-based nanoparticles on nitrogen-incorporated carbon as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.212</link>
      <description>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, Selvam Mathi, Shankara S. Kalanur, T. Maiyalagan, Mohammed Ali Alshehri, Nagaraj P. Shetti, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 103(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406504119

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ranjan S. Shetti, M. Sreenivasulu, Selvam Mathi, Shankara S. Kalanur, T. Maiyalagan, Mohammed Ali Alshehri, Nagaraj P. Shetti</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-based catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolysers: The need to look beyond just another catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.485</link>
      <description>Shailendra Kumar Sharma, Chang Wu, Niall Malone, Laura J. Titheridge, Chuan Zhao, Prasanth Gupta, Hicham Idriss, J. Kennedy, Vedran Jovic, Aaron T. Marshall, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406522527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shailendra Kumar Sharma, Chang Wu, Niall Malone, Laura J. Titheridge, Chuan Zhao, Prasanth Gupta, Hicham Idriss, J. Kennedy, Vedran Jovic, Aaron T. Marshall</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of &#946;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Ir/Ru Co-substitution for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</link>
      <description>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406534076

                The efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media is severely limited by the poor stability, low activity, and high cost of available catalysts. Enhancing intrinsic activity while maintaining stability and reducing reliance on precious metals is crucial. The typical adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) leads to high overpotentials and low activity, making the transition to alternative mechanisms, such as the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) or oxide path mechanism (OPM), highly desirable due to their lower overpotentials. Here, we combine density functional theory (DFT) calculations with experimental validation to enhance the activity and stability of &#946;-MnO2 via co-substitution with ruthenium (Ru) and iridium (Ir), enabling the transition from AEM to OPM. DFT calculations reveal that AEM is hindered by the weak nucleophilicity of water, while LOM suffers from high kinetic barriers due to structural distortions. In contrast, OPM demonstrates a significantly lower kinetic barrier, facilitated by the synergistic interaction between Ru and Ir. Experimentally, IrRuMnOx was synthesized through co-precipitation and hydrothermal methods, showing an 80-fold improvement in mass activity and a 96-fold increase in stability compared to commercial IrO2, with minimal noble metal leaching, as confirmed by inductively coupled plasma optical emission spectroscopy (ICP-OES). IrRuMnOx exhibited an ultralow overpotential of 475 mV at 1 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 44.26 mV&#183;dec&#8211;1 in 0.5 M H2SO4, maintaining stable performance for over 100 h. Moreover, the IrRuMnOx-based membrane electrode, with a low Ir loading of 0.075 mgIr&#183;cm&#8211;2, achieved remarkable current densities of 1.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.66 V and 2.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.91 V at 80 &#176;C. This performance surpasses that of both unsupported and conventional supported Ir-based catalysts at comparable Ir loading levels. This study offers critical insights into OER mechanisms in acidic media and paves the way for developing efficient and durable OER electrocatalysts for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase&#8208;Engineered Bi&#8208;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Single&#8208;Atom Alloy Oxide Boosting Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417777</link>
      <description>Zhichao Yang, Yutian Ding, Wen Chen, Shuiping Luo, Daofan Cao, Xin Long, Lei Xie, Xincheng Zhou, Xinyi Cai, Ke Liu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406543620

                Abstract Engineering nanomaterials at single&#8208;atomic sites can enable unprecedented catalytic properties for broad applications, yet it remains challenging to do so on RuO 2 &#8208;based electrocatalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE). Herein, the rational design and construction of Bi&#8208;RuO 2 single&#8208;atom alloy oxide (SAAO) are presented to boost acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), via phase engineering a novel hexagonal close packed ( hcp ) RuBi single&#8208;atom alloy. This Bi&#8208;RuO 2 SAAO electrocatalyst exhibits a low overpotential of 192 mV and superb stability over 650 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , enabling a practical PEMWE that needs only 1.59 V to reach 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 under industrial conditions. Operando differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy analysis, coupled with density functional theory studies, confirmed the adsorbate&#8208;evolving mechanism on Bi&#8208;RuO 2 SAAO and that the incorporation of Bi 1 improves the activity by electronic density optimization and the stability by hindering surface Ru demetallation. This work not only introduces a new strategy to fabricate high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts at atomic&#8208;level, but also demonstrates their potential use in industrial electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Zhichao Yang, Yutian Ding, Wen Chen, Shuiping Luo, Daofan Cao, Xin Long, Lei Xie, Xincheng Zhou, Xinyi Cai, Ke Liu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable adsorption configuration searching in hetero-catalysis based on similar distribution and active learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115971</link>
      <description>Jiaqiang Yang, Xiaofei Zhang, Xiaofeng Zhang, Bingbo Niu, Feifeng Wu, Ning Luo, Jilin He, Chengduo Wang, Bin Shan, Qingkui Li, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406559764

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqiang Yang, Xiaofei Zhang, Xiaofeng Zhang, Bingbo Niu, Feifeng Wu, Ning Luo, Jilin He, Chengduo Wang, Bin Shan, Qingkui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyrrole-type TM-N3 sites as high-efficient bifunctional oxygen reactions electrocatalysts: From theoretical prediction to experimental validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.01.002</link>
      <description>Chunxia Wu, Yanhui Yu, Yiming Song, Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Ying Liang, Liqiang Jing, Kai Zhang, Zhenjie Zhang, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406560069

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunxia Wu, Yanhui Yu, Yiming Song, Peng Rao, Xing&#8208;Qi Han, Ying Liang, Liqiang Jing, Kai Zhang, Zhenjie Zhang, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.01.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing energy and economic costs in post-combustion carbon capture with intelligent amine selection system: A case study on the Abadan power plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2025.01.034</link>
      <description>Farzin Hosseinifard, Amir Mohsen Soufeh, Mohsen Salimi, Milad Hosseinpour, Majid Amidpour, Energy Reports. 13(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406561569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Farzin Hosseinifard, Amir Mohsen Soufeh, Mohsen Salimi, Milad Hosseinpour, Majid Amidpour</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.egyr.2025.01.034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of the onset voltage of water adsorption on Pt(111) surface using density functional theory/Implicit model calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105809</link>
      <description>Maxim Shishkin, Takeo Yamaguchi, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406562334

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maxim Shishkin, Takeo Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor for electro-oxidation of glycerol with high-efficiency bifunctional Cu-N single atom catalyst and coupled with hydrogen evolution/carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.122</link>
      <description>Mingyue Lv, Hao Sun, Hui Wang, Jing&#8208;yao Liu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 685(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyue Lv, Hao Sun, Hui Wang, Jing&#8208;yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of transition metal atom doped MoS2 as single-atom electrocatalysts for nitrogen fixation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115090</link>
      <description>Wei Song, Zhe Fu, Jiale Liu, Jinqiang Li, Chaozheng He, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Song, Zhe Fu, Jiale Liu, Jinqiang Li, Chaozheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ growth of Ni2.86Te2 and Mo6Te8 telluride catalysts on foam NiMo substrates for enhanced oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</link>
      <description>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406570335

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridinic&#8208;N Seized Co in Biphasic Nanoarchitecture for Reversible Oxygen Electrocatalysis Enabling Longevous (&amp;gt;1200 h) Aqueous and Dual&#8208;Anion Kosmotropic Electrolyte Stabilized High Power Quasisolid&#8208;State Zn&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401874</link>
      <description>Srijib Das, Saikat Bolar, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, A. J. Pathak, Ranjit Thapa, Ujjwal Phadikar, Haradhan Kolya, Chun&#8211;Won Kang, Tapas Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Aniruddha Kundu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406593979

                Abstract Integration of different active sites by heterostructure engineering is pivotal to optimize the intrinsic activities of an oxygen electrocatalyst and much needed to enhance the performance of rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, a biphasic nanoarchitecture encased in in situ grown N&#8208;doped graphitic carbon (MnO/Co&#8208;NGC) with heterointerfacial sites are constructed. The density functional theory model reveals formation of lattice oxygen bridged heterostructure with pyridinic nitrogen atoms anchored Co species, which facilitate adsorption of oxygen intermediates. Consequently, the well&#8208;designed catalyst with accessible active sites, abundant oxygen vacant sites, and heterointerfacial coupling effects, simultaneously accelerate the electron/mass transfer and thus promotes the trifunctional electrocatalysis. The assembled aqueous ZAB delivers maximum power density of &#8776;268 mW cm &#8722;2 and a specific capacity of 797.8 mAh g zn &#8722;1 along with excellent rechargeability and extremely small voltage gap decay rate of 0.0007 V h &#8722;1 . Further, the fabricated quasisolid&#8208;state ZAB owns a remarkable power density of 163 mW cm &#8722;2 and long cycle life, outperforming the benchmark air&#8208;electrode and many recent reports, underlining its robustness and suitability for practical utilization in diverse portable applications.</description>
      <author>Srijib Das, Saikat Bolar, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, A. J. Pathak, Ranjit Thapa, Ujjwal Phadikar, Haradhan Kolya, Chun&#8211;Won Kang, Tapas Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Aniruddha Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ electrochemical production of solid peroxide from urine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01277-3</link>
      <description>Xinjian Shi, Yue Jiang, Bailin Zeng, Zhuo-Yue Sun, Maojin Yun, Peng Lv, Yu Jia, Xiaolin Zheng, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406602061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinjian Shi, Yue Jiang, Bailin Zeng, Zhuo-Yue Sun, Maojin Yun, Peng Lv, Yu Jia, Xiaolin Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01277-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Adsorption of Small Molecule Inhibitors and Trimethylaluminum Precursors on the Cu(111) Surface during Area-Selective Atomic Layer Deposition: A GCMC Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04323</link>
      <description>Chen Li, Yichun Li, Jian Weng, Jiafeng Chen, Xiaoyong Cao, Chunlei Wei, Nan Xu, Yi He, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406605724

                In area-selective atomic layer deposition (AS-ALD), small molecule inhibitors (SMIs) play a critical role in directing surface selectivity, preventing unwanted deposition on non-growth surfaces, and enabling precise thin-film formation essential for semiconductor and advanced manufacturing processes. This study utilizes grand canonical Monte Carlo (GCMC) simulations to investigate the competitive adsorption characteristics of three SMIs&#9472;aniline, 3-hexyne, and propanethiol (PT)&#9472;alongside trimethylaluminum (TMA) precursors on a Cu(111) surface. Single-component adsorption analyses reveal that aniline attains the highest coverage among the SMIs, attributed to its strong interaction with the Cu surface; however, this coverage decreases by approximately 42% in the presence of TMA, underscoring its susceptibility to competitive adsorption effects. By contrast, 3-hexyne displays minimal alteration in adsorption when it is in competition with TMA, effectively inhibiting TMA adsorption and indicating its suitability as a robust SMI for AS-ALD. PT also demonstrates moderate inhibitory capability against TMA, although it is less effective than 3-hexyne in this regard. These findings highlight the importance of intermolecular forces and adsorption energies in determining SMI effectiveness in blocking TMA on non-growth surfaces. Mechanistic insights from this study reveal the nuanced influence of specific SMI&#8211;precursor interactions, emphasizing the necessity of selecting SMIs tailored to precursor characteristics and surface interactions. This work provides essential contributions to the rational design of SMIs in AS-ALD, with implications for improving deposition precision and optimizing AS-ALD parameters in nanomanufacturing applications.</description>
      <author>Chen Li, Yichun Li, Jian Weng, Jiafeng Chen, Xiaoyong Cao, Chunlei Wei, Nan Xu, Yi He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient chromium-based transition metal nitrides catalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115385</link>
      <description>Muhammad Faizan, Humaira A. Bibi, Erum Aamir, Roheen Saeed, Sieh Kiong Tiong, Hua Song, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 212(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406605754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Faizan, Humaira A. Bibi, Erum Aamir, Roheen Saeed, Sieh Kiong Tiong, Hua Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De novo-design of highly exposed Co&#8722;N&#8722;C single-atom catalyst for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5813(24)60481-0</link>
      <description>Dan Zhou, Haolin Zhu, Yang Zhao, Yiming Liu, Journal of Fuel Chemistry and Technology. 53(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406608127

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Zhou, Haolin Zhu, Yang Zhao, Yiming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5813(24)60481-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of palladium core size on the activity and durability of Pt-Monolayer electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162477</link>
      <description>Jiye Choi, Eunjik Lee, Seung-min Woo, Youngjoo Whang, Yongmin Kwon, Min Ho Seo, Eunae Cho, Gu&#8208;Gon Park, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615391

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiye Choi, Eunjik Lee, Seung-min Woo, Youngjoo Whang, Yongmin Kwon, Min Ho Seo, Eunae Cho, Gu&#8208;Gon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;Layered Double Hydroxide Heterostructures as Efficient Alkaline Water Splitting (Photo)Electro&#8208;catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409097</link>
      <description>Kayvan Moradi, Maysam Ashrafi, Abdollah Salimi, Marko Melander, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406617906

                Abstract Designing cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts with fast reaction kinetics and high stability is an outstanding challenge in green hydrogen generation through overall water splitting (OWS). Layered double hydroxide (LDH) heterostructure materials are promising candidates to catalyze both oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the two OWS half&#8208;cell reactions. This work develops a facile hydrothermal route to synthesiz hierarchical heterostructure MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;LDH and MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH electrocatalysts, which exhibit extremely good OER and HER performance as witnessed by their low IR&#8208;corrected overpotentials of 156 and 61 mV with at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 under light assistance. The MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH&#8208;MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;LDH OWS cell achieves a low cell voltage of 1.46V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 during light&#8208;assisted water electrolysis. Both materials exhibited exceptional stability under industrially relevant HER and OER conditions, maintaining a current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 with minimal alterations in their potential and performance. The experimental and computational results demonstrate that doping the LDH matrix with high&#8208;valence Mo atoms and MoS 2 quantum dots improves the electrocatalytic activity by 1) enhancing electron transfer, 2) making the electrocatalyst metallic, 3) increasing the number of active sites, 4) lowering the thermodynamic overpotential, and 5) changing the OER mechanism. Overall, this work develops a facile synthesis method to design highly active and stable MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH heterostructure electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Kayvan Moradi, Maysam Ashrafi, Abdollah Salimi, Marko Melander</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-tunable cobalt borides with amorphous shell toward highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236255</link>
      <description>Yuxin Gao, Xiaowei Yang, Yuyang Zong, Lihong Bao, Ruguang Ma, Jijun Zhao, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406618795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Gao, Xiaowei Yang, Yuyang Zong, Lihong Bao, Ruguang Ma, Jijun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of In2+ doping in MoS2 nanosheets for rapid hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118032</link>
      <description>Sanjay A. Bhakhar, G. K. Solanki, Shweta D. Dabhi, Trupti K. Gajaria, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh, Materials Science and Engineering B. 314(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406629707

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sanjay A. Bhakhar, G. K. Solanki, Shweta D. Dabhi, Trupti K. Gajaria, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Nitrogen and Phosphorus Doping of Reduced Graphene Oxide in the Hydrogen Evolution Catalytic Activity of Supported Ru Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15547</link>
      <description>Laura Mall&#243;n, Javier Navarro&#8208;Ruiz, Christian Cerezo-Navarrete, Nuria Romero, Iker Del Rosal, Jordi Garc&#237;a&#8208;Ant&#243;n, Roger Bofill, Luis M. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Prieto, Karine Philippot, Romuald Poteau, Xavier Sala, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406632336

                Three different cathodic materials for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) consisting of Ru nanoparticles (NPs) supported onto a bare and two doped reduced graphene oxides (r-GO) have been studied. Ru NPs have been synthesized in situ by means of the organometallic approach in the presence of each reduced graphene support (bare (rGO), N-doped (NH2-rGO) and P-doped (P-rGO)). (HR)TEM, EDX, EA, ICP-OES, XPS, Raman and NMR techniques have been used to fully characterize the obtained rGO-supported Ru materials. These materials have been deposited onto a glassy carbon rotating disk electrode (GC-RDE) to assess their HER electrocatalytic activity at acidic pH. The results show that all three materials are stable under reductive conditions for at least 12 h, and that the heteroatom-doping of the graphene structure extremely increases the activity of the electrodes, especially for the case of Ru@P-rGO, where the overpotential at &#8722;10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 decreases to only 2 mV. Realistic (based on experimental compositional data) modeling of the three rGO supports combined with DFT computational analysis of the electronic and electrocatalytic properties of the hybrid nanocatalysts allows attributing the observed electrocatalytic performances to a combination of interrelated factors such as the distance of the Ru atoms to the dopped rGO support and the hydride content at the Ru NP surface.</description>
      <author>Laura Mall&#243;n, Javier Navarro&#8208;Ruiz, Christian Cerezo-Navarrete, Nuria Romero, Iker Del Rosal, Jordi Garc&#237;a&#8208;Ant&#243;n, Roger Bofill, Luis M. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Prieto, Karine Philippot, Romuald Poteau, Xavier Sala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrostatic and Electronic Effects on Doped Nickel Oxide Nanofilms for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14493</link>
      <description>Ina &#216;str&#248;m, Marco Favaro, Moein Seyfouri, Patrick A. Burr, Bram Hoex, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406632531

                An ideal water-splitting electrocatalyst is inexpensive, abundant, highly active, stable, selective, and durable. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the main bottleneck for H2 production with a complex and not fully resolved mechanism, slow kinetics, and high overpotential. Nickel oxide-based catalysts (NiOx) are highly active and cheaper than precious metal catalysts. However, rigorous catalyst tests and DFT calculations are still needed to rationally optimize NiOx catalysts. In this work, we combine plasma-enhanced atomic layer deposition (PE-ALD) and density functional theory (DFT) to address the role of dopants in promoting NiOx OER activity. Ultrathin films of NiOx doped with Zn2+, Al3+, and Sn4+ presented improved intrinsic activity, stability, and durability for the OER. The results show a low to high catalytic performance of ZnNiOx &lt; NiOx &lt; AlNiOx &lt; SnNiOx, which we attribute to an increase in the concentration of valence band (VB) holes combined with conduction band (CB) electron conductivity, characterized by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The influence of doping on the electronic structure and catalytic activity was investigated using advanced characterization techniques and density functional theory (DFT) calculations (PEB0/pob-TZVP). DFT complements the experimental results, showing that the dopant charge states and orbital hybridization enhance the OER by improving the charge carrier concentration and mobility, thus allowing optimal binding energies and charge dynamics and delocalization. Our findings demonstrate the potential of PE-ALD-doped nanofilms NiOx and DFT to rationally design and develop catalysts for sustainable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Ina &#216;str&#248;m, Marco Favaro, Moein Seyfouri, Patrick A. Burr, Bram Hoex</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The InP(100) Surface Phase Diagram: From the Gas Phase to the Electrochemical Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20370</link>
      <description>Holger Euchner, Vibhav Yadav, Matthias M. May, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406636092

                The versatile optoelectronic properties of the material class of III&#8211;V semiconductors enable the highest performance in photovoltaic and photoelectrochemical solar cells. While a high level of control and understanding with respect to different surface reconstructions of these compounds in gas-phase ambient has been reached, the situation in an electrochemical environment still poses challenges. Here, we therefore have undertaken a computational study of the InP(100) surface in the presence of hydrogen and chlorine, mimicking the contact with a hydrochloric acid-containing electrolyte, aiming at an understanding of ion adsorption and dominant surface reconstructions with respect to applied potential and electrolyte concentration. For this purpose, the most stable surface terminations for hydrogen and chlorine (co)adsorption from the gas phase as well as the corresponding phase diagrams have been determined with respect to the hydrogen and chlorine chemical potential. In this context, we also introduce a quantitative type of phase diagram to highlight the stability of surface phases with respect to competing structures. Finally, by making use of the computational hydrogen electrode approach, these results were then transferred to the potential domain. We find that hydrogen (chlorine) adsorption is dominating at more (less) cathodic potentials, while coadsorption is limited to small fractions of the phase space. This allows us to determine experimentally accessible phases for which no detrimental effects, such as the creation of in-gap surface states, are to be expected.</description>
      <author>Holger Euchner, Vibhav Yadav, Matthias M. May</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20370</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All-round enhancement induced by oxophilic single Ru and W atoms for alkaline hydrogen oxidation of tiny Pt nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56240-y</link>
      <description>Wensheng Jiao, Zhanghao Ren, Zhibo Cui, Chao Ma, Ziang Shang, Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Tao Gan, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406639376

                Anion exchange membrane fuel cells (AEMFCs) are one of the ideal energy conversion devices. However, platinum (Pt), as the benchmark catalyst for the hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) of AEMFCs anodes, still faces issues of insufficient performance and susceptibility to CO poisoning. Here, we report the Joule heating-assisted synthesis of a small sized Ru1Pt single-atom alloy catalyst loaded on nitrogen-doped carbon modified with single W atoms (s-Ru1Pt@W1/NC), in which the near-range single Ru atoms on the Ru1Pt nanoparticles and the long-range single W atoms on the support simultaneously modulate the electronic structure of the active Pt-site, enhancing alkaline HOR performance of s-Ru1Pt@W1/NC. The mass activity of s-Ru1Pt@W1/NC is 7.54 A mgPt+Ru-1 and exhibits notable stability in 1000 ppm CO/H2-saturated electrolyte. Surprisingly, it can operate stably in H2-saturated electrolyte for 1000 h with only 24.60 % decay. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that the proximal single Ru atoms and the remote single W atoms synergistically optimize the electronic structure of the active Pt-site, improving the HOR activity and CO tolerance of the catalyst. The development of anode catalysts for anion-exchange membrane fuel cells is promising but challenging in practical applications. Here, the authors report the tiny single-atom alloy nanoparticles that catalyze hydrogen oxidation reaction with very high activity, stability, and CO resistance.</description>
      <author>Wensheng Jiao, Zhanghao Ren, Zhibo Cui, Chao Ma, Ziang Shang, Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Tao Gan, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56240-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Mechanism on Pristine and Defective Nickel Phosphate Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsurfi.2025.100431</link>
      <description>Dyah Puspasari Wijayanti, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Damar Rastri Adhika, Hamad AlMohamadi, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Results in Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406642017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dyah Puspasari Wijayanti, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Damar Rastri Adhika, Hamad AlMohamadi, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsurfi.2025.100431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Screening of Efficient TM/GaN Single-Atom Catalysts for Electroreduction of Nitrate to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06861</link>
      <description>Huifang Ma, Saifei Yuan, Shujuan Li, Jiayao Wang, Huiyun Zhang, Yuping Zhang, Jingxiu Yang, Jinbo Sun, Ke Xu, Shulai Lei, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406681579

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huifang Ma, Saifei Yuan, Shujuan Li, Jiayao Wang, Huiyun Zhang, Yuping Zhang, Jingxiu Yang, Jinbo Sun, Ke Xu, Shulai Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual active site and metal&#8211;substrate interface effect endow platinum&#8211;ruthenium/molybdenum carbide efficient pH-universal hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.180</link>
      <description>H. Ling, Qiang Yuan, Tian Sheng, Xun Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406683610

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Ling, Qiang Yuan, Tian Sheng, Xun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive review of two-dimensional high-entropy layered hydroxides: Synthesis, characterization, and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216435</link>
      <description>Abdul Hai, Muhammad Daud, Ghulam Mujtaba, Fawzi Banat, Mamdouh A. Al&#8208;Harthi, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 529(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406684537

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Hai, Muhammad Daud, Ghulam Mujtaba, Fawzi Banat, Mamdouh A. Al&#8208;Harthi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Changes in Metal Chalcogenide Nanoclusters Associated with Single Heteroatom Incorporation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c07000</link>
      <description>Xi-Lai Li, Shana Havenridge, Habib Gholipour&#8208;Ranjbar, Dylan Forbes, W. O. Crain, Cong Liu, Julia Laskin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406690302

                Atomically precise nanoclusters (NCs) are promising building blocks for designing materials and interfaces with unique properties. By incorporating heteroatoms into the core, the electronic and magnetic properties of NCs can be precisely tuned. To accurately predict these properties, density functional theory (DFT) is often employed, making the rigorous benchmarking of DFT results particularly important. In this study, we present a benchmarking approach based on metal chalcogenide NCs as a model system. We synthesized a series of bimetallic, iron&#8211;cobalt chalcogenide NCs [Co6&#8211;xFexS8(PEt3)6]+ (x = 0&#8211;6) (PEt = triethyl phosphine) and investigated the effect of heteroatoms in the octahedral metal chalcogenide core on their size and electronic properties. Using ion mobility-mass spectrometry (IM-MS), we observed a gradual increase in the collision cross section (CCS) with an increase in the number of Fe atoms in the core. DFT calculations combined with trajectory method CCS simulations successfully reproduced this trend, revealing that the increase in cluster size is primarily due to changes in metal&#8211;ligand bond lengths, while the electronic properties of the core remain largely unchanged. Moreover, this method allowed us to exclude certain multiplicity states of the NCs, as their CCS values were significantly different from those predicted for the lowest-energy structures. This study demonstrates that gas-phase IM-MS is a powerful technique for detecting subtle size differences in atomically precise NCs, which are often challenging to observe using conventional NC characterization methods. Accurate CCS measurements are established as a benchmark for comparison with theoretical calculations. The excellent correspondence between experimental data and theoretical predictions establishes a robust foundation for investigating structural changes of transition metal NCs of interest to a broad range of applications.</description>
      <author>Xi-Lai Li, Shana Havenridge, Habib Gholipour&#8208;Ranjbar, Dylan Forbes, W. O. Crain, Cong Liu, Julia Laskin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c07000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unifying the Description of Hydrocarbons and Hydrogenated Carbon Materials with a Chemically Reactive Machine Learning Interatomic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02905</link>
      <description>Rina Ibragimova, Mikhail S. Kuklin, Tigany Zarrouk, A. Miguel, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406690375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rina Ibragimova, Mikhail S. Kuklin, Tigany Zarrouk, A. Miguel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating CALPHAD-based phase diagram predictions in complex alloys using universal machine learning potentials: Opportunities and challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.120747</link>
      <description>Siya Zhu, Do&#287;uhan Sar&#305;t&#252;rk, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406693067

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siya Zhu, Do&#287;uhan Sar&#305;t&#252;rk, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.120747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling electrochemical nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101239</link>
      <description>&#193;rni Bj&#246;rn H&#246;skuldsson, Yasufumi Sakai, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406694788

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#193;rni Bj&#246;rn H&#246;skuldsson, Yasufumi Sakai, Egill Sk&#250;lason</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of two-dimensional conductive MOFs as OER catalysts assisted by machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10612-3</link>
      <description>Yuyang Liu, Jianping Sun, Yuxin Chai, Yu Yang, Zhi Yang, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406696510

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuyang Liu, Jianping Sun, Yuxin Chai, Yu Yang, Zhi Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10612-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re3(C6O6)2 monolayer: a promising metal&#8211;organic framework-based electro-catalyst for N2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-025-02449-y</link>
      <description>Honglan Li, Lei Yang, Xinglin Yang, Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406703810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Honglan Li, Lei Yang, Xinglin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-025-02449-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into Methanol Electro-Oxidation on NiPd Nanoelectrocatalysts: Investigating the Carbonate&#8211;Palladium Oxide Pathway and the Role of Water and OH Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15020101</link>
      <description>Alan Santove&#241;a-Uribe, Aldo Ledesma&#8211;Dur&#225;n, Julisa Torres-Enriquez, I. Santamar&#305;&#769;a-Holek, Catalysts. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406704738

                We conducted a theoretical and experimental study on the electro-oxidation of methanol (MOR) on NixPdy nanoparticles. The results are presented in terms of kinetic parameters, surface concentrations, and peak currents, showing significant differences between three main compositions: Ni3Pd1, Ni1Pd1, and Ni1Pd3. The kinetic mechanism adopted for accounting the linear voltammetry experiments performed follows the carbonate&#8211;palladium oxide pathway of the MOR. Numerical simulations of the kinetic equations, fitted to experimental data obtained at varying methanol concentrations, allowed us to distinguish the adsorption contributions of methanol, water, and OH ions from the nonlinear contribution associated with palladium oxide and carbon dioxide production. The synergistic effects of Ni:Pd nanoalloys on the MOR were then assessed by analyzing the behavior and tendencies of the reaction rate constants for different bulk methanol concentrations. Our results suggest that a higher Pd content favors more efficient oxidation mechanisms by reducing the formation of intermediate products that cause surface poisoning, such as CO, carbonates, or palladium oxide. However, as the proportion of Ni increases, an increase in the concentration of adsorbed OH is observed, which dominates the blocking of active sites even greater than the palladium oxide blocking.</description>
      <author>Alan Santove&#241;a-Uribe, Aldo Ledesma&#8211;Dur&#225;n, Julisa Torres-Enriquez, I. Santamar&#305;&#769;a-Holek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15020101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed atomistic&#8211;implicit quantum/classical approach to molecular nanoplasmonics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245629</link>
      <description>Pablo Grobas Illobre, Piero Lafiosca, Luca Bonatti, Tommaso Giovannini, Chiara Cappelli, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706023

                A multiscale quantum mechanical (QM)/classical approach is presented that is able to model the optical properties of complex nanostructures composed of a molecular system adsorbed on metal nanoparticles. The latter is described by a combined atomistic&#8211;continuum model, where the core is described using the implicit boundary element method (BEM) and the surface retains a fully atomistic picture and is treated employing the frequency-dependent fluctuating charge and fluctuating dipole (&#969;FQF&#956;) approach. The integrated QM/&#969;FQF&#956;-BEM model is numerically compared with state-of-the-art fully atomistic approaches, and the quality of the continuum/core partition is evaluated. The method is then extended to compute surface-enhanced Raman scattering within a time-dependent density functional theory framework.</description>
      <author>Pablo Grobas Illobre, Piero Lafiosca, Luca Bonatti, Tommaso Giovannini, Chiara Cappelli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confining Surface Oxygen Redox in Double Perovskites for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404560</link>
      <description>Natasha Hales, Jinzhen Huang, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Ivano E. Castelli, Radim Skoup&#253;, Adam H. Clark, Micha&#322; Andrzejewski, Nicola Casati, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706492

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;based double perovskites AA&#8242;BB&#8242;O 6 are an underexplored class of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, in which B&#8208;site substitution is used to tune electronic and structural properties. BaSrNiWO 6 , with a B&#8208;site comprised of alternating Ni and W, exhibits high oxygen evolution activity, attributed to the evolution of a highly OER active surface phase. The redox transformation of Ni 2+ (3d 8 ) to Ni 3+ (3d 7 ) combined with partial W dissolution into the electrolyte from the linear Ni(3d)&#8208;O(2p)&#8208;W(5d) chains drives an in situ reconstruction of the surface to an amorphized, NiO&#8208;like layer, promoting oxygen redox in the OER mechanism. However, the high valence W 6+ (5d 0 ) acts as a stabilizing electronic influence in the bulk, preventing the mobilization of lattice oxygen which is bound in highly covalent W&#9472;O bonds. It is proposed that the surface generated during the OER can support a lattice oxygen evolution mechanism (LOEM) in which oxygen vacancies are created and preferentially refilled by electrolytic OH &#8722; , while bulk O species remain stable. This surface LOEM (sLOEM) allows BaSrNiWO 6 to retain structural integrity during OER catalysis. With a Tafel slope of 45 mV dec &#8722;1 in 0.1 m KOH, BaSrNiWO 6 illustrates the potential of Ni&#8208;based double perovskites to offer both OER efficiency and bulk stability in alkaline electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Natasha Hales, Jinzhen Huang, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Ivano E. Castelli, Radim Skoup&#253;, Adam H. Clark, Micha&#322; Andrzejewski, Nicola Casati, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid fabrication of phase-separated Cu-Zn particles though &#8220;droplet-to-particle&#8221; method and their performance in CO2 electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134360</link>
      <description>Kejie Zhang, Weijian Hua, Renhui Ruan, Baochong Cui, Mingxing Su, Xuebin Wang, Houzhang Tan, Fuel. 388(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406712294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kejie Zhang, Weijian Hua, Renhui Ruan, Baochong Cui, Mingxing Su, Xuebin Wang, Houzhang Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening corrosion-resistant genetic elements of Sn-0.7Cu solders by high-throughput calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2025.112726</link>
      <description>Ancang Yang, Jiale Wu, Bin Zhang, Yonghua Duan, Lishi Ma, Mingjun Peng, Shanju Zheng, Linfen Su, Mengnie Li, Corrosion Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406715355

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ancang Yang, Jiale Wu, Bin Zhang, Yonghua Duan, Lishi Ma, Mingjun Peng, Shanju Zheng, Linfen Su, Mengnie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2025.112726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3d transition metal anchored boron nitride edge for CO2 reduction reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112616</link>
      <description>Wenlong Guo, Haiyue Liao, Wenhong Zeng, Xinlin Tang, Xin Lian, Peng Xiao, Guangyong Gao, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406719852

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenlong Guo, Haiyue Liao, Wenhong Zeng, Xinlin Tang, Xin Lian, Peng Xiao, Guangyong Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ternary nanostructured materials: Properties and their applications as oxygen reduction catalysts in fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114861</link>
      <description>Fereshteh Dehghani Sanij, Narayanamoorthy Bhuvanendran, A.A. Shah, Huaneng Su, Qian Xu, Molecular Catalysis. 574(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406722385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fereshteh Dehghani Sanij, Narayanamoorthy Bhuvanendran, A.A. Shah, Huaneng Su, Qian Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degree of span control to determine the impact of different mechanisms and limiting steps: Oxygen evolution reaction over Co3O4(001) as a case study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115970</link>
      <description>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406732898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Formation of High Entropy Solid Solutions and High Entropy Intermetallics by In Situ X-ray Diffraction and Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02470</link>
      <description>Nicolas Schlegel, Stefanie Punke, Christian M. Clausen, Ulrik Friis-Jensen, Adam F. Sapnik, Dragos Stoian, Olivia Aalling&#8208;Frederiksen, Divyansh Gautam, Jan Rossmeisl, Rebecca K. Pittkowski, Matthias Arenz, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406738489

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicolas Schlegel, Stefanie Punke, Christian M. Clausen, Ulrik Friis-Jensen, Adam F. Sapnik, Dragos Stoian, Olivia Aalling&#8208;Frederiksen, Divyansh Gautam, Jan Rossmeisl, Rebecca K. Pittkowski, Matthias Arenz, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study of oxygen reduction reaction activity and stability on Mn-Ni dual-atom electrocatalysts anchored at graphene edges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162495</link>
      <description>Faizal Helmi, Muhammad Hakim, Ahmad Nuruddin, Nadya Amalia, Sasfan Arman Wella, Hamad AlMohamadi, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faizal Helmi, Muhammad Hakim, Ahmad Nuruddin, Nadya Amalia, Sasfan Arman Wella, Hamad AlMohamadi, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GC-DFT simulation of coverage and potential effect for oxygen evolution reaction on RuO2-based electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</link>
      <description>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon Hybridization in Rotation Bimetallic-Chain System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07988</link>
      <description>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yongqi Chen, Yurui Fang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406743596

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yongqi Chen, Yurui Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress of porous covalent organic frameworks membranes for gas- and liquid-phase separation towards environmental chemical engineering applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115487</link>
      <description>Xiaojian Yang, Wenxuan Li, Shenglin Wang, Honglei Shuai, Han Zhang, Xinsheng Zhao, Yanan Gao, Hui L&#252;, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406560945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojian Yang, Wenxuan Li, Shenglin Wang, Honglei Shuai, Han Zhang, Xinsheng Zhao, Yanan Gao, Hui L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.115487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for metal additive manufacturing process optimization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-22145-3.00006-2</link>
      <description>Harpreet Kaur Channi, Raman Kumar, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406568255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harpreet Kaur Channi, Raman Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-22145-3.00006-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alchemical harmonic approximation based potential for iso-electronic diatomics: Foundational baseline for &#916;-machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241872</link>
      <description>Simon Le&#243;n Krug, Danish Khan, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706160

                We introduce the alchemical harmonic approximation (AHA) of the absolute electronic energy for charge-neutral iso-electronic diatomics at fixed interatomic distance d0. To account for variations in distance, we combine AHA with this ansatz for the electronic binding potential, E(d)=(Eu&#8722;Es)Ec&#8722;EsEu&#8722;Esd/d0+Es, where Eu, Ec, Es correspond to the energies of the united atom, calibration at d0, and the sum of infinitely separated atoms, respectively. Our model covers the two-dimensional electronic potential energy surface spanned by distances of 0.7&#8211;2.5 &#197; and differences in nuclear charge from which only one single point (with elements of nuclear charge Z1, Z2, and distance d0) is drawn to calibrate Ec. Using reference data from pbe0/cc-pVDZ, we present numerical evidence for the electronic ground-state of all neutral diatomics with 8, 10, 12, and 14 electrons. We assess the validity of our model by comparison to legacy interatomic potentials (harmonic oscillator, Lennard-Jones, and Morse) within the most relevant range of binding (0.7&#8211;2.5 &#197;) and find comparable accuracy if restricted to single diatomics and significantly better predictive power when extrapolating to the entire iso-electronic series. We also investigated &#916;-learning of the electronic absolute energy using our model as a baseline. This baseline model results in a systematic improvement, effectively reducing training data needed for reaching chemical accuracy by up to an order of magnitude from &#8764;1000 to &#8764;100. By contrast, using AHA+Morse as a baseline hardly leads to any improvement and sometimes even deteriorates the predictive power. Inferring the energy of unseen CO converges to a prediction error of &#8764;0.1 Ha in direct learning and &#8764;0.04 Ha with our baseline.</description>
      <author>Simon Le&#243;n Krug, Danish Khan, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the fourth paradigm of modeling in chemical engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-024-00170-x</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird, Nature Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706802

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-024-00170-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficacy of biochar as a catalyst for a Fenton-like reaction: Experimental, statistical and mathematical modeling analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2025.107014</link>
      <description>Oscar M. Rodr&#237;guez-Narv&#225;ez, Bhuman Pandita, Omesh Goyal, Srinivas Rallapalli, Mahinda I. Ranasinghe, Alain S. Conejo-D&#225;vila, Erick R. Bandala, Ashantha Goonetilleke, Journal of Water Process Engineering. 70(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406561020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oscar M. Rodr&#237;guez-Narv&#225;ez, Bhuman Pandita, Omesh Goyal, Srinivas Rallapalli, Mahinda I. Ranasinghe, Alain S. Conejo-D&#225;vila, Erick R. Bandala, Ashantha Goonetilleke</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2025.107014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Optoelectronic Properties of SrVO3 via Strain and Transition-Metal Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-025-11735-8</link>
      <description>P. V. Manivannan, Sudatta Giri, Debolina Misra, Journal of Electronic Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406610752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P. V. Manivannan, Sudatta Giri, Debolina Misra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-025-11735-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orbital Resolution of the Reconstruction of CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (100) Facet&#8211;Hybrid-DFT and COHP Investigations Supported by HR-TEM Imaging</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06854</link>
      <description>Leszek Nowakowski, Filip Zasada, Joanna Grybo&#347;, Zbigniew Sojka, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406676582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leszek Nowakowski, Filip Zasada, Joanna Grybo&#347;, Zbigniew Sojka</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development and Thermo-Mechanical Testing of Low Hysteresis Shape Memory Alloy for Satellite Actuators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12794/metadc2048636</link>
      <description>Andre Montagnoli, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4406530876

                Shape memory alloys (SMAs) have gained much attention as a powerful source of actuation due to their improved performance, reduced size, and reduced complexity between components as well as having a high work output density. Their primary mechanism of actuation relies on a non-diffusional cyclic phase transformation from martensite to austenite, where the amount of thermal energy needed per cycle is directly associated with the hysteresis width between the austenite final and martensite final temperatures. Consequently, a narrower gap between those two temperature ranges requires a much lower energy demand to produce the actuation needed. Previous studies have indicated that the hysteresis width is linked to a strong coherence between the austenite/martensite interface. It has been shown that elemental additions to NiTi-based SMAs can further improve this coherency. Another huge challenge facing this unique technology is linked with its thermo-mechanical stability. Binary NiTi SMAs often exhibit significant transformation temperature shifts after each thermo-mechanical cycle, which can contribute to a shorter lifespan. The primary goal of this project is to identify and develop thermo-mechanically stable, low hysteresis shape memory alloys (LHSMAs) for actuator applications. To accomplish this goal, elemental additions of Cu, Co, Hf, and Pd were incorporated into NiTi-based SMAs and the results were compared in respect to their hysteresis width and thermo-mechanical stability through differential scanning calorimetry, scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive spectroscopy, and compressive thermo-mechanical testing. Two quaternary SMAs containing small additions of Cu and Pd were shown to exhibit promising results with respect to hysteresis width and good thermo-mechanical stability.</description>
      <author>Andre Montagnoli</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12794/metadc2048636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIOSYNTHESIS OF &#946;-LACTAM ANTIBIOTICS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-08-022092-5.50012-8</link>
      <description>D. John Aberhart, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 1978. https://openalex.org/W4406680887

                No abstract</description>
      <author>D. John Aberhart</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1978 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-08-022092-5.50012-8</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
