<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 01:51:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A General Machine-Learning Framework for High-Throughput Screening for Stable and Efficient RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02247</link>
      <description>Zhe Shang, Susu Zhao, Qian Dang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412403632

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhe Shang, Susu Zhao, Qian Dang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in thermocatalytic acetylene selective hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs01237b</link>
      <description>Xiaocheng Lan, Kuan Chang, Tiefeng Wang, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412418605

                This review highlights recent advances in acetylene selective hydrogenation, focusing on active site engineering, support/modifier effects, reaction media, and future directions for achieving high performance and industrial relevance.</description>
      <author>Xiaocheng Lan, Kuan Chang, Tiefeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs01237b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M-N-C-based non-precious metal catalyst materials for electrocatalytic ORR applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136163</link>
      <description>Shambhulinga Aralekallu, Vijay Singh, Fuel. 404(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412419968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shambhulinga Aralekallu, Vijay Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-induced electronic modulation in Mn2@g-C3N4 catalysts for enhanced nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136260</link>
      <description>H.P. Wang, Cheng Liu, Youyong Li, Fuel. 404(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412420146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H.P. Wang, Cheng Liu, Youyong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT+U calculations on substitutionally doped (Ni, Cu, Zn) Mg-vanadate surfaces for the oxidative dehydrogenation of alkanes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116313</link>
      <description>Hansel Montalvo-Castro, Siby Thomas, Randall J. Meyer, David Hibbitts, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412421019

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hansel Montalvo-Castro, Siby Thomas, Randall J. Meyer, David Hibbitts</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic insights into chloride-induced depassivation mechanisms of protective Cu2O films in marine environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2025.113171</link>
      <description>Ao Chen, Ying Wang, Jiawei Le, Kai Xu, Yongbo Kuang, Keke Chang, Corrosion Science. 256(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412421881

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ao Chen, Ying Wang, Jiawei Le, Kai Xu, Yongbo Kuang, Keke Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2025.113171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Stability, Mechanistic Evaluation, and Electronic Properties of Polyoxoniobate-Based SACs (TM@PONb): A Promising Multifunctional Electrocatalyst for HER/OER/ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02057</link>
      <description>Faheem Abbas, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Sharmarke Mohamed, Yongge Wei, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412422395

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faheem Abbas, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Sharmarke Mohamed, Yongge Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing Iridium Over-Oxidation Via Catalyst&#8211;Support Interactions on Tungsten Oxide Nanowires Revealed by In-Situ Xps for Durable, Low-Loaded Pem Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5352647</link>
      <description>Lu&#8208;Yu Chueh, Yu&#8208;Chien Chien, Yu-Wei Hsu, Zun-Wei Wang, Ding&#8208;Huei Tsai, Chang-Ming Wu, Shao&#8208;Chu Huang, Hsiang-Jung Chen, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Meng&#8208;Hsuan Tsai, Chia&#8208;Hsin Wang, Chueh&#8208;Cheng Yang, Yung&#8208;Tin Pan, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412427364

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu&#8208;Yu Chueh, Yu&#8208;Chien Chien, Yu-Wei Hsu, Zun-Wei Wang, Ding&#8208;Huei Tsai, Chang-Ming Wu, Shao&#8208;Chu Huang, Hsiang-Jung Chen, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Meng&#8208;Hsuan Tsai, Chia&#8208;Hsin Wang, Chueh&#8208;Cheng Yang, Yung&#8208;Tin Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5352647</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale modeling and optimization of proton exchange membrane electrolysis cells: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126451</link>
      <description>Dongqi Zhao, Jisen Li, Ze Zhou, Liyan Zhang, Zheng Li, Qihong Chen, Xi Li, Applied Energy. 398(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412427726

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongqi Zhao, Jisen Li, Ze Zhou, Liyan Zhang, Zheng Li, Qihong Chen, Xi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen reduction reaction catalyzed by C2N nanosheet doped with a phosphorous atom: Insights from DFT calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2025.109125</link>
      <description>Mina Shahdust, Mehdi D. Esrafili, Morteza Vahedpour, Journal of Molecular Graphics and Modelling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412432804

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mina Shahdust, Mehdi D. Esrafili, Morteza Vahedpour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2025.109125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and microkinetic insights into potential-dependent competition between CO2 reduction and HER on Mo2CTx MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165927</link>
      <description>Caihong Liang, Zhonghan Zhang, Zheng Liu, Liang Wang, Yeng Ming Lam, Chemical Engineering Journal. 520(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412433324

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Caihong Liang, Zhonghan Zhang, Zheng Liu, Liang Wang, Yeng Ming Lam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidirectional Photoinduced Electron Transfer between Anatase and Rutile Titanium(IV) Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03078</link>
      <description>Shin&#8208;ichi Naya, Miwako Teranishi, Tetsuro Soejima, Hiroaki Tada, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412434299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shin&#8208;ichi Naya, Miwako Teranishi, Tetsuro Soejima, Hiroaki Tada</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic and catalytic insights into rare earth element-doped &#947;-NiOOH for oxygen evolution and reduction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.003</link>
      <description>Sadaf Bibi, Xiaolei Huang, Yanjie Wang, Yanjie Li, Gui Lu, Xin Xia, Kai Zhang, Cau&#234; Ribeiro, Tao He, Detlef W. Bahnemann, Jia Hong Pan, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412435074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sadaf Bibi, Xiaolei Huang, Yanjie Wang, Yanjie Li, Gui Lu, Xin Xia, Kai Zhang, Cau&#234; Ribeiro, Tao He, Detlef W. Bahnemann, Jia Hong Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insight on interface enhancement mechanism and electrocatalytic water splitting reactions using heteroatoms-mediated graphene/Cu composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113306</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Linxiu Du, Zhihua Yuan, Dong Wang, Peide Han, Zhuxia Zhang, Materials Today Communications. 48(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412435754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Linxiu Du, Zhihua Yuan, Dong Wang, Peide Han, Zhuxia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom Catalysts Based on SiC Monolayer for Efficient Nitrite Electroreduction to Ammonia: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107145</link>
      <description>Alice Hu, Donglin Ma, Jianjun Hu, Yongfan Zhang, Shuping Huang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412436613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alice Hu, Donglin Ma, Jianjun Hu, Yongfan Zhang, Shuping Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of nitrate reduction on CoP (010): Adsorption behavior, reaction mechanism, and selectivity towards ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107181</link>
      <description>Guozheng Zhao, Miao Yu, Chaozheng He, Surfaces and Interfaces. 72(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412436730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guozheng Zhao, Miao Yu, Chaozheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced RuO2-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction: A perspective from coordination structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100110</link>
      <description>Qian Sun, Jilei Zhang, Wei Kong Pang, Bernt Johannessen, Peng Li, Guoqiang Zhao, Huaming Yang, Materials Today Catalysis. 10(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412438260

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Sun, Jilei Zhang, Wei Kong Pang, Bernt Johannessen, Peng Li, Guoqiang Zhao, Huaming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Effect of Ruthenium on Fe-Catalyzed Growth of Small-Diameter Single-Wall Carbon Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10714</link>
      <description>Brian M. Everhart, Haider Almkhelfe, Morgen L. Smith, Tsung-Wei Liu, Diego A. G&#243;mez&#8208;Gualdr&#243;n, Robert Waelder, Rahul Rao, Benji Maruyama, Placidus B. Amama, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412439082

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brian M. Everhart, Haider Almkhelfe, Morgen L. Smith, Tsung-Wei Liu, Diego A. G&#243;mez&#8208;Gualdr&#243;n, Robert Waelder, Rahul Rao, Benji Maruyama, Placidus B. Amama</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen adsorption via the synergistic catalysis of graphitic nitrogen carbon and antiperovskite ZnCNi3 in Zinc- Air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138412</link>
      <description>Jiahui Guo, Huan Liu, Yulong Gao, Xiaopeng Liu, Jie Bai, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412442000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahui Guo, Huan Liu, Yulong Gao, Xiaopeng Liu, Jie Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the activity of CO2 reduction electrocatalysts via modifying metals and ligand of conductive two-dimensional metal&#8212;organic framework ligands: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146920</link>
      <description>Yang Liu, Huohai Yang, Siying Liu, Z CHEN, Xin Chen, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412447743

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Liu, Huohai Yang, Siying Liu, Z CHEN, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146920</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the role of doping and intrinsic vacancies in BiVO4 for enhanced photoelectrochemical water splitting: a first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150384</link>
      <description>Otmane El Ouardi, Hamza Ladib, Brigitte Vigolo, Jones Alami, M. Makha, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 157(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412448019

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Otmane El Ouardi, Hamza Ladib, Brigitte Vigolo, Jones Alami, M. Makha</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spall strength of symmetric tilt grain boundaries in 6H silicon carbide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0277595</link>
      <description>Chunyu Li, Alejandro Strachan, Journal of Applied Physics. 138(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412448371

                Characterizing microstructural effects on the dynamical response of materials is challenging due to the extreme conditions and the short timescales involved. For example, little is known about how grain boundary characteristics affect spall strength. This study explores 6H-SiC bicrystals under shock waves via large-scale molecular dynamics simulations. We focused on symmetric tilt grain boundaries with a wide range of misorientations and found that spall strength and dynamical fracture surface energy are strongly affected by the grain boundary microstructure, especially the excess free volume. Grain boundary energy also plays a considerable role. As expected, low-angle grain boundaries tend to have higher spallation strengths. We also extracted cohesive models for the dynamical strength of bulk systems and grain boundaries that can be used in continuum simulations.</description>
      <author>Chunyu Li, Alejandro Strachan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0277595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy in hydrogen evolution reaction: Insights and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.101061</link>
      <description>Zhenglong Li, Xingyu Ding, Da Liu, Jin Zhou, Yong Gao, Yanxia Liu, Lin Jiang, Renbing Wu, Hongge Pan, Materials Science and Engineering R Reports. 166(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412448704

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenglong Li, Xingyu Ding, Da Liu, Jin Zhou, Yong Gao, Yanxia Liu, Lin Jiang, Renbing Wu, Hongge Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.101061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability enhancement strategy for LOM-based Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107169</link>
      <description>Jianhe Liu, Tao Yang, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Guoyong Huang, Enhui Wang, Kai Wang, Hongyang Wang, Xinmei Hou, Surfaces and Interfaces. 72(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412450153

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianhe Liu, Tao Yang, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Guoyong Huang, Enhui Wang, Kai Wang, Hongyang Wang, Xinmei Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal design principles of self-supporting iron-group (Fe/Co/Ni) electrocatalysts for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150313</link>
      <description>Mingzhe Li, F. Zheng, Jiahui Zheng, Xin Zhang, Yunlong Wang, Xiaofen Wang, Yuzhen Lv, Kepi Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 155(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412452771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingzhe Li, F. Zheng, Jiahui Zheng, Xin Zhang, Yunlong Wang, Xiaofen Wang, Yuzhen Lv, Kepi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of porphyrin-based metal organic frameworks for efficient CO2-to-CO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150353</link>
      <description>Shengshen Gu, Jiacheng Lu, Xiangyu Zhu, Yang Pan, Ting Qi, Danfeng Wang, Jing Zhong, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 156(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412452806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengshen Gu, Jiacheng Lu, Xiangyu Zhu, Yang Pan, Ting Qi, Danfeng Wang, Jing Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium&#8208;Doped Monoclinic Zirconia as a Catalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500769</link>
      <description>M.S. Nissen, Heine Anton Hansen, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412454446

                Abstract New acid&#8208;stable catalysts that reduce reliance on iridium (Ir) for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) could pave the way for efficient energy conversion and storage. Using DFT this work investigates Ir&#8208;dopings of the monoclinic () surface as an Ir&#8208;lean OER catalyst. It is found that these Ir&#8208;doped surfaces are likely to segregate into their constituent oxide phases, and . The OER activity is limited due to under binding of the OER intermediates on pure and overbinding on the Ir&#8208;doped surface, both leading to high overpotentials. Water adsorption on the surface layer stabilizes all surfaces, with a more pronounced stabilization observed for the Ir&#8208;doped systems. This adsorption significantly impacts the activity for the nondoped surface, as leaving a surface site unoccupied creates a high energy state in the band gap, making the surface highly reactive. A similar situation is found for an Ir&#8208;doped surface, contrasted by the formation of lower energy states.</description>
      <author>M.S. Nissen, Heine Anton Hansen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the Oxygen Reduction Reaction Selectivity of Single-Atom Catalysts on N-Doped Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146904</link>
      <description>Tahereh Jangjooye Shaldehi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412457940

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tahereh Jangjooye Shaldehi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146904</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical explorations of hydrogen evolution reaction mechanisms in transition metal-doped intermetallic compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44422-025-00003-9</link>
      <description>Jun-long Kou, Mingzi Sun, Haitao Yu, Xiao Wu, Zhiguo Xing, Suzhe Liang, Bolong Huang, No host. 1(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412461118

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun-long Kou, Mingzi Sun, Haitao Yu, Xiao Wu, Zhiguo Xing, Suzhe Liang, Bolong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44422-025-00003-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of trimetallic dual-atom alloy catalysts for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.015</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Wang, Chunmei Tang, Ting Xiao, Feng Xiong, Xiaofeng Zhou, Kaixiao Zhang, Jiangfeng Gong, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412464547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Wang, Chunmei Tang, Ting Xiao, Feng Xiong, Xiaofeng Zhou, Kaixiao Zhang, Jiangfeng Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interplay between alkaline water oxidation temperature, composition and performance of electrospun high-entropy non-equimolar (Cr,Mn,Fe,Co,Ni) oxide electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237887</link>
      <description>Claudia Triolo, Kaveh Moulaee, Fulvio Bellato, Gioele Pagot, Alessandro Ponti, Susan Maida, Nicola Pinna, G. Neri, Vito Di Noto, S. Santangelo, Journal of Power Sources. 654(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412467626

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Claudia Triolo, Kaveh Moulaee, Fulvio Bellato, Gioele Pagot, Alessandro Ponti, Susan Maida, Nicola Pinna, G. Neri, Vito Di Noto, S. Santangelo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical study of novel Rh2P2 and their analogs for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.113022</link>
      <description>Chenglin Li, Yinchang Zhao, Zhenhong Dai, Junru Wang, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412468213

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenglin Li, Yinchang Zhao, Zhenhong Dai, Junru Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.113022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling the catalytic and degradation mechanisms of cobalt active sites during acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01812-x</link>
      <description>Darcy Simondson, Marc F. Tesch, Ioannis Spanos, Travis E. Jones, Jining Guo, Brittany V. Kerr, Manjunath Chatti, Shannon A. Bonke, Ronny Golnak, Bernt Johannessen, Jie Xiao, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Rosalie K. Hocking, Alexandr N. Simonov, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412470602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Darcy Simondson, Marc F. Tesch, Ioannis Spanos, Travis E. Jones, Jining Guo, Brittany V. Kerr, Manjunath Chatti, Shannon A. Bonke, Ronny Golnak, Bernt Johannessen, Jie Xiao, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Rosalie K. Hocking, Alexandr N. Simonov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01812-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implicit neural representations for chemical reaction paths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0267023</link>
      <description>Kalyan Ramakrishnan, Lars L. Schaaf, Chen Lin, Guangrun Wang, Philip H. S. Torr, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412472088

                We show that neural networks can be optimized to represent minimum energy paths as continuous functions, offering a flexible alternative to discrete path-search methods such as Nudged Elastic Band (NEB). Our approach parameterizes reaction paths with a network trained on a loss function that discards tangential energy gradients and enables instant estimation of the transition state. We first validate the method on two-dimensional potentials and then demonstrate its advantages over NEB on challenging atomistic systems where (i) poor initial guesses yield unphysical paths, (ii) multiple competing paths exist, or (iii) the reaction follows a complex multi-step mechanism. Results highlight the versatility of the method: for instance, a simple adjustment to the sampling strategy during optimization can help escape local-minimum solutions. Finally, in a low-dimensional setting, we demonstrate that a single neural network can learn from existing paths and generalize to unseen systems, showing promise for a universal reaction path representation.</description>
      <author>Kalyan Ramakrishnan, Lars L. Schaaf, Chen Lin, Guangrun Wang, Philip H. S. Torr</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0267023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five key concepts linking vacancies, structure, and oxygen evolution reaction activity in cobalt-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cc02438b</link>
      <description>Kenneth Crossley, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412475511

                Focusing on five key concepts, we review the roles of cation and oxygen vacancies in determining the surface reconstruction pathway, reaction mechanism, and ultimate activity of cobalt-based oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Kenneth Crossley, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cc02438b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthened Ru&#8211;O Bonds for Robust Oxygen Evolution in Acid Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02453</link>
      <description>Danning Li, Wenrui Ma, Mathan K. Eswaran, Chunfeng Li, Jiayi Chen, Guangxin Sun, Shibo Xi, Sergey M. Kozlov, Chunnian He, Lei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412479227

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Danning Li, Wenrui Ma, Mathan K. Eswaran, Chunfeng Li, Jiayi Chen, Guangxin Sun, Shibo Xi, Sergey M. Kozlov, Chunnian He, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02453</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI for Complex Catalytic Systems: High-Entropy Alloys in Electrocatalytic Acetylene Semihydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04236</link>
      <description>Zhen Tan, Xinyu Li, Rui Bai, Chang Guo, Xiao Han, Qinfeng Shi, Jian Zhang, Haobo Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412479777

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhen Tan, Xinyu Li, Rui Bai, Chang Guo, Xiao Han, Qinfeng Shi, Jian Zhang, Haobo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow p-n heterostructures with vacancy engineering to enhance Z-scheme photocatalytic CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165595</link>
      <description>Zhitao Zou, Yaxin Wang, Tianyi Zhang, Jing L&#252;, V. Z. Turkevich, Yueqin Yu, Jixiang Xu, Haifeng Lin, Yanyan Li, Lei Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. 520(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412490038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhitao Zou, Yaxin Wang, Tianyi Zhang, Jing L&#252;, V. Z. Turkevich, Yueqin Yu, Jixiang Xu, Haifeng Lin, Yanyan Li, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation the coordination of Fe-Co diatomic sites with boron atom for fuel cells and Zn-Air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125679</link>
      <description>Dai Dang, Lin Zhang, Guifa Long, Chao Liu, Wenjun Fan, Jie Zheng, Tiejun Wang, Quanbing Liu, Xiaopeng Han, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. 379(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412490061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dai Dang, Lin Zhang, Guifa Long, Chao Liu, Wenjun Fan, Jie Zheng, Tiejun Wang, Quanbing Liu, Xiaopeng Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating surface properties of catalysts to promote the oxidation of multi-component VOCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.118118</link>
      <description>Min Zhang, Liangyu Liu, Ling Ding, Ningjie Fang, Yinghao Chu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412467963

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Zhang, Liangyu Liu, Ling Ding, Ningjie Fang, Yinghao Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.118118</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
