<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 01:18:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Mechanism on Pristine and Defective Nickel Phosphate Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsurfi.2025.100431</link>
      <description>Dyah Puspasari Wijayanti, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Damar Rastri Adhika, Hamad AlMohamadi, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Results in Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406642017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dyah Puspasari Wijayanti, Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, Damar Rastri Adhika, Hamad AlMohamadi, Nadhratun Naiim Mobarak, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsurfi.2025.100431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Screening of Efficient TM/GaN Single-Atom Catalysts for Electroreduction of Nitrate to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06861</link>
      <description>Huifang Ma, Saifei Yuan, Shujuan Li, Jiayao Wang, Huiyun Zhang, Yuping Zhang, Jingxiu Yang, Jinbo Sun, Ke Xu, Shulai Lei, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406681579

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huifang Ma, Saifei Yuan, Shujuan Li, Jiayao Wang, Huiyun Zhang, Yuping Zhang, Jingxiu Yang, Jinbo Sun, Ke Xu, Shulai Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual active site and metal&#8211;substrate interface effect endow platinum&#8211;ruthenium/molybdenum carbide efficient pH-universal hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.180</link>
      <description>H. Ling, Qiang Yuan, Tian Sheng, Xun Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 685(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406683610

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Ling, Qiang Yuan, Tian Sheng, Xun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive review of two-dimensional high-entropy layered hydroxides: Synthesis, characterization, and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216435</link>
      <description>Abdul Hai, Muhammad Daud, Ghulam Mujtaba, Fawzi Banat, Mamdouh A. Al&#8208;Harthi, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 529(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406684537

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Hai, Muhammad Daud, Ghulam Mujtaba, Fawzi Banat, Mamdouh A. Al&#8208;Harthi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Changes in Metal Chalcogenide Nanoclusters Associated with Single Heteroatom Incorporation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c07000</link>
      <description>Xi-Lai Li, Shana Havenridge, Habib Gholipour&#8208;Ranjbar, Dylan Forbes, W. O. Crain, Cong Liu, Julia Laskin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406690302

                Atomically precise nanoclusters (NCs) are promising building blocks for designing materials and interfaces with unique properties. By incorporating heteroatoms into the core, the electronic and magnetic properties of NCs can be precisely tuned. To accurately predict these properties, density functional theory (DFT) is often employed, making the rigorous benchmarking of DFT results particularly important. In this study, we present a benchmarking approach based on metal chalcogenide NCs as a model system. We synthesized a series of bimetallic, iron&#8211;cobalt chalcogenide NCs [Co6&#8211;xFexS8(PEt3)6]+ (x = 0&#8211;6) (PEt = triethyl phosphine) and investigated the effect of heteroatoms in the octahedral metal chalcogenide core on their size and electronic properties. Using ion mobility-mass spectrometry (IM-MS), we observed a gradual increase in the collision cross section (CCS) with an increase in the number of Fe atoms in the core. DFT calculations combined with trajectory method CCS simulations successfully reproduced this trend, revealing that the increase in cluster size is primarily due to changes in metal&#8211;ligand bond lengths, while the electronic properties of the core remain largely unchanged. Moreover, this method allowed us to exclude certain multiplicity states of the NCs, as their CCS values were significantly different from those predicted for the lowest-energy structures. This study demonstrates that gas-phase IM-MS is a powerful technique for detecting subtle size differences in atomically precise NCs, which are often challenging to observe using conventional NC characterization methods. Accurate CCS measurements are established as a benchmark for comparison with theoretical calculations. The excellent correspondence between experimental data and theoretical predictions establishes a robust foundation for investigating structural changes of transition metal NCs of interest to a broad range of applications.</description>
      <author>Xi-Lai Li, Shana Havenridge, Habib Gholipour&#8208;Ranjbar, Dylan Forbes, W. O. Crain, Cong Liu, Julia Laskin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c07000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unifying the Description of Hydrocarbons and Hydrogenated Carbon Materials with a Chemically Reactive Machine Learning Interatomic Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02905</link>
      <description>Rina Ibragimova, Mikhail S. Kuklin, Tigany Zarrouk, A. Miguel, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406690375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rina Ibragimova, Mikhail S. Kuklin, Tigany Zarrouk, A. Miguel</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating CALPHAD-based phase diagram predictions in complex alloys using universal machine learning potentials: Opportunities and challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.120747</link>
      <description>Siya Zhu, Do&#287;uhan Sar&#305;t&#252;rk, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406693067

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siya Zhu, Do&#287;uhan Sar&#305;t&#252;rk, Raymundo Arr&#243;yave</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.120747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling electrochemical nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101239</link>
      <description>&#193;rni Bj&#246;rn H&#246;skuldsson, Yasufumi Sakai, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406694788

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#193;rni Bj&#246;rn H&#246;skuldsson, Yasufumi Sakai, Egill Sk&#250;lason</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of two-dimensional conductive MOFs as OER catalysts assisted by machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10612-3</link>
      <description>Yuyang Liu, Jianping Sun, Yuxin Chai, Yu Yang, Zhi Yang, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406696510

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuyang Liu, Jianping Sun, Yuxin Chai, Yu Yang, Zhi Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-025-10612-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re3(C6O6)2 monolayer: a promising metal&#8211;organic framework-based electro-catalyst for N2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-025-02449-y</link>
      <description>Honglan Li, Lei Yang, Xinglin Yang, Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406703810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Honglan Li, Lei Yang, Xinglin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-025-02449-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into Methanol Electro-Oxidation on NiPd Nanoelectrocatalysts: Investigating the Carbonate&#8211;Palladium Oxide Pathway and the Role of Water and OH Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15020101</link>
      <description>Alan Santove&#241;a-Uribe, Aldo Ledesma&#8211;Dur&#225;n, Julisa Torres-Enriquez, I. Santamar&#305;&#769;a-Holek, Catalysts. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406704738

                We conducted a theoretical and experimental study on the electro-oxidation of methanol (MOR) on NixPdy nanoparticles. The results are presented in terms of kinetic parameters, surface concentrations, and peak currents, showing significant differences between three main compositions: Ni3Pd1, Ni1Pd1, and Ni1Pd3. The kinetic mechanism adopted for accounting the linear voltammetry experiments performed follows the carbonate&#8211;palladium oxide pathway of the MOR. Numerical simulations of the kinetic equations, fitted to experimental data obtained at varying methanol concentrations, allowed us to distinguish the adsorption contributions of methanol, water, and OH ions from the nonlinear contribution associated with palladium oxide and carbon dioxide production. The synergistic effects of Ni:Pd nanoalloys on the MOR were then assessed by analyzing the behavior and tendencies of the reaction rate constants for different bulk methanol concentrations. Our results suggest that a higher Pd content favors more efficient oxidation mechanisms by reducing the formation of intermediate products that cause surface poisoning, such as CO, carbonates, or palladium oxide. However, as the proportion of Ni increases, an increase in the concentration of adsorbed OH is observed, which dominates the blocking of active sites even greater than the palladium oxide blocking.</description>
      <author>Alan Santove&#241;a-Uribe, Aldo Ledesma&#8211;Dur&#225;n, Julisa Torres-Enriquez, I. Santamar&#305;&#769;a-Holek</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15020101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed atomistic&#8211;implicit quantum/classical approach to molecular nanoplasmonics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245629</link>
      <description>Pablo Grobas Illobre, Piero Lafiosca, Luca Bonatti, Tommaso Giovannini, Chiara Cappelli, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706023

                A multiscale quantum mechanical (QM)/classical approach is presented that is able to model the optical properties of complex nanostructures composed of a molecular system adsorbed on metal nanoparticles. The latter is described by a combined atomistic&#8211;continuum model, where the core is described using the implicit boundary element method (BEM) and the surface retains a fully atomistic picture and is treated employing the frequency-dependent fluctuating charge and fluctuating dipole (&#969;FQF&#956;) approach. The integrated QM/&#969;FQF&#956;-BEM model is numerically compared with state-of-the-art fully atomistic approaches, and the quality of the continuum/core partition is evaluated. The method is then extended to compute surface-enhanced Raman scattering within a time-dependent density functional theory framework.</description>
      <author>Pablo Grobas Illobre, Piero Lafiosca, Luca Bonatti, Tommaso Giovannini, Chiara Cappelli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0245629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confining Surface Oxygen Redox in Double Perovskites for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404560</link>
      <description>Natasha Hales, Jinzhen Huang, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Ivano E. Castelli, Radim Skoup&#253;, Adam H. Clark, Micha&#322; Andrzejewski, Nicola Casati, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706492

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;based double perovskites AA&#8242;BB&#8242;O 6 are an underexplored class of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, in which B&#8208;site substitution is used to tune electronic and structural properties. BaSrNiWO 6 , with a B&#8208;site comprised of alternating Ni and W, exhibits high oxygen evolution activity, attributed to the evolution of a highly OER active surface phase. The redox transformation of Ni 2+ (3d 8 ) to Ni 3+ (3d 7 ) combined with partial W dissolution into the electrolyte from the linear Ni(3d)&#8208;O(2p)&#8208;W(5d) chains drives an in situ reconstruction of the surface to an amorphized, NiO&#8208;like layer, promoting oxygen redox in the OER mechanism. However, the high valence W 6+ (5d 0 ) acts as a stabilizing electronic influence in the bulk, preventing the mobilization of lattice oxygen which is bound in highly covalent W&#9472;O bonds. It is proposed that the surface generated during the OER can support a lattice oxygen evolution mechanism (LOEM) in which oxygen vacancies are created and preferentially refilled by electrolytic OH &#8722; , while bulk O species remain stable. This surface LOEM (sLOEM) allows BaSrNiWO 6 to retain structural integrity during OER catalysis. With a Tafel slope of 45 mV dec &#8722;1 in 0.1 m KOH, BaSrNiWO 6 illustrates the potential of Ni&#8208;based double perovskites to offer both OER efficiency and bulk stability in alkaline electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Natasha Hales, Jinzhen Huang, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Ivano E. Castelli, Radim Skoup&#253;, Adam H. Clark, Micha&#322; Andrzejewski, Nicola Casati, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid fabrication of phase-separated Cu-Zn particles though &#8220;droplet-to-particle&#8221; method and their performance in CO2 electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134360</link>
      <description>Kejie Zhang, Weijian Hua, Renhui Ruan, Baochong Cui, Mingxing Su, Xuebin Wang, Houzhang Tan, Fuel. 388(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406712294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kejie Zhang, Weijian Hua, Renhui Ruan, Baochong Cui, Mingxing Su, Xuebin Wang, Houzhang Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening corrosion-resistant genetic elements of Sn-0.7Cu solders by high-throughput calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2025.112726</link>
      <description>Ancang Yang, Jiale Wu, Bin Zhang, Yonghua Duan, Lishi Ma, Mingjun Peng, Shanju Zheng, Linfen Su, Mengnie Li, Corrosion Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406715355

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ancang Yang, Jiale Wu, Bin Zhang, Yonghua Duan, Lishi Ma, Mingjun Peng, Shanju Zheng, Linfen Su, Mengnie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2025.112726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3d transition metal anchored boron nitride edge for CO2 reduction reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112616</link>
      <description>Wenlong Guo, Haiyue Liao, Wenhong Zeng, Xinlin Tang, Xin Lian, Peng Xiao, Guangyong Gao, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406719852

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenlong Guo, Haiyue Liao, Wenhong Zeng, Xinlin Tang, Xin Lian, Peng Xiao, Guangyong Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ternary nanostructured materials: Properties and their applications as oxygen reduction catalysts in fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114861</link>
      <description>Fereshteh Dehghani Sanij, Narayanamoorthy Bhuvanendran, A.A. Shah, Huaneng Su, Qian Xu, Molecular Catalysis. 574(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406722385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fereshteh Dehghani Sanij, Narayanamoorthy Bhuvanendran, A.A. Shah, Huaneng Su, Qian Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.114861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degree of span control to determine the impact of different mechanisms and limiting steps: Oxygen evolution reaction over Co3O4(001) as a case study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115970</link>
      <description>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406732898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Formation of High Entropy Solid Solutions and High Entropy Intermetallics by In Situ X-ray Diffraction and Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02470</link>
      <description>Nicolas Schlegel, Stefanie Punke, Christian M. Clausen, Ulrik Friis-Jensen, Adam F. Sapnik, Dragos Stoian, Olivia Aalling&#8208;Frederiksen, Divyansh Gautam, Jan Rossmeisl, Rebecca K. Pittkowski, Matthias Arenz, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406738489

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nicolas Schlegel, Stefanie Punke, Christian M. Clausen, Ulrik Friis-Jensen, Adam F. Sapnik, Dragos Stoian, Olivia Aalling&#8208;Frederiksen, Divyansh Gautam, Jan Rossmeisl, Rebecca K. Pittkowski, Matthias Arenz, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study of oxygen reduction reaction activity and stability on Mn-Ni dual-atom electrocatalysts anchored at graphene edges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162495</link>
      <description>Faizal Helmi, Muhammad Hakim, Ahmad Nuruddin, Nadya Amalia, Sasfan Arman Wella, Hamad AlMohamadi, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741646

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faizal Helmi, Muhammad Hakim, Ahmad Nuruddin, Nadya Amalia, Sasfan Arman Wella, Hamad AlMohamadi, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GC-DFT simulation of coverage and potential effect for oxygen evolution reaction on RuO2-based electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</link>
      <description>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon Hybridization in Rotation Bimetallic-Chain System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07988</link>
      <description>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yongqi Chen, Yurui Fang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406743596

                Plasmon hybridization phenomena in metallic chain heterodimers represent a frontier in nanoscale optoelectronic research, offering insights into the quantum mechanisms that govern their behavior. Utilizing first-principles-based computational methods, we conduct a systematic study into the dimer configurations formed by Na8 and Mg8 chains, encompassing Na8 homodimer, Mg8 homodimer, and Na8Mg8 heterodimer. The study reveals that with the variation of bichain rotation angles, the plasmonic resonance modes within the dimers undergo significant hybridization, resulting in the emergence of new split peaks at the lower-energy range due to hybridization of the longitude mode and the transverse mode in the middle of the chain induced by it. At the high-energy range, the longitude multipole mode on the other chain is induced by the transverse center, and the interaction results in the splitting and appearance of hidden modes as the rotation angle increases. Both the excitation in the orthogonal direction and the electromagnetic field enhancement effects confirm the hybridization, which also provides the tenability of the plasmon resonance. This research provides a new theoretical perspective for understanding plasmonic hybridization phenomena at the nanoscale and offers important theoretical guidance for designing novel optoelectronic devices based on molecular plasmonics.</description>
      <author>Nan Gao, Haoran Liu, Yongqi Chen, Yurui Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Regulation of High-Entropy Perovskite Oxides through Hole Doping for Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20338</link>
      <description>Gaoliang Fu, Ruipeng Hou, Li Sun, Huili Liu, Yaru Wei, Ruixue Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Shouren Zhang, Baocheng Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406747925

                Due to the high configuration entropy, unique atomic arrangement, and electronic structures, high-entropy materials are being actively pursued as bifunctional catalysts for both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in rechargeable zinc-air batteries (ZABs). However, a relevant strategy to enhance the catalytic activity of high-entropy materials is still lacking. Herein, a hole doping strategy has been employed to enable the high-entropy perovskite La(Cr0.2Mn0.2Fe0.2Co0.2Ni0.2)O3 to effectively catalyze the ORR and OER. Hole doping experiments rely on the substitution of Sr2+ for La3+. The optimized La0.7Sr0.3(Cr0.2Mn0.2Fe0.2Co0.2Ni0.2)O3 displays remarkable activity for the ORR and the OER, with a low potential difference of 0.880 V between the half-wave potential of the ORR and the OER potential at 10 mA cm-2, exceeding the majority of perovskite bifunctional catalysts. Further analysis of the electronic structures reveals that hole doping could regulate the eg-orbital filling of the transition-metal cations in high-entropy perovskites to an ideal position and thereby generate many highly active sites to promote the redox activity of oxygen. The assembled rechargeable ZAB with the targeted high-entropy perovskite as the cathode affords a specific capacity of 774.5 mAh gZn-1 under 10 mA cm-2 and durability for a period of 300 cycles, comparable to that of the 20%Pt/C + RuO2 ZAB. This work offers an important approach for the advancement of efficient high-entropy perovskites for ZABs.</description>
      <author>Gaoliang Fu, Ruipeng Hou, Li Sun, Huili Liu, Yaru Wei, Ruixue Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Shouren Zhang, Baocheng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening of multifunctional single-atom catalysts supported by VS2 monolayer for the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115098</link>
      <description>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406748597

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct free energy calculation from &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; path integral Monte Carlo simulations of warm dense matter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.l041114</link>
      <description>Tobias Dornheim, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Sebastian Schwalbe, Jan Vorberger, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406759192

                We carry out highly accurate path integral Monte Carlo simulations to directly estimate the free energy of various warm dense matter systems including the uniform electron gas and hydrogen without any nodal restrictions or other approximations. Since our approach is based on an effective ensemble in a bosonic configuration space, it does not increase the computational complexity beyond the usual fermion sign problem. Its application to inhomogeneous cases such as an electronic system in a fixed external ion potential is straightforward and opens up the enticing possibility to benchmark density functional theory and other existing methods. Finally, it is not limited to warm dense matter and can be applied to a gamut of other systems such as ultracold atoms and electrons in quantum dots. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>Tobias Dornheim, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Sebastian Schwalbe, Jan Vorberger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.l041114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening and research of nitrogen reduction on 2D metal&#8211;organic framework: First-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221872</link>
      <description>Zheng-Yun Xiong, Wen-qing Hong, Yu&#8208;Qing Zhao, Wen-Jin Yin, Ying Xu, Applied Physics Letters. 126(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406762355

                Developing efficient nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) catalysts remains challenging. Two-dimensional metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) stand out because of their large holes and high metal utilization. Based on first-principles high-throughput calculations, we studied the catalytic capacity of MOF catalyst TM3 (HITP)2 for NRR. Our calculated results indicate that among 29 catalytic structures, Mo3(HITP)2 and Os3(HITP)2 exhibit excellent activity for NRR, with the overpotential being 0.39 and 0.43 V, respectively. The unoccupied 4d orbitals of Mo are especially closer to the antibonding N-2p orbitals, leading to better nitrogen activation and lower overpotential. In addition, a descriptor related to charge variation and the electronegativity of metals and coordinating atoms is established, which has a good volcano plot relationship with the limiting potential of NRR and can provide ideas for catalyst screening. This research contributes valuable insights for the screening of NRR catalysts based on MOF.</description>
      <author>Zheng-Yun Xiong, Wen-qing Hong, Yu&#8208;Qing Zhao, Wen-Jin Yin, Ying Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author-Centric Pattern Detection in Scopus Citation Network via Community Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-7839-3_1</link>
      <description>R. Kiruthika, N. Radha, Lecture notes in networks and systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406772073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Kiruthika, N. Radha</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-7839-3_1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of Schottky Barrier Height and Electronic Structure in Transition-Metal@Nitrogen-Doped-Carbon Core&#8211;Shell Cocatalysts Loaded with Mn&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;S Nanorods for Enhanced Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06476</link>
      <description>Yufeng Li, Songqing Zhang, Chunmei He, Hongxia Yao, Changfa Guo, Wentao Wang, Yong Hu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406786311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yufeng Li, Songqing Zhang, Chunmei He, Hongxia Yao, Changfa Guo, Wentao Wang, Yong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applications of density functional theory to corrosion and corrosion prevention of metals: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.83</link>
      <description>Dihao Chen, Wenjie Zhou, Yucheng Ji, Dihao Chen, Materials Genome Engineering Advances. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406786726

                Abstract Recently, density functional theory (DFT) has been a powerful tool to model the corrosion behaviors of materials, provide insights into the corrosion mechanisms, predict the corrosion performance of materials, and design the corrosion&#8208;resistant alloys and organic inhibitors. DFT enables corrosion scientist to fundamentally understand the corrosion behaviors and corrosion mechanisms of materials from the perspective of atomic and electronic structures, combining with the traditional and advanced experimental tests. This review briefly summarizes the main features of DFT calculations and present a comprehensive overview of their typical applications to corrosion and corrosion prevention of metals, involving potential&#8208;pH diagrams, hydrogen evolution reaction, anodic dissolution, passivity and passivity breakdown, and organic inhibitor for metals. The paper also reviews the correlations between DFT&#8208;computed descriptors and the micro/macro physiochemical parameters of corrosion. Despite the great progress achieved by DFT, there are still some challenges in addressing corrosion issues due to the lack of bridges between the DFT&#8208;calculated electronic parameters and the macro corrosion performance of materials. The DFT modeling&#8208;experiment&#8208;engineering&#8208;theory model will be a potential method to clarify and build the links.</description>
      <author>Dihao Chen, Wenjie Zhou, Yucheng Ji, Dihao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/mgea.83</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of two critical operating factors on the enhanced catalytic conversion of aqueous NO3&#8211; to NH4+ by Pt-Co@NC and theoretical verification of its surface reaction mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159874</link>
      <description>Nurbek Nurlan, Jaewoo Jeong, Meiirzhan Nurmyrza, Hyungjun Kim, Hye&#8208;Young Shin, Woojin Lee, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406788037

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nurbek Nurlan, Jaewoo Jeong, Meiirzhan Nurmyrza, Hyungjun Kim, Hye&#8208;Young Shin, Woojin Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the structure-activity relationship of phosphorus-doped Fe-Cu@NC catalysts: Exploring the influence of different coordination layers on oxygen reduction reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236302</link>
      <description>Youzheng Wu, Penghui Ren, Ruopeng Li, Xun Zheng, Changning Bai, Yidi Liu, Meng Fan, Xuesong Peng, Lihui Xiao, Anmin Liu, Hao Xu, Dan Wang, Jinqiu Zhang, Maozhong An, Shizheng Wen, Yaqiang Li, Peixia Yang, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406791942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youzheng Wu, Penghui Ren, Ruopeng Li, Xun Zheng, Changning Bai, Yidi Liu, Meng Fan, Xuesong Peng, Lihui Xiao, Anmin Liu, Hao Xu, Dan Wang, Jinqiu Zhang, Maozhong An, Shizheng Wen, Yaqiang Li, Peixia Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the frontiers of electrocatalysis: advanced theoretical methods for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s40580-024-00467-w</link>
      <description>Seong Chan Cho, Jun Ho Seok, Hung Ngo Manh, Jae Hun Seol, Chi H. Lee, Sang Uck Lee, Nano Convergence. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406793010

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting, which encompasses the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), offers a promising route for sustainable hydrogen production. The development of efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts is crucial for advancing this technology, especially given the reliance on expensive transition metals, such as Pt and Ir, in traditional catalysts. This review highlights recent advances in the design and optimization of electrocatalysts, focusing on density functional theory (DFT) as a key tool for understanding and improving catalytic performance in the HER and OER. We begin by exploring DFT-based approaches for evaluating catalytic activity under both acidic and alkaline conditions. The review then shifts to a material-oriented perspective, showcasing key catalyst materials and the theoretical strategies employed to enhance their performance. In addition, we discuss scaling relationships that exist between binding energies and electronic structures through the use of charge-density analysis and d -band theory. Advanced concepts, such as the effects of adsorbate coverage, solvation, and applied potential on catalytic behavior, are also discussed. We finally focus on integrating machine learning (ML) with DFT to enable high-throughput screening and accelerate the discovery of novel water-splitting catalysts. This comprehensive review underscores the pivotal role that DFT plays in advancing electrocatalyst design and highlights its potential for shaping the future of sustainable hydrogen production. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Seong Chan Cho, Jun Ho Seok, Hung Ngo Manh, Jae Hun Seol, Chi H. Lee, Sang Uck Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s40580-024-00467-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating alloy design and discovery with physics-aware multimodal multiagent AI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2414074122</link>
      <description>Alireza Ghafarollahi, Markus J. Buehler, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406794696

                The design of new alloys is a multiscale problem that requires a holistic approach that involves retrieving relevant knowledge, applying advanced computational methods, conducting experimental validations, and analyzing the results, a process that is typically slow and reserved for human experts. Machine learning can help accelerate this process, for instance, through the use of deep surrogate models that connect structural and chemical features to material properties, or vice versa. However, existing data-driven models often target specific material objectives, offering limited flexibility to integrate out-of-domain knowledge and cannot adapt to new, unforeseen challenges. Here, we overcome these limitations by leveraging the distinct capabilities of multiple AI agents that collaborate autonomously within a dynamic environment to solve complex materials design tasks. The proposed physics-aware generative AI platform, AtomAgents, synergizes the intelligence of large language models (LLMs) and the dynamic collaboration among AI agents with expertise in various domains, including knowledge retrieval, multimodal data integration, physics-based simulations, and comprehensive results analysis across modalities. The concerted effort of the multiagent system allows for addressing complex materials design problems, as demonstrated by examples that include autonomously designing metallic alloys with enhanced properties compared to their pure counterparts. Our results enable accurate prediction of key characteristics across alloys and highlight the crucial role of solid solution alloying to steer the development of advanced metallic alloys. Our framework enhances the efficiency of complex multiobjective design tasks and opens avenues in fields such as biomedical materials engineering, renewable energy, and environmental sustainability.</description>
      <author>Alireza Ghafarollahi, Markus J. Buehler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2414074122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt-MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Hybrid Electrocatalysts Modulating Local Environment for Enhanced Activity toward Hydrogen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c02409</link>
      <description>Jueun Koh, Sohee Kim, Gyeonghye Yim, Ji&#8211;Hun Yu, Jaehwan Kim, Sang Hoon Joo, Hongje Jang, Young Jin, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406795838

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jueun Koh, Sohee Kim, Gyeonghye Yim, Ji&#8211;Hun Yu, Jaehwan Kim, Sang Hoon Joo, Hongje Jang, Young Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c02409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte effects on reaction kinetics in electrochemical CO2 reduction: The roles of pH, cations, and anions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242304</link>
      <description>Wei Chen, Xinjuan Du, Shuaikang Tao, Bo Lin, Ionu&#355; Tranca, Frederik Tielens, Ming Ma, Zhaochun Liu, Chemical Physics Reviews. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406800318

                The electrochemical reduction of CO2 (CO2RR) holds significant potential for converting CO2 into value-added fuels and chemicals under mild reaction conditions. The kinetics of CO2RR is strongly influenced by both the electrocatalysts and the local environment at the electrode/electrolyte interface. While considerable research has focused on elucidating the &#8220;structure-activity&#8221; relationships of electrocatalysts, a fundamental understanding of the role of electrolyte-related factors (such as the ionic species) near the electrode/electrolyte interface is highly important for the further enhancement in the catalytic performance of CO2RR. In this review, we discuss the effects of pH, cations, and anions in the vicinity of the catalyst, using CO2RR as a model reaction. The mechanistic understanding of these effects is also analyzed via experimental findings from in situ spectroscopic techniques and theoretical insights from density functional theory simulations. This review underscores the importance of understanding the various interactions of electrolytes with catalyst surfaces or intermediates and their impact on reaction kinetics of CO2RR.</description>
      <author>Wei Chen, Xinjuan Du, Shuaikang Tao, Bo Lin, Ionu&#355; Tranca, Frederik Tielens, Ming Ma, Zhaochun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-Fe dual-atom anchored g-C3N5 for photocatalytic overall water splitting: Fe-driven Ni-N dual sites synergy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.301</link>
      <description>Tao Ma, Xin Wang, Jiehang Wei, Hongqiang Xia, Ying-Tao Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 105(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406804136

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Ma, Xin Wang, Jiehang Wei, Hongqiang Xia, Ying-Tao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating SnSx species for electroreduction of CO2 towards formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162486</link>
      <description>Yi&#8208;Bing Yang, Xiao Yang, Shuwen Zhao, Zhipeng Liu, Yi Xiao, Lili Han, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406817545

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi&#8208;Bing Yang, Xiao Yang, Shuwen Zhao, Zhipeng Liu, Yi Xiao, Lili Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qcforever2: Advanced Automation of Quantum Chemistry Computations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70017</link>
      <description>Masato Sumita, Kei Terayama, Shoichi Ishida, K. SUGA, Shohei Saito, Koji Tsuda, Journal of Computational Chemistry. 46(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406823375

                ABSTRACT QCforever is a wrapper designed to automatically and simultaneously calculate various physical quantities using quantum chemical (QC) calculation software for blackbox optimization in chemical space. We have updated it to QCforever2 to search the conformation and optimize density functional parameters for a more accurate and reliable evaluation of an input molecule. In blackbox optimization, QCforever2 can work as compactly arranged surrogate models for costly chemical experiments. QCforever2 is the future of QC calculations and would be a good companion for chemical laboratories, providing more reliable search and exploitation in the chemical space.</description>
      <author>Masato Sumita, Kei Terayama, Shoichi Ishida, K. SUGA, Shohei Saito, Koji Tsuda</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.70017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-doping strategy for perovskite anodes towards high-performance ammonia-fueled SOFCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236320</link>
      <description>Or Rahumi, Yuliy Yuferov, Louisa Meshi, Nitzan Maman, Konstantin Borodianskiy, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406828837

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Or Rahumi, Yuliy Yuferov, Louisa Meshi, Nitzan Maman, Konstantin Borodianskiy</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural-property relationships of phenyl-based multifunctional hybrid ligand 2D MOFs (Ni-XnY4-n, where X, Y = NH, O, S): A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162541</link>
      <description>Jingyuan Zhou, Wen Zhao, Mingxiang Zhang, A. M. Zhang, Hao Ren, Houyu Zhu, Yuhua Chi, Wenyue Guo, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406829098

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingyuan Zhou, Wen Zhao, Mingxiang Zhang, A. M. Zhang, Hao Ren, Houyu Zhu, Yuhua Chi, Wenyue Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can phosphides catalyze CO2 reduction reaction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.145755</link>
      <description>Naveed Ashraf, Diego Bitzenhofer Betolaza, H&#225;lfd&#225;n Ingi Gunnarsson, Mohammad Khatibi, Atef Iqbal, Younes Abghoui, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406829230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naveed Ashraf, Diego Bitzenhofer Betolaza, H&#225;lfd&#225;n Ingi Gunnarsson, Mohammad Khatibi, Atef Iqbal, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.145755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-doping-induced electron spin polarization activates scandium oxide as high-performance zinc-air battery cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.223</link>
      <description>Yuhui Chen, Chang Ming Li, Yiqing Chen, Ying Cheng, Xinxin Tian, Dongdong Xiao, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Linjie Zhang, Wenlie Lin, Jun Luo, Lili Han, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406834376

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhui Chen, Chang Ming Li, Yiqing Chen, Ying Cheng, Xinxin Tian, Dongdong Xiao, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Linjie Zhang, Wenlie Lin, Jun Luo, Lili Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alchemical harmonic approximation based potential for iso-electronic diatomics: Foundational baseline for &#916;-machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241872</link>
      <description>Simon Le&#243;n Krug, Danish Khan, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706160

                We introduce the alchemical harmonic approximation (AHA) of the absolute electronic energy for charge-neutral iso-electronic diatomics at fixed interatomic distance d0. To account for variations in distance, we combine AHA with this ansatz for the electronic binding potential, E(d)=(Eu&#8722;Es)Ec&#8722;EsEu&#8722;Esd/d0+Es, where Eu, Ec, Es correspond to the energies of the united atom, calibration at d0, and the sum of infinitely separated atoms, respectively. Our model covers the two-dimensional electronic potential energy surface spanned by distances of 0.7&#8211;2.5 &#197; and differences in nuclear charge from which only one single point (with elements of nuclear charge Z1, Z2, and distance d0) is drawn to calibrate Ec. Using reference data from pbe0/cc-pVDZ, we present numerical evidence for the electronic ground-state of all neutral diatomics with 8, 10, 12, and 14 electrons. We assess the validity of our model by comparison to legacy interatomic potentials (harmonic oscillator, Lennard-Jones, and Morse) within the most relevant range of binding (0.7&#8211;2.5 &#197;) and find comparable accuracy if restricted to single diatomics and significantly better predictive power when extrapolating to the entire iso-electronic series. We also investigated &#916;-learning of the electronic absolute energy using our model as a baseline. This baseline model results in a systematic improvement, effectively reducing training data needed for reaching chemical accuracy by up to an order of magnitude from &#8764;1000 to &#8764;100. By contrast, using AHA+Morse as a baseline hardly leads to any improvement and sometimes even deteriorates the predictive power. Inferring the energy of unseen CO converges to a prediction error of &#8764;0.1 Ha in direct learning and &#8764;0.04 Ha with our baseline.</description>
      <author>Simon Le&#243;n Krug, Danish Khan, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence interventions in 2D MXenes-based photocatalytic applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216460</link>
      <description>Durga Madhab Mahapatra, Ashish Kumar, Rajesh Kumar, Navneet Kumar Gupta, Baranitharan Ethiraj, Lakhveer Singh, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 529(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406789185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Durga Madhab Mahapatra, Ashish Kumar, Rajesh Kumar, Navneet Kumar Gupta, Baranitharan Ethiraj, Lakhveer Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2025.216460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the fourth paradigm of modeling in chemical engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-024-00170-x</link>
      <description>John R. Kitchin, Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird, Nature Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706802

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John R. Kitchin, Victor Alves, Carl D. Laird</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-024-00170-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orbital Resolution of the Reconstruction of CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (100) Facet&#8211;Hybrid-DFT and COHP Investigations Supported by HR-TEM Imaging</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06854</link>
      <description>Leszek Nowakowski, Filip Zasada, Joanna Grybo&#347;, Zbigniew Sojka, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406676582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leszek Nowakowski, Filip Zasada, Joanna Grybo&#347;, Zbigniew Sojka</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning of imidazole-based ionic liquid for highly efficient and reversible direct air capture via hydrogen bonding interaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131790</link>
      <description>Kaili Wang, Jiayi Bai, Zhenyu Zhao, Zhaowei Zhang, Weiqi Mao, Lili Jiang, Haoran Li, Congmin Wang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406792619

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaili Wang, Jiayi Bai, Zhenyu Zhao, Zhaowei Zhang, Weiqi Mao, Lili Jiang, Haoran Li, Congmin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131790</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Surface Chemistry of Methanol on Cu&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Pd(111): Effects of Metal Alloying and Reaction with Hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07648</link>
      <description>Kasala Prabhakar Reddy, Jeongjin Kim, Hojoon Lim, Arephin Islam, Irene Barba-Nieto, Xiao Tong, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, Jos&#233; A. Rodr&#237;guez, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406792959

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kasala Prabhakar Reddy, Jeongjin Kim, Hojoon Lim, Arephin Islam, Irene Barba-Nieto, Xiao Tong, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, Jos&#233; A. Rodr&#237;guez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biogenic CuO nanoparticles from Camellia sinensis and Pimpinella anisum plant extracts and their role as antimicrobial agents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plana.2025.100138</link>
      <description>A. Paganotti, Carolina Cunha de Freitas, Roney H. Pereira, Vitor Gon&#231;alves Vital, Giovanna S.M. Paiva, Lucas F. de Lima, Leonardo Silva, Elizabeth Teodorov, R.A.G. Silva, Suzan Pantaroto de Vasconcellos, Amedea B. Seabra, Plant Nano Biology. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406818093

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Paganotti, Carolina Cunha de Freitas, Roney H. Pereira, Vitor Gon&#231;alves Vital, Giovanna S.M. Paiva, Lucas F. de Lima, Leonardo Silva, Elizabeth Teodorov, R.A.G. Silva, Suzan Pantaroto de Vasconcellos, Amedea B. Seabra</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plana.2025.100138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIOSYNTHESIS OF &#946;-LACTAM ANTIBIOTICS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-08-022092-5.50012-8</link>
      <description>D. John Aberhart, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 1978. https://openalex.org/W4406680887

                No abstract</description>
      <author>D. John Aberhart</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1978 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-08-022092-5.50012-8</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
