<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 01:03:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism and performance of photocatalytic H2 evolution for carbon self-doped TiO2 derived from MIL-125</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.154</link>
      <description>Ying Zhao, Nan Yang, Tong Zhou, Wei Zhan, Jie Zhao, Mingpeng Chen, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Yuming Zhang, Genlin Zhang, Qingju Liu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393925299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Zhao, Nan Yang, Tong Zhou, Wei Zhan, Jie Zhao, Mingpeng Chen, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Yuming Zhang, Genlin Zhang, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Structure of Pd@Ni&#8211;Co Nanowires and Their Electrochemical Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00376</link>
      <description>Dariusz &#321;ukowiec, Magdalena Gw&#243;&#378;d&#378;, Alina Brz&#281;czek&#8208;Szafran, Tomasz Wasiak, Dawid Janas, Jerzy Kubacki, Stanis&#322;aw Wac&#322;awek, Adrian Rado&#324;, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393927143

                One-dimensional transition metal materials are promising supports for precious metals used in energy production processes. Due to their electrochemical properties, 3d-group metals (such as Ni, Co, and Fe) can actively interact with catalysts by a strong metal&#8211;support interaction. This study shows that changing the Ni:Co ratio makes it possible to modulate the structure of the catalyst supports, which, in turn, provides a tool for designing their electrical and electrochemical properties. For example, Ni1&#8211;Co9 shows the highest electrical conductivity (5.8&#8211;10&#8211;4 S/cm) among all of the materials examined. On the contrary, the Pd@Ni7&#8211;Co3 system presents the highest mass activity (&gt;2000 mA mg&#8211;1) at 0.7 V, exceeding by several times that of commercial Pt/C (&gt;300 mA mg&#8211;1) at the same potential. Our study opens the gateway for applications of bimetallic transition metal nanowires in catalytic conversion and energy production processes.</description>
      <author>Dariusz &#321;ukowiec, Magdalena Gw&#243;&#378;d&#378;, Alina Brz&#281;czek&#8208;Szafran, Tomasz Wasiak, Dawid Janas, Jerzy Kubacki, Stanis&#322;aw Wac&#322;awek, Adrian Rado&#324;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into Mo Cluster Modified Fe5C2 Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108839</link>
      <description>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Jinhong Bi, Rongjian Sa, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393928748

                The pursuit of green ammonia synthesis via electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction (NRR) faces challenges in developing high-performance, selective electrocatalysts. Inspired by the nitrogenase Fe-Mo cofactor, this study explores the catalytic efficiency of Mo clusters anchored on Fe5C2 for NRR. We investigate structural stability, N2 adsorption, and Gibbs free energy, revealing that Mon clusters on Fe5C2 demonstrate robust NRR selectivity and notable catalytic activity. Each of the three cluster structures demonstrated superior adsorption capacity in the "side-on" configuration. Among the studied cluster configurations, the Mo5-Fe5C2 shows the lowest limiting potential (-0.24 V), and the Mo4-Fe5C2 exhibits heightened selectivity for NRR, minimizing interference from the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This enhanced performance is attributed to the unique structure and interactive dynamics of Mon-Fe5C2 and the electron orbital interactions facilitating direct nitrogen charge transfer. Our findings underscore the potential of Mo cluster-modified Fe5C2 as a pioneering catalyst for electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction.</description>
      <author>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Jinhong Bi, Rongjian Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; through the Phase Transition&#8208;Mediated Hydrogen Spillover to Outperform Pt for Electrocatalytic pH&#8208;Universal Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400783</link>
      <description>Jiexian Liu, Peifang Guo, Da Li, Xiaoxiao Yan, Xin Tu, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393931341

                Abstract Endowing conventional materials with specific functions that are hardly available is invariably of significant importance but greatly challenging. TiO 2 is proven to be highly active for the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution while intrinsically inert for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to its poor electrical conductivity and unfavorable hydrogen adsorption/desorption behavior. Herein, the first activation of inert TiO 2 for electrocatalytic HER is demonstrated by synergistically modulating the positions of d&#8208;band center and triggering hydrogen spillover through the dual doping&#8208;induced partial phase transition. The N, F co&#8208;doping&#8208;induced partial phase transition from anatase to rutile phase in TiO 2 (AR&#8208;TiO 2 |(N,F)) exhibits extraordinary HER performance with overpotentials of 74, 80, and 142 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH, 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 , and 1.0 M phosphate&#8208;buffered saline electrolytes, respectively, which are substantially better than pure TiO 2 , and even superior to the benchmark Pt/C catalysts. These findings may open a new avenue for the development of low&#8208;cost alternative to noble metal catalysts for electrocatalytic hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Jiexian Liu, Peifang Guo, Da Li, Xiaoxiao Yan, Xin Tu, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational studies on Mg ion conductivity in Mg2xHf1-x Nb(PO4)3 using neural network potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05862-1</link>
      <description>Keisuke Makino, Naoto Tanibata, Hiromasa Takeda, Masanobu Nakayama, Journal of solid state electrochemistry (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393935368

                Abstract Low Mg diffusivity in solid-state oxides is an obstacle for the development of materials for Mg ion batteries, which are expected to have high capacity. In this study, we focused on NASICON-type and &#946;-iron sulfate-type Mg 2x Hf 1-x Nb(PO 4 ) 3 that exhibit relatively high Mg ionic conductivity and investigated the Hf/Nb configuration and composition dependence of phase stability and ion conductivity by atomistic simulation using neural network potentials. The calculations show that the NASICON-type structure is slightly more stable and has higher Mg ionic conductivity than that of the &#946;-iron sulfate-type. The effect of the Hf/Nb configuration was investigated and showed that the ordered stable structure had much lower ionic conductivity than the disordered structure. Furthermore, as the Mg ion concentration increased, the ionic conductivity increased monotonically at low concentrations but tended to converge to a constant value above a certain concentration. The saturation of the ionic conductivity despite increasing the Mg concentration may be due to the trapping effect of the Mg ions caused by the Hf vacancies as well as the Hf/Nb arrangement. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Keisuke Makino, Naoto Tanibata, Hiromasa Takeda, Masanobu Nakayama</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05862-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Engineering of Unconventional Crystal-Phase Noble Metal Nanocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29071617</link>
      <description>Jie Wang, Yidong Jiang, Sixuan Chen, Qinyong Zhang, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393944761

                The crystal phase, alongside the composition, morphology, architecture, facet, size, and dimensionality, has been recognized as a critical factor influencing the properties of noble metal nanomaterials in various applications. In particular, unconventional crystal phases can potentially enable fascinating properties in noble metal nanomaterials. Recent years have witnessed notable advances in the phase engineering of nanomaterials (PEN). Within the accessible strategies for phase engineering, the effect of strain cannot be ignored because strain can act not only as the driving force of phase transition but also as the origin of the diverse physicochemical properties of the unconventional crystal phase. In this review, we highlight the development of unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanomaterials within strain engineering. We begin with a short introduction of the unconventional crystal phase and strain effect in noble metal nanomaterials. Next, the correlations of the structure and performance of strain-engineered unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanomaterials in electrocatalysis are highlighted, as well as the phase transitions of noble metal nanomaterials induced by the strain effect. Lastly, the challenges and opportunities within this rapidly developing field (i.e., the strain engineering of unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanocatalysts) are discussed.</description>
      <author>Jie Wang, Yidong Jiang, Sixuan Chen, Qinyong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29071617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading biomass derived furan aldehydes by coupled electrochemical conversion over silver-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151001</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Dai, Xi Lu, Nan Li, Yichen Zhang, Xuebing Zhao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393944922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Dai, Xi Lu, Nan Li, Yichen Zhang, Xuebing Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction on IrO2(110) is governed by Walden-type mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4101847/v1</link>
      <description>Kai S. Exner, Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393945519

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key process for sustainable energy, although renewable sources require the use of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers, with IrO 2 -based materials being the gold standard due to their high activity and stability under dynamic anodic polarization conditions. However, even for the (110) facet of a single-crystalline IrO 2 model electrode, the reaction mechanism is not settled yet due to contradictory reports in literature. In the present manuscript, we disentangle the conflicting results of previous theoretical studies in the density functional theory approximation. We demonstrate that dissimilar reaction mechanisms and limiting steps for the OER over IrO 2 (110) are obtained for different active surface configurations present on the IrO 2 electrode. In contrast to previous studies, we factor Walden-type mechanisms, in which the formation of the product O 2 and adsorption of the reactant H 2 O occur simultaneously, into the analysis of the elementary steps. Combining free-energy diagrams along the reaction coordinate and Bader charge analysis of the active site under constant potential, we elucidate why mononuclear- or bifunctional-Walden pathways excel the traditional OER mechanisms for the OER over IrO 2 (110). Our computational methodology to identify the reaction mechanism and limiting step of proton-coupled electron transfer steps is universally applicable to electrochemical processes in the field of energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Kai S. Exner, Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4101847/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-dependent activities in interpreting the reaction mechanism of dual-metal atom catalysts for Li-CO2 batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.022</link>
      <description>Xiaolin Liu, Meng-Jun Zhou, Xiaobin Liao, Yan Zhao, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393971031

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaolin Liu, Meng-Jun Zhou, Xiaobin Liao, Yan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the potential Ru-based catalysts for commercial-scale polymer electrolyte membrane water electrolysis: A systematic review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101294</link>
      <description>Shaoxiong Li, Sheng Zhao, Feng Hu, Linlin Li, Jianwei Ren, Lifang Jiao, Seeram Ramakrishna, Shengjie Peng, Progress in Materials Science/Progress in materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393971265

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaoxiong Li, Sheng Zhao, Feng Hu, Linlin Li, Jianwei Ren, Lifang Jiao, Seeram Ramakrishna, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;Ab initio&lt;/i&gt; calculations of the chemisorption of atomic H and O on Pt and Ir metal and on bimetallic Pt&lt;sub&gt; &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;Ir&lt;sub&gt; &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/sub&gt; surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/znb-2023-0087</link>
      <description>Tobias Wittemann, Halil &#304;brahim S&#246;zen, Mehtap Oezaslan, Thorsten Kl&#252;ner, Zeitschrift f&#252;r Naturforschung B. 79(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393973736

                Abstract Understanding the chemisorption of atoms on precious metal surfaces is of substantial interest for the rational design of heterogeneous and electrochemical catalysts. In this study, we report density functional theory (DFT) investigations of the chemisorption of atomic H and O on bimetallic Pt x Ir y (111) surfaces for bifunctional anode catalyst materials in polymer electrolyte membrane (PEM) fuel cells. We found that for both adsorbates, the adsorption on the Pt(111) surface is in general less exothermic than on the Ir(111) surface. Our study has revealed that chemisorption on the bimetallic surfaces becomes more stable with increasing number of Ir surface atoms at the adsorption site. While for hydrogen atoms the ONTOP sites yield the most negative adsorption energies, the chemisorption of oxygen atoms appears to be most stable on the FCC sites for both the mono- and bimetallic surfaces. Using the ab initio thermodynamics approach, we calculated phase diagrams for the chemisorption of H and O atoms on these metal surfaces in order to transfer our findings to finite temperature and pressure conditions. Our theoretical results may provide an improved understanding of the hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on intermetallic Pt x Ir y (111) surfaces and may be helpful for the rational design of new bifunctional PEM fuel cell anode catalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Tobias Wittemann, Halil &#304;brahim S&#246;zen, Mehtap Oezaslan, Thorsten Kl&#252;ner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/znb-2023-0087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomolecular dynamics with machine-learned quantum-mechanical force fields trained on diverse chemical fragments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adn4397</link>
      <description>Oliver T. Unke, Martin St&#246;hr, Stefan Ganscha, Thomas Unterthiner, Hartmut Maennel, Sergii Kashubin, Daniel Ahlin, Michael Gastegger, Leonardo Medrano Sandonas, Joshua T. Berryman, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Klaus-Robert M&#252;ller, Science advances. 10(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393973933

                The GEMS method enables molecular dynamics simulations of large heterogeneous systems at ab initio quality.</description>
      <author>Oliver T. Unke, Martin St&#246;hr, Stefan Ganscha, Thomas Unterthiner, Hartmut Maennel, Sergii Kashubin, Daniel Ahlin, Michael Gastegger, Leonardo Medrano Sandonas, Joshua T. Berryman, Alexandre Tkatchenko, Klaus-Robert M&#252;ller</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adn4397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composite Materials with Nanoscale Multilayer Architecture Based on Cathodic-Arc Evaporated WN/NbN Coatings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10242</link>
      <description>Kateryna Smyrnova, Miroslav Sahul, Mari&#225;n Har&#353;&#225;ni, &#1042;. &#1052;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1089;&#1085;&#1077;&#1074;, Martin Truchl&#253;, &#317;ubom&#237;r &#268;aplovi&#269;, M&#225;ria &#268;aplovi&#269;ov&#225;, Martin Kus&#253;, A.O. Kozak, Dominik Flock, Alexey Kassymbaev, A.D. Pogrebnjak, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393976383

                Hard nitride coatings are commonly employed to protect components subjected to friction, whereby such coatings should possess excellent tribomechanical properties in order to endure high stresses and temperatures. In this study, WN/NbN coatings are synthesized by using the cathodic-arc evaporation (CA-PVD) technique at various negative bias voltages in the 50&#8211;200 V range. The phase composition, microstructural features, and tribomechanical properties of the multilayers are comprehensively studied. Fabricated coatings have a complex structure of three nanocrystalline phases: &#946;-W2N, &#948;-NbN, and &#949;-NbN. They demonstrate a tendency for (111)-oriented grains to overgrow (200)-oriented grains with increasing coating thickness. All of the data show that a decrease in the fraction of &#949;-NbN phase and formation of the (111)-textured grains positively impact mechanical properties and wear behavior. Investigation of the room-temperature tribological properties reveals that with an increase in bias voltage from &#8722;50 to &#8722;200 V, the wear mechanisms change as follows: oxidative &#8594; fatigue and oxidative &#8594; adhesive and oxidative. Furthermore, WN/NbN coatings demonstrate a high hardness of 33.6&#8211;36.6 GPa and a low specific wear rate of (1.9&#8211;4.1) &#215; 10&#8211;6 mm3/Nm. These results indicate that synthesized multilayers hold promise for tribological applications as wear-resistant coatings.</description>
      <author>Kateryna Smyrnova, Miroslav Sahul, Mari&#225;n Har&#353;&#225;ni, &#1042;. &#1052;. &#1041;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1089;&#1085;&#1077;&#1074;, Martin Truchl&#253;, &#317;ubom&#237;r &#268;aplovi&#269;, M&#225;ria &#268;aplovi&#269;ov&#225;, Martin Kus&#253;, A.O. Kozak, Dominik Flock, Alexey Kassymbaev, A.D. Pogrebnjak</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Reduction of Co 2 to Ethanol Over Si/Cu(111) Surface: An Insights from the First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4784997</link>
      <description>Chang Liu, Dan Wang, Boting Yang, Song Jiang, Gang Sun, Yong&#8208;Qing Qiu, Chun&#8208;Guang Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393979607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang Liu, Dan Wang, Boting Yang, Song Jiang, Gang Sun, Yong&#8208;Qing Qiu, Chun&#8208;Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4784997</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradient OH Desorption Facilitating Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Over Ultrafine Quinary Nanoalloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400777</link>
      <description>Hao Ren, Zhihao Zhang, Zhimin Geng, Zhe Wang, Fengyi Shen, Xinhu Liang, Zengjian Cai, Yufang Wang, Dan Cheng, Yanan Cao, Xiaoxin Yang, Mingzhen Hu, Xia Yao, Kebin Zhou, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393991736

                Abstract Strengthening OH adsorption on electrocatalyst is crucial to promote the rate&#8208;determining water dissociation step of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), whereas too&#8208;intensified OH adsorption will poison the active sites instead. This dilemma remains one of the major challenges for improving the electrocatalysts&#8217; alkaline HER activities. Herein, a surprising finding that the strongly adsorbed OH on an ultrafine quinary PtCoCuNiZn nanoalloy can be facilely desorbed via a unique gradient OH desorption pattern is reported, which tremendously boosts its alkaline HER activity. Theoretical simulations unravel that the ultrafine PtCoCuNiZn nanoalloy possesses versatile metal sites for adsorbing OH and the strongly adsorbed OH can be gradiently transferred to desorb from the ultrafine PtCoCuNiZn nanoalloy with moderate energy barriers for each transfer step that is the gradient OH desorption. In the meanwhile, the unique gradient OH desorption mode on the ultrafine PtCoCuNiZn nanoalloy is also experimentally evidenced by the in situ Raman spectroscopy and cyclic voltammetry measurements. This finding offers a fresh opportunity to expedite the alkaline HER without compromising the OH adsorption strength on electrocatalysts, which thus maximally promotes their water dissociation properties and unlocks the full potential of their alkaline HER activities.</description>
      <author>Hao Ren, Zhihao Zhang, Zhimin Geng, Zhe Wang, Fengyi Shen, Xinhu Liang, Zengjian Cai, Yufang Wang, Dan Cheng, Yanan Cao, Xiaoxin Yang, Mingzhen Hu, Xia Yao, Kebin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress on Computation&#8208;Guided Catalyst Design for Highly Efficient Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400773</link>
      <description>Tianyi Dai, Tong&#8208;Hui Wang, Zi Wen, Q. Jiang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393993179

                Abstract Electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) for ammonia synthesis has attracted great interest in recent years, which presents a carbon&#8208;free alternative to the energy&#8208;intensive Haber&#8211;Bosch process. Besides, NRR also provides a promising coverage route of renewable energy since NH 3 is considered the second generation of hydrogen energy while possessing established technologies of liquefaction, storage, and transport. However, there are long&#8208;term challenges in catalyst design for NRR due to its low intrinsic activity and unsatisfied selectivity. Fortunately, by conducting extensive explorations in this field, much progress is achieved in boosting the NRR performance. Herein, from a view of the atomic/electronic level, three promotion effects are summarized for NRR (i.e., electron effect, geometry effect, and ligand effect), which tackle the challenges of activity and selectivity. Representative studies with taking fully advantages of the promotion effects are reviewed, which realized remarkable NRR performance. Finally, the future research directions and prospects are discussed. It is highly expected that this review will enable the advancement of NRR catalysts and promote the further development of electrochemical NRR.</description>
      <author>Tianyi Dai, Tong&#8208;Hui Wang, Zi Wen, Q. Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ammonolysis&#8208;Driven Exsolution of Ru Nanoparticle Embedded in Conductive Metal Nitride Matrix to Boost Electrocatalyst Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202309819</link>
      <description>So Yeon Yun, Sangseob Lee, Jin X, Aloysius Soon, Seong&#8208;Ju Hwang, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394008309

                Abstract Exsolution is an effective method for synthesizing robust nanostructured metal&#8208;based functional materials. However, no studies have investigated the exsolution of metal nanoparticles into metal nitride substrates. In this study, a versatile nitridation&#8208;driven exsolution method is developed for embedding catalytically active metal nanoparticles in conductive metal nitride substrates via the ammonolysis of multimetallic oxides. Using this approach, Ti 1&#8722;x Ru x O 2 nanowires are phase&#8208;transformed into holey TiN nanotubes embedded with exsolved Ru nanoparticles. These Ru&#8208;exsolved holey TiN nanotubes exhibit outstanding electrocatalytic activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction with excellent durability, which is significantly higher than that of Ru&#8208;deposited TiN nanotubes. The enhanced stability of the Ru&#8208;exsolved TiN nanotubes can be attributed to the Ru nanoparticles embedded in the robust metal nitride matrix and the formation of interfacial Ti 3+ &#9472;N&#9472;Ru 4+ bonds. Density functional theory calculations reveal that the exsolved Ru nanoparticles have a lower d &#8208;band center position and optimized hydrogen affinity than deposited Ru nanoparticles, indicating the superior electrocatalyst performance of the former. In situ Raman spectroscopic analysis reveals that the electron transfer from TiN to Ru nanoparticles is enhanced during the electrocatalytic process. The proposed approach opens a new avenue for stabilizing diverse metal nanostructures in many conductive matrices like metal phosphides and chalcogenides.</description>
      <author>So Yeon Yun, Sangseob Lee, Jin X, Aloysius Soon, Seong&#8208;Ju Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202309819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-modified nanoparticle surfaces influence CO electroreduction selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47319-z</link>
      <description>Erfan Shirzadi, Jin Qiu, Ali Shayesteh Zeraati, Roham Dorakhan, Tiago J. Goncalves, Jehad Abed, Byoung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Armin Sedighian Rasouli, Joshua Wicks, Jinqiang Zhang, Pengfei Ou, Victor Boureau, Sungjin Park, Weiyan Ni, Geonhui Lee, Cong Tian, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, David Sinton, Samira Siahrostami, Edward H. Sargent, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394009681

                Abstract Improving the kinetics and selectivity of CO 2 /CO electroreduction to valuable multi-carbon products is a challenge for science and is a requirement for practical relevance. Here we develop a thiol-modified surface ligand strategy that promotes electrochemical CO-to-acetate. We explore a picture wherein nucleophilic interaction between the lone pairs of sulfur and the empty orbitals of reaction intermediates contributes to making the acetate pathway more energetically accessible. Density functional theory calculations and Raman spectroscopy suggest a mechanism where the nucleophilic interaction increases the sp 2 hybridization of CO (ad) , facilitating the rate-determining step, CO* to (CHO)*. We find that the ligands stabilize the (HOOC&#8211;CH 2 )* intermediate, a key intermediate in the acetate pathway. In-situ Raman spectroscopy shows shifts in C&#8211;O, Cu&#8211;C, and C&#8211;S vibrational frequencies that agree with a picture of surface ligand-intermediate interactions. A Faradaic efficiency of 70% is obtained on optimized thiol-capped Cu catalysts, with onset potentials 100 mV lower than in the case of reference Cu catalysts.</description>
      <author>Erfan Shirzadi, Jin Qiu, Ali Shayesteh Zeraati, Roham Dorakhan, Tiago J. Goncalves, Jehad Abed, Byoung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Armin Sedighian Rasouli, Joshua Wicks, Jinqiang Zhang, Pengfei Ou, Victor Boureau, Sungjin Park, Weiyan Ni, Geonhui Lee, Cong Tian, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, David Sinton, Samira Siahrostami, Edward H. Sargent</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47319-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytically Active Carbon for Oxygen Reduction Reaction in Energy Conversion: Recent Advances and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202308040</link>
      <description>Shilin Liu, Ao Wang, Yanyan Liu, Wenshu Zhou, Hao Wen, Huanhuan Zhang, Kang Sun, Shu-Qi Li, Jingjing Zhou, Yongfeng Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Baojun Li, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394011690

                Abstract The shortage and unevenness of fossil energy sources are affecting the development and progress of human civilization. The technology of efficiently converting material resources into energy for utilization and storage is attracting the attention of researchers. Environmentally friendly biomass materials are a treasure to drive the development of new&#8208;generation energy sources. Electrochemical theory is used to efficiently convert the chemical energy of chemical substances into electrical energy. In recent years, significant progress has been made in the development of green and economical electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Although many reviews have been reported around the application of biomass&#8208;derived catalytically active carbon (CAC) catalysts in ORR, these reviews have only selected a single/partial topic (including synthesis and preparation of catalysts from different sources, structural optimization, or performance enhancement methods based on CAC catalysts, and application of biomass&#8208;derived CACs) for discussion. There is no review that systematically addresses the latest progress in the synthesis, performance enhancement, and applications related to biomass&#8208;derived CAC&#8208;based oxygen reduction electrocatalysts synchronously. This review fills the gap by providing a timely and comprehensive review and summary from the following sections: the exposition of the basic catalytic principles of ORR, the summary of the chemical composition and structural properties of various types of biomass, the analysis of traditional and the latest popular biomass&#8208;derived CAC synthesis methods and optimization strategies, and the summary of the practical applications of biomass&#8208;derived CAC&#8208;based oxidative reduction electrocatalysts. This review provides a comprehensive summary of the latest advances to provide research directions and design ideas for the development of catalyst synthesis/optimization and contributes to the industrialization of biomass&#8208;derived CAC electrocatalysis and electric energy storage.</description>
      <author>Shilin Liu, Ao Wang, Yanyan Liu, Wenshu Zhou, Hao Wen, Huanhuan Zhang, Kang Sun, Shu-Qi Li, Jingjing Zhou, Yongfeng Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Baojun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202308040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Symmetry: Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Performance of Janus Zr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;COT (T = F, Cl, Br, I) MXenes by Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00812</link>
      <description>Jisong Hu, Moshang Fan, Rui Zhang, Xiao Ji, Ling Miao, Jianjun Jiang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394015209

                This investigation highlights the significant impact of asymmetric Janus Zr2COT (T = F, Cl, Br, I) monolayers on enhancing the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance. Employing density functional theory (DFT), our research demonstrates that introducing asymmetric functional groups into Zr2COT structures effectively tailors their electronic properties, leading to a marked improvement in HER activity. This structural innovation notably reduces the hydrogen adsorption Gibbs free energy (&#916;GH*) from 0.877 eV for the symmetric Zr2CO2 to below 0.2 eV for the Janus Zr2COT configurations, with Zr2COBr and Zr2COI achieving exceptionally low &#916;GH* values of 0.045 and &#8722;0.042 eV, respectively, at a hydrogen coverage of 1/4. The monolayers also exhibit remarkable thermal stability and superior electrical conductivity, vital for high-efficiency electrocatalysis. Furthermore, strain engineering underscores the durability of these materials, maintaining &#916;GH* values within &#177;0.2 eV under extensive tensile strain and emphasizing their practical application potential. Crucially, this work uncovers the critical role of electronic structure adjustments in optimizing the HER performance, aligning with the Sabatier principle, and offering fresh perspectives for designing effective, cost-efficient electrocatalysts. In a word, Janus Zr2COT monolayers emerge as promising candidates, challenging traditional noble metal catalysts and paving the way for the development of sustainable electrocatalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Jisong Hu, Moshang Fan, Rui Zhang, Xiao Ji, Ling Miao, Jianjun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal-based chalcogenides as electrocatalysts for overall water splitting in hydrogen energy production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.275</link>
      <description>Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Hadi M. Marwani, Jehan Y. Al&#8208;Humaidi, S. Rehman, Raed H. Althomali, Mohammed M. Rahman, International journal of hydrogen energy. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394019055

                The main and significant element in the energy system is hydrogen atom. In addition, electrochemical water splitting is among the most crucial approaches for displacing the extensively utilized petroleum and petroleum products. It is crucial to look for effective electro-catalysts to split the water molecule to produce hydrogen. Because of their good conductivity, distinctive outer shell electronic distribution, and various superficial structural nano-morphology, transition metal chalcogenides are very attractive as effective electrocatalysts for hydrogen production. Currently synthesized transition metal-built chalcogens (containing Sulfur, Selenium, and Tellurium) as efficient catalysts for general splitting of target water using hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), have been discussed in this review.</description>
      <author>Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Hadi M. Marwani, Jehan Y. Al&#8208;Humaidi, S. Rehman, Raed H. Althomali, Mohammed M. Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction and Synthesis of Nonmetal-Doped Anatase TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (101) for Boosting Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01047</link>
      <description>Nan Yang, Ying Zhao, Tianwei He, Ke Wang, Zhongbao Luo, Hongshun Zheng, Yuandong Shen, Alain R. Puente Santiago, Tong Zhou, Wei Zhan, Jin Zhang, Genlin Zhang, Qingju Liu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394063838

                TiO2-based photocatalysts are eco-friendly, cost-effective, and stable but only exert catalytic performance in the ultraviolet region, and the photocatalytic efficiency is very low. In this work, we employ DFT calculations to deeply investigate the effect of nonmetallic C-doped TiO2 (101) on the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution performance. Specifically, the effects of C substitution or interstitial doping at the surface, subsurface, and bulk on the electronic structure, optical properties, and catalytic hydrogen evolution activity were substantially investigated. We discovered that different C atom doping strategies impinge different effects on the catalytic activity. Among them, the CO-bulk4, CTi-surf2, and Cinter-surf systems showed superior catalytic activities with &#916;G of &#8722;0.012, &#8722;0.055, and &#8722;0.024 eV, respectively. The C atom replaces the Ti atom and alters the original coordination environment, which leads to charge redistribution and consequently to the activation of the O sites. Additionally, carbon-self-doped TiO2 photocatalysts were fabricated using an experimental hydrothermal synthesis, and the XPS analyses confirmed that O is replaced by C. In addition, the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution rate is 0.3 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1, while there is no hydrogen evolution for pure TiO2. Our findings suggest that nonmetallic doped TiO2(101) photocatalysts can improve light absorption, modulate charge distribution, and enhance hydrogen evolution activity.</description>
      <author>Nan Yang, Ying Zhao, Tianwei He, Ke Wang, Zhongbao Luo, Hongshun Zheng, Yuandong Shen, Alain R. Puente Santiago, Tong Zhou, Wei Zhan, Jin Zhang, Genlin Zhang, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Mechanism of the Electrochemical Polymerization of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Hard Carbon over CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08356</link>
      <description>Florian Keller, Johannes D&#246;hn, Axel Gro&#223;, Michael Busch, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566077

                Conversion of CO2 to hard carbon is an interesting technology for the removal of carbon dioxide from the atmosphere. Recently, it was shown that CeO2 can selectively catalyze this reaction, but we still lack information regarding the reaction mechanism. Using density functional theory modeling, we explore possible reaction mechanisms that allow for the polymerization of CO2. According to our computations, the reaction is initialized by the adsorption of CO2 in an oxygen vacancy. Owing to the rich defect chemistry of ceria, a large number of suitable sites are available at the surface. C&#8211;C bond formation is achieved through an aldol condensation-type mechanism which comprises the electrochemical elimination of water to form a carbene. This carbene then performs a nucleophilic attack on CO2. The reaction mechanism possesses significant similarities to the corresponding reactions in synthetic organic chemistry. Since the mechanism is completely generic, it allows for all relevant steps of the formation of hard carbon like chain growth, chain linkage, and the formation of side chains or aromatic rings. Surprisingly, ceria mainly serves as an anchor for CO2 in an oxygen vacancy, while all other subsequent reaction steps are almost completely independent from the catalyst. These insights are important for the development of novel catalysts for CO2 reduction and may also lead to new reactions for the electrosynthesis of organic molecules.</description>
      <author>Florian Keller, Johannes D&#246;hn, Axel Gro&#223;, Michael Busch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-induced long-range surface strain improves oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115484</link>
      <description>Mailde S. Oz&#243;rio, Marie Berg Nygaard, Amanda Schramm Petersen, R. J&#252;rgen Behm, Jan Rossmeisl, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566426

                For decades, it has been recognized that alloying platinum (Pt) with a secondary metal can enhance the catalytic activity of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) compared to pristine Pt catalysts. However, the mechanisms underlying this phenomenon vary significantly from one alloy to another. Here, we report the results of a computational study on the origin of the experimentally observed enhanced ORR activity of AgxPt1-x/Pt(1 1 1) monolayer surface alloy with 7 %-50 % Ag contents. A phase-separation model was developed and able to generate 2D phase-separation distributions of Ag and Pt atoms in AgxPt1-x/Pt(1 1 1) surfaces in line with atomic resolution scanning tunneling microscopy. We employed DFT-calculated *OH adsorption energy as a descriptor to obtain the activity of those surfaces, which reveals the ORR activity dominated by the reaction on Pt(Pt6) heptamers and also gives evidence of long-range self-induced surface strain as the source of the enhanced activity of binary AgxPt1-x/Pt(1 1 1) surfaces, i.e., the slightly larger surface Ag atoms induce a compressive strain of Pt-Pt bonds of the Pt(Pt6) heptamers, which increases the activity of binary surfaces compared to the pristine Pt(1 1 1) surface. Moreover, the excellent simulated-experimental agreement for the polarization curves shows the high quality of this approach and its more general potential for an improved understanding of the catalytic properties of inhomogeneous binary surfaces as the basis for a rational design of binary catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mailde S. Oz&#243;rio, Marie Berg Nygaard, Amanda Schramm Petersen, R. J&#252;rgen Behm, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant In-Plane Flexoelectricity and Radial Polarization in Janus IV&#8211;VI Monolayers and Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01527</link>
      <description>Kai Zheng, Tejs Vegge, Ivano E. Castelli, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Zheng, Tejs Vegge, Ivano E. Castelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Promotion of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Programmable Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00365</link>
      <description>Sallye R. Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar A. Abdelrahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394568896

                Hydrogen gas is a promising renewable energy storage medium when produced via water electrolysis, but this process is limited by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we used a microkinetic model to investigate promoting the OER using programmable oxide catalysts (i.e., forced catalyst dynamics). We found that programmable catalysts could increase current density at a fixed overpotential (100&#8211;600&#215; over static rates) or reduce the overpotential required to reach a fixed current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 (45&#8211;140% reduction vs static). In our kinetic parametrization, the key parameters controlling the quality of the catalytic ratchet were the O*-to-OOH* and O*-to-OH* activation barriers. Our findings indicate that programmable catalysts may be a viable strategy for accelerating the OER or enabling lower-overpotential operation, but a more accurate kinetic parametrization is required for precise predictions of performance, ratchet quality, and resulting energy efficiency.</description>
      <author>Sallye R. Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar A. Abdelrahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Efficiency Iridium&#8208;Yttrium Alloy Catalyst for Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304479</link>
      <description>Xiang Xiong, Jialin Tang, Jian Yuan, Weiqing Xue, Haoyuan Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Hongliang Zeng, Yizhou Dai, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Xinyan Li, Qiu Jiang, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394572023

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis holds great promise in revolutionizing clean energy production by enabling the efficient generation of hydrogen. Nevertheless, a formidable challenge persists in the realm of designing electrocatalysts that are both highly active and acid&#8208;resistant during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), thereby mitigating the substantial kinetic barrier. In this study, the facile synthesis of iridium&#8208;yttrium (IrY) alloy nanocatalysts via a thermal shock method is introduced, which exhibits exceptional activity in the context of acidic water oxidation. Through the strategic incorporation of dispersed Y into the lattice of Ir metal, the IrY catalyst demonstrates a notably low overpotential of 255 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and showcases remarkable catalytic stability in acidic electrolytes, enduring for over 500 h with a high current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Through a comprehensive set of in situ characterizations and analytical methods, the formation of a surface Ir&#8208;based oxide layer, induced by deprotonation and electrochemical oxidation is unveiled, which is notably stabilized by the presence of Y dopants. This stabilization of the active site imparts enhanced resistance to over&#8208;oxidation and dissolution, underpinning the exceptional stability of the catalyst. Theoretical calculations suggest that the incorporation of Y into the catalyst structure has a significant impact on enhancing the reactivity of the oxygen intermediate (O*) at adjacent Ir sites, thus lowering the overpotential and promoting OER activity. The alloying approach presents a straightforward method for achieving atomic&#8208;level modifications in catalyst design and can pave the way for the development of more effective and economically viable OER catalysts and beyond.</description>
      <author>Xiang Xiong, Jialin Tang, Jian Yuan, Weiqing Xue, Haoyuan Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Hongliang Zeng, Yizhou Dai, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Xinyan Li, Qiu Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Efficiency of Water Splitting and Oxygen Reduction Via &lt;scp&gt;Single&#8208;Atom&lt;/scp&gt; Anchoring on Graphyne Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12723</link>
      <description>Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Beenish Bashir, Khan Muhammad Ajmal, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394573820

                Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have received significant interest for optimizing metal atom utilization and superior catalytic performance in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we investigate a range of single&#8208;transition metal (STM 1 = Sc 1 , Ti 1 , V 1 , Cr 1 , Mn 1 , Fe 1 , Co 1 , Ni 1 , Cu 1 , Zr 1 , Nb 1 , Mo 1 , Ru 1 , Rh 1 , Pd 1 , Ag 1 , W 1 , Re 1 , Os 1 , Ir 1 , Pt 1 , and Au 1 ) atoms supported on graphyne (GY) surface for HER/OER and ORR using first&#8208;principle calculations. Ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations and phonon dispersion spectra reveal the dynamic and thermal stabilities of the GY surface. The exceptional stability of all supported STM 1 atoms within the H1 cavity of the GY surface exists in an isolated form, facilitating the uniform distribution and proper arrangement of single atoms on GY. In particular, Sc 1 , Co 1 , Fe 1 , and Au 1 /GY demonstrate promising catalytic efficiency in the HER due to idealistic &#916;G H* values via the Volmer&#8208;Heyrovsky pathway. Notably, Sc 1 and Au 1 /GY exhibit superior HER catalytic activity compared to other studied catalysts. Co 1 /GY catalyst exhibits higher selectivity and activity for the OER, with an overpotential (0.46 V) comparable to MoC 2 , IrO 2 , and RuO 2 . Also, Rh 1 and Co 1 /GY SACs exhibited promising electrocatalysts for the ORR, with an overpotential of 0.36 and 0.46 V, respectively. Therefore, Co 1 /GY is a versatile electrocatalyst for metal&#8208;air batteries and water&#8208;splitting. This study further incorporates computational analysis of the kinetic potential energy barriers of Co 1 and Rh 1 in the OER and ORR. A strong correlation is found between the estimated kinetic activation barriers for the thermodynamic outcomes and all proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer steps. We establish a relation for the Gibbs free energy of intermediates to understand the mechanism of SACs supported on STM 1 /GY and introduce a key descriptor. This study highlights GY as a favorable single&#8208;atom support for designing highly active and cost&#8208;effective versatile electrocatalysts for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Beenish Bashir, Khan Muhammad Ajmal, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrifying Energy and Chemical Transformations with Single-Atom Alloy Nanoparticle Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00365</link>
      <description>Qiang Gao, Xue Han, Yuanqi Liu, Huiyuan Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394576674

                Single-atom alloys (SAAs) have attracted considerable attention as promising electrocatalysts in reactions central to energy conversion and chemical transformation. In contrast to monometallic nanocrystals and metal alloys, SAAs possess unique and intriguing physicochemical properties, positioning them as ideal model systems for studying structure&#8211;property relationships. However, the field is still in its early stages. In this Perspective, we first review and summarize rational synthesis methods and advanced characterization techniques for SAA nanoparticle catalysts. We then emphasize the extensive applications of SAAs in a range of electrocatalytic reactions, including fuel cell reactions, water splitting, and carbon dioxide and nitrate reductions. Finally, we provide insights into existing challenges and prospects associated with the controlled synthesis, characterization, and design of SAA catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qiang Gao, Xue Han, Yuanqi Liu, Huiyuan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into Dual-Atomic Catalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08289</link>
      <description>Yun Yang, Shixi Liu, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394594221

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yun Yang, Shixi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Insight into the Mechanistic Study of Electrochemical Cyanide Reduction Reaction on Post-Transition Metal Based Single-Atom Catalysts Anchored by Phthalocyanine Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05646</link>
      <description>Kuang-Yen Chiu, Chongzhao Fan, Chih-Wei Hsu, Hui-Lung Chen, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394602283

                As a catalytic center, the 4N-coordinated post-transition metal (PM) confined within phthalocyanine (Pc) shows promise for the environmentally friendly synthesis of CH4 and NH3. A range of PM&#8211;Pc catalysts (where PM represents Al, Ga, In, Tl, Ge, Sn, Pb, and Bi) is methodically evaluated through DFT mechanistic analysis and electrochemical exploration to determine their stability, activity, and selectivity. Our comparative analysis reveals that the orientational specificity of initial cyanide adsorption would play a crucial role in cyanide electroreduction reaction (CNRR) pathways within diverse PM&#8211;Pc nanosheets. Specifically, the NC* model typically requires higher supplies of Gibbs free energy for the CNRR, preponderantly resulting in CH3NH2. Conversely, the counterpart of the CN* model necessitates lower energetic demands, leading to a broader diversity of products including methane and ammonia. Of particular significance that the relationships of limiting potentials (UL) through two types of descriptors, &#916;GNC*&#8594;HNC* and &#916;GCN*&#8594;HCN*, were essential for constructing volcano plots, thus illustrating the relation within the intrinsic adsorption performance of diverse PM&#8211;Pc series and their associated prominent CNRR efficiency. From a comprehensive screening of the studied results, we have determined that the nanosheets Al&#8211;Pc, In&#8211;Pc, Ge&#8211;Pc, and Sn&#8211;Pc (triggered by the CN* model) are the exceptionally proficient electrocatalysts, specifically in producing only CH4 and NH3 via the CNRR process, as indicated by our final compiled findings. Within the range of nanosheets evaluated, the Al&#8211;Pc associated model emerges as a standout, demonstrating markedly higher selectivity and CNRR activity than its counterparts. This study advances the understanding of the unique superior characteristics of SACs, subsequently providing innovative perspectives that could directly guide their discovery for CNRR applications.</description>
      <author>Kuang-Yen Chiu, Chongzhao Fan, Chih-Wei Hsu, Hui-Lung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we talk about when we talk about breaking scaling relations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0192779</link>
      <description>Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Applied physics reviews. 11(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394606253

                For more than a dozen years, &#8220;breaking scaling relations&#8221; has been regarded by many as a top priority in computational and experimental electrocatalysis. Numerous works claim to have done it, and literature reviews are available that summarize the strategies to do it. However, in most cases, it seems more like a slogan than a clear, experimentally realizable catalyst design paradigm. It is worth asking whether we know of any materials that unmistakably break scaling relations and, more importantly, if the breaking of a problematic scaling relation is the end of all troubles in electrocatalysis. On the basis of some quantitative examples related to CO2 electroreduction and the concept of &#8220;ghost scaling relation,&#8221; I will try to address these and other fundamental questions related to scaling relations.</description>
      <author>Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0192779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massively scalable workflows for quantum chemistry: &lt;scp&gt;BigChem&lt;/scp&gt; and &lt;scp&gt;ChemCloud&lt;/scp&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0190834</link>
      <description>Colton B. Hicks, Todd J. Mart&#305;&#769;nez, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394608928

                Electronic structure theory, i.e., quantum chemistry, is the fundamental building block for many problems in computational chemistry. We present a new distributed computing framework (BigChem), which allows for an efficient solution of many quantum chemistry problems in parallel. BigChem is designed to be easily composable and leverages industry-standard middleware (e.g., Celery, RabbitMQ, and Redis) for distributed approaches to large scale problems. BigChem can harness any collection of worker nodes, including ones on cloud providers (such as AWS or Azure), local clusters, or supercomputer centers (and any mixture of these). BigChem builds upon MolSSI packages, such as QCEngine to standardize the operation of numerous computational chemistry programs, demonstrated here with Psi4, xtb, geomeTRIC, and TeraChem. BigChem delivers full utilization of compute resources at scale, offers a programable canvas for designing sophisticated quantum chemistry workflows, and is fault tolerant to node failures and network disruptions. We demonstrate linear scalability of BigChem running computational chemistry workloads on up to 125 GPUs. Finally, we present ChemCloud, a web API to BigChem and successor to TeraChem Cloud. ChemCloud delivers scalable and secure access to BigChem over the Internet.</description>
      <author>Colton B. Hicks, Todd J. Mart&#305;&#769;nez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0190834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversing the Interfacial Electric Field in Metal Phosphide Heterojunction by Fe&#8208;Doping for Large&#8208;Current Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202308477</link>
      <description>Zhong Li, Xu Cheng, Zheye Zhang, Shan Xia, Dongsheng Li, Liren Liu, Peng Chen, Xiaochen Dong, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394615348

                Abstract Developing non&#8208;precious&#8208;metal electrocatalysts that can operate with a low overpotential at a high current density for industrial application is challenging. Heterogeneous bimetallic phosphides have attracted much interest. Despite high hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance, the ordinary oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance hinders their practical use. Herein, it is shown that Fe&#8208;doping reverses and enlarges the interfacial electrical field at the heterojunction, turning the H intermediate favorable binding sites for HER into O intermediate favorable sites for OER. Specifically, the self&#8208;supported heterojunction catalysts on nickel foam (CoP@Ni 2 P/NF and Fe&#8208;CoP@Fe&#8208;Ni 2 P/NF) are readily synthesized. They only require the overpotentials of 266 and 274 mV to drive a large current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 ( j 1000 ) for HER and OER, respectively. Furthermore, a water splitting cell equipped with these electrodes only requires a voltage of 1.724 V to drive j 1000 with excellent durability, demonstrating the potential of industrial application. This work offers new insights on interfacial engineering for heterojunction catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhong Li, Xu Cheng, Zheye Zhang, Shan Xia, Dongsheng Li, Liren Liu, Peng Chen, Xiaochen Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202308477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlation between Electrocatalytic Activity and Impedance Shape: A Theoretical Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/prxenergy.3.023001</link>
      <description>Jun Huang, PRX energy. 3(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394621947

                Toward understanding a relationship between the shapes of electrochemical impedance plots and volcano plots for electrocatalytic activity, a systematic mathematical analysis of electrocatalytic reactions is presented and compared to experimental data.</description>
      <author>Jun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/prxenergy.3.023001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum-Modified Cobalt Oxide/Cobalt Nanotubes as Multifunctional Electrocatalysts in Alkaline and Acidic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c06119</link>
      <description>Julia Mayes, Gesilda Noka, I. G. Dillon, Daniel Ma, Kathryn Kingsbury, Gurpreet Singh, Lukasz Sztaberek, Scott C. McGuire, Stanislaus S. Wong, Christopher Koenigsmann, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394622066

                Nanostructure platinum is an effective catalyst that is active toward a broad range of electrochemical processes over a wide range of pH values. However, its high cost and low abundance prevent its widespread use in practical devices. A promising strategy to overcome the limitations of platinum is to combine platinum with less expensive and more abundant transition metals. In this report, we employ an ambient, template-based approach to prepare monodisperse Co nanotubes (NTs) and modify them with platinum via an electroless deposition process. The composition of the resulting Pt modified Co NTs (Pt-Co NTs) can be varied by controlling the Pt ion concentration in the electroless deposition step. The resulting Pt-Co NTs have a hierarchical structure consisting of Pt-Co NTs coated with an amorphous Co-oxide film. The amorphous Co-oxide coating activates the Pt-Co NTs to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) leading to a 9-fold enhancement in the OER activity in an 80% (by mass) Pt-Co NT relative to pure Pt nanowires. The surface oxide coating can be selectively removed by cycling the Pt-Co NTs in an acidic solution. Removing the oxide film activates the Pt-Co NTs toward methanol oxidation (MOR) and oxygen reduction (ORR) reactions. In both cases, the trends in MOR and ORR activity follow a volcano-type dependence as a function of composition. The catalyst with the optimum composition of 60% Pt has a 4-fold increase in the specific activity for MOR and maintains a +20 mV shift in the half-wave potential for ORR relative to that of pure Pt nanowires.</description>
      <author>Julia Mayes, Gesilda Noka, I. G. Dillon, Daniel Ma, Kathryn Kingsbury, Gurpreet Singh, Lukasz Sztaberek, Scott C. McGuire, Stanislaus S. Wong, Christopher Koenigsmann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c06119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Study of Activated Multi-Walled Carbon Nanotubes on Catalyzing Amine-Based Carbon Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4788676</link>
      <description>Lingling Li, Xin He, Pan Li, Si Chen, Tongtong Wang, Chunxi Hai, Yong Sun, Qian Xu, Shengde Dong, Luxiang Ma, Yuan Zhou, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394627684

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Lingling Li, Xin He, Pan Li, Si Chen, Tongtong Wang, Chunxi Hai, Yong Sun, Qian Xu, Shengde Dong, Luxiang Ma, Yuan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4788676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing lithium-silver alloy phases for enhanced energy density and electrochemical performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</link>
      <description>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu, Next materials. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393925878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
