<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:44:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a 3D Ni-Mn Binary Oxide Anode for Energy-Efficient Electro-Oxidation of Organic Pollutants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112562</link>
      <description>Keyvan Mirehbar, Jaime S. Sanchez, Sergio Pinilla, Freddy E. Oropeza, Ignasi Sir&#233;s, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Jes&#250;s Palma, Julio J. Lado, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. 12(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392974422

                The depletion of clean water resources and the consequent accumulation of contaminants in aquatic systems must be urgently addressed by means of innovative solutions. Electro-oxidation (EO) is considered a promising technology, prized for its versatility and eco-friendliness. However, the excessively high prices and the toxicity associated with some of the materials currently employed for EO impede its broader application. This study introduces cost-effective Ni-Mn binary oxide anodes prepared on Ni foam (NF) substrate. A scalable synthesis route that enables a 35-fold increase in the production of active material through a single optimization step has been devised. The synthesized binary oxide material underwent electrochemical characterization, and its effectiveness was assessed in an electrochemical flow-through cell, benchmarked against single Ni or Mn oxides and more conventional alternatives like boron-doped diamond (BDD) and dimensionally-stable anode (DSA). The novel binary oxide anode demonstrated exceptional performance, achieving complete removal of phenol at very low current density of 5 mA cm-2, along with an 80% of chemical oxygen demand (COD) decay within only 60 min. The NF/NiMnO3 anode outperformed the BDD and DSA when using comparable projected surface areas, owing to its high porosity and ability to produce hydroxyl radicals, as confirmed from the degradation profiles in the presence of radical scavengers. Furthermore, GC/MS analysis served to elucidate the degradation pathways of phenol.</description>
      <author>Keyvan Mirehbar, Jaime S. Sanchez, Sergio Pinilla, Freddy E. Oropeza, Ignasi Sir&#233;s, V&#237;ctor A. de la Pe&#241;a O&#8217;Shea, Jes&#250;s Palma, Julio J. Lado</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin Amorphous NaIrRuOx Nanosheets with Rich Oxygen Vacancies for Efficient Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114660</link>
      <description>Junan Gao, Xiaofeng Wu, Xinying Teng, Xin Jing, Sung Lai Jimmy Yun, Hong Zhao, Jianwei Li, Jie Zhang, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392976595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junan Gao, Xiaofeng Wu, Xinying Teng, Xin Jing, Sung Lai Jimmy Yun, Hong Zhao, Jianwei Li, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal Intercalation/Alloying Hybrid Mechanism with &#8208;ICOHP Criterion in MAX Toward Steadily Ascending Lithium&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400099</link>
      <description>Xueyi Guo, Quan Zhou, Changda Wang, Yong Cao, Xiya Yang, Shiqiang Wei, Wenjie Xu, Shuangming Chen, Kehua Zhu, Pengjun Zhang, Hongwei Shou, Yixiu Wang, Peter Joseph Chimtali, Xiaojun Wu, Song Li, Xiaosong Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392978666

                Abstract Profiting from the unique atomic laminated structure, metallic conductivity, and superior mechanical properties, transition metal carbides and nitrides named MAX phases have shown great potential as anodes in lithium&#8208;ion batteries. However, the complexity of MAX configurations poses a challenge. To accelerate such application, a minus integrated crystal orbital Hamilton populations descriptor is innovatively proposed to rapidly evaluate the lithium storage potential of various MAX, along with density functional theory computations. It confirms that surface A&#8208;element atoms bound to lithium ions have odds of escaping from MAX. Interestingly, the activated A&#8208;element atoms enhance the reversible uptake of lithium ions by MAX anodes through an efficient alloying reaction. As an experimental verification, the charge compensation and Sn x Li y phase evolution of designed Zr 2 SnC MAX with optimized structure is visualized via in situ synchrotron radiation XRD and XAFS technique, which further clarifies the theoretically expected intercalation/alloying hybrid storage mechanism. Notably, Zr 2 SnC electrodes achieve remarkably 219.8% negative capacity attenuation over 3200 cycles at 1 A g &#8722;1 . In principle, this work provides a reference for the design and development of advanced MAX electrodes, which is essential to explore diversified applications of the MAX family in specific energy fields.</description>
      <author>Xueyi Guo, Quan Zhou, Changda Wang, Yong Cao, Xiya Yang, Shiqiang Wei, Wenjie Xu, Shuangming Chen, Kehua Zhu, Pengjun Zhang, Hongwei Shou, Yixiu Wang, Peter Joseph Chimtali, Xiaojun Wu, Song Li, Xiaosong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Effect of Solvent for Hydrogen Evolution in Pt-Doped Mxenes and Corresponding High-Entropy Phase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4762261</link>
      <description>Zheng Shu, Zhangsheng Shi, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Teck Leong Tan, Yongqing Cai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392978980

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Zheng Shu, Zhangsheng Shi, Man&#8208;Fai Ng, Teck Leong Tan, Yongqing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4762261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type Label Framework for Bonded Force Fields in LAMMPS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c08419</link>
      <description>Jacob R. Gissinger, Ilia Nikiforov, Yaser Afshar, Brendon Waters, Moon Han Choi, Daniel S. Karls, Alexander Stukowski, Wonpil Im, Hendrik Heinz, Axel Kohlmeyer, Ellad B. Tadmor, The Journal of Physical Chemistry B. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392987296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jacob R. Gissinger, Ilia Nikiforov, Yaser Afshar, Brendon Waters, Moon Han Choi, Daniel S. Karls, Alexander Stukowski, Wonpil Im, Hendrik Heinz, Axel Kohlmeyer, Ellad B. Tadmor</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c08419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of Stable Surfaces with Extreme Work Functions by High&#8208;Throughput Density Functional Theory and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401764</link>
      <description>Peter Schindler, Evan R. Antoniuk, Gowoon Cheon, Yanbing Zhu, Evan J. Reed, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392991859

                Abstract The work function is the key surface property that determines the energy required to extract an electron from the surface of a material. This property is crucial for thermionic energy conversion, band alignment in heterostructures, and electron emission devices. This work presents a high&#8208;throughput workflow using density functional theory (DFT) to calculate the work function and cleavage energy of 33,631 slabs (58,332 work functions) that are created from 3,716 bulk materials. The number of calculated surface properties surpasses the previously largest database by a factor of &#8776;27. Several surfaces with an ultra&#8208;low (&lt;2 eV) and ultra&#8208;high (&gt;7 eV) work function are identified. Specifically, the (100)&#8208;Ba&#8208;O surface of BaMoO 3 and the (001)&#8208;F surface of Ag 2 F have record&#8208;low (1.25 eV) and record&#8208;high (9.06 eV) steady&#8208;state work functions. Based on this database a physics&#8208;based approach to featurize surfaces is utilized to predict the work function. The random forest model achieves a test mean absolute error (MAE) of 0.09 eV, comparable to the accuracy of DFT. This surrogate model enables rapid predictions of the work function (&#8776; 10 5 faster than DFT) across a vast chemical space and facilitates the discovery of material surfaces with extreme work functions for energy conversion and electronic device applications.</description>
      <author>Peter Schindler, Evan R. Antoniuk, Gowoon Cheon, Yanbing Zhu, Evan J. Reed</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Activity of Trimetallic Oxygen Reduction PtNiMo/C Catalysts Through Initial Conditioning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400070</link>
      <description>Bilal Danisman, Guirong Zhang, Adrian F. Baumunk, Juntao Yang, Olaf Brummel, Philipp Darge, Dominik Dworschak, Karl Johann Jakob Mayrhofer, J&#246;rg Libuda, Xin Zhou, Mingjian Wu, Erdmann Spiecker, Marc Ledendecker, Bastian J. M. Etzold, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392993818

                Abstract This study investigates the importance of preconditioning in Pt&#8208;alloy catalysts for oxygen&#8211;reduction reactions. Previous research indicated that slower scanning rates during preconditioning initially boost activity, but this is followed by a rapid decline. The study reveals the required number of cycles to achieve the first constant steady state activity in PtNiMo/C catalysts when using slower scanning rates during preconditioning. It also highlights the resulting activity differences. Remarkably, a catalyst preconditioned with 150 slow cycles showed an activity of approximately 1.25 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0.90 V RHE , significantly higher than one preconditioned at a fast rate (0.82 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Both ex&#8211;situ and in&#8211;situ analyses revealed that Pt, along with Ni, was leached during pretreatment. At slower scan rates of 20 mV s &#8722;1 , the dissolved Pt redeposited as highly active, small&#8208;sized clusters or single atoms. Fast scan rates of of 500 mV s &#8722;1 , in contrast, resulted in fewer such clusters. Accelerated stress tests up to 1.10 V RHE confirmed the high stability of these clusters, demonstrating a substantial activity increase even after 24,000 cycles.</description>
      <author>Bilal Danisman, Guirong Zhang, Adrian F. Baumunk, Juntao Yang, Olaf Brummel, Philipp Darge, Dominik Dworschak, Karl Johann Jakob Mayrhofer, J&#246;rg Libuda, Xin Zhou, Mingjian Wu, Erdmann Spiecker, Marc Ledendecker, Bastian J. M. Etzold</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Extraction Process During Initial Oxidation of Pt(111): Effect of Hydrophilic/Hydrophobic Cations in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11334</link>
      <description>Tomoaki Kumeda, Kengo Kondo, Syunnosuke Tanaka, Osami Sakata, Nagahiro Hoshi, Masashi Nakamura, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392994699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tomoaki Kumeda, Kengo Kondo, Syunnosuke Tanaka, Osami Sakata, Nagahiro Hoshi, Masashi Nakamura</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Metastability-Triggered Reactivity of Pt&lt;sub&gt;7,8&lt;/sub&gt; Clusters on Graphene: Unraveling Statistical Ensemble Representation for ORR in Gas and Implicit Solvent Phases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00376</link>
      <description>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392999038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Quality and Reliability of Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials through Better Reporting Practices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00028</link>
      <description>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393002362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tristan Maxson, Ademola Soyemi, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Tibor Szilv&#225;si</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity and stability of catalysts for electrocatalytic water splitting in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2727-5</link>
      <description>Zhenbin Wang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393004005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenbin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2727-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Accuracy Matters: Applications of Machine Learned Potential Energy Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03405</link>
      <description>Silvan K&#228;ser, Markus Meuwly, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393025231

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silvan K&#228;ser, Markus Meuwly</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the crucial contribution of additive chromate to efficient and stable alkaline seawater oxidation on Ni-based layered double hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.132</link>
      <description>Lin Yang, Yao Ding, Xueqing Niu, Xinyue Xu, Kaicai Fan, Wen Ye, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Xiaofan Du, Tianrong Zhan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393029507

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lin Yang, Yao Ding, Xueqing Niu, Xinyue Xu, Kaicai Fan, Wen Ye, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Xiaofan Du, Tianrong Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Locating Transition States by Variational Reaction Path Optimization with an Energy-Derivative-Free Objective Function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01246</link>
      <description>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393031108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Machine Learning Model Focusing on Active Sites for the Discovery of Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts in Binary Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17377</link>
      <description>C Y Wang, Bing Wang, Changhao Wang, Zhipeng Chang, Mengqi Yang, Ruzhi Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393039373

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C Y Wang, Bing Wang, Changhao Wang, Zhipeng Chang, Mengqi Yang, Ruzhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converging Divergent Paths: Constant Charge vs Constant Potential Energetics in Computational Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07954</link>
      <description>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Simeon D. Beinlich, Karsten Reuter, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393040617

                Using the example of a proton adsorption process, we analyze and compare two prominent modeling approaches in computational electrochemistry at metallic electrodes&#9472;electronically canonical, constant-charge and electronically grand-canonical, constant-potential calculations. We first confirm that both methodologies yield consistent results for the differential free energy change in the infinite cell size limit. This validation emphasizes that, fundamentally, both methods are equally valid and precise. In practice, the grand-canonical, constant-potential approach shows superior interpretability and size convergence as it aligns closer to experimental ensembles and exhibits smaller finite-size effects. On the other hand, constant-charge calculations exhibit greater resilience against discrepancies, such as deviations in interfacial capacitance and absolute potential alignment, as their results inherently only depend on the surface charge and not on the modeled charge vs potential relation. The present analysis thus offers valuable insights and guidance for selecting the most appropriate ensemble when addressing diverse electrochemical challenges.</description>
      <author>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Simeon D. Beinlich, Karsten Reuter</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Thermodynamic Equivalence of Grand Canonical, Infinite&#8208;Size, and Capacitor&#8208;Based Models in First&#8208;Principle Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202300950</link>
      <description>Georg Kastlunger, Sudarshan Vijay, Xi Chen, Shubham Sharma, Andrew A. Peterson, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393044438

                Abstract First principles&#8208;based computational and theoretical methods are constantly evolving trying to overcome the many obstacles towards a comprehensive understanding of electrochemical processes on an atomistic level. One of the major challenges has been the determination of reaction energetics under a constant potential. Here, a theoretical framework was proposed applying standard electronic structure methods and extrapolating to the infinite&#8208;cell size limit where reactions do not alter the potential. Today, electronically grand canonical modifications to electronic structure methods, holding the potential constant by varying the number of electrons in a finite simulation cell, become increasingly popular. In this perspective, we show that these two schemes are thermodynamically equivalent. Further, we link these methods to capacitive models of the interface, in the limit that the capacitance of the charging components (whether continuum or atomistic) are equal and invariant along the reaction pathway. We benchmark the three approaches with an example of alkali cation adsorption on Pt(111) showing that all three approaches converge in the cases of Li, Na and K. For Cs, however, strong deviation from the ideal conditions leads to a spread in the respective results. We discuss the latter by highlighting the cases of broken equivalence and assumptions among the approaches.</description>
      <author>Georg Kastlunger, Sudarshan Vijay, Xi Chen, Shubham Sharma, Andrew A. Peterson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202300950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CREST&#8212;A program for the exploration of low-energy molecular chemical space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0197592</link>
      <description>Philipp Pracht, Stefan Grimme, Christoph Bannwarth, Fabian Bohle, Sebastian Ehlert, Gereon Feldmann, Johannes Gorges, Marcel M&#252;ller, Tim Stauch, Christoph Plett, Sebastian Spicher, Pit Steinbach, Patryk A. Weso&#322;owski, Felix Zeller, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393045038

                Conformer&#8211;rotamer sampling tool (CREST) is an open-source program for the efficient and automated exploration of molecular chemical space. Originally developed in Pracht et al. [Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 22, 7169 (2020)] as an automated driver for calculations at the extended tight-binding level (xTB), it offers a variety of molecular- and metadynamics simulations, geometry optimization, and molecular structure analysis capabilities. Implemented algorithms include automated procedures for conformational sampling, explicit solvation studies, the calculation of absolute molecular entropy, and the identification of molecular protonation and deprotonation sites. Calculations are set up to run concurrently, providing efficient single-node parallelization. CREST is designed to require minimal user input and comes with an implementation of the GFNn-xTB Hamiltonians and the GFN-FF force-field. Furthermore, interfaces to any quantum chemistry and force-field software can easily be created. In this article, we present recent developments in the CREST code and show a selection of applications for the most important features of the program. An important novelty is the refactored calculation backend, which provides significant speed-up for sampling of small or medium-sized drug molecules and allows for more sophisticated setups, for example, quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics and minimum energy crossing point calculations.</description>
      <author>Philipp Pracht, Stefan Grimme, Christoph Bannwarth, Fabian Bohle, Sebastian Ehlert, Gereon Feldmann, Johannes Gorges, Marcel M&#252;ller, Tim Stauch, Christoph Plett, Sebastian Spicher, Pit Steinbach, Patryk A. Weso&#322;owski, Felix Zeller</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0197592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of penta-CN2 quantum dots for efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.016</link>
      <description>Rupali Jindal, Rachana Yogi, Alok Shukla, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 63(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393059030

                The objective of our research is to investigate the electrocatalytic properties of novel metal-free quantum dots (QDs) composed of the recently discovered 2D material penta-CN2, with the aim of replacing costly and scarce catalysts such as Pt and Pd. Employing a first-principles density functional theory (DFT) based approach, the geometries of the three penta-CN2 quantum dots (QDs) of increasing sizes, 3 &#215; 3, 3 &#215; 4, 4 &#215; 4 are optimized. Through comprehensive analysis, our research extensively explored the structural stability of penta-CN2 QDs, delved into their electronic properties, and assessed their catalytic performance concerning the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER). Notably, the H-adsorbed penta-CN2 QDs exhibit a significant reduction in the HOMO-LUMO gap (Eg) ranging from 35% to 49% compared to the pristine QD. This observation underscores the crucial impact of H-adsorption on Penta-CN2 QD and is further supported by the appearance of mid-gap states in total and partial density of states plots. Next, we investigated their catalytic performance relevant to HER, using well-known descriptors: (i) adsorption energy, (ii) over-potential, (iii) Gibbs free energy and (iv) exchange current density along with the volcano curve. As far as size dependence of the catalytic performance is concerned, the value of the average change in Gibbs free energy, &#916;G(av), is minimum for 3 &#215; 3 penta&#8211;CN2 QD, with those of 3 &#215; 4 and 4 &#215; 4 QDs being slightly larger. Our calculations predict a high value of exchange current density 2.24&#215;10&#8722;3 A-cm&#8722;2 for one of the sites (N11 for 3 &#215; 3 QD), which we believe will lead to significantly enhanced HER properties. The minimum value of &#916;G=0.158eV for a 3 &#215; 3 penta-CN2 QD implies that its catalytic performance is at least as effective or perhaps better than most of the metal-free hybrid and non-hybrid structures. Our research outcomes hold great promise in advancing the discovery of abundant, non-toxic, and cost-effective catalysts for HER, playing a vital role in facilitating large-scale hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Rupali Jindal, Rachana Yogi, Alok Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the versatility of porous nanoarchitectures: A voyage for sustainable electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64581-4</link>
      <description>Jian Yiing Loh, Joel Jie Foo, Feng Ming Yap, Hanfeng Liang, Wee&#8208;Jun Ong, Chinese Journal of Catalysis. 58(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393063102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Yiing Loh, Joel Jie Foo, Feng Ming Yap, Hanfeng Liang, Wee&#8208;Jun Ong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64581-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Effects Drive Water Oxidation Catalysis in Cobalt Electrocatalysts through the Destabilization of Intermediates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11651</link>
      <description>Benjamin Moss, Katrine L. Svane, David Nieto&#8208;Castro, Reshma R. Rao, S&#248;ren B. Scott, Cindy Tseng, Michael L. Sachs, Anuj Pennathur, Caiwu Liang, Louise I. Oldham, Eva Mazzolini, Lole Jurado, Gopinathan Sankar, Stephen Parry, Ver&#243;nica Celorrio, Jahan M. Dawlaty, Jan Rossmeisl, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, Ifan E. L. Stephens, James R. Durrant, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393069559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benjamin Moss, Katrine L. Svane, David Nieto&#8208;Castro, Reshma R. Rao, S&#248;ren B. Scott, Cindy Tseng, Michael L. Sachs, Anuj Pennathur, Caiwu Liang, Louise I. Oldham, Eva Mazzolini, Lole Jurado, Gopinathan Sankar, Stephen Parry, Ver&#243;nica Celorrio, Jahan M. Dawlaty, Jan Rossmeisl, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, Ifan E. L. Stephens, James R. Durrant</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Overall and Hybrid Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00332</link>
      <description>Quan Li, Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Yujie Sun, Bo You, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393071097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Quan Li, Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Yujie Sun, Bo You</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom platinum with asymmetric coordination environment on fully conjugated covalent organic framework for efficient electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46872-x</link>
      <description>Ziqi Zhang, Zhe Zhang, Cailing Chen, Rui Wang, Minggang Xie, Shouhong Wan, Ruige Zhang, Linchuan Cong, Haiyan Lu, Yu Han, Xing Wang, Zhan Shi, Shouhua Feng, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393074416

                Abstract Two-dimensional (2D) covalent organic frameworks (COFs) and their derivatives have been widely applied as electrocatalysts owing to their unique nanoscale pore configurations, stable periodic structures, abundant coordination sites and high surface area. This work aims to construct a non-thermodynamically stable Pt-N 2 coordination active site by electrochemically modifying platinum (Pt) single atoms into a fully conjugated 2D COF as conductive agent-free and pyrolysis-free electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). In addition to maximizing atomic utilization, single-atom catalysts with definite structures can be used to investigate catalytic mechanisms and structure-activity relationships. In this work, in-situ characterizations and theoretical calculations reveal that a nitrogen-rich graphene analogue COF not only exhibits a favorable metal-support effect for Pt, adjusting the binding energy between Pt sites to H* intermediates by forming unique Pt-N 2 instead of the typical Pt-N 4 coordination environment, but also enhances electron transport ability and structural stability, showing both conductivity and stability in acidic environments.</description>
      <author>Ziqi Zhang, Zhe Zhang, Cailing Chen, Rui Wang, Minggang Xie, Shouhong Wan, Ruige Zhang, Linchuan Cong, Haiyan Lu, Yu Han, Xing Wang, Zhan Shi, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46872-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linker-free Functionalization of Phosphorene Nanosheets by Sialic Acid Biomolecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00128</link>
      <description>Nasrin Khazamipour, Amir H. Souri, Omid Babaee, Behzad Dadashnia, Pouya Soltan-Khamsi, Sadegh Mousavi, Shams Mohajerzadeh, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393077704

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nasrin Khazamipour, Amir H. Souri, Omid Babaee, Behzad Dadashnia, Pouya Soltan-Khamsi, Sadegh Mousavi, Shams Mohajerzadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assembled RhRuFe Trimetallene for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400336</link>
      <description>Wenshu Zhang, Kai Wang, Fangxu Lin, Qinghua Zhang, Yingjun Sun, Heng Luo, Weiyu Zhang, Junhu Zhou, Fan Lv, Dawei Wang, Lin Gu, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393083920

                Abstract Industrializing water electrolyzers demands better electrocatalysts, especially for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The prevailing OER catalysts are Ir or Ru&#8208;based nanomaterials, however, they still suffer from insufficient stability. An alternative yet considerably less explored approach is to upgrade Rh, a known stable but moderately active element for OER electrocatalysis, via rational structural engineering. Herein, a precise synthesis of assembled RhRuFe trimetallenes (RhRuFe TMs) with an average thickness of 1 nm for boosting overall water splitting catalysis is reported. Favorable mass transport and optimized electronic structure collectively render RhRuFe TMs with an improved OER activity of an overpotential of 330 mV to deliver 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is significantly lower than the Rh/C control (by 601 mV) and reported Rh&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts. In particular, the RhRuFe TMs&#8208;based water splitting devices can achieve the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at a low voltage of 1.63 V, which is among the best in the Rh&#8208;based bifunctional catalysts for electrolyzers. The addition of Fe in RhRuFe TMs can modulate the strain/electron distribution of the multi&#8208;alloy, which regulates the binding energies of H * and OH * in hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions for achieving the enhanced bifunctional OER and HER catalysis is further demonstrated.</description>
      <author>Wenshu Zhang, Kai Wang, Fangxu Lin, Qinghua Zhang, Yingjun Sun, Heng Luo, Weiyu Zhang, Junhu Zhou, Fan Lv, Dawei Wang, Lin Gu, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Neural Network Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00004</link>
      <description>Timothy T. Duignan, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393037991

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timothy T. Duignan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on Advancing Sustainable CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion Processes: Trinomial Technology, Environment, and Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07133</link>
      <description>Lourdes F. Vega, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Ismail I.I. Alkhatib, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393097423

                CO2 can be converted into value-added products such as fuels, chemicals, and building materials, adding an economic incentive for CO2 capture and green economy, while also reducing the environmental footprint of hard-to-abate industries such as aviation, construction, and metallurgy. Nonetheless, most available technologies for direct CO2 conversion, while promising, are still in early development stages, facing technical and economic challenges for their scale-up, questioning their viability to truly instill a timely impact on global CO2 emissions. Furthermore, a clear environmental benefit should be obtained for the new processes versus the traditional ones they are replacing in the market. In this perspective, we examine the range of available technologies for direct CO2 conversion using thermal, electrical, and photochemical routes and mineralization including the advancements in their role in synthesizing a range of resulting products from methanol, methane, carbon monoxide, and solid carbonates. We offer insights on the trends in current research and development and the required direction to expedite the technological readiness of attractive CO2 conversion technologies in terms of catalytic material and reactor design. We also highlight the important role of modeling (molecular and process levels) as an enabling tool to deploy these technologies at the commercial scale originating from understanding their behavior at the molecular level. Lastly, we highlight the significance of carrying out reliable life cycle analysis in identifying the environmental hotspots as well as gaps in the technology that allows improving their environmental footprint and economic attractiveness.</description>
      <author>Lourdes F. Vega, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Ismail I.I. Alkhatib</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending the definition of atomic basis sets to atoms with fractional nuclear charge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0196383</link>
      <description>Giorgio Domenichini, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393152656

                Alchemical transformations showed that perturbation theory can be applied also to changes in the atomic nuclear charges of a molecule. The alchemical path that connects two different chemical species involves the conceptualization of a non-physical system in which an atom possess a non-integer nuclear charge. A correct quantum mechanical treatment of these systems is limited by the fact that finite size atomic basis sets do not define exponents and contraction coefficients for fractional charge atoms. This paper proposes a solution to this problem and shows that a smooth interpolation of the atomic orbital coefficients and exponents across the periodic table is a convenient way to produce accurate alchemical predictions, even using small size basis sets.</description>
      <author>Giorgio Domenichini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0196383</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface structure determination by exhaustive search of asymmetric unit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.115430</link>
      <description>Xingxing Dong, Caiyun He, Chao He, Hui Wang, Shaogang Xu, Hu Xu, Physical review. 109(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393157853

                Determining surface structures is a substantial challenge due to the limitations of experimental techniques and the complexity of theoretical models. In this work, we use a method called the exhaustive search of asymmetric unit (ESAU), designed to identify surface structures through a detailed analysis of the asymmetric unit. This method employs two main strategies: narrowing the research area by focusing on a smaller, unique segment rather than the entire unit cell, and transforming the infinite possibilities of atomic positions into discrete, manageable units. These strategies allow us to systematically enumerate all potential surface structures. Employing the ESAU method, we have successfully replicated a variety of known surface structures, including two-dimensional materials on substrates, and have also uncovered some previously unknown structures. Importantly, the ESAU method shows significant promise not only in utilizing experimental data but also in predicting surface and crystal structures without prior experimental evidence. Our results affirm that the ESAU approach provides a comprehensive and efficient tool for uncovering material structures, paving the way for more in-depth studies on the properties and behaviors of materials.</description>
      <author>Xingxing Dong, Caiyun He, Chao He, Hui Wang, Shaogang Xu, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.115430</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
