<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 01:36:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Crystallization Instead of Amorphization in Collision Cascades in Gallium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.126101</link>
      <description>J. Zhao, Javier Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Alexander Azarov, Ru He, &#216;ystein Prytz, K. Nordlund, Mengyuan Hua, Flyura Djurabekova, Andrej Kuznetsov, Physical Review Letters. 134(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408815345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Zhao, Javier Garc&#237;a&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Alexander Azarov, Ru He, &#216;ystein Prytz, K. Nordlund, Mengyuan Hua, Flyura Djurabekova, Andrej Kuznetsov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevlett.134.126101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor-Driven Prediction of Adsorption Energy of Oxygenates on Metal Dioxide Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00005</link>
      <description>Chen Chen, Zhihui Li, Jia Yang, Haifeng Wang, De Chen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408820301

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Chen, Zhihui Li, Jia Yang, Haifeng Wang, De Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving pH-universal oxygen electrolysis via synergistic density and coordination tuning over biomass-derived Fe single-atom catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58297-1</link>
      <description>Wei Guo, Meiling Pan, Qianjie Xie, Hua Fan, Laihao Luo, Qun Jing, Yehua Shen, Yan Yan, Mingkai Liu, Zheng Wang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408824299

                Renewable biomass serves as a cost-effective source of carbon matrix to carry single-atom catalysts (SACs). However, the natural abundant oxygen in these materials hinders the sufficient dispersion of element with high oxygen affinity such iron (Fe). The lowered-density and oxidized SACs greatly limits their catalytic applications. Here we develop a facile continuous activation (CA) approach for synthesizing robust biomass-derived Fe-SACs. Comparing to the traditional pyrolysis method, the CA approach significantly increases the Fe loading density from 1.13 atoms nm&#8722;2 to 4.70 atoms nm&#8722;2. Simultaneously, the CA approach induces a distinct coordination tuning from dominated Fe-O to Fe-N moieties. We observe a pH-universal oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance over the CA-derived Fe-SACs with a half-wave potential of 0.93 V and 0.78 V vs. RHE in alkaline and acidic electrolyte, respectively. Density functional theory calculations further reveal that the increased Fe-N coordination effectively reduces the energy barriers for the ORR, thus enhancing the catalytic activity. The Fe-SACs-based zinc-air batteries show a specific capacity of 792 mA&#183;h&#183;gZn&#8722;1 and ultra-long life span of over 650 h at 5 mA cm&#8722;2. Developing efficient single-atom catalysts for clean energy technologies is still challenging. Here, the authors report a facile method to increase the density and tune the coordination of iron atom loaded in single-atom catalysts that boosts the activity for pH-universal oxygen electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Wei Guo, Meiling Pan, Qianjie Xie, Hua Fan, Laihao Luo, Qun Jing, Yehua Shen, Yan Yan, Mingkai Liu, Zheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58297-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO2 reduction catalysis on Mo and Nb single atoms anchored to g-C3N4: A DFT investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.127451</link>
      <description>Asad Mahmood, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408826432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asad Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.127451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Density Functional Theory Calculations and Machine Learning to Identify Conduction Band Minimum as a Descriptor for High-Efficiency Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Catalysts in Transition Metal Dichalcogenides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040309</link>
      <description>Xiaolin Jiang, G.H. Liu, L. Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Catalysts. 15(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408829497

                Identifying efficient and physically meaningful descriptors is crucial for the rational design of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalysts. In this study, we systematically investigate the HER activity of transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) monolayers by combining density functional theory (DFT) calculations and machine learning techniques. By exploring the relationship between key electronic properties, including the conduction band minimum (CBM), pz band center, and hydrogen adsorption free energy (&#916;G*H), we establish a strong linear correlation between the CBM and &#916;G*H, identifying the CBM as a reliable and physically meaningful descriptor for HER activity. Furthermore, this correlation is validated in vacancy-defected TMD systems, demonstrating that the CBM remains an effective descriptor even in the presence of structural defects. To enable the rapid and accurate prediction of the CBM, we develop an interpretable three-dimensional model using the Sure Independence Screening and Sparsifying Operator (SISSO) algorithm. The SISSO model achieves a high predictive accuracy, with correlation coefficients (r) and coefficients of determination (R2) reaching 0.98 and 0.97 in the training and 0.99 and 0.99 in the validation tests, respectively. This study provides an efficient computational framework that combines first-principles calculations and machine learning to accelerate the screening and design of high-performance TMD-based HER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaolin Jiang, G.H. Liu, L. Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15040309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single transition metal atom catalysts on defective VSeTe monolayer for efficient ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112715</link>
      <description>Lujing Zhao, Changmin Shi, Guangliang Cui, Hongmei Liu, Feifei Li, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408837809

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lujing Zhao, Changmin Shi, Guangliang Cui, Hongmei Liu, Feifei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous CoO/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanostructures as Efficient Anodes for Hydrogen Generation via Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00422</link>
      <description>Dafeng Zhang, Dongliang Zhang, Yage Cao, Yumei Chen, Baozhong Liu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408840745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dafeng Zhang, Dongliang Zhang, Yage Cao, Yumei Chen, Baozhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.5c00422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling active ensembles consisting of clusters and single atoms for oxygen reduction: a synergy of machine learning and DFT calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5qi00219b</link>
      <description>Xinyi Li, Dongxu Jiao, Jingxiang Zhao, Xiao Zhao, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408844613

                Combining ML and DFT, we screened 1521 candidates to identify 24 active ORR catalysts. Key metal features correlate with &#951; ORR , enabling efficient optimization. Pt 3 Ni-CoNC, Pt 3 Ni-ZnNC, Pt 3 V-ZnNC, and Pt 3 Mo-CoNC show high activity and durability.</description>
      <author>Xinyi Li, Dongxu Jiao, Jingxiang Zhao, Xiao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5qi00219b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in theory and computational methods for next-generation thermoelectric materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241645</link>
      <description>Junsoo Park, Alex M. Ganose, Yi Xia, Applied Physics Reviews. 12(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408848753

                This is a review of theoretical and methodological development over the past decade pertaining to computational characterization of thermoelectric materials from first principles. Primary focus is on electronic and thermal transport in solids. Particular attention is given to the relationships between the various methods in terms of the theoretical hierarchy as well as the tradeoff of physical accuracy and computational efficiency of each. Further covered are up-and-coming methods for modeling defect formation and dopability, keys to realizing a material's thermoelectric potential. We present and discuss all these methods in close connection with parallel developments in high-throughput infrastructure and code implementation that enable large-scale computing and materials screening. In all, it is demonstrated that advances in computational tools are now ripe for efficient and accurate targeting of the needles in the haystack, which are &#8220;next-generation&#8221; thermoelectric materials.</description>
      <author>Junsoo Park, Alex M. Ganose, Yi Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative Dehydrogenation of Ethane Combined with CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Splitting via Chemical Looping on In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Modified with Ni&#8211;Cu Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07737</link>
      <description>Kosuke Watanabe, Takuma Higo, Koki Saegusa, Shigemi Matsumoto, Hiroshi Sampei, Yuki Isono, Akira Shimojuku, Hideki Furusawa, Yasushi Sekine, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408849089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kosuke Watanabe, Takuma Higo, Koki Saegusa, Shigemi Matsumoto, Hiroshi Sampei, Yuki Isono, Akira Shimojuku, Hideki Furusawa, Yasushi Sekine</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of C(1s) binding energy shifts in amorphous carbon materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.035601</link>
      <description>Michael Walter, Filippo Mangolini, J. Brandon McClimon, Robert W. Carpick, Michael Moseler, Physical Review Materials. 9(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408851648

                The quantitative evaluation of the carbon hybridization state by x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) has been a surface-analysis problem for the last three decades due to the challenges associated with the unambiguous identification of the characteristic binding energy values for sp2- and sp3-bonded carbon. Here, we computed the binding energy values of C(1s) core electrons on the absolute energy scale for model structures of amorphous carbon (a-C) using density functional theory (DFT). The DFT calculations show that in the case of hydrogen-free a-C, the C(1s) binding energy for sp3 carbon atoms is a distribution found approximately 1 eV higher than the binding energy distribution of sp2-hybridized carbons. However, the introduction of hydrogen in the a-C network reduces the distance between the characteristic signals of sp3- and sp2-bonded carbon due to the increased ability to screen the core hole by neighboring hydrogen atoms as compared to carbon atoms. This effect hinders the unambiguous quantification of the carbon hybridization state on the basis of C(1s) XPS data alone. This work can assist surface scientists in the use of XPS for the accurate characterization of carbon-based materials. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>Michael Walter, Filippo Mangolini, J. Brandon McClimon, Robert W. Carpick, Michael Moseler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.9.035601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilot&#8208;Scale Photoreforming of Hydrolyzed Polylactic Acid Waste to High&#8208;Value Chemicals and H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Atomic Ru Integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202500015</link>
      <description>Feng Liu, Chun&#8208;yang Zhang, Kejian Lu, Xueli Yan, Yi Wang, Dengwei Jing, Liejin Guo, Maochang Liu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408854007

                Abstract Photoreforming of polylactic acid (PLA) waste into valuable chemicals offers a promising approach for environmental protection and waste valorization, yet faces challenges of low yields and harsh conditions. Herein, a Cd 0.5 Zn 0.5 S nanotwin catalyst decorated with Ru single atoms and clusters is reported, enabling selective photoreforming of PLA into pyruvic acid (PA) and H 2 . It is demonstrated that Ru single atoms favor PA formation via hydroxyl dissociation, while the further incorporation of Ru clusters serve as active sites for H 2 production. This synergistic effect significantly enhances photocatalytic performance, achieving 96.8% PA selectivity and efficient H 2 production with a record&#8208;breaking apparent quantum efficiency of 83.7% at 400 nm. This approach is scalable for outdoor processes, utilizing direct 1 m 2 sunlight irradiation to deliver &#8776;1191 mL h &#8722;1 of H 2 and 47.27 mmol h &#8722;1 of PA from PLA waste, paving a viable pathway for large&#8208;scale simultaneous production of high&#8208;value chemicals and H 2 .</description>
      <author>Feng Liu, Chun&#8208;yang Zhang, Kejian Lu, Xueli Yan, Yi Wang, Dengwei Jing, Liejin Guo, Maochang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202500015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lanthanide single-atom catalysts for efficient CO2-to-CO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57464-8</link>
      <description>Qiyou Wang, Tao Luo, Xueying Cao, Yujie Gong, Yuxiang Liu, Y. L. Xiao, Hongmei Li, Franz Gr&#246;bmeyer, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chao Ma, Kang Liu, Junwei Fu, Shiguo Zhang, Changxu Liu, Lin Zhang, Liyuan Chai, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Min Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408857437

                Abstract Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have received increasing attention due to their 100% atomic utilization efficiency. The electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) to CO using SAC offers a promising approach for CO 2 utilization, but achieving facile CO 2 adsorption and CO desorption remains challenging for traditional SACs. Instead of singling out specific atoms, we propose a strategy utilizing atoms from the entire lanthanide (Ln) group to facilitate the CO 2 RR. Density functional theory calculations, operando spectroscopy, and X-ray absorption spectroscopy elucidate the bridging adsorption mechanism for a representative erbium (Er) single-atom catalyst. As a result, we realize a series of Ln SACs spanning 14 elements that exhibit CO Faradaic efficiencies exceeding 90%. The Er catalyst achieves a high turnover frequency of ~130,000 h &#8722; 1 at 500 mA cm &#8722; 2 . Moreover, 34.7% full-cell energy efficiency and 70.4% single-pass CO 2 conversion efficiency are obtained at 200 mA cm &#8722; 2 with acidic electrolyte. This catalytic platform leverages the collective potential of the lanthanide group, introducing new possibilities for efficient CO 2 -to-CO conversion and beyond through the exploration of unique bonding motifs in single-atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qiyou Wang, Tao Luo, Xueying Cao, Yujie Gong, Yuxiang Liu, Y. L. Xiao, Hongmei Li, Franz Gr&#246;bmeyer, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chao Ma, Kang Liu, Junwei Fu, Shiguo Zhang, Changxu Liu, Lin Zhang, Liyuan Chai, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Min Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-57464-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-Dependent Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction Catalysis on Ni-Anchored &#947;-Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(110) Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08378</link>
      <description>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408869529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deewan S. Teja, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c08378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the activity origin and mechanisms of the oxygen reduction reaction on the tetramethyl metalloporphyrin/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra00814j</link>
      <description>Tran Phuong Dung, Pham Tran Nguyen Nguyen, Viorel Chihaia, Do Ngoc Son, RSC Advances. 15(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408873061

                This study elucidated the impact of metal substitutions in MeTMP/MoS 2 on the mechanisms and activity of the ORR. The Co atom is the best substitution in MeTMP/MoS 2 catalysts, while the MoS 2 support favours the dissociative ORR mechanism.</description>
      <author>Tran Phuong Dung, Pham Tran Nguyen Nguyen, Viorel Chihaia, Do Ngoc Son</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra00814j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Dynamics Simulation of Polymer Electrolyte Membrane for Understanding Structure and Proton Conductivity at Various Hydration Levels Using Neural Network Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.macromol.4c02607</link>
      <description>Attila T&#225;borosi, Kentaro Aoki, Nobuyuki Zettsu, Michihisa Koyama, Yuki Nagao, Macromolecules. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408888610

                Alkyl sulfonated polyimides (ASPIs), as alternative polymer electrolytes for fuel cells, are known to exhibit lyotropic liquid crystalline behavior upon water uptake, forming organized lamellar structures and achieving high proton conductivity. Previous experimental studies have shown that ASPIs with planar backbones exhibit enhanced proton conductivity (0.2 S/cm) compared to those with bent backbones (0.03 S/cm). To explain this difference at the atomistic level, molecular dynamics simulations were conducted using a universal neural network potential. The appearance of monomer unit length in planar ASPIs, indicating higher molecular order, was found to correlate with higher proton conductivity compared to that of bent ASPIs. Despite the similar deprotonation and solvation of sulfonic acid groups in both planar and bent ASPIs, the proton conductivity was independent of these factors. Directional mean square displacement analysis provided further insights into the differences in proton conductivity between planar and bent types.</description>
      <author>Attila T&#225;borosi, Kentaro Aoki, Nobuyuki Zettsu, Michihisa Koyama, Yuki Nagao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.macromol.4c02607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The advantages of reheated and intercooled gas turbines for combined cycles with post-combustion CO2 capture and storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2025.104345</link>
      <description>Andrea Zelaschi, Davide Bonalumi, Paolo Chiesa, Emanuele Martelli, International journal of greenhouse gas control. 144(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408899645

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrea Zelaschi, Davide Bonalumi, Paolo Chiesa, Emanuele Martelli</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijggc.2025.104345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCoP-stabilized single atoms for efficient hydrogen evolution: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.323</link>
      <description>Yihong Sun, Jianfeng Wan, Wenyan Bi, Shizheng Xie, Menglin Yu, Yikai Hou, Tianen Li, Dongkui Zhou, Lebin Li, Baozhong Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 120(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408903140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yihong Sun, Jianfeng Wan, Wenyan Bi, Shizheng Xie, Menglin Yu, Yikai Hou, Tianen Li, Dongkui Zhou, Lebin Li, Baozhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia using &#947;-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/BCN in a Neutral Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00936</link>
      <description>Soniya Mariya Varghese, Anju Vakakuzhiyil Gopinathan, Sudhin Rathnakumaran, S. Sasikumar, Sooraj Kunnikuruvan, G. Ranga Rao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408903528

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soniya Mariya Varghese, Anju Vakakuzhiyil Gopinathan, Sudhin Rathnakumaran, S. Sasikumar, Sooraj Kunnikuruvan, G. Ranga Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c00936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Investigation of Monolayer Sc&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;X&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (X = Cl, Br) as a High-Performance Photocatalyst for Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00155</link>
      <description>Dandan Mao, Rundong Wan, Zhengfu Zhang, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408905661

                Two-dimensional materials hold substantial promise for photocatalytic water splitting, primarily due to their unique structural properties and high-efficiency light absorption. However, finding such applicable materials poses a huge challenge because there are many strict requirements to meet. In this study, we employ first-principles calculations to design and evaluate two monolayers, Sc2Se2X2 (X = Cl, Br), highlighting their potential as high-performance photocatalysts. these materials exhibit low activation energy barriers for water-splitting redox reactions, which facilitate high catalytic performance. The photogenerated electric field promotes oxygen adsorption, accelerating the overall reaction. The structural, mechanical, dynamical, and thermodynamic stabilities of these materials are confirmed through comprehensive analyses. With band gaps of 2.65 and 2.40 eV, respectively, these materials meet the band gap requirements for photocatalytic water splitting. Furthermore, a prominent characteristic of these materials is their significantly high electron mobility along the y-axis, reaching 26,560.74 and 17,634.01 cm2 V-1 s-1, which far surpasses the hole mobility. This characteristic effectively reduces electron-hole recombination and enhances photocatalytic performance. With solar-to-hydrogen efficiencies of 13.60% and 20.58%, respectively, these materials surpass the 10% threshold required for commercial photocatalytic applications. These findings indicate that monolayer Sc2Se2X2 (X = Cl, Br) has great theoretical potential for photocatalytic water splitting.</description>
      <author>Dandan Mao, Rundong Wan, Zhengfu Zhang, Mengnie Li, Guocai Tian, Chen Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c00155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiMo LDH-Derived Mo@NiSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as Advanced Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution in Acidic and Alkaline Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c06371</link>
      <description>M Pratheeksha, Hemavathi NJ, Sumanth Dongre S, Suman Kalyan Sahoo, R. Geetha Balakrishna, R. Shwetharani, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408914637

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M Pratheeksha, Hemavathi NJ, Sumanth Dongre S, Suman Kalyan Sahoo, R. Geetha Balakrishna, R. Shwetharani</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c06371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeePMD-GNN: A DeePMD-kit Plugin for External Graph Neural Network Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c02441</link>
      <description>Jinzhe Zeng, Timothy J. Giese, Duo Zhang, Han Wang, Darrin M. York, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408914802

                Machine learning potentials (MLPs) have revolutionized molecular simulation by providing efficient and accurate models for predicting atomic interactions. MLPs continue to advance and have had profound impact in applications that include drug discovery, enzyme catalysis, and materials design. The current landscape of MLP software presents challenges due to the limited interoperability between packages, which can lead to inconsistent benchmarking practices and necessitates separate interfaces with molecular dynamics (MD) software. To address these issues, we present DeePMD-GNN, a plugin for the DeePMD-kit framework that extends its capabilities to support external graph neural network (GNN) potentials.DeePMD-GNN enables the seamless integration of popular GNN-based models, such as NequIP and MACE, within the DeePMD-kit ecosystem. Furthermore, the new software infrastructure allows GNN models to be used within combined quantum mechanical/molecular mechanical (QM/MM) applications using the range corrected &#916;MLP formalism.We demonstrate the application of DeePMD-GNN by performing benchmark calculations of NequIP, MACE, and DPA-2 models developed under consistent training conditions to ensure fair comparison.</description>
      <author>Jinzhe Zeng, Timothy J. Giese, Duo Zhang, Han Wang, Darrin M. York</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c02441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal nitrides vs. metal carbides: a comparative analysis of catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43153-025-00552-5</link>
      <description>Yuping Yang, Abdulrahman T. Ahmed, Pinank Patel, Hussein Riyadh Abdul Kareem Al&#8208;Hetty, Thiagarajan Ramachandran, Aman Shankhyan, Vikasdeep Singh Mann, Deepak K. Gupta, Muthena Kariem, Marwa Akram Nafea, Brazilian Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408916889

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuping Yang, Abdulrahman T. Ahmed, Pinank Patel, Hussein Riyadh Abdul Kareem Al&#8208;Hetty, Thiagarajan Ramachandran, Aman Shankhyan, Vikasdeep Singh Mann, Deepak K. Gupta, Muthena Kariem, Marwa Akram Nafea</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43153-025-00552-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity in LiMgFe&#8322;O&#8324;: structural, morphological, and magnetic insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06229-w</link>
      <description>Nilesh N. Kengar, Atul D. Teli, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, C.M. Kanamadi, Ionics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408920725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nilesh N. Kengar, Atul D. Teli, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, C.M. Kanamadi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-025-06229-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Oxygen Octahedra Regulation of Iridium&#8208;Based Perovskites for Efficient and Durable Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202506467</link>
      <description>Yang Yang, Yu&#8208;Ting Chen, Yueying Yan, Bohan Yao, Huanhuan Xing, Dongxu Jiao, Zhicai Xing, Dewen Wang, Xiurong Yang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934016

                Abstract The dissolution and inactivation of anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts remain significant barriers to the development of acidic water electrolysis. Here, the activity and stability of BaIrO 3 (BIO) perovskite are enhanced through the controlled regulation of metal&#8208;oxygen octahedra via B&#8208;site substitution with Co (BICO). During OER process, the dissolution of Ba and Co leads to the formation of highly active IrCoO x nanoparticles on the amorphous surface layers of BICO. The introduction of Co not only increases the concentration of high&#8208;valence Ir species with high activity but also prevents the excessive oxidation and dissolution of Ir by taking over its oxidation role during the reaction. Theoretical calculations reveal a substantial reduction in the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) after Co doping. BICO&#8208;2 electrocatalyst demonstrates exceptional OER performance, requiring an overpotential of 216 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , while maintaining continuous operation for over 140 h without significant degradation, and boasting a stability number (S&#8208;number) of 4.3 &#215; 10 5 . Additionally, BICO&#8208;2 exhibits excellent activity and durability in proton exchange membranes (PEM) water electrolysis. This work introduces a novel approach for designing and fabricating efficient, long&#8208;lasting electrocatalysts, offering significant insights for advancing acidic water electrolysis technologies.</description>
      <author>Yang Yang, Yu&#8208;Ting Chen, Yueying Yan, Bohan Yao, Huanhuan Xing, Dongxu Jiao, Zhicai Xing, Dewen Wang, Xiurong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202506467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of a 2D tungsten MXene for electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00773-z</link>
      <description>Anupma Thakur, Wyatt J. Highland, Brian C. Wyatt, Jiayi Xu, Nithin Chandran, Bowen Zhang, Zachary D. Hood, Shiba P. Adhikari, Emad Oveisi, Barbara Pac&#225;kov&#225;, Fernando Vega, Jeffrey Simon, Colton Fruhling, Benjamin Reigle, Mohammad Asadi, Pawe&#322; Piotr Micha&#322;owski, Vladimir M. Shalaev, Alexandra Boltasseva, Thomas E. Beechem, Cong Liu, Babak Anasori, Nature Synthesis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934620

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anupma Thakur, Wyatt J. Highland, Brian C. Wyatt, Jiayi Xu, Nithin Chandran, Bowen Zhang, Zachary D. Hood, Shiba P. Adhikari, Emad Oveisi, Barbara Pac&#225;kov&#225;, Fernando Vega, Jeffrey Simon, Colton Fruhling, Benjamin Reigle, Mohammad Asadi, Pawe&#322; Piotr Micha&#322;owski, Vladimir M. Shalaev, Alexandra Boltasseva, Thomas E. Beechem, Cong Liu, Babak Anasori</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-025-00773-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidation of interfacial cobalt controls the pH dependence of the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01784-1</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Kenneth Crossley, Julie Guehl, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Nature Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Kenneth Crossley, Julie Guehl, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01784-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a unified benchmark and framework for deep learning-based prediction of nuclear magnetic resonance chemical shifts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00783-z</link>
      <description>Fanjie Xu, Wentao Guo, Feng Wang, Lin Yao, Hongshuai Wang, Fujie Tang, Zhifeng Gao, Linfeng Zhang, E Weinan, Zhong&#8208;Qun Tian, Jun Cheng, Nature Computational Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934721

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fanjie Xu, Wentao Guo, Feng Wang, Lin Yao, Hongshuai Wang, Fujie Tang, Zhifeng Gao, Linfeng Zhang, E Weinan, Zhong&#8208;Qun Tian, Jun Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s43588-025-00783-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical production of disinfectants from seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01530-y</link>
      <description>Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Zehua Gao, Nhat Truong Nguyen, Junxiang Chen, Xianhu Liu, Lei Wang, Limin Wu, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408934833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Zehua Gao, Nhat Truong Nguyen, Junxiang Chen, Xianhu Liu, Lei Wang, Limin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01530-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Selectivity Differences of NO Electroreduction on Ag and Au Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00656</link>
      <description>Lin Li, Dong Luan, Jun Long, Jianping Xiao, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408939668

                Although noble metals Ag and Au have similar chemical reactivities, their catalytic selectivity for NO electroreduction is significantly different. Namely, hydroxylamine is often considerably produced on Ag while not observed on the Au electrode. In this study, first-principles calculations and the electric field controlling constant potential (EFC-CP) method are adopted to unveil the underlying reasons. We first reveal a distinct NO* adsorption configuration, vertical on Ag and inclined on Au, leading to different reduction pathways to NOH* and HNO*, respectively. Via complete electrochemical barrier calculations and detailed kinetic analysis, we find the hydroxylamine selectivity difference between Ag and Au is mainly induced by adsorption strength of NH2OH*. On Ag, the obtained NH2OH* prefers to desorb and produce hydroxylamine, while NH2OH* is bonded strongly to Au and favors further reduction to ammonia. The study advances our understanding of factors regulating product selectivity, providing crucial insights for designing NO electroreduction catalysts toward hydroxylamine production.</description>
      <author>Lin Li, Dong Luan, Jun Long, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c00656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient screening and influencing effect of superior catalysts among TM@Janus WSSe for CO2RR to various C1 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106291</link>
      <description>Xiunan Chen, Yuhong Huang, J. R. Niu, Haiping Lin, Xiumei Wei, Fei Ma, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408941742

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiunan Chen, Yuhong Huang, J. R. Niu, Haiping Lin, Xiumei Wei, Fei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic in-situ reconstruction of active site circulators for photo-Fenton-like reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58392-3</link>
      <description>Chang-Wei Bai, Fu-Qiao Yang, Pijun Duan, Zhiquan Zhang, Yi-Jiao Sun, Xin-Jia Chen, Fei Chen, Han&#8208;Qing Yu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408944939

                Developing efficient and stable heterogeneous catalysts for the continuous activation of oxidants is crucial to mitigating the global water resource crisis. Guided by computational predictions, this research achieved this goal through the synthesis of a modified graphitic carbon nitride with enhanced catalytic activity and stability. Its intrinsic activity was further amplified by dynamic in-situ reconstruction using the I&#8722;/I3&#8722; redox mediator system during photoreactions. Impressively, this reconstructed catalyst demonstrated the capability for at least 30 regeneration cycles while maintaining high purification efficacy. The mechanism underlying the in-situ reconstruction of active sites for periodate functionalization was elucidated through theoretical calculations, coupled with semi-in-situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and electrochemical analyses. The system's capacity to detoxify recalcitrant pollutants was demonstrated through successful Escherichia coli cultivation and Zebrafish embryo experiments. The economic feasibility and environmental impacts are quantitatively assessed by the Electrical Energy per Order (EE/O) metric and Life Cycle Assessment (LCA), confirming the system's scalability and applicability in real-world scenarios. This dual-site constrained interlayer insertion, and controllable in-situ catalyst reconstruction achieve durable robustness of the photocatalyst, paving the way for the development of sustainable catalytic water purification technologies. Efficient and stable heterogeneous catalysts for sustained oxidant activation are vital for solving the global water crisis but elusive. Here, the authors explore the in situ dynamic reconstruction of graphitic carbon nitride photocatalysts with iodine redox mediators, to develop a solar-driven Fenton-like system that activates periodate for effective and sustainable wastewater regeneration.</description>
      <author>Chang-Wei Bai, Fu-Qiao Yang, Pijun Duan, Zhiquan Zhang, Yi-Jiao Sun, Xin-Jia Chen, Fei Chen, Han&#8208;Qing Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58392-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of encapsulated transition metal atoms on the hydrophilic properties of C84 fullerene: A computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142067</link>
      <description>Shakhrizoda Matnazarova, Nosir Matyakubov, Umedjon Khalilov, Maksudbek Yusupov, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408952322

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shakhrizoda Matnazarova, Nosir Matyakubov, Umedjon Khalilov, Maksudbek Yusupov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress on transition metal-based amorphous ribbons as electrocatalysts for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12613-024-3015-4</link>
      <description>Tianjing Li, Hainan Sun, Zhenhua Dan, Lian Zhou, International Journal of Minerals Metallurgy and Materials. 32(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408952335

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianjing Li, Hainan Sun, Zhenhua Dan, Lian Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12613-024-3015-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and Electronic Properties of 2&#8208;D Conductive Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks M&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(C&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/andp.202400397</link>
      <description>Yue Zhang, Feifei Xu, Hao Ren, Wen Zhao, Annalen der Physik. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408955510

                Abstract The stability and electronic properties of 2&#8208;D conducting metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) play a crucial role in their potential applications in energy&#8208;related processes. In this study, The structural stability and electronic characteristics of M 3 (C 6 Se 6 ) (M = Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Mo, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ir, and Pt) are systematically investigated using first&#8208;principles calculations. Formation energy calculations and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations confirm the excellent thermodynamic and thermal stability of these frameworks. Additionally, density of states (DOS) analysis reveals that nine of these structures exhibit high electrical conductivity, making them promising for electronic and electrocatalytic applications. To further understand their electronic structure, the d &#8208;band center and crystal orbital Hamilton population (COHP) are analyzed, providing insight into the bonding characteristics and electronic interactions within the frameworks. Moreover, the catalytic performance of the conductive MOFs is evaluated as multifunctional catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). This study highlights the robust stability and tunable electronic properties of M 3 (C 6 Se 6 ), serving as a foundation for future investigations into their functional applications in energy conversion and storage technologies.</description>
      <author>Yue Zhang, Feifei Xu, Hao Ren, Wen Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/andp.202400397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility of Active and Durable Lattice Oxygen&#8208;Mediated Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers Through d&lt;sup&gt;0&lt;/sup&gt; Metal Ion Incorporation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411374</link>
      <description>Yeju Jang, Ho Young Kim, Dongmin Park, Sunghoon Han, Hyunwoo Jun, Jinkyu Park, Seongbeen Kim, Yousung Jung, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jong Hyun Jang, Seonggyu Lee, Jinwoo Lee, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408956458

                Abstract The primary hurdle faced in the practical application of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) involves improving the intrinsic kinetic activity of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts while concurrently enhancing their durability. Although electrocatalysts based on lattice oxygen&#8208;mediated mechanism (LOM) have the potential to significantly enhance the activity in OER without being restricted by scaling relationships, they are neglected in acidic electrolytes due to limited durability. In this study, an innovative approach is presented to simultaneously promote the activation of lattice oxygen and improve the durability of LOM&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts by incorporating d 0 metal ions into the RuO 2 electrocatalyst. Leveraging the unique electronic properties of the d 0 metal ion, the O 2p band center and Ru&#8208;O covalency of the electrocatalyst are successfully engineered, resulting in the change in OER mechanism. Furthermore, in a single cell of PEMWE, the LOM&#8208;based electrocatalyst demonstrates outstanding performance, achieving 3.0 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.81 V and maintaining durability for 100 h at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 , surpassing commercial RuO 2 . This innovative strategy challenges the traditional viewpoint that suppressing lattice oxygen activation in OER is essential for enhancing PEMWE durability, offering new perspectives for the development of OER electrocatalysts in acidic electrolytes.</description>
      <author>Yeju Jang, Ho Young Kim, Dongmin Park, Sunghoon Han, Hyunwoo Jun, Jinkyu Park, Seongbeen Kim, Yousung Jung, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jong Hyun Jang, Seonggyu Lee, Jinwoo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Tungsten Enhances CO Tolerance in Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Oxidation by Regulating the 5d-Orbital Electrons of Platinum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmate.2025.100288</link>
      <description>Xu Zhang, Peng Yu, Di Shen, Bin Cai, Tianyu Han, Ying Xie, Lei Wang, Advanced Powder Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408965107

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu Zhang, Peng Yu, Di Shen, Bin Cai, Tianyu Han, Ying Xie, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmate.2025.100288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proximity electronic effect of adjacent Ni Site enhances compatibility of hydrogenation and deoxygenation over Cu Site to boost nitrate electroreduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60221-4</link>
      <description>Xue&#8208;Feng Cheng, Qing Liu, Qimeng Sun, Huilong Dong, Dongyun Chen, Ying Zheng, Qingfeng Xu, Jianmei Lu, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 70(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408965558

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue&#8208;Feng Cheng, Qing Liu, Qimeng Sun, Huilong Dong, Dongyun Chen, Ying Zheng, Qingfeng Xu, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60221-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iterative charge equilibration for fourth-generation high-dimensional neural network potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0252566</link>
      <description>Emir Kocer, Andreas Singraber, Jonas A. Finkler, Philipp Misof, Tsz Wai Ko, Christoph Dellago, J&#246;rg Behler, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(12)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408831566

                Machine learning potentials allow performing large-scale molecular dynamics simulations with about the same accuracy as electronic structure calculations, provided that the selected model is able to capture the relevant physics of the system. For systems exhibiting long-range charge transfer, fourth-generation machine learning potentials need to be used, which take global information about the system and electrostatic interactions into account. This can be achieved in a charge equilibration step, but the direct solution of the set of linear equations results in an unfavorable cubic scaling with system size, making this step computationally demanding for large systems. In this work, we propose an alternative approach that is based on the iterative solution of the charge equilibration problem (iQEq) to determine the atomic partial charges. We have implemented the iQEq method, which scales quadratically with system size, in the parallel molecular dynamics software LAMMPS for the example of a fourth-generation high-dimensional neural network potential (4G-HDNNP) intended to be used in combination with the n2p2 library. The method itself is general and applicable to many different types of fourth-generation MLPs. An assessment of the accuracy and the efficiency is presented for a benchmark system of FeCl3 in water.</description>
      <author>Emir Kocer, Andreas Singraber, Jonas A. Finkler, Philipp Misof, Tsz Wai Ko, Christoph Dellago, J&#246;rg Behler</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0252566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution of 2D Multinary Copper Chalcogenide Nanocrystals Enabled by Tuning Metal Precursors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501503</link>
      <description>Yu Li, Zheming Liu, Liya Zhang, Jie Chen, Shuaibing Wang, Mengmeng Ma, Zhe Yin, Zhongwei Man, Yi Ding, Zhijie Wang, Aiwei Tang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408921956

                It is challenging to clarify modulation mechanisms and structure-activity relationships in the ion-regulation engineering of multinary copper chalcogenide nanocrystals (NCs) for solar-to-hydrogen conversion. Herein, quaternary 2D Cu-In-Zn-S NCs are fabricated using various indium precursors to expose a high proportion of (0002) crystal facets that are positively correlated with their photocatalytic activities. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that the specific adsorption of anions on the crystal facets significantly influences their anisotropic growth and, in turn, photocatalytic performance. Furthermore, 2D Cu-In-Ga-Zn-S (CIGZS) NCs are prepared by partially or completely substituting In3+ with Ga3+ cations. As the Ga3&#8314; content gradually increases, the resulting photocatalytic activities follow a bell-shaped trend. The initial increase is attributed to a synergistic effect of optimized catalytic ability and a stronger electron driving force introduced by Ga3&#8314; incorporation. However, excessive Ga3&#8314; substitution widens the bandgap, reducing light absorption and conversion, ultimately leading to a decline in photocatalytic activities. Notably, the photocatalytic activity of Cu-Ga-Zn-S NCs with the highest hydrogen evolution rate of 1566.8 &#181;mol g-1 h-1 under visible light surpassed those of all In-based NCs due to enhanced electron-hole separation efficiency and highly effective active sites. This study provides valuable insights into the rational design of multinary copper-based photocatalysts for solar-driven hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Yu Li, Zheming Liu, Liya Zhang, Jie Chen, Shuaibing Wang, Mengmeng Ma, Zhe Yin, Zhongwei Man, Yi Ding, Zhijie Wang, Aiwei Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501503</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
