<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 01:37:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorine and Amine Functionalized Co, Rh, and Ir-Doped Porphyrins for Oxygen Reduction and Hydrogen Evolution Catalysis: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00986-y</link>
      <description>Angappan Kausalya, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415202592

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angappan Kausalya, Senthilkumar Lakshmipathi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-025-00986-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid synthesis of subnanoscale high-entropy alloys with ultrahigh durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-025-02358-9</link>
      <description>Chao Zhang, Zhongliao Wang, Chang Liu, Yu Bai, Changhao Liang, Jingxiang Low, Yujie Xiong, Nature Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415208913

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Zhang, Zhongliao Wang, Chang Liu, Yu Bai, Changhao Liang, Jingxiang Low, Yujie Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-025-02358-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decomposition dynamics of peroxide by a redox mediator-anchored doped graphene catalyst in a Li&#8211;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp02363g</link>
      <description>Babita Behera, Bhabani S. Mallik, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415209649

                DMSO solvent and tetrachloroquinone (TCQ) redox mediator synergistically promote Li 2 O 2 decomposition at the electrode-electrolyte interface via forming LiO 2 (DMSO) 3 and Li(DMSO) 4 complex in Li&#8211;O 2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Babita Behera, Bhabani S. Mallik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cp02363g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability, electronic properties, and synergistic photoelectrocatalytic activity in corrosion-resistant seawater-splitting anodes Co2(OH)3Cl and Ni2(OH)3Cl: constant-potential dynamics via continuum solvation models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164843</link>
      <description>Jiahao Zhang, Chen Kang, Jun-Feng Dong, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen, Zijing Lin, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415215014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahao Zhang, Chen Kang, Jun-Feng Dong, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen, Zijing Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts for Electrochemical Oxidation of Ammonia: A Comprehensive Review of Fundamentals and Optimization Strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202509364</link>
      <description>Yike Ye, Chencheng Dai, Kamal Elouarzaki, Gang Wu, Zhichuan J. Xu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415215383

                Abstract The realization of a hydrogen (H 2 ) economy confronts formidable challenges in storage, transportation, and logistics. To address these challenges, H 2 carriers have been proposed as alternative solutions. Ammonia (NH 3 ), as one of the most promising H 2 carriers, becomes a game&#8208;changer, offering higher volumetric H 2 density than compressed H 2 , simplified logistics, and compatibility with existing infrastructure, which thereby reduces costs and supply chain complexities. However, fully realizing NH 3 &#8217;s potential requires overcoming downstream inefficiencies associated with its conversion either back into H 2 or into energy. Downstream processes primarily include thermal cracking, NH 3 electrolysis, and direct NH 3 fuel cells, two of which are electrochemical systems leveraging the NH 3 oxidation reaction (AOR). The efficiency of these electrochemical systems is significantly limited by severe surface poisoning and poor AOR catalytic activity, underscoring the urgent need for advanced catalyst design. Here, a comprehensive review of AOR electrocatalysis is provided, with a focus on mechanistic insights into activity&#8208;governing steps and surface poisoning pathways. Recent advances in catalyst design are summarized, and overlooked factors are highlighted for performance enhancement. Finally, perspectives on future research directions are presented for AOR catalyst development to accelerate the integration of NH 3 &#8208;based technologies into the hydrogen economy.</description>
      <author>Yike Ye, Chencheng Dai, Kamal Elouarzaki, Gang Wu, Zhichuan J. Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202509364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protective mass-charge transfer regulation layer via magnetron co-sputtering towards stable Zn anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121641</link>
      <description>Xing Fan, Zhongxiao Song, Yangyang Liu, Acta Materialia. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415215911

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xing Fan, Zhongxiao Song, Yangyang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actamat.2025.121641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zigzag-edged B2S nanostructures as highly efficient electrocatalysts for ammonia oxidation: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137155</link>
      <description>Yasmeen G. Abou El-Reash, Mahmoud A. S. Sakr, Abdullah N. Alotaibi, Hazem Abdelsalam, Nahed H. Teleb, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415216447

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yasmeen G. Abou El-Reash, Mahmoud A. S. Sakr, Abdullah N. Alotaibi, Hazem Abdelsalam, Nahed H. Teleb</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and electronic properties of H- and O-Functionalized Diamond (100) with variable coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2025.100580</link>
      <description>James Cruz, Hector Gomez, Michael N. Groves, Mahesh R. Neupane, Carbon Trends. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415218477

                No abstract</description>
      <author>James Cruz, Hector Gomez, Michael N. Groves, Mahesh R. Neupane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cartre.2025.100580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Bonding Mediated Interfacial Charge Transfer Between BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and {Co&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;} Cubanes for Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202523057</link>
      <description>Hao Li, Zhiang Hou, Yao Hu, Jinnan Wang, Aimin Li, Philippe F.-X. Corvini, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415218772

                Abstract Although molecular cocatalysts (MCs) have demonstrated significant application potential for photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting, the immobilization and stabilization of them for long&#8208;term application remains challenging. Herein, an integrated photoanode (BiVO 4 @NM88B(Fe)/Co 4 O 4 ) is developed by immobilizing Co 4 O 4 cubanes onto NH 2 &#8208;MIL&#8208;88B(Fe) (NM88B(Fe)) decorated BiVO 4 via site&#8208;isolation strategy. The unoccupied coordination sites in NM88B(Fe) covalently bound to both Co 4 O 4 and BiVO 4 , which significantly decreases the interfacial charge transfer resistance of BiVO 4 @NM88B(Fe)/Co 4 O 4 and achieve prolonged stability. More importantly, the oxygen evolution cocatalyst (OEC) NM88B(Fe)/Co 4 O 4 remarkably lowered the energy barrier and thermodynamically favored surface water oxidation. Consequently, the photocurrent density of BiVO 4 @NM88B(Fe)/Co 4 O 4 photoanode achieved up to 5.26 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V RHE , which is 3.73 times higher than that of bare BiVO 4 . This work presents a site&#8208;isolation strategy to overcome molecular catalyst stabilization challenges in PEC systems while offering crucial insights into designing efficient charge transfer channels between OECs and semiconductors for enhanced water splitting performance.</description>
      <author>Hao Li, Zhiang Hou, Yao Hu, Jinnan Wang, Aimin Li, Philippe F.-X. Corvini</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202523057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning&#8208;Guided Design of L1&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Type Pt&#8208;Based High&#8208;Entropy Intermetallic Compound for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202510424</link>
      <description>Zhe Wang, Xi Chen, Ting Lin, Baokun Zhang, Kepeng Song, Lin Gu, Tomas Edvinsson, Hong Liu, Rafael B. Araujo, Xiaowen Yu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415219099

                Abstract Rational design of high&#8208;entropy intermetallic compounds (HEICs) remains challenging due to complex structure&#8208;property relationships and the lack of predictive tools. Here, a data&#8208;driven framework is presented to evaluate the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity of L1 2 &#8208;type quinary Pt 3 M(4) HEICs, where M comprises any four elements from six 3 d transition metals (Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Zn). Guided by the Pm&#8208;3m space group, 15 distinct compositions with numerous microstates are designed. A deep neural network, trained on 453 computed datasets, predicts hydrogen adsorption energy (&#8710; E H* ) across 20 000 microstructures per composition, enabling statistical mapping of site&#8208;specific performance. To capture the effect of local atomic environments, a novel statistical evaluation approach is introduced that quantifies the number of microstates falling within the optimal &#8710; E H* range, advancing beyond conventional mean&#8208;based evaluations. Among all candidates, Pt 3 (CrMnFeCo) emerges as the most promising HER catalyst, validated experimentally over a wide pH range. Further in&#8208;depth data mining reveals that surface Co, Cr, and Fe optimize Pt&#8208;Pt&#8208;M sites, while subsurface Ni and Co modulate Pt&#8208;Pt&#8208;Pt interactions. This study establishes a new paradigm for HEIC catalyst design and deepens the mechanistic understanding of activity origin in complex multimetal systems.</description>
      <author>Zhe Wang, Xi Chen, Ting Lin, Baokun Zhang, Kepeng Song, Lin Gu, Tomas Edvinsson, Hong Liu, Rafael B. Araujo, Xiaowen Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202510424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of iron, cobalt and copper in nickel-based bimetal catalysts for CO2 activation - Insights from DFT and DRIFTS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115537</link>
      <description>P Athira, Koustuv Ray, Molecular Catalysis. 588(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415219969

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P Athira, Koustuv Ray</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonequilibrium molecular dynamics of ion conduction with equivariant neural network models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/fll6-v5fx</link>
      <description>Saori Minami, Alex Kutana, Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Ryoji Asahi, Physical Review Materials. 9(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415225106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saori Minami, Alex Kutana, Ryosuke Jinnouchi, Ryoji Asahi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/fll6-v5fx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric nano-disordering with favored charge and reaction kinetics to boost CO2 photoreduction with high stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169616</link>
      <description>Yan Shen, Haojie Wang, Miao Jiang, Ziting Liu, Delong Chen, Chengfei Zhu, Yong Zhou, Zhigang Zou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415226020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Shen, Haojie Wang, Miao Jiang, Ziting Liu, Delong Chen, Chengfei Zhu, Yong Zhou, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169616</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RANGE: A robust adaptive nature-inspired global explorer of potential energy surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0288910</link>
      <description>Difan Zhang, Ma&#322;gorzata Z. Mako&#347;, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki&#8208;Alexandra Glezakou, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(15)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415243118

                With the growing demand for realistic representations of chemical structures and the advent of exascale computing, the intelligent sampling of potential energy surfaces and efficient identification of global minima have become more essential but also more feasible. Building on prior studies demonstrating the efficiency of the Artificial Bee Colony (ABC) swarm intelligence algorithm, we report a hybrid metaheuristic framework that integrates the adaptive exploration capabilities of ABC coupled with the exploitation strengths of genetic algorithms (GA) in a scalable, Python-based implementation. The resulting tool, RANGE (Robust Adaptive Nature-inspired Global Explorer), provides seamless interfaces to multiple potential energy evaluators, either directly or via widely used Python libraries, and is designed for high-performance computing environments. We describe the implementation details of RANGE and evaluate its performance, relative to ABC- or GA-alone based algorithms, on a variety of chemical systems, including molecular clusters and heterogeneous surfaces. Our results demonstrate RANGE&#8217;s efficiency, robustness, and broad applicability in addressing challenging global optimization problems in computational chemistry and materials science.</description>
      <author>Difan Zhang, Ma&#322;gorzata Z. Mako&#347;, Roger Rousseau, Vassiliki&#8208;Alexandra Glezakou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0288910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence in atomic layer deposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0004881</link>
      <description>Pouyan Navabi, Remya Ampadi Ramachandran, Harshdeep Bhatia, Majid Jaberi&#8208;Douraki, Urmila M. Diwekar, Cortino Sukotjo, Christos G. Takoudis, Journal of Vacuum Science &amp; Technology A Vacuum Surfaces and Films. 43(6)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415245310

                Atomic layer deposition (ALD) is a vapor-phase thin-film deposition technique offering precise atomic-scale control over film thickness and conformality. Widely used across diverse fields including microelectronics, energy storage, and biomaterials, traditional optimization of ALD processes typically relies on trial-and-error experimentation or computational simulations. Recently, artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) methods have emerged as powerful tools to significantly accelerate and improve ALD process optimization, material discovery, and fundamental understanding of ALD chemistry. In this review, we highlight recent advancements in the intersection of ALD and AI/ML, examining their roles in process optimization, new material development, reaction mechanism exploration, and the application of advanced algorithms, including large language models. Additionally, we introduce a bibliometric approach to systematically collect and analyze relevant scientific literature. Finally, we outline existing challenges and provide insights into the future potential of integrating AI with ALD to drive further innovation in materials science and engineering.</description>
      <author>Pouyan Navabi, Remya Ampadi Ramachandran, Harshdeep Bhatia, Majid Jaberi&#8208;Douraki, Urmila M. Diwekar, Cortino Sukotjo, Christos G. Takoudis</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0004881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrative Approaches to Reveal Catalyst Dynamics: Bridging &lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; Techniques, Theory, and Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c10976</link>
      <description>Tae Hyung Lee, Serin Lee, L. Yuan, Jennifer A. Dionne, Jungwon Park, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415246062

                Catalysts operate under complex conditions that require sophisticated approaches to understand their dynamics. This perspective outlines advances in experimental operando techniques, theoretical approaches, and machine learning (ML)-based data analysis to elucidate catalyst dynamics and improve the next-generation catalyst design. We first survey operando techniques, spanning electron microscopy, X-ray spectroscopy, and vibrational spectroscopy, that capture catalyst dynamics under operating conditions. We then discuss how operando observations integrate with and inform theoretical models, creating an iterative feedback loop between experiment and computation. Finally, we highlight how advanced data analysis, especially ML, enables the interpretation of high-dimensional operando data sets and can even inform catalyst design. Together, these synergetic approaches provide a unified framework for probing catalyst function and accelerating the rational design of efficient, durable catalytic systems for sustainable chemical manufacturing.</description>
      <author>Tae Hyung Lee, Serin Lee, L. Yuan, Jennifer A. Dionne, Jungwon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c10976</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation over MOF-74-Based Catalysts: Role of Physical Mixing and Mg-MOF-74 as a Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c04141</link>
      <description>Shunsaku Yasumura, Masahito Yamazaki, Masaru Ogura, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415252014

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shunsaku Yasumura, Masahito Yamazaki, Masaru Ogura</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c04141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Description of Adsorbed Hydroxyl to Make Predictive Catalytic Activity Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04121</link>
      <description>Eleonora Romeo, Futian You, Haibin Ma, Francesc Illas, Boon Siang Yeo, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415252388

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eleonora Romeo, Futian You, Haibin Ma, Francesc Illas, Boon Siang Yeo, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floating zone growth of large tetragonal Ruddlesden-Popper bilayer nickelate YySr3&#8722;yNi2&#8722;xAlxO7&#8722;&#948; single crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42005-025-02340-6</link>
      <description>Hasan Yilmaz, Pablo Sosa-Lizama, M. Knauft, Kathrin K&#252;ster, Ulrich Starke, Masahiko Isobe, Oliver Clemens, Peter A. van Aken, Y. Eren Suyolcu, Pascal Puphal, Communications Physics. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415260984

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hasan Yilmaz, Pablo Sosa-Lizama, M. Knauft, Kathrin K&#252;ster, Ulrich Starke, Masahiko Isobe, Oliver Clemens, Peter A. van Aken, Y. Eren Suyolcu, Pascal Puphal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42005-025-02340-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts for green hydrogen production in seawater: enhancement mechanism in catalytic activity and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5gc03577e</link>
      <description>Bingxu Wang, Xiao Tang, F.W. Sun, Sailong Wang, Xiaobin Liu, Jianping Lai, Jingqi Chi, Lei Wang, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415262798

                This study focuses on MSOEs as electrocatalysts for seawater oxygen evolution reaction (OER), summarizes strategies for improving the OER activity and durability, and discusses OER in seawater its improvement strategies based on sustainability.</description>
      <author>Bingxu Wang, Xiao Tang, F.W. Sun, Sailong Wang, Xiaobin Liu, Jianping Lai, Jingqi Chi, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5gc03577e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo&#8322;O&#8324;-Co&#8322;P Interfaces Inducing High-Spin Co&#178;&#8314; for Boosted Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147591</link>
      <description>Xu Fang, Zhonghai Zhang, Chen Hu, Lingjie Xuan, Bingbing Hong, Mengxue Sun, Yuhang Song, Jiang Wu, Jia Lin, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415269448

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu Fang, Zhonghai Zhang, Chen Hu, Lingjie Xuan, Bingbing Hong, Mengxue Sun, Yuhang Song, Jiang Wu, Jia Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultralow Ru Loading on Spinel Oxide Enhances Oxygen Coupling for Efficient Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c15539</link>
      <description>Mingxin Cai, Guopu Cai, Ke Liu, Degao Wang, Hongbin Zhao, Peilei He, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415272613

                The development of proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) technologies urgently demands electrocatalytic systems capable of maintaining exceptional activity and durability under harsh acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) conditions. Here, we present ultralow Ru loading on cobalt&#8211;manganese oxides (Ru&#8211;Co2MnO4.5) through a facile synthetic strategy. Ru and Co sites facilitate the direct coupling of the oxygen radicals, thereby exceeding the limitations of the scaling relation and triggering the oxide pathway mechanism. Structural characterizations and theoretical calculations demonstrate that the incorporation of Ru single atoms suppresses both lattice oxygen and metal dissolution while maintaining good coordination environments and crystal structures. Furthermore, Ru single-atom loading enhances the hydroxyl adsorption on the catalyst surface and promotes the OER kinetics. Consequently, the Ru&#8211;Co2MnO4.5 catalyst achieves an optimal trade-off between catalytic efficiency and structural durability. In 0.5 M H2SO4, the Ru&#8211;Co2MnO4.5 demonstrates a minimal overpotential of 176 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and exhibits excellent stability during 600 h. In the PEMWE device, the Ru&#8211;Co2MnO4.5 catalyst requires merely a voltage of 1.638 V to achieve 1 A cm&#8211;2, with an ultralow Ru loading of 20 &#956;g cm&#8211;2. The system can operate for over 100 h under a high current density of 1 A cm&#8211;2, showcasing its potential in a practical hydrogen production device. This work presents an innovative strategy for advancing the development of high-efficiency and large-scale green hydrogen production systems while elucidating the underlying reaction mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Mingxin Cai, Guopu Cai, Ke Liu, Degao Wang, Hongbin Zhao, Peilei He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c15539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Superhydrophobic Ni-W/GrPTFE by Reinforcing Ni-W with Graphene and Polytetrafluoroethylene to Enhance Fouling and Corrosion Resistance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/01457632.2025.2571271</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zafar Ullah, Ashfaq Ahmad, Mingyan Liu, Heat Transfer Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415274215

                Fouling and corrosion are critical challenges in heat transfer equipment. This study developed nickel-tungsten (Ni-W) composite coatings reinforced with micro- and nano-graphene (Gr) and polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) particles (Ni-W/Gr and Ni-W/GrPTFE) to enhance resistance to fouling and corrosion. The Ni-W/GrPTFE superhydrophobic coating exhibited a significantly greater water contact angle (152.1&#176;) compared to bare Q235 carbon steel (90.1&#176;) and a notably lower surface free energy of 3.48 mJ/m2, compared to 31.36 mJ/m2 for bare Q235 carbon steel. Surface roughness, chemical composition, and micromorphology were analyzed using atomic force microscopy, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy, and scanning electron microscopy. The electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results revealed superior corrosion resistance for the Ni-W/GrPTFE coating, with a minimal corrosion current density of 2.25 &#215; 10&#8722;5 &#181;A/cm2, a higher impedance modulus of 8.8 &#215; 104 &#937;&#183;cm2 at low frequencies, and substantial charge transfer resistance of 5.49 &#215; 104 &#937;&#183;cm2. Tafel polarization further confirmed a lower corrosion rate of 2.12x10&#8722;3 mm/a. Furthermore, fouling tests at various temperatures showed that the Ni-W/GrPTFE coating achieved a 90.74% fouling inhibition rate. Additionally, self-cleaning tests confirmed the absence of surface contaminants. These results indicate that the Ni-W/GrPTFE composite superhydrophobic coating offers exceptional durability, making it a promising solution for harsh conditions in heat transfer systems, geothermal applications, and chemical industries.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zafar Ullah, Ashfaq Ahmad, Mingyan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/01457632.2025.2571271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A survey of AI-supported materials informatics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cosrev.2025.100845</link>
      <description>Sanjay Chakraborty, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Martin Dahlqvist, Johanna Rosen, Fredrik Heintz, Computer Science Review. 59(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415278663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sanjay Chakraborty, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Martin Dahlqvist, Johanna Rosen, Fredrik Heintz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cosrev.2025.100845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cavity&#8208;Networked Copper Nanocatalysts with Acid&#8208;Tolerant Microenvironments for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction to Ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202520743</link>
      <description>Zhongshuang Xu, Qikui Fan, Huanran Miao, Xinwei Zhang, Hongyu Zhang, Xi Cao, Pengxu Yan, Xiai Zhang, Zhimao Yang, Jian Yang, Chuncai Kong, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415279076

                Abstract Gasophilic/hydrophobic microstructured Cu nanomaterials address the multi&#8208;carbon (C 2+ ) selectivity bottleneck in electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), yet their morphological control is hindered by low reduction potentials and high surface atomic mobility. This study reports a bioinspired gas&#8208;trapping hydrophobic Cu nanostructure (BGH&#8208;Cu) via in situ electrochemical reconstruction, forming an interconnected cavity network that confers gasophilic/hydrophobic properties. Mechanistic studies reveal cavities act as dynamic electrolyte reservoirs, selectively retaining OH &#8722; /K + to suppress proton transport and create a local micro&#8208;alkaline environment, while cavity&#8208;enhanced cation enrichment synergizes with C&#9472;C coupling. BGH&#8208;Cu achieves C 2 H 4 Faradaic efficiency of 54.7% at current density of 600 mA cm &#8722;2 in strongly acidic conditions (pH 1), with 63.7% single&#8208;pass carbon efficiency and 40 h stability in a membrane electrode assembly configuration. This work provides a non&#8208;extreme synthesis strategy for gasophilic/hydrophobic Cu nanomaterials, elucidates the &#8220;cavity microenvironment modulation&#8221; mechanism for C 2+ selectivity, and offers a new paradigm for high&#8208;current&#8208;density acidic CO 2 RR to C 2+ products.</description>
      <author>Zhongshuang Xu, Qikui Fan, Huanran Miao, Xinwei Zhang, Hongyu Zhang, Xi Cao, Pengxu Yan, Xiai Zhang, Zhimao Yang, Jian Yang, Chuncai Kong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202520743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TorchANI 2.0: An Extensible, High-Performance Library for the Design, Training, and Use of NN-IPs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01853</link>
      <description>Ignacio Pickering, Jiangeng Xue, Kate Huddleston, Nicholas Terrel, Adri&#225;n E. Roitberg, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415285772

                In this work, we introduce TorchANI 2.0, a significantly improved version of the free and open source TorchANI software package for training and evaluation of ANI (ANAKIN-ME) deep learning models. TorchANI 2.0 builds upon the foundation of its predecessor, while addressing its limitations and introducing new features. These changes greatly enhance its extensibility, performance, and suitability as a framework for developing models ready for molecular dynamics applications. These improvements include the introduction of a modular system to add arbitrary pairwise potentials to models, CUDA-accelerated optimization for faster and more memory-efficient calculation of local atomic features, and a batched system for better performance of network ensembles, among others. Our benchmarks demonstrate that TorchANI 2.0 achieves significant speedup over previous versions in both training and inference, and the library enhancements allow users to train physically constrained models that better represent important qualities of chemical systems. We demonstrate this by introducing three new ANI models that incorporate these features and evaluating their capabilities.</description>
      <author>Ignacio Pickering, Jiangeng Xue, Kate Huddleston, Nicholas Terrel, Adri&#225;n E. Roitberg</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Modeling of Defects in Nanomaterials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527850273.ch7</link>
      <description>C.M. Ramos-Castillo, J. Hern&#225;ndez-Tecorralco, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415289901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C.M. Ramos-Castillo, J. Hern&#225;ndez-Tecorralco</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527850273.ch7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect and Interface Engineering in Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527850273.ch15</link>
      <description>J.C. Cruz, Blandy Pamplona-Solis, K. Garc&#237;a Uitz, M.P. Gurrola, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415290180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J.C. Cruz, Blandy Pamplona-Solis, K. Garc&#237;a Uitz, M.P. Gurrola</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527850273.ch15</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Synthesis and Device Integration of Long 17-Atom-Wide Armchair Graphene Nanoribbons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c11981</link>
      <description>Jeong Ha Hwang, Nicol&#242; Bassi, Mayada Fadel, Oliver Braun, Tim Dumslaff, Carlo A. Pignedoli, Michael Stiefel, Roman Furrer, Hironobu Hayashi, Hiroko Yamada, Akimitsu Narita, Kl&#228;us M&#252;llen, Michel Calame, Mickael L. Perrin, Rom&#225;n Fasel, Pascal Ruffieux, Vincent Meunier, Gabriela Borin Barin, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415297053

                Seventeen-carbon-atom-wide armchair graphene nanoribbons (17-AGNRs) are promising candidates for high-performance electronic devices due to their narrow electronic bandgap. Atomic precision in edge structure and width control is achieved through a bottom-up on-surface synthesis (OSS) approach from tailored molecular precursors in ultrahigh vacuum (UHV). This synthetic protocol must be optimized to meet the structural requirements for device integration, with the ribbon length being the most critical parameter. Here, we report optimized OSS conditions that produce 17-AGNRs with an average length of &#8764;17 nm. This length enhancement is achieved through a gradual temperature ramping during an extended annealing period, combined with a template-like effect driven by monomer assembly at high surface coverage. The resulting 17-AGNRs are comprehensively characterized in UHV by using scanning probe techniques and Raman spectroscopy. Raman measurements following substrate transfer enabled the characterization of GNRs' length distribution on the device substrate and confirmed their stability under ambient conditions and harsh chemical environments, including acid vapors and etchants. The increased length and ambient stability of the 17-AGNRs led to their reliable integration into device architectures. As a proof of concept, we integrate 17-AGNRs into field-effect transistors (FETs) with graphene electrodes and confirm that electronic transport occurs through the GNRs. This work demonstrates the feasibility of integrating narrow bandgap GNRs into functional devices and contributes to advancing the development of carbon-based nanoelectronics.</description>
      <author>Jeong Ha Hwang, Nicol&#242; Bassi, Mayada Fadel, Oliver Braun, Tim Dumslaff, Carlo A. Pignedoli, Michael Stiefel, Roman Furrer, Hironobu Hayashi, Hiroko Yamada, Akimitsu Narita, Kl&#228;us M&#252;llen, Michel Calame, Mickael L. Perrin, Rom&#225;n Fasel, Pascal Ruffieux, Vincent Meunier, Gabriela Borin Barin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c11981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Locking the Lattice Oxygen in Commercial RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for High Stable Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202523636</link>
      <description>Yanhui Yu, G. S. Huang, Wenjun Fan, Zihao Fan, Hanqing Gao, Daoxiong Wu, Tianjiao Wang, Jing Li, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang, Peilin Deng, Ying Liang, Xinlong Tian, Peng Rao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415304115

                Abstract Efficient and sustainable hydrogen production via proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) requires the development of robust low&#8208;cost oxygen evolution reaction catalysts. A robust acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst is fabricated, featuring single Co atoms incorporated into commercial RuO 2 (Co SA /RuO 2 ) and demonstrate that the Co sites suppress the mobility of lattice oxygen in commercial RuO 2 , thereby eliminating the stability&#8208;limited lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism and improving the catalyst stability. The theoretical calculations reveal that the atomically dispersed Co sites shifts the &#949;d&#8208;dn of RuO 2 downward, optimizing the adsorption of O * and * OOH, thereby changing the rate&#8208;determining step and improving the catalytic performance. In addition, atomically dispersed Co enhances the strength of the Ru&#8211;O lattice interaction, thereby alleviating the dissolution of Ru and effectively improving the stability of the catalyst under OER conditions. Specifically, the Co SA /RuO 2 &#8208;promoted PEMWE requires a voltage of 1.662 V to achieve a current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 and can be stably performed for &gt;550 h at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 with negligible performance decay. Thus, this work paves the way for the fabrication of highly active and stable ruthenium oxide&#8211;based OER catalysts and their use as alternatives to the costly Ir&#8208;based counterparts.</description>
      <author>Yanhui Yu, G. S. Huang, Wenjun Fan, Zihao Fan, Hanqing Gao, Daoxiong Wu, Tianjiao Wang, Jing Li, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang, Peilin Deng, Ying Liang, Xinlong Tian, Peng Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202523636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridinic-N Dominates ORR Performance: Decoding Configuration-Sensitive Electrocatalysis of N-Doped Graphene Quantum Dots</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04899</link>
      <description>Jiayu Yuan, Xiao&#8208;Bao Yang, Haofan Wang, Yonghai Cao, Hongjuan Wang, Guangxing Yang, Hao Yu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415309445

                Developing low-cost, high-performance metal-free oxygen reduction catalysts demands precise quantification of structure-performance relationships in nitrogen-doped carbons. Structural search algorithms combined with density functional theory (DFT) enable comprehensive analysis of catalytic performance versus structural features. Using nitrogen-doped graphene quantum dots (NGQDs) as models, we computationally resolve how nitrogen species types (pyridinic-N, graphitic-N) and substitution positions influence the stability and intrinsic activity. Boltzmann statistics quantify the contributions of all configurations to the current density during oxygen reduction. Furthermore, we identify dominant configurations grouping NGQDs into configuration lumps. Thermodynamically, nitrogen atoms preferentially occupy carbon atoms at defect-adjacent sites as pyridinic-N. Their spatial distribution controls local atomic charge redistribution and adsorption environments, thereby modulating intrinsic activity. These materials exhibit extreme configuration sensitivity: thermodynamically stable dominant configurations may contribute minimally to current density. Crucially, lumped pyridinic-N configurations dominate ORR performance. This work provides theoretical insights supporting carbon adjacent to pyridinic-N as the primary active site in N-doped carbon ORR catalysts. It establishes a universal framework for analyzing structure&#8211;activity relationships in nonmodel catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Jiayu Yuan, Xiao&#8208;Bao Yang, Haofan Wang, Yonghai Cao, Hongjuan Wang, Guangxing Yang, Hao Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Path-integral molecular dynamics with actively-trained and universal machine learning force fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109902</link>
      <description>&#1040;. &#1040;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1099;&#1093;, Nikita Rybin, Ivan Novikov, Alexander V. Shapeev, Computer Physics Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415313398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1040;. &#1040;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1099;&#1093;, Nikita Rybin, Ivan Novikov, Alexander V. Shapeev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109902</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C Catalyst Integrating Single&#8208;Atom Fe and Nanoscale CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; towards Efficient Oxygen Reduction Reaction for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries&lt;sup&gt;&#8224;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.70315</link>
      <description>Yukui Pei, Jianfeng Zuo, Xiannong Tang, Longbin Li, Ting Hu, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415313625

                Comprehensive Summary Developing high&#8208;performance, durable, and cost&#8208;effective oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts is essential for advancing next&#8208;generation energy devices like zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, we engineer a hybrid Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C catalyst (FeSA&#8208;Fe NP /CeO 2 @NC) integrating atomically dispersed Fe&#8208;N x sites, Fe nanoparticles, and oxygen vacancy&#8208;rich CeO 2 nanoparticles within a nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon matrix. Interfacial charge transfer and oxygen vacancy&#8208;mediated electron redistribution, synergistically enhanced by strong metal&#8208;support interactions (SMSI), optimize the electronic configuration of Fe&#8208;N x sites and reduce their electron density. The resulting catalyst exhibits exceptional ORR activity and stability, featuring a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.925 V (vs. RHE) in alkaline media and minimal degradation (1% and 2.8% negative shifts after 10,000/20,000 cycles). In ZABs, it achieves a peak power density of 310.29 mW&#183;cm &#8211;2 while sustaining stable operation for over 600 h. This work demonstrates dual role of CeO 2 in enhancing activity and stability, establishing a design principle for high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts in energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Yukui Pei, Jianfeng Zuo, Xiannong Tang, Longbin Li, Ting Hu, Dirk L&#252;tzenkirchen&#8208;Hecht, Kai Yuan, Yiwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.70315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Aluminum Distribution in Cu-MOR Systems on Methane-to-Methanol Conversion: A Combined Experimental and Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c06045</link>
      <description>Peter N. Njoroge, Bj&#248;rn Gading Solemsli, Asanka Wijerathne, Izar Capel Berdiell, Agnieszka Seremak, Mario Chiesa, Yu&#8208;Kai Liao, Beatrice Garetto, Nishant N. Patel, Karoline Kvande, Elisa Borfecchia, Christopher Paolucci, Unni Olsbye, Pablo Beato, Stian Svelle, Sebastian Prodinger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415313906

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peter N. Njoroge, Bj&#248;rn Gading Solemsli, Asanka Wijerathne, Izar Capel Berdiell, Agnieszka Seremak, Mario Chiesa, Yu&#8208;Kai Liao, Beatrice Garetto, Nishant N. Patel, Karoline Kvande, Elisa Borfecchia, Christopher Paolucci, Unni Olsbye, Pablo Beato, Stian Svelle, Sebastian Prodinger</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c06045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Accelerated Discovery of Electrocatalyst Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.5c00135</link>
      <description>Yifan Zeng, Jun Wang, Fengwang Li, Tongliang Liu, Aoni Xu, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415317511

                The rational exploration and design of high-performance, stable electrocatalysts are crucial for efficient renewable energy storage, conversion, and utilization. Artificial intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing this field by significantly reducing the time and cost associated with conventional trial-and-error experimentation and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Advancements in data quality, computing power, and algorithms have positioned AI as a key enabler in understanding electrocatalytic mechanisms, designing advanced materials, analyzing structures, and predicting performance. This review highlights the pivotal role of AI in electrocatalyst discovery, focusing on the critical aspects of data, descriptors, and machine learning models. We discuss various AI approaches, including their applications in accelerating DFT calculations, exploring reaction mechanisms, designing electrocatalysts, and predicting performance, providing a comprehensive overview of the current state-of-the-art. We also address the challenges and opportunities in leveraging AI for electrocatalyst development, emphasizing the importance of data quality, model selection, and collaborative research. This review aims to guide researchers in effectively utilizing AI to accelerate the discovery and optimization of electrocatalysts for a renewable energy future.</description>
      <author>Yifan Zeng, Jun Wang, Fengwang Li, Tongliang Liu, Aoni Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.5c00135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Infrared Spectra of OH&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;&#183;(H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;and OH&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;&#183;(H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; with Constrained Nuclear-Electronic Orbital Molecular Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c04334</link>
      <description>Zhe Liu, Yiwen Wang, Yuzhe Zhang, Nan Yang, Yang Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415320972

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhe Liu, Yiwen Wang, Yuzhe Zhang, Nan Yang, Yang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.5c04334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled synthesis of NiFe alloy nanoparticles confined in carbon matrices: study on the effect of morphology on enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.139301</link>
      <description>Xiang Li, Silvia Giordani, Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Devis Di Tommaso, Cristina Giordano, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415327059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Li, Silvia Giordani, Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Devis Di Tommaso, Cristina Giordano</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.139301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution electrocatalysis resilient to voltage fluctuations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01665-y</link>
      <description>Ailong Li, Hideshi Ooka, Shuang Kong, Kiyohiro Adachi, Yuchen Zhang, Kazuna Fushimi, Satoru Hamamoto, Masaki Oura, Sun Hee Kim, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura, Nature Sustainability. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415349311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ailong Li, Hideshi Ooka, Shuang Kong, Kiyohiro Adachi, Yuchen Zhang, Kazuna Fushimi, Satoru Hamamoto, Masaki Oura, Sun Hee Kim, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41893-025-01665-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D Mo&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanowires for Sustainable Hydrogen Evolution: Size and Fermi-Level Driven Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c05646</link>
      <description>Xiaoqing Shang, Lingxiao Zhu, He Ma, Yue Liu, Yan Liu, Tian Cui, Da Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415352692

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoqing Shang, Lingxiao Zhu, He Ma, Yue Liu, Yan Liu, Tian Cui, Da Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c05646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic NiO-Pt heterostructure for enhanced hydrogen evolution: Boosting charge transfer and catalytic efficiency in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137226</link>
      <description>Faria Rafique, Shahzad Ameen, Muhammad Ali, Aleena Tahir, Aashaq Shah, A. U. Bhatti, Tanveer ul Haq, Mira Tul Zubaida Butt, Ammar Ahmed Khan, Saleh A. Ahmed, Irshad Hussain, Habib ur Rehman, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415355028

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faria Rafique, Shahzad Ameen, Muhammad Ali, Aleena Tahir, Aashaq Shah, A. U. Bhatti, Tanveer ul Haq, Mira Tul Zubaida Butt, Ammar Ahmed Khan, Saleh A. Ahmed, Irshad Hussain, Habib ur Rehman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dpdata: A Scalable Python Toolkit for Atomistic Machine Learning Data Sets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01767</link>
      <description>Jinzhe Zeng, Xulong Peng, Yong&#8208;Bin Zhuang, Haidi Wang, Fengbo Yuan, Duo Zhang, Renxi Liu, Yingze Wang, Ping Tuo, Yuzhi Zhang, Yixiao Chen, Yifan Li, Cao Thang Nguyen, Jiameng Huang, Anyang Peng, Mari&#225;n Rynik, Weihong Xu, Zezhong Zhang, Xuyuan Zhou, Tao Chen, Jiahao Fan, Wanrun Jiang, Bowen Li, Denan Li, Haoxi Li, Wenshuo Liang, Rundong Liao, Liping Liu, Chenxing Luo, Logan Ward, Kaiwei Wan, Junjie Wang, Pan Xiang, Chengqian Zhang, Jinchao Zhang, R. Zhou, Jiaxin Zhu, Linfeng Zhang, Han Wang, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415356660

                Seamless management of atomistic data sets is a critical prerequisite for the successful development and deployment of machine learning potentials (MLPs). Here, we present dpdata, an open-source Python library designed to streamline every aspect of MLP data handling. Built upon a flexible, plugin-based architecture, dpdata supports reading, writing, and converting between a broad range of file formats&#9472;from popular quantum-chemistry packages and molecular-dynamics engines to specialized MLP frameworks. Users may define custom data types, formats, drivers, and minimizers, enabling effortless extension to emerging software. Key utilities include automated train-test splitting, coordinate perturbation for active learning, outlier-energy removal, &#916;-learning data set generation, error-metric computation, and unit conversion. Through efficient NumPy-backed storage and system-level operations, dpdata achieves significant memory saving and inference speedups over configuration-by-configuration tools such as ASE. We also highlight practical impact, with dpdata used across published studies, for format conversion, data storage, coordinate perturbation, and utilization in other projects for data processing.</description>
      <author>Jinzhe Zeng, Xulong Peng, Yong&#8208;Bin Zhuang, Haidi Wang, Fengbo Yuan, Duo Zhang, Renxi Liu, Yingze Wang, Ping Tuo, Yuzhi Zhang, Yixiao Chen, Yifan Li, Cao Thang Nguyen, Jiameng Huang, Anyang Peng, Mari&#225;n Rynik, Weihong Xu, Zezhong Zhang, Xuyuan Zhou, Tao Chen, Jiahao Fan, Wanrun Jiang, Bowen Li, Denan Li, Haoxi Li, Wenshuo Liang, Rundong Liao, Liping Liu, Chenxing Luo, Logan Ward, Kaiwei Wan, Junjie Wang, Pan Xiang, Chengqian Zhang, Jinchao Zhang, R. Zhou, Jiaxin Zhu, Linfeng Zhang, Han Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.5c01767</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature-dependent mechanism evolution on RhRu3Ox for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64286-1</link>
      <description>Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, Heng Liu, Sihua Feng, Xiaozhi Su, Jie Xu, Hengli Duan, Ruiqi Liu, Yingkang Qin, Wensheng Yan, Sheng Zhu, Rui Wu, Hao Li, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415358253

                The oxygen evolution reaction, as the anodic reaction of many electrochemical devices, plays a crucial role in energy conversion. However, the insufficient stability of non-iridium-based materials during the oxygen evolution reaction has severely limited the large-scale application of such devices. Here, using a home-made operando differential electrochemical mass spectrometry system, we show a temperature dependent mechanism evolution effect of RhRu3Ox in the oxygen evolution process, which highlights the role of temperature in triggering mechanism evolution. This effect enriches the strategies for pathway manipulation. Since different kinetic pathways can influence catalyst stability, this finding suggests that temperature-dependent pathway regulation may serve as an approach to optimize stability. To evaluate the potential of RhRu3Ox for practical applications, we assemble it into a proton exchange membrane electrolyzer and demonstrate its stability at room temperature for over 1000 hours at a current density of 200 mA cm&#8722;2. Density functional theory studies suggest that the existence of a kinetic barrier related to lattice oxygen activation might be the reason for the observed temperature dependent behavior of RhRu3Ox at elevated temperatures. The oxygen evolution reaction enables many clean energy technologies, but most acid-unstable catalysts still block deployment. Here the authors report a temperature dependent mechanistic evolution in RhRu3Ox that links reaction pathways to stability, enabling durable acidic water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Ming&#8208;Rong Qu, Heng Liu, Sihua Feng, Xiaozhi Su, Jie Xu, Hengli Duan, Ruiqi Liu, Yingkang Qin, Wensheng Yan, Sheng Zhu, Rui Wu, Hao Li, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64286-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen evolution performances of NiO-based electrocatalysts through synergistic plasma processing and laser treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ya00273g</link>
      <description>Davide Barreca, Alessandro Bellucci, Matteo Mastellone, D.M. Trucchi, Chiara Maccato, Elisa Sefora Pierobon, Alberto Gasparotto, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Energy Advances. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415369965

                Engineering of NiO-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution has been demonstrated by a combined plasma synthesis and ex situ laser treatment.</description>
      <author>Davide Barreca, Alessandro Bellucci, Matteo Mastellone, D.M. Trucchi, Chiara Maccato, Elisa Sefora Pierobon, Alberto Gasparotto, Gian Andrea Rizzi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ya00273g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Single-Step Synthesis of PVP-Stabilized Ru NPs for Electrochemical Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02899</link>
      <description>Rahul Bhise, Riddhi Kadrekar, Priti Singh, Nagapradeep Nidamanuri, Priyamvada Arte, Pinku Nath, Yu Wang, Arif D. Sheikh, Mudit Dixit, Sushant P. Sahu, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415376615

                An efficient electrochemical hydrogen generation catalyst composed of robust ruthenium nanoparticles (Ru NPs) was synthesized through a simple one-pot hydrothermal reaction, where formaldehyde was employed as a reductant and low-molecular-weight poly(vinylpyrrolidone) (PVP) was employed as a stabilizing agent. The as-synthesized nanoparticles were initially characterized by powder X-ray diffraction, which confirmed their hexagonal, close-packed ruthenium phase. Structural analysis was performed by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM), which disclosed PVP-stabilized nanoflowers composed of Ru NPs with an average diameter of 5 nm. Further, energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX) confirmed the presence of ruthenium and carbon, and their oxidation states were also studied with X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). The as-synthesized PVP-supported Ru NPs exhibited remarkable hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity, with overpotentials of 51 and 39 mV at a cathodic current density of &#8722;10 mA cm&#8211;2 and corresponding Tafel slopes of 23 and 40 mV dec&#8211;1 in acidic and alkaline conditions, respectively. Such a high performance of the PVP-protected Ru NPs was further evaluated in a continuous manner by using an electrolyzer flow cell, and our findings were supported by the corresponding density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Calculations of the Gibbs free energy for varied surface coverage on the (002) facet revealed that the individual site activity improved with an increase in surface coverage, enhancing the continuous HER performance. Besides reinforcing the exploitation of eco-friendly raw materials for nanocatalyst development, this work serves as a prelude to our upcoming systematic investigations on the influence of the molecular weight of the PVP polymer on the size of metallic nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>Rahul Bhise, Riddhi Kadrekar, Priti Singh, Nagapradeep Nidamanuri, Priyamvada Arte, Pinku Nath, Yu Wang, Arif D. Sheikh, Mudit Dixit, Sushant P. Sahu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02899</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable dioxin-linked metallophthalocyanine covalent organic frameworks as trifunctional electrocatalysts for overall water splitting and oxygen reduction: A combining density functional theory and machine learning study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.152132</link>
      <description>Lu Song, Yi Ding, Jiadi Ying, Tiancun Liu, Qiang Li, Yong Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 187(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415376829

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Song, Yi Ding, Jiadi Ying, Tiancun Liu, Qiang Li, Yong Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.152132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition-Metal Doped Armchair Hexagonal SiC Quantum Dots: Insights into Stability, Electronic Structure, and Optoelectronic Properties from First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7654081/v1</link>
      <description>Nahed H. Teleb, Mahmoud A.S. Sakr, Ghada M. Abdelrazek, Omar H. Abd&#8208;Elkader, M. Abdel Rafea, Hazem Abdelsalam, Qinfang Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415382862

                Abstract The rational design of stable, earth-abundant quantum dots with tunable electronic and optical properties is crucial for advancing sustainable optoelectronic and photocatalytic technologies. In this work, density functional theory (DFT) is employed to investigate pristine and 3d transition-metal (TM)-doped armchair hexagonal silicon carbide quantum dots (AH-SiC-QDs, Si&#8325;&#8327;C&#8325;&#8327;H&#8323;&#8320;). Structural analysis reveals that pristine AH-SiC-QDs exhibit high stability (5.612 eV), surpassing previously reported SiC- and AlN-based QDs. Upon TM incorporation, stability remains robust, with Ni-doping providing the strongest binding and Sc-doping the weakest. Electronic structure calculations show significant dopant-induced modifications in HOMO&#8211;LUMO distributions and bandgaps, where Ti- and Sc-doped systems achieve remarkable bandgap narrowing (1.056 and 0.919 eV), enhancing electronic coupling with the host lattice. Optical absorption studies demonstrate pronounced red-shifts into the visible and near-infrared regions, with Sc- and V-doped systems offering extended light-harvesting potential. Mulliken charge and natural bond orbital (NBO) analyses confirm strong donor&#8211;acceptor interactions, orbital rehybridization, and enhanced charge transfer, directly linking dopant chemistry to improved catalytic and optoelectronic behavior. These findings establish TM-doped AH-SiC-QDs as versatile and highly tunable platforms for next-generation photocatalysis and energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Nahed H. Teleb, Mahmoud A.S. Sakr, Ghada M. Abdelrazek, Omar H. Abd&#8208;Elkader, M. Abdel Rafea, Hazem Abdelsalam, Qinfang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7654081/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a scientific community? The WOEPS workshop and the evolution of the economics of science, 1994&#8211;2023</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10438599.2025.2571618</link>
      <description>Daniel Souza, Aldo Geuna, Cornelia Lawson, Economics of Innovation and New Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415387026

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Souza, Aldo Geuna, Cornelia Lawson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/10438599.2025.2571618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain&#8208;Tunable Bandgaps, Strong Light Absorption, and Active Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Light Metal&#8208;Decorated Borophene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pssr.202500326</link>
      <description>Zhen Gao, Fengxian Ma, Yalong Jiao, physica status solidi (RRL) - Rapid Research Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415387753

                Current strategies for stabilizing 2D borophene sheets and compensating for boron's electron deficiency primarily rely on transition metals, many of which are heavy and costly, thereby limiting their practical applications. In contrast, the use of light&#8208;metal elements to stabilize borophene has remained largely unexplored. This work demonstrates that the light&#8208;metal beryllium (Be) can effectively stabilize 2D boron sheets. Through swarm&#8208;intelligence structural searches combined with first&#8208;principles calculations, three stable monolayers of beryllium tetraboride (BeB 4 )&#8212;the &#945;&#8208;, &#946;&#8208;, and &#947;&#8208;phases&#8212;are predicted. The &#945;&#8208;BeB 4 phase is metallic, while &#946;&#8208; and &#947;&#8208;BeB 4 are indirect semiconductors with bandgaps of 0.39 and 1.65 eV, respectively. Notably, biaxial strain can reversibly tune &#946;&#8208;BeB 4 between semiconducting and metallic states. Furthermore, &#947;&#8208;BeB 4 exhibits a high visible&#8208;light absorption coefficient (3.80 &#215; 10 5 cm &#8722; 1 ) and an out&#8208;of&#8208;plane negative Poisson's ratio, indicating auxetic behavior. Remarkably, &#945;&#8208;BeB 4 demonstrates a near&#8208;zero Gibbs free energy for hydrogen adsorption, suggesting excellent catalytic activity for the hydrogen evolution reaction. These unique properties position BeB 4 monolayers as promising, lightweight, and cost&#8208;effective candidates for next&#8208;generation energy conversion and optoelectronic applications.</description>
      <author>Zhen Gao, Fengxian Ma, Yalong Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pssr.202500326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computation of a Quasiparticle Band Structure with the Quantum-Selected Configuration Interaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7566/jpsj.94.114002</link>
      <description>Takahiro Ohgoe, Hokuto Iwakiri, Kazuhide Ichikawa, Sho Koh, Masaya Kohda, Journal of the Physical Society of Japan. 94(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415388831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Takahiro Ohgoe, Hokuto Iwakiri, Kazuhide Ichikawa, Sho Koh, Masaya Kohda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7566/jpsj.94.114002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven optimization of boron-doped graphene work function for enhanced anode materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137168</link>
      <description>Qingwei Zhang, Lai Li, Yunhua Lu, Chao Zhang, Junan Zhang, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415390254

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingwei Zhang, Lai Li, Yunhua Lu, Chao Zhang, Junan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.137168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction on MXene Materials via First-Principles Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03901</link>
      <description>Colton J. Lund, Jiayi Xu, Cong Liu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415396086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Colton J. Lund, Jiayi Xu, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulse-combustion-synthesized carbon-supported NiM (M = Co, Cu) nanoparticles: A framework for alkaline oxygen evolution studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116492</link>
      <description>Brend de Coen, Luis Fernando Le&#243;n&#8208;Fernandez, Kevin Van Daele, Nick Daems, Matija Gatalo, Miha Hotko, Nejc Hodnik, Tom Breugelmans, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415401262

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brend de Coen, Luis Fernando Le&#243;n&#8208;Fernandez, Kevin Van Daele, Nick Daems, Matija Gatalo, Miha Hotko, Nejc Hodnik, Tom Breugelmans</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning (ML)-assisted development of 2D green catalysts to support sustainability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5mh01739d</link>
      <description>Manshu Dhillon, Sadhan Mahapatra, Adreeja Basu, Shyam S. Pandey, Manpreet Singh Manna, Shantanu Bhattacharya, Basab Chakraborty, Ajeet Kaushik, Aviru Kumar Basu, Materials Horizons. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415209188

                Combining green-synthesized 2D nanomaterials with ML for catalytic applications to support sustainability.</description>
      <author>Manshu Dhillon, Sadhan Mahapatra, Adreeja Basu, Shyam S. Pandey, Manpreet Singh Manna, Shantanu Bhattacharya, Basab Chakraborty, Ajeet Kaushik, Aviru Kumar Basu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5mh01739d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Carbon Dioxide Capture and Electrochemical Conversion: Chemistry, Electrode and Electrolyzer Design, and Economic Viability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202502564</link>
      <description>Behnam Nourmohammadi Khiarak, Gelson T. S. T. da Silva, Hongchang Lai, Hossein Esmaeili, Anh Ngoc Nguyen, Khac&#8208;Huy Dinh, Qian Zhang, L&#250;cia H. Mascaro, Cao&#8208;Thang Dinh, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415213415

                Abstract Electrochemical carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) conversion (ECC) offers a promising route to reduce CO 2 emissions and to store renewable electricity in the form of chemical fuels. To date, ECC has been mainly based on pure CO 2 gas isolated from carbon capture solutions, which is an energy&#8208;intensive step. Recently, direct CO 2 conversion from a capture solution, which enables integrated CO 2 capture and electrochemical conversion, has attracted attention because it can eliminate the energy&#8208;intensive CO 2 isolation step. In addition, producing concentrated gas products in integrated systems reduces the cost for downstream separation. This review discusses the key aspects of integrated CO 2 capture and electrochemical conversion systems, including direct air capture (DAC), the chemistry of CO 2 capture and release, electrode designs and system configurations, as well as technoeconomic viability. First, the fundamental concepts and chemistry of CO 2 capture and in situ CO 2 release in electrochemical reactors are summarized. Then, recent advancements in integrated systems are discussed, covering both system configurations and electrode designs. Potential avenues for enhancing product selectivity toward high&#8208;value chemicals, such as ethylene and ethanol, as well as lowering operating cell voltages and improving the economic viability of integrated systems, are highlighted. Finally, major technical and economic challenges as well as emerging research opportunities in the domain of integrated CO 2 capture and conversion are highlighted.</description>
      <author>Behnam Nourmohammadi Khiarak, Gelson T. S. T. da Silva, Hongchang Lai, Hossein Esmaeili, Anh Ngoc Nguyen, Khac&#8208;Huy Dinh, Qian Zhang, L&#250;cia H. Mascaro, Cao&#8208;Thang Dinh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202502564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of aluminum doping in enhancing high-temperature stability of lithium-rich cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169609</link>
      <description>Min&#8208;Ho Kim, Aditya Narayan Singh, Miran Ha, Wang&#8208;Geun Lee, Saeed Pourasad, Abhishek Meena, Haeseong Jang, Jeongwoo Seo, Jaehyun Park, Seok Ju Kang, Kyung&#8208;Wan Nam, Tae Joo Shin, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Kwang S. Kim, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415225623

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min&#8208;Ho Kim, Aditya Narayan Singh, Miran Ha, Wang&#8208;Geun Lee, Saeed Pourasad, Abhishek Meena, Haeseong Jang, Jeongwoo Seo, Jaehyun Park, Seok Ju Kang, Kyung&#8208;Wan Nam, Tae Joo Shin, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Kwang S. Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169609</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative evaluation of isotherm and kinetic models for optimizing fixed-bed direct air capture systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169895</link>
      <description>Dana Marini&#269;, &#381;an Lavri&#269;, Matej Hu&#353;, Janvit Ter&#382;an, Bla&#382; Likozar, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415370898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dana Marini&#269;, &#381;an Lavri&#269;, Matej Hu&#353;, Janvit Ter&#382;an, Bla&#382; Likozar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Catalysis Understanding via Large Language Model Data Extraction and Shallow Machine Learning Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c01087</link>
      <description>Brianna R. Farris, Kevin C. Leonard, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415398029

                Catalysis is inherently complex. The lack of precise knowledge available to experimental researchers about the microenvironment, catalytic sites, mechanisms, and changes that occur under reaction conditions has hindered the effectiveness of deep-learning artificial intelligence algorithms to predict catalyst behavior under reaction conditions. Given the type and quality of data available in the scientific literature, there are still open questions on how machine learning can be used by experimentalists working in the field of catalysis to accelerate catalyst design. Here, we present a framework that leverages large language models to extract textual data from known and trusted sources to automatically generate large, but relatively low-fidelity, experimental catalysis data sets across many research groups. We also show that instead of using deep-learning models, which require high-quality data, shallow learning models with posthoc interpretability can extract valuable information about experimental catalytic systems from these low-fidelity data sets. The innovation of this work lies not in the model development but in the prompt engineering, data encoding, and question architectures employed to extract meaningful information. We applied this framework to two different model reactions: the electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide and the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction. We showcase that this framework has the ability to uncover known and established facts within the catalysis community, such as the catalytic properties of Cu, as well as novel insights, including the critical role of voltages above a certain threshold in producing multicarbon products from CO2. We anticipate that this proposed framework will serve as an entryway for experimental catalytic researchers to utilize machine learning to rapidly process literature, generate novel hypotheses, and design experiments to accelerate catalyst development.</description>
      <author>Brianna R. Farris, Kevin C. Leonard</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c01087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00016-3</link>
      <description>, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415297692

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00016-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear deterministic hybrid dynamic modeling of time-to-event processes (LDHDM)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00007-2</link>
      <description>G.S. Ladde, Emmanuel A. Appiah, Jay G. Ladde, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415298230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G.S. Ladde, Emmanuel A. Appiah, Jay G. Ladde</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-322343-3.00007-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simple and Scalable Kernel Density Approach for Reliable Uncertainty Quantification in Atomistic Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02595</link>
      <description>Daniel Willimetz, Luk&#225;&#353; Grajciar, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4415262246

                Machine learning models are increasingly used to predict material properties and accelerate atomistic simulations, but the reliability of their predictions depends on the representativeness of the training data. We present a scalable, GPU-accelerated uncertainty quantification framework based on k-nearest-neighbor kernel density estimation (KDE) in a PCA-reduced descriptor space. This method efficiently detects sparsely sampled regions in large, high-dimensional data sets and provides a transferable, model-agnostic uncertainty metric without requiring retraining costly model ensembles. The framework is validated across diverse case studies varying in (i) chemistry, (ii) prediction models (including foundational neural network), (iii) descriptors used for KDE estimation, and (iv) properties whose uncertainty is sought. In all cases, the KDE-based score reliably flags extrapolative configurations, correlates well with conventional ensemble-based uncertainties, and highlights regions of reduced prediction trustworthiness. The approach offers a practical route for improving the interpretability, robustness, and deployment readiness of ML models in materials science.</description>
      <author>Daniel Willimetz, Luk&#225;&#353; Grajciar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02595</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
