<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 01:03:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal clusters with precise numbers of atoms anchored on graphdiyne as multifunctional electrocatalysts for OER/ORR/HER: a computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02611-7</link>
      <description>Xin-Yang Liu, J. W. Liu, Gang Li, Jingxiang Zhao, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393850997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Yang Liu, J. W. Liu, Gang Li, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02611-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration on Machine-Learned Potentials with IPSuite: A Modular Framework for Learning-on-the-Fly</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c07187</link>
      <description>Fabian Zills, Moritz Sch&#228;fer, Nico Segreto, Johannes K&#228;stner, Christian Holm, Samuel Tovey, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. B (1997 : Online). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393854049

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fabian Zills, Moritz Sch&#228;fer, Nico Segreto, Johannes K&#228;stner, Christian Holm, Samuel Tovey</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c07187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning A&#8208;Site Cation Deficiency in Pr&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;La&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;BaCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5+&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Perovskite to Realize Large&#8208;Scale Hydrogen Evolution at 2000 mA cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;2&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400760</link>
      <description>Kaiqian Li, Tian Xia, Ruiping Deng, Yingnan Dou, Jingping Wang, Qiang Li, Liping Sun, Li-Hua Huo, Hui Zhao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393865235

                Abstract Industrial&#8208;level hydrogen production from the water electrolysis requires reducing the overpotential ( &#951; ) as much as possible at high current density, which is closely related to intrinsic activity of the electrocatalysts. Herein, A&#8208;site cation deficiency engineering is proposed to screen high&#8208;performance catalysts, demonstrating effective Pr 0.5&#8208; x La 0.5 BaCo 2 O 5+ &#948; (P 0.5&#8208; x LBC) perovskites toward alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Among all perovskite compositions, Pr 0.4 La 0.5 BaCo 2 O 5+ &#948; (P0.4LBC) exhibits superior HER performance along with unique operating stability at large current densities ( J = 500&#8211;2000 mA cm&#8722;2 geo). The overpotential of &#8776;636 mV is achieved in P0.4LBC at 2000 mA cm&#8722;2 geo, which outperforms commercial Pt/C benchmark (&#8776;974 mV). Furthermore, the Tafel slope of P0.4LBC (34.1 mV dec &#8722;1 ) is close to that of Pt/C (35.6 mV dec &#8722;1 ), reflecting fast HER kinetics on the P0.4LBC catalyst. Combined with experimental and theoretical results, such catalytic activity may benefit from enhanced electrical conductivity, enlarged Co&#8208;O covalency, and decreased desorption energy of H * species. This results highlight effective A&#8208;site cation&#8208;deficient strategy for promoting electrochemical properties of perovskites, highlighting potential water electrolysis at ampere&#8208;level current density.</description>
      <author>Kaiqian Li, Tian Xia, Ruiping Deng, Yingnan Dou, Jingping Wang, Qiang Li, Liping Sun, Li-Hua Huo, Hui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique production strategy of Pt/C electrocatalysts via pulsed laser for hydrogen generation: Insights screening by DFT calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144218</link>
      <description>Yujeong Jeong, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Seung Jun Lee, Ramesh Kumar Chitumalla, Cheol Joo Moon, Ahreum Min, Soorathep Kheawhom, Joonkyung Jang, Myong Yong Choi, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393865560

                Design and optimizing the components and structure of highly-active electrocatalysts is a prevalent approach for reducing the input electrical energy consumption and concurrently H2 fuel production. An efficient and sustainable method is a water-electrolyzer for H2 generation, but still restricted by the stable electrode materials. In this study, a green chemistry approach for one-pot production of Pt/C nanospherical with controllable ratios of Pt and C was demonstrated using simple pulsed laser ablation in liquid (PLAL) process, during which Pt target ablation in diverse solvents (water, methanol, ethanol, and 1-propanol) without external carbon source and reducing/capping agents. The carbon-rich solvents are acted as both C-source and solvent, which are decomposed during the PLA process, producing C, H, and OH ions inside the cavitation bubble which condenses as C-shells on the Pt surface. The optimal Pt/C proportions have the highest electrochemical H2-evolution in acidic media with an overpotential of 59 mV at 10 mA/cm2, Tafel slope of 41 mV/dec, and j0 of 0.686 mA/cm2. The exceptional electrocatalytic concert of optimal Pt/C was further supported by the density functional theory. Optimized C-content in Pt/C reveals good dispersion and strong interaction of C with Pt can make efficient electron transfer, structural stability, and electrochemical durability, resulting in superior electrocatalytic performance in electrolyzer devices.</description>
      <author>Yujeong Jeong, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Seung Jun Lee, Ramesh Kumar Chitumalla, Cheol Joo Moon, Ahreum Min, Soorathep Kheawhom, Joonkyung Jang, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Advances of Non-Noble Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071637</link>
      <description>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Gang Li, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Xianjie Yuan, Yingjia Wang, Bin Cao, Materials. 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393871266

                Water splitting is an important way to obtain hydrogen applied in clean energy, which mainly consists of two half-reactions: hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the kinetics of the OER of water splitting, which occurs at the anode, is slow and inefficient, especially in acid. Currently, the main OER catalysts are still based on noble metals, such as Ir and Ru, which are the main active components. Hence, the exploration of new OER catalysts with low cost, high activity, and stability has become a key issue in the research of electrolytic water hydrogen production technology. In this paper, the reaction mechanism of OER in acid was discussed and summarized, and the main methods to improve the activity and stability of non-noble metal OER catalysts were summarized and categorized. Finally, the future prospects of OER catalysts in acid were made to provide a little reference idea for the development of advanced OER catalysts in acid in the future.</description>
      <author>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Gang Li, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Xianjie Yuan, Yingjia Wang, Bin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric coordination engineering of active centers in MXene-based single atom catalysts for high-performance ECO2RR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119094</link>
      <description>Shoufu Cao, Hongyu Chen, Xiaofei Wei, Jiao Li, Chunyu Yang, Zengxuan Chen, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393898802

                Asymmetric coordination effect is an important concept in heterogeneous catalysis where both catalytic activity and product selectivity are serious influenced. However, this effect has rarely been understood because of the difficult in characterizing detailed coordination information. Here, by employing a theoretical study on electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR) towards HCOOH over Ti3C2O2-based NS/NN co-coordinated transition metal single atom catalysts (TM-NS/NN-Ti3C2O2 SACs), we show that asymmetric coordination environments have great impact on the electronic structure of the active center. Both electron transferring ability and spin polarization of the active center are vital to optimize the adsorption and hydrogenation of key intermediates. As a result, both catalytic activity and product selectivity can be maximized. V-NN-Ti3C2O2 are predicted to promote high-throughput HCOOH generation process at operation applied potential of &#8722;0.32 with considerable electrochemical stability, surpassing most reported catalysts. This work demonstrates V-NN-Ti3C2O2 as high-performance ECO2RR catalysts, and highlights that the introduction of the concept of asymmetric coordination effect may offer a new insight into the rational design of more efficient SACs.</description>
      <author>Shoufu Cao, Hongyu Chen, Xiaofei Wei, Jiao Li, Chunyu Yang, Zengxuan Chen, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism and performance of photocatalytic H2 evolution for carbon self-doped TiO2 derived from MIL-125</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.154</link>
      <description>Ying Zhao, Nan Yang, Tong Zhou, Wei Zhan, Jie Zhao, Mingpeng Chen, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Yuming Zhang, Genlin Zhang, Qingju Liu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393925299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Zhao, Nan Yang, Tong Zhou, Wei Zhan, Jie Zhao, Mingpeng Chen, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Yuming Zhang, Genlin Zhang, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Structure of Pd@Ni&#8211;Co Nanowires and Their Electrochemical Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00376</link>
      <description>Dariusz &#321;ukowiec, Magdalena Gw&#243;&#378;d&#378;, Alina Brz&#281;czek&#8208;Szafran, Tomasz Wasiak, Dawid Janas, Jerzy Kubacki, Stanis&#322;aw Wac&#322;awek, Adrian Rado&#324;, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393927143

                One-dimensional transition metal materials are promising supports for precious metals used in energy production processes. Due to their electrochemical properties, 3d-group metals (such as Ni, Co, and Fe) can actively interact with catalysts by a strong metal&#8211;support interaction. This study shows that changing the Ni:Co ratio makes it possible to modulate the structure of the catalyst supports, which, in turn, provides a tool for designing their electrical and electrochemical properties. For example, Ni1&#8211;Co9 shows the highest electrical conductivity (5.8&#8211;10&#8211;4 S/cm) among all of the materials examined. On the contrary, the Pd@Ni7&#8211;Co3 system presents the highest mass activity (&gt;2000 mA mg&#8211;1) at 0.7 V, exceeding by several times that of commercial Pt/C (&gt;300 mA mg&#8211;1) at the same potential. Our study opens the gateway for applications of bimetallic transition metal nanowires in catalytic conversion and energy production processes.</description>
      <author>Dariusz &#321;ukowiec, Magdalena Gw&#243;&#378;d&#378;, Alina Brz&#281;czek&#8208;Szafran, Tomasz Wasiak, Dawid Janas, Jerzy Kubacki, Stanis&#322;aw Wac&#322;awek, Adrian Rado&#324;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into Mo Cluster Modified Fe5C2 Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108839</link>
      <description>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Jinhong Bi, Rongjian Sa, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393928748

                The pursuit of green ammonia synthesis via electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction (NRR) faces challenges in developing high-performance, selective electrocatalysts. Inspired by the nitrogenase Fe-Mo cofactor, this study explores the catalytic efficiency of Mo clusters anchored on Fe5C2 for NRR. We investigate structural stability, N2 adsorption, and Gibbs free energy, revealing that Mon clusters on Fe5C2 demonstrate robust NRR selectivity and notable catalytic activity. Each of the three cluster structures demonstrated superior adsorption capacity in the "side-on" configuration. Among the studied cluster configurations, the Mo5-Fe5C2 shows the lowest limiting potential (-0.24 V), and the Mo4-Fe5C2 exhibits heightened selectivity for NRR, minimizing interference from the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This enhanced performance is attributed to the unique structure and interactive dynamics of Mon-Fe5C2 and the electron orbital interactions facilitating direct nitrogen charge transfer. Our findings underscore the potential of Mo cluster-modified Fe5C2 as a pioneering catalyst for electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction.</description>
      <author>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Jinhong Bi, Rongjian Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; through the Phase Transition&#8208;Mediated Hydrogen Spillover to Outperform Pt for Electrocatalytic pH&#8208;Universal Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400783</link>
      <description>Jiexian Liu, Peifang Guo, Da Li, Xiaoxiao Yan, Xin Tu, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393931341

                Abstract Endowing conventional materials with specific functions that are hardly available is invariably of significant importance but greatly challenging. TiO 2 is proven to be highly active for the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution while intrinsically inert for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to its poor electrical conductivity and unfavorable hydrogen adsorption/desorption behavior. Herein, the first activation of inert TiO 2 for electrocatalytic HER is demonstrated by synergistically modulating the positions of d&#8208;band center and triggering hydrogen spillover through the dual doping&#8208;induced partial phase transition. The N, F co&#8208;doping&#8208;induced partial phase transition from anatase to rutile phase in TiO 2 (AR&#8208;TiO 2 |(N,F)) exhibits extraordinary HER performance with overpotentials of 74, 80, and 142 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH, 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 , and 1.0 M phosphate&#8208;buffered saline electrolytes, respectively, which are substantially better than pure TiO 2 , and even superior to the benchmark Pt/C catalysts. These findings may open a new avenue for the development of low&#8208;cost alternative to noble metal catalysts for electrocatalytic hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Jiexian Liu, Peifang Guo, Da Li, Xiaoxiao Yan, Xin Tu, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational studies on Mg ion conductivity in Mg2xHf1-x Nb(PO4)3 using neural network potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05862-1</link>
      <description>Keisuke Makino, Naoto Tanibata, Hiromasa Takeda, Masanobu Nakayama, Journal of solid state electrochemistry (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393935368

                Abstract Low Mg diffusivity in solid-state oxides is an obstacle for the development of materials for Mg ion batteries, which are expected to have high capacity. In this study, we focused on NASICON-type and &#946;-iron sulfate-type Mg 2x Hf 1-x Nb(PO 4 ) 3 that exhibit relatively high Mg ionic conductivity and investigated the Hf/Nb configuration and composition dependence of phase stability and ion conductivity by atomistic simulation using neural network potentials. The calculations show that the NASICON-type structure is slightly more stable and has higher Mg ionic conductivity than that of the &#946;-iron sulfate-type. The effect of the Hf/Nb configuration was investigated and showed that the ordered stable structure had much lower ionic conductivity than the disordered structure. Furthermore, as the Mg ion concentration increased, the ionic conductivity increased monotonically at low concentrations but tended to converge to a constant value above a certain concentration. The saturation of the ionic conductivity despite increasing the Mg concentration may be due to the trapping effect of the Mg ions caused by the Hf vacancies as well as the Hf/Nb arrangement. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Keisuke Makino, Naoto Tanibata, Hiromasa Takeda, Masanobu Nakayama</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05862-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Engineering of Unconventional Crystal-Phase Noble Metal Nanocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29071617</link>
      <description>Jie Wang, Yidong Jiang, Sixuan Chen, Qinyong Zhang, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393944761

                The crystal phase, alongside the composition, morphology, architecture, facet, size, and dimensionality, has been recognized as a critical factor influencing the properties of noble metal nanomaterials in various applications. In particular, unconventional crystal phases can potentially enable fascinating properties in noble metal nanomaterials. Recent years have witnessed notable advances in the phase engineering of nanomaterials (PEN). Within the accessible strategies for phase engineering, the effect of strain cannot be ignored because strain can act not only as the driving force of phase transition but also as the origin of the diverse physicochemical properties of the unconventional crystal phase. In this review, we highlight the development of unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanomaterials within strain engineering. We begin with a short introduction of the unconventional crystal phase and strain effect in noble metal nanomaterials. Next, the correlations of the structure and performance of strain-engineered unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanomaterials in electrocatalysis are highlighted, as well as the phase transitions of noble metal nanomaterials induced by the strain effect. Lastly, the challenges and opportunities within this rapidly developing field (i.e., the strain engineering of unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanocatalysts) are discussed.</description>
      <author>Jie Wang, Yidong Jiang, Sixuan Chen, Qinyong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29071617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading biomass derived furan aldehydes by coupled electrochemical conversion over silver-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151001</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Dai, Xi Lu, Nan Li, Yichen Zhang, Xuebing Zhao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393944922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Dai, Xi Lu, Nan Li, Yichen Zhang, Xuebing Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction on IrO2(110) is governed by Walden-type mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4101847/v1</link>
      <description>Kai S. Exner, Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393945519

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key process for sustainable energy, although renewable sources require the use of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers, with IrO 2 -based materials being the gold standard due to their high activity and stability under dynamic anodic polarization conditions. However, even for the (110) facet of a single-crystalline IrO 2 model electrode, the reaction mechanism is not settled yet due to contradictory reports in literature. In the present manuscript, we disentangle the conflicting results of previous theoretical studies in the density functional theory approximation. We demonstrate that dissimilar reaction mechanisms and limiting steps for the OER over IrO 2 (110) are obtained for different active surface configurations present on the IrO 2 electrode. In contrast to previous studies, we factor Walden-type mechanisms, in which the formation of the product O 2 and adsorption of the reactant H 2 O occur simultaneously, into the analysis of the elementary steps. Combining free-energy diagrams along the reaction coordinate and Bader charge analysis of the active site under constant potential, we elucidate why mononuclear- or bifunctional-Walden pathways excel the traditional OER mechanisms for the OER over IrO 2 (110). Our computational methodology to identify the reaction mechanism and limiting step of proton-coupled electron transfer steps is universally applicable to electrochemical processes in the field of energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Kai S. Exner, Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4101847/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Mechanism of the Electrochemical Polymerization of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Hard Carbon over CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08356</link>
      <description>Florian Keller, Johannes D&#246;hn, Axel Gro&#223;, Michael Busch, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566077

                Conversion of CO2 to hard carbon is an interesting technology for the removal of carbon dioxide from the atmosphere. Recently, it was shown that CeO2 can selectively catalyze this reaction, but we still lack information regarding the reaction mechanism. Using density functional theory modeling, we explore possible reaction mechanisms that allow for the polymerization of CO2. According to our computations, the reaction is initialized by the adsorption of CO2 in an oxygen vacancy. Owing to the rich defect chemistry of ceria, a large number of suitable sites are available at the surface. C&#8211;C bond formation is achieved through an aldol condensation-type mechanism which comprises the electrochemical elimination of water to form a carbene. This carbene then performs a nucleophilic attack on CO2. The reaction mechanism possesses significant similarities to the corresponding reactions in synthetic organic chemistry. Since the mechanism is completely generic, it allows for all relevant steps of the formation of hard carbon like chain growth, chain linkage, and the formation of side chains or aromatic rings. Surprisingly, ceria mainly serves as an anchor for CO2 in an oxygen vacancy, while all other subsequent reaction steps are almost completely independent from the catalyst. These insights are important for the development of novel catalysts for CO2 reduction and may also lead to new reactions for the electrosynthesis of organic molecules.</description>
      <author>Florian Keller, Johannes D&#246;hn, Axel Gro&#223;, Michael Busch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-induced long-range surface strain improves oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115484</link>
      <description>Mailde S. Oz&#243;rio, Marie Berg Nygaard, Amanda Schramm Petersen, R. J&#252;rgen Behm, Jan Rossmeisl, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566426

                For decades, it has been recognized that alloying platinum (Pt) with a secondary metal can enhance the catalytic activity of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) compared to pristine Pt catalysts. However, the mechanisms underlying this phenomenon vary significantly from one alloy to another. Here, we report the results of a computational study on the origin of the experimentally observed enhanced ORR activity of AgxPt1-x/Pt(1 1 1) monolayer surface alloy with 7 %-50 % Ag contents. A phase-separation model was developed and able to generate 2D phase-separation distributions of Ag and Pt atoms in AgxPt1-x/Pt(1 1 1) surfaces in line with atomic resolution scanning tunneling microscopy. We employed DFT-calculated *OH adsorption energy as a descriptor to obtain the activity of those surfaces, which reveals the ORR activity dominated by the reaction on Pt(Pt6) heptamers and also gives evidence of long-range self-induced surface strain as the source of the enhanced activity of binary AgxPt1-x/Pt(1 1 1) surfaces, i.e., the slightly larger surface Ag atoms induce a compressive strain of Pt-Pt bonds of the Pt(Pt6) heptamers, which increases the activity of binary surfaces compared to the pristine Pt(1 1 1) surface. Moreover, the excellent simulated-experimental agreement for the polarization curves shows the high quality of this approach and its more general potential for an improved understanding of the catalytic properties of inhomogeneous binary surfaces as the basis for a rational design of binary catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mailde S. Oz&#243;rio, Marie Berg Nygaard, Amanda Schramm Petersen, R. J&#252;rgen Behm, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant In-Plane Flexoelectricity and Radial Polarization in Janus IV&#8211;VI Monolayers and Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01527</link>
      <description>Kai Zheng, Tejs Vegge, Ivano E. Castelli, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Zheng, Tejs Vegge, Ivano E. Castelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Promotion of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Programmable Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00365</link>
      <description>Sallye R. Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar A. Abdelrahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394568896

                Hydrogen gas is a promising renewable energy storage medium when produced via water electrolysis, but this process is limited by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we used a microkinetic model to investigate promoting the OER using programmable oxide catalysts (i.e., forced catalyst dynamics). We found that programmable catalysts could increase current density at a fixed overpotential (100&#8211;600&#215; over static rates) or reduce the overpotential required to reach a fixed current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 (45&#8211;140% reduction vs static). In our kinetic parametrization, the key parameters controlling the quality of the catalytic ratchet were the O*-to-OOH* and O*-to-OH* activation barriers. Our findings indicate that programmable catalysts may be a viable strategy for accelerating the OER or enabling lower-overpotential operation, but a more accurate kinetic parametrization is required for precise predictions of performance, ratchet quality, and resulting energy efficiency.</description>
      <author>Sallye R. Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar A. Abdelrahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Efficiency Iridium&#8208;Yttrium Alloy Catalyst for Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304479</link>
      <description>Xiang Xiong, Jialin Tang, Jian Yuan, Weiqing Xue, Haoyuan Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Hongliang Zeng, Yizhou Dai, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Xinyan Li, Qiu Jiang, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394572023

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis holds great promise in revolutionizing clean energy production by enabling the efficient generation of hydrogen. Nevertheless, a formidable challenge persists in the realm of designing electrocatalysts that are both highly active and acid&#8208;resistant during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), thereby mitigating the substantial kinetic barrier. In this study, the facile synthesis of iridium&#8208;yttrium (IrY) alloy nanocatalysts via a thermal shock method is introduced, which exhibits exceptional activity in the context of acidic water oxidation. Through the strategic incorporation of dispersed Y into the lattice of Ir metal, the IrY catalyst demonstrates a notably low overpotential of 255 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and showcases remarkable catalytic stability in acidic electrolytes, enduring for over 500 h with a high current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Through a comprehensive set of in situ characterizations and analytical methods, the formation of a surface Ir&#8208;based oxide layer, induced by deprotonation and electrochemical oxidation is unveiled, which is notably stabilized by the presence of Y dopants. This stabilization of the active site imparts enhanced resistance to over&#8208;oxidation and dissolution, underpinning the exceptional stability of the catalyst. Theoretical calculations suggest that the incorporation of Y into the catalyst structure has a significant impact on enhancing the reactivity of the oxygen intermediate (O*) at adjacent Ir sites, thus lowering the overpotential and promoting OER activity. The alloying approach presents a straightforward method for achieving atomic&#8208;level modifications in catalyst design and can pave the way for the development of more effective and economically viable OER catalysts and beyond.</description>
      <author>Xiang Xiong, Jialin Tang, Jian Yuan, Weiqing Xue, Haoyuan Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Hongliang Zeng, Yizhou Dai, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Xinyan Li, Qiu Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Efficiency of Water Splitting and Oxygen Reduction Via &lt;scp&gt;Single&#8208;Atom&lt;/scp&gt; Anchoring on Graphyne Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12723</link>
      <description>Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Beenish Bashir, Khan Muhammad Ajmal, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394573820

                Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have received significant interest for optimizing metal atom utilization and superior catalytic performance in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we investigate a range of single&#8208;transition metal (STM 1 = Sc 1 , Ti 1 , V 1 , Cr 1 , Mn 1 , Fe 1 , Co 1 , Ni 1 , Cu 1 , Zr 1 , Nb 1 , Mo 1 , Ru 1 , Rh 1 , Pd 1 , Ag 1 , W 1 , Re 1 , Os 1 , Ir 1 , Pt 1 , and Au 1 ) atoms supported on graphyne (GY) surface for HER/OER and ORR using first&#8208;principle calculations. Ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations and phonon dispersion spectra reveal the dynamic and thermal stabilities of the GY surface. The exceptional stability of all supported STM 1 atoms within the H1 cavity of the GY surface exists in an isolated form, facilitating the uniform distribution and proper arrangement of single atoms on GY. In particular, Sc 1 , Co 1 , Fe 1 , and Au 1 /GY demonstrate promising catalytic efficiency in the HER due to idealistic &#916;G H* values via the Volmer&#8208;Heyrovsky pathway. Notably, Sc 1 and Au 1 /GY exhibit superior HER catalytic activity compared to other studied catalysts. Co 1 /GY catalyst exhibits higher selectivity and activity for the OER, with an overpotential (0.46 V) comparable to MoC 2 , IrO 2 , and RuO 2 . Also, Rh 1 and Co 1 /GY SACs exhibited promising electrocatalysts for the ORR, with an overpotential of 0.36 and 0.46 V, respectively. Therefore, Co 1 /GY is a versatile electrocatalyst for metal&#8208;air batteries and water&#8208;splitting. This study further incorporates computational analysis of the kinetic potential energy barriers of Co 1 and Rh 1 in the OER and ORR. A strong correlation is found between the estimated kinetic activation barriers for the thermodynamic outcomes and all proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer steps. We establish a relation for the Gibbs free energy of intermediates to understand the mechanism of SACs supported on STM 1 /GY and introduce a key descriptor. This study highlights GY as a favorable single&#8208;atom support for designing highly active and cost&#8208;effective versatile electrocatalysts for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Beenish Bashir, Khan Muhammad Ajmal, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrifying Energy and Chemical Transformations with Single-Atom Alloy Nanoparticle Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00365</link>
      <description>Qiang Gao, Xue Han, Yuanqi Liu, Huiyuan Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394576674

                Single-atom alloys (SAAs) have attracted considerable attention as promising electrocatalysts in reactions central to energy conversion and chemical transformation. In contrast to monometallic nanocrystals and metal alloys, SAAs possess unique and intriguing physicochemical properties, positioning them as ideal model systems for studying structure&#8211;property relationships. However, the field is still in its early stages. In this Perspective, we first review and summarize rational synthesis methods and advanced characterization techniques for SAA nanoparticle catalysts. We then emphasize the extensive applications of SAAs in a range of electrocatalytic reactions, including fuel cell reactions, water splitting, and carbon dioxide and nitrate reductions. Finally, we provide insights into existing challenges and prospects associated with the controlled synthesis, characterization, and design of SAA catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qiang Gao, Xue Han, Yuanqi Liu, Huiyuan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing lithium-silver alloy phases for enhanced energy density and electrochemical performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</link>
      <description>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu, Next materials. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393925878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolytic Regeneration of Spent Caustic Soda from CO2 Capture Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</link>
      <description>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho, Processes. 12(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393866132

                The traditional electrochemical caustic soda recovery system uses the generated pH gradient across the ion exchange membrane for the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent from CO2 capture. This electrochemical CO2 capture system releases the by-products H2 and O2 at the cathode and anode, respectively. Although effective for capturing CO2, the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limit the energy efficiency of this technique. Hence, this study proposed and validated a hybrid electrochemical cell based on the H2-cycling from the cathode to the anode to eliminate the reliance on anodic oxygen generation. The results show that our lab-scale prototype enabled effective spent caustic soda recovery with an electron utilisation efficiency of 90%, and a relative carbonate/bicarbonate diffusional flux of approximately 40%. The system also enabled the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent with a minimum electrochemical energy input of 0.19 kWh/kg CO2 at a CO2 recovery rate of 0.7 mol/m2/h, accounting for 30% lower energy demand than a control system without H2-recycling, making this technique a promising alternative to the conventional thermal regeneration technology.</description>
      <author>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
