<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 01:52:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-Engineered Rh Single Atoms on Curved WS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Hydrogen Production and Coupled Photochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c04928</link>
      <description>Ting Gao, Jie Gu, Chuanguang Yang, Rui Wang, Chan Wang, Pengfei Zhang, Jiatong Li, Xiaoyan Zheng, Yujie Fan, Puheng Yang, Xiufu Hua, Junfeng Hui, Huigang Zhang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412172437

                Hydrogen is a promising clean energy carrier, yet the high energy demand of water electrolysis limits its widespread adoption. Catalysis is crucial to enhance the efficiency of hydrogen production and lower energy costs. However, conventional catalyst design guided by the d-band theory faces inconsistencies in predicting adsorption behavior, and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a major efficiency bottleneck. To address these challenges, we developed a strain-engineered Rh single-atom catalyst anchored on curved WS2 supported by carbon nanotubes (RhSA/WS2@CNT) to modulate the electronic structure. The resultant catalyst achieves an ultralow overpotential of 17.4 mV at 10 mA cm-2 for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and a mass activity &#8764;65 times higher than that of commercial Pt/C. Mechanistic analysis reveals that the H* adsorption trend contradicts d-band theory predictions but is explained by orbital symmetry adaptation, where the strain-modulated dxz orbital plays a major role in governing adsorption energetics. Beyond catalyst design, the HER catalyst was coupled with a photocatalytic iodide oxidation reaction (IOR) to replace the OER and reduce the water-splitting voltage to 0.7 V. This study not only introduces a strain-engineering strategy to optimize single-atom catalysts but also demonstrates a coupled electro-photo system that enhances energy efficiency, offering an alternative approach for sustainable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Ting Gao, Jie Gu, Chuanguang Yang, Rui Wang, Chan Wang, Pengfei Zhang, Jiatong Li, Xiaoyan Zheng, Yujie Fan, Puheng Yang, Xiufu Hua, Junfeng Hui, Huigang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c04928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Electrocatalytic Potential of Ni&#8208;Metal&#8211;Organic Framework: A Synergistic Approach to Electrocatalysis and Theoretical Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500796</link>
      <description>Debojyoti Kundu, Sanjukta Zamindar, Sandip Kumar Tudu, Swarup Kumar Maji, Abhijit Hazra, Pravat Ghorai, S.K. Samanta, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Priyabrata Banerjee, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412172680

                Abstract Hydrogen stands at the forefront of next&#8208;generation clean energy solutions. Specifically, electrochemical water splitting represents a cutting&#8208;edge, environmentally benign approach for sustainable green hydrogen generation. The development of next&#8208;generation highly efficient electrocatalysts with high efficiency and durability is pivotal to overcome the intrinsic kinetic limitations of both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Contextually, metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), owing to their ultrahigh surface area, tuneable nanostructures, and exceptional porosity, have emerged as a versatile class of materials for designing advanced bifunctional electrocatalysts. Herein, a nickel&#8208;metal complex ( NMC ) and a nickel&#8208;metal&#8211;organic framework ( NMF ) was rationally synthesized. Electrochemical analyses revealed that the NMF exhibited superior bifunctional activity, with low overpotentials of 144 mV for HER and 347 mV for OER at the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline media. Remarkably, the NMF || NMF catalyst delivered a low overall water splitting cell voltage of 1.647 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , along with outstanding long&#8208;term stability. Comprehensive experimental and in silico insights confirm that NMF dramatically lowers the energy barrier for hydrogen adsorption. These findings highlight the NMF as a state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art electrocatalyst, underscoring its potential to enable next&#8208;generation, advanced water electrolysis techniques for green hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Debojyoti Kundu, Sanjukta Zamindar, Sandip Kumar Tudu, Swarup Kumar Maji, Abhijit Hazra, Pravat Ghorai, S.K. Samanta, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Priyabrata Banerjee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500796</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pursuing spatiotemporal coordination in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41570-025-00741-3</link>
      <description>Yuanfu Ren, Kuo&#8208;Wei Huang, Huabin Zhang, Nature Reviews Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412195668

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanfu Ren, Kuo&#8208;Wei Huang, Huabin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41570-025-00741-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of the d band center and geometric distortion &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; an axial nitrogen strategy of the Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C oxygen electrocatalyst for a Zn&#8211;air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta03017j</link>
      <description>Yao Lu, Xiong Du, Shudong Chen, Hao Cheng, Zheng Li, Mengran Wang, Zhongliang Tian, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412199309

                The bifunctional catalyst Fe&#8211;N 5 C, with an axial N atom, shows improved oxygen reduction/evolution catalytic performance. The catalyst enables the aqueous rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery to achieve a 330 h long serving time with only 0.84 V voltage gap.</description>
      <author>Yao Lu, Xiong Du, Shudong Chen, Hao Cheng, Zheng Li, Mengran Wang, Zhongliang Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ta03017j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise Design of D&#8211;A Type Metal Covalent Organic Framework for Regulating Intramolecular-Charge-Transfer toward H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01416</link>
      <description>Bin Liu, Haiyan Cheng, Yu Xia, Lei Wang, Ning An, Jingwei Huang, Houde She, Qizhao Wang, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412349380

                For most organic structures, the donor-acceptor (D-A) effect can effectively regulate the separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers, thereby enhancing the photocatalytic performance. However, the internal correlation between the structure and charge transportation, especially at the molecular level, is insufficiently explored. Herein, Cu3(PyCA)3 (PyCA = pyrazolate-4-carboxaldehyde), tris(4-aminophenyl) amine, and [2,2'-bipyridine]-5,5'-diamine were employed to prepare two metal-covalent organic frameworks (MCOFs), namely, Tap-MCOF and Bpy-MCOF, both of which are D-A-type structure. In accordance, Tap-MCOF exhibits improved conversion of H2O and O2 to H2O2 in the absence of sacrificial agent, achieving the H2O2 production rate of 288.58 &#956;mol g-1 h-1, which is approximately 2.7-fold higher than that of Bpy-MCOF. It is considered due to the intensified D-A effect within Tap-MCOF, it presents a narrower band gaps and greater separation of photoinduced carriers, compared with that of Bpy-MCOF. The transient photocurrent response intensity of Tap-MCOF is significantly higher than that of Bpy-MCOF, indicating its superior charge separation and transport efficiency. These results not only provide a strategy for manipulating the carrier separation efficiency of photocatalysts at the molecular level but also furnish insights into the effective photocatalytic ORR and WOR transformations of organic semiconducting catalysts.</description>
      <author>Bin Liu, Haiyan Cheng, Yu Xia, Lei Wang, Ning An, Jingwei Huang, Houde She, Qizhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c01416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst for Anodic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394247653.ch10</link>
      <description>Soner &#199;akar, Mahmut &#214;zacar, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412350527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soner &#199;akar, Mahmut &#214;zacar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394247653.ch10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite Electrocatalyst for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394247653.ch3</link>
      <description>Nawishta Jabeen, Imtiaz Ahmad Khan, Adeela Naz, Ahmad Hussain, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412350534

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nawishta Jabeen, Imtiaz Ahmad Khan, Adeela Naz, Ahmad Hussain</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394247653.ch3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394247653.ch9</link>
      <description>Srijita Basumallick, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412350606

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Srijita Basumallick</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394247653.ch9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamics of Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394247653.ch1</link>
      <description>Manash P. Nath, Manju Kumari Jaiswal, Suvankar Deka, Biswajit Choudhury, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412350697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manash P. Nath, Manju Kumari Jaiswal, Suvankar Deka, Biswajit Choudhury</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394247653.ch1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Electrocatalyst Design for Hydrogen Production by Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-88550-1_7</link>
      <description>Sachin Kumar, Yang Yang, Green energy and technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412354569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sachin Kumar, Yang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-88550-1_7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Accurate Machine Learning Interatomic Potential for Graphene: Capturing Stress&#8211;Strain and Vibrational Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03470</link>
      <description>Felipe Hawthorne, Paulo R. E. Raulino, Ronaldo Rodrigues Pel&#225;, Cristiano F. Woellner, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412364943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Felipe Hawthorne, Paulo R. E. Raulino, Ronaldo Rodrigues Pel&#225;, Cristiano F. Woellner</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Catalytic Conversion of Nitrite to Ammonium by an Oxygen-Tolerant Molecular Cobalt Complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03677</link>
      <description>Rajaneesh Kumar Verma, Ankita Kumari, Arpan Bera, Avijit Das, Durgesh Pandey, Dibyajyoti Ghosh, Sayantan Paria, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412365026

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rajaneesh Kumar Verma, Ankita Kumari, Arpan Bera, Avijit Das, Durgesh Pandey, Dibyajyoti Ghosh, Sayantan Paria</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c03677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved ORR Performance of Precious Metal&#8208;Free Fe Single&#8208;Atom Catalysts by Heteroatom Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500253</link>
      <description>Zaifa Pan, Yiming Zhu, Yihong Liu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Yujie Cui, Yang Zhao, Menghao Yang, Hongfei Cheng, Nicol&#225;s Alonso&#8208;Vante, Jiwei Ma, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412372629

                Abstract The development of platinum group metal (PGM)&#8208;free catalysts is essential to advance the wide application of fuel cells. Single&#8208;atom Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C catalysts are one type of promising PGM&#8208;free catalysts that can replace the expensive Pt/C catalyst for the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction. However, Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C catalysts still suffer from poor stability due to the inevitable Fenton reaction. In this work, a doping strategy is demonstrated to alter the electronic structure around the catalytic sites and significantly improve their catalytic activity. In particular, the phosphorous&#8208;doped Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C catalyst (P&#9472;Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C) achieves a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.885 V versus RHE in 0.1 m KOH and demonstrates excellent stability, with only a 7 mV decay in the half&#8208;wave potential after 10 000 cyclic voltammetry cycles, superior to that of boron&#8208;doped one (B&#9472;Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations further confirm that heteroatom doping favors the ORR process, highlighting the potential of this catalyst for advanced energy applications.</description>
      <author>Zaifa Pan, Yiming Zhu, Yihong Liu, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Yujie Cui, Yang Zhao, Menghao Yang, Hongfei Cheng, Nicol&#225;s Alonso&#8208;Vante, Jiwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma&#8208;Assisted Nitridation Modulates the Electronic Structure of the NiSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Ni@Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N Ternary Heterojunction Enhancing Its Dual&#8208;Function Catalytic Performance and Inhibiting Zn Dendrite Growth in Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202511117</link>
      <description>Zejun Xu, Jialong Wu, Weiheng Chen, Zhongqing Jiang, Jun Cao, Guangliang Chen, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412372658

                Abstract In this work, a novel synthetic strategy to construct a structurally advanced bifunctional electrocatalyst via Ar/NH 3 radio&#8208;frequency plasma&#8208;assisted nitridation and subsequent high&#8208;temperature selenization is proposed. The resulting self&#8208;supporting electrode, denoted as p&#8208;NiSe 2 /Ni@Ni 3 N/NCNT@CC, consists of selenium&#8208;vacancy&#8208;rich NiSe 2 /Ni@Ni 3 N nanoparticles (NPs) uniformly anchored on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes (NCNTs) in situ grown on carbon&#8208;cloth (CC). The formation of this ternary heterostructure is governed by interactions between plasma&#8208;generated reactive species (NH*, NH 2 *, Ar*) and Ni NPs. It demonstrates outstanding bifunctional performance and stability in 0.1 m KOH, featuring a half&#8208;wave potential for oxygen&#8208;reduction reaction (ORR) of 0.80 V, an overpotential of 311 mV for oxygen&#8208;evolution reaction (OER) at 30 mA cm&#8315; 2 , and a minimal &#916;E of 0.74 V, surpassing commercial Pt/C+RuO 2 . Liquid zinc&#8211;air batteries (L&#8208;ZABs) using this catalyst as the air cathode deliver a high peak power&#8208;density of 137.94 mW cm&#8315; 2 and stable cycling over 1 000 cycles, with minimal voltage polarization. More impressively, it serves as a competitive self&#8208;supporting electrode in flexible all&#8208;solid&#8208;state ZABs (ASS&#8208;ZABs), achieving 1.49 V open&#8208;circuit voltage (OCV), 106.8 mW cm&#8315; 2 peak power&#8208;density, and excellent cycling and low&#8208;temperature performance. DFT calculations confirm that the enhanced activity and durability stem from the synergistic effects of heterostructure engineering, selenium vacancy modulation, and conductive carbon integration.</description>
      <author>Zejun Xu, Jialong Wu, Weiheng Chen, Zhongqing Jiang, Jun Cao, Guangliang Chen, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202511117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core&#8211;Shell IrPt Nanoalloy on La/Ni&#8211;Co3O4 for High-Performance Bifunctional PEM Electrolysis with Ultralow Noble Metal Loading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-025-01845-7</link>
      <description>Yifei Liu, Xinmeng Er, Xinyao Wang, Hangxing Ren, Wenchao Wang, Feng Cao, Taiyan Zhang, Pan Liu, Yakun Yuan, Fangbo Yu, Ren Yang, Fuqiang Huang, Wenjiang Ding, Lina Chong, Nano-Micro Letters. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412379237

                Abstract The development of highly efficient and durable bifunctional catalysts with minimal precious metal usage is critical for advancing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). We present an iridium&#8211;platinum nanoalloy (IrPt) supported on lanthanum and nickel co-doped cobalt oxide, featuring a core&#8211;shell architecture with an amorphous IrPtOx shell and an IrPt core. This catalyst exhibits exceptional bifunctional activity for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions in acidic media, achieving 2 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.72 V in a PEMWE device with ultralow loadings of 0.075 mg Ir cm &#8722;2 and 0.075 mg Pt cm &#8722;2 at anode and cathode, respectively. It demonstrates outstanding durability, sustaining water splitting for over 646 h with a degradation rate of only 5 &#956;V h &#8722;1 , outperforming state-of-the-art Ir-based catalysts. In situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy and density functional theory simulations reveal that the optimized charge redistribution between Ir and Pt, along with the IrPt core&#8211;IrPtOx shell structure, enhances performance. The Ir&#8211;O&#8211;Pt active sites enable a bi-nuclear mechanism for oxygen evolution reaction and a Volmer&#8211;Tafel mechanism for hydrogen evolution reaction, reducing kinetic barriers. Hierarchical porosity, abundant oxygen vacancies, and a high electrochemical surface area further improve electron and mass transfer. This work offers a cost-effective solution for green hydrogen production and advances the design of high-performance bifunctional catalysts for PEMWE. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Yifei Liu, Xinmeng Er, Xinyao Wang, Hangxing Ren, Wenchao Wang, Feng Cao, Taiyan Zhang, Pan Liu, Yakun Yuan, Fangbo Yu, Ren Yang, Fuqiang Huang, Wenjiang Ding, Lina Chong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-025-01845-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectured CuTe Thin Films: A Next-Generation Platform for Ultra-Sensitive Biosensing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c02615</link>
      <description>Arya Vasanth, Aditya Ashok, Ho Ngoc Nam, Quan Manh Phung, Hoang&#8208;Phuong Phan, Md. Shahriar A. Hossain, Yusuke Yamauchi, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412379254

                Efficient and cost-effective biosensing platforms are difficult to maintain. Recently, researchers have begun to explore the use of materials that are alternative to traditional noble metals. On this note, the present work focuses on the biosensing capabilities of nanoarchitectured copper telluride (CuTe) semiconductor thin films. The vast surface area established within the mesoporous framework facilitates effective current transfer in traditional electrolytes, rendering them highly suitable for applications in biological sensing by demonstrating their ability in glucose sensors, showing an exceptionally low detection threshold (57.38 nM) and a notable sensitivity of 682.4 &#956;A&#183;cm-2&#183;&#956;M-1, which is approximately three times higher than that of mesoporous gold (mAu) films. Our findings indicate that nanoarchitectured CuTe semiconductor thin films possess substantial potential for integration into advanced biosensing technologies, enabling possibilities for the enhanced and ultrasensitive detection of biological molecules.</description>
      <author>Arya Vasanth, Aditya Ashok, Ho Ngoc Nam, Quan Manh Phung, Hoang&#8208;Phuong Phan, Md. Shahriar A. Hossain, Yusuke Yamauchi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.5c02615</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Fundamental Origin of the CO-Free Pathway Selectivity in Alkaline Methanol Electrooxidation on Bi-Modified Pt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02098</link>
      <description>Lecheng Liang, Hengyu Li, Peng Li, Jinhui Liang, Shao Ye, Binwen Zeng, Mingjia Lu, Yanhong Xie, Yucheng Wang, Taisuke Ozaki, Shengli Chen, Zhiming Cui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412382224

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lecheng Liang, Hengyu Li, Peng Li, Jinhui Liang, Shao Ye, Binwen Zeng, Mingjia Lu, Yanhong Xie, Yucheng Wang, Taisuke Ozaki, Shengli Chen, Zhiming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-recycling of spent cathode and anode &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; redox-mediated lithiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5gc02248g</link>
      <description>Zhimin Du, Peng Gao, Yuxiang Chen, Yingming Zhang, Yongzhi Liu, Xuejing Qiu, Lingling Xie, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412382897

                Co-recycling of spent cathode/anode via redox-mediated lithiation enables anodic de-lithiation and cathodic re-lithiation, regenerating Al, Cu, graphite and LiFePO 4 .</description>
      <author>Zhimin Du, Peng Gao, Yuxiang Chen, Yingming Zhang, Yongzhi Liu, Xuejing Qiu, Lingling Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5gc02248g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the reconstruction of copper bimetallic catalysts during CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01368-9</link>
      <description>Intae Kim, Gi-Baek Lee, Sungin Kim, Hyun Dong Jung, Ji-Yong Kim, Taemin Lee, Hyesung Choi, Jaeyeon Jo, Geosan Kang, Sang&#8208;Ho Oh, Woosuck Kwon, Deokgi Hong, Hyoung Gyun Kim, Yujin Lee, Ung-gi Kim, Hyeontae Kim, Miyoung Kim, Seoin Back, Jungwon Park, Young&#8208;Chang Joo, Dae&#8208;Hyun Nam, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412388001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Intae Kim, Gi-Baek Lee, Sungin Kim, Hyun Dong Jung, Ji-Yong Kim, Taemin Lee, Hyesung Choi, Jaeyeon Jo, Geosan Kang, Sang&#8208;Ho Oh, Woosuck Kwon, Deokgi Hong, Hyoung Gyun Kim, Yujin Lee, Ung-gi Kim, Hyeontae Kim, Miyoung Kim, Seoin Back, Jungwon Park, Young&#8208;Chang Joo, Dae&#8208;Hyun Nam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-025-01368-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Atomic Structure Prediction of Multimetallic Nanoparticles with Physics-Based Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c04082</link>
      <description>Bassel Alkhatib, Maya Salem, Klaertje Kiyora Hesselink, Giannis Mpourmpakis, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412388269

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bassel Alkhatib, Maya Salem, Klaertje Kiyora Hesselink, Giannis Mpourmpakis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c04082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating structure relaxation in chemically disordered materials with a chemistry-driven model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01694-3</link>
      <description>Liying An, Huan Ma, Jinjia Liu, Wenping Guo, Xiaodong Wen, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412389970

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liying An, Huan Ma, Jinjia Liu, Wenping Guo, Xiaodong Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01694-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo-Enhanced Passivity of Stainless Steels Studied at Metal/Oxide Interfaces by Dft Atomistic Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5351156</link>
      <description>Xian Huang, Dominique Costa, Vincent Maurice, Philippe Marcus, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412399149

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xian Huang, Dominique Costa, Vincent Maurice, Philippe Marcus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5351156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A General Machine-Learning Framework for High-Throughput Screening for Stable and Efficient RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02247</link>
      <description>Zhe Shang, Susu Zhao, Qian Dang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412403632

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhe Shang, Susu Zhao, Qian Dang, Fengmei Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in thermocatalytic acetylene selective hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs01237b</link>
      <description>Xiaocheng Lan, Kuan Chang, Tiefeng Wang, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412418605

                This review highlights recent advances in acetylene selective hydrogenation, focusing on active site engineering, support/modifier effects, reaction media, and future directions for achieving high performance and industrial relevance.</description>
      <author>Xiaocheng Lan, Kuan Chang, Tiefeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs01237b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M-N-C-based non-precious metal catalyst materials for electrocatalytic ORR applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136163</link>
      <description>Shambhulinga Aralekallu, Vijay Singh, Fuel. 404(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412419968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shambhulinga Aralekallu, Vijay Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-induced electronic modulation in Mn2@g-C3N4 catalysts for enhanced nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136260</link>
      <description>H.P. Wang, Cheng Liu, Youyong Li, Fuel. 404(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412420146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H.P. Wang, Cheng Liu, Youyong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT+U calculations on substitutionally doped (Ni, Cu, Zn) Mg-vanadate surfaces for the oxidative dehydrogenation of alkanes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116313</link>
      <description>Hansel Montalvo-Castro, Siby Thomas, Randall J. Meyer, David Hibbitts, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412421019

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hansel Montalvo-Castro, Siby Thomas, Randall J. Meyer, David Hibbitts</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.116313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic insights into chloride-induced depassivation mechanisms of protective Cu2O films in marine environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2025.113171</link>
      <description>Ao Chen, Ying Wang, Jiawei Le, Kai Xu, Yongbo Kuang, Keke Chang, Corrosion Science. 256(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412421881

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ao Chen, Ying Wang, Jiawei Le, Kai Xu, Yongbo Kuang, Keke Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2025.113171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Stability, Mechanistic Evaluation, and Electronic Properties of Polyoxoniobate-Based SACs (TM@PONb): A Promising Multifunctional Electrocatalyst for HER/OER/ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02057</link>
      <description>Faheem Abbas, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Sharmarke Mohamed, Yongge Wei, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412422395

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faheem Abbas, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Sharmarke Mohamed, Yongge Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c02057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale modeling and optimization of proton exchange membrane electrolysis cells: a review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126451</link>
      <description>Dongqi Zhao, Jisen Li, Ze Zhou, Liyan Zhang, Zheng Li, Qihong Chen, Xi Li, Applied Energy. 398(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412427726

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongqi Zhao, Jisen Li, Ze Zhou, Liyan Zhang, Zheng Li, Qihong Chen, Xi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen reduction reaction catalyzed by C2N nanosheet doped with a phosphorous atom: Insights from DFT calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2025.109125</link>
      <description>Mina Shahdust, Mehdi D. Esrafili, Morteza Vahedpour, Journal of Molecular Graphics and Modelling. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412432804

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mina Shahdust, Mehdi D. Esrafili, Morteza Vahedpour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2025.109125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and microkinetic insights into potential-dependent competition between CO2 reduction and HER on Mo2CTx MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165927</link>
      <description>Caihong Liang, Zhonghan Zhang, Zheng Liu, Liang Wang, Yeng Ming Lam, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412433324

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Caihong Liang, Zhonghan Zhang, Zheng Liu, Liang Wang, Yeng Ming Lam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unidirectional Photoinduced Electron Transfer between Anatase and Rutile Titanium(IV) Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03078</link>
      <description>Shin&#8208;ichi Naya, Miwako Teranishi, Tetsuro Soejima, Hiroaki Tada, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412434299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shin&#8208;ichi Naya, Miwako Teranishi, Tetsuro Soejima, Hiroaki Tada</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c03078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic and catalytic insights into rare earth element-doped &#947;-NiOOH for oxygen evolution and reduction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.003</link>
      <description>Sadaf Bibi, Xiaolei Huang, Yanjie Wang, Yanjie Li, Gui Lu, Xin Xia, Kai Zhang, Cau&#234; Ribeiro, Tao He, Detlef W. Bahnemann, Jia Hong Pan, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412435074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sadaf Bibi, Xiaolei Huang, Yanjie Wang, Yanjie Li, Gui Lu, Xin Xia, Kai Zhang, Cau&#234; Ribeiro, Tao He, Detlef W. Bahnemann, Jia Hong Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insight on interface enhancement mechanism and electrocatalytic water splitting reactions using heteroatoms-mediated graphene/Cu composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113306</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Linxiu Du, Zhihua Yuan, Dong Wang, Peide Han, Zhuxia Zhang, Materials Today Communications. 48(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412435754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Linxiu Du, Zhihua Yuan, Dong Wang, Peide Han, Zhuxia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom Catalysts Based on SiC Monolayer for Efficient Nitrite Electroreduction to Ammonia: A Computational Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107145</link>
      <description>Alice Hu, Donglin Ma, Jianjun Hu, Yongfan Zhang, Shuping Huang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412436613

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alice Hu, Donglin Ma, Jianjun Hu, Yongfan Zhang, Shuping Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of nitrate reduction on CoP (010): Adsorption behavior, reaction mechanism, and selectivity towards ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107181</link>
      <description>Guozheng Zhao, Miao Yu, Chaozheng He, Surfaces and Interfaces. 72(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412436730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guozheng Zhao, Miao Yu, Chaozheng He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced RuO2-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction: A perspective from coordination structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100110</link>
      <description>Qian Sun, Jilei Zhang, Wei Kong Pang, Bernt Johannessen, Peng Li, Guoqiang Zhao, Huaming Yang, Materials Today Catalysis. 10(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412438260

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Sun, Jilei Zhang, Wei Kong Pang, Bernt Johannessen, Peng Li, Guoqiang Zhao, Huaming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Effect of Ruthenium on Fe-Catalyzed Growth of Small-Diameter Single-Wall Carbon Nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10714</link>
      <description>Brian M. Everhart, Haider Almkhelfe, Morgen L. Smith, Tsung-Wei Liu, Diego A. G&#243;mez&#8208;Gualdr&#243;n, Robert Waelder, Rahul Rao, Benji Maruyama, Placidus B. Amama, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412439082

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Brian M. Everhart, Haider Almkhelfe, Morgen L. Smith, Tsung-Wei Liu, Diego A. G&#243;mez&#8208;Gualdr&#243;n, Robert Waelder, Rahul Rao, Benji Maruyama, Placidus B. Amama</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c10714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen adsorption via the synergistic catalysis of graphitic nitrogen carbon and antiperovskite ZnCNi3 in Zinc- Air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138412</link>
      <description>Jiahui Guo, Huan Liu, Yulong Gao, Xiaopeng Liu, Jie Bai, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412442000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahui Guo, Huan Liu, Yulong Gao, Xiaopeng Liu, Jie Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the activity of CO2 reduction electrocatalysts via modifying metals and ligand of conductive two-dimensional metal&#8212;organic framework ligands: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146920</link>
      <description>Yang Liu, Huohai Yang, Siying Liu, Z CHEN, Xin Chen, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412447743

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Liu, Huohai Yang, Siying Liu, Z CHEN, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146920</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the role of doping and intrinsic vacancies in BiVO4 for enhanced photoelectrochemical water splitting: a first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150384</link>
      <description>Otmane El Ouardi, Hamza Ladib, Brigitte Vigolo, Jones Alami, M. Makha, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 157(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412448019

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Otmane El Ouardi, Hamza Ladib, Brigitte Vigolo, Jones Alami, M. Makha</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spall strength of symmetric tilt grain boundaries in 6H silicon carbide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0277595</link>
      <description>Chunyu Li, Alejandro Strachan, Journal of Applied Physics. 138(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412448371

                Characterizing microstructural effects on the dynamical response of materials is challenging due to the extreme conditions and the short timescales involved. For example, little is known about how grain boundary characteristics affect spall strength. This study explores 6H-SiC bicrystals under shock waves via large-scale molecular dynamics simulations. We focused on symmetric tilt grain boundaries with a wide range of misorientations and found that spall strength and dynamical fracture surface energy are strongly affected by the grain boundary microstructure, especially the excess free volume. Grain boundary energy also plays a considerable role. As expected, low-angle grain boundaries tend to have higher spallation strengths. We also extracted cohesive models for the dynamical strength of bulk systems and grain boundaries that can be used in continuum simulations.</description>
      <author>Chunyu Li, Alejandro Strachan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0277595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy in hydrogen evolution reaction: Insights and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.101061</link>
      <description>Zhenglong Li, Xingyu Ding, Da Liu, Jin Zhou, Yong Gao, Yanxia Liu, Lin Jiang, Renbing Wu, Hongge Pan, Materials Science and Engineering R Reports. 166(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412448704

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenglong Li, Xingyu Ding, Da Liu, Jin Zhou, Yong Gao, Yanxia Liu, Lin Jiang, Renbing Wu, Hongge Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2025.101061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability enhancement strategy for LOM-based Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107169</link>
      <description>Jianhe Liu, Tao Yang, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Guoyong Huang, Enhui Wang, Kai Wang, Hongyang Wang, Xinmei Hou, Surfaces and Interfaces. 72(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412450153

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianhe Liu, Tao Yang, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Guoyong Huang, Enhui Wang, Kai Wang, Hongyang Wang, Xinmei Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal design principles of self-supporting iron-group (Fe/Co/Ni) electrocatalysts for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150313</link>
      <description>Mingzhe Li, F. Zheng, Jiahui Zheng, Xin Zhang, Yunlong Wang, Xiaofen Wang, Yuzhen Lv, Kepi Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 155(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412452771

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingzhe Li, F. Zheng, Jiahui Zheng, Xin Zhang, Yunlong Wang, Xiaofen Wang, Yuzhen Lv, Kepi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of porphyrin-based metal organic frameworks for efficient CO2-to-CO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150353</link>
      <description>Shengshen Gu, Jiacheng Lu, Xiangyu Zhu, Yang Pan, Ting Qi, Danfeng Wang, Jing Zhong, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 156(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412452806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengshen Gu, Jiacheng Lu, Xiangyu Zhu, Yang Pan, Ting Qi, Danfeng Wang, Jing Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.150353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium&#8208;Doped Monoclinic Zirconia as a Catalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500769</link>
      <description>M.S. Nissen, Heine Anton Hansen, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412454446

                Abstract New acid&#8208;stable catalysts that reduce reliance on iridium (Ir) for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) could pave the way for efficient energy conversion and storage. Using DFT this work investigates Ir&#8208;dopings of the monoclinic () surface as an Ir&#8208;lean OER catalyst. It is found that these Ir&#8208;doped surfaces are likely to segregate into their constituent oxide phases, and . The OER activity is limited due to under binding of the OER intermediates on pure and overbinding on the Ir&#8208;doped surface, both leading to high overpotentials. Water adsorption on the surface layer stabilizes all surfaces, with a more pronounced stabilization observed for the Ir&#8208;doped systems. This adsorption significantly impacts the activity for the nondoped surface, as leaving a surface site unoccupied creates a high energy state in the band gap, making the surface highly reactive. A similar situation is found for an Ir&#8208;doped surface, contrasted by the formation of lower energy states.</description>
      <author>M.S. Nissen, Heine Anton Hansen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the Oxygen Reduction Reaction Selectivity of Single-Atom Catalysts on N-Doped Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146904</link>
      <description>Tahereh Jangjooye Shaldehi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412457940

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tahereh Jangjooye Shaldehi, Kai S. Exner, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.146904</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical explorations of hydrogen evolution reaction mechanisms in transition metal-doped intermetallic compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44422-025-00003-9</link>
      <description>Jun-long Kou, Mingzi Sun, Haitao Yu, Xiao Wu, Zhiguo Xing, Suzhe Liang, Bolong Huang, No host. 1(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412461118

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun-long Kou, Mingzi Sun, Haitao Yu, Xiao Wu, Zhiguo Xing, Suzhe Liang, Bolong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44422-025-00003-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of trimetallic dual-atom alloy catalysts for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.015</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Wang, Chunmei Tang, Ting Xiao, Feng Xiong, Xiaofeng Zhou, Kaixiao Zhang, Jiangfeng Gong, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412464547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Wang, Chunmei Tang, Ting Xiao, Feng Xiong, Xiaofeng Zhou, Kaixiao Zhang, Jiangfeng Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.07.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interplay between alkaline water oxidation temperature, composition and performance of electrospun high-entropy non-equimolar (Cr,Mn,Fe,Co,Ni) oxide electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237887</link>
      <description>Claudia Triolo, Kaveh Moulaee, Fulvio Bellato, Gioele Pagot, Alessandro Ponti, Susan Maida, Nicola Pinna, G. Neri, Vito Di Noto, S. Santangelo, Journal of Power Sources. 654(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412467626

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Claudia Triolo, Kaveh Moulaee, Fulvio Bellato, Gioele Pagot, Alessandro Ponti, Susan Maida, Nicola Pinna, G. Neri, Vito Di Noto, S. Santangelo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.237887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical study of novel Rh2P2 and their analogs for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.113022</link>
      <description>Chenglin Li, Yinchang Zhao, Zhenhong Dai, Junru Wang, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412468213

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenglin Li, Yinchang Zhao, Zhenhong Dai, Junru Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.113022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling the catalytic and degradation mechanisms of cobalt active sites during acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01812-x</link>
      <description>Darcy Simondson, Marc F. Tesch, Ioannis Spanos, Travis E. Jones, Jining Guo, Brittany V. Kerr, Manjunath Chatti, Shannon A. Bonke, Ronny Golnak, Bernt Johannessen, Jie Xiao, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Rosalie K. Hocking, Alexandr N. Simonov, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412470602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Darcy Simondson, Marc F. Tesch, Ioannis Spanos, Travis E. Jones, Jining Guo, Brittany V. Kerr, Manjunath Chatti, Shannon A. Bonke, Ronny Golnak, Bernt Johannessen, Jie Xiao, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Rosalie K. Hocking, Alexandr N. Simonov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-025-01812-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implicit neural representations for chemical reaction paths</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0267023</link>
      <description>Kalyan Ramakrishnan, Lars L. Schaaf, Chen Lin, Guangrun Wang, Philip H. S. Torr, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412472088

                We show that neural networks can be optimized to represent minimum energy paths as continuous functions, offering a flexible alternative to discrete path-search methods such as Nudged Elastic Band (NEB). Our approach parameterizes reaction paths with a network trained on a loss function that discards tangential energy gradients and enables instant estimation of the transition state. We first validate the method on two-dimensional potentials and then demonstrate its advantages over NEB on challenging atomistic systems where (i) poor initial guesses yield unphysical paths, (ii) multiple competing paths exist, or (iii) the reaction follows a complex multi-step mechanism. Results highlight the versatility of the method: for instance, a simple adjustment to the sampling strategy during optimization can help escape local-minimum solutions. Finally, in a low-dimensional setting, we demonstrate that a single neural network can learn from existing paths and generalize to unseen systems, showing promise for a universal reaction path representation.</description>
      <author>Kalyan Ramakrishnan, Lars L. Schaaf, Chen Lin, Guangrun Wang, Philip H. S. Torr</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0267023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five key concepts linking vacancies, structure, and oxygen evolution reaction activity in cobalt-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cc02438b</link>
      <description>Kenneth Crossley, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412475511

                Focusing on five key concepts, we review the roles of cation and oxygen vacancies in determining the surface reconstruction pathway, reaction mechanism, and ultimate activity of cobalt-based oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Kenneth Crossley, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cc02438b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthened Ru&#8211;O Bonds for Robust Oxygen Evolution in Acid Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02453</link>
      <description>Danning Li, Wenrui Ma, Mathan K. Eswaran, Chunfeng Li, Jiayi Chen, Guangxin Sun, Shibo Xi, Sergey M. Kozlov, Chunnian He, Lei Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412479227

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Danning Li, Wenrui Ma, Mathan K. Eswaran, Chunfeng Li, Jiayi Chen, Guangxin Sun, Shibo Xi, Sergey M. Kozlov, Chunnian He, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c02453</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI for Complex Catalytic Systems: High-Entropy Alloys in Electrocatalytic Acetylene Semihydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04236</link>
      <description>Zhen Tan, Xinyu Li, Rui Bai, Chang Guo, Xiao Han, Qinfeng Shi, Jian Zhang, Haobo Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412479777

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhen Tan, Xinyu Li, Rui Bai, Chang Guo, Xiao Han, Qinfeng Shi, Jian Zhang, Haobo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Capture from Natural Gas Flue Emissions and Air via (Bi)Carbonate Formation in a Cyclodextrin-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07336</link>
      <description>Seng Lim, Mary E. Zick, Jaehwan Kim, Benjamin J. Rhodes, Joharimanitra Randrianandraina, Tristan A. Pitt, R.T. Jerozal, Jung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Alexander C. Forse, Phillip J. Milner, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412184735

                Carbon capture and utilization or sequestration (CCUS) from industrial point sources and direct air capture (DAC) are both necessary to curb the rising atmospheric levels of CO2. Amine scrubbers, the current leading carbon capture technology, suffer from poor oxidative and thermal stability, limiting their long-term cycling stability under oxygen-rich streams such as air and the emissions from natural gas combined cycle (NGCC) power plants. Herein, we demonstrate that the hydroxide-based cyclodextrin metal-organic framework (CD-MOF) Rb2CO3 CD-MOF ST possesses high CO2 capacities from dry dilute streams at low temperatures and humid streams at elevated temperatures. Additionally, it displays good thermal, oxidative, and cycling stabilities and selective CO2 capture under mixed gas conditions in dynamic breakthrough experiments. Unexpectedly, under dry, hot conditions, a shift in the CO2 adsorption mechanism&#9472;from reversibly formed bicarbonate to irreversibly formed carbonate&#9472;is observed, as supported by gas sorption and spectroscopic studies coupled with density functional theory (DFT) calculations. This mechanistic switch, akin to urea formation in amine-functionalized sorbents, has not been previously reported in a hydroxide-based material and sheds new light on the interplay between bicarbonate and carbonate species during CO2 capture. Our findings provide valuable insight for the design of next-generation materials containing oxygen-based nucleophiles for carbon capture applications.</description>
      <author>Seng Lim, Mary E. Zick, Jaehwan Kim, Benjamin J. Rhodes, Joharimanitra Randrianandraina, Tristan A. Pitt, R.T. Jerozal, Jung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Alexander C. Forse, Phillip J. Milner</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating surface properties of catalysts to promote the oxidation of multi-component VOCs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.118118</link>
      <description>Min Zhang, Liangyu Liu, Ling Ding, Ningjie Fang, Yinghao Chu, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412467963

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Zhang, Liangyu Liu, Ling Ding, Ningjie Fang, Yinghao Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2025.118118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antisymmetry rules of response properties in certain chemical spaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0271350</link>
      <description>Takafumi Shiraogawa, Simon Le&#243;n Krug, Masahiro Ehara, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412192731

                Understanding chemical compound space (CCS), a set of molecules and materials, is crucial for the rational discovery of molecules and materials. Concepts of symmetry have recently been introduced into CCS to account for near degeneracies and differences in electronic energies between iso-electronic materials. In this work, we present approximate relationships of response properties based on a first-principles view of CCS. They have been derived from perturbation theory and antisymmetry considerations involving nuclear charges. These rules allow approximate predictions of relative response properties of pairs of distinct compounds with opposite nuclear charge variations from a highly symmetric reference material, without the need for experiments or quantum chemical calculations of each compound. We numerically and statistically verified these rules for electric and magnetic response properties (electric dipole moment, polarizabilities, hyperpolarizabilities, and magnetizabilities) among charge-neutral and iso-electronic boron nitride-doped polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon derivatives of naphthalene, anthracene, and pyrene. Our analysis indicates that, despite their simplicity, antisymmetry rule-based predictions are remarkably accurate, enabling dimensionality reduction of CCS. The rules predict the electric response properties more accurately than the magnetizabilities. The electric response properties in alchemical perturbation density functional theory were investigated to clarify the origin of this predictive power.</description>
      <author>Takafumi Shiraogawa, Simon Le&#243;n Krug, Masahiro Ehara, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0271350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flow-driven data intensification to accelerate autonomous inorganic materials discovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-025-00249-z</link>
      <description>Fernando Delgado&#8208;Licona, Abdulrahman Alsaiari, Hannah Dickerson, Philip Klem, Arup Ghorai, Richard B. Canty, Jeffrey A. Bennett, Pragyan Jha, Nikolai Mukhin, Junbin Li, Enrique A. L&#243;pez-Guajardo, Sina Sadeghi, Fazel Bateni, Milad Abolhasani, Nature Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4412388002

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fernando Delgado&#8208;Licona, Abdulrahman Alsaiari, Hannah Dickerson, Philip Klem, Arup Ghorai, Richard B. Canty, Jeffrey A. Bennett, Pragyan Jha, Nikolai Mukhin, Junbin Li, Enrique A. L&#243;pez-Guajardo, Sina Sadeghi, Fazel Bateni, Milad Abolhasani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-025-00249-z</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
