<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 01:37:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Combustion synthesis of carbon hollow nanocubes: DFT modelling and electrochemical performance analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120268</link>
      <description>Hayk H. Nersisyan, Junmo Jeong, Hoyoung Suh, Jong&#8208;Hyeon Lee, Carbon. 238(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408983373

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hayk H. Nersisyan, Junmo Jeong, Hoyoung Suh, Jong&#8208;Hyeon Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120268</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updating the sub-nanometric cognition of reconstructed oxyhydroxide active phase for water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58424-y</link>
      <description>Yu Sun, Yong Xie, Xiaoxuan Chen, Jing Wu, Peng Fei Liu, Xin Wang, Zhen Tian, Wenhao Zheng, Zhouyu Jiang, Zhuo Kang, Yue Zhang, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408984077

                Unveiling structure-activity correlations at the sub-nanoscale remains an essential challenge in catalysis science. During electrocatalysis, dynamic structural evolution drives the ambiguous entanglement of crystals and electrons degrees of freedom that obscure the activity origin. Here, we track the structural evolution of Ni-based model pre-catalysts (Ni(OH)2, NiS2, NiSe2, NiTe), detailing their catalytically active state during water oxidation via operando techniques and theoretical calculations. We reveal the sub-nanometric structural difference of NiO6 unit with a regular distortion in the reconstructed active phase NiOOH, codetermined by the geometric (bond lengths) and electronic (covalency) structure of the pre-catalysts on both spatial and temporal scales. The symmetry-broken active units induce the delicate balance of the p and d orbitals in NiOOH, further steering the modulation of catalytic intermediate configurations and mechanisms, with improved performance. This work recognizes the fine structural differences of the active phases from the sub-nanometer scale, and quantitatively explains their influence on activity. Our findings provide a more intuitive design framework for high-efficiency materials through targeted symmetry engineering of active units. Unveiling structure-activity correlations is essential in catalysis science. Here, the authors report the structural evolution of Ni-based pre-catalysts during the reaction and demonstrate how sub-nanometric variations affect catalytic performance in the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Yu Sun, Yong Xie, Xiaoxuan Chen, Jing Wu, Peng Fei Liu, Xin Wang, Zhen Tian, Wenhao Zheng, Zhouyu Jiang, Zhuo Kang, Yue Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58424-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ SO42&#8722; regulation of ZrFeCoNiAl-based high-entropy electrocatalysts to enhance O&#8211;O coupling in the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2025.01.061</link>
      <description>Bingxuan Zhai, Yan He, Jiawen Chen, Xuemin Cui, Leping Liu, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408985637

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingxuan Zhai, Yan He, Jiawen Chen, Xuemin Cui, Leping Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2025.01.061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-engineered CoP-Co2P/coal-based carbon fibers composite as self-supporting electrocatalyst for efficient overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137461</link>
      <description>Mengran Lou, Ruiying Wang, Luxiang Wang, Yang Wang, Xinyue Jia, Fengrui Sun, Shengjiao Wen, Yali Cao, Tong Zeng, Zhiqian Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408987024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengran Lou, Ruiying Wang, Luxiang Wang, Yang Wang, Xinyue Jia, Fengrui Sun, Shengjiao Wen, Yali Cao, Tong Zeng, Zhiqian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.137461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen diffusion in magnesium using machine learning potentials: a comparative study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01555-z</link>
      <description>Andrea Angeletti, Luca Leoni, Dario Massa, Luca Pasquini, Stefanos Papanikolaou, Cesare Franchini, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408988998

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrea Angeletti, Luca Leoni, Dario Massa, Luca Pasquini, Stefanos Papanikolaou, Cesare Franchini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01555-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Cu3 clusters on MXene (Ti2CO2) for CO electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163118</link>
      <description>Tiantian Wang, Hailong Li, Yulong Li, Tianbin Yuan, Kan&#8208;Hao Xue, Feng Yu, Canqing Yu, Juan Hou, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408989185

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tiantian Wang, Hailong Li, Yulong Li, Tianbin Yuan, Kan&#8208;Hao Xue, Feng Yu, Canqing Yu, Juan Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.163118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced CO2 reduction on transition metal-doped AlN and GaN quantum dots: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112723</link>
      <description>Zhilong Wang, Nahed H. Teleb, Mahmoud A.S. Sakr, Omar H. Abd&#8208;Elkader, Hazem Abdelsalam, Qinfang Zhang, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408989503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhilong Wang, Nahed H. Teleb, Mahmoud A.S. Sakr, Omar H. Abd&#8208;Elkader, Hazem Abdelsalam, Qinfang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2025.112723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the role of surface reconstruction and charge redistribution in M1M2-N4-Grs for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.339</link>
      <description>Yao Chen, Xuefei Liu, Gaofu Liu, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Zhen Wang, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Changsong Gao, Jinshun Bi, Wei Deng, Xuemin Zhang, Wenting Li, Yang Luo, Wentao Liang, Wenjun Xiao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 121(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408989730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Chen, Xuefei Liu, Gaofu Liu, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Zhen Wang, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Changsong Gao, Jinshun Bi, Wei Deng, Xuemin Zhang, Wenting Li, Yang Luo, Wentao Liang, Wenjun Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PtMIr (M= Ni, Co, Fe, Mn, V, Ti) nanowires electrocatalysts towards ORR in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121592</link>
      <description>Changhai Liang, Qiang Wang, Guangwei Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Sai Luo, Zhijia Han, Danmin Xing, Chuang Li, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408991561

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changhai Liang, Qiang Wang, Guangwei Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Sai Luo, Zhijia Han, Danmin Xing, Chuang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing catalytic reduction efficiency of MnSiB metallic glasses through boron modification by first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142073</link>
      <description>W. Zhu, S. Y. Tan, Y HUANG, Ke Gao, Peixin Fu, Lansong Yang, Huafeng Dong, Yuanzheng Yang, Chemical Physics Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408991730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W. Zhu, S. Y. Tan, Y HUANG, Ke Gao, Peixin Fu, Lansong Yang, Huafeng Dong, Yuanzheng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2025.142073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the catalytic activity of transition metal/cyclo[18] carbon single atom catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.poly.2025.117522</link>
      <description>Nuha Wazzan, Polyhedron. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408993821

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nuha Wazzan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.poly.2025.117522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric photooxidation of glycerol to hydroxypyruvic acid over Rb&#8211;Ir catalytic pairs on poly(heptazine imides)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-025-01897-1</link>
      <description>Zhenyuan Teng, Zhenzong Zhang, Ying Tu, Qitao Zhang, Nan Jian, Liujun Yang, Jiadong Xiao, Jie Ding, Lihong Huang, Teruhisa Ohno, Chengyin Wang, Dengsong Zhang, Han Yu, Jianmei Lu, Chenliang Su, Bin Liu, Nature Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408994781

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenyuan Teng, Zhenzong Zhang, Ying Tu, Qitao Zhang, Nan Jian, Liujun Yang, Jiadong Xiao, Jie Ding, Lihong Huang, Teruhisa Ohno, Chengyin Wang, Dengsong Zhang, Han Yu, Jianmei Lu, Chenliang Su, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-025-01897-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the integration of sulfonated poly(phenylene sulfone) ionomers into the cathode catalyst layers of proton exchange membrane fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236896</link>
      <description>Didem Yazili-Marini, Lionel Talley Fogang, Emanuele Marini, Tobias Morawietz, Giorgi Titvinidze, Joachim Bansmann, Markus H&#246;lzle, Ludwig J&#246;rissen, Journal of Power Sources. 641(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409007979

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Didem Yazili-Marini, Lionel Talley Fogang, Emanuele Marini, Tobias Morawietz, Giorgi Titvinidze, Joachim Bansmann, Markus H&#246;lzle, Ludwig J&#246;rissen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236896</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New insights into the long-range interaction mechanism of nitrogen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.024</link>
      <description>Yumeng Cheng, Wei Chen, Cheng He, Wenxue Zhang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409016616

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yumeng Cheng, Wei Chen, Cheng He, Wenxue Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in understanding mechanism of electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction via operando/in situ characterizations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101332</link>
      <description>Rashid Mehmood, Fuxiang Zhang, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409037945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rashid Mehmood, Fuxiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2025.101332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward improved descriptors by refining the complex reaction network in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0255158</link>
      <description>Lu Han, Huan Li, Jun Long, Hao Li, Jianping Xiao, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(13)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409038379

                Electrocatalysis is one of the key technologies for developing sustainable and fossil resource free routes to produce fuels and chemicals. The limiting potential (UL), defined by the reaction free energy of the most difficult electrochemical step in a given pathway, is an effective descriptor for establishing the activity trend of a set of electrocatalysts, allowing high throughput screening of new catalysts. However, the reaction network of electrocatalytic processes is rather complex, especially for the reactions with necessary thermochemical steps, e.g., the synthesis of valuable C&#8211;N bond-containing chemicals. Thermochemical steps cannot be significantly enhanced by electrode potentials, where kinetics is a non-negligible issue at even high overpotentials. This makes it challenge by using limiting potential to accurately describe activity trends for the reactions with necessary thermochemical steps. To this end, we propose an effective scheme to determine an improved descriptor. We suggest refining the rather complex reaction network at first. In particular, it is suggested to decouple electro- and thermochemical steps and exclude the unfavorable pathways with an excessively high thermochemical barrier. Then, a global comparison among the other pathways can be made, to determine the optimal pathway and the improved descriptor (the reaction free energy of the most difficult step of the optimal pathway, defined as &#916;GrRPD-limiting). In addition, the studies on reaction kinetics are also suggested to understand the exception of the best catalysts and provide the direction of experimental optimization. This scheme is of a great compromise between practical efficiency and the accuracy toward the rational design of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Lu Han, Huan Li, Jun Long, Hao Li, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0255158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface strain hampers dissociation and induces curious rotational-alignment effect for HCl on the Au/Cu(111) alloy surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0260125</link>
      <description>Tianhui Liu, Bina Fu, Dong H. Zhang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(13)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409038844

                We present the first six-dimensional quantum dynamics study of HCl on a strained pseudomorphic monolayer of Au deposited on a Cu(111) substrate, utilizing a newly developed machine learning-based potential energy surface. The strain in the surface lattice, resulting from a 12.62% compression of the Au monolayer, induces a significant high barrier height (1.81 eV) and a tight saddle point. These effects lead to a marked suppression of the reactivity of ground-state HCl (v = 0) on Au/Cu(111), while the dissociation probability of vibrationally excited (v = 1) HCl increases substantially. As a result, the vibrational efficiency is notably higher compared to those for HCl on pure Au(111) and alloyed Au/Ag(111) surfaces. In addition, the surface strain induces a distinctive rotational alignment effect in the title reaction, where for HCl in the (v = 0, j) states, dissociation is most favorable when an HCl molecule collides with its rotation perpendicular to the Au/Cu(111) surface (the cartwheel alignment). In contrast, for HCl in the (v = 1, j) states, the opposite (helicopter) alignment is preferred. This leads to a pronounced difference in the effects of rotational excitation, depending on whether HCl is initially in the ground or excited vibrational state.</description>
      <author>Tianhui Liu, Bina Fu, Dong H. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0260125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum simulations of chemistry in first quantization with any basis set</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41534-025-00987-1</link>
      <description>Timothy N. Georges, Marius Bothe, Christoph S&#252;nderhauf, Bjorn K. Berntson, R&#243;bert Izs&#225;k, Aleksei V. Ivanov, npj Quantum Information. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409047502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timothy N. Georges, Marius Bothe, Christoph S&#252;nderhauf, Bjorn K. Berntson, R&#243;bert Izs&#225;k, Aleksei V. Ivanov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41534-025-00987-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT study on single-atom catalysts of Fe-V2CS2 with low overpotential and high selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2025.138467</link>
      <description>Yibo Sun, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Zeliang Ju, Qingxin Kang, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409051811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yibo Sun, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Zeliang Ju, Qingxin Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2025.138467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Substituent Effects in CO to CH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;OH Conversion on a Cobalt Phthalocyanine Catalyst Using DFT Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07097</link>
      <description>Prasenjit Das, Ilya Grinberg, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409052190

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Prasenjit Das, Ilya Grinberg</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchoring single iridium atoms on defective nickel&#8211;iron layered double hydroxides for promoting oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121606</link>
      <description>Jianguo Huang, Ruijie Gao, Baowei Wang, Xun Cui, Lun Pan, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409053420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianguo Huang, Ruijie Gao, Baowei Wang, Xun Cui, Lun Pan, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.121606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V activated electro-epoxidation catalyst in membrane electrode assembly system for the production of propylene oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58486-y</link>
      <description>Yan Lin, Hui Li, Xiaodong Miao, Yang Sun, Hao Ren, Xifeng Yu, Wangyang Cui, Mingbo Wu, Zhongtao Li, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409060602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Lin, Hui Li, Xiaodong Miao, Yang Sun, Hao Ren, Xifeng Yu, Wangyang Cui, Mingbo Wu, Zhongtao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58486-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials for Electrocatalysis: Future Prospects in Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400254</link>
      <description>John M. George, Susikumar Thangarasu, J. Archana, P. Justin Jesuraj, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409075137

                Abstract Electrocatalysts play a pivotal role in various energy conversion processes, such as water splitting, batteries, carbon dioxide reduction, and fuel cell reactions, by significantly reducing the energy barrier and enhancing reaction kinetics. This review highlights the potential of earth&#8208;abundant electrocatalysts, with a particular focus on their capabilities in critical electrochemical reactions, including oxygen evolution reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction. Emphasis is also placed on bifunctional, trifunctional, and tetrafunctional performance, showcasing their adaptability and effectiveness across diverse energy applications. Exploration is done on a range of promising materials, including transition metal chalcogenides, MXenes, metal&#8208;organic frameworks, covalent organic frameworks, and layered double hydroxides. By examining their intrinsic properties, structural versatility, and surface engineering strategies, this review sheds light on the factors that govern their catalytic efficiency and stability. The integration of experimental advancements with theoretical insights provides a deeper understanding of mechanisms driving their catalytic activity. Additionally, we address the scalability, cost&#8208;effectiveness, and environmental impact of these materials, underlining their potential for large&#8208;scale deployment. By synthesizing recent progress and identifying challenges, this work delivers a roadmap for the model and application of multifunctional electrocatalysts, fostering innovations that align with the goals of sustainable energy systems.</description>
      <author>John M. George, Susikumar Thangarasu, J. Archana, P. Justin Jesuraj</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Antimony Tin Oxide with a Particle Assembly Structure as an IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Support for an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Proton-Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00875</link>
      <description>Zuobo Yang, Xiaokuan Wu, Leilei Cai, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, Xin Liang, Hong Zhao, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409076512

                Proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) holds great promise for hydrogen production applications. However, the reliance of PEMWE membrane electrodes on high loadings of expensive iridium poses a significant barrier to their commercial viability. Therefore, the development of high-performance oxygen evolution catalysts with a low iridium content is of critical importance. In this research, a porous antimony tin oxide (ATO) conductive support with a particle assembly aggregate structure was fabricated by a carbon template removal method. ATO-supported IrO2 exhibits significantly improved oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, with a much lower overpotential compared to the unsupported IrO2 catalyst. Moreover, it achieves 1.8 V at 2 A cm-2 with an ultralow loading of iridium (0.3 mgIr cm-2) for the proton-exchange membrane electrolyzer. Characterization techniques and density functional theory calculations have elucidated that the enhanced performance is attributed to the porous morphology of ATO and the strong metal oxide-support interaction between IrO2 and the ATO support. These findings validate the practicality of conductive nanostructured antimony-tin-oxide-supported catalysts for PEMWE applications and offer a pathway for the design of low-Ir OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zuobo Yang, Xiaokuan Wu, Leilei Cai, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, Xin Liang, Hong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c00875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polydisperse Pt Deposits Over TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Nanotube&#8208;Array&#8208;Supported Ru Nanoparticles: Harnessing the Interfacial Synergy for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411870</link>
      <description>Mila N. Krstaji&#263; Paji&#263;, Ana S. Dobrota, Anca Mazare, Sladjana Djurdji&#263;, Xin Zhou, Nikita Denisov, Natalia V. Skorodumova, Dragan Manojlovi&#263;, Rastko Vasili&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, Patrik Schmuki, U.&#268;. La&#269;njevac, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409084727

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective precious metal electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is key to realizing the economic viability of acidic water electrolysis. Herein, galvanic displacement is employed for in situ formation of bimetallic Pt/Ru deposits on H&#8208;intercalated TiO 2 nanotube arrays. It is found that a two&#8208;step procedure yields polydisperse deposits with a dominant fraction of Ru nanoparticles coated with atomic and subnanometric Pt islands. These Pt|Ru nanointerfaces induce charge transfer from Pt to Ru, which modulates the electronic structure of Pt sites for accelerated HER kinetics. By varying the platinization time in the second step, a balance between the exposure of catalytically active Pt|Ru nanointerfaces and the total number of Pt surface sites is achieved. The optimized composite, termed Ru&#8208;30min@Pt&#8208;30min, requires an overpotential of 58 mV to deliver a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1.0 m HClO 4 and maintains performance stability and structure integrity under prolonged operation. Moreover, it presents a 3.5&#8208;fold increase in precious metal mass activity over Pt/C at &#951; = 80 mV. Theoretical calculations reveal that the electronic interactions generated by Pt&#8208;modification of Ru and hydrogenated TiO 2 surfaces provide multiple active sites with improved H ads energetics compared to pure Pt and Ru.</description>
      <author>Mila N. Krstaji&#263; Paji&#263;, Ana S. Dobrota, Anca Mazare, Sladjana Djurdji&#263;, Xin Zhou, Nikita Denisov, Natalia V. Skorodumova, Dragan Manojlovi&#263;, Rastko Vasili&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, Patrik Schmuki, U.&#268;. La&#269;njevac</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Rich Selenide Monolayers as Metal-Free Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reactions: A First-Principles Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7020055</link>
      <description>Yao Xu, Fengyu Li, Chemistry. 7(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409092115

                Carbon-based materials have garnered significant attention for electrocatalysis applications in fuel cells due to their unique structural and electronic properties, but rapid oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at the cathode of fuel cells is challenging. Dopants are typically used as active sites for ORR, and increasing the number of active sites for carbon-based catalysts remains a challenge. Here, we carried out first-principles calculations for the electrocatalytic ORR performance of the recently reported monolayer superconductors of carbon-rich selenides. Remarkably, the abundant C atoms serve as the active centers instead of the foreign atoms (Se). All the free energy changes during the ORR process are downhill, suggesting that these carbon-rich selenides hold promise as metal-free electrocatalysts for ORR. Note that the promising electrocatalytic performance of carbon-rich selenides is theoretically predicted; validation is encouraged for experimental efforts.</description>
      <author>Yao Xu, Fengyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7020055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Definition of Important Terms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527853205.ch4</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409187927

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527853205.ch4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MgCo2O4 nanostructures as cathode electrodes for perspective application in electrochemical CO2 pumping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.304</link>
      <description>M.V. Contreras-Mart&#237;nez, Irene Gatto, Alessandra Carbone, Goldie Oza, G. Sanghez de Luna, Domingo I. Garc&#237;a-Guti&#233;rrez, No&#233; Arjona, J. Ledesma&#8208;Garc&#237;a, L.G. Arr&#237;aga, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4408979232

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M.V. Contreras-Mart&#237;nez, Irene Gatto, Alessandra Carbone, Goldie Oza, G. Sanghez de Luna, Domingo I. Garc&#237;a-Guti&#233;rrez, No&#233; Arjona, J. Ledesma&#8208;Garc&#237;a, L.G. Arr&#237;aga</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainable classification of goat vocalizations using convolutional neural networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0318543</link>
      <description>Stavros Ntalampiras, Gabriele Pesando Gamacchio, PLoS ONE. 20(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409049727

                Efficient precision livestock farming relies on having timely access to data and information that accurately describes both the animals and their surrounding environment. This paper advances classification of goat vocalizations leveraging a publicly available dataset recorded at diverse farms breeding different species. We developed a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) architecture tailored for classifying goat vocalizations, yielding an average classification rate of 95.8% in discriminating various goat emotional states. To this end, we suitably augmented the existing dataset using pitch shifting and time stretching techniques boosting the robustness of the trained model. After thoroughly demonstrating the superiority of the designed architecture over the contrasting approaches, we provide insights into the underlying mechanisms governing the proposed CNN by carrying out an extensive interpretation study. More specifically, we conducted an explainability analysis to identify the time-frequency content within goat vocalisations that significantly impacts the classification process. Such an XAI-driven validation not only provides transparency in the decision-making process of the CNN model but also sheds light on the acoustic features crucial for distinguishing the considered classes. Last but not least, the proposed solution encompasses an interactive scheme able to provide valuable information to animal scientists regarding the analysis performed by the model highlighting the distinctive components of the considered goat vocalizations. Our findings underline the effectiveness of data augmentation techniques in bolstering classification accuracy and highlight the significance of leveraging XAI methodologies for validating and interpreting complex machine learning models applied to animal vocalizations.</description>
      <author>Stavros Ntalampiras, Gabriele Pesando Gamacchio</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0318543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Simulations of Skaergaardite (CuPd) with a Self-Consistent Hubbard U-Correction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7020056</link>
      <description>Martino Napoli, Assimo Maris, Chemistry. 7(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4409091991

                The electronic and phonon bands of Skaergaardite are investigated using density functional theory (DFT) as implemented in Quantum ESPRESSO. Skaergaardite is a copper palladium mineral (CuPd) found in the Skaergaard intrusion with a CsCl-type (B2) structure. Due to its porous structure, it presents a large surface area available for interactions, which makes it a promising catalyst. The PBE-GGA functional with a Hubbard-like localized term (DFT+U) is combined with ultrasoft and norm-conserving pseudopotentials, and a conventional approach with a dense Monkhorst&#8211;Pack grid of k-points 12 &#215; 12 &#215; 12 is applied. The electronic valence bands are mainly constituted by 3d orbitals of Cu and 4d orbitals of Pd and a pseudo-gap can be recognized. With respect to DFT, DFT+U causes a general downward shift in the valence band. The acoustic and optical phonon branches are separated by a few cm&#8722;1 gap at about 150 cm&#8722;1 and show a density of state curve typical of ordered materials. These results highlight the reliability of DFT+U in studying bimetallic systems with scarce experimental benchmarks, offering insights into the behavior of Skaergaardite and its potential applications in material science such as reduction reactions and hydrogen storage.</description>
      <author>Martino Napoli, Assimo Maris</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7020056</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
