<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 01:25:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Boron and Nitrogen Bridged Mn Single&#8208;Atom Catalyst for Highly Efficient Nitrogen Electroreduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507387</link>
      <description>Hansaem Choi, Siraj Sultan, Mahdi Zafari, Aram Yoon, Hojeong Lee, Miran Ha, Beomgyun Jeong, HyungKuk Ju, Hyung Chul Yoon, Kwang S. Kim, Zonghoon Lee, Geunsik Lee, Youngkook Kwon, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414647449

                Abstract Ammonia (NH 3 ) is a globally important commodity for energy storage, carbon&#8208;free energy carrier, and fertilizer production, but its synthesis through the Haber&#8208;Bosch process is energy&#8208;intensive and emits significant amounts of CO 2 . Electrochemical reduction of N 2 under ambient conditions is a green and potentially promising approach for NH 3 synthesis, but is limited by a high energy barrier of the first *N 2 protonation step, competitive hydrogen evolution reaction, and lack of efficient electrocatalysts. Herein, a newly designed electrocatalyst is reported by bridging B 2 N 2 with an Mn single atom in B/N co&#8208;doped carbon (denoted MnB 2 N 2 /C), which exhibits a highly efficient N 2 reduction reaction (N 2 RR) activity with NH 3 Faradaic efficiency (FE NH3 ) of &#8776;37.15% in the aqueous phase system and good electrocatalytic and material stability. The FE NH3 of the MnB 2 N 2 /C catalyst is &#8776;2.1 times higher than that of the as&#8208;synthesized MnN 4 /C counterpart under the same conditions. In the gas phase system, this MnB 2 N 2 /C catalyst shows a remarkably high NH 3 production rate (87.54 &#181;g mg cat. &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 ) and FE NH3 (45.66%). The density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed that the high N 2 RR to NH 3 performance arising from the Mn site and the neighboring B site suppresses the parasitic HER on the Mn sites.</description>
      <author>Hansaem Choi, Siraj Sultan, Mahdi Zafari, Aram Yoon, Hojeong Lee, Miran Ha, Beomgyun Jeong, HyungKuk Ju, Hyung Chul Yoon, Kwang S. Kim, Zonghoon Lee, Geunsik Lee, Youngkook Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202507387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct generation of nitrogen-centered radicals via non-covalent interaction between Cu complexes and BiVO4 photoanodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63670-1</link>
      <description>Lei Wu, Kun Dang, Qiaozhen Li, Yi Xu, Yuchao Zhang, Jincai Zhao, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414652534

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Wu, Kun Dang, Qiaozhen Li, Yi Xu, Yuchao Zhang, Jincai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63670-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cluster expansion-accelerated exploration of the surface structure properties of a PdPtAg ternary alloy for the oxygen reduction reaction across the compositional space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra05089h</link>
      <description>Minghao Hua, Shuo Li, Xuelei Tian, Xiaohang Lin, Guoxiang Li, RSC Advances. 15(43)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414673957

                The amount and distribution of dopant metals Pt and Pd in the ternary alloy Pd/Pt/Ag can be controlled by adjusting the temperature; the atomic distribution can be observed using the cluster expansion with Monte Carlo simulations.</description>
      <author>Minghao Hua, Shuo Li, Xuelei Tian, Xiaohang Lin, Guoxiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ra05089h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cl-adsorbed Cu(111)/H2O interface selectively realizes electrochemical CO2 reduction towards C2H4 product: Mechanistic understanding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111920</link>
      <description>Lihui Ou, Z. Y. Liu, Dai&#8208;Huo Liu, Zhi Zhang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414674832

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lihui Ou, Z. Y. Liu, Dai&#8208;Huo Liu, Zhi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111920</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of MOF-derived porous N-doped carbon-supported Co-RuSe2 via microwave-triggered in situ foaming for efficient alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164759</link>
      <description>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, M.K. Han, Shujie Yang, Yanghong Li, Meiling Zhan, Bozhi Yang, Shaorou Ke, Xin Li, Minghao Fang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414679663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyu Zhu, Minghao Fang, M.K. Han, Shujie Yang, Yanghong Li, Meiling Zhan, Bozhi Yang, Shaorou Ke, Xin Li, Minghao Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu Nanoclusters and Rh Single-Atom-Modified N-Doped Carbon for Electroreduction of Nitrate to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c03508</link>
      <description>W. H. Dai, Yahan Fang, Junfeng Huang, Zhongwei Wang, Jian Li, Mudong Tu, Huijiao Wang, Jun Yang, Cailing Xu, Hua Li, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414689140

                To tackle the pressing issue of nitrate (NO3&#8211;) pollution in wastewater and simultaneously convert it into ammonia (NH3), Cu nanocluster-modified Rhodium (Rh) single atoms anchored on N-doped carbon were synthesized via pyrolysis of a zeolitic imidazolate framework-8 (ZIF-8) precursor and applied to the electrochemical reduction of nitrate at a low concentration. Structural characterizations (X-ray powder diffractometer (XRD), high-angle annular dark-field scanning transmission electron microscopy (HAADF-STEM), and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS)) confirmed the coexistence of Rh single atoms and Cu nanoclusters as well as their strong electronic interactions. Mechanistic investigations revealed that Rh sites enhanced *H generation via water dissociation and promoted NO3&#8211; adsorption, thereby facilitating *H transfer and subsequent hydrogenation steps. As a result, the optimized Cu97.5Rh2.5/NC catalyst exhibited outstanding NO3&#8211;RR performance, with a Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 84.53%, an NH3 yield rate of 1252.22 &#956;g&#183;h&#8211;1 mgcat&#8211;1 at &#8722;1.0 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), an NH3 selectivity of 89.13% at &#8722;1.0 V vs RHE, and a NO3&#8211; conversion rate of 93.34% at &#8722;1.1 V vs RHE. This work presents a rational design for atom-economical catalysts, enabling sustainable NH3 electrosynthesis from nitrate-laden wastewater and reducing effluent NO3&#8211;&#8211;N to meet World Health Organization (WHO) drinking water standards.</description>
      <author>W. H. Dai, Yahan Fang, Junfeng Huang, Zhongwei Wang, Jian Li, Mudong Tu, Huijiao Wang, Jun Yang, Cailing Xu, Hua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5c03508</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Pathways Tuning Facilitates Photoelectrochemical Upcycling of Nitrite to Ammonia Using CuPd Nanoalloy on GaN/Si Photocathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.5c04038</link>
      <description>Kejian Li, Tianyin Qiu, Bingxing Zhang, Zhengwei Ye, Jan Paul Menzel, Wan Jae Dong, Yuyang Pan, Songtao Tang, Zhuoran Long, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Zetian Mi, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414689575

                Solar-driven photoelectrochemical conversion of nitrite to ammonia represents a sustainable yet unexplored approach for environmental remediation and resource recovery. Here, we demonstrate that Cu5Pd1 alloy nanoparticles, integrated with vertically grown GaN nanowires on an n+-p Si photocathode (Cu5Pd1/GaN/Si), enable highly efficient and selective nitrite reduction to ammonia. This photoelectrode achieves a Faradaic efficiency of 99.7% for NH3, with a yield rate of 162.2 &#956;mol h&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2 and a nearly 100% selectivity. Additionally, the Cu5Pd1/GaN/Si photoelectrode maintains robust performance in the presence of various anions and can effectively remove &#8764;98% of nitrite even at low concentrations. Density functional theory calculations, supported by in situ spectroscopic techniques, reveal that Cu&#8211;Pd alloying fundamentally alters the nitrite reduction mechanisms. Unlike the *NOH-mediated pathway on Cu and Pd, which can lead to competing N2 formation, the CuPd alloy preferentially stabilizes the *NHO intermediate, making NH3 production thermodynamically preferred and highly selective. These findings highlight that a rational electrocatalyst design can effectively tune reaction pathways to enhance both the efficiency and selectivity of photoelectrocatalytic nitrite upcycling.</description>
      <author>Kejian Li, Tianyin Qiu, Bingxing Zhang, Zhengwei Ye, Jan Paul Menzel, Wan Jae Dong, Yuyang Pan, Songtao Tang, Zhuoran Long, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Zetian Mi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.5c04038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-34088-8.00009-4</link>
      <description>Alexandra C. Iacoban, Florentina Nea&#355;u, &#350;tefan Nea&#355;u, Mihaela Florea, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414697017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alexandra C. Iacoban, Florentina Nea&#355;u, &#350;tefan Nea&#355;u, Mihaela Florea</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-34088-8.00009-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron&#8211;Water Interface at Different Electrochemical Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04170</link>
      <description>Adenilson Felipe Sousa Silva, D&#237;dac A. Fenoll, Mariona Sodupe, Luis Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Santiago, Xavier Solans&#8208;Monfort, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414697622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adenilson Felipe Sousa Silva, D&#237;dac A. Fenoll, Mariona Sodupe, Luis Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Santiago, Xavier Solans&#8208;Monfort</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain boundary segregation engineering in high-entropy multiphase alloys for overall water splitting at ultra-high current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126035</link>
      <description>Yifan Cui, Yonghui Wang, Bo Li, Yu Sui, Gang Wang, Juntao Huo, Jianhua Li, Jia&#8208;Qi Huang, Yan Du, Zhen&#8208;Qiang Yu, Jianfei Sun, Sida Jiang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414698900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Cui, Yonghui Wang, Bo Li, Yu Sui, Gang Wang, Juntao Huo, Jianhua Li, Jia&#8208;Qi Huang, Yan Du, Zhen&#8208;Qiang Yu, Jianfei Sun, Sida Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.126035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological Luttinger-semimetal CoAs3 dye-sensitized photocatalyst for efficient solar hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63843-y</link>
      <description>Yuan Cao, Han Zhuo, Rui Song, Yuqi Liu, Shucai Xia, Xinlei Zhang, Jing Leng, Changhao Wang, Wenliang Zhu, Yin Yu, Xiaomin Tian, Jiaqi He, Yu Zou, Yi Ma, Jianzhi Gao, Chuanyao Zhou, Feng Song, Wei Huang, Minghu Pan, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414700634

                Solar-driven photocatalytic water splitting is a process for hydrogen production from a renewable source. The practical implementation of this technology is limited by the low conversion efficiency of the hydrogen evolution reaction under visible light and the insufficient long-term stability of photocatalysts. Here we demonstrate a dye (Eosin Y)-sensitized photocatalyst for efficient hydrogen production. The topological semimetal CoAs3 achieves a hydrogen production rate of 2688 &#956;mol h&#8722;1 g&#8722;1 (&#955; &#8805; 420 nm) and an apparent quantum efficiency of 15.2% at &#955; = 500 nm. Efficient photocatalytic activity is attributed to the electronic properties of CoAs3, which facilitate electron transfer at the Eosin Y/CoAs3 interface, determined by transient absorption spectroscopy. Density functional theory calculations predict that CoAs3 is a Luttinger semimetal, exhibiting a quadratic band touching point near the Fermi level and an associated topological insulator gap. The carrier mobility of the material facilitates the transfer of injected electrons from the dye to active sites. Herein, we report a topological photocatalyst that exhibits enhanced stability and efficiency for solar hydrogen production. Developing photocatalysts from earth-abundant materials is crucial for sustainable solar hydrogen production, yet challenges in efficiency and stability persist. Here, the authors report that the topological semimetal cobalt triarsenide functions as an active and durable platform for this reaction.</description>
      <author>Yuan Cao, Han Zhuo, Rui Song, Yuqi Liu, Shucai Xia, Xinlei Zhang, Jing Leng, Changhao Wang, Wenliang Zhu, Yin Yu, Xiaomin Tian, Jiaqi He, Yu Zou, Yi Ma, Jianzhi Gao, Chuanyao Zhou, Feng Song, Wei Huang, Minghu Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63843-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Data in Electron Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7050160</link>
      <description>&#1053;. &#1052;. &#1048;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Alexey S. Kashin, Valentine P. Ananikov, Chemistry. 7(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414701117

                The goal of this study is to estimate the amount of lost data in electron microscopy and to analyze the extent to which experimentally acquired images are utilized in peer-reviewed scientific publications. Analysis of the number of images taken on electron microscopes at a core user facility and the number of images subsequently included in peer-reviewed scientific journals revealed low efficiency of data utilization. Up to around 90% of electron microscopy data generated during routine instrument operation can remain unused. Of the more than 150,000 electron microscopy images evaluated in this study, only approximately 3500 (just over 2%) were made available in publications. For the analyzed dataset, the amount of lost data in electron microscopy can be estimated as &gt;90% (in terms of data being recorded but not being published in peer-reviewed literature). On the one hand, these results highlight a shortcoming in the optimal use of microscopy images; on the other hand, they indicate the existence of a large pool of electron microscopy data that can facilitate research in data science and the development of AI-based projects. The considerations important to unlock the potential of lost data are discussed in the present article.</description>
      <author>&#1053;. &#1052;. &#1048;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Alexey S. Kashin, Valentine P. Ananikov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemistry7050160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Enhancement of &#946;-NiOOH Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance through Transition Metal Atom Doping and Vacancy Modulating</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147485</link>
      <description>Chenghuan Zhong, Dawei Li, Shimao Xie, Pengcheng Yang, Jiao Teng, Yeyun Kang, Jianfeng Tang, Hua Lin, Chunmei Li, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414706162

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenghuan Zhong, Dawei Li, Shimao Xie, Pengcheng Yang, Jiao Teng, Yeyun Kang, Jianfeng Tang, Hua Lin, Chunmei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain-modulated photocatalytic hydrogen production and storage capacity analysis of Li2S monolayer: A DFT approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107772</link>
      <description>Abdul Rehman, Ghulam Nabi, S.S.A. Gillani, &#8207;Abdullah K. Alanazi, M. Shakil&#8206;, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414706471

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Rehman, Ghulam Nabi, S.S.A. Gillani, &#8207;Abdullah K. Alanazi, M. Shakil&#8206;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107772</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hammett-Inspired Product Baseline for Data-Efficient &#916;-ML in Chemical Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00848</link>
      <description>V. Diana Rakotonirina, Marco Bragato, Guido Falk von Rudorff, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414706768

                Data-hungry machine learning methods have become a new standard to efficiently navigate chemical compound space for molecular and materials design and discovery. Due to the severe scarcity and cost of high-quality experimental or synthetic simulated training data, however, data-acquisition costs can be considerable. Relying on reasonably accurate approximate legacy baseline labels with low computational complexity represents one of the most effective strategies to curb data-needs, e.g. through &#916;-, transfer-, or multifidelity learning. A surprisingly effective and data-efficient baseline model is presented in the form of a generic coarse-graining Hammett-inspired product (HIP) Ansatz, generalizing the empirical Hammett equation toward arbitrary systems and properties. Numerical evidence for the applicability of HIP includes solvation free energies of molecules, formation energies of quaternary elpasolite crystals, carbon adsorption energies on heterogeneous catalytic surfaces, HOMO-LUMO gaps of metallorganic complexes, activation energies for SN2 reactions, and catalyst-substrate binding energies in cross-coupling reactions. After calibration on the same training sets, HIP yields an effective baseline for improved &#916;-machine learning models with superior data-efficiency when compared to previously introduced specialized domain-specific models.</description>
      <author>V. Diana Rakotonirina, Marco Bragato, Guido Falk von Rudorff, O. Anatole von Lilienfeld</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.5c00848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the code of CO2 Photoreduction: Band engineering in BN for methane selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169071</link>
      <description>Zhen Ge, Pengxin Pu, Haisong Feng, Mengjie Yu, Guanyi Zhang, Tianyong Liu, Xin Song, Shiquan Zhao, Lei Wang, Yusen Yang, Yibo Dou, Min Wei, Xin Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414711805

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhen Ge, Pengxin Pu, Haisong Feng, Mengjie Yu, Guanyi Zhang, Tianyong Liu, Xin Song, Shiquan Zhao, Lei Wang, Yusen Yang, Yibo Dou, Min Wei, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.169071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Enhancement of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction by Bio-surfactant and Visible Light in Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cep.2025.110567</link>
      <description>Mardi Santoso, Azizan Ahmad, David Fernando Sinurat, Nurkholis Hamidi, Purnami Purnami, Chemical Engineering and Processing - Process Intensification. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414715324

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mardi Santoso, Azizan Ahmad, David Fernando Sinurat, Nurkholis Hamidi, Purnami Purnami</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cep.2025.110567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand modulation of active interfaces to promote photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.139126</link>
      <description>Meihua Li, Lan Yao, Xu Li, Jingjing Quan, Saqib Mujtaba, Chenglong Li, Xingming Ning, Pei Chen, Zhongwei An, Xinbing Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414723458

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meihua Li, Lan Yao, Xu Li, Jingjing Quan, Saqib Mujtaba, Chenglong Li, Xingming Ning, Pei Chen, Zhongwei An, Xinbing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.139126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced catalytic activity by topological flat bands at the charge neutrality point</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/56zz-7kwp</link>
      <description>Yang Song, Wen&#8208;Han Dong, Jie Yang, Ziyuan Liu, Mengxi Liu, Jia Zhu, Shixuan Du, Feng Liu, Lizhi Zhang, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 112(15)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414727590

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Song, Wen&#8208;Han Dong, Jie Yang, Ziyuan Liu, Mengxi Liu, Jia Zhu, Shixuan Du, Feng Liu, Lizhi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/56zz-7kwp</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Electrolyte pH Affects the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c14208</link>
      <description>Jay T. Bender, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Nicolas Bueno Ponce, Angel E. Valles, Alyssa K. Uvodich, Delia J. Milliron, John R. Kitchin, Joaquin Resasco, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414731738

                Electrolyte pH is known to affect catalytic activity and selectivity for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). But a clear understanding of why ORR rates respond more strongly to pH over certain catalysts than others has not been developed. Here, we propose that pH effects on the ORR result from electric field induced changes in the binding energies of intermediates involved in kinetically relevant elementary steps. For strongly binding metals (Pt, Ir, Ru, and Pd), whose rates are limited by the proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) step to form *OOH or remove adsorbed OH (*OH), ORR rates are weakly affected by electrolyte pH. This behavior is observed because the binding energies of the reaction intermediates in these steps are minimally affected by electric field strength. The weak pH dependence is most pronounced for Pt, which shows essentially identical rates in acidic and alkaline electrolytes. For weakly binding metals (Au, Ag), whose rates are limited by non-PCET O2 adsorption, ORR rates increase significantly when moving from acidic to alkaline electrolytes. This strong pH dependence results from the stabilization of adsorbed O2 by the increasingly negative electric field present at the catalyst surface under alkaline conditions. We argue that modifying electrolyte pH does not change the rate-determining elementary step for the ORR, but does decrease the apparent activation barrier for O2 adsorption over weakly binding catalysts. These arguments are substantiated by a combination of experimental kinetic studies and atomistic simulations.</description>
      <author>Jay T. Bender, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Nicolas Bueno Ponce, Angel E. Valles, Alyssa K. Uvodich, Delia J. Milliron, John R. Kitchin, Joaquin Resasco</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c14208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A morphotropic phase boundary in MA1&#8722;xFAxPbI3: linking structure, dynamics, and electronic properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64526-4</link>
      <description>Tobias Hainer, Erik Fransson, Sangita Dutta, Julia Wiktor, Paul Erhart, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414746328

                Abstract Understanding the phase behavior of mixed-cation halide perovskites is critical for optimizing their structural stability and optoelectronic performance. Here, we map the phase diagram of MA 1&#8722; x FA x PbI 3 using a machine-learned interatomic potential in molecular dynamics simulations. We identify a morphotropic phase boundary (MPB) at approximately 27% FA content, delineating the transition between out-of-phase and in-phase octahedral tilt patterns. Phonon mode projections reveal that this transition coincides with a mode crossover composition, where the free energy landscapes of the M and R phonon modes become nearly degenerate. This results in nanoscale layered structures with alternating tilt patterns, suggesting minimal interface energy between competing phases. Our results provide a systematic and consistent description of this important system, complementing earlier partial and sometimes conflicting experimental assessments. Furthermore, density functional theory calculations show that band edge fluctuations peak near the MPB, indicating an enhancement of electron-phonon coupling and dynamic disorder effects. These findings establish a direct link between phonon dynamics, phase behavior, and electronic structure, providing a further composition-driven pathway for tailoring the optoelectronic properties of perovskite materials. By demonstrating that phonon overdamping serves as a hallmark of the MPB, our study offers insights into the design principles for stable, high-performance perovskite solar cells.</description>
      <author>Tobias Hainer, Erik Fransson, Sangita Dutta, Julia Wiktor, Paul Erhart</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-64526-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separation-free artificial photosynthesis of concentrated hydrogen peroxide and value-added fuels over Ta atomic sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63838-9</link>
      <description>Hao Tan, Peng Zhou, Yu Gu, Youxing Liu, Wenxing Chen, Hongyu Guo, Fangxu Lin, Heng Luo, Xiaoqing Cao, Lingyou Zeng, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414747567

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Tan, Peng Zhou, Yu Gu, Youxing Liu, Wenxing Chen, Hongyu Guo, Fangxu Lin, Heng Luo, Xiaoqing Cao, Lingyou Zeng, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63838-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density-Potential Functional Theoretic (DPFT) Schemes of Modeling Reactive Solid&#8211;Liquid Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.5c00071</link>
      <description>X. Wang, Jun Huang, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414757050

                No abstract</description>
      <author>X. Wang, Jun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.5c00071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced water splitting performance in passivated Co-doping of LNS-TiO2 homojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164791</link>
      <description>R.J. Zhang, Siwei Dong, Nan Mu, R. R. Xu, Yanyu Liu, Wei Zhou, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414767807

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R.J. Zhang, Siwei Dong, Nan Mu, R. R. Xu, Yanyu Liu, Wei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164791</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Synergistic Interactions Among Metal Atoms Through S Doping for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-025-05198-z</link>
      <description>Shengjie Jiang, Qi Wang, Gonggang Sun, Xinbao Li, Catalysis Letters. 155(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414771032

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengjie Jiang, Qi Wang, Gonggang Sun, Xinbao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-025-05198-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncoordinated Single&#8208;Site Ru Confined in Spinel Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Lattice for High&#8208;Performance and Low&#8208;Cost PEM Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202516742</link>
      <description>Chengli Rong, He&#8208;Lin Zhuang, Qian He, Qian Sun, Sicheng Wu, Jun Chen, Zhongkang Han, Chuan Zhao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414773684

                Abstract Ruthenium&#8208;based catalysts have emerged as cost&#8208;effective and active alternatives to iridium&#8208;based materials for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis. However, their widespread application is constrained by poor stability under high current densities. Herein, an uncoordinated single&#8208;site Ru catalyst embedded within spinel Co 3 O 4 lattice is developed, delivering a current density of 3.0 A cm &#8722; 2 at 2.02 V with an ultra&#8208;low loading of 13.8 &#181;g Ru cm &#8722; 2 and excellent durability over 300 h at 0.7 A cm &#8722; 2 . Notably, a low energy consumption of 46.1 kW h kg &#8722;1 H 2 with an ultralow noble metal cost of 2.1 $ m &#8722; 2 is achieved, far exceeding commercial RuO 2 (48.6 kW h kg &#8722; 1 H 2 and 2280 $ m &#8722; 2 ) and most reported Ir&#8208;based catalysts. In situ spectroscopy and theoretical simulations reveal strong electronic metal&#8211;support interactions (EMSI) between Ru single site and Co 3 O 4 effectively modulate the Ru electronic structure and simultaneously activate adjacent Co sites, lowering the OER energy barrier for activity enhancement. Additionally, the EMSI imparts the catalyst with redox reversibility and structural flexibility, mitigating subsurface oxygen loss and suppressing over&#8208;oxidation and dissolution of both Ru and Co for sustaining stability. This work provides a promising design strategy for advanced Ru&#8208;based catalysts as promising alternatives to IrO 2 for PEM water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Chengli Rong, He&#8208;Lin Zhuang, Qian He, Qian Sun, Sicheng Wu, Jun Chen, Zhongkang Han, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202516742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting and stabilizing oxygen evolution reaction through Ru single atoms anchored amorphous NiMoOx electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63870-9</link>
      <description>J Li, Yiming Zhu, Changyuan Li, Qian Zhang, Ju Rong, Shuxiang Guo, Nicol&#225;s Alonso&#8208;Vante, Long Yang, Min&#8208;Hsin Yeh, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Xiaohua Yu, Hongfei Cheng, Jiwei Ma, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414779347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J Li, Yiming Zhu, Changyuan Li, Qian Zhang, Ju Rong, Shuxiang Guo, Nicol&#225;s Alonso&#8208;Vante, Long Yang, Min&#8208;Hsin Yeh, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Xiaohua Yu, Hongfei Cheng, Jiwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-63870-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Mesh Modified with Electrodeposited Graphene Oxide for Electrooxidation of Ethanol and Bioethanol in Alkaline Media&#8208; Toward Stable and Noble Metal&#8208;Free Electrodes for Direct Ethanol Fuel Cells (DEFCs)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500905</link>
      <description>Vishal Thakur, Sweta Lal, Sai Phani Kumar Vangala, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414780037

                Abstract This study reports the application of electrodeposited graphene oxide (GO)&#8208;modified nickel mesh electrodes (GO@Ni&#8208;m) as efficient electrodes for direct ethanol fuel cell (DEFC). GO@Ni&#8208;m50 (50 cyclic voltammetry cycles) exhibited the best electrocatalytic activity, achieving a (current density &#8764;15.37 mA cm &#8722;2 and onset potential 0.45 V versus Hg/HgO) at 1 M ethanol in 0.1 M KOH, due to improved surface area, conductivity, excellent stability, and low charge transfer resistance (R ct &#8776; 4.5 &#937;&#183;cm 2 ). The density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal a direct mechanism of ethanol electrooxidation to acetaldehyde, at an adsorption energy of &#8722;0.77 eV on GO@Ni&#8208;m50, due to the synergism of GO and Ni&#8208;m. Further surface modification with iron&#8208;nickel (FeNi) and platinum&#8208;carbon (Pt/C) nanoparticles revealed contrasting effects with reduced current densities due to hindered electron mobility through GO layers. Next, the electrooxidation of bioethanol (derived from potato peel fermentation) resulted in a current density of &gt;10 mA cm &#8722;2 , confirming its practical applicability in bioethanol driven alkaline fuel cells. The GO@Ni&#8208;m50 platform demonstrates high efficiency for ethanol and bioethanol oxidation and holds promise for other biomass&#8208;derived alcohol fuels. The future studies on enhancing long&#8208;term durability of the electrodes can enrich their applicability in sustainable electrochemical energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Vishal Thakur, Sweta Lal, Sai Phani Kumar Vangala</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202500905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Structure Modulation of La&lt;sub&gt;0.6&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.4&lt;/sub&gt;CoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Films on SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; (001) Substrate under Electrochemical Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c11807</link>
      <description>A. Fujisawa, Xu-hui Xu, Yuta Ishii, Hidekazu Shimotani, Yuta Inoue, Yuto Miyahara, Kohei Miyazaki, Yusuke Wakabayashi, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414787899

                The surface structure of the La0.6Sr0.4CoO3 film, a typical model water-splitting catalyst, is examined under vacuum and electrochemical conditions using surface X-ray diffraction. The pristine sample has a two-unit-cell-thick strongly polarized SrCoO3 layer at the surface, and the surface termination is predominantly a CoO2 layer with apical oxygen atoms. After electrochemical treatment, the surface was covered with an additional edge-shared CoO6 double layer. The polarization in the SrCoO3 region was greatly reduced. These structural changes were accompanied by an increase in the working electrode current, suggesting a strong relationship between surface structure modulation and catalytic activity. Reversible structural modulation induced by the film's electric potential was observed and was qualitatively understood as atomic displacements caused by the local electric field and change in the Co ionic radii.</description>
      <author>A. Fujisawa, Xu-hui Xu, Yuta Ishii, Hidekazu Shimotani, Yuta Inoue, Yuto Miyahara, Kohei Miyazaki, Yusuke Wakabayashi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c11807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Are Dopant &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;-States Free-Atom-Like? Periodic Trends and Confinement Effects in Single-Atom Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07771</link>
      <description>Fabian Berger, Angelos Michaelides, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414788037

                The free-atom-like character of dopant d-states is a defining feature of single-atom alloys (SAAs), contributing to their exceptional selectivity and activity in heterogeneous catalysis. Based on reliable density functional theory (DFT) calculations for the full series of 4d transition metal (TM) dopants embedded in various hosts, we provide a unified perspective on when dopants exhibit this characteristic and how it can be tuned. Only late TM dopants exhibit the narrow, free-atom-like d-bands typically associated with SAAs, whereas early TM dopants display significantly broader d-bands that approach the width of host metal d-bands. This variation is not driven by increased dopant&#8211;host d-state mixing, which remains minimal across the series. Instead, we attribute the observed periodic trend to differences in the spatial extent of the localized dopant states and their overlap with surrounding host atoms, as well as to avoided hybridization associated with d-state filling. We further corroborate that dopant confinement, quantified by the number and proximity of surrounding host atoms, is as a key factor: more confined dopants exhibit broader d-bands, whereas less confined dopants feature narrower d-bands. Reduced dopant confinement also stabilizes high-spin configurations, enhancing spin polarization for certain 4d elements. Together, these findings offer fundamental insights into the origins of the unique electronic structure of SAAs. Building on these findings, we establish design principles for tuning dopant d-band shape and spin and illustrate how such modifications impact catalytic selectivity. The developed guidelines are also encapsulated in a machine learning model that predicts d-band widths, facilitating the rational design of SAAs.</description>
      <author>Fabian Berger, Angelos Michaelides</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c07771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Integration of Magnetic Fields and Catalysts for Clean Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501973</link>
      <description>Ziyong Zhang, Bo Feng, Junting Sun, Guowei Li, Zunming Lu, Junqiang Wang, Juntao Huo, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414793182

                Abstract Electrocatalysis is a crucial approach for achieving clean energy transitions, requiring highly efficient catalytic materials to expedite this process. However, overcoming the thermodynamic and kinetic constraints is key to discovering next&#8208;generation materials that are both cost&#8208;effective and efficient. The introduction of magnetic fields offers new opportunities for modulating the electronic structures of catalytic materials, optimizing the adsorption/desorption behavior of key intermediates, and enhancing catalytic efficiency. This review starts with the fundamental principles of classical electrocatalytic reactions, and revisits the main mechanisms by which magnetic fields affect magnetic catalytic materials and electrocatalytic systems, including magneto&#8208;thermal effects, magnetohydrodynamic effects, and spin&#8208;selective effects. Focusing on amorphous materials, topological materials, and metal oxides, the review highlights the design of magnetic catalytic materials, the control of magnetic structures, and their response behaviors to external fields. Finally, it discusses the major bottlenecks facing magnetic catalysis and its potential applications in other important small molecule catalytic transformations. This review provides a new perspective for understanding the essence of magnetic field chemistry and accelerating the development of catalytic materials aimed at applications.</description>
      <author>Ziyong Zhang, Bo Feng, Junting Sun, Guowei Li, Zunming Lu, Junqiang Wang, Juntao Huo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202501973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface microenvironment regulation of nitrogen-doped carbon via deep eutectic solvent for enhanced oxygen reaction kinetics in zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.122738</link>
      <description>Guowei Hao, Peng Wang, D. Yuhui Deng, Wei Zhang, Suqin Wu, Wenhao Zhang, Henan Li, Li Xu, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414797360

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guowei Hao, Peng Wang, D. Yuhui Deng, Wei Zhang, Suqin Wu, Wenhao Zhang, Henan Li, Li Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2025.122738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing How Acid Sites Enhance the Electrocatalytic Glycerol Oxidation Performance on Pt Loaded Zeolite&#8208;Carbon Composite Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202511220</link>
      <description>Ju Ye Kim, S.Y. No, Jinwoo Hwang, M.H. Yoo, Hak&#8208;Ju Lee, Youngbi Kim, Youngmin Kim, Yong Tae Kim, Jeong&#8208;Chul Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Kyoungsoo Kim, Hyung Ju Kim, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414812358

                Abstract The catalytic role and function of acid sites in solid acid catalysts, such as zeolites, are well understood in the context of heterogeneous catalytic reactions. But although many studies have highlighted the importance of acid sites, their catalytic effects in electrocatalytic reactions have rarely been investigated. In this work, a novel catalyst synthesis strategy is developed, integrating metal sites with acid sites for application in the electrocatalytic glycerol oxidation reaction (EGOR). Specifically, an ordered microporous carbon support containing acidic aluminum sites (AlYTC) is prepared through a nanocasting approach using a sacrificial zeolite template. Platinum (Pt) nanoclusters are then deposited onto the AlYTC support, forming a structure that exposes both acid sites and Pt nanoclusters on a zeolite&#8208;templated 3D carbon framework (PtAlYTC). The prepared PtAlYTC catalyst demonstrates a turnover frequency (TOF, s &#8722;1 ) 30 times higher and a reaction rate () 17 times greater than those of a Pt catalyst lacking acid sites (PtYTC) in the EGOR. First&#8208;principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that the combination of Pt sites and acidic Al sites lowers the Gibbs free energy of key reaction steps, improves charge transfer, and strengthens hydrogen adsorption, thereby significantly enhancing the catalytic performance in EGOR.</description>
      <author>Ju Ye Kim, S.Y. No, Jinwoo Hwang, M.H. Yoo, Hak&#8208;Ju Lee, Youngbi Kim, Youngmin Kim, Yong Tae Kim, Jeong&#8208;Chul Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Kyoungsoo Kim, Hyung Ju Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202511220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Carbon Dioxide-to-Formic Acid Conversion via Composition and Vacancy Engineering of MoxNbyV1-(x+y)Se2 Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-025-00555-5</link>
      <description>Getasew Mulualem Zewdie, Hong Seok Kang, Hyeyoung Shin, Korean Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414827683

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Getasew Mulualem Zewdie, Hong Seok Kang, Hyeyoung Shin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-025-00555-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strained-Induced Morphological Reconstruction of RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110) Thin-Film Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08607</link>
      <description>Jacob Som, Austin Jerad Reese, Luka Mitrovic, R. Soyoung Kim, Shay McBride, Swapnil Nalawade, Shyam Aravamudhan, Geoffroy Hautier, Junko Yano, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414843702

                Strain is a widely used strategy for electrocatalyst engineering. Overstraining, however, can lead to unintentional materials transformation. We investigate the impact of strain on the surface morphology of a rutile RuO2(110) film grown on a symmetry-matching rutile TiO2(110) substrate. When the film thickness exceeds 9 nm, the RuO2 surface relaxes by forming step edges that expose the {011} plane. Density functional theory (DFT) calculation shows that the (011) facet is among the lower energy surfaces of rutile RuO2, suggesting that this formation incurs minimal energetic penalties. In situ atomic force microscopy (AFM) shows that the film maintains the (110) structure of the terrace during electrochemistry. Inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) further reveals the insensitivity of the Ru dissolution to strain. Our findings show a strain-relieving pathway via surface reconstruction in RuO2(110) and provide an example of a strain-relieving mechanism that does not affect dissolution.</description>
      <author>Jacob Som, Austin Jerad Reese, Luka Mitrovic, R. Soyoung Kim, Shay McBride, Swapnil Nalawade, Shyam Aravamudhan, Geoffroy Hautier, Junko Yano, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c08607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin&#8208;State Reconfiguration and Lattice Oxygen Activation Co&#8208;Mediated Oxygen Evolution Catalysis Pathway via Artificial Hetero&#8208;Sites for Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202514933</link>
      <description>Hongmei Tang, Maohong Fan, Lin Lv, Gang Cheng, Fei Han, Junhua Zou, Qing Gong, Zhenxiong Huang, Xiaoping Chen, Bohong Chen, Houzhao Wan, Hao Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414845333

                Abstract It is desirable but challenging to develop low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) applications. In this work, a series of cerium oxide&#8208;coated cobalt vanadium oxide nanoplates (denoted as CVO@CeO 2 ) are prepared using different CeO 2 loadings through a facile two&#8208;step method. Compared to bare CVO, CeO 2, and commercial RuO 2 , the CVO@CeO 2 &#8208;0.20 catalyst presents much higher activity toward OER in alkaline solutions. Moreover, the CVO@CeO 2 &#8208;0.20 also exhibits superior open&#8208;circuit voltage and durability when utilized as the cathode in ZABs. Both theoretical calculations and experimental results disclose that the decoration of CeO 2 on CVO not only regulates the formation of high&#8208;spin state Co 3+ , optimizing the absorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) pathway, but also activates lattice oxygen, enhancing the lattice oxide oxidation mechanism (LOM) pathway. This research presents the CVO@CeO 2 heterojunction as an excellent catalyst for the OER and proposes a promising interface&#8208;regulated strategy for developing catalysts based on the reinforcement of AEM and LOM mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Hongmei Tang, Maohong Fan, Lin Lv, Gang Cheng, Fei Han, Junhua Zou, Qing Gong, Zhenxiong Huang, Xiaoping Chen, Bohong Chen, Houzhao Wan, Hao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202514933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing hydrogen evolution reaction performance of ZnIn2S4-Based single atom catalysts via surface vacancies and interlayer charge transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151790</link>
      <description>Wenli Xie, Bin Cui, Desheng Liu, Haicai Huang, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 183(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414860439

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenli Xie, Bin Cui, Desheng Liu, Haicai Huang, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151790</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Understanding of Laser&#8208;Induced Defect Engineering of Anisotropic Cobalt Oxide Spinel Platelets in Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501054</link>
      <description>Dana Schellenburg, Thomas Bihnam, Carsten Placke&#8208;Yan, Georg Bendt, Oleg Prymak, Takuma Sato, Dylan Jennings, Catalina Leiva&#8208;Leroy, Dongsheng Zhang, Milen Nachev, Kapil Dhaka, F.B.S. Nkou, Ulrich Hagemann, Markus Heidelmann, St&#233;phane Kenmoe, Kai S. Exner, Bernd Sures, Martin Muhler, Christian H. Liebscher, Alexander Schnegg, Stephan Schulz, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414866193

                Abstract In this study, we employ the pulsed laser defect engineering in liquid (PUDEL) to tailor the surface properties of cobalt (II, III) oxide (Co 3 O 4 ) platelets grown in the &lt; 111 &gt; direction. By varying the laser intensity and pulse number, we systematically investigate the relationship between defect formation and catalytic performance in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and selective oxidation of two alcohols. Our results reveal that the PUDEL processing leads to the formation of lattice distortions, the gradual alteration of three different paramagnetic defect sites, a partial reduction of Co 3 O 4 , and enrichment of the Co 3 O 4 (111) surface with hydroxyl groups (*OH), which significantly enhances OER activity. Theoretical investigations confirm that optimized hydroxyl coverage is critical for determining OER activity. The observed trends in selectivity and conversion efficiency for the selective oxidation of cinnamyl alcohol (CA) and ethylene glycol (EG) suggest different reaction mechanisms. The activity trend of the selective oxidation of CA appears to follow the trend of a defect&#8208;attributed paramagnetic species that was assigned to a surface&#8208;near, distorted high&#8208;spin (S = 3/2) Co 2+ . In turn, the catalytic activity and OER activity trends for the EG oxidation showed similar trends, which followed the density of a paramagnetic CoO x species observed during EPR spectroscopy. In particular, the highest OER activity and EG conversion were both found for moderate (2 PPV, ), yet not too intense PUDEL processing. Our findings establish PUDEL as a precise method for catalyst optimization, both for thermal and electro&#8208;catalytic oxidation over defect&#8208;enriched cobalt oxides, which enables the correlation of specific laser&#8208;induced defects with catalytic activity trends.</description>
      <author>Dana Schellenburg, Thomas Bihnam, Carsten Placke&#8208;Yan, Georg Bendt, Oleg Prymak, Takuma Sato, Dylan Jennings, Catalina Leiva&#8208;Leroy, Dongsheng Zhang, Milen Nachev, Kapil Dhaka, F.B.S. Nkou, Ulrich Hagemann, Markus Heidelmann, St&#233;phane Kenmoe, Kai S. Exner, Bernd Sures, Martin Muhler, Christian H. Liebscher, Alexander Schnegg, Stephan Schulz, Stephan Barcikowski, Sven Reichenberger</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Specific Nitrogen Vacancy Engineering in BaMO2N (M = Ta, Nb) for Enhanced Electrochemical Ammonia Production: Insights from First-Principles Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100125</link>
      <description>Santhanamoorthi Nachimuthu, Chenglin Chu, Zhong-Lun Li, Kenta Hongo, Ryo Maezono, Yuji Masubuchi, Jyh&#8208;Chiang Jiang, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414871685

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Santhanamoorthi Nachimuthu, Chenglin Chu, Zhong-Lun Li, Kenta Hongo, Ryo Maezono, Yuji Masubuchi, Jyh&#8208;Chiang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superparamagnetic Fe&#8211;Ni mixed oxides-based electrocatalysts for enhanced alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151026</link>
      <description>Tabassum Taspya, Tanvir Ahmed, Md. Mominul Islam, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414872926

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tabassum Taspya, Tanvir Ahmed, Md. Mominul Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determining the Potential of Maximum Entropy from Ab Initio Molecular Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500958</link>
      <description>Amanda Schramm Petersen, T. Madsen, Theophilus Kobina Sarpey, Christian M. Schott, Elena L. Gubanova, Adrian V. Himmelreich, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Jan Rossmeisl, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414874714

                Abstract Understanding electrochemical interfaces at the atomic level is essential for optimizing catalytic performance in energy conversion and storage technologies. This study introduces a computational framework based on ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations to predict the potential of maximum entropy (PME) a descriptor of electric double layer disorder and charge transfer efficiency. By integrating AIMD with the generalized computational hydrogen electrode, it is systematically investigated how electrolyte composition, cation identity, and pH effect the position of PME. The approach reproduces experimental shifts in PME for Au and Pt electrodes and provides unprecedented insights into the emergence of multiple PME values in mixed&#8208;cation systems. The findings challenge conventional models of electrolyte structuring by revealing the presence of multiple PME values within mixed&#8208;cation systems. This suggests a more complex interplay between cations, adsorbates, and interfacial disorder than previously assumed. The computational framework developed in this study provides a predictive tool for understanding these interactions, offering new strategies for tuning electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Amanda Schramm Petersen, T. Madsen, Theophilus Kobina Sarpey, Christian M. Schott, Elena L. Gubanova, Adrian V. Himmelreich, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202500958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Supercooled Liquid Sulfur for Enhanced Electrochemical Performance in Nanoporous Metal-Based Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c01173</link>
      <description>Cong Xi, Shuo Hao, Xiaotong Wang, Lei Bi, Zejing Lin, Chunchen Zhang, Jiuhui Han, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414857526

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cong Xi, Shuo Hao, Xiaotong Wang, Lei Bi, Zejing Lin, Chunchen Zhang, Jiuhui Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.5c01173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable machine learning-guided plasma catalysis for hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-025-00287-7</link>
      <description>Saleh Ahmat Ibrahim, Shengyan Meng, Charles Milhans, Magda H. Barecka, Yilang Liu, Qiang Li, Jiaqi Yang, Yabing Sha, Yanhui Yi, Fanglin Che, Nature Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414777625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saleh Ahmat Ibrahim, Shengyan Meng, Charles Milhans, Magda H. Barecka, Yilang Liu, Qiang Li, Jiaqi Yang, Yabing Sha, Yanhui Yi, Fanglin Che</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44286-025-00287-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring beyond experiment: generating high-quality datasets of transition metal complexes with quantum chemistry and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101189</link>
      <description>Jacob Toney, Aaron Garrison, Weiliang Luo, R. Michel, Sukrit Mukhopadhyay, Heather J. Kulik, Current Opinion in Chemical Engineering. 50(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414826559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jacob Toney, Aaron Garrison, Weiliang Luo, R. Michel, Sukrit Mukhopadhyay, Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coche.2025.101189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph neural networks for predicting metal&#8211;ligand coordination of transition metal complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2415658122</link>
      <description>Jacob Toney, R. Michel, Aaron Garrison, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(41)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414857994

                High-throughput virtual screening campaigns are invaluable for surveying the combinatorial space of possible transition metal complexes (TMCs), but they rely on accurate metal&#8211;ligand connectivity for meaningful results. Here, we curate a dataset of 70,069 unique ligands of known coordination from experimental structures of TMCs deposited in the Cambridge Structural Database. Using this dataset, we train separate graph neural network models to predict the total number and individual identities of ligand coordinating atoms with high accuracy and precision. Interpreting each model in terms of the learned molecular representations uncovers trends aligned with our understanding of coordination chemistry as well as chemical insights. Next, we integrate the trained models with the high-throughput screening software molSimplify and illustrate their utility by generating 1,175 TMCs and validating their geometries with density functional theory calculations. We anticipate these models will accelerate computational screening of TMCs with de novo combinations of metals and ligands in physically realistic coordination.</description>
      <author>Jacob Toney, R. Michel, Aaron Garrison, Ilia Kevlishvili, Heather J. Kulik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2415658122</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
