<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 01:01:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/Crystalline Phases Mixed Nanosheets Array Rich in Oxygen Vacancies Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Spinel Oxides in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401504</link>
      <description>Ying Liu, Liyang Xiao, Haiwen Tan, Jingtong Zhang, Cunku Dong, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Jing Yang, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393403940

                Abstract As promising oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, spinel&#8208;type oxides face the bottleneck of weak adsorption for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates, so it is challenging to make a further breakthrough in remarkably lowering the OER overpotential. In this study, a novel strategy is proposed to substantially enhance the OER activity of spinel oxides based on amorphous/crystalline phases mixed spinel FeNi 2 O 4 nanosheets array, enriched with oxygen vacancies, in situ grown on a nickel foam (NF). This unique architecture is achieved through a one&#8208;step millisecond laser direct writing method. The presence of amorphous phases with abundant oxygen vacancies significantly enhances the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and changes the rate&#8208;determining step from OH*&#8594;O* to O*&#8594;OOH*, which greatly reduces the thermodynamic energy barrier. Moreover, the crystalline phase interweaving with amorphous domains serves as a conductive shortcut to facilitate rapid electron transfer from active sites in the amorphous domain to NF, guaranteeing fast OER kinetics. Such an anodic electrode exhibits a nearly ten fold enhancement in OER intrinsic activity compared to the pristine counterpart. Remarkably, it demonstrates record&#8208;low overpotentials of 246 and 315 mV at 50 and 500 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH with superior long&#8208;term stability, outperforming other NiFe&#8208;based spinel oxides catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ying Liu, Liyang Xiao, Haiwen Tan, Jingtong Zhang, Cunku Dong, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Jing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing the Hydrogen Bonding Interaction with *Ooh Toward Efficient H2o2 Electrosynthesis Via Remote Electronic Tuning of Co-N4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4781821</link>
      <description>Jiawei Zhang, Hongwei Zeng, Bingling He, Ying Liu, Jingcheng Xu, Tianye Niu, Chengsi Pan, Ying Zhang, Lei Yang, Yao Wang, Yuanhua Dong, Yongfa Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393408035

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Zhang, Hongwei Zeng, Bingling He, Ying Liu, Jingcheng Xu, Tianye Niu, Chengsi Pan, Ying Zhang, Lei Yang, Yao Wang, Yuanhua Dong, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4781821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the ORR/OER Activity of Cobalt&#8208;Based Nano&#8208;Catalysts by Co 3d Orbital Regulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400855</link>
      <description>Nan Meng, Feng Yan, Zhenwei Zhao, Fang Lian, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393409592

                Abstract The transition metal oxides/sulfides are considered promising catalysts due to their abundant resources, facile synthesis, and reasonable electrocatalytic activity. Herein, a significantly improved intrinsic catalytic activity is achieved for constructing a Co&#8208;based nanocrystal (Co&#8208;S@NC) with the coordination of Co&#9472;S, Co&#9472;S&#9472;C, and Co&#9472;N x &#9472;C. The calculational and experimental results demonstrate that the diversified chemical environment of Co&#8208;cations induces the transition of 3d orbitals to a high spin&#8208;state that exhibits the coexistence of Co 2+ with fully occupied d &#960; orbitals and Co 3+ with unpaired electrons in d &#960; orbitals. The diverse d &#960; orbitals occupation contributes to an elevated d&#8208;band center of Co ions, which accelerates oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalytic kinetics of the Co&#8208;S@NC nanocrystal. Therefore, the Li&#8211;O 2 batteries with Co&#8208;S@NC as cathode catalyst exhibit 300 cycles at the current density of 500 mA g &#8722;1 with a cut&#8208;off capacity of 1000 mAh g &#8722;1 . Moreover, the ultrahigh discharge specific capacity of 34 587 mAh g &#8722;1 is obtained at a current density of 1000 mA g &#8722;1 , corresponding to the energy density 949 Wh kg &#8722;1 of a prototype Li&#8211;O 2 battery. The study on 3d orbital regulation of nanocrystals provides an innovative strategy for bifunctional electrocatalysts toward the practical application of metal&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Nan Meng, Feng Yan, Zhenwei Zhao, Fang Lian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards improved online dissolution evaluation of Pt-alloy PEMFC electrocatalysts via electrochemical flow cell - ICP-MS setup upgrades</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144200</link>
      <description>L&#233;onard Moriau, Tina &#272;uki&#263;, Vojtech Domin, Roman Kod&#253;m, Martin Prokop, Karel Bouzek, Matija Gatalo, Martin &#352;ala, Nejc Hodnik, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393428641

                Electrochemical flow cell coupled with an inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometer (EFC-ICP-MS) is a powerful electroanalytical technique to monitor in-situ dissolution of metallic electrocatalysts and to understand mechanism of degradation under operating conditions. Its utilisation has witnessed a notable increase in the electrocatalyst field in the last decade where it has been extensively used to study the stability of platinum group metals (PGMs) under oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction conditions. Online ICP-MS has allowed the scientific and industrial community to optimise the activity and stability of PGMs thanks to a better understanding of the complex metal corrosion processes. Among the different setups, the electrochemical flow cell design is the most common as it is based on a commercially available design. Nonetheless, besides different materials and different electrochemical protocols, the impact of the geometry and various parameters of the setup on the recorded dissolution signal has not been studied until now. Such parameters can influence the results obtained with an EFC-ICP-MS and thus the interpretation of the dissolution mechanism and/or stability assessment. Hereby, we demonstrate that the length of the tubing between the outlet of the cell and the inlet of the ICP-MS impacts the resolution of the PtCo catalyst dissolution peaks. This, in turn, facilitates studies where the detection of extremely low concentrations is necessary, such as under a very narrow potential window. Similarly, a reduced internal volume of the cell restricts Pt redeposition, contributing to a more precise evaluation of stability. These claims were supported by dynamic continuum mechanics modelling of the ion concentration in a model EFC. Finally, we provide guidelines and advice to properly measure dissolution with an electrochemical cell coupled with ICP-MS.</description>
      <author>L&#233;onard Moriau, Tina &#272;uki&#263;, Vojtech Domin, Roman Kod&#253;m, Martin Prokop, Karel Bouzek, Matija Gatalo, Martin &#352;ala, Nejc Hodnik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electro-Catalysis for H$$_2$$O Oxidation and Chlorine Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46870-4_7</link>
      <description>Travis E. Jones, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393433643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Travis E. Jones</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46870-4_7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical Chemistry Education and Research in an Open-Sourced Future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.3c00078</link>
      <description>Jeffrey T. DuBose, Sheila Scott, Benjamin Moss, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393436798

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jeffrey T. DuBose, Sheila Scott, Benjamin Moss</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.3c00078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal clusters with precise numbers of atoms anchored on graphdiyne as multifunctional electrocatalysts for OER/ORR/HER: a computational study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02611-7</link>
      <description>Xin-Yang Liu, J. W. Liu, Gang Li, Jingxiang Zhao, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393850997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Yang Liu, J. W. Liu, Gang Li, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02611-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration on Machine-Learned Potentials with IPSuite: A Modular Framework for Learning-on-the-Fly</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c07187</link>
      <description>Fabian Zills, Moritz Sch&#228;fer, Nico Segreto, Johannes K&#228;stner, Christian Holm, Samuel Tovey, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. B (1997 : Online). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393854049

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fabian Zills, Moritz Sch&#228;fer, Nico Segreto, Johannes K&#228;stner, Christian Holm, Samuel Tovey</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c07187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning A&#8208;Site Cation Deficiency in Pr&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;La&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;BaCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5+&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Perovskite to Realize Large&#8208;Scale Hydrogen Evolution at 2000 mA cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;2&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400760</link>
      <description>Kaiqian Li, Tian Xia, Ruiping Deng, Yingnan Dou, Jingping Wang, Qiang Li, Liping Sun, Li-Hua Huo, Hui Zhao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393865235

                Abstract Industrial&#8208;level hydrogen production from the water electrolysis requires reducing the overpotential ( &#951; ) as much as possible at high current density, which is closely related to intrinsic activity of the electrocatalysts. Herein, A&#8208;site cation deficiency engineering is proposed to screen high&#8208;performance catalysts, demonstrating effective Pr 0.5&#8208; x La 0.5 BaCo 2 O 5+ &#948; (P 0.5&#8208; x LBC) perovskites toward alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Among all perovskite compositions, Pr 0.4 La 0.5 BaCo 2 O 5+ &#948; (P0.4LBC) exhibits superior HER performance along with unique operating stability at large current densities ( J = 500&#8211;2000 mA cm&#8722;2 geo). The overpotential of &#8776;636 mV is achieved in P0.4LBC at 2000 mA cm&#8722;2 geo, which outperforms commercial Pt/C benchmark (&#8776;974 mV). Furthermore, the Tafel slope of P0.4LBC (34.1 mV dec &#8722;1 ) is close to that of Pt/C (35.6 mV dec &#8722;1 ), reflecting fast HER kinetics on the P0.4LBC catalyst. Combined with experimental and theoretical results, such catalytic activity may benefit from enhanced electrical conductivity, enlarged Co&#8208;O covalency, and decreased desorption energy of H * species. This results highlight effective A&#8208;site cation&#8208;deficient strategy for promoting electrochemical properties of perovskites, highlighting potential water electrolysis at ampere&#8208;level current density.</description>
      <author>Kaiqian Li, Tian Xia, Ruiping Deng, Yingnan Dou, Jingping Wang, Qiang Li, Liping Sun, Li-Hua Huo, Hui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique production strategy of Pt/C electrocatalysts via pulsed laser for hydrogen generation: Insights screening by DFT calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144218</link>
      <description>Yujeong Jeong, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Seung Jun Lee, Ramesh Kumar Chitumalla, Cheol Joo Moon, Ahreum Min, Soorathep Kheawhom, Joonkyung Jang, Myong Yong Choi, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393865560

                Design and optimizing the components and structure of highly-active electrocatalysts is a prevalent approach for reducing the input electrical energy consumption and concurrently H2 fuel production. An efficient and sustainable method is a water-electrolyzer for H2 generation, but still restricted by the stable electrode materials. In this study, a green chemistry approach for one-pot production of Pt/C nanospherical with controllable ratios of Pt and C was demonstrated using simple pulsed laser ablation in liquid (PLAL) process, during which Pt target ablation in diverse solvents (water, methanol, ethanol, and 1-propanol) without external carbon source and reducing/capping agents. The carbon-rich solvents are acted as both C-source and solvent, which are decomposed during the PLA process, producing C, H, and OH ions inside the cavitation bubble which condenses as C-shells on the Pt surface. The optimal Pt/C proportions have the highest electrochemical H2-evolution in acidic media with an overpotential of 59 mV at 10 mA/cm2, Tafel slope of 41 mV/dec, and j0 of 0.686 mA/cm2. The exceptional electrocatalytic concert of optimal Pt/C was further supported by the density functional theory. Optimized C-content in Pt/C reveals good dispersion and strong interaction of C with Pt can make efficient electron transfer, structural stability, and electrochemical durability, resulting in superior electrocatalytic performance in electrolyzer devices.</description>
      <author>Yujeong Jeong, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Seung Jun Lee, Ramesh Kumar Chitumalla, Cheol Joo Moon, Ahreum Min, Soorathep Kheawhom, Joonkyung Jang, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Advances of Non-Noble Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071637</link>
      <description>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Gang Li, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Xianjie Yuan, Yingjia Wang, Bin Cao, Materials (Basel). 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393871266

                Water splitting is an important way to obtain hydrogen applied in clean energy, which mainly consists of two half-reactions: hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the kinetics of the OER of water splitting, which occurs at the anode, is slow and inefficient, especially in acid. Currently, the main OER catalysts are still based on noble metals, such as Ir and Ru, which are the main active components. Hence, the exploration of new OER catalysts with low cost, high activity, and stability has become a key issue in the research of electrolytic water hydrogen production technology. In this paper, the reaction mechanism of OER in acid was discussed and summarized, and the main methods to improve the activity and stability of non-noble metal OER catalysts were summarized and categorized. Finally, the future prospects of OER catalysts in acid were made to provide a little reference idea for the development of advanced OER catalysts in acid in the future.</description>
      <author>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Gang Li, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Xianjie Yuan, Yingjia Wang, Bin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric coordination engineering of active centers in MXene-based single atom catalysts for high-performance ECO2RR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119094</link>
      <description>Shoufu Cao, Hongyu Chen, Xiaofei Wei, Jiao Li, Chunyu Yang, Zengxuan Chen, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393898802

                Asymmetric coordination effect is an important concept in heterogeneous catalysis where both catalytic activity and product selectivity are serious influenced. However, this effect has rarely been understood because of the difficult in characterizing detailed coordination information. Here, by employing a theoretical study on electrocatalytic CO2 reduction reaction (ECO2RR) towards HCOOH over Ti3C2O2-based NS/NN co-coordinated transition metal single atom catalysts (TM-NS/NN-Ti3C2O2 SACs), we show that asymmetric coordination environments have great impact on the electronic structure of the active center. Both electron transferring ability and spin polarization of the active center are vital to optimize the adsorption and hydrogenation of key intermediates. As a result, both catalytic activity and product selectivity can be maximized. V-NN-Ti3C2O2 are predicted to promote high-throughput HCOOH generation process at operation applied potential of &#8722;0.32 with considerable electrochemical stability, surpassing most reported catalysts. This work demonstrates V-NN-Ti3C2O2 as high-performance ECO2RR catalysts, and highlights that the introduction of the concept of asymmetric coordination effect may offer a new insight into the rational design of more efficient SACs.</description>
      <author>Shoufu Cao, Hongyu Chen, Xiaofei Wei, Jiao Li, Chunyu Yang, Zengxuan Chen, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaoqing Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism and performance of photocatalytic H2 evolution for carbon self-doped TiO2 derived from MIL-125</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.154</link>
      <description>Ying Zhao, Nan Yang, Tong Zhou, Wei Zhan, Jie Zhao, Mingpeng Chen, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Yuming Zhang, Genlin Zhang, Qingju Liu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393925299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Zhao, Nan Yang, Tong Zhou, Wei Zhan, Jie Zhao, Mingpeng Chen, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Yuming Zhang, Genlin Zhang, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Structure of Pd@Ni&#8211;Co Nanowires and Their Electrochemical Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00376</link>
      <description>Dariusz &#321;ukowiec, Magdalena Gw&#243;&#378;d&#378;, Alina Brz&#281;czek&#8208;Szafran, Tomasz Wasiak, Dawid Janas, Jerzy Kubacki, Stanis&#322;aw Wac&#322;awek, Adrian Rado&#324;, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393927143

                One-dimensional transition metal materials are promising supports for precious metals used in energy production processes. Due to their electrochemical properties, 3d-group metals (such as Ni, Co, and Fe) can actively interact with catalysts by a strong metal&#8211;support interaction. This study shows that changing the Ni:Co ratio makes it possible to modulate the structure of the catalyst supports, which, in turn, provides a tool for designing their electrical and electrochemical properties. For example, Ni1&#8211;Co9 shows the highest electrical conductivity (5.8&#8211;10&#8211;4 S/cm) among all of the materials examined. On the contrary, the Pd@Ni7&#8211;Co3 system presents the highest mass activity (&gt;2000 mA mg&#8211;1) at 0.7 V, exceeding by several times that of commercial Pt/C (&gt;300 mA mg&#8211;1) at the same potential. Our study opens the gateway for applications of bimetallic transition metal nanowires in catalytic conversion and energy production processes.</description>
      <author>Dariusz &#321;ukowiec, Magdalena Gw&#243;&#378;d&#378;, Alina Brz&#281;czek&#8208;Szafran, Tomasz Wasiak, Dawid Janas, Jerzy Kubacki, Stanis&#322;aw Wac&#322;awek, Adrian Rado&#324;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into Mo Cluster Modified Fe5C2 Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108839</link>
      <description>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Jinhong Bi, Rongjian Sa, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393928748

                The pursuit of green ammonia synthesis via electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction (NRR) faces challenges in developing high-performance, selective electrocatalysts. Inspired by the nitrogenase Fe-Mo cofactor, this study explores the catalytic efficiency of Mo clusters anchored on Fe5C2 for NRR. We investigate structural stability, N2 adsorption, and Gibbs free energy, revealing that Mon clusters on Fe5C2 demonstrate robust NRR selectivity and notable catalytic activity. Each of the three cluster structures demonstrated superior adsorption capacity in the "side-on" configuration. Among the studied cluster configurations, the Mo5-Fe5C2 shows the lowest limiting potential (-0.24 V), and the Mo4-Fe5C2 exhibits heightened selectivity for NRR, minimizing interference from the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This enhanced performance is attributed to the unique structure and interactive dynamics of Mon-Fe5C2 and the electron orbital interactions facilitating direct nitrogen charge transfer. Our findings underscore the potential of Mo cluster-modified Fe5C2 as a pioneering catalyst for electrocatalytic nitrogen reduction.</description>
      <author>Meiyan Chen, Qingyu Li, Diwen Liu, Zuju Ma, Yanjie Zhang, De&#8208;Jing Li, Jinhong Bi, Rongjian Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; through the Phase Transition&#8208;Mediated Hydrogen Spillover to Outperform Pt for Electrocatalytic pH&#8208;Universal Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400783</link>
      <description>Jiexian Liu, Peifang Guo, Da Li, Xiaoxiao Yan, Xin Tu, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu, Small (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393931341

                Abstract Endowing conventional materials with specific functions that are hardly available is invariably of significant importance but greatly challenging. TiO 2 is proven to be highly active for the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution while intrinsically inert for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to its poor electrical conductivity and unfavorable hydrogen adsorption/desorption behavior. Herein, the first activation of inert TiO 2 for electrocatalytic HER is demonstrated by synergistically modulating the positions of d&#8208;band center and triggering hydrogen spillover through the dual doping&#8208;induced partial phase transition. The N, F co&#8208;doping&#8208;induced partial phase transition from anatase to rutile phase in TiO 2 (AR&#8208;TiO 2 |(N,F)) exhibits extraordinary HER performance with overpotentials of 74, 80, and 142 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH, 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 , and 1.0 M phosphate&#8208;buffered saline electrolytes, respectively, which are substantially better than pure TiO 2 , and even superior to the benchmark Pt/C catalysts. These findings may open a new avenue for the development of low&#8208;cost alternative to noble metal catalysts for electrocatalytic hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Jiexian Liu, Peifang Guo, Da Li, Xiaoxiao Yan, Xin Tu, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational studies on Mg ion conductivity in Mg2xHf1-x Nb(PO4)3 using neural network potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05862-1</link>
      <description>Keisuke Makino, Naoto Tanibata, Hiromasa Takeda, Masanobu Nakayama, Journal of solid state electrochemistry (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393935368

                Abstract Low Mg diffusivity in solid-state oxides is an obstacle for the development of materials for Mg ion batteries, which are expected to have high capacity. In this study, we focused on NASICON-type and &#946;-iron sulfate-type Mg 2x Hf 1-x Nb(PO 4 ) 3 that exhibit relatively high Mg ionic conductivity and investigated the Hf/Nb configuration and composition dependence of phase stability and ion conductivity by atomistic simulation using neural network potentials. The calculations show that the NASICON-type structure is slightly more stable and has higher Mg ionic conductivity than that of the &#946;-iron sulfate-type. The effect of the Hf/Nb configuration was investigated and showed that the ordered stable structure had much lower ionic conductivity than the disordered structure. Furthermore, as the Mg ion concentration increased, the ionic conductivity increased monotonically at low concentrations but tended to converge to a constant value above a certain concentration. The saturation of the ionic conductivity despite increasing the Mg concentration may be due to the trapping effect of the Mg ions caused by the Hf vacancies as well as the Hf/Nb arrangement. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Keisuke Makino, Naoto Tanibata, Hiromasa Takeda, Masanobu Nakayama</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05862-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Engineering of Unconventional Crystal-Phase Noble Metal Nanocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29071617</link>
      <description>Jie Wang, Yidong Jiang, Sixuan Chen, Qinyong Zhang, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393944761

                The crystal phase, alongside the composition, morphology, architecture, facet, size, and dimensionality, has been recognized as a critical factor influencing the properties of noble metal nanomaterials in various applications. In particular, unconventional crystal phases can potentially enable fascinating properties in noble metal nanomaterials. Recent years have witnessed notable advances in the phase engineering of nanomaterials (PEN). Within the accessible strategies for phase engineering, the effect of strain cannot be ignored because strain can act not only as the driving force of phase transition but also as the origin of the diverse physicochemical properties of the unconventional crystal phase. In this review, we highlight the development of unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanomaterials within strain engineering. We begin with a short introduction of the unconventional crystal phase and strain effect in noble metal nanomaterials. Next, the correlations of the structure and performance of strain-engineered unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanomaterials in electrocatalysis are highlighted, as well as the phase transitions of noble metal nanomaterials induced by the strain effect. Lastly, the challenges and opportunities within this rapidly developing field (i.e., the strain engineering of unconventional crystal-phase noble metal nanocatalysts) are discussed.</description>
      <author>Jie Wang, Yidong Jiang, Sixuan Chen, Qinyong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29071617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading biomass derived furan aldehydes by coupled electrochemical conversion over silver-based electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151001</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Dai, Xi Lu, Nan Li, Yichen Zhang, Xuebing Zhao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393944922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Dai, Xi Lu, Nan Li, Yichen Zhang, Xuebing Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction on IrO2(110) is governed by Walden-type mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4101847/v1</link>
      <description>Kai S. Exner, Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393945519

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key process for sustainable energy, although renewable sources require the use of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers, with IrO 2 -based materials being the gold standard due to their high activity and stability under dynamic anodic polarization conditions. However, even for the (110) facet of a single-crystalline IrO 2 model electrode, the reaction mechanism is not settled yet due to contradictory reports in literature. In the present manuscript, we disentangle the conflicting results of previous theoretical studies in the density functional theory approximation. We demonstrate that dissimilar reaction mechanisms and limiting steps for the OER over IrO 2 (110) are obtained for different active surface configurations present on the IrO 2 electrode. In contrast to previous studies, we factor Walden-type mechanisms, in which the formation of the product O 2 and adsorption of the reactant H 2 O occur simultaneously, into the analysis of the elementary steps. Combining free-energy diagrams along the reaction coordinate and Bader charge analysis of the active site under constant potential, we elucidate why mononuclear- or bifunctional-Walden pathways excel the traditional OER mechanisms for the OER over IrO 2 (110). Our computational methodology to identify the reaction mechanism and limiting step of proton-coupled electron transfer steps is universally applicable to electrochemical processes in the field of energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Kai S. Exner, Muhammad Usama, Samad Razzaq, Christof H&#228;ttig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4101847/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing lithium-silver alloy phases for enhanced energy density and electrochemical performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</link>
      <description>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu, Next materials. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393925878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuheng Huang, Shiwei Chen, Jiqiong Liu, Yu Yang, Xiao Yu, Xinchen Xu, Huirong Jing, Yunlong Guo, Shou&#8208;Hang Bo, Huanan Duan, Hong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolytic Regeneration of Spent Caustic Soda from CO2 Capture Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</link>
      <description>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho, Processes. 12(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393866132

                The traditional electrochemical caustic soda recovery system uses the generated pH gradient across the ion exchange membrane for the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent from CO2 capture. This electrochemical CO2 capture system releases the by-products H2 and O2 at the cathode and anode, respectively. Although effective for capturing CO2, the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limit the energy efficiency of this technique. Hence, this study proposed and validated a hybrid electrochemical cell based on the H2-cycling from the cathode to the anode to eliminate the reliance on anodic oxygen generation. The results show that our lab-scale prototype enabled effective spent caustic soda recovery with an electron utilisation efficiency of 90%, and a relative carbonate/bicarbonate diffusional flux of approximately 40%. The system also enabled the regeneration of spent alkaline absorbent with a minimum electrochemical energy input of 0.19 kWh/kg CO2 at a CO2 recovery rate of 0.7 mol/m2/h, accounting for 30% lower energy demand than a control system without H2-recycling, making this technique a promising alternative to the conventional thermal regeneration technology.</description>
      <author>Hossein Mohammadpour, Almantas Pivrikas, Ka Yu Cheng, G. E. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12040723</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
