<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:43:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the crucial contribution of additive chromate to efficient and stable alkaline seawater oxidation on Ni-based layered double hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.132</link>
      <description>Lin Yang, Yao Ding, Xueqing Niu, Xinyue Xu, Kaicai Fan, Wen Ye, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Xiaofan Du, Tianrong Zhan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393029507

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lin Yang, Yao Ding, Xueqing Niu, Xinyue Xu, Kaicai Fan, Wen Ye, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Xiaofan Du, Tianrong Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Locating Transition States by Variational Reaction Path Optimization with an Energy-Derivative-Free Objective Function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01246</link>
      <description>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393031108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shin-ichi Koda, Shinji Saito</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Machine Learning Model Focusing on Active Sites for the Discovery of Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts in Binary Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17377</link>
      <description>C Y Wang, Bing Wang, Changhao Wang, Zhipeng Chang, Mengqi Yang, Ruzhi Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393039373

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C Y Wang, Bing Wang, Changhao Wang, Zhipeng Chang, Mengqi Yang, Ruzhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converging Divergent Paths: Constant Charge vs Constant Potential Energetics in Computational Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07954</link>
      <description>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Simeon D. Beinlich, Karsten Reuter, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393040617

                Using the example of a proton adsorption process, we analyze and compare two prominent modeling approaches in computational electrochemistry at metallic electrodes&#9472;electronically canonical, constant-charge and electronically grand-canonical, constant-potential calculations. We first confirm that both methodologies yield consistent results for the differential free energy change in the infinite cell size limit. This validation emphasizes that, fundamentally, both methods are equally valid and precise. In practice, the grand-canonical, constant-potential approach shows superior interpretability and size convergence as it aligns closer to experimental ensembles and exhibits smaller finite-size effects. On the other hand, constant-charge calculations exhibit greater resilience against discrepancies, such as deviations in interfacial capacitance and absolute potential alignment, as their results inherently only depend on the surface charge and not on the modeled charge vs potential relation. The present analysis thus offers valuable insights and guidance for selecting the most appropriate ensemble when addressing diverse electrochemical challenges.</description>
      <author>Nicolas G. H&#246;rmann, Simeon D. Beinlich, Karsten Reuter</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Thermodynamic Equivalence of Grand Canonical, Infinite&#8208;Size, and Capacitor&#8208;Based Models in First&#8208;Principle Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202300950</link>
      <description>Georg Kastlunger, Sudarshan Vijay, Xi Chen, Shubham Sharma, Andrew A. Peterson, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393044438

                Abstract First principles&#8208;based computational and theoretical methods are constantly evolving trying to overcome the many obstacles towards a comprehensive understanding of electrochemical processes on an atomistic level. One of the major challenges has been the determination of reaction energetics under a constant potential. Here, a theoretical framework was proposed applying standard electronic structure methods and extrapolating to the infinite&#8208;cell size limit where reactions do not alter the potential. Today, electronically grand canonical modifications to electronic structure methods, holding the potential constant by varying the number of electrons in a finite simulation cell, become increasingly popular. In this perspective, we show that these two schemes are thermodynamically equivalent. Further, we link these methods to capacitive models of the interface, in the limit that the capacitance of the charging components (whether continuum or atomistic) are equal and invariant along the reaction pathway. We benchmark the three approaches with an example of alkali cation adsorption on Pt(111) showing that all three approaches converge in the cases of Li, Na and K. For Cs, however, strong deviation from the ideal conditions leads to a spread in the respective results. We discuss the latter by highlighting the cases of broken equivalence and assumptions among the approaches.</description>
      <author>Georg Kastlunger, Sudarshan Vijay, Xi Chen, Shubham Sharma, Andrew A. Peterson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202300950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CREST&#8212;A program for the exploration of low-energy molecular chemical space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0197592</link>
      <description>Philipp Pracht, Stefan Grimme, Christoph Bannwarth, Fabian Bohle, Sebastian Ehlert, Gereon Feldmann, Johannes Gorges, Marcel M&#252;ller, Tim Stauch, Christoph Plett, Sebastian Spicher, Pit Steinbach, Patryk A. Weso&#322;owski, Felix Zeller, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393045038

                Conformer&#8211;rotamer sampling tool (CREST) is an open-source program for the efficient and automated exploration of molecular chemical space. Originally developed in Pracht et al. [Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 22, 7169 (2020)] as an automated driver for calculations at the extended tight-binding level (xTB), it offers a variety of molecular- and metadynamics simulations, geometry optimization, and molecular structure analysis capabilities. Implemented algorithms include automated procedures for conformational sampling, explicit solvation studies, the calculation of absolute molecular entropy, and the identification of molecular protonation and deprotonation sites. Calculations are set up to run concurrently, providing efficient single-node parallelization. CREST is designed to require minimal user input and comes with an implementation of the GFNn-xTB Hamiltonians and the GFN-FF force-field. Furthermore, interfaces to any quantum chemistry and force-field software can easily be created. In this article, we present recent developments in the CREST code and show a selection of applications for the most important features of the program. An important novelty is the refactored calculation backend, which provides significant speed-up for sampling of small or medium-sized drug molecules and allows for more sophisticated setups, for example, quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics and minimum energy crossing point calculations.</description>
      <author>Philipp Pracht, Stefan Grimme, Christoph Bannwarth, Fabian Bohle, Sebastian Ehlert, Gereon Feldmann, Johannes Gorges, Marcel M&#252;ller, Tim Stauch, Christoph Plett, Sebastian Spicher, Pit Steinbach, Patryk A. Weso&#322;owski, Felix Zeller</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0197592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of penta-CN2 quantum dots for efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.016</link>
      <description>Rupali Jindal, Rachana Yogi, Alok Shukla, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 63(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393059030

                The objective of our research is to investigate the electrocatalytic properties of novel metal-free quantum dots (QDs) composed of the recently discovered 2D material penta-CN2, with the aim of replacing costly and scarce catalysts such as Pt and Pd. Employing a first-principles density functional theory (DFT) based approach, the geometries of the three penta-CN2 quantum dots (QDs) of increasing sizes, 3 &#215; 3, 3 &#215; 4, 4 &#215; 4 are optimized. Through comprehensive analysis, our research extensively explored the structural stability of penta-CN2 QDs, delved into their electronic properties, and assessed their catalytic performance concerning the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER). Notably, the H-adsorbed penta-CN2 QDs exhibit a significant reduction in the HOMO-LUMO gap (Eg) ranging from 35% to 49% compared to the pristine QD. This observation underscores the crucial impact of H-adsorption on Penta-CN2 QD and is further supported by the appearance of mid-gap states in total and partial density of states plots. Next, we investigated their catalytic performance relevant to HER, using well-known descriptors: (i) adsorption energy, (ii) over-potential, (iii) Gibbs free energy and (iv) exchange current density along with the volcano curve. As far as size dependence of the catalytic performance is concerned, the value of the average change in Gibbs free energy, &#916;G(av), is minimum for 3 &#215; 3 penta&#8211;CN2 QD, with those of 3 &#215; 4 and 4 &#215; 4 QDs being slightly larger. Our calculations predict a high value of exchange current density 2.24&#215;10&#8722;3 A-cm&#8722;2 for one of the sites (N11 for 3 &#215; 3 QD), which we believe will lead to significantly enhanced HER properties. The minimum value of &#916;G=0.158eV for a 3 &#215; 3 penta-CN2 QD implies that its catalytic performance is at least as effective or perhaps better than most of the metal-free hybrid and non-hybrid structures. Our research outcomes hold great promise in advancing the discovery of abundant, non-toxic, and cost-effective catalysts for HER, playing a vital role in facilitating large-scale hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Rupali Jindal, Rachana Yogi, Alok Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the versatility of porous nanoarchitectures: A voyage for sustainable electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64581-4</link>
      <description>Jian Yiing Loh, Joel Jie Foo, Feng Ming Yap, Hanfeng Liang, Wee&#8208;Jun Ong, Chinese Journal of Catalysis. 58(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393063102

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Yiing Loh, Joel Jie Foo, Feng Ming Yap, Hanfeng Liang, Wee&#8208;Jun Ong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(23)64581-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative Effects Drive Water Oxidation Catalysis in Cobalt Electrocatalysts through the Destabilization of Intermediates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11651</link>
      <description>Benjamin Moss, Katrine L. Svane, David Nieto&#8208;Castro, Reshma R. Rao, S&#248;ren B. Scott, Cindy Tseng, Michael L. Sachs, Anuj Pennathur, Caiwu Liang, Louise I. Oldham, Eva Mazzolini, Lole Jurado, Gopinathan Sankar, Stephen Parry, Ver&#243;nica Celorrio, Jahan M. Dawlaty, Jan Rossmeisl, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, Ifan E. L. Stephens, James R. Durrant, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393069559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benjamin Moss, Katrine L. Svane, David Nieto&#8208;Castro, Reshma R. Rao, S&#248;ren B. Scott, Cindy Tseng, Michael L. Sachs, Anuj Pennathur, Caiwu Liang, Louise I. Oldham, Eva Mazzolini, Lole Jurado, Gopinathan Sankar, Stephen Parry, Ver&#243;nica Celorrio, Jahan M. Dawlaty, Jan Rossmeisl, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, Ifan E. L. Stephens, James R. Durrant</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c11651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Overall and Hybrid Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00332</link>
      <description>Quan Li, Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Yujie Sun, Bo You, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393071097

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Quan Li, Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Yujie Sun, Bo You</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom platinum with asymmetric coordination environment on fully conjugated covalent organic framework for efficient electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46872-x</link>
      <description>Ziqi Zhang, Zhe Zhang, Cailing Chen, Rui Wang, Minggang Xie, Shouhong Wan, Ruige Zhang, Linchuan Cong, Haiyan Lu, Yu Han, Xing Wang, Zhan Shi, Shouhua Feng, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393074416

                Abstract Two-dimensional (2D) covalent organic frameworks (COFs) and their derivatives have been widely applied as electrocatalysts owing to their unique nanoscale pore configurations, stable periodic structures, abundant coordination sites and high surface area. This work aims to construct a non-thermodynamically stable Pt-N 2 coordination active site by electrochemically modifying platinum (Pt) single atoms into a fully conjugated 2D COF as conductive agent-free and pyrolysis-free electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). In addition to maximizing atomic utilization, single-atom catalysts with definite structures can be used to investigate catalytic mechanisms and structure-activity relationships. In this work, in-situ characterizations and theoretical calculations reveal that a nitrogen-rich graphene analogue COF not only exhibits a favorable metal-support effect for Pt, adjusting the binding energy between Pt sites to H* intermediates by forming unique Pt-N 2 instead of the typical Pt-N 4 coordination environment, but also enhances electron transport ability and structural stability, showing both conductivity and stability in acidic environments.</description>
      <author>Ziqi Zhang, Zhe Zhang, Cailing Chen, Rui Wang, Minggang Xie, Shouhong Wan, Ruige Zhang, Linchuan Cong, Haiyan Lu, Yu Han, Xing Wang, Zhan Shi, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46872-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linker-free Functionalization of Phosphorene Nanosheets by Sialic Acid Biomolecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00128</link>
      <description>Nasrin Khazamipour, Amir H. Souri, Omid Babaee, Behzad Dadashnia, Pouya Soltan-Khamsi, Sadegh Mousavi, Shams Mohajerzadeh, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393077704

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nasrin Khazamipour, Amir H. Souri, Omid Babaee, Behzad Dadashnia, Pouya Soltan-Khamsi, Sadegh Mousavi, Shams Mohajerzadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assembled RhRuFe Trimetallene for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400336</link>
      <description>Wenshu Zhang, Kai Wang, Fangxu Lin, Qinghua Zhang, Yingjun Sun, Heng Luo, Weiyu Zhang, Junhu Zhou, Fan Lv, Dawei Wang, Lin Gu, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393083920

                Abstract Industrializing water electrolyzers demands better electrocatalysts, especially for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The prevailing OER catalysts are Ir or Ru&#8208;based nanomaterials, however, they still suffer from insufficient stability. An alternative yet considerably less explored approach is to upgrade Rh, a known stable but moderately active element for OER electrocatalysis, via rational structural engineering. Herein, a precise synthesis of assembled RhRuFe trimetallenes (RhRuFe TMs) with an average thickness of 1 nm for boosting overall water splitting catalysis is reported. Favorable mass transport and optimized electronic structure collectively render RhRuFe TMs with an improved OER activity of an overpotential of 330 mV to deliver 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is significantly lower than the Rh/C control (by 601 mV) and reported Rh&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts. In particular, the RhRuFe TMs&#8208;based water splitting devices can achieve the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at a low voltage of 1.63 V, which is among the best in the Rh&#8208;based bifunctional catalysts for electrolyzers. The addition of Fe in RhRuFe TMs can modulate the strain/electron distribution of the multi&#8208;alloy, which regulates the binding energies of H * and OH * in hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions for achieving the enhanced bifunctional OER and HER catalysis is further demonstrated.</description>
      <author>Wenshu Zhang, Kai Wang, Fangxu Lin, Qinghua Zhang, Yingjun Sun, Heng Luo, Weiyu Zhang, Junhu Zhou, Fan Lv, Dawei Wang, Lin Gu, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous high-entropy alloy coatings as highly efficient electrocatalysts for electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150622</link>
      <description>Xiaoran Huo, Sainan Nie, Yuanwu Zhang, Xiaojiao Zuo, Xuelu Xu, Nannan Zhang, Jiayi Huang, Xiaofei Zhu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393087349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoran Huo, Sainan Nie, Yuanwu Zhang, Xiaojiao Zuo, Xuelu Xu, Nannan Zhang, Jiayi Huang, Xiaofei Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Design of Bifunctional Single-Atom Catalyst over g-C2N2 for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114657</link>
      <description>Xuefei Wu, Junan Gao, Hong Zhao, Zhigang Lei, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, Guang-Jie Xia, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393089380

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuefei Wu, Junan Gao, Hong Zhao, Zhigang Lei, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, Guang-Jie Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co&#9472;Mn Bimetallic Nanowires by Interfacial Modulation with/without Vacancy Filling as Active and Durable Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400859</link>
      <description>Yong-quan Jiang, Zhao-Hui Song, Meijiao Qu, Yong Jiang, Wei Luo, Rongxing He, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393093387

                Abstract Active and stable nonnoble electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are required for water splitting by sustainable electricity. Here, Mn bonded with O and P is incorporated to modulate Co 3 S 4 and Co 2 P respectively to enhance the catalytic activity and extend the catalyst lifetime. Mn 3 O 4 adjusts the electronic structure of Co 3 S 4 and Co atom fills the oxygen vacancy in Mn 3 O 4 . The interfacial interaction endows Co 3 S 4 /Mn 3 O 4 to a lower reaction barrier due to ideal binding energies for OER intermediates. Structure stability of active sites and enhanced Co&#9472;S bonds by Operando Raman spectroscopy and theoretical calculations reduce the dissolution of Co 3 S 4 /Mn 3 O 4 , resulting in a lifetime of 500 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER. The modulation of Co 2 P by MnP weakens the interaction between Co sites and adsorbed H * , achieving a high activity under a large current for HER. The assembled electrolyzer affords 50 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.58 V and exhibits a lifetime of 350 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . The calculations disclose the electron interaction for the activity and stability, as well as the enhanced conductivity. The findings develop new avenues toward promoting catalytic activity and stability, making Co&#9472;Mn bimetallic nanowires efficient electrocatalysts for nonnoble water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Yong-quan Jiang, Zhao-Hui Song, Meijiao Qu, Yong Jiang, Wei Luo, Rongxing He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concurrent learning scheme for crystal structure prediction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.094117</link>
      <description>Z. J. Wang, Xiao-Yang Wang, Xiaoshan Luo, Pengyue Gao, Yanfeng Sun, Jian Lv, Han Wang, Yanchao Wang, Yanming Ma, Physical review. 109(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393094535

                Crystal structure prediction (CSP) and machine learning potential (MLP) are two fundamental methods for modern computational material discovery. While the former aims at efficient sampling of the potential energy surface (PES) for discovering new materials, the latter focuses on reproducing the PES to accelerate various atomic simulation tasks. In this work, we combine the two methods within a concurrent learning framework in an effort to generate efficient MLP models for accelerating CSP. The proposed scheme explores the PES through the swarm-intelligence calypso method, labels the most representative structures with quantum mechanical calculations, and learns the PES through a deep potential (DP) model. The process proceeds in an iterative, computationally efficient, and automated manner, leading to the collection of a most compact reference training set from which the resulting DP model is proven particularly suitable for accelerating calypso structure prediction. The scheme has been systematically benchmarked on binary magnesium-aluminium (Mg-Al) alloys and ternary lithium-lanthanum-hydrogen (Li-La-H) superhydrides, demonstrating its efficiency and reliability in DP model construction and calypso structure prediction. The proposed scheme represents a promising routine to perform the structure prediction of large or multicomponent systems.</description>
      <author>Z. J. Wang, Xiao-Yang Wang, Xiaoshan Luo, Pengyue Gao, Yanfeng Sun, Jian Lv, Han Wang, Yanchao Wang, Yanming Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.094117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A microkinetic study of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; hydrogenation to methanol on Pd&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Cu(111) and Pd&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Ag(111) catalysts: a DFT analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00070f</link>
      <description>Abdulrauf Onimisi Ibrahim, Wan Mohd Ashri Wan Daud, Muhamad Fazly Abdul Patah, Ahmed Halilu, Joon Ching Juan, Gazali Tanimu, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393107747

                We explored the complex reaction routes of hydrogenating CO 2 to CH 3 OH on palladium single-atom alloy catalysts using microkinetic reaction modelling and mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Abdulrauf Onimisi Ibrahim, Wan Mohd Ashri Wan Daud, Muhamad Fazly Abdul Patah, Ahmed Halilu, Joon Ching Juan, Gazali Tanimu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00070f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom anchored on curved boron nitride fullerene surface as efficient electrocatalyst for carbon dioxide reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114040</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu, Molecular Catalysis. 559(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393116736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Liu, Aling Ma, Zhenzhen Wang, Zongpeng Ding, Yan Pang, Guohong Fan, Hong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles study of direct Z-scheme GaS/WTe2 van der Waals heterostructure as photocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.415882</link>
      <description>Caichao Wan, Wei Yan, Chun-Sheng Liu, Lan Meng, Xin Yan, Physica B: Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393120277

                The effective separation of charge carriers and the redox capacity for water splitting are two crucial factors that influence photocatalysis. Here, we studied the photocatalytic properties of GaS/WTe2 van der Waals heterostructure (vdWH) using first-principle calculations. The results show that this heterostructure acts as a direct Z-scheme with GaS as the water oxidation photocatalyst and WTe2 as the water reduction photocatalyst. Photogenerated charge carriers are efficiently separated, with electrons in GaS combining with holes in WTe2, while other charge carriers with high redox ability remain in the respective materials for water splitting. More importantly, the heterostructure exhibits excellent performance in all acid and alkali solutions (pH 0&#8211;14) and has strong light absorption in the ultraviolet (UV) and visible region. The power conversion efficiency(PCE) reaches 19.73%. This work reveals that GaS/WTe2 heterostructure is a highly promising material for photocatalytic water splitting.</description>
      <author>Caichao Wan, Wei Yan, Chun-Sheng Liu, Lan Meng, Xin Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.415882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Second-row transition metals decorated cyclo[18]carbon: Single-atom catalysts for excellent hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108351</link>
      <description>Zarna D. Ponkiya, Darshil Chodvadiya, Prafulla K. Jha, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 176(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393122969

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zarna D. Ponkiya, Darshil Chodvadiya, Prafulla K. Jha</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering the Lattice Strain in Bismuth&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts for Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;to&#8208;Formate Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400928</link>
      <description>Xinyan Li, Haiyan Zheng, Qiang Sun, Jingting He, Xiaohui Yao, C. P. Sun, Guo&#8208;Gang Shan, Min Zhang, Changyan Zhu, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Xinlong Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393130525

                Abstract Tuning the lattice strain of catalysts represents a powerful strategy to alter their electronic structures and ultimately regulate catalytic performance. Electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction is a promising avenue to accomplish the carbon&#8208;neutral cycle, however, there still lacks a distinct and systematic understanding of the lattice strain effect in CO 2 electrochemical conversion. In this work, the influence of lattice strain on Bi (012) facets to formate production is studied. The pre&#8208;executed density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that lattice compression promotes the wrinkling of exposed Bi surface and increases the total density of state (DOS) of active sites at the Fermi level. As the gradual intensification of lattice contraction, the selectivity of CO 2 reduction exhibits a volcanic alteration, with an optimal lattice contraction of 3%. Experimentally synthesized Bi 2 O 2 CO 3 /Bi heterogeneous catalyst confirms the effect of lattice compression. When compression reaches &#8722;3.04% on Bi (012) facets, the catalyst possesses the highest Faraday efficiency (FE) of 96.17% at &#8722;1.2 V RHE and an industrially scalable current density of &#8722;600 mA cm &#8722;2 . Additionally, in seawater&#8208;based electrolysis, the catalyst also exhibits excellent remarkable FE of 95.43% of formate production.</description>
      <author>Xinyan Li, Haiyan Zheng, Qiang Sun, Jingting He, Xiaohui Yao, C. P. Sun, Guo&#8208;Gang Shan, Min Zhang, Changyan Zhu, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Xinlong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the synergistic effect of amorphous CoW-phospho-borides for overall alkaline water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.090</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Rinkoo Bhabal, Kishan H. Mali, B.R. Bhagat, Alpa Dashora, Maulik Patel, R. Fernandes, N. Patel, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 63(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393137824

                Amorphous transition-metal-phospho-borides (TMPBs) are emerging as a new class of hybrid bifunctional catalysts for water-splitting. The present work reports the discovery of CoWPB as a new promising material that adds to the smaller family of TMPBs. The optimized compositions, namely Co4WPB5 and Co2WPB1 could achieve 10 mA/cm2 at just 72 mV and 262 mV of overpotentials for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively, in 1 M KOH. Furthermore, the catalyst showed good performance in a 2-electrode assembly (1.59 V for 10 mA/cm2) with considerable stability (70 h stability, 10,000 operating cycles). Detailed morphological and electrochemical characterizations unveiled insights into the role of all elements in catalyst's improved performance. The presence of W was found to be crucial in improving the electronic conductivity and charge redistribution, making CoWPB suitable for both HER and OER. In computational simulation analysis, two configurations with different atomic environments, namely, CoWPBH and CoWPBO were found to have the lowest calculated overpotentials for HER and OER, respectively. It was found that the surface P-sites in CoWPBH were HER-active while the Co-sites in CoWPBO were OER-active sites. The study presents new knowledge about active sites in such multi-component catalysts that will foster more advancement in the area of water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Rinkoo Bhabal, Kishan H. Mali, B.R. Bhagat, Alpa Dashora, Maulik Patel, R. Fernandes, N. Patel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Density Functional Theory Investigation of Ammonia Oxidation on the M-Doped &#946;-Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (M = Cr, Co, Cu, Fe) Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00596</link>
      <description>Shayne Johnston, Rachelle M. Choueiri, Xinrun Liu, Brendan J. R. Laframboise, Stephen W. Tatarchuk, Leanne D. Chen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393138765

                The ammonia oxidation reaction (AOR) has applications as a sustainable energy source and in wastewater remediation. Nickel based catalysts for the AOR reaction are ideal as they are cost efficient, have longer lifetimes than more expensive alternatives, and can produce value-added products. Dopants can be applied to these nickel catalysts to further increase their value. This work explores the effects on reaction potentials when &#946;-Ni(OH)2 is doped with chromium, cobalt, copper, or iron using density functional theory to model the AOR. Limiting potentials for dinitrogen production improved when &#946;-Ni(OH)2 was doped with chromium and cobalt. Limiting potentials for nitrite production remained consistent when &#946;-Ni(OH)2 was doped with cobalt or iron. Compared with the pristine &#946;-Ni(OH)2 surface, there was no improvement in the limiting potential of nitrate formation for any of the doped surfaces. This research begins to reveal the importance of exploring dopant addition to &#946;-Ni(OH)2 as a method of improving the catalyst activity for the AOR.</description>
      <author>Shayne Johnston, Rachelle M. Choueiri, Xinrun Liu, Brendan J. R. Laframboise, Stephen W. Tatarchuk, Leanne D. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic conversion of CH4 and CO2 to acetic acid over Cu/ZnO catalysts under mild conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150690</link>
      <description>N. Y. Liu, Na L&#252;, Kun Zhao, Pengxiao Liu, Zhao-Yan Sun, Jing L&#252;, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393142632

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. Y. Liu, Na L&#252;, Kun Zhao, Pengxiao Liu, Zhao-Yan Sun, Jing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Neural Network Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00004</link>
      <description>Timothy T. Duignan, ACS Physical Chemistry Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393037991

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Timothy T. Duignan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphyschemau.4c00004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on Advancing Sustainable CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion Processes: Trinomial Technology, Environment, and Economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07133</link>
      <description>Lourdes F. Vega, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Ismail I.I. Alkhatib, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393097423

                CO2 can be converted into value-added products such as fuels, chemicals, and building materials, adding an economic incentive for CO2 capture and green economy, while also reducing the environmental footprint of hard-to-abate industries such as aviation, construction, and metallurgy. Nonetheless, most available technologies for direct CO2 conversion, while promising, are still in early development stages, facing technical and economic challenges for their scale-up, questioning their viability to truly instill a timely impact on global CO2 emissions. Furthermore, a clear environmental benefit should be obtained for the new processes versus the traditional ones they are replacing in the market. In this perspective, we examine the range of available technologies for direct CO2 conversion using thermal, electrical, and photochemical routes and mineralization including the advancements in their role in synthesizing a range of resulting products from methanol, methane, carbon monoxide, and solid carbonates. We offer insights on the trends in current research and development and the required direction to expedite the technological readiness of attractive CO2 conversion technologies in terms of catalytic material and reactor design. We also highlight the important role of modeling (molecular and process levels) as an enabling tool to deploy these technologies at the commercial scale originating from understanding their behavior at the molecular level. Lastly, we highlight the significance of carrying out reliable life cycle analysis in identifying the environmental hotspots as well as gaps in the technology that allows improving their environmental footprint and economic attractiveness.</description>
      <author>Lourdes F. Vega, Daniel Baham&#243;n, Ismail I.I. Alkhatib</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending the definition of atomic basis sets to atoms with fractional nuclear charge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0196383</link>
      <description>Giorgio Domenichini, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 160(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393152656

                Alchemical transformations showed that perturbation theory can be applied also to changes in the atomic nuclear charges of a molecule. The alchemical path that connects two different chemical species involves the conceptualization of a non-physical system in which an atom possess a non-integer nuclear charge. A correct quantum mechanical treatment of these systems is limited by the fact that finite size atomic basis sets do not define exponents and contraction coefficients for fractional charge atoms. This paper proposes a solution to this problem and shows that a smooth interpolation of the atomic orbital coefficients and exponents across the periodic table is a convenient way to produce accurate alchemical predictions, even using small size basis sets.</description>
      <author>Giorgio Domenichini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0196383</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface structure determination by exhaustive search of asymmetric unit</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.115430</link>
      <description>Xingxing Dong, Caiyun He, Chao He, Hui Wang, Shaogang Xu, Hu Xu, Physical review. 109(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393157853

                Determining surface structures is a substantial challenge due to the limitations of experimental techniques and the complexity of theoretical models. In this work, we use a method called the exhaustive search of asymmetric unit (ESAU), designed to identify surface structures through a detailed analysis of the asymmetric unit. This method employs two main strategies: narrowing the research area by focusing on a smaller, unique segment rather than the entire unit cell, and transforming the infinite possibilities of atomic positions into discrete, manageable units. These strategies allow us to systematically enumerate all potential surface structures. Employing the ESAU method, we have successfully replicated a variety of known surface structures, including two-dimensional materials on substrates, and have also uncovered some previously unknown structures. Importantly, the ESAU method shows significant promise not only in utilizing experimental data but also in predicting surface and crystal structures without prior experimental evidence. Our results affirm that the ESAU approach provides a comprehensive and efficient tool for uncovering material structures, paving the way for more in-depth studies on the properties and behaviors of materials.</description>
      <author>Xingxing Dong, Caiyun He, Chao He, Hui Wang, Shaogang Xu, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.115430</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
