<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 01:08:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atoms on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Can Catalyze Water Oxidation in Photoelectrochemical Experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03319</link>
      <description>Shi Wu, Wu Lu, Nikita Denisov, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Giorgio Zoppellaro, Xiaoyu Yang, Patrik Schmuki, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399380646

                Photoelectrochemical water splitting on n-type semiconductors is highly dependent on catalysis of the rate-determining reaction of O2 evolution. Conventionally, in electrochemistry and photoelectrochemistry O2 evolution is catalyzed by metal oxide catalysts like IrO2 and RuO2, whereas noble metals such as Pt are considered unsuitable for this purpose. However, our study finds that Pt, in its single-atom form, exhibits exceptional cocatalytic properties for photoelectrochemical water oxidation on a TiO2 photoanode, in contrast to Pt in a nanoparticle form. The decoration of Pt single atoms onto TiO2 yields a remarkable current density of 5.89 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.23 VRHE, surpassing bare TiO2 (or Pt nanoparticle decorated TiO2) by 2.52 times. Notably, this enhancement remains consistent over a wide pH range. By accompanying theoretical work, we assign this significant enhancement to an improved charge transfer and separation efficiency along with accelerated kinetics in the oxygen evolution reaction facilitated by the presence of Pt single atoms on the TiO2 surface.</description>
      <author>Shi Wu, Wu Lu, Nikita Denisov, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Giorgio Zoppellaro, Xiaoyu Yang, Patrik Schmuki</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of High Entropy Alloys on a Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Approaching Active Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01278</link>
      <description>Jing Liang, Yanling Ma, Yanjie Li, Wencong Zhang, Hao Hu, Jie Su, Zhenpeng Yao, Wenpei Gao, Wen Shang, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399380880

                High-entropy alloys (HEAs) have garnered considerable attention as promising nanocatalysts for effectively utilizing Pt in catalysis toward oxygen reduction reactions due to their unique properties. Nonetheless, there is a relative dearth of attention regarding the structural evolution of HEAs in response to electrochemical conditions. In this work, we propose a thermal reduction method to synthesize high entropy nanoparticles by leveraging the confinement effect and abundant nitrogen-anchored sites provided by pyrolyzed metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs). Notably, the prepared catalysts exhibit enhanced activity accompanied by structural reconstruction during electrochemical activation, approaching 1 order of magnitude higher mass activity compared to Pt/C in oxygen reduction. Atomic-scale structural characterization reveals that abundant defects and single atoms are formed during the activation process, contributing to a significant boost in the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction reactions. This study provides deep insights into surface reconstruction engineering during electrochemical operations, with practical implications for fuel cell applications.</description>
      <author>Jing Liang, Yanling Ma, Yanjie Li, Wencong Zhang, Hao Hu, Jie Su, Zhenpeng Yao, Wenpei Gao, Wen Shang, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of pH&#8208;universal electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.555</link>
      <description>Jingwen Lin, Qianqian Wang, Zhenyun Zhao, Dongliang Chen, Rumin Liu, Zhizhen Ye, Bin L&#252;, Bin Yang, Jianguo Lu, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399436717

                Abstract The path to searching for sustainable energy has never stopped since the depletion of fossil fuels can lead to serious environmental pollution and energy shortages. Using water electrolysis to produce hydrogen has been proven to be a prioritized approach for green resource production. It is highly crucial to explore inexpensive and high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for accelerating hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and apply them to industrial cases on a large scale. Here, we summarize the different mechanisms of HER in different pH settings and review recent advances in non&#8208;noble&#8208;metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Then, based on the previous efforts, we discuss several universal strategies for designing pH&#8208;independent catalysts and show directions for the future design of pH&#8208;universal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jingwen Lin, Qianqian Wang, Zhenyun Zhao, Dongliang Chen, Rumin Liu, Zhizhen Ye, Bin L&#252;, Bin Yang, Jianguo Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water structure and local potential distribution at Pt surface in alkaline cation mediated hydrogen evolution regulable by electric field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4507558/v1</link>
      <description>Junguang Tao, Ding Pan, Dan Xing, Chang Pu, Lixiu Guan, Shuo Zhang, Zhuoao Li, Yunfei Zhang, Mengying Jia, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399442130

                Abstract The impact of alkaline media on hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) rate and selectivity is crucial for advancement of water electrolysis technology. Herein, we revealed the mechanism through which alkali metal cations (AM+) influence HER performance of Pt electrodes. We quantified the interfacial potential drops, which are regulatable by E-field and found that the local surface concentration of AM+ is 5.0 ~ 8.6 times higher than in the bulk solution. Decreasing AM+ concentration through reverse E-field disrupts adsorbate-surface interactions and boosts HER activity without affecting hydrogen binding energetics and kinetics. Complexes of OH&#948;&#8722;-(H2O)x-AM+ are formed near the interface, impacting intermediate product detachment. The presence of AM+ also plays a role in restructuring interfacial water and improving proton transfer efficiency. For Li+, the reorientation of O-H bonds towards Pt surface facilitates the HER process. These findings shed light on potential avenues for enhancing the efficiency of HER processes.</description>
      <author>Junguang Tao, Ding Pan, Dan Xing, Chang Pu, Lixiu Guan, Shuo Zhang, Zhuoao Li, Yunfei Zhang, Mengying Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4507558/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adsorption and solar light activity of noble metal adatoms (Au and Zn) on Fe(111) surface: a first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cp04504h</link>
      <description>Qaiser Rafiq, Muhammad Tahir Khan, Sardar Sikandar Hayat, Sikander Azam, Amin Ur Rahman, Hosam O. Elansary, Muhammad Shan, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399442509

                Noble metals such as gold (Au), zinc (Zn), and iron (Fe) are highly significant in both fundamental and technological contexts owing to their applications in optoelectronics, light-emitting devices, photovoltaics, nanotechnology, batteries, and thermal barrier coatings.</description>
      <author>Qaiser Rafiq, Muhammad Tahir Khan, Sardar Sikandar Hayat, Sikander Azam, Amin Ur Rahman, Hosam O. Elansary, Muhammad Shan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cp04504h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient tuning of the selectivity of Cu-based interface for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction by ligand modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101620</link>
      <description>Yonggao Yan, Tongxian Li, Manuel Oliva&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Yuguo Zhao, Shuo Wang, Xin Chen, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang, Xiayan Wang, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399446319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yonggao Yan, Tongxian Li, Manuel Oliva&#8208;Ram&#237;rez, Yuguo Zhao, Shuo Wang, Xin Chen, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang, Xiayan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101620</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Urea Synthesis via One-Step N&#8722;C&#8722;N Coupling: Strong Metal-Support Interaction-Driven Planar Cu Clusters on Two-Dimensional Mo2C MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02393e</link>
      <description>Yue Zhang, Linguo Lu, Tiantian Zhao, Jingxiang Zhao, Qinghai Cai, Zhongfang Chen, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399451390

                The anchoring of the Cu cluster on Mo 2 C substrate can achieve a planar configuration, effectively boosting urea synthesis via a one-step mechanism.</description>
      <author>Yue Zhang, Linguo Lu, Tiantian Zhao, Jingxiang Zhao, Qinghai Cai, Zhongfang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02393e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic reduction of CO2 to C2H4 by monometallic Cu4 cluster supported on CeO2(110) surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.060</link>
      <description>Ping Liu, Zhu Hai-yan, Baiyue Li, Chen Wu, Jia Shi, Bingbing Suo, Wenli Zou, Yawei Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 73(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399466754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ping Liu, Zhu Hai-yan, Baiyue Li, Chen Wu, Jia Shi, Bingbing Suo, Wenli Zou, Yawei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening of single-atom catalysts supported on Al12N12 nanocage for nitrogen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109509</link>
      <description>Xinlin Tang, H. Liao, Wenhong Zeng, Wei Guo, Xin Lian, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399487964

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinlin Tang, H. Liao, Wenhong Zeng, Wei Guo, Xin Lian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compressively Strained and Interconnected Platinum Cones with Greatly Enhanced Activity and Durability toward Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404677</link>
      <description>Mingkai Liu, Siyu Zhou, Marc Figueras&#8208;Valls, Y. Ding, Zhiheng Lyu, Manos Mavrikakis, Younan Xia, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399490867

                Abstract The synthesis of cone&#8208;shaped Pt nanoparticles featuring compressively&#8208;strained {111} facets by depositing Pt atoms on the vertices of Pd icosahedral nanocrystals, followed by selective removal of the Pd template via wet etching, is reported. By controlling the lateral dimensions down to ca. 3 nm, together with a thickness of ca. 2 nm, the Pt cones show greatly enhanced specific and mass activities toward oxygen reduction, with values being 2.8 and 6.4 times those of commercial Pt/C, respectively. Both the strain field and the observed activity trend are rationalized using density functional theory calculations. With the formation of ultrathin linkers among the Pt cones derived from the same Pd icosahedral seed, the interconnected Pt cones acquire stronger interactions with the carbon support, preventing them from detachment and aggregation during the catalytic reaction. Even after 20 000 cycles of accelerated durability test, the Pt cones still show a mass activity 5.3 times higher than the initial value of the Pt/C.</description>
      <author>Mingkai Liu, Siyu Zhou, Marc Figueras&#8208;Valls, Y. Ding, Zhiheng Lyu, Manos Mavrikakis, Younan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-support spin orders: Crucial effect on electrocatalytic oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0207891</link>
      <description>Yi-jie Chen, Jun Wen, Zhenlin Luo, Fu-li Sun, Wenxian Chen, Gui&#8722;Lin Zhuang, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399494915

                Magnetic property (e.g. spin order) of support is of great importance in the rational design of heterogeneous catalysts. Herein, we have taken the Ni-supported ferromagnetic (FM) CrBr3 support (Nix/CrBr3) to thoroughly investigate the effect of spin-order on electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) via spin-polarized density functional theory calculations. Specifically, Ni loading induces anti-FM coupling in Ni-Cr, leading to a transition from FM-to-ferrimagnetic (FIM) properties, while Ni-Ni metallic bonds create a robust FM direct exchange, benefiting the improvement of the phase transition temperature. Interestingly, with the increase in Ni loading, the easy magnetic axis changes from out-of-plane (2D-Heisenberg) to in-plane (2D-XY). The adsorption properties of Nix/CrBr3, involving O2 adsorption energy and configuration, are not governed by the d-band center but strongly correlate with magnetic anisotropy. It is noteworthy that the applied potential and electrolyte acidity triggers spin-order transition phenomena during the ORR and induces the catalytic pathway change from 4e- ORR to 2e- ORR with the excellent onset potential of 0.93 V/reversible hydrogen electrode, comparable to the existing most excellent noble-metal catalysts. Generally, these findings offer new avenues to understand and design heterogeneous catalysts with magnetic support.</description>
      <author>Yi-jie Chen, Jun Wen, Zhenlin Luo, Fu-li Sun, Wenxian Chen, Gui&#8722;Lin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0207891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seawater electrolysis for fuels and chemicals production: fundamentals, achievements, and perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00822c</link>
      <description>Changjian Lin, Chang Yu, Junting Dong, Yingnan Han, Hongling Huang, Wenbin Li, Yafang Zhang, Xin Tan, Jieshan Qiu, Chemical Society reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399500181

                The production of value-added fuels and chemicals via seawater electrolysis is a promising step or support towards sustainable energy development and carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Changjian Lin, Chang Yu, Junting Dong, Yingnan Han, Hongling Huang, Wenbin Li, Yafang Zhang, Xin Tan, Jieshan Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs00822c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrN supported by carbon nanosheets as efficient catalysts toward oxygen reduction reaction and Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02855-x</link>
      <description>Yating Zhang, Fan Zhang, Zhe L&#252;, Junming Luo, Suyang Feng, Zhihui Wang, Hui Chen, Haoming Wu, Zhengpei Miao, Bin Chi, Neng Yu, Chen You, Jing Li, Xinlong Tian, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399508774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yating Zhang, Fan Zhang, Zhe L&#252;, Junming Luo, Suyang Feng, Zhihui Wang, Hui Chen, Haoming Wu, Zhengpei Miao, Bin Chi, Neng Yu, Chen You, Jing Li, Xinlong Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02855-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential Dependence and Substituent Effect in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction on a Cobalt Phthalocyanine Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05089</link>
      <description>Yin&#8208;Long Li, Xiangqian Jiang, Hao Cao, Zhao Hong-yan, Jun Li, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399513636

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yin&#8208;Long Li, Xiangqian Jiang, Hao Cao, Zhao Hong-yan, Jun Li, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced learning loop framework accelerates screening of bimetallic catalysts with high oxygen reduction properties in different coordination environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.040</link>
      <description>Pei Song, Zepeng Jia, Sen Lu, Zhiguo Wang, Tiren Peng, Zi Gao, Xue Bai, Qi Jiang, Hong Cui, Weizhi Tian, Rong Feng, Zhiyong Liang, Qin Kang, Hongkuan Yuan, International journal of hydrogen energy. 73(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399516365

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pei Song, Zepeng Jia, Sen Lu, Zhiguo Wang, Tiren Peng, Zi Gao, Xue Bai, Qi Jiang, Hong Cui, Weizhi Tian, Rong Feng, Zhiyong Liang, Qin Kang, Hongkuan Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced electrocatalysts for fuel cells: Evolution of active sites and synergistic properties of catalysts and carrier materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20230052</link>
      <description>Zhijie Kong, Jianghua Wu, Zhijuan Liu, Dafeng Yan, Zhi Peng Wu, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, Exploration. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399516623

                Abstract Proton exchange&#8208;membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) is a clean and efficient type of energy storage device. However, the sluggish reaction rate of the cathode oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) has been a significant problem in its development. This review reports the recent progress of advanced electrocatalysts focusing on the interface/surface electronic structure and exploring the synergistic relationship of precious&#8208;based and non&#8208;precious metal&#8208;based catalysts and support materials. The support materials contain non&#8208;metal (C/N/Si, etc.) and metal&#8208;based structures, which have demonstrated a crucial role in the synergistic enhancement of electrocatalytic properties, especially for high&#8208;temperature fuel cell systems. To improve the strong interaction, some exciting synergistic strategies by doping and coating heterogeneous elements or connecting polymeric ligands containing carbon and nitrogen were also shown herein. Besides the typical role of the crystal surface, phase structure, lattice strain, etc., the evolution of structure&#8208;performance relations was also highlighted in real&#8208;time tests. The advanced in situ characterization techniques were also reviewed to emphasize the accurate structure&#8208;performance relations. Finally, the challenge and prospect for developing the ORR electrocatalysts were concluded for commercial applications in low&#8208; and high&#8208;temperature fuel cell systems.</description>
      <author>Zhijie Kong, Jianghua Wu, Zhijuan Liu, Dafeng Yan, Zhi Peng Wu, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20230052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Design of Two-Dimensional Transition Metal Supported Biphenylene as Efficient Electrocatalysts toward Nitrogen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144578</link>
      <description>Dinesh Kumar Dhanthala Chittibabu, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399517644

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dinesh Kumar Dhanthala Chittibabu, Hsin&#8208;Tsung Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Nitrogen Reduction on the Transition Metal Carbonitride (110) Facet: DFT Predictions and Mechanistic Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02148</link>
      <description>Atef Iqbal, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Younes Abghoui, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399522828

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Atef Iqbal, Egill Sk&#250;lason, Younes Abghoui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techno-economic analysis of AMP/PZ solvent for CO2 capture in a biomass CHP plant: towards net negative emissions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1325212</link>
      <description>Muhammad Salman, Brieuc Beguin, Thomas Nyssen, Gr&#233;goire L&#233;onard, Frontiers in energy research. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399524686

                Compared to conventional monoethanolamine (MEA), alternative solvents are expected to substantially contribute to reduce the energy demand of post-combustion CO 2 capture from flue gases. This study presents a comprehensive techno-economic analysis of a 27 wt% 2-amino-2-methyl-1-propanol (AMP) + 13 wt% piperazine (PZ) aqueous solution for CO 2 capture, compared to a 30 wt% MEA solution. The study addresses the retrofit of a carbon capture unit to a biomass-fired combined heat and power (CHP) plant, effectively making it a bioenergy with a carbon capture and storage (BECCS) system. The treated flue gas has a flow rate of 23 tons/hour (t/h) with 11.54 vol% CO 2 and a 90% capture rate is aimed for. Aspen Plus V14 was employed for process simulations. Initially, binary interaction parameters for AMP/PZ, AMP/H 2 O, and PZ/H 2 O are regressed using vapor-liquid equilibrium (VLE) data, which were retrieved from literature along with reaction kinetics. Validation of parameters from available experimental literature yields an average absolute relative deviation (AARD) of only 5.9%. Afterwards, a process simulation model is developed and validated against experimental data from a reference pilot plant, using a similar AMP/PZ blend, resulting in 5% AARD. Next, a sensitivity analysis optimizes operating conditions, including solvent rate, absorber/stripper packing heights, and stripper pressure, based on regeneration energy impact. Optimized results, compared to MEA, reveal that AMP/PZ reduces the energy consumption from 3.61 to 2.86 GJ/tCO 2 . The retrofitting of the capture unit onto the selected CHP plant is examined through the development of a dedicated model. Two control strategies are compared to address energy unavailability for supplying the capture unit. The analysis spans 4 months, selected to account for seasonal variations. At nominal capacity, CO 2 emissions, rendered negative by biomass combustion and CO 2 capture, reach a maximum of &#8722;3.4 tCO 2 /h compared to 0.36 tCO 2 /h before retrofitting. Depending on the control strategy and CHP plant operating point, the Specific Primary Energy Consumption for CO 2 Avoided (SPECCA) ranges from 4.91 MJ/kgCO 2 to 1.76 MJ/kgCO 2 . Finally, an economic comparison based on systematic methodology reveals a 7.87% reduction in capture cost favoring the AMP/PZ blend. Together, these findings highlight AMP/PZ as a highly favorable alternative solvent.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Salman, Brieuc Beguin, Thomas Nyssen, Gr&#233;goire L&#233;onard</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1325212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Principles Study of Aluminum Doped Polycrystalline Silicon as a Potential Anode Candidate in Li&#8208;ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400924</link>
      <description>Sree Harsha Bhimineni, Shu&#8208;Ting Ko, Casey Cornwell, Yantao Xia, Sarah H. Tolbert, Jian Luo, Philippe Sautet, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399526907

                Abstract Addressing sustainable energy storage remains crucial for transitioning to renewable sources. While Li&#8208;ion batteries have made significant contributions, enhancing their capacity through alternative materials remains a key challenge. Micro&#8208;sized silicon is a promising anode material due to its tenfold higher theoretical capacity compared to conventional graphite. However, its substantial volumetric expansion during cycling impedes practical application due to mechanical failure and rapid capacity fading. A novel approach is proposed to mitigate this issue by incorporating trace amounts of aluminum into the micro&#8208;sized silicon electrode using ball milling. Density functional theory (DFT) is employed to establish a theoretical framework elucidating how grain boundary sliding, a key mechanism involved in preventing mechanical failure is facilitated by the presence of trace aluminum at grain boundaries. This, in turn, reduces stress accumulation within the material, reducing the likelihood of failure. To validate the theoretical predictions, capacity retention experiments are conducted on undoped and Al&#8208;doped micro&#8208;sized silicon samples. The results demonstrate significantly reduced capacity fading in the doped sample, corroborating the theoretical framework and showcasing the potential of aluminum doping for improved Li&#8208;ion battery performance.</description>
      <author>Sree Harsha Bhimineni, Shu&#8208;Ting Ko, Casey Cornwell, Yantao Xia, Sarah H. Tolbert, Jian Luo, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From computational screening to the synthesis of a promising OER catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc00192c</link>
      <description>Sai Govind Hari Kumar, Carlota Bozal&#8208;Ginesta, Ning Wang, Jehad Abed, Chunhui Shan, Zhenpeng Yao, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399527523

                The search for new materials can be laborious and expensive. With computational inverse design, material properties can be predicted before synthesis, thus accelerating materials discovery.</description>
      <author>Sai Govind Hari Kumar, Carlota Bozal&#8208;Ginesta, Ning Wang, Jehad Abed, Chunhui Shan, Zhenpeng Yao, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc00192c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing triple-layer photocatalytic systems based on direct Z-scheme photocatalytic systems: Toward higher solar-to-hydrogen efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160470</link>
      <description>L. G. Wang, Tao Shen, Jia Liu, Zhong Fang, Jie Ren, Shuang Li, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399534331

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. G. Wang, Tao Shen, Jia Liu, Zhong Fang, Jie Ren, Shuang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning-accelerated screening of Heusler alloys for nitrogen reduction reaction with graph neural network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160519</link>
      <description>Jing Zhou, Xiayong Chen, Xinrui Jiang, Zean Tian, Wangyu Hu, Bowen Huang, Dingwang Yuan, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399534351

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhou, Xiayong Chen, Xinrui Jiang, Zean Tian, Wangyu Hu, Bowen Huang, Dingwang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LDHs and their Derivatives for Electrochemical Energy Storage and Conversion Systems: Design, Insights and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400156</link>
      <description>Jianyi Liu, Kaitian Zheng, Yani Hua, Ling Peng, Xiaohong Meng, Chi Zhang, Rui Su, Xinyue Tao, Haiying Hu, Yibing Guo, Chunjian Xu, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399537103

                Abstract Electrochemical energy storage and conversion systems (EESCSs), including batteries, supercapacitors, fuel cells, and water electrolysis technologies, enabling the direct conversion between chemical and electrical energies. They are key to the flexible storage and utilization of renewable energy and play an important role in future energy technologies. The physical and chemical properties of electrode materials significantly influence the performance of EESCSs, necessitating the development of materials with both high cost&#8208;effectiveness and superior electrochemical storage and catalytic capabilities. Layered double hydroxides (LDHs), due to their unique properties as high surface area, evenly distributed active sites, and tunable compositions, makes themselves and the derivatives have become focal points in the EESCSs. This review summarizes recent advances of LDH and their derivates for diverse EESCSs applications, aims to elucidate the modification strategies of LDH materials and provide valuable insights for exploring LDH&#8208;derived materials in various electrochemical devices, offering interdisciplinary perspectives for the rational design of LDH&#8208;based materials.</description>
      <author>Jianyi Liu, Kaitian Zheng, Yani Hua, Ling Peng, Xiaohong Meng, Chi Zhang, Rui Su, Xinyue Tao, Haiying Hu, Yibing Guo, Chunjian Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the function of monolayer shell structure over Pt-based alloy catalysts in tuning ethane dehydrogenation reactivity and coking resistance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152898</link>
      <description>Yuan Zhang, Mifeng Xue, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, Chemical engineering journal. 494(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399539665

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan Zhang, Mifeng Xue, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zinc-indium-sulfide favors efficient C &#8722; H bond activation by concerted proton-coupled electron transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49265-2</link>
      <description>Xuejiao Wu, Xue-Ting Fan, Shunji Xie, Ivan Scodeller, Xiaojian Wen, Dario Vangestel, Jun Cheng, Bert F. Sels, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399542916

                Abstract C &#8722; H bond activation is a ubiquitous reaction that remains a major challenge in chemistry. Although semiconductor-based photocatalysis is promising, the C &#8722; H bond activation mechanism remains elusive. Herein, we report value-added coupling products from a wide variety of biomass and fossil-derived reagents, formed via C &#8722; H bond activation over zinc-indium-sulfides (Zn-In-S). Contrary to the commonly accepted stepwise electron-proton transfer pathway (PE-ET) for semiconductors, our experimental and theoretical studies evidence a concerted proton-coupled electron transfer (CPET) pathway. A pioneering microkinetic study, considering the relevant elementary steps of the surface chemistry, reveals a faster C &#8722; H activation with Zn-In-S because of circumventing formation of a charged radical, as it happens in PE-ET where it retards the catalysis due to strong site adsorption. For CPET over Zn-In-S, H abstraction, forming a neutral radical, is rate-limiting, but having lower energy barriers than that of PE-ET. The rate expressions derived from the microkinetics provide guidelines to rationally design semiconductor catalysis, e.g., for C &#8722; H activation, that is based on the CPET mechanism.</description>
      <author>Xuejiao Wu, Xue-Ting Fan, Shunji Xie, Ivan Scodeller, Xiaojian Wen, Dario Vangestel, Jun Cheng, Bert F. Sels</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49265-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice oxygen evolution in rutile Ru&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e367" altimg="si69.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&#8722;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;Ni&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e379" altimg="si70.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;O&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/&#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144567</link>
      <description>Adrian Frandsen, Kate&#345;ina Macounov&#225;, Jan Rossmeisl, Petr Krtil, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399544974

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adrian Frandsen, Kate&#345;ina Macounov&#225;, Jan Rossmeisl, Petr Krtil</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction and Experimental Verification of IrO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Supported on Titanium Nitride for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02936</link>
      <description>Xue Han, Tianyou Mou, A. T. M. N. Islam, Sinwoo Kang, Qiaowan Chang, Zhenghui Xie, Xinbing Zhao, Kotaro Sasaki, Jos&#233; A. Rodr&#237;guez, Ping Liu, Jingguang G. Chen, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399546622

                Reducing iridium (Ir) catalyst loading for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical strategy for large-scale hydrogen production via proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis. However, simultaneously achieving high activity, long-term stability, and reduced material cost remains challenging. To address this challenge, we develop a framework by combining density functional theory (DFT) prediction using model surfaces and proof-of-concept experimental verification using thin films and nanoparticles. DFT results predict that oxidized Ir monolayers over titanium nitride (IrO</description>
      <author>Xue Han, Tianyou Mou, A. T. M. N. Islam, Sinwoo Kang, Qiaowan Chang, Zhenghui Xie, Xinbing Zhao, Kotaro Sasaki, Jos&#233; A. Rodr&#237;guez, Ping Liu, Jingguang G. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Reduction Mechanisms of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Edges Using Grand-Canonical DFT: From CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Adsorption to HCOOH or CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03266</link>
      <description>Muhammad Akif Ramzan, R. Favre, Stephan N. Steinmann, Tangui Le Bahers, Pascal Raybaud, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399546763

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Akif Ramzan, R. Favre, Stephan N. Steinmann, Tangui Le Bahers, Pascal Raybaud</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gallium-based materials for electrocatalytic and photocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.073</link>
      <description>Chunmei Liu, Jiamin Ma, Zimei Fu, Peipei Zhao, Bo Meng, Yinyi Gao, Man Zhao, Yingluo He, He Xiao, Jianfeng Jia, International journal of hydrogen energy. 73(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399552673

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunmei Liu, Jiamin Ma, Zimei Fu, Peipei Zhao, Bo Meng, Yinyi Gao, Man Zhao, Yingluo He, He Xiao, Jianfeng Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of reaction-driven active configuration for enhanced CO2 electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109873</link>
      <description>Shanyong Chen, Tao Luo, Xiaoqing Li, Kejun Chen, Qiyou Wang, Junwei Fu, Kang Liu, Chao Ma, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Hongmei Li, Kishan S. Menghrajani, Changxu Liu, Stefan A. Maier, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Junwei Fu, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399555339

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shanyong Chen, Tao Luo, Xiaoqing Li, Kejun Chen, Qiyou Wang, Junwei Fu, Kang Liu, Chao Ma, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Hongmei Li, Kishan S. Menghrajani, Changxu Liu, Stefan A. Maier, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Junwei Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109873</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The MTO and DTO processes as greener alternatives to produce olefins: A review of kinetic models and reactor design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152906</link>
      <description>Tom&#225;s Cordero&#8208;Lanzac, Ana G. Gayubo, Andr&#233;s T. Aguayo, Javier Bilbao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399556348

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tom&#225;s Cordero&#8208;Lanzac, Ana G. Gayubo, Andr&#233;s T. Aguayo, Javier Bilbao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conformal surface intensive doping of low-valence Bi on Cu2O for highly efficient electrochemical nitrate reduction to ammonia production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.05.007</link>
      <description>Thi Kim Cuong Phu, Won Tae Hong, Hyungu Han, Young In Song, Jong Hun Kim, Seung Hun Roh, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Jai Hyun Koh, Byung&#8208;Keun Oh, Jun Young Kim, Chan&#8211;Hwa Chung, Dong Hoon Lee, Jung Kyu Kim, Materials today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399556499

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thi Kim Cuong Phu, Won Tae Hong, Hyungu Han, Young In Song, Jong Hun Kim, Seung Hun Roh, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Jai Hyun Koh, Byung&#8208;Keun Oh, Jun Young Kim, Chan&#8211;Hwa Chung, Dong Hoon Lee, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.05.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening WS2&#8722;based single&#8722;atom catalysts for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction to ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.038</link>
      <description>Mamutjan Tursun, Abdukader Abdukayum, Chao Wu, Caihong Wang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 73(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399558931

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mamutjan Tursun, Abdukader Abdukayum, Chao Wu, Caihong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patterned graphene: An effective platform for adsorption, immobilization, and destruction of SARS-CoV-2 Mpro</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.072</link>
      <description>Jiawen Wang, Huilong Dong, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li, Shuit&#8208;Tong Lee, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399563048

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawen Wang, Huilong Dong, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li, Shuit&#8208;Tong Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrahigh resolution x-ray Thomson scattering measurements at the European X-ray Free Electron Laser</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.l241112</link>
      <description>Thomas Gawne, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Oliver Humphries, Karen Appel, Carsten Baehtz, V. Bouffetier, E. Brambrink, Attila Cangi, S. G&#246;de, Zuzana Kon&#244;pkov&#225;, Mikako Makita, Mikhail Mishchenko, M. Nakatsutsumi, Kushal Ramakrishna, Lisa Randolph, Sebastian Schwalbe, Jan Vorberger, Lennart Wollenweber, U. Zastrau, Tobias Dornheim, Thomas R. Preston, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 109(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399566144

                Using an ultrahigh resolution (&#916;E&#8764;0.1eV) setup to measure electronic features in x-ray Thomson scattering (XRTS) experiments at the European XFEL in Germany, we have studied the collective plasmon excitation in aluminium at ambient conditions, which we can measure very accurately even at low momentum transfers. As a result, we can resolve previously reported discrepancies between time-dependent density functional theory simulations and experimental observations. The demonstrated capability for high-resolution XRTS measurements will be a game changer for the diagnosis of experiments with matter under extreme densities, temperatures, and pressures, and unlock the full potential of state-of-the-art x-ray free electron laser (XFEL) facilities to study planetary interior conditions, to understand inertial confinement fusion applications, and for material science and discovery. Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Thomas Gawne, Zhandos A. Moldabekov, Oliver Humphries, Karen Appel, Carsten Baehtz, V. Bouffetier, E. Brambrink, Attila Cangi, S. G&#246;de, Zuzana Kon&#244;pkov&#225;, Mikako Makita, Mikhail Mishchenko, M. Nakatsutsumi, Kushal Ramakrishna, Lisa Randolph, Sebastian Schwalbe, Jan Vorberger, Lennart Wollenweber, U. Zastrau, Tobias Dornheim, Thomas R. Preston</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.l241112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuneable bimetallic PdxCu100-x catalysts for selective butadiene hydrogenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114877</link>
      <description>Oscar E. Brandt Corstius, Hidde L. Nolten, George F. Tierney, Zhuoran Xu, Eric J. Doskocil, Jessi E. S. van der Hoeven, Petra E. de Jongh, Catalysis today. 441(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399566446

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Oscar E. Brandt Corstius, Hidde L. Nolten, George F. Tierney, Zhuoran Xu, Eric J. Doskocil, Jessi E. S. van der Hoeven, Petra E. de Jongh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modification of Metals and Ligands in Two-Dimensional Conjugated Metal-Organic Frameworks for Co2 Electroreduction: A Combined Dft and Machine Learning Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4863114</link>
      <description>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Guang&#8208;Yan Sun, Jing-yao Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399570693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanru Xing, Shize Liu, Guang&#8208;Yan Sun, Jing-yao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4863114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Codebase release r1.0 for amcheck</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21468/scipostphyscodeb.30-r1.0</link>
      <description>Andriy Smolyanyuk, Libor &#352;mejkal, I. I. Mazin, SciPost physics codebases. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399573734

                Altermagnets (AM) is a recently discovered class of collinear magnets that share some properties (anomalous transport, etc) with ferromagnets, some (zero net magnetization) with antiferromagnets, while also exhibiting unique properties (spin-splitting of electronic bands and resulting spin-splitter current). Since the moment compensation in AM is driven by symmetry, it must be possible to identify them by analyzing the crystal structure directly, without computing the electronic structure. Given the significant potential of AM for spintronics, it is very useful to have a tool for such an analysis. This work presents an open-access code implementing such a direct check.</description>
      <author>Andriy Smolyanyuk, Libor &#352;mejkal, I. I. Mazin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21468/scipostphyscodeb.30-r1.0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis via Electrocatalytic N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction on the Defective Surfaces of Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; MXenes: Theoretical and Experimental Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00802</link>
      <description>Feng Ren, Hanqing Yin, Lei Tian, Hui Zhang, Fengwei Tian, Jingquan Liu, Aijun Du, Wenrong Yang, Zhen Liu, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399574786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Ren, Hanqing Yin, Lei Tian, Hui Zhang, Fengwei Tian, Jingquan Liu, Aijun Du, Wenrong Yang, Zhen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal conductivity of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;Li&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;3&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;PS&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; solid electrolytes with &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; accuracy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.065403</link>
      <description>Davide Tisi, Federico Grasselli, Lorenzo Gigli, Michele Ceriotti, Physical review materials. 8(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399580171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Davide Tisi, Federico Grasselli, Lorenzo Gigli, Michele Ceriotti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.065403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insightful Understanding of Synergistic Oxygen Reduction on PtCo&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(111) Toward Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403894</link>
      <description>Xiangxiong Chen, Jiangnan Guo, Dong Qian, Jie Wu, Weixiong Liao, Geoffrey I.N. Waterhouse, Jinlong Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399581991

                Abstract Theory&#8208;guided materials design is an effective strategy for designing catalysts with high intrinsic activity whilst minimizing the usage of expensive metals like platinum. As proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept, herein it demonstrates that using density functional theory (DFT) calculations and experimental validation that intermetallic PtCo 3 alloy nanoparticles offer enhanced electrocatatalytic performance for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) compared to Pt nanoparticles. DFT calculations established that PtCo 3 (111) surfaces possess better intrinsic ORR activity compared to Pt(111) surfaces, owing to the synergistic action of adjacent Pt and Co active sites which optimizes the binding strength of ORR intermediates to boost overall ORR kinetics. With this understanding, a PtCo 3 /NC catalyst, comprising PtCo 3 nanoparticles exposing predominantly (111) facets dispersed on an N&#8208;doped carbon support, is successfully fabricated. PtCo 3 /NC demonstrates a high specific activity (3.4 mA cm &#8722;2 mg Pt &#8722;1 ), mass activity (0.67 A mg Pt &#8722;1 ), and cycling stability for the ORR in 0.1 M KOH, significantly outperforming a commercial 20 wt.% Pt/C catalyst. Moreover, a zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB) assembled with PtCo 3 /NC as the air&#8208;electrode catalyst delivered an open&#8208;circuit voltage of 1.47 V, a specific capacity of 775.1 mAh g Zn &#8722;1 and excellent operation durability after 200 discharge/charge cycles, vastly superior performance to a ZAB built using commercial Pt/C+IrO 2 as the air&#8208;electrode catalyst.</description>
      <author>Xiangxiong Chen, Jiangnan Guo, Dong Qian, Jie Wu, Weixiong Liao, Geoffrey I.N. Waterhouse, Jinlong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tool to check whether a symmetry-compensated collinear magnetic material is antiferro- or altermagnetic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21468/scipostphyscodeb.30</link>
      <description>Andriy Smolyanyuk, Libor &#352;mejkal, I. I. Mazin, SciPost physics codebases. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399582224

                Altermagnets (AM) is a recently discovered class of collinear magnets that share some properties (anomalous transport, etc) with ferromagnets, some (zero net magnetization) with antiferromagnets, while also exhibiting unique properties (spin-splitting of electronic bands and resulting spin-splitter current). Since the moment compensation in AM is driven by symmetry, it must be possible to identify them by analyzing the crystal structure directly, without computing the electronic structure. Given the significant potential of AM for spintronics, it is very useful to have a tool for such an analysis. This work presents an open-access code implementing such a direct check.</description>
      <author>Andriy Smolyanyuk, Libor &#352;mejkal, I. I. Mazin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21468/scipostphyscodeb.30</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and structure measurements of heavy-ion-heated diamond using &lt;i&gt;in situ&lt;/i&gt; X-ray diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0203005</link>
      <description>J. L&#252;tgert, P. Hesselbach, Maximilian Sch&#246;rner, V. Bagnoud, R.P. Belikov, P. Drechsel, Benedikt Heuser, Oliver Humphries, Peter Katr&#237;k, Bj&#248;rn Lindqvist, Chongbing Qu, R. Redmer, D. Riley, G. Schaumann, S. Schumacher, A. Tauschwitz, D. Varentsov, K. Weyrich, Xiaomei Yu, B. Zielbauer, Zs. Major, P. Neumayer, D. Kraus, Matter and radiation at extremes. 9(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399583691

                We present in situ measurements of spectrally resolved X-ray scattering and X-ray diffraction from monocrystalline diamond samples heated with an intense pulse of heavy ions. In this way, we determine the samples&#8217; heating dynamics and their microscopic and macroscopic structural integrity over a timespan of several microseconds. Connecting the ratio of elastic to inelastic scattering with state-of-the-art density functional theory molecular dynamics simulations allows the inference of average temperatures around 1300 K, in agreement with predictions from stopping power calculations. The simultaneous diffraction measurements show no hints of any volumetric graphitization of the material, but do indicate the onset of fracture in the diamond sample. Our experiments pave the way for future studies at the Facility for Antiproton and Ion Research, where a substantially increased intensity of the heavy ion beam will be available.</description>
      <author>J. L&#252;tgert, P. Hesselbach, Maximilian Sch&#246;rner, V. Bagnoud, R.P. Belikov, P. Drechsel, Benedikt Heuser, Oliver Humphries, Peter Katr&#237;k, Bj&#248;rn Lindqvist, Chongbing Qu, R. Redmer, D. Riley, G. Schaumann, S. Schumacher, A. Tauschwitz, D. Varentsov, K. Weyrich, Xiaomei Yu, B. Zielbauer, Zs. Major, P. Neumayer, D. Kraus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0203005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approaches to Construct High-Performance Mg&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-57012-4_20</link>
      <description>Hao Liang, Wenhui Yao, Wenbo Du, Hao Liang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399586187

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Liang, Wenhui Yao, Wenbo Du, Hao Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-57012-4_20</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of anionic species on the low temperature pyrolysis performance of heated tobacco sheets catalyzed by sodium salts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1425244</link>
      <description>Xuebin Zhao, Qiuling Wang, Dan Ai, Haiying Tian, Zhan Zhang, Ke Cao, Yixuan Wang, Wei Qi, Bo Li, Yapeng Niu, Lingchuang Meng, Beibei Gao, Bin Li, Frontiers in chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399594316

                Development of low temperature catalytic pyrolysis technology for heated tobacco sheets is expected to increase the aroma of heated tobacco products and improve their overall smoking quality. In this study, the low temperature pyrolysis performances of heated tobacco sheets catalyzed by various anionic sodium salts were investigated using TG-DTG, Py-GC-MS technology and smoke routine chemical composition analysis. The results showed that the total weight loss between 100&#176;C and 300&#176;C increased by 7.8%&#8211;13.15% after adding various anionic sodium salts, among which, sodium acetate and sodium tartrate showed a relatively higher weight loss. The relative content of free hydroxyacetone, furfuryl alcohol, butyrolactone and megastigmatrienone in the pyrolysis gas increased, while the relative content of free nicotine decreased. With the change of anionic species, the catalytic decomposition ability of cellulose, lignin, and other substances may change, resulting in the distribution alteration of compounds in the pyrolysis gas. After adding sodium acetate and sodium citrate, the release of total particulate matter (TPM), glycerol, and nicotine in flue gas increased. Overall, the addition of sodium acetate and sodium citrate showed a higher low temperature pyrolysis performance of heated tobacco sheets. The research results in this paper provide data support for changing the low temperature catalytic pyrolysis performance of heated tobacco sheets by adjusting the type of anions in sodium salts.</description>
      <author>Xuebin Zhao, Qiuling Wang, Dan Ai, Haiying Tian, Zhan Zhang, Ke Cao, Yixuan Wang, Wei Qi, Bo Li, Yapeng Niu, Lingchuang Meng, Beibei Gao, Bin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1425244</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
