<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 01:06:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Biologically templated formation of Cobalt-Phosphide-Graphene hybrids with charge redistribution for efficient hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.047</link>
      <description>Xingchen Zhou, Lanqian Gong, Chen Wu, Yanfang Peng, Bin Cao, Huan Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Xueliang Jiang, Bao Yu Xia, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760234

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingchen Zhou, Lanqian Gong, Chen Wu, Yanfang Peng, Bin Cao, Huan Yang, Daoxiong Wu, Xueliang Jiang, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical research on efficient electrocatalysis of CO2 reduction reaction by borophene loaded transition metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104454</link>
      <description>Meiling Liu, Rao Fu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meiling Liu, Rao Fu, Jayaraman Balamurugan, Tongxiang Liang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Active Sites In Situ Formed in Metal Nanoparticle Reshaping under Reaction Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00088</link>
      <description>Xiao Yan Li, Pengfei Ou, Xinyi Duan, Ying Liu, Jun Meng, Beien Zhu, Yi Gao, JACS Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396764064

                Understanding the nonequilibrium transformation of nanocatalysts under reaction conditions is important because metastable atomic structures may be created during the process, which offers unique activities in reactions. Although reshaping of metal nanoparticles (NPs) under reaction conditions has been widely recognized, the dynamic reshaping process has been less studied at the atomic scale. Here, we develop an atomistic kinetic Monte Carlo model to simulate the complete reshaping process of Pt nanoparticles in a CO environment and reveal the in situ formation of atomic clusters on the NP surface, a new type of active site beyond conventional understanding, boosting the reactivities in the CO oxidation reaction. Interestingly, highly active peninsula and inactive island clusters both form on the (111) facets and interchange in varying states of dynamic equilibrium, which influences the catalytic activities significantly. This study provides new fundamental knowledge of nanocatalysis and new guidance for the rational design of nanocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiao Yan Li, Pengfei Ou, Xinyi Duan, Ying Liu, Jun Meng, Beien Zhu, Yi Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.4c00088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Co3O4-Based Hybrid Structures for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-024-00183-5</link>
      <description>Ha Huu, Quyet Van Le, Hai Bang Truong, Korean journal of chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396765408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ha Huu, Quyet Van Le, Hai Bang Truong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11814-024-00183-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Gold Precipitation by a Tertiary Diamide Driven by Thermodynamic Control</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01279</link>
      <description>Susanna S. M. Vance, Mateusz Mojsak, Luke M. M. Kinsman, Rebecca Rae, Caroline Kirk, Jason B. Love, Carole A. Morrison, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396767472

                The simple diamide ligand</description>
      <author>Susanna S. M. Vance, Mateusz Mojsak, Luke M. M. Kinsman, Rebecca Rae, Caroline Kirk, Jason B. Love, Carole A. Morrison</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming poisoning issues in hydrogen fuel cells with face-centered tetragonal FePt bimetallic catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.04.036</link>
      <description>Daeil Choi, Injoon Jang, Taekyung Lee, Yun Sik Kang, Sung Jong Yoo, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396767948

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daeil Choi, Injoon Jang, Taekyung Lee, Yun Sik Kang, Sung Jong Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.04.036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ion Exchange in Metal-Organic Frameworks and Their Derivatives: A Facile Strategy for Enhanced Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101595</link>
      <description>Haoran Li, Xin Li, Dai Jiayan, Shiyou Zheng, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396768176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoran Li, Xin Li, Dai Jiayan, Shiyou Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas-Phase Production of Hydroxylated Silicon Oxide Cluster Cations: Structure, Infrared Spectroscopy, and Astronomical Relevance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsearthspacechem.3c00346</link>
      <description>Andrea Donato, Bianca-Andreea Ghejan, Joost M. Bakker, Thorsten M. Bernhardt, Stefan T. Bromley, Sandra M. Lang, ACS earth and space chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396773745

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andrea Donato, Bianca-Andreea Ghejan, Joost M. Bakker, Thorsten M. Bernhardt, Stefan T. Bromley, Sandra M. Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsearthspacechem.3c00346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physical Prior Mean Function-Driven Gaussian Processes Search for Minimum-Energy Reaction Paths with a Climbing-Image Nudged Elastic Band: A General Method for Gas-Phase, Interfacial, and Bulk-Phase Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00291</link>
      <description>Chong Teng, Yan Wang, Junwei Lucas Bao, Journal of chemical theory and computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396773889

                The climbing-image nudged elastic band (CI-NEB) method serves as an indispensable tool for computational chemists, offering insight into minimum-energy reaction paths (MEPs) by delineating both transition states (TSs) and intermediate nonstationary structures along reaction coordinates. However, executing CI-NEB calculations for reactions with extensive reaction coordinate spans necessitates a large number of images to ensure a reliable convergence of the MEPs and TS structures, presenting a computationally demanding optimization challenge, even with mildly costly electronic-structure methods. In this study, we advocate for the utilization of physically inspired prior mean function-based Gaussian processes (GPs) to expedite MEP exploration and TS optimization via the CI-NEB method. By incorporating reliable prior physical approximations into potential energy surface (PES) modeling, we demonstrate enhanced efficiency in multidimensional CI-NEB optimization with surrogate-based optimizers. Our physically informed GP approach not only outperforms traditional nonsurrogate-based optimizers in optimization efficiency but also on-the-fly learns the reaction path valley during optimization, culminating in significant advancements. The surrogate PES derived from our optimization exhibits high accuracy compared to true PES references, aligning with our emphasis on leveraging reliable physical priors for robust and efficient posterior mean learning in GPs. Through a systematic benchmark study encompassing various reaction pathways, including gas-phase, bulk-phase, and interfacial/surface reactions, our physical GPs consistently demonstrate superior efficiency and reliability. For instance, they outperform the popular fast inertial relaxation engine optimizer by approximately a factor of 10, showcasing their versatility and efficacy in exploring reaction mechanisms and surface reaction PESs.</description>
      <author>Chong Teng, Yan Wang, Junwei Lucas Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Insights on Structural Sensitivity of Cobalt in NO Electroreduction to Ammonia and Hydroxylamine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01986</link>
      <description>Pengran Guo, Dong Luan, Huan Li, Lin Liu, Shaoxue Yang, Jianping Xiao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780897

                It has been reported that it was selective to produce ammonia on metallic cobalt in the electrocatalytic nitric oxide reduction reaction (eNORR), where hexagonal close-packed (hcp) cobalt outperforms face-centered cubic (fcc) cobalt. However, hydroxylamine is more selectively produced on a cobalt single-atom catalyst (Co-SAC). Herein, we uncover the structural sensitivity over hcp-Co, fcc-Co, and Co-SAC in eNORR by employing a recently developed constant potential simulation method and microkinetic modeling. It was found that the superior activity for ammonia production on hcp-Co can be attributed to its facile electron and proton transfer and a stronger lateral suppression effect from NO* over fcc-Co. The exceptional hydroxylamine selectivity on Co-SAC is due to the modified electronic structure, namely, a positively charged active center. It was found that it is more favorable to produce NOH* over hcp-Co and fcc-Co, while HNO* is more preferable on Co-SAC, which are firmly correlated with the vertical and strong NO adsorption on the former and the moderate adsorption on the latter. In other words, a key factor for selectivity control is the first step of NO* protonation. Therefore, the local structure and electronic structure of the catalysts can be critical in regulating the activity and selectivity in eNORR.</description>
      <author>Pengran Guo, Dong Luan, Huan Li, Lin Liu, Shaoxue Yang, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in tandem electrocatalysis of carbon dioxide: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114516</link>
      <description>Jiateng Chen, Liang Xu, Boxiong Shen, Renewable &amp; sustainable energy reviews. 199(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396785483

                The attainment of carbon neutrality has become a global consensus as a result of the increasing environmental problems caused by the consumption of fossil fuels. To achieve this objective, there has been widespread attention towards the electrocatalytic reduction reaction of carbon dioxide driven by renewable energy sources due to its mild reaction conditions. In recent years, generating high value-added multicarbon products has been the focus of considerable research efforts. However, the process of generating these products has been restricted by the complexity of the reaction path, the limitations of the scaling relationship, and the poor adaptability to the reaction environment, thereby impeding previous studies from achieving efficient conversion at high current densities. As a result, a more suitable catalyst design strategy is required to obtain high value-added products. This study proposes that the design approach of tandem catalysis will be effective in generating multicarbon products by exploring the mechanism of C&#8211;C bond coupling and the configuration of the reaction environment. This research summaries the mechanism and design requirements of tandem catalysis scaled by different intermediates transport distances and review strategies of tandem catalyst configurations, such as nanostructures, phase-mixed, phase-separated, and application of special supports, in facilitating the generation of multicarbon products. The study provides suggestions for the design of CO2 electrocatalytic tandem catalysts and conclude with a discussion of possible future directions.</description>
      <author>Jiateng Chen, Liang Xu, Boxiong Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of chalcogen doping in Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts for hydrogen-air polymer electrolyte fuel cells: Selenium doped Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234612</link>
      <description>S&#322;awomir Dyjak, Wojciech Tokarz, A. B&#322;achowski, Mateusz Gratzke, Barbara Szcz&#281;&#347;niak, Kamil Sobczak, Wojciech Kici&#324;ski, Journal of power sources. 609(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396791589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S&#322;awomir Dyjak, Wojciech Tokarz, A. B&#322;achowski, Mateusz Gratzke, Barbara Szcz&#281;&#347;niak, Kamil Sobczak, Wojciech Kici&#324;ski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ion solvation free energy calculations based on first-principles molecular dynamics thermodynamic integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0191068</link>
      <description>Chao Lin, Xiaojun He, Cong Xi, Qianfan Zhang, Lin&#8208;Wang Wang, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803459

                Numerous electrochemistry reactions require the precise calculation of the ion solvation energy. Despite the significant progress in the first-principles calculations for crystals and defect formation energies for solids, the liquid system free energy calculations still face many challenges. Ion solvation free energies can be calculated via different semiempirical ways, e.g., using implicit solvent models or cluster of explicit molecule models; however, systematically improving these models is difficult due to their lack of a solid theoretical base. A theoretically sound approach for calculating the free energy is to use thermodynamic integration. Nevertheless, owing to the difficulties of self-consistent convergence in first-principles calculations for unphysical atomic configurations, the computational alchemy approach has not been widely used for first-principles calculations. This study proposes a general approach to use first-principles computational alchemy for calculating the ion solvation energy. This approach is also applicable for other small molecules. The calculated ion solvation free energies for Li+, Na+, K+, Be2+, Mg2+, and Ca2+ are close to the experimental results, and the standard deviation due to molecular dynamics fluctuations is within 0.06 eV.</description>
      <author>Chao Lin, Xiaojun He, Cong Xi, Qianfan Zhang, Lin&#8208;Wang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0191068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe Based Mof Encapsulating [Co(En)3]3+ to Prepare Fen3-Con3 Dual-Atom Catalyst for Efficient Orr in Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823403</link>
      <description>Xiaopeng Zhang, Cheng Gao, Longzhu Li, Xiaoming Yan, Ning Zhang, Junjiang Bao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaopeng Zhang, Cheng Gao, Longzhu Li, Xiaoming Yan, Ning Zhang, Junjiang Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Via Partial Oxidation of Re Through Co Modification in Nanoalloy Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823406</link>
      <description>An Jiang, Chao Chen, Jiwen Feng, Qiang Li, Wei Liu, Mingdong Dong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396804020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>An Jiang, Chao Chen, Jiwen Feng, Qiang Li, Wei Liu, Mingdong Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic exploration of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</link>
      <description>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng, Computational and theoretical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396807019

                The reaction rate of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an important factor restricting its application. In this work, we have systematic explorated of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for ORR and OER. Firstly, a variety of stability analysis methods show that most of the catalysts have excellent stability. Secondly, a series of excellent bifunctional catalysts are screened by volcanic maps, ORR overpotential (&#951;ORR), OER overpotential (&#951;OER), and bifunctional index (BI), such as, RhN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.28 V, &#951;OER = 0.34 V, BI = 0.62 V) and CoN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.33 V, &#951;OER = 0.37 V, BI = 0.70 V). In particular, RhN3O1-1 has the smallest BI value, indicating that it has the best bifunctional catalytic activity. This study offers insights into how the coordination environment affects the activity of OER/ORR.</description>
      <author>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Nanoparticles Supported on P-Doped Tungsten Nitride Nanosheets as Catalysts for Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01135</link>
      <description>Shuqin Liang, Pengyuan Wang, Meizan Jing, Huashuai Hu, Shaohong Zhang, Zifan Cang, Youpeng Zhao, H. Gong, Jian Liu, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396829656

                Electrochemical water decomposition is a promising alternative to hydrogen production (HER), but it is significantly limited by the scarcity of precious metals. Here, we propose a highly efficient yet low-cost phosphorus-modified nickel/tungsten nitride (P-Ni/WN) electrocatalyst, which exhibits excellent HER performance with a low overpotential (45 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2) and a high exchange current density (2.02 mA cm&#8211;2). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations and experiments reveal that the introduction of P and Ni attracts electrons from W species, making WN more conducive to the HER reaction. Moreover, the P doping contributes to the dispersion of Ni nanoparticles on the WN support, thereby enhancing the HER performance of the P-Ni/WN catalyst. This work provides a facile approach to improve the electrocatalytic activity of nickel-based catalysts in the context of the HER.</description>
      <author>Shuqin Liang, Pengyuan Wang, Meizan Jing, Huashuai Hu, Shaohong Zhang, Zifan Cang, Youpeng Zhao, H. Gong, Jian Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the pH-Dependent Catalytic Activity for the Layered Li&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;CoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00413</link>
      <description>Huiyan Zeng, Jiajun Chen, Chao Wang, Jun Qi, Zhongfei Liu, Mengxian Li, Long Gu, Jian Wen Wang, Enna Hong, Yan Zhang, Jin Xu, Chunzhen Yang, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830301

                Many highly active catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) demonstrate strong pH-dependent catalytic activities. However, the exact mechanism behind this phenomenon is still a subject of debate. In this study, delithiated Li0.5CoO2 is utilized as a model catalyst due to its tunable chemical states and layered structure that can facilitate reversible intercalation and deintercalation of cations. By increasing the pH to 14 using a 1.0 M CsOH solution, rapid intercalation of Cs+ cations and water molecules induce notable lattice expansion up to 9.9 &#197;, resulting in an order of magnitude higher OER intrinsic activity comparing to that in 0.1 M CsOH. It is hypothesized that lattice water in layered structure facilitates the dynamic intercalation and deintercalation of Cs+ cations, promoting the so-called "electrochemical-chemical" reaction mechanism. These findings provide valuable insights into the intricate nature of surface dynamics and the redox chemistry on the catalyst/electrolyte interface during the OER.</description>
      <author>Huiyan Zeng, Jiajun Chen, Chao Wang, Jun Qi, Zhongfei Liu, Mengxian Li, Long Gu, Jian Wen Wang, Enna Hong, Yan Zhang, Jin Xu, Chunzhen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time&#8208;Resolved Oxidation State Changes Are Key to Elucidating the Bifunctionality of Perovskite Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12737</link>
      <description>Casey E. Beall, Emiliana Fabbri, Adam H. Clark, Vivian Meier, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Dino Aegerter, Thomas Graule, Thomas Schmidt, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831905

                In a unified regenerative fuel cell (URFC) or reversible fuel cell, the oxygen bifunctional catalyst must switch reversibly between the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), fuel cell mode, and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), electrolyzer mode. However, it is often unclear what effect alternating between ORR and OER has on the electrochemical behavior and physiochemical properties of the catalyst. Herein, operando X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) is utilized to monitor the continuous and dynamic evolution of the Co, Mn, and Fe oxidation states of perovskite catalysts Ba 0.5 Sr 0.5 Co 0.8 Fe 0.2 O 3&#8208;&#948; (BSCF) and La 0.4 Sr 0.6 MnO 3&#8208;&#948; (LSM), while the potential is oscillated between reducing and oxidizing potentials with cyclic voltammetry. The results reveal the importance of investigating bifunctional catalysts by alternating between fuel cell and electrolyzer operation and highlight the limitations and challenges of bifunctional catalysts. It is shown that the requirements for ORR and OER performance are divergent and that the oxidative potentials of OER are detrimental to ORR activity. These findings are used to give guidelines for future bifunctional catalyst design. Additionally, it is demonstrated how sunlight can be used to reactivate the ORR activity of LSM after rigorous cycling.</description>
      <author>Casey E. Beall, Emiliana Fabbri, Adam H. Clark, Vivian Meier, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Dino Aegerter, Thomas Graule, Thomas Schmidt</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#28023;&#32966;&#29366;CoTe-CoP&#24322;&#36136;&#32467;&#26500;&#20652;&#21270;&#21058;&#22312;&#20840;pH&#33539;&#22260;&#20869;&#39640;&#25928;&#26512;&#27682;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2820-0</link>
      <description>Shengli Zhu, Minghui Xing, Zhe L&#252;, Zelong Qiao, Shitao Wang, Qianchuan Zhao, Yu Zhang, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao, Science China. Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834143

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengli Zhu, Minghui Xing, Zhe L&#252;, Zelong Qiao, Shitao Wang, Qianchuan Zhao, Yu Zhang, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2820-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous enhanced photocatalytic overall water splitting on AlO/WSi2N4 vdW heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160247</link>
      <description>C. H. Li, Liang Xu, Zehua Jin, Qiongchao Wang, Bin Xiao, Zhengquan Li, Lingling Wang, Kun Dong, Tong Chen, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834524

                Completely achieving spontaneous water splitting without sacrificing co-catalysts poses a significant challenge, as factors such as electrical, optical, and catalytic activity can limit the conversion efficiency of solar energy to hydrogen. Herein, we propose a type-II van der Waals heterostructure composed of vertically stacked AlO and WSi2N4, and systematically investigate its mechanism and potential for catalyzing water splitting. Photon-induced photocatalytic water splitting takes advantage of the staggered energy bands of the heterojunction, effectively promoting the separation of photogenerated carriers and thus enhancing catalytic efficiency. In neutral water environment, the band edge position of AlO/WSi2N4 aligns with the redox potential required for water decomposition. Thermodynamic analysis of the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions indicates that the external potential provided by photogenerated carriers is expected to trigger spontaneous water decomposition. Moreover, with its high electron mobility (4800.62 cm2/Vs) and a solar-to-hydrogen energy conversion efficiency of up to 19.98 %, the AlO/WSi2N4 heterojunction demonstrates substantial potential as a photoelectric catalyst. This research introduces a promising avenue for efficient photocatalytic production of clean energy.</description>
      <author>C. H. Li, Liang Xu, Zehua Jin, Qiongchao Wang, Bin Xiao, Zhengquan Li, Lingling Wang, Kun Dong, Tong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of transition metal atom-doped NiSe2 electrocatalysts for efficient alkaline hydrogen precipitation using first principles screening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141324</link>
      <description>Yangyang Xu, Yiwei Zhao, Yuanjiang Lv, Xinmeng Er, Mingxia Liu, Fei Ma, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834534

                Transition metal (TM) doping exhibits great potential in designing high-performance two-dimensional (2D) NiSe2-based catalysts for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). 22 TM atom-doped 2D-NiSe2 catalysts are screened, and the effects of TM doping on the thermal stability and HER catalytic activity are investigated by first-principles calculations. Among them, Cu doped 2D-NiSe2 might exhibit remarkable HER properties with the water dissociation energy of 1.03 eV and H adsorption Gibbs free energy of &#8722;0.05 eV. Furthermore, we elucidate the reasons behind the different HER activities. These findings suggest new possibilities for the application of Cu doped 2D-NiSe2 for alkaline HER, offering new perspectives for future research.</description>
      <author>Yangyang Xu, Yiwei Zhao, Yuanjiang Lv, Xinmeng Er, Mingxia Liu, Fei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Hydrogen Passivation Effects in TiC-Based Single-Atom Catalysts for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00550</link>
      <description>Seong Chan Cho, Chi Ho Lee, Sang Uck Lee, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834660

                The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is crucial for producing hydrogen gas via electrochemical water splitting. Among diverse strategies to activate the HER, single-atom catalysts (SACs) are efficient alternatives to conventional platinum catalysts, focusing on titanium carbide (TiC) as a support material with good redox and electronic stability. Using this, we conducted a comprehensive investigation of various SAC candidates, screening their thermodynamic stabilities and HER activities. These calculations revealed four possible transition metal (TM) (Pt, Pd, Au, and Ag)-embedded TiC candidates (TM@TiC) that are thermodynamically stable and further suggested that they exhibit an intriguing H*-passivated surface state, significantly improving HER activities. Notably, the Pt@TiC demonstrates superior activity, promoting H2 gas generation due to its unique H*-passivated surface, which enables a sustainable HER. Therefore, this work introduces a new SAC paradigm centered around the H*-passivated surface, expanding the conventional focus on a single TM site.</description>
      <author>Seong Chan Cho, Chi Ho Lee, Sang Uck Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperation between single atom catalyst and support to promote nitrogen electroreduction to ammonia: A theoretical insight</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.002</link>
      <description>Wei Guo, Siyao Wang, Hongxia Wang, Qinghai Cai, Jingxiang Zhao, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835133

                The co-catalysis between single atom catalyst (SAC) and its support has recently emerged as a promising strategy to synergistically boost the catalytic activity of some complex electrochemical reactions, encompassing multiple intermediates and pathways. Herein, we utilized defective BC3 monolayer-supported SACs as a prototype to investigate the cooperative effects of SACs and their support on the catalytic performance of the nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) for ammonia (NH3) production. The results showed that these SACs can be firmly stabilized on these defective BC3 supports with high stability against aggregation. Furthermore, co-activation of the inert N2 reactant was observed in certain embedded SACs and their neighboring B atoms on the certain BC3 sheets due to the noticeable charge transfer and significant N&#8211;N bond elongation. Our high-throughput screening revealed that the Mo/DVCC and W/DVCC exhibit superior NRR catalytic performance, characterized by a low limiting potential of &#8722;0.33 and &#8722;0.43V, respectively, which can be further increased under acid conditions based on the constant potential method. Moreover, varying NRR catalytic activities can be attributed to the differences in the valence state of active sites. Remarkably, further microkinetic modeling analysis displayed that the turnover frequency of N2&#8211;to&#8211;NH3 conversion on Mo/DVCC is as large as 1.20 &#215; 10&#8722;3 s&#8722;1 site&#8722;1 at 700 K and 100 bar, thus guaranteeing its ultra-fast reaction rate. Our results not only suggest promising advanced electrocatalysts for NRR, but also offered an effective avenue to regulate the electrocatalytic performance via the co-catalytic metal&#8211;support interactions.</description>
      <author>Wei Guo, Siyao Wang, Hongxia Wang, Qinghai Cai, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretical Benchmark of the Geometric and Optical Properties for 3d Transition Metal Nanoclusters via Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00408</link>
      <description>Shana Havenridge, Cong Liu, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A/&#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry. A.. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835391

                Understanding structure&#8211;property relationships in atomically precise metal nanoclusters is vital in finding selective and tunable catalysts. In this study, density functional theory (DFT) was used to benchmark seven exchange correlation functionals at different basis sets for 17 atomically precise nanoclusters against experimentally determined geometries, band gaps, and optical gaps. The set contains both monometallic and bimetallic clusters that possess at least two types of 3d transition metals (specifically, Cu, Ni, Fe, or Co). The benchmark highlights that PBE0 is a good functional to use regardless of the basis set, and Minnesota functionals do well with respect to specific metals. Further, while long-range corrected functionals overestimate band and optical gaps, they model absorption features better than the other considered functionals. The study additionally looks at the photoinduced hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the CO2 reduction mechanism on nanoclusters reported from the literature.</description>
      <author>Shana Havenridge, Cong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Capture With Mixed-Matrix Membrane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-93940-9.00269-3</link>
      <description>Hojatollah Vali, Arash Sadeghi, Mohammad Javad Shafiee, M Barzegar, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396838798

                One promising technology for carbon capture is mixed-matrix membrane (MMM) technology. MMMs are composite materials that combine a polymer matrix with inorganic fillers or nanoparticles to enhance the separation performance of the membrane. These membranes offer several advantages, including high selectivity, tunable permeability, and resistance to harsh operating conditions. The incorporation of inorganic fillers or nanoparticles into the polymer matrix improves the separation properties of the membrane by creating a tortuous path for gas molecules, increasing the surface area, and enhancing the interaction between the membrane and the gas molecules. This results in improved carbon dioxide capture efficiency and selectivity. MMM technology offers potential advantages over other carbon capture technologies. It has the potential for lower energy consumption compared to solvent-based absorption processes and can be easily integrated into existing gas separation systems. MMMs also have the advantage of being scalable and cost-effective, making them suitable for large-scale industrial applications. This chapter will delve deeper into the principles of carbon capture technologies, mixed-matrix membranes (MMMs), the materials used in MMMs, the strategies for improving MMMs, and the challenges associated with them.</description>
      <author>Hojatollah Vali, Arash Sadeghi, Mohammad Javad Shafiee, M Barzegar, Mohammad Reza Rahimpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-93940-9.00269-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Electrocatalysts Anchored on Phosphoniobic Acid (M&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;/PNb&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;40&lt;/sub&gt;) Cluster for Water Splitting (HER/OER) and Metal-Air Batteries (ORR)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00349</link>
      <description>Sajjad Hussain, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li, Zhansheng Lu, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396844986

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajjad Hussain, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li, Zhansheng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the First Activation Step of Electrochemical CO2 Reduction over Ag and Ni-N-C Active Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109728</link>
      <description>Yujie Wang, Jungho Kim, Hyun Dong Jung, Jun Liu, Ke Yao, Chuan Xia, Seoin Back, Kun Jiang, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396846502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Wang, Jungho Kim, Hyun Dong Jung, Jun Liu, Ke Yao, Chuan Xia, Seoin Back, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109728</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Hydrogenation of Carbon Dioxide as a Method to Produce Valuable Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s2070050424010045</link>
      <description>I. A. Makaryan, &#1048;. &#1042;. &#1057;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1057;&#1072;&#1074;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Catalysis in industry. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396852768

                No abstract</description>
      <author>I. A. Makaryan, &#1048;. &#1042;. &#1057;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1042;. &#1048;. &#1057;&#1072;&#1074;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s2070050424010045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peierls-like distortion drives anion ordering in rutile TiOF</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.054602</link>
      <description>S. Senthil Nathan, Danilo Puggioni, James M. Rondinelli, Physical review materials. 8(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Senthil Nathan, Danilo Puggioni, James M. Rondinelli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.054602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu Atomic Subnanoclusters on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01277</link>
      <description>Hanjun Zou, Yan Tong, Yajie Feng, Yongfeng Zhou, Jiaxun Xiao, Xia Lu, Anku Guha, B&#225;rbara B. Polesso, Bin Zhang, Juanli Liu, Kaiwen Wang, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857555

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hanjun Zou, Yan Tong, Yajie Feng, Yongfeng Zhou, Jiaxun Xiao, Xia Lu, Anku Guha, B&#225;rbara B. Polesso, Bin Zhang, Juanli Liu, Kaiwen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dewetting of Pt Nanoparticles Boosts Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Due to Electronic Metal&#8208;Support Interaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403628</link>
      <description>Shreyas Harsha, Rakesh Kumar Sharma, Martin Dierner, Christoph Baeumer, Igor A. Makhotkin, Guido Mul, Paolo Ghigna, Erdmann Spiecker, Johannes Will, Marco Altomare, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396860609

                Abstract Solid&#8208;state dewetting is the heat&#8208;induced agglomeration of thin metal films into defined nanoparticles (NPs). Dewetted Pt nanoparticles are investigated on F&#8208;doped SnO 2 (FTO) substrates as model binder&#8208;free electrodes for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Dewetting of Pt films into particles exposes the FTO substrate and the metal/support (Pt&#8208;FTO) contact line. Despite the decrease in Pt electrochemical surface area (ECSA) upon dewetting, dewetted NPs show a &gt;3&#8208;fold increase in ECSA&#8208;normalized HER activity compared to as&#8208;deposited nanocrystalline Pt films. Electrodes designed with dewetted Pt NPs of different sizes show that the HER activity does not only correlate with the ECSA but also increases with increasing the Pt&#8208;FTO contact line length. The smaller the NPs, the larger the Pt&#8208;FTO contact line, and the higher the activity. This effect is ascribed to electronic metal&#8208;support interaction (EMSI), due to electron transfer from FTO to Pt. It is proposed that EMSI effects alter the electronic structure of Pt sites near the Pt&#8208;FTO contact line, facilitating the H 2 evolution kinetics. When NPs are a few nm&#8208;sized, a large mass fraction of Pt is affected by EMSI, resulting in a further increase of HER activity compared to NPs &#8805;10 nm despite the lower ECSA.</description>
      <author>Shreyas Harsha, Rakesh Kumar Sharma, Martin Dierner, Christoph Baeumer, Igor A. Makhotkin, Guido Mul, Paolo Ghigna, Erdmann Spiecker, Johannes Will, Marco Altomare</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase segregation and nanoconfined fluid O2 in a lithium-rich oxide cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-024-01873-5</link>
      <description>Kit McColl, Samuel W. Coles, Pezhman Zarabadi&#8211;Poor, Benjamin J. Morgan, M. Sa&#239;ful Islam, Nature materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396862249

                Abstract Lithium-rich oxide cathodes lose energy density during cycling due to atomic disordering and nanoscale structural rearrangements, which are both challenging to characterize. Here we resolve the kinetics and thermodynamics of these processes in an exemplar layered Li-rich (Li 1.2&#8211; x Mn 0.8 O 2 ) cathode using a combined approach of ab initio molecular dynamics and cluster expansion-based Monte Carlo simulations. We identify a kinetically accessible and thermodynamically favourable mechanism to form O 2 molecules in the bulk, involving Mn migration and driven by interlayer oxygen dimerization. At the top of charge, the bulk structure locally phase segregates into MnO 2 -rich regions and Mn-deficient nanovoids, which contain O 2 molecules as a nanoconfined fluid. These nanovoids are connected in a percolating network, potentially allowing long-range oxygen transport and linking bulk O 2 formation to surface O 2 loss. These insights highlight the importance of developing strategies to kinetically stabilize the bulk structure of Li-rich O-redox cathodes to maintain their high energy densities.</description>
      <author>Kit McColl, Samuel W. Coles, Pezhman Zarabadi&#8211;Poor, Benjamin J. Morgan, M. Sa&#239;ful Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-024-01873-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of copper as a unique catalyst for C&#8211;C coupling in electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02056a</link>
      <description>Jie Chen, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Jia Zhang, Wei Chen, Yi&#8208;Yang Sun, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396863962

                Evolution of the molecular orbitals during CO&#8211;CO coupling on the Cu(100) surface and identification of the corresponding frontier molecular orbitals.</description>
      <author>Jie Chen, Benjamin W. J. Chen, Jia Zhang, Wei Chen, Yi&#8208;Yang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc02056a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into effect of dopant site and dopant concentration on structural, electronic and optical properties of GaNbO&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e1237" altimg="si56.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; and its implications on visible light photocatalytic behavior: An ab-initio study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cocom.2024.e00916</link>
      <description>Bhakti Kshirsagar, Ankosh D. Deshmukh, David Mascarenhas, Vaishali Shah, Computational condensed matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bhakti Kshirsagar, Ankosh D. Deshmukh, David Mascarenhas, Vaishali Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cocom.2024.e00916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Simulation, and Membrane Wetting Estimation in Gas&#8211;Liquid Contacting Processes Including Shell-Side Reaction: Biogas Upgrading Using DEA Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00525</link>
      <description>G. Pantoleontos, D. Koutsonikolas, Akrivi Asimakopoulou, &#931;&#959;&#965;&#950;&#940;&#957;&#945; &#923;&#959;&#961;&#941;&#957;&#964;&#950;&#959;&#965;, George Karagiannakis, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396771432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. Pantoleontos, D. Koutsonikolas, Akrivi Asimakopoulou, &#931;&#959;&#965;&#950;&#940;&#957;&#945; &#923;&#959;&#961;&#941;&#957;&#964;&#950;&#959;&#965;, George Karagiannakis</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering of polydisperse porous media for enhanced fluid flows through systematic topology tuning via differentiable direct numerical simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevfluids.9.054103</link>
      <description>Mohammed Alhashim, Michael P. Brenner, Physical review fluids. 9(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396813474

                Recent advancements in automatic differentiation, which played a pivotal role in deep learning, offer a promising approach to addressing challenges in controlling fluid flow behavior. We demonstrate the power of the method by optimizing the packing of a polydisperse system of periodically arranged circular rods to minimize the pressure drop across the media. We show how the optimum topology of the porous media changes with changing the packing fraction.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Alhashim, Michael P. Brenner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevfluids.9.054103</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
