<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:45:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Fine&#8208;tuning electronic structure of N&#8208;doped graphitic carbon&#8208;supported Co&#8208; and Fe&#8208;incorporated Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C to achieve ultrahigh electrochemical water oxidation activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.488</link>
      <description>Md. Selim Arif Sher Shah, Hyeonjung Jung, Vinod K. Paidi, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Jeong Woo Han, Jae Hyung Park, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392740367

                Abstract Mo 2 C is an excellent electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, Mo 2 C is a poor electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, two different elements, namely Co and Fe, are incorporated in Mo 2 C that, therefore, has a finely tuned electronic structure, which is not achievable by incorporation of any one of the metals. Consequently, the resulting electrocatalyst Co 0.8 Fe 0.2 &#8211;Mo 2 C&#8208;80 displayed excellent OER catalytic performance, which is evidenced by a low overpotential of 214.0 (and 246.5) mV to attain a current density of 10 (and 50) mA cm &#8722;2 , an ultralow Tafel slope of 38.4 mV dec &#8722;1 , and long&#8208;term stability in alkaline medium. Theoretical data demonstrates that Co 0.8 Fe 0.2 &#8211;Mo 2 C&#8208;80 requires the lowest overpotential (1.00 V) for OER and Co centers to be the active sites. The ultrahigh catalytic performance of the electrocatalyst is attributed to the excellent intrinsic catalytic activity due to high Brunauer&#8211;Emmett&#8211;Teller specific surface area, large electrochemically active surface area, small Tafel slope, and low charge&#8208;transfer resistance.</description>
      <author>Md. Selim Arif Sher Shah, Hyeonjung Jung, Vinod K. Paidi, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Jeong Woo Han, Jae Hyung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress of electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215758</link>
      <description>Yuping Chen, Chunyan Shang, Xin Xiao, Weihua Guo, Qiang Xu, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 508(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392743186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuping Chen, Chunyan Shang, Xin Xiao, Weihua Guo, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect engineering in two-dimensional Janus pentagonal noble metal sulfide MXY (M=Pd, Pt; X, Y S, Se, Te; X&#8800;Y) materials for highly efficient electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.338</link>
      <description>Jinbo Hao, Yirong Ma, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Chunyu Zhang, Ge Wu, Wen Chen, Yuanzi Li, Pengfei Lu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392743218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinbo Hao, Yirong Ma, Baonan Jia, Xinhui Zhang, Chunyu Zhang, Ge Wu, Wen Chen, Yuanzi Li, Pengfei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Sustainable Lattice Strains of Morphology-Tuned Nanowires in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00451</link>
      <description>Zhi Hui Kong, Zhi Peng Wu, Yazan Maswadeh, Gang Yu, Jorge Vargas, Dominic Caracciolo, Valeri Petkov, Shuang&#8208;Quan Zang, Tao Li, Shuangyin Wang, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392748981

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhi Hui Kong, Zhi Peng Wu, Yazan Maswadeh, Gang Yu, Jorge Vargas, Dominic Caracciolo, Valeri Petkov, Shuang&#8208;Quan Zang, Tao Li, Shuangyin Wang, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO Hydrogenation Promoted by Oxygen Atoms Adsorbed onto Cu(100)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00666</link>
      <description>Kaito Nagita, Kazuhide Kamiya, Shuji Nakanishi, Yoshisuke Hamamoto, Yoshitada Morikawa, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392752465

                The electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) on Cu-based catalysts is a promising method for converting anthropogenic CO2 to valuable chemical feedstocks and fuels. Although pure CO2 gas has been widely used as a reactant in CO2RR-related research, CO2 gas collected from the atmosphere inevitably includes some amount of various impurity gases in the actual application of this method. Among such impurities, O2 gas has high reactivity and can easily contaminate the reaction environment, thereby substantially affecting the reactivity of the CO2RR. Herein, we performed first-principles calculations for the CO2RR in the presence of O2 reduction reaction intermediates on the Cu(100) surface. Specifically, we calculated the reaction and activation free energies for the hydrogenation of adsorbed CO* to CHO* on a Cu(100) surface covered with O* or OH*. When the coverage of O* reached 25%, the initial state of CO hydrogenation became destabilized to a greater extent than the transition state, which decreased the reaction and activation free energies by 0.27 and 0.16 eV, respectively. The projected density of states analyses revealed that O* weakens the interaction between CO* and the Cu surface, whereas OH* less strongly affects CO hydrogenation.</description>
      <author>Kaito Nagita, Kazuhide Kamiya, Shuji Nakanishi, Yoshisuke Hamamoto, Yoshitada Morikawa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion-Limited Crystal Growth of Gallium Nitride Using Active Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.3c01504</link>
      <description>Xiangyu Chen, Nam Q. Le, Paulette Clancy, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392760776

                Gallium nitride (GaN) is an important semiconductor with properties that make it particularly suitable for high-temperature applications in power systems. Unfortunately, its crystalline synthesis involves an energy-intensive process requiring high temperatures and pressures. A new additive manufacturing process offers a lower-temperature alternative, but little is understood of the molecular-scale mechanisms that drive its crystallization from the melt. Traditional semiempirical force fields within a molecular dynamics (MD) simulation are typically unable to capture bond-making and -breaking, whereas ab initio MD, while more accurate, suffers from high computational expense. This paper uses a machine-learned force field based on the FLARE++ framework to mimic the liquid-phase epitaxy of GaN, simulating the diffusion of nitrogen atoms through liquid gallium to form GaN. We show that nitrogen diffusion through Ga is slow, and relatedly, there is a pronounced tendency for nitrogen to phase-segregate within liquid Ga. This leads to nitrogen being less available to react and form crystalline GaN. As a result, the predicted crystal growth at the melt/crystal interface is extremely slow, as seen experimentally. In this work, we demonstrate the potential of a MLFF to describe complex, multiphase behavior under different conditions. We also uncover the key atomistic-level mechanism of diffusion-limited GaN crystal growth, which is an important step toward further control of the additive manufacturing process.</description>
      <author>Xiangyu Chen, Nam Q. Le, Paulette Clancy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.3c01504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immobilizing Ultralow Loading Platinum Nanoparticles onto MXene through Defect Engineering to Enhance the Activity of the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03270</link>
      <description>Meng Xu, Jiahao Huang, Xin Yue, Shaoming Huang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763100

                Developing low-cost, highly active, and durable electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acidic medium is essential for achieving the large-scale utilization of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers. It has been demonstrated that non-precious-metal electrocatalysts are unable to substitute the most efficient platinum in a short period. Consequently, the fabrication of Pt-based heterogeneous electrocatalysts with ultralow loading and ultrahigh Pt utilization efficiency becomes a practical approach. Herein, an approach is reported to immobilize ultralow loading (&#8764;0.26 wt %) Pt NPs to Mo vacancies on the surface of Mo2Ti2C3Tx MXene. Because of the anchoring by Mo vacancies and the vast surface area of MXene, defect enriched Mo2Ti2C3Tx supported Pt nanoparticles (Pt NPs/d-Mo2Ti2C3Tx) possess ultrasmall particle sizes (&#8764;2.1 nm) and increased dispersity of Pt NPs. As a result, the as-prepared Pt NPs/d-Mo2Ti2C3Tx reaches a current density 100 mA cm&#8211;2 at an overpotential of 123 mV. When compared to Pt/C (20 wt %), the mass activity of Pt on Pt NPs/d-Mo2Ti2C3Tx is found to be 134 times higher. Meanwhile, it presents a high turnover frequency (8.49 H2 s&#8211;1 at overpotential of 50 mV) and fast kinetics (a Tafel slope of 30.1 mV dec&#8211;1) as well as high durability (maintaining the current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2 for more than 15 h). Theoretical simulations reveal that transferring electrons from Mo atoms regulated the d-band electronic structure of Pt NPs, resulting in a stronger interaction with adsorbed H species and ultimately boosting the HER activity.</description>
      <author>Meng Xu, Jiahao Huang, Xin Yue, Shaoming Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Spin-Valence States of Vanadium-Based Single-Atom Oxygen Reduction Catalysts through Substrate and Axial Ligand Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03756</link>
      <description>Jessie Manopo, Yudi Darma, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763690

                We study the effect of different carbon-based oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts on which atomically dispersed vanadium is anchored: graphene and graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4), by means of density functional theory. We found that different substrates and axial ligands modulate the spin and valence states of the vanadium metal center, thus modifying the catalytic activity. We observed that the magnetic moments of the metal center are related to the number of available electrons to be transferred from the catalyst to the adsorbate. The bare V-N4-graphene active site prefers a dissociative ORR mechanism due to strong binding between the vanadium metal center to oxygen-containing intermediates, and thus the OOH intermediate cannot be stably adsorbed. After the adsorption of the &#8211;OH ligand, the number of available electrons in the vanadium metal center is decreased, thus enhancing the ORR activity and shifting the ORR overpotential to 0.34 V, and the active site may prefer an associative mechanism. However, the magnetic moment of the catalysts is not the only factor affecting the adsorption behavior of the catalyst. Population analysis shows V-N4-graphene active site has the same number of available electrons in the d orbital of the vanadium metal center as the OH-V-g-C3N4. However, the V-N4-graphene active site exhibits stronger binding to oxygen-containing intermediates compared to OH-V-g-C3N4. We found that the valence states of the catalysts also affect the catalytic activity of the catalyst. The availability of an occupied dz2 orbital in the V-N4-graphene active site makes it have a stronger interaction with oxygen-containing intermediates compared to OH-V-g-C3N4. These combined effects lead to a spin-valence synergistic effect. These findings can pave the way to the design of better catalysts for efficient ORR in the future.</description>
      <author>Jessie Manopo, Yudi Darma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Inner- and Outer-Sphere Mechanistic Pathways of ORR on M&#8211;N&#8211;Cs with Pyrrolic MN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Motifs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00299</link>
      <description>Jian Liang Low, Christina Roth, Beate Paulus, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763821

                Metal- and nitrogen-doped carbon materials (M&#8211;N&#8211;Cs) have emerged as promising alternatives to costly platinum-group metals (PGMs) for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in renewable energy applications. Notably, there is increasing experimental and theoretical evidence supporting pyrrolic MN4 coordination over pyridinic MN4 in these materials, which aligns closer to the MN4 geometries found in nature. This study utilizes density functional theory (DFT) to elucidate the ability of each metal to catalyze various ORR mechanisms at the pyrrolic MN4 sites. Among the M&#8211;N&#8211;Cs of first&#8211;row transition metals, pyrrolic CrN4 and FeN4 exhibit exceptional 4e-ORR activity, promoting both inner- and outer-sphere mechanisms and H2O2 dissociation. Pyrrolic CoN4 is also promising for 2e-ORR catalysis due to its effective outer-sphere electron-transfer capabilities. These findings offer valuable insights for designing sustainable electrocatalysts to exploit the full potential of renewable energy sources, advancing the path toward carbon neutrality.</description>
      <author>Jian Liang Low, Christina Roth, Beate Paulus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structured Catalysts and Catalytic Processes: Transport and Reaction Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00081</link>
      <description>Pei Chen, Sai Chen, Donglong Fu, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763930

                The structure of catalysts determines the performance of catalytic processes. Intrinsically, the electronic and geometric structures influence the interaction between active species and the surface of the catalyst, which subsequently regulates the adsorption, reaction, and desorption behaviors. In recent decades, the development of catalysts with complex structures, including bulk, interfacial, encapsulated, and atomically dispersed structures, can potentially affect the electronic and geometric structures of catalysts and lead to further control of the transport and reaction of molecules. This review describes comprehensive understandings on the influence of electronic and geometric properties and complex catalyst structures on the performance of relevant heterogeneous catalytic processes, especially for the transport and reaction over structured catalysts for the conversions of light alkanes and small molecules. The recent research progress of the electronic and geometric properties over the active sites, specifically for theoretical descriptors developed in the recent decades, is discussed at the atomic level. The designs and properties of catalysts with specific structures are summarized. The transport phenomena and reactions over structured catalysts for the conversions of light alkanes and small molecules are analyzed. At the end of this review, we present our perspectives on the challenges for the further development of structured catalysts and heterogeneous catalytic processes.</description>
      <author>Pei Chen, Sai Chen, Donglong Fu, Zhi&#8208;Jian Zhao, Jinlong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.3c00081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Structural Optimization through Fingerprinting Space Integration on the Potential Energy Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00275</link>
      <description>Shuo Tao, Xuecheng Shao, Li Zhu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392763962

                Structural optimization has been a crucial component in computational materials research, and structure predictions have relied heavily on this technique, in particular. In this study, we introduce a novel method that enhances the efficiency of local optimization by integrating extra fingerprint space into the optimization process. Our approach utilizes a mixed energy concept in the hyper potential energy surface (PES), combining real energy and a newly introduced fingerprint energy derived from the symmetry of the local atomic environment. This method strategically guides the optimization process toward high-symmetry, low-energy structures by leveraging the intrinsic symmetry of the atomic configurations. The effectiveness of our approach was demonstrated through structural optimizations of silicon, silicon carbide, and Lennard-Jones cluster systems. Our results show that the fingerprint space biasing technique significantly enhances the performance and probability of discovering energetically favorable, high-symmetry structures as compared to conventional optimizations. The proposed method is anticipated to streamline the search for new materials and facilitate the discovery of novel energetically favorable configurations.</description>
      <author>Shuo Tao, Xuecheng Shao, Li Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare earth modified carbon-based catalysts for oxygen electrode reactions: A machine learning assisted density functional theory investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119045</link>
      <description>Qiming Fu, Tao Xu, Daomiao Wang, Chao Liu, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392768636

                The oxygen electrode reactions (oxygen reduction reaction, ORR and oxygen evolution reaction, OER) are two key reactions in applications such as metal-air batteries, however, slow kinetics have a significant impact on the overall reaction efficiency of the batteries, thus emphasizing the profound significance of catalyst development. In this study, we systematically investigated the catalytic activity of rare-earth-doped graphene (RENxC4-x) as electrocatalysts using a combination of density functional theory (DFT) and machine learning (ML). Furthermore, we successfully screened and identified one ORR catalyst, four OER catalysts, and one bifunctional electrocatalyst from candidate materials. The origins of activity were elucidated in two dimensions using the SHAP (SHapley Additive exPlanation) analysis framework and DFT calculations, revealing that atomic/covalent radius and &#916;G*OH are an important characteristics for describing ORR electrocatalysts, while Pauling electronegativity is crucial for describing OER. Finally, the explicit relationship expression between properties and activity was obtained using the SISSO method, and its generalizability was verified. The interdisciplinary approach of DFT-ML provides insights into the complex origins of activity, offering a new pathway for the discovery and design of high-performance single-atom catalysts (SACs).</description>
      <author>Qiming Fu, Tao Xu, Daomiao Wang, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119045</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting chemisorption strength with AutoML-based feature deletion experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2320232121</link>
      <description>Zhuo Li, Chenguang Zhao, Hai-Kun Wang, Yanqing Ding, Y Chen, Philippe Schwaller, Kai Yang, Hua Cheng, Yulian He, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392779374

                The chemisorption energy of reactants on a catalyst surface,   E  ads    , is among the most informative characteristics of understanding and pinpointing the optimal catalyst. The intrinsic complexity of catalyst surfaces and chemisorption reactions presents significant difficulties in identifying the pivotal physical quantities determining   E  ads    . In response to this, the study proposes a methodology, the feature deletion experiment, based on Automatic Machine Learning (AutoML) for knowledge extraction from a high-throughput density functional theory (DFT) database. The study reveals that, for binary alloy surfaces, the local adsorption site geometric information is the primary physical quantity determining   E  ads    , compared to the electronic and physiochemical properties of the catalyst alloys. By integrating the feature deletion experiment with instance-wise variable selection (INVASE), a neural network-based explainable AI (XAI) tool, we established the best-performing feature set containing 21 intrinsic, non-DFT computed properties, achieving an MAE of 0.23 eV across a periodic table-wide chemical space involving more than 1,600 types of alloys surfaces and 8,400 chemisorption reactions. This study demonstrates the stability, consistency, and potential of AutoML-based feature deletion experiment in developing concise, predictive, and theoretically meaningful models for complex chemical problems with minimal human intervention.</description>
      <author>Zhuo Li, Chenguang Zhao, Hai-Kun Wang, Yanqing Ding, Y Chen, Philippe Schwaller, Kai Yang, Hua Cheng, Yulian He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2320232121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDEP: Temperature Dependent Effective Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.06150</link>
      <description>Florian Knoop, Nina Shulumba, Alo&#239;s Castellano, Jos&#233; Batista, Roberta Farris, Matthieu J. Verstraete, Matthew Heine, David Broido, Dennis Kim, Johan Klarbring, Igor A. Abrikosov, Sergei I. Simak, Olle Hellman, Journal of open source software. 9(94)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392787419

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Florian Knoop, Nina Shulumba, Alo&#239;s Castellano, Jos&#233; Batista, Roberta Farris, Matthieu J. Verstraete, Matthew Heine, David Broido, Dennis Kim, Johan Klarbring, Igor A. Abrikosov, Sergei I. Simak, Olle Hellman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.06150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional materials by large-scale computations and chemical exfoliation of layered solids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adj6556</link>
      <description>Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Jie Zhou, Per Persson, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Science. 383(6688)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392797038

                MXenes are a family of two-dimensional (2D) materials typically formed by etching the A element from a parent MAX phase. Computational screening for other 3D precursors suitable for such exfoliation is challenging because of the intricate chemical processes involved. We present a theoretical approach for predicting 2D materials formed through chemical exfoliation under acidic conditions by identifying 3D materials amenable for selective etching. From a dataset of 66,643 3D materials, we identified 119 potentially exfoliable candidates, within several materials families. To corroborate the method, we chose a material distinctly different from MAX phases, in terms of structure and chemical composition, for experimental verification. We selectively etched Y from YRu 2 Si 2 , resulting in 2D Ru 2 Si x O y . The high-throughput methodology suggests a vast chemical space of 2D materials from chemical exfoliation.</description>
      <author>Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Jie Zhou, Per Persson, Johanna Ros&#233;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adj6556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consecutive Reduction of Five Carbon Dioxide Molecules by Gas-Phase Niobium Carbide Cluster Anions Nb&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt;: Unusual Mechanism for Enhanced Reactivity by the Carbon Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00371</link>
      <description>Yiheng Zhang, Jia-Bi Ma, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392799839

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiheng Zhang, Jia-Bi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c00371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal evaporation-driven fabrication of Ru/RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles onto nickel foam for efficient overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr06204j</link>
      <description>Yan Huang, Qi Zheng, Han Xu, Yingxin Liu, Wei Zhang, Xueqin Cao, Yongyong Cao, Jian&#8208;Ping Lang, Hongwei Gu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392804222

                A self-supported substrate material of Ru/NF could be obtained by a two-stage metal&#8211;organic thermal evaporation strategy. The synergistic effect between Ru and RuO 2 species greatly promotes water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yan Huang, Qi Zheng, Han Xu, Yingxin Liu, Wei Zhang, Xueqin Cao, Yongyong Cao, Jian&#8208;Ping Lang, Hongwei Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr06204j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of hydrogen binding energy via oxygen vacancy enables an efficient trifunctional Rh-Rh2O3 electrocatalyst for fuel cells and water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.095</link>
      <description>Jie Gao, Wanqing Yu, Jing Liu, Qin Liu, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Xuejing Cui, Luhua Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392815895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Gao, Wanqing Yu, Jing Liu, Qin Liu, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Xuejing Cui, Luhua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-Center Tight-Binding Together with Multipolar Auxiliary Functions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00018</link>
      <description>Matthias Van den Bossche, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392818035

                We present an ab initio tight-binding method that allows to improve on the effective potential and minimal basis approximations employed in semiempirical calculations. Three-center expansions are used to evaluate the zeroth-order Hamiltonian matrix elements and repulsive energy terms in the spirit of the Horsfield method. Self-consistency is handled by expanding atomic orbital products in an auxiliary basis following the work of Giese and York, combined with a two-center expansion of the exchange&#8211;correlation kernels. Together with nonminimal main basis sets (double-&#950; plus polarization), we show that the resulting method trades a modest amount of accuracy for a significant gain in speed, compared to that of numerical atomic orbital density functional theory, in calculations on small molecules, bulk compounds, and metal nanoclusters.</description>
      <author>Matthias Van den Bossche</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring optimal total metal loading of Ni3Fe/Al2O3 catalyst for CO2 methanation and its kinetic model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131447</link>
      <description>Jitendra Kumar Prabhakar, Pankaj A. Apte, Goutam Deo, Fuel. 367(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392826876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jitendra Kumar Prabhakar, Pankaj A. Apte, Goutam Deo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Chemical Environment Dependent Nitrate-Reduction-to-Ammonia Performance on Cu-Based Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03462</link>
      <description>Tao Hu, Mengting Wang, Ling Ren, Chang Ming Li, Chunxian Guo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392845760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Hu, Mengting Wang, Ling Ren, Chang Ming Li, Chunxian Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on machine learning in flexible surgical and interventional robots: Where we are and where we are going</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106179</link>
      <description>Di Wu, R. Zhang, Ameya Pore, Diego Dall&#8217;Alba, Xuan Thao Ha, Zhen Li, Yao Zhang, Francisco Herrera, Mouloud Ourak, Wojtek Kowalczyk, Elena De Momi, Al&#305;&#769;cia Casals, Jenny Dankelman, Jens Kober, Arianna Menciassi, Paolo Fiorini, Emmanuel Vander Poorten, Biomedical Signal Processing and Control. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392848497

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Di Wu, R. Zhang, Ameya Pore, Diego Dall&#8217;Alba, Xuan Thao Ha, Zhen Li, Yao Zhang, Francisco Herrera, Mouloud Ourak, Wojtek Kowalczyk, Elena De Momi, Al&#305;&#769;cia Casals, Jenny Dankelman, Jens Kober, Arianna Menciassi, Paolo Fiorini, Emmanuel Vander Poorten</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonmetal-modification 2D molybdenum carbide (MXene) for enhanced activity in hydrogen evolution reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114649</link>
      <description>Cong Zhang, Wei Chu, Congmei Chen, Wenjing Sun, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392858414

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cong Zhang, Wei Chu, Congmei Chen, Wenjing Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on Cu&#8211;Ag Bimetallic Catalysts for Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction: A Mini-Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c05194</link>
      <description>Peiqi Guo, Kaili Liu, Longya Xu, Ruhan Liu, Zongyou Yin, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392858685

                The atmospheric CO2 concentration has increased significantly since the Industrial Revolution, leading to various environmental issues and energy crisis. The electrochemical reduction of CO2 powered by renewable energy is attracting widespread attention, due to its capacity to transform CO2 into value-added chemicals and fuels and contribute to carbon neutrality. Among Cu-based catalysts, Cu&#8211;Ag bimetallic catalysts exhibit superior selectivity for high value-added multicarbon compounds. This mini-review provides an overview of Cu&#8211;Ag bimetallic catalysts including alloy system and composite structure system, emphasizing the relationship between catalysts' structure and the influencing factors for the enhanced selectivity toward C2+. At the end of this review, we outline the challenges and perspectives for the better development of electrochemical CO2 reduction by Cu&#8211;Ag bimetallic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Peiqi Guo, Kaili Liu, Longya Xu, Ruhan Liu, Zongyou Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c05194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Computational Screening of Molecules with Inverted Singlet&#8211;Triplet Energy Gaps Using the Pariser&#8211;Parr&#8211;Pople Semiempirical Quantum Chemistry Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.3c06357</link>
      <description>Kjell Jorner, Robert Pollice, Cyrille Lavigne, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392858753

                Molecules with an inverted energy gap between their first singlet and triplet excited states have promising applications in the next generation of organic light-emitting diode (OLED) materials. Unfortunately, such molecules are rare, and only a handful of examples are currently known. High-throughput virtual screening could assist in finding novel classes of these molecules, but current efforts are hampered by the high computational cost of the required quantum chemical methods. We present a method based on the semiempirical Pariser&#8211;Parr&#8211;Pople theory augmented by perturbation theory and show that it reproduces inverted gaps at a fraction of the cost of currently employed excited-state calculations. Our study paves the way for ultrahigh-throughput virtual screening and inverse design to accelerate the discovery and development of this new generation of OLED materials.</description>
      <author>Kjell Jorner, Robert Pollice, Cyrille Lavigne, Al&#225;n Aspuru&#8208;Guzik</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.3c06357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repulsive Lateral Interaction of Water Molecules at the Initial Stages of Adsorption in Microporous AlPO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-11 According to &lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;Al NMR and DFT</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03969</link>
      <description>Ilya V. Yakovlev, A. A. Shubin, Evgeniy Papulovskiy, Alexander V. Toktarev, Olga B. Lapina, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392760814

                Lateral (adsorbate&#8211;adsorbate) interactions between adsorbed molecules affect various physical and chemical properties of microporous adsorbents and catalysts, influencing their functional properties. In this work, we studied the hydration of microporous AlPO4-11 aluminophosphate, which has an unusually ordered structure upon adsorption of water vapor, and according to 27Al NMR data, only tetrahedrally or octahedrally coordinated Al sites are present in the AlPO4-11. These 27Al NMR data are consistent with the results of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of hydrated AlPO4-11, which revealed the presence of a strong repulsive lateral interaction at the initial stage of adsorption, suppressing the adsorption of water on neighboring (separated by one &#8722;O&#8211;P&#8211;O&#8211; bridge) Al crystallographic sites. As a result, of all the different aluminum sites, only half of the Al1 sites adsorb two water molecules and acquire octahedral coordination.</description>
      <author>Ilya V. Yakovlev, A. A. Shubin, Evgeniy Papulovskiy, Alexander V. Toktarev, Olga B. Lapina</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03969</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
