<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 01:20:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-dependent kinetics of oxygen chemisorption as the crucial step of oxygen reduction reaction: GCDFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118708</link>
      <description>Vitaliy A. Kislenko, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1055;&#1072;&#1074;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, Sergey A. Kislenko, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403287304

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vitaliy A. Kislenko, &#1057;. &#1042;. &#1055;&#1072;&#1074;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, Sergey A. Kislenko</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118708</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Used Literature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394173310.oth</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403326060

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394173310.oth</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on renewable energy: Conversion and utilization of biomass</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smo.20240019</link>
      <description>Xinping Yang, Yongjia Zhang, Peiliang Sun, Chong Peng, Smart Molecules. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403295336

                Abstract The significant increase in demand for fuels and chemicals driven by global economic expansion has exacerbated concerns over fossil fuel consumption and environmental pollution. To achieve sustainable production of fuels and chemicals, biomass resources provide a rich repository for carbon&#8208;neutral, green renewable energy, and organic carbon. This paper reviews the transformation and utilization of lignocellulosic biomass and its derivatives, emphasizing their valorization into high&#8208;quality chemicals and biofuels. The advantages and disadvantages of various pretreatment methods are discussed based on the composition of lignocellulose. Furthermore, the methods and pathways for the valorization and conversion of cellulose, hemicellulose, and lignin are detailed according to the unique functional groups of different lignocellulosic platform molecules. However, the complex and resilient structure of biomass presents challenges for the disassembly and utilization of single components, and achieving high yields and selectivity for target products remains difficult. In conclusion, this paper comprehensively reviews the various types and pretreatment technologies of lignocellulose, focusing on the methods and pathways for the valorization of lignocellulosic biomass and its derivatives, thereby providing clear guidance and insights for optimizing lignocellulose utilization in the future.</description>
      <author>Xinping Yang, Yongjia Zhang, Peiliang Sun, Chong Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smo.20240019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing OH species in situ generated on low-valence Cu sites for selective carbonyl oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2408770121</link>
      <description>Yang Cao, Qiaozhi Zhang, Iris K.M. Yu, Daniel C.W. Tsang, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 121(42)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403298282

                Catalytic oxidation through the transfer of lattice oxygen from metal oxides to reactants, namely the Mars-van Krevelen mechanism, has been widely reported. In this study, we evidence the overlooked oxidation route that features the in situ formation of surface OH species on Cu catalysts and its selective addition to the reactant carbonyl group. We observed that glucose oxidation to gluconic acid in air (21% O</description>
      <author>Yang Cao, Qiaozhi Zhang, Iris K.M. Yu, Daniel C.W. Tsang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2408770121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electric Fields Drive Rearrangement of Adsorbed Cysteine and Electrolyte Ions on Au Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04216</link>
      <description>H. Sudhakar, Julie Renner, Robert E. Warburton, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403298496

                Electrode surfaces modified with peptides or other biomolecules are of great interest for applications in catalysis and separations. At the electrochemical interface, the structure of biomolecular adsorbates may be sensitive to the applied potential and the distribution of solvent and ions near the electrode surface. Herein, periodic density functional theory (DFT) calculations are used to describe changes in the adsorption structure of the l-cysteine amino acid on Au(111) as a function of applied potential. This theoretical study reveals the fundamental mechanisms of potential-dependent rearrangement of cysteine on electrode surfaces. These systems are analyzed using a hybrid quantum&#8211;classical computational approach that combines constant-potential periodic DFT with a classical representation of the liquid electrolyte. In agreement with experimental measurements, grand canonical thermodynamic analyses suggest that the cysteine exists primarily in its zwitterionic form over a wide range of applied potentials. The structure of adsorbed zwitterionic cysteine is dictated by the cationic ammonium and anionic carboxylate functional groups, where these charged moieties experience competing Coulombic interactions with the charged Au(111) surface and the electrolyte ions within the electric double layer. These competing interactions drive the rearrangement of cysteine with applied potential, which in turn determines the nature of ion structuring at the interface. The potential-dependent free energies of cysteine zwitterions are also significantly influenced by the ionic strength of the electrolyte because of the interactions between charged zwitterion functional groups and oppositely charged electrolyte ions. Understanding the interplay between adsorption structure, applied potential, and electrolyte ion structuring can guide the assembly of structured biomolecules on solid surfaces. The impact of zwitterionic amino acids and peptides on near-surface electrolyte composition may be further exploited to tailor microenvironments for various applications of interfacial electrochemistry.</description>
      <author>H. Sudhakar, Julie Renner, Robert E. Warburton</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu&#8722;based bimetallic sites' p-d orbital hybridization promotes CO asymmetric coupling conversion to C2 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101565</link>
      <description>Jiayong Xiao, Jofrey J. Masana, Ming Qiu, Ying Yu, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403302059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayong Xiao, Jofrey J. Masana, Ming Qiu, Ying Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances and modulation tactics in Ru- and Ir-based electrocatalysts for PEMWE anodes at large current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100323</link>
      <description>Yu Wang, Haijing Yan, Honggang Fu, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403302755

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Wang, Haijing Yan, Honggang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles Thermodynamical Modeling of Molecular Reactions on &#945;-U(001) and &#945;-UH3(001) Surfaces and Their Influence on Hydrogen Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2024.155455</link>
      <description>Jinfan Chen, Tao Tang, Journal of Nuclear Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403303670

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinfan Chen, Tao Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2024.155455</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of frozen density embedding in CP2K and OpenMolcas: CASSCF wavefunctions embedded in a Gaussian and plane wave DFT environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0222409</link>
      <description>Lukas Schreder, Sandra Luber, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403305801

                Most chemical processes happen at a local scale where only a subset of molecular orbitals is directly involved and only a subset of covalent bonds may be rearranged. To model such reactions, Density Functional Theory (DFT) is often inadequate, and the use of computationally more expensive correlated wavefunction (WF) methods is required for accurate results. Mixed-resolution approaches backed by quantum embedding theory have been used extensively to approach this imbalance. Based on the frozen density embedding freeze-and-thaw algorithm, we describe an approach to embed complete active space self-consistent field simulations run in the OpenMolcas code in a DFT environment calculated in CP2K without requiring any external tools. This makes it possible to study a local, active part of a chemical system in a larger and relatively static environment with a computational cost balanced between the accuracy of a WF method and the efficiency of DFT, which we test on environment&#8211;subsystem pairs. Finally, we apply the implementation to an oxygen molecule leaving an aluminum (111) surface and a ruthenium(IV) oxide (110) surface.</description>
      <author>Lukas Schreder, Sandra Luber</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0222409</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-derived CuNi-doped RuO2 electrocatalyst with abundant oxygen vacancies for the oxygen evolution reaction in PEM water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176940</link>
      <description>Sunjin Park, Debasish Mandal, Hansung Kim, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403312301

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sunjin Park, Debasish Mandal, Hansung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The past, present, and future of low-dimensional materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-29046-6.00013-4</link>
      <description>Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Dai&#8208;Ming Tang, Xiaolong Zou, Lili Zhang, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403316836

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Dai&#8208;Ming Tang, Xiaolong Zou, Lili Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-29046-6.00013-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel properties of low-dimensional materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-29046-6.00011-0</link>
      <description>Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Dai&#8208;Ming Tang, Xiaolong Zou, Lili Zhang, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403316858

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Dai&#8208;Ming Tang, Xiaolong Zou, Lili Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-29046-6.00011-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Manipulation to Create High-Valent Fe&lt;sup&gt;4+&lt;/sup&gt; for Efficient and Ultrastable Oxygen Evolution at Industrial-Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c09259</link>
      <description>Yong Feng, Huan Wang, Kun Feng, Chengyu Li, Shuo Li, Cheng L&#252;, Youyong Li, Ding Ma, Jun Zhong, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403318150

                Manipulating the electronic structure of a catalyst at the atomic level is an effective but challenging way to improve the catalytic performance. Here, by stretching the Fe-O bond in FeOOH with an inserted Mo atom, a Fe-O-Mo unit can be created, which will induce the formation of high-valent Fe</description>
      <author>Yong Feng, Huan Wang, Kun Feng, Chengyu Li, Shuo Li, Cheng L&#252;, Youyong Li, Ding Ma, Jun Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c09259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cutting-Edge PCN-ZnO Nanocomposites with Experimental and DFT Insights into Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01932</link>
      <description>Narayan N. Som, A. Opali&#324;ska, Madhurya Chandel, Pratik M. Pataniya, Iwona Koltsov, Julita Smalc&#8208;Koziorowska, Anna &#346;widerska&#8208;&#346;roda, S. Gierlotka, C.K. Sumesh, Witold &#321;ojkowski, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403318557

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Narayan N. Som, A. Opali&#324;ska, Madhurya Chandel, Pratik M. Pataniya, Iwona Koltsov, Julita Smalc&#8208;Koziorowska, Anna &#346;widerska&#8208;&#346;roda, S. Gierlotka, C.K. Sumesh, Witold &#321;ojkowski</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01932</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduction of carbon dioxide to methane and ethanol on the surface of graphyne-like boron nitride (BNyen) monolayer: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112380</link>
      <description>Mohamed J. Saadh, Ahmed Mahal, Maha Mohammed Tawfiq, Abbas Hameed Abdul Hussein, Aseel Salah Mansoor, Usama Kadem Radi, Ahmad J. Obaidullah, Parminder Singh, Ahmed Elawady, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403330022

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohamed J. Saadh, Ahmed Mahal, Maha Mohammed Tawfiq, Abbas Hameed Abdul Hussein, Aseel Salah Mansoor, Usama Kadem Radi, Ahmad J. Obaidullah, Parminder Singh, Ahmed Elawady</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latent space active learning with message passing neural network: The case of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;HfO&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.103804</link>
      <description>Xinjian Ouyang, Zhilong Wang, Xiao Hua Jie, Feng Zhang, Yanxing Zhang, Laijun Liu, Dawei Wang, Physical Review Materials. 8(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403334377

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinjian Ouyang, Zhilong Wang, Xiao Hua Jie, Feng Zhang, Yanxing Zhang, Laijun Liu, Dawei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.103804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal active phase evolution for CO2 electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.09.008</link>
      <description>Juwon Kim, Si Young Lee, Sejun Kim, Bonho Koo, Jinkyu Chung, Danwon Lee, Subin Choi, Jimin Kim, Sungjae Seo, Chihyun Nam, Karl Adrian Gandionco, Gwangsu Bak, Sugeun Jo, Namdong Kim, Hyun&#8208;Joon Shin, Keun Hwa Chae, Da Hye Won, Matthew A. Marcus, David A. Shapiro, Shu-Chih Haw, Daan Hein Alsem, Norman Salmon, Byoung Koun Min, Hyungjun Kim, Yun Jeong Hwang, Jongwoo Lim, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403334608

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juwon Kim, Si Young Lee, Sejun Kim, Bonho Koo, Jinkyu Chung, Danwon Lee, Subin Choi, Jimin Kim, Sungjae Seo, Chihyun Nam, Karl Adrian Gandionco, Gwangsu Bak, Sugeun Jo, Namdong Kim, Hyun&#8208;Joon Shin, Keun Hwa Chae, Da Hye Won, Matthew A. Marcus, David A. Shapiro, Shu-Chih Haw, Daan Hein Alsem, Norman Salmon, Byoung Koun Min, Hyungjun Kim, Yun Jeong Hwang, Jongwoo Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.09.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05754</link>
      <description>Qinyu Wu, Muhammad Saeed, Jiaqi Wang, Xuejuan Ma, Shengfu Tong, Zongwei Mei, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403336114

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qinyu Wu, Muhammad Saeed, Jiaqi Wang, Xuejuan Ma, Shengfu Tong, Zongwei Mei</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing high-fidelity neural network potentials through low-fidelity sampling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0222779</link>
      <description>Gang Seob Jung, APL Machine Learning. 2(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403336420

                The efficacy of neural network potentials (NNPs) critically depends on the quality of the configurational datasets used for training. Prior research using empirical potentials has shown that well-selected liquid&#8211;solid transitional configurations of a metallic system can be translated to other metallic systems. This study demonstrates that such validated configurations can be relabeled using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, thereby enhancing the development of high-fidelity NNPs. Training strategies and sampling approaches are efficiently assessed using empirical potentials and subsequently relabeled via DFT in a highly parallelized fashion for high-fidelity NNP training. Our results reveal that relying solely on energy and force for NNP training is inadequate to prevent overfitting, highlighting the necessity of incorporating stress terms into the loss functions. To optimize training involving force and stress terms, we propose employing transfer learning to fine-tune the weights, ensuring that the potential surface is smooth for these quantities composed of energy derivatives. This approach markedly improves the accuracy of elastic constants derived from simulations in both empirical potential-based NNPs and relabeled DFT-based NNPs. Overall, this study offers significant insights into leveraging empirical potentials to expedite the development of reliable and robust NNPs at the DFT level.</description>
      <author>Gang Seob Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0222779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Design of the Metal&#8211;Support Interface in Methanol Electrocatalytic Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.3c01466</link>
      <description>Bart&#322;omiej M. Szyja, Joanna Zasada, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403336763

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bart&#322;omiej M. Szyja, Joanna Zasada</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.3c01466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress of dual-atom catalysts on zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.09.008</link>
      <description>Kexin Wang, Xu Zhang, Jing Lyu, Miao Tian, Xingyang Wu, Xiang Li, Dashuang Wang, Zhongkai Hao, Yuxin Zhang, Nano Materials Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403342419

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kexin Wang, Xu Zhang, Jing Lyu, Miao Tian, Xingyang Wu, Xiang Li, Dashuang Wang, Zhongkai Hao, Yuxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.09.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Doped Fullerene (MN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;C&lt;sub&gt;54&lt;/sub&gt;) as Bifunctional Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c03413</link>
      <description>Junkai Xu, Yunhao Wang, Xiaoxue Yu, Jianjun Fang, Xian-Fang Yue, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, Jing Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403347338

                Development of high-performance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts is crucial to realizing the electrolytic water cycle. C60 is an ideal substrate material for single atom catalysts (SACs) due to its unique electron-withdrawing properties and spherical structure. In this work, we screened for a novel single-atom catalyst based on C60, which anchored transition metal atoms in the C60 molecule by coordination with N atoms. Through first-principles calculations, we evaluated the stability and activity of MN4&#8211;C54 (M = Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Rh, Ru, Pd, Ag, Pt, Ir, Au). The results indicate that CuN4&#8211;C54, which is based only on earth-abundant elements, exhibited low overpotentials of 0.46 and 0.47 V for the OER and ORR, respectively, and was considered a promising bifunctional catalyst, showing better performance than the noble-metal ones. In addition, according to the linear relationship of intermediates, we established volcano plots to describe the activity trends of the OER and ORR on MN4&#8211;C54. Finally, d-band center and crystal orbital Hamiltonian populations methods were used to explain the catalytic origin. Suitable d-band centers lead to moderate adsorption strength, further leading to good catalytic performances.</description>
      <author>Junkai Xu, Yunhao Wang, Xiaoxue Yu, Jianjun Fang, Xian-Fang Yue, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpca.4c03413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic performance of a single atom Pd1Ag10/Al2O3 catalyst for the selective hydrogenation of acetylene: The role of CO-induced segregation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161516</link>
      <description>Igor S. Mashkovsky, Andrey V. Bukhtiyarov, &#1055;. &#1042;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1088;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1043;. &#1054;. &#1041;&#1088;&#1072;&#1075;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, &#1043;. &#1053;. &#1041;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1053;. &#1057;. &#1057;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Maxim A. Panafidin, I.A. Chetyrin, E. Yu. Gerasimov, Yan V. Zubavichus, A. Yu. Stakheev, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403348623

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Igor S. Mashkovsky, Andrey V. Bukhtiyarov, &#1055;. &#1042;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1088;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, &#1043;. &#1054;. &#1041;&#1088;&#1072;&#1075;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, &#1043;. &#1053;. &#1041;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1053;. &#1057;. &#1057;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Maxim A. Panafidin, I.A. Chetyrin, E. Yu. Gerasimov, Yan V. Zubavichus, A. Yu. Stakheev</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cooperativity in Fe2N5P Dual-Atomic Site: Designing Dual Atom Catalysts for Water-Splitting Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177025</link>
      <description>Tahereh Ghaed-Sharaf, Akbar Omidvar, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403364356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tahereh Ghaed-Sharaf, Akbar Omidvar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonate-carbonate coupling on platinum surface promotes electrochemical water oxidation to hydrogen peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53134-3</link>
      <description>Heng Zhu, Xianshun Lv, Yuexu Wu, Li Wang, Yuping Wu, Shicheng Yan, Yuhui Chen, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403370664

                Water electro-oxidation to form H2O2 is an important way to produce H2O2 which is widely applied in industry. However, its mechanism is under debate and HO(ads), hydroxyl group adsorbed onto the surface of the electrode, is regarded as an important intermediate. Herein, we study the mechanism of water oxidation to H2O2 at Pt electrode using in-situ Raman spectroscopy and differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy and find peroxide bond mainly originated from the coupling of two CO32- via a C2O62- intermediate. By quantifying the 18O isotope in the product, we find that 93% of H2O2 was formed via the CO32- coupling route and 7% of H2O2 is from OH(ads)-CO3&#8226;&#8722; route. The OH(ads)-OH(ads) coupling route has a negligible contribution. The comparison of various electrodes shows that the strong adsorption of CO3(ads) at the electrode surface is essential. Combining with a commercial cathode catalyst to produce H2O2 during oxygen reduction, we assemble a flow cell in which the cathode and anode simultaneously produce H2O2. It shows a Faradaic efficiency of 150% of H2O2 at 1 A cm&#8722;2 with a cell voltage of 2.3 V. Electrosynthesis via two electron water reactions offers a promising method for decentralized H2O2 production, yet its mechanism remains unclear. Here, the authors address the challenge by using in-situ Raman and DEMS, and demonstrate 93% of H2O2 forms via the carbonate coupling route through a C2O62&#8722; intermediate.</description>
      <author>Heng Zhu, Xianshun Lv, Yuexu Wu, Li Wang, Yuping Wu, Shicheng Yan, Yuhui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53134-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretical Perspective for Ammonia Synthesis: Nitric Oxide or Nitrate Electroreduction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401208</link>
      <description>Q.G. Wang, Pu Guo, Huan Li, Jun Long, Shaoxue Yang, Jianping Xiao, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403378857

                Abstract Ammonia is an important raw material for agricultural production, playing a key role in global food production. However, conventional ammonia synthesis resulted in extensive greenhouse gas emissions and huge energy consumption. Recently, researchers have proposed electrocatalytic reverse artificial nitrogen cycle (eRANC) routes to circumvent these issues, which can be driven by electrocatalysis and sustainable electricity. Here, a theoretical and computational perspective on the challenges and opportunities with the comparison with experimental results: electrochemical reduction of nitrate (eNO 3 RR) and nitrite (eNO 2 RR), electrochemical reduction of nitric oxide (eNORR) combined with oxidative nitrogen fixation are presented. By comparison, the N 2 &#8594;NO&#8594;NH 3 route is proposed as the most promising in case the NO solubility can be solved well in reactor design. Its high efficiency of ammonia production is demonstrated. Instead, the eNO 3 RR can be another choice because it is non&#8208;toxic and the solid&#8208;liquid interface is usually efficient for electrochemical reactions, while its low selectivity at low overpotentials is an issue. These fundamentals highlight the potential and key factors of eRANC as an efficient and sustainable route for ammonia production.</description>
      <author>Q.G. Wang, Pu Guo, Huan Li, Jun Long, Shaoxue Yang, Jianping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox-mediated decoupled seawater direct splitting for H2 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53335-w</link>
      <description>Tao Liu, Cheng Lan, Min Tang, Mengxin Li, Yi-Tao Xu, Huimin Yang, Qingyue Deng, Wenchuan Jiang, Zhiyu Zhao, Yifan Wu, Heping Xie, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403384925

                Abstract Seawater direct electrolysis (SDE) using renewable energy provides a sustainable pathway to harness abundant oceanic hydrogen resources. However, the side-reaction of the chlorine electro-oxidation reaction (ClOR) severely decreased direct electrolysis efficiency of seawater and gradually corrodes the anode. In this study, a redox-mediated strategy is introduced to suppress the ClOR, and a decoupled seawater direct electrolysis (DSDE) system incorporating a separate O 2 evolution reactor is established. Ferricyanide/ferrocyanide ([Fe(CN) 6 ] 3&#8722;/4&#8722; ) serves as an electron-mediator between the cell and the reactor, thereby enabling a more dynamically favorable half-reaction to supplant the traditional oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This alteration involves a straightforward, single-electron-transfer anodic reaction without gas precipitation and effectively eliminates the generation of chlorine-containing byproducts. By operating at low voltages (~1.37 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and ~1.57 V at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and maintaining stability even in a Cl &#8722; -saturated seawater electrolyte, this system has the potential of undergoing decoupled seawater electrolysis with zero chlorine emissions. Further improvements in the high-performance redox-mediators and catalysts can provide enhanced cost-effectiveness and sustainability of the DSDE system.</description>
      <author>Tao Liu, Cheng Lan, Min Tang, Mengxin Li, Yi-Tao Xu, Huimin Yang, Qingyue Deng, Wenchuan Jiang, Zhiyu Zhao, Yifan Wu, Heping Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53335-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generalization of Biasing Particle Insertion and Deletion for Grand Canonical Monte Carlo Simulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00755</link>
      <description>T Ikeda, Akira Nakayama, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403389357

                A general formulation of biasing particle insertion/deletion for the grand canonical Monte Carlo (GCMC) simulation is presented. The proposed formulation unifies the concepts of the conventional cavity- and configurational-type biasing techniques and modifies a cavity biasing method to strictly satisfy the detailed balance condition. Numerical examples of this modified cavity bias method are presented for Lennard&#8211;Jones fluid and hydrogen adsorption on a platinum surface. The results obtained using this method are compared with those obtained using various GCMC methods. Furthermore, a rigorous on-the-fly on-lattice GCMC simulation for surface adsorption is formulated and performed for comparison. The numerical examples clearly demonstrate the efficiency and accuracy of the proposed formulation.</description>
      <author>T Ikeda, Akira Nakayama</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Role of Anions in the Adsorption of Pyrrolidinium Based Ionic Liquids on Pt(111) Surface Using Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.27497</link>
      <description>Arka Prava Sarkar, International Journal of Quantum Chemistry. 124(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403406494

                ABSTRACT The adsorption properties of ionic liquids containing pyrrolidinium cations and various inorganic anions as electrolytes on a platinum surface were analyzed using first principle density functional theory. Three different orientations of the alkyl cation chain were observed during the adsorption process. The strength and structural stability varied between non&#8208;fluorinated and fluorinated anions upon adsorption, with oxygen atoms influencing the mechanism of adsorption and driving the structural stability of the anion, while fluorine atoms played a role in determining the orientation of the cation during adsorption. Net atomic charges analysis, electron density difference methods, and electron density accumulation for this complex system were utilized to further investigate these phenomena. The results of this study provide valuable insights into the role of anions in the adsorption behavior of pyrrolidinium&#8208;based ionic liquids on platinum surfaces, shedding light on the factors that influence their adsorption properties and structural stability on a molecular level. The findings of this study contribute to a better understanding of the interplay between anions and platinum surfaces in the adsorption of pyrrolidinium based ionic liquids, which can have implications for various applications such as electrochemistry, catalysis, and energy storage.</description>
      <author>Arka Prava Sarkar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.27497</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the phase transition and electrochemical application of MoSe2 material for energy conversion and storage devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160990</link>
      <description>Muthuraja Velpandian, Priyanka Gupta, Anshid Kuttasseri, Arup Mahata, Suddhasatwa Basu, Applied Surface Science. 677(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403410060

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muthuraja Velpandian, Priyanka Gupta, Anshid Kuttasseri, Arup Mahata, Suddhasatwa Basu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical investigation of graphdiyne-supported single-cluster catalysts for electroreduction of nitric oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161522</link>
      <description>Ya Gao, Erpeng Wang, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403411757

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya Gao, Erpeng Wang, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effect of Cobalt/Ferrocene as a Catalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02039</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; M. Abad, Alba Duprat-Alvaro, Raquel Sainz, M.V. Mart&#305;&#769;nez-Huerta, Marcos Pita, Ant&#243;nio L. De Lacey, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403415342

                There is a great deal of interest in the development of electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) that are stable and have high activity because this anodic half-reaction is the main bottleneck in water splitting and other key technologies. Cobalt and iron oxide and oxyhydroxide electrocatalysts constitute a cheaper alternative to the highly active and commonly used Ir- and Ru-based catalysts. Most of the described electrocatalysts require tedious synthetic and expensive preparation procedures. We report here a facile and straightforward preparation of an electrocatalyst by a combination of commercial compounds, such as cobalt chloride and ferrocene. A highly active and stable OER electrocatalyst is obtained, which shows a low overpotential in the alkaline medium as a consequence of a synergistic effect between both compounds and is inexpensive.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; M. Abad, Alba Duprat-Alvaro, Raquel Sainz, M.V. Mart&#305;&#769;nez-Huerta, Marcos Pita, Ant&#243;nio L. De Lacey</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly asymmetrically configured single atoms anchored on flame-roasting deposited carbon black as cathode catalysts for ultrahigh power density Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100134</link>
      <description>Yu-Chieh Ting, Chih-Chieh Cheng, Fan-Yu Yen, Guan-Ru Li, Shao-I Chang, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403415418

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu-Chieh Ting, Chih-Chieh Cheng, Fan-Yu Yen, Guan-Ru Li, Shao-I Chang, Chih&#8208;Heng Lee, Hsin&#8208;Yi Tiffany Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Simulations of Thermal Transport across Iron Oxide&#8211;Hydrocarbon Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09434</link>
      <description>F. H. Carman, James P. Ewen, Fernando Bresme, Billy Wu, Daniele Dini, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403416315

                The rational design of dielectric fluids for immersion cooling of batteries requires a molecular-level understanding of the heat flow across the battery casing/dielectric fluid interface. Here, we use nonequilibrium molecular dynamics (NEMD) simulations to quantify the interfacial thermal resistance (ITR) between hematite and poly-&#945;-olefin (PAO), which are representative of the outer surface of the steel battery casing and a synthetic hydrocarbon dielectric fluid, respectively. After identifying the most suitable force fields to model the thermal properties of the individual components, we then compared different solid&#8211;liquid interaction potentials for the calculation of the ITR. These potentials resulted in a wide range of ITR values (4&#8211;21 K m2 GW&#8211;1), with stronger solid&#8211;liquid interactions leading to lower ITR. The increase in ITR is correlated with an increase in density of the fluid layer closest to the surface. Since the ITR has not been experimentally measured for the hematite/PAO interface, we validate the solid&#8211;liquid interaction potential using the work of adhesion calculated using the dry-surface method. The work of adhesion calculations from the simulations were compared to those derived from experimental contact angle measurements for PAO on steel. We find that all of the solid&#8211;liquid potentials overestimate the experimental work of adhesion. The experiments and simulations can only be reconciled by further reducing the strength of the interfacial interactions. This suggests some screening of the solid&#8211;liquid interactions, which may be due to the presence of an interfacial water layer between PAO and steel in the contact angle experiments. Using the solid&#8211;liquid interaction potential that reproduces the experimental work of adhesion, we obtain a higher ITR (33 K m2 GW&#8211;1), suggesting inefficient thermal transport. The results of this study demonstrate the potential for NEMD simulations to improve understanding of the nanoscale thermal transport across industrially important interfaces. This study represents an important step toward the rational design of more effective fluids for immersion cooling systems for electric vehicles and other applications where thermal management is of high importance.</description>
      <author>F. H. Carman, James P. Ewen, Fernando Bresme, Billy Wu, Daniele Dini</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09434</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interaction of Nitric Oxide with Late 3d Transition Metals: Dissociation and Metal Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03048</link>
      <description>O. Quinn Carvalho, Hoan K.K. Nguyen, Sri Krishna Murthy Padavala, L&#237;ney &#193;rnad&#243;ttir, Ethan J. Crumlin, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403424207

                No abstract</description>
      <author>O. Quinn Carvalho, Hoan K.K. Nguyen, Sri Krishna Murthy Padavala, L&#237;ney &#193;rnad&#243;ttir, Ethan J. Crumlin, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactive scattering of H2 on Cu(111) at 925 K: Effective Hartree potential vs sudden approximation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231559</link>
      <description>B. Smits, Mantu Kumar Sah, Koushik Naskar, Satrajit Adhikari, J&#246;rg Meyer, Mark F. Somers, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403430403

                We present new quantum dynamical results for the reactive scattering of hydrogen molecules from a Cu(111) surface at a surface temperature of 925 K. Reaction, scattering, and diffraction probabilities are compared for results obtained using both an effective Hartree potential (EfHP) and a sudden approximation approach, implemented through the static corrugation model (SCM), to include surface temperature effects. Toward this goal, we show how the SRP48 DFT-functional and an embedded atom potential perform when used to calculate copper lattice constants and thermal expansion coefficients based on lattice dynamics calculations within the quasi-harmonic approximation. The so-calculated phonons are then used in the EfHP approach to replace the normal modes of a fictitious copper cluster used in earlier work. We find that both the EfHP and SCM approaches correctly predict the reaction probability curve broadening effect when the surface temperature is increased. Similarly, results for rovibrationally elastic scattering appear to be improved, predominantly for the SCM model. The behavior of the EfHP results appears to remain much closer to that of a Born&#8211;Oppenheimer static surface approach, which excludes any surface temperature effects. Finally, for the diffraction, we show very clear attenuation effects for the SCM approach, significantly decreasing specular diffraction probabilities at 925 K surface temperature. These results demonstrate that state-of-the-art theoretical models are able to reproduce strictly quantum mechanical scattering effects with a sudden approximation model and open up interesting opportunities for further comparisons to experimental diffraction results.</description>
      <author>B. Smits, Mantu Kumar Sah, Koushik Naskar, Satrajit Adhikari, J&#246;rg Meyer, Mark F. Somers</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Electrocatalysts with High Performance Based on Thermodynamics and Kinetics: Progress and Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413826</link>
      <description>Minshu Du, Feihan Yu, Shumin Gong, Liu Feng, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403433257

                Abstract Efficient and robust electrocatalysts play a central role in clean energy conversion, enabling a number of sustainable processes for future technologies. The traditional explorations of electrocatalyst relying on the trial&#8208;and&#8208;error approaches are definitely tedious and inefficient. Theoretical progresses on reactive thermodynamics and kinetics in recent years have initiated a powerful theory&#8208;guided design strategy of electrocatalysts. Herein, this review first summarizes design principles for reactive activity and stability, presenting the thermodynamics, kinetics, and the synergistic thermokinetic correlation in electrocatalytic reaction. Second, the screening criterion, reasonable design, mechanistic understanding, and performance evaluation of the typical electrocatalysts as divided into the thermodynamics oriented&#8208;, kinetics oriented&#8208;, and thermokinetic correlation oriented&#8208;designs are discussed. The necessity of correlating thermodynamics and kinetics into the rational design and mechanism clarification is highlighted. Finally, the conclusions and perspectives of the development of highly efficient electrocatalysts are proposed.</description>
      <author>Minshu Du, Feihan Yu, Shumin Gong, Liu Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Libtool: Bridging Textual Analysis Gaps for Non&#8208;Programmers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.1072</link>
      <description>Faizhal Arif Santosa, Manika Lamba, Crissandra George, J. Stephen Downie, Proceedings of the Association for Information Science and Technology. 61(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403433714

                ABSTRACT In the era of big and ubiquitous data, professionals and students alike are finding themselves needing to perform a number of textual analysis tasks. Historically, the general lack of statistical expertise and programming skills has stopped many with humanities or social sciences backgrounds from performing and fully benefiting from such analyses. Thus, we introduce Coconut Libtool ( www.coconut-libtool.com/ ), an open&#8208;source, web&#8208;based application that utilizes state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art natural language processing (NLP) technologies. Coconut Libtool analyzes text data from customized files and bibliographic databases such as Web of Science, Scopus, and Lens. Users can verify which functions can be performed with the data they have. Coconut Libtool deploys multiple algorithmic NLP techniques at the backend, including topic modeling ( LDA, Biterm, and BERTopic algorithms), network graph visualization, keyword lemmatization, and sunburst visualization. Coconut Libtool is the people&#8208;first web application designed to be used by professionals, researchers, and students in the information sciences, digital humanities, and computational social sciences domains to promote transparency, reproducibility, accessibility, reciprocity, and responsibility in research practices.</description>
      <author>Faizhal Arif Santosa, Manika Lamba, Crissandra George, J. Stephen Downie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.1072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the ORR performance of PtMnM ternary intermetallics by tuning the surface strain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2312-x</link>
      <description>Min Young Song, Guanyu Luo, Qian Zhang, Hanyu Hu, Deli Wang, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403453751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Young Song, Guanyu Luo, Qian Zhang, Hanyu Hu, Deli Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2312-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chlorine vacancy&#8722;induced activation in two&#8722;dimensional transition metal dichlorides nanosheets for efficient CO electroreduction to C2+ products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.09.032</link>
      <description>Qiwen Su, L. Chen, Lichang Yin, Jingxiang Zhao, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiwen Su, L. Chen, Lichang Yin, Jingxiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.09.032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn-doped Bi2O3 grown on PTFE-treated carbon paper for electrochemical CO2-to-formate production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115798</link>
      <description>Junjie Shi, Paulina Pr&#353;lja, Milla Suominen, Benjin Jin, Jouko Lahtinen, Lilian Moumaneix, Xiangze Kong, Tanja Kallio, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457987

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junjie Shi, Paulina Pr&#353;lja, Milla Suominen, Benjin Jin, Jouko Lahtinen, Lilian Moumaneix, Xiangze Kong, Tanja Kallio</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical regeneration of high-purity CO2 from (bi)carbonates in a porous solid electrolyte reactor for efficient carbon capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01654-z</link>
      <description>Xiao Zhang, Zhiwei Fang, Peng Zhu, Xia Yang, Haotian Wang, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403338665

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao Zhang, Zhiwei Fang, Peng Zhu, Xia Yang, Haotian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01654-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent development of non&#8208;iridium&#8208;based electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.170</link>
      <description>Lei Shi, Wenhui Zhang, Jiayu Li, Qing Yan, Zhengfei Chen, Xianbo Zhou, Jihong Li, Ruiqin Gao, Yuxue Wu, Guodong Li, Carbon Neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403380005

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolyser (PEMWE) possesses great significance for the production of high purity of hydrogen. To expedite the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) that involved multiple electron&#8211;proton&#8208;coupled process, efficient and stable electrocatalysts are highly desired. Currently, noble&#8208;metal Ir&#8208;based materials are the benchmark anode due to its corrosion&#8208;resistant property and favourable combination of activity/stability. However, the large&#8208;scale deployment of PEMWE is usually constrained due to the use of the scarcest element iridium. In this review, we disclose the current research progress towards the non&#8208;iridium&#8208;based electrocatalysts for OER in acidic media, and then summarize some typical oxides that possesses good catalytic performance. Besides, we also present the unresolved problems and challenges in an attempt to enhance the activity/stability of these catalysts.</description>
      <author>Lei Shi, Wenhui Zhang, Jiayu Li, Qing Yan, Zhengfei Chen, Xianbo Zhou, Jihong Li, Ruiqin Gao, Yuxue Wu, Guodong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Crystalline Material Properties with AI: Bridging Molecular to Particle Scales</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03224</link>
      <description>Weiye Chen, Muyang Li, Tuo Yao, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Shengzhe Jia, Zhenguo Gao, Junbo Gong, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403423791

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiye Chen, Muyang Li, Tuo Yao, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Shengzhe Jia, Zhenguo Gao, Junbo Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03224</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
