<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 01:13:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel oxide modified FeCoNi alloy composites prepared with one-step pyrolytic reduction as bifunctional catalyst for ORR/OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175802</link>
      <description>Qing Chen, Peng Mao, Qiongyu Liu, Meixiu Wan, Maocong Hu, Zhenhua Yao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1004(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401242556

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Chen, Peng Mao, Qiongyu Liu, Meixiu Wan, Maocong Hu, Zhenhua Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile construction of plasmonic Ag/Nb2O5 films and their photocatalytic activity against organic dye and nanoplastics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105881</link>
      <description>Te Hu, Liang Hao, Qian Zhao, Rong Jia, Sujun Guan, Yiqiang He, Yun Lu, Journal of Water Process Engineering. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401243725

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Te Hu, Liang Hao, Qian Zhao, Rong Jia, Sujun Guan, Yiqiang He, Yun Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven Design of Catalytic Materials in Methane Oxidation Based on a Site Isolation Concept</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02103</link>
      <description>Aliaksei Mazheika, M. Geske, Matthias M&#252;ller, Stephan A. Schunk, Frank Rosowski, Ralph Kraehnert, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401246258

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aliaksei Mazheika, M. Geske, Matthias M&#252;ller, Stephan A. Schunk, Frank Rosowski, Ralph Kraehnert</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Fe&#8208;Doped Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;NiS@Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanorod Array with Regulated Heterostructural Interface and Band Structure for Expediting Alkaline Electrocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409849</link>
      <description>Ruidong Shi, Yuanting Li, Xiaoxin Xu, Xue Wang, Gongbing Zhou, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401260932

                Abstract Aiming to efficiently expedite alkaline overall water splitting (OWS) by addressing challenges such as sluggish kinetics and limited stability, a hollow Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 &#8208;NiS@Ni(OH) 2 nanorod array with surface nanosheets is devised, featuring a high&#8208;index Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 (101)&#8208;NiS(211) heterostructural interface and an upshifted d &#8208;band center. This nanoarchitecture intensifies the adsorption and interaction of H 2 O and OH &#8722; reactants on the electrocatalyst surface, suitably bonds the * H intermediate in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and accelerates electron movement of * H, minimizes the energy requirement of the rate&#8208;limiting phase ( * OH &#8594; * O) in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by facilitating O&#9472;H cleavage of * OH and optimally adsorbs * O, amplifies the exposure of surface&#8208;active centers, and ultimately reduces the apparent activation energy. Consequently, the overpotentials are as low as 66.4 mV (HER) and 254.9 mV (OER) at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , alongside high turnover frequencies of 142 s &#8722;1 (H 2 ) and 279 s &#8722;1 (O 2 ) at 100 and 300 mV, respectively, markedly outperforming direct&#8208;electrodeposited analogues. When functioning as a bifunctional electrode in OWS, this material merely requires 1.57 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and sustains an operation for 168 h, approaching Pt/C||RuO 2 benchmark.</description>
      <author>Ruidong Shi, Yuanting Li, Xiaoxin Xu, Xue Wang, Gongbing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uniting activity design principles of anode catalysts for direct liquid fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00100a</link>
      <description>Daniel J. Zheng, Jiayu Peng, Kaylee McCormack, Hongbin Xu, Jin Soo Kang, Zhenshu Wang, Zhichu Ren, Ju Li, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, EES Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401263876

                This review provides a comprehensive overview of liquid fuel oxidation electrocatalysts, from fundamental principles to state-of-the-art materials in an effort to unify design principles for future materials.</description>
      <author>Daniel J. Zheng, Jiayu Peng, Kaylee McCormack, Hongbin Xu, Jin Soo Kang, Zhenshu Wang, Zhichu Ren, Ju Li, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00100a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmed electrochemical reconstruction of NiCoxMo4-xN5 for making Core-Shell shaped Schottky junction electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154473</link>
      <description>Selvaraj Seenivasan, Miyeon Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Junhyeok Seo, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401268956

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Selvaraj Seenivasan, Miyeon Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Junhyeok Seo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biaxial strain induced OH engineer for accelerating alkaline hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50942-5</link>
      <description>Tao Zhang, Qitong Ye, Zhidong Han, Qingyi Liu, Yipu Liu, Dongshuang Wu, Hong Jin Fan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401277047

                The sluggish kinetics of Volmer step in the alkaline hydrogen evolution results in large energy consumption. The challenge that has yet well resolved is to control the water adsorption and dissociation. Here, we develop biaxially strained MoSe2 three dimensional nanoshells that exhibit enhanced catalytic performance with a low overpotential of 58.2 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in base, and long-term stable activity in membrane-electrode-assembly based electrolyser at 1 A cm&#8722;2. Compared to the flat and uniaxial-strained MoSe2, we establish that the stably adsorbed OH engineer on biaxially strained MoSe2 changes the water adsorption configuration from O-down on Mo to O-horizontal on OH* via stronger hydrogen bonds. The favorable water dissociation on 3-coordinated Mo sites and hydrogen adsorption on 4-coordinated Mo sites constitute a tandem electrolysis, resulting in thermodynamically favorable hydrogen evolution. This work deepens our understanding to the impact of strain dimensions on water dissociation and inspires the design of nanostructured catalysts for accelerating the rate-determining step in multi-electron reactions. Hydroxide is the most abundant anion in alkaline solutions, but its impact on alkaline water electrolysis remains unclear. Herein, the authors report a biaxial strain induced OH engineer on MoSe2 to accelerate alkaline hydrogen evolution by modifying the water dissociation.</description>
      <author>Tao Zhang, Qitong Ye, Zhidong Han, Qingyi Liu, Yipu Liu, Dongshuang Wu, Hong Jin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50942-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Intrinsic Mechanism of High&#8208;Performance Electrocatalytic Nitrogen Fixation by Heterogenization of Homonuclear Dual&#8208;Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12803</link>
      <description>Yue&#8208;Fei Zhang, Yang Yu, Yu Zhang, Xuefei Liu, Wenjun Xiao, Degui Wang, Gang Wang, Zhen Wang, Jinshun Bi, Jincheng Liu, Xun Zhou, Wentao Wang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401277908

                A heteronuclear dual transition metal atom catalyst is a promising strategy to solve and relieve the increasing energy and environment crisis. However, the role of each atom still does not efficiently differentiate due to the high activity but low detectability of each transition metal in the synergistic catalytic process when considering the influence of heteronuclear induced atomic difference for each transition metal atom, thus seriously hindering intrinsic mechanism finding. Herein, we proposed coordinate environment vary induced heterogenization of homonuclear dual&#8208;transition metal, which inherits the advantage of heteronuclear transition metal atom catalyst but also controls the variable of the two atoms to explore the underlying mechanism. Based on this proposal, employing density functional theory study and machine learning, 23 kinds of homonuclear transition metals are doping in four asymmetric C 3 N for heterogenization to evaluate the underlying catalytic mechanism. Our results demonstrate that five catalysts exhibit excellent catalytic performance with a low limiting potential of &#8722;0.28 to &#8722;0.48 V. In the meantime, a new mechanism, &#8220;capture&#8211;charge distribution&#8211;recapture&#8211;charge redistribution&#8221;, is developed for both side&#8208;on and end&#8208;on configuration. More importantly, the pronate site of the first hydrogenation is identified based on this mechanism. Our work not only initially makes a deep understanding of the transition dual metal&#8208;based heteronuclear catalyst indirectly but also broadens the development of complicated homonuclear dual&#8208;atom catalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Yue&#8208;Fei Zhang, Yang Yu, Yu Zhang, Xuefei Liu, Wenjun Xiao, Degui Wang, Gang Wang, Zhen Wang, Jinshun Bi, Jincheng Liu, Xun Zhou, Wentao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of polyhedral Pt-Pd-Ni nanobelts regulated by W(CO)6 and applied as a highly performing oxygen reduction reaction electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154476</link>
      <description>Yuanyan Luo, Tao Zhou, Costas Molochas, Yifang Ouyang, Xiaoting Huang, Zhen&#8208;Yu Chen, Jinliang Zhu, Panagiotis Tsiakaras, Pei Kang Shen, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401282320

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyan Luo, Tao Zhou, Costas Molochas, Yifang Ouyang, Xiaoting Huang, Zhen&#8208;Yu Chen, Jinliang Zhu, Panagiotis Tsiakaras, Pei Kang Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154476</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution with Nickel Oxide Nanoparticle-Modified Glassy Carbon Electrodes in Alkaline Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c04700</link>
      <description>Abdulrahman I. Alharthi, Omar A. Hazazi, Badreah A. Al Jahdaly, Mohammed A. Kassem, Mohamed I. Awad, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401282919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulrahman I. Alharthi, Omar A. Hazazi, Badreah A. Al Jahdaly, Mohammed A. Kassem, Mohamed I. Awad</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c04700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advancements in aqueous electrowinning for metal recovery: A comprehensive review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2024.108897</link>
      <description>Zuowei Liu, Xueyi Guo, Zhipeng Xu, Qinghua Tian, Minerals Engineering. 216(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401283898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zuowei Liu, Xueyi Guo, Zhipeng Xu, Qinghua Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2024.108897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learned interatomic potentials for transition metal dichalcogenide Mo1&#8722;xWxS2&#8722;2ySe2y alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01357-9</link>
      <description>Anas Siddiqui, Nicholas D. M. Hine, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401284655

                Abstract Machine Learned Interatomic Potentials (MLIPs) combine the predictive power of Density Functional Theory (DFT) with the speed and scaling of interatomic potentials, enabling theoretical spectroscopy to be applied to larger and more complex systems than is possible with DFT. In this work, we train an MLIP for quaternary Transition Metal Dichalcogenide (TMD) alloy systems of the form Mo 1&#8722; x W x S 2&#8722;2 y Se 2 y , using the equivariant Neural Network (NN) MACE. We demonstrate the ability of this potential to calculate vibrational properties of alloy TMDs including phonon spectra for pure monolayers, and Vibrational Density of States (VDOS) and first-order Raman spectra for alloys across the range of x and y . We show that we retain DFT level accuracy while greatly extending feasible system size and extent of sampling over alloy configurations. We are able to characterize the first-order Raman active modes across the whole range of concentration, particularly for the &#8220;disorder-induced&#8221; modes.</description>
      <author>Anas Siddiqui, Nicholas D. M. Hine</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01357-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Structure Search Study of 17-&#946;-Estradiol Adsorption on Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03485</link>
      <description>Suvi Sippola, Milica Todorovi&#263;, Emilia Peltola, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401286422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suvi Sippola, Milica Todorovi&#263;, Emilia Peltola</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretical Inquest of Atomically Injected Ni-Atom over Graphene and Analogous Substrates for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00884-9</link>
      <description>Hemang P. Tanna, Prafulla K. Jha, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401290965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hemang P. Tanna, Prafulla K. Jha</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00884-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial Ligand Engineering Enhanced CoN4-Based catalysts as efficient Electrocatalysts for ORR/OER with low overpotentials: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135001</link>
      <description>Zhihua Ju, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Qingxin Kang, Yan Liang, Fapeng Yu, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401304827

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhihua Ju, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Qingxin Kang, Yan Liang, Fapeng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ba promoter effect on cobalt-catalyzed ammonia decomposition kinetics: A theoretical analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.050</link>
      <description>Zahra Almisbaa, Philippe Sautet, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401306038

                Ammonia decomposition is a key reaction in the context of hydrogen storage, transport, and release. This study combines density functional theory (DFT) calculations with microkinetic modeling to address the promotion mechanism of Ba species for ammonia decomposition on Co catalysts. The modified adsorption properties of Co upon the addition of metallic Ba or BaO suggest that the promoters play a role in alleviating the competitive adsorption of H. Calculating the full reaction pathway of ammonia decomposition shows that limiting the investigation to the N&#8211;N association step, as done previously, overlooks the effect of the promoter on the energy barriers of the NHx dehydrogenation steps. Challenges of modeling the ammonia decomposition reaction are addressed by understanding that the NH2 intermediate is stabilized on the step sites rather than the terrace sites. When the effect of H-coverage on the adsorption of NH3 is not considered in the microkinetic simulations, the results conflict with the experiments. However, accounting for the effect of H-coverage, as performed here, shows that BaO-doped Co has higher rates than pristine Co and Ba-doped Co at the reaction temperature of 723.15 K. When H is adsorbed on the Ba-doped Co, the adsorption of ammonia becomes significantly endergonic, which makes the rates relatively slow. The superiority of the BaO-promoted catalyst is attributed to a lower energy for the transition state of the rate-determining step, coupled with a reduced impact of the hydrogen coverage on weakening the ammonia adsorption. The kinetic analysis of the influence of Ba and BaO on the Co surface shows that BaO-doped Co aligns more closely with experimental observations than Ba-doped Co. This implies that Ba on the Co surface is likely to be in an oxide form under reaction conditions. Understanding the kinetics of the ammonia decomposition reaction provides a foundation for developing highly effective catalysts to accelerate the industrial utilization of ammonia as a sustainable hydrogen carrier.</description>
      <author>Zahra Almisbaa, Philippe Sautet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic order in the computational 2D materials database (C2DB) from high throughput spin spiral calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01318-2</link>
      <description>Joachim S&#248;dequist, Thomas Olsen, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401315005

                Abstract We report high throughput computational screening for magnetic ground state order in 2D materials. The workflow is based on spin spiral calculations and yields the magnetic order in terms of a two-dimensional ordering vector Q . We then include spin-orbit coupling to extract the easy and hard axes for collinear structures and the orientation of spiral planes in non-collinear structures. Finally, for all predicted ferromagnets we compute the Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interactions and determine whether or not these are strong enough to overcome the magnetic anisotropy and stabilise a chiral spin spiral ground state. We find 58 ferromagnets, 21 collinear anti-ferromagnets, and 85 non-collinear ground states of which 15 are chiral spin spirals driven by Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interactions. The results show that non-collinear order is in fact as common as collinear order in these materials and emphasise the need for detailed investigation of the magnetic ground state when reporting magnetic properties of new materials.</description>
      <author>Joachim S&#248;dequist, Thomas Olsen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01318-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colloidal copper nanospheres boost propanol electrosynthesis from CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4544481/v1</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Anna Loiudice, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez Al&#233;, Krishna Kumar, Dragos Stoian, Zan Lian, Petru P. Albertini, Ludovic Zaza, Jari Leemans, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Raffaella Buonsanti, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401323735

                Abstract Achieving a carbon neutral manufacturing of chemicals is imperative to accelerate the transition towards a sustainable future. Propanol electrosynthesis from CO electroreduction represents a promising alternative to the current manufacturing of this chemical. Yet, the catalyst features driving propanol formation are poorly understood, which limits further advancement in the performance. Herein, we report on a comprehensive mapping of the sensitivity of the CO electroreduction to the catalyst structure exploiting well-defined copper nanocrystals (NCs) with tunable shape and size synthesized via colloidal chemistry. In addition to clarify the dependence from the exposed surfaces, we discover that spheres uniquely promote n-propanol selectivity, which we explain mostly with strain effects. Driven by this novel insight, we achieve unprecedent n-propanol production via electrosynthesis with a copper catalyst. We demonstrate that colloidal copper nanospheres with a diameter of 4 nm deliver n-propanol faradaic efficiency of 39.6&#177;1.4% at 119&#177;4.2 mA/cm2 production rate, the latter being ten times the current state of the art for copper catalysts.</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Anna Loiudice, Enric Ib&#225;&#241;ez Al&#233;, Krishna Kumar, Dragos Stoian, Zan Lian, Petru P. Albertini, Ludovic Zaza, Jari Leemans, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Raffaella Buonsanti</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4544481/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ionic liquid&#8211;electrode interface: classification of ions, saturation of layers, and structure-determined potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144829</link>
      <description>Karl Karu, E.R. Nerut, Xueran Tao, Sergei A. Kislenko, Kaija P&#245;hako&#8208;Esko, Iuliia V. Voroshylova, Vladislav Ivani&#353;t&#353;ev, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401325023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karl Karu, E.R. Nerut, Xueran Tao, Sergei A. Kislenko, Kaija P&#245;hako&#8208;Esko, Iuliia V. Voroshylova, Vladislav Ivani&#353;t&#353;ev</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning driven advancements in catalysis for predicting hydrogen evolution reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129805</link>
      <description>Priyanka Sinha, M. V. Jyothirmai, B. Moses Abraham, Jayant K. Singh, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326351

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Priyanka Sinha, M. V. Jyothirmai, B. Moses Abraham, Jayant K. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from Up-Scaling CO2 Capture: Challenges and Experiences with Pilot work</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120576</link>
      <description>Sai Hema Bhavya Vinjarapu, Isaac A. L&#248;ge, Randi Neerup, Anders Hellerup Larsen, Valdemar Emil Rasmussen, Jens Kristian J&#248;rsboe, Sebastian Nis Bay Villadsen, S&#248;ren Holdt Jensen, Jakob Lindkvist Karlsson, Jannik Kappel, Henrik Lassen, Peter Blinksbjerg, Nicolas von Solms, Philip Loldrup Fosb&#248;l, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sai Hema Bhavya Vinjarapu, Isaac A. L&#248;ge, Randi Neerup, Anders Hellerup Larsen, Valdemar Emil Rasmussen, Jens Kristian J&#248;rsboe, Sebastian Nis Bay Villadsen, S&#248;ren Holdt Jensen, Jakob Lindkvist Karlsson, Jannik Kappel, Henrik Lassen, Peter Blinksbjerg, Nicolas von Solms, Philip Loldrup Fosb&#248;l</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spglib: a software library for crystal symmetry search</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/27660400.2024.2384822</link>
      <description>Atsushi Togo, K. Shinohara, Isao Tanaka, Science and Technology of Advanced Materials Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401339223

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Atsushi Togo, K. Shinohara, Isao Tanaka</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/27660400.2024.2384822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano&#8208;Single&#8208;Atom Heterointerface Engineering for pH&#8208;Universal Electrochemical Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409089</link>
      <description>Jian Song, Sheng&#8722;Jie Qian, Wenqiang Yang, Jiali Mu, Jingwei Li, Yaping Liu, Fanfei Sun, Shuwen Yu, Feifei Xu, Xiangen Song, Dehui Deng, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Yan Li, Yunjie Ding, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401339369

                Abstract Nano&#8208;single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts have the potential to combine the respective advantages of both nano&#8208;catalysts and single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts and thus exhibit enhanced performance. Generally, the separation of active sites in space limits the interaction between single atoms and nanoparticles. Heterointerface engineering has the potential to break this limitation. Regretfully, studies on the interface effect between single atoms and nanoparticles are rarely reported. Herein, an unprecedented nano&#8208;single&#8208;atom heterointerface composed of Fe single&#8208;atoms and carbon&#8208;shell&#8208;coated FeP nanoparticles (Fe SAC/FeP@C) is demonstrated as an efficient electrocatalyst for the nitrate reduction process from alkaline to acidic. Compared with typical nano&#8208;single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts (Fe SAC/FePO 4 ) and single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts (Fe SAC), the constructed Fe SAC/FeP@C heterostructure exhibits dramatically enhanced nitrate&#8208;to&#8208;ammonia performance. Especially in acidic media, the maxmium Faradaic efficiency of ammonia (NH 3 ) can reach 95.6 &#177; 0.5%, with a maximum NH 3 yield of 36.2 &#177; 3.1 mg h &#8722;1 mg cat &#8722;1 (pH = 1.2), which is considerably higher than previously reported. Density functional theory calculations and in situ spectroscopic investigations indicate that the unique charge redistribution at the interface, together with the optimized electronic structure of Fe single&#8208;atoms, strengthens intermediate adsorption and catalytic activity. This work provides a feasible strategy for designing nano&#8208;single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts with unique heterointerfaces, as well as valuable insights into nitrate conversion under environmentally relevant wastewater conditions.</description>
      <author>Jian Song, Sheng&#8722;Jie Qian, Wenqiang Yang, Jiali Mu, Jingwei Li, Yaping Liu, Fanfei Sun, Shuwen Yu, Feifei Xu, Xiangen Song, Dehui Deng, Yang&#8208;Gang Wang, Yan Li, Yunjie Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum&#8208;Ruthenium Bimetallic Nanoparticle Catalysts Synthesized Via Direct Joule Heating for Methanol Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403967</link>
      <description>Yeyu Deng, Haibo Liu, Leo Lai, Fangxin She, Fangzhou Liu, Mohan Li, Zixun Yu, Jing Li, Di Zhu, Hao Li, Li Wei, Yuan Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401357624

                Platinum-Ruthenium (PtRu) bimetallic nanoparticles are promising catalysts for methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) required by direct methanol fuel cells. However, existing catalyst synthesis methods have difficulty controlling their composition and structures. Here, a direct Joule heating method to yield highly active and stable PtRu catalysts for MOR is shown. The optimized Joule heating condition at 1000 &#176;C over 50 microseconds produces uniform PtRu nanoparticles (6.32 wt.% Pt and 2.97 wt% Ru) with an average size of 2.0 &#177; 0.5 nanometers supported on carbon black substrates. They have a large electrochemically active surface area (ECSA) of 239 m</description>
      <author>Yeyu Deng, Haibo Liu, Leo Lai, Fangxin She, Fangzhou Liu, Mohan Li, Zixun Yu, Jing Li, Di Zhu, Hao Li, Li Wei, Yuan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bi&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;CuCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Hollow Carbon Nanofibers Boosts NH&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Production from Electrocatalytic Nitrate Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409696</link>
      <description>Hexing Lin, Jinshan Wei, Ying Guo, Yi Li, Xihui Lu, Chucheng Zhou, Shaoqing Liu, Ya&#8208;yun Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358428

                Abstract Ammonia, as a high&#8208;energy&#8208;density carrier for hydrogen storage, is in great demand worldwide. Electrocatalytic nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) provides a green NH 3 production process. However, the complex reaction pathways for NO 3 RR to NH 3 and the difficulty in controlling intermediate products limit the reduction process. Herein, by incorporating atomic&#8208;level bismuth (Bi) into CuCo 2 O 4 hollow carbon nanofibers, the catalytic activity of the electrocatalyst for NO 3 RR is enhanced. The maximum Faradaic efficiency of Bi 1 &#8208;CuCo 2 O 4 is 95.53%, with an NH 3 yield of 448.74 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 at &#8722;0.8 V versus RHE. Density Functional Theory calculations show that the presence of Bi lowers the reaction barrier for the hydrogenation step from *NO 2 to *NO 2 H, while promoting mass transfer on the release of *NH 3 and the reactivation of surface&#8208;active sites. Differential charge density calculations also show that after Bi doping, the charge supplied by the catalyst to NO 3 &#8722; increases from 0.62 to 0.72 e &#8208; , thus reasoned for enhanced NO 3 RR activity. The established nitrate&#8208;Zn battery shows an energy density of 2.81 mW cm &#8722;2 , thus implying the potential application.</description>
      <author>Hexing Lin, Jinshan Wei, Ying Guo, Yi Li, Xihui Lu, Chucheng Zhou, Shaoqing Liu, Ya&#8208;yun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles investigation of the two-dimensional van der Waals g-C3N4/g-ZnO heterojunction: Enhancing the photocatalytic hydrogen evolution activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104919</link>
      <description>Xinxin Tian, Zizhou Cai, Yunlan Sun, Minggao Xu, Baozhong Zhu, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401371191

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinxin Tian, Zizhou Cai, Yunlan Sun, Minggao Xu, Baozhong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Properties of Single-Atom Metal Catalysts Supported on Nitrogen-Doped Carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03232</link>
      <description>Maria G. Minotaki, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401389123

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maria G. Minotaki, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Insights into the ORR Catalysis on Pt Alloy Nanoparticles from an Element Specific &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;-Band Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01912</link>
      <description>Tyler Joe Ziehl, Junrui Li, Shouheng Sun, Peng Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401395709

                Bolstered by their unique atomic structures and tailored compositions, nanoalloys exhibit extraordinary properties making them ideal materials to solve challenges in energy storage and conversion catalysis. However, a quantitative description of the structure-property relationships using an accurate descriptor-based model for nanoalloys, ranging from bimetallic to multimetallic compositions, is needed to drive efficient material design toward high-performance catalysis. In this work, we highlight the electronic property and catalytic activity relationship from an element specific</description>
      <author>Tyler Joe Ziehl, Junrui Li, Shouheng Sun, Peng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Ammonia Oxidation to Nitrite and Nitrate with NiOOH&#8208;Ni</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401675</link>
      <description>Hanwen Liu, Cheng&#8208;Jie Yang, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Jiashu Wang, Xin Zhang, Andrey Lyalin, Tetsuya Taketsugu, Zhiqi Chen, Daqin Guan, Xiaomin Xu, Zongping Shao, Zhenguo Huang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401396156

                Abstract Ammonia electrooxidation in aqueous solutions can be a highly energy&#8208;efficient process in producing nitrate and nitrite while generating hydrogen under ambient conditions. However, the kinetics of this reaction are slow and the role of catalyst in facilitating ammonia electrooxidation is not well understood. In this study, a high&#8208;performance NiOOH&#8208;Ni catalyst is introduced for converting ammonia into nitrite with Faraday efficiency of up to 90.4% and nitrate production rate of 1 mg h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 . By employing Operando techniques, the role of NiOOH catalyst is elucidated in the dynamic electrooxidation of ammonia. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations support experimental observations and reveal the mechanism of the electrochemical oxidation of ammonia to nitrite and nitrate. Overall, this research contributes to the development of a cost&#8208;effective and highly efficient catalyst for large&#8208;scale ammonia electrolysis, while shedding light on the underlying mechanism of the NiOOH catalyst in ammonia electrooxidation.</description>
      <author>Hanwen Liu, Cheng&#8208;Jie Yang, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Jiashu Wang, Xin Zhang, Andrey Lyalin, Tetsuya Taketsugu, Zhiqi Chen, Daqin Guan, Xiaomin Xu, Zongping Shao, Zhenguo Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Atom&#8211;Support Interaction in Single Atom Catalysts toward Hydrogen Peroxide Electrosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c07916</link>
      <description>Jizhou Duan, Haitao Xu, Wang Gao, Shanshan Chen, Feng Li, Dongyuan Zhao, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401397949

                Single metal atom catalysts (SACs) have garnered considerable attention as promising agents for catalyzing important industrial reactions, particularly the electrochemical synthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H</description>
      <author>Jizhou Duan, Haitao Xu, Wang Gao, Shanshan Chen, Feng Li, Dongyuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c07916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Morphology of Layered Double Hydroxide in Electrochemical Energy Storage and Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400519</link>
      <description>Peng Song, Qianfeng Pan, Yixuan Qiao, Tiantian Wang, Nyan Lynn Htut, Bo Chen, Marc A. Anderson, Yang Wang, Han Hu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401400887

                The development of nanomaterials for energy storage and conversion has always been important. Layered double hydroxide (LDH) is a promising material due to its high capacity, tunable composition and easy synthesis. In this work, the morphology of NiCo-LDH is tuned with surfactants including sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS) and cetyltrimethylammonium bromide (CTAB), and investigated the correlation between morphology and electrochemical properties. NiCo-LDH-SDS with a layered structure exhibited a specific capacitance of 1004 C g</description>
      <author>Peng Song, Qianfeng Pan, Yixuan Qiao, Tiantian Wang, Nyan Lynn Htut, Bo Chen, Marc A. Anderson, Yang Wang, Han Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging electrocatalysts for green ammonia production: Recent progress and future outlook</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arabjc.2024.105950</link>
      <description>Sajid Mahmood, Shahid Iqbal, Sajid Mahmood, Muhammad Ammar, Muhammad Javed Iqbal, Ali Bahadur, Nasser S. Awwad, Hala A. Ibrahium, Arabian Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401406586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sajid Mahmood, Shahid Iqbal, Sajid Mahmood, Muhammad Ammar, Muhammad Javed Iqbal, Ali Bahadur, Nasser S. Awwad, Hala A. Ibrahium</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arabjc.2024.105950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable topological magnetism in superlattices of nonmagnetic B20 systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.l060407</link>
      <description>Vladislav Borisov, Anna Delin, Olle Eriksson, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401418556

                We predict topological magnetic properties of B20 systems, that are organized in atomically thin multilayers. In particular, we focus on FeSi/CoSi and FeSi/FeGe superlattices with different numbers of layers and interface structures. We demonstrate that the absence of long-range magnetic order, previously observed in bulk FeSi and CoSi, is broken near the FeSi/CoSi interface, where a magnetic state with a nontrivial topological texture appears. Using the Heisenberg and Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya (DM) interactions calculated from first principles, we perform finite-temperature atomistic spin dynamics simulations for up to 2&#215;106 spins to capture the complexity of noncollinear textures. Our simulations predict the formation of antiskyrmions in a [001]-oriented FeSi/CoSi multilayer, intermediate skyrmions in a [111]-oriented FeSi/CoSi system, and Bloch skyrmions in the FeSi/FeGe (001) system, with a size between 7 and 37 nm. These varieties of topological magnetic textures in the studied systems can be attributed to the complex asymmetric structure of the DM matrix, which is different from previously known magnetic materials. We demonstrate that through structural engineering both ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic skyrmions can be stabilized, where the latter are especially appealing for applications due to the zero skyrmion Hall effect. The proposed B20 multilayers show a potential for further exploration and call for experimental confirmation. Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Vladislav Borisov, Anna Delin, Olle Eriksson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.l060407</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Low Temperature Lithium-ion Battery Performance under High-rate Conditions with Niobium Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101663</link>
      <description>Elizabeth A. Pogue, Spencer Langevin, Tanner Hamann, Karun K. Rao, Marshall A. Schroeder, Nam Q. Le, Courtney McHale, Zachary Burchfield, Jesse S. Ko, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401422129

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elizabeth A. Pogue, Spencer Langevin, Tanner Hamann, Karun K. Rao, Marshall A. Schroeder, Nam Q. Le, Courtney McHale, Zachary Burchfield, Jesse S. Ko</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of Extrinsic Factors That Limit the Catalytic Performance of Transition Metal Dichalcogenides (TMDs) in Hydrogen Evolution Reactions (HER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400259</link>
      <description>Jeyavelan Muthu, Farheen Khurshid, Mario Hofmann, Ya&#8208;Ping Hsieh, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401427676

                Abstract Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) have garnered attention as potential catalysts for water splitting owing to their unique structures, diverse electronic properties, and composition from earth&#8208;abundant elements. While certain TMD catalysts, notably MoS 2 , have shown promising activity for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER), achieving performance comparable to traditional platinum catalysts remains a challenge. While significant effort has been invested into understanding the effect of TMD's structural properties, such as defectiveness and crystalline phases, recent work has emphasized the role of extrinsic factors on HER. This review summarizes the current understanding of the impact of commonly overlooked electrocatalytic effects that exhibit an enhanced importance in TMD&#8208;based HER. By combining recent advances in theoretical modeling and experimental work, we review the dominating effects of extrinsic factors including electronic resistance, interfacial barriers, surface roughness, oxidation, and valence impurities. Our work aims to provide insights into optimizing TMDs as highly efficient catalysts for HER, facilitating future advancements in hydrogen generation technology.</description>
      <author>Jeyavelan Muthu, Farheen Khurshid, Mario Hofmann, Ya&#8208;Ping Hsieh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Direct Electrochemical Fischer&#8211;Tropsch Chemistry of C&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;C&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrocarbons via Perimeter Engineering of Au&#8211;SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402062</link>
      <description>Ju Hyun Yang, Gi Beom Sim, So Jeong Park, Choong Kyun Rhee, Chang Woo Myung, Youngku Sohn, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401427793

                Abstract Traditionally, Fischer&#8211;Tropsch (FT) synthesis is performed using thermal catalysts and syngas (CO and H 2 ) under high&#8208;pressure and high&#8208;temperature conditions. However, this study introduces an approach that relies on FT chemistry assisted by electrochemistry, referred to here as direct electrochemical (EC) FT chemistry, under ambient conditions. A series of CH 4 , C n H 2n , and C n H 2n+2 hydrocarbons (n = 1&#8211;7) is successfully produced over gold (Au) nanoparticle&#8208;loaded perovskite strontium titanate (SrTiO 3 ) nanostructures grown on rutile TiO 2 supported on Ti. Au (1.0 nm)&#8211;SrTiO 3 shows the best interface formation, with the highest Faradaic efficiency for C 2+ hydrocarbons. This direct EC&#8208;FT process proceeds via a C&#9472;C coupling chain growth reaction at the Au&#8208;SrTiO 3 interface as evidenced by the hydrocarbon weight distribution analysis and density functional theory calculations. The robust combination of experimental and computational findings reveals that optimum conditions for producing surface hydrogenation and C&#9472;C coupling polymerization, initiated by surface * CO and * H are achieved by controlling the undercoordinated Au at the perimeter sites of supported Au nanoparticles and by ensuring a harmonized density of states between Au and SrTiO 3 . This EC&#8208;FT process opens a promising avenue for the direct conversion of CO 2 and H 2 O into value&#8208;added long&#8208;chain hydrocarbons.</description>
      <author>Ju Hyun Yang, Gi Beom Sim, So Jeong Park, Choong Kyun Rhee, Chang Woo Myung, Youngku Sohn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the scaling relations of effective CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; electrochemical reduction in diatomic catalysts by adjusting the flow direction of intermediate structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03085k</link>
      <description>Yanwen Zhang, Zhaoqun Yao, Yiming Yang, Xingwu Zhai, Feng Zhang, Zhijun Guo, Xinghuan Liu, Bin Yang, Yunxia Liang, Guixian Ge, Xin Jia, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401430982

                High-throughput calculations show 11 flow directions from *CO to *CHO on DACs. The catalyst disrupting the linear adsorption relationship is linked to multiple, not just one, flow direction.</description>
      <author>Yanwen Zhang, Zhaoqun Yao, Yiming Yang, Xingwu Zhai, Feng Zhang, Zhijun Guo, Xinghuan Liu, Bin Yang, Yunxia Liang, Guixian Ge, Xin Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03085k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical enhancement for TiO2-based photoanodes: in-situ electrochemical analysis, modification strategies and mechanism studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144859</link>
      <description>Xiaoying Shang, Shouxin Zhang, Zhiwei Li, Li Fu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401433845

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoying Shang, Shouxin Zhang, Zhiwei Li, Li Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxophilic gallium single atoms bridged ruthenium clusters for practical anion-exchange membrane electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51200-4</link>
      <description>Chenhui Zhou, Jia Shi, Zhaoqi Dong, Yunqi Liu, Yan Chen, Ying Han, Lu Li, Wenyu Zhang, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Fan Lv, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437692

                The development of highly efficient and durable alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalysts is crucial for achieving high-performance practical anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) at ampere-level current density. Herein, we report a design concept by employing Ga single atoms as an electronic bridge to stabilize the Ru clusters for boosting alkaline HER performance in practical AEMWE. Experimental and theoretical results collectively reveal that the bridged Ga sites trigger strong metal-support interaction for the homogeneous distribution of Ru clusters with high density, as well as optimize the Ru-H bond strength due to the electron transfer between Ru and Ga for enhanced intrinsic HER activity. Moreover, the oxophilic Ga sites near the Ru clusters tend to adsorb the hydroxyl species and accelerate the water dissociation for sufficient proton supplement in an alkaline medium. The Ru-Ga</description>
      <author>Chenhui Zhou, Jia Shi, Zhaoqi Dong, Yunqi Liu, Yan Chen, Ying Han, Lu Li, Wenyu Zhang, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Fan Lv, Mingchuan Luo, Shaojun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51200-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HfS2/BN Heterostructures: A Repeatable Detectable Water Sensing Material</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104906</link>
      <description>Jiashuo Zhang, Zihan Chen, Tongtong Li, Junkuo Gao, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401295962

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiashuo Zhang, Zihan Chen, Tongtong Li, Junkuo Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles data for solid solution niobium-tantalum-vanadium alloys with body-centered-cubic structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-qpwsg-v2</link>
      <description>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, German D. Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Jong Youl Choi, Junqi Yin, Ying Yang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401335548

                We present four open-source datasets that provide results of density functional theory (DFT) calculations of ground-state properties of refractory solid solution binary alloys niobium-tantalum (NbTa), niobium-vanadium (NbV), tantalum-vanadium (TaV), and ternary alloys NbTaV ordered in body-centered-cubic (BCC) structures with 128 Bravais lattice sites. The first-principles code used to run the calculations is the Vienna Ab-Initio Simulation Package. The calculations have been collected by uniformly sampling chemical compositions across the entire compositional range. For each chemical composition, the calculations have been run for 100 randomized arrangements of the constituents on the BCC lattice sites. This sampling methodology resulted in running DFT simulations for a total of 3,100 randomized atomic configurations over 31 chemical compositions for each of the three binary alloys Nb-Ta, Nb-V, Ta-V, and a total of 10,500 randomized atomic structures over 105 chemical compositions for the ternary alloys Nb-Ta-V. For each atomic configuration, geometry optimization has been performed, and the data released contains information about each step of geometry optimization for each atomic configuration.</description>
      <author>Massimiliano Lupo Pasini, German D. Samolyuk, Markus Eisenbach, Jong Youl Choi, Junqi Yin, Ying Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-qpwsg-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially Resolved Uncertainties for Machine Learning Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00904</link>
      <description>Esther Heid, Johannes Sch&#246;rghuber, Ralf Wanzenb&#246;ck, Georg K. H. Madsen, Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401386355

                Machine learning potentials have become an essential tool for atomistic simulations, yielding results close to ab initio simulations at a fraction of computational cost. With recent improvements on the achievable accuracies, the focus has now shifted on the data set composition itself. The reliable identification of erroneously predicted configurations to extend a given data set is therefore of high priority. Yet, uncertainty estimation techniques have achieved mixed results for machine learning potentials. Consequently, a general and versatile method to correlate energy or atomic force uncertainties with the model error has remained elusive to date. In the current work, we show that epistemic uncertainty cannot correlate with model error by definition but can be aggregated over groups of atoms to yield a strong correlation. We demonstrate that our method correctly estimates prediction errors both globally per structure and locally resolved per atom. The direct correlation of local uncertainty and local error is used to design an active learning framework based on identifying local subregions of a large simulation cell and performing ab initio calculations only for the subregion subsequently. We successfully utilized this method to perform active learning in the low-data regime for liquid water.</description>
      <author>Esther Heid, Johannes Sch&#246;rghuber, Ralf Wanzenb&#246;ck, Georg K. H. Madsen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00904</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
