<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 01:24:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Perovskite Oxides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Structures, Mechanisms, and Strategies for Performance Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416705</link>
      <description>Xiong Sun, Ying Yuan, Shuzhi Liu, Hongqing Zhao, Suqiang Yao, Sun Yuying, Shouxin Zhang, Yijiang Liu, Zhiqun Lin, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404618145

                Abstract Perovskite&#8208;type oxides are widely employed as oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts due to their tunable composition, diverse structure, abundant natural reserves, remarkable stability, and low cost. The intrinsic OER electrocatalytic activity of these perovskite oxides is generally enhanced by improving conductivity, increasing specific surface area, and optimizing the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates. This is achieved through rationally designed strategies, including compositional engineering, defect engineering, hybridization, and surface regulation. In this review, recent advances in perovskite oxides for OER are summarized, with a focus on exploring structure&#8208;performance relationships. This review provides a brief introduction to the application of perovskite oxides in OER, followed by the classification and characteristics of these perovskite oxides. The primary OER catalytic mechanisms, and well&#8208;established activity descriptors are discussed. The key strategies are concentrated for enhancing OER activity, including composition engineering, defect engineering, hybridization, and surface reconstruction. Finally, the challenges and opportunities in developing high&#8208;performance perovskite oxides as OER electrocatalysts are presented.</description>
      <author>Xiong Sun, Ying Yuan, Shuzhi Liu, Hongqing Zhao, Suqiang Yao, Sun Yuying, Shouxin Zhang, Yijiang Liu, Zhiqun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>: A Toolkit for Autonomous, User-Guided Construction of Machine-Learned Potential Energy Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109446</link>
      <description>Kai T&#246;pfer, Luis Itza Vazquez-Salazar, Markus Meuwly, Computer Physics Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404626715

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai T&#246;pfer, Luis Itza Vazquez-Salazar, Markus Meuwly</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2024.109446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Cationic Vacancy Defects to Switch Oxygen Evolution Mechanisms on Atomically Dispersed Ru for Enhanced Acidic Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124845</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Deshuai Yang, Zhen Yang, Lili Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404628614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Deshuai Yang, Zhen Yang, Lili Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Photocatalytic Conversion of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Ethanol via Unsaturated Cu&#8211;O Domains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11842</link>
      <description>Yan Wang, Mingqi He, Pengxin Yang, Yanan Zhou, Li Wang, Kaifu Zhang, Zhuo Jiang, Qiquan Luo, Shan Gao, Jinlong Yang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404629041

                Enhancing the selectivity of photocatalytic CO2 reduction to valuable multicarbon (C2+) products remains a significant challenge in green synthetic chemistry. Here, we present a dual-center strategy for metal oxides that boosts the photochemical conversion of CO2 to ethanol by regulating the coordination number of metal and oxygen sites. Notably, CuO catalysts rich in low-coordinated Cu&#8211;O domains have achieved nearly perfect ethanol selectivity (96.9%), extraordinary durability (60 h), and a superior yield rate of 30.5 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1, surpassing the performance of many existing photocatalysts in water vapor and CO2. Density functional theory calculations and operando spectroscopic results provide conclusive evidence that tricoordinated copper (Cu3c) increases the coverage of key *CO species, while bicoordinated oxygen (O2c) controls the migration of *CO species, thereby effectively reducing the energy requirement for *CO dimerization into *OC&#8211;CO intermediates (&#916;G*OC&#8211;CO = &#8722;0.56 eV) in the ethanol pathway. This work offers valuable insights for designing photocatalysts that exhibit improved selectivity for C2+ fuels.</description>
      <author>Yan Wang, Mingqi He, Pengxin Yang, Yanan Zhou, Li Wang, Kaifu Zhang, Zhuo Jiang, Qiquan Luo, Shan Gao, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving electrocatalytic OER activity of perovskites through insertion of ternary B-site metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102414</link>
      <description>M. Jones, Cheng Lyu, David P. Trudgeon, Jack Corbin, Ida Nawrocka, Zhenyu Zhang, Mikkel B. Lykkegaard, Shaoliang Guan, Tim Dodwell, Xiaohong Li, Materials Today Chemistry. 42(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404629505

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Jones, Cheng Lyu, David P. Trudgeon, Jack Corbin, Ida Nawrocka, Zhenyu Zhang, Mikkel B. Lykkegaard, Shaoliang Guan, Tim Dodwell, Xiaohong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in advanced design of iridium&#8208;based and ruthenium&#8208;based perovskite catalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.79</link>
      <description>Yuqing Cheng, Yibo Wang, Zhaoping Shi, Hongxiang Wu, Jiahao Yang, Jing Ni, Ming Yang, Ziang Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631203

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is of great importance for the production of green hydrogen. The large&#8208;scale implementation of PEMWE, however, is seriously impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode, which results in considerable overpotential and thus the decreased energy conversion efficiency. To overcome this problem, researchers have extensively explored efficient anode catalysts that possess high activity and prolonged stability. Up to now, Ir&#8208;based and Ru&#8208;based catalysts are considered to be the most efficient candidates. Especially perovskite&#8208;based catalysts have received intensive attention due to their distinctive structures and exceptional OER catalytic performance. To further promote their practical application, considerable research efforts are devoted to structural engineering toward enhanced activity and stability. In this paper, a review of the research progress on the advanced design of Ir&#8208; and Ru&#8208;based perovskite catalysts is presented, with a focus on phase engineering, doping/substitution, morphology control, and compositing with other materials for perovskite catalysts as well as some preparation methods commonly used. It also summarizes the challenges and opportunities concerning perovskite&#8208;based catalysts in current research, yielding further comprehension of the pertinent preparation and scrutiny of perovskite catalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Cheng, Yibo Wang, Zhaoping Shi, Hongxiang Wu, Jiahao Yang, Jing Ni, Ming Yang, Ziang Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.79</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe/Co bimetallic borides with modified electronic structure for Efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161893</link>
      <description>Shuai Wan, Lihong Bao, Yuyang Zong, Jiayu Xiao, Jiaru He, Xinyu Gao, Sheng Wang, Ruguang Ma, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631327

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Wan, Lihong Bao, Yuyang Zong, Jiayu Xiao, Jiaru He, Xinyu Gao, Sheng Wang, Ruguang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161893</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying stable Nb-O clusters using evolutionary algorithm and DFT: A foundation for machine learning potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112533</link>
      <description>I.S. Popov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1042;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, Andrey N. Enyashin, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631358

                No abstract</description>
      <author>I.S. Popov, &#1040;. &#1040;. &#1042;&#1072;&#1083;&#1077;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, Andrey N. Enyashin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking performance: A round-robin testing for liquid alkaline electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.288</link>
      <description>Simon Appelhaus, L. Ritz, Sharon V. Pape, Felix Lohmann&#8208;Richters, Mikkel Ryk&#230;r Kraglund, Jens Oluf Jensen, Francesco Massari, Mehrdad Boroomandnia, Matteo C. Romano, Justin Albers, Clemens Kubeil, Christian Immanuel Bern&#228;cker, Michelle Sophie Lemcke, Nadine Menzel, Guido Bender, Binyu Chen, Steven Holdcroft, Renaud Delmelle, Joris Proost, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Pertti Kauranen, Vesa Ruuskanen, Toni Viinanen, Martin M&#252;ller, Thomas Turek, Meital Shviro, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 95(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404632463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simon Appelhaus, L. Ritz, Sharon V. Pape, Felix Lohmann&#8208;Richters, Mikkel Ryk&#230;r Kraglund, Jens Oluf Jensen, Francesco Massari, Mehrdad Boroomandnia, Matteo C. Romano, Justin Albers, Clemens Kubeil, Christian Immanuel Bern&#228;cker, Michelle Sophie Lemcke, Nadine Menzel, Guido Bender, Binyu Chen, Steven Holdcroft, Renaud Delmelle, Joris Proost, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Pertti Kauranen, Vesa Ruuskanen, Toni Viinanen, Martin M&#252;ller, Thomas Turek, Meital Shviro</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Electronic Correlations in Ruthenium Oxides for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00068</link>
      <description>Xianbing Miao, Jingda Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Shiming Zhou, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404632938

                Elucidating the electronic factors dominating the adsorption properties of transition-metal oxides is essential to construct highly efficient oxygen-evolving catalysts for hydrogen production by water splitting but remains a great challenge. Electron correlation from on-site Coulomb repulsion (U) among d-electrons is generally believed to significantly affect the electronic structure of these materials; however, it has long been neglected in studying their adsorption properties. Here, by choosing ruthenium oxide as a model system, we demonstrate the role of electron correlation on the electrocatalytic activity toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Our density functional theory plus U calculations on rutile RuO2 reveal that the electron correlation can tune the adsorption energies for oxygenated intermediate and optimize them after the metallic oxide being a Mott insulator upon increasing U. By regulating the RuO6 octahedral network, we constructed and synthesized a series of strongly correlated ruthenium oxides, where the Mott insulating ones indeed exhibit a superior OER performance to the metallic RuO2. Our work builds a bridge between the electrochemistry and Mott physics for transition-metal oxides, opening a new avenue for designing advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xianbing Miao, Jingda Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Shiming Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Offsetting Carbon Footprints: Exploring CCUS Challenges and Solutions Across Diverse Industries in India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-70262-4_10</link>
      <description>Bidisha Chakrabarti, Sadichha Jagadale, Hemant Bherwani, Rajesh B. Biniwale, Environmental footprints and eco-design of products and processes. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404633031

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bidisha Chakrabarti, Sadichha Jagadale, Hemant Bherwani, Rajesh B. Biniwale</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-70262-4_10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversion of Waste Tecoma Leaves into Heteroatom Doped Graphitic Carbon via a One-Step Chemical Activation Method for the Catalytic Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Supercapacitor Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.4c00329</link>
      <description>Avinash Sharma, Prakash Majee, Pooja Pooja, Ravinder Pawar, Yadagiri Naik Banothu, Mukul Pradhan, ACS Sustainable Resource Management. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404634956

                For solid waste management and sustainable development, the conversion of waste materials into valuable feedstocks is essential. Keeping in mind the concept of "waste-to-wealth," we have synthesized value-added microporous graphitic carbon from waste Tecoma leaves, referred to as TA, through a one-step chemical activation process and utilized it for oxygen reduction reactions (ORRs) and capacitive energy storage applications. The transformation of biomass into metal-free porous graphitic carbon having an ORR efficiency comparable to or even better than commercially available Pt/C is critical for renewable energy conversion technologies. The TA-900 sample, synthesized at 900 &#176;C having a high surface area of 1429 m2 g&#8211;1, containing 4.41 atom % nitrogen and 4.74 atom % oxygen, demonstrated excellent ORR performance among the synthesized graphitic carbon samples at different temperatures. It showed an onset potential (Eonset) of 1 V and a limiting current density (JL) of 6.21 mA cm&#8211;2, comparable to 10 wt % Pt/C. Both experimental and theoretical findings suggest that the TA-900 electrocatalyst exhibited a 4e&#8211; transfer mechanism in the electrocatalytic reduction of O2 to H2O. Regarding supercapacitor application, TA-900 achieved a high specific capacitance of 546 F g&#8211;1 in acidic and 327 F g&#8211;1 in neutral aqueous electrolyte at a current density of 1 A g&#8211;1 in a three-electrode setup. The TA-900-based symmetrical supercapacitor (SSC) device has remarkable durability, retaining its 84% capacitance retention even after 3000 cycles at 1 A g&#8211;1. It also achieved a notable energy density (33 Wh kg&#8211;1 and 6.60 mWh cm&#8211;3) and a power density (6.20 kW kg&#8211;1 and 1320 mW cm&#8211;3). The findings emphasize that heteroatom-doped TA-900 electrocatalysts synthesized from waste Tecoma leaves will be a promising, affordable alternative to the high-cost Pt/C catalyst used for clean energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Avinash Sharma, Prakash Majee, Pooja Pooja, Ravinder Pawar, Yadagiri Naik Banothu, Mukul Pradhan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.4c00329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights into the hydrogen evolution reaction catalyzed by Co MoP (n = 1 &#8764; 5) clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112527</link>
      <description>Tinghui Wu, Zhigang Zak Fang, Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635623

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tinghui Wu, Zhigang Zak Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2024.112527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Donation from Carbon Support Enhances the Activity and Stability of Ultrasmall Ruo2 Nanoparticles in Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030506</link>
      <description>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the in-gap defect states in the photo-generated electrons&#8217; dynamics over two dimensional defective bismuth oxybromide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physleta.2024.130080</link>
      <description>Z. Fan, Mengshi Zhou, Jin Li, Chaoyu He, Tao Ouyang, Chunxiao Zhang, Chao Tang, Jianxin Zhong, Physics Letters A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Z. Fan, Mengshi Zhou, Jin Li, Chaoyu He, Tao Ouyang, Chunxiao Zhang, Chao Tang, Jianxin Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physleta.2024.130080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Pretrained Transformer for Heterogeneous Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11504</link>
      <description>Dong Hyeon Mok, Seoin Back, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404636284

                Discovery of novel and promising materials is a critical challenge in the field of chemistry and material science, traditionally approached through methodologies ranging from trial-and-error to machine-learning-driven inverse design. Recent studies suggest that transformer-based language models can be utilized as material generative models to expand the chemical space and explore materials with desired properties. In this work, we introduce the catalyst generative pretrained transformer (CatGPT), trained to generate string representations of inorganic catalyst structures from a vast chemical space. CatGPT not only demonstrates high performance in generating valid and accurate catalyst structures but also serves as a foundation model for generating the desired types of catalysts by text-conditioning and fine-tuning. As an example, we fine-tuned the pretrained CatGPT using a binary alloy catalyst data set designed for screening two-electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e-ORR) catalyst and generated catalyst structures specialized for 2e-ORR. Our work demonstrates the potential of generative language models as generative tools for catalyst discovery.</description>
      <author>Dong Hyeon Mok, Seoin Back</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of uncompensated resistance on Hads-terminated Pt electrodeposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-06130-y</link>
      <description>Yihua Liu, M.C. Lafouresse, Ugo Bertocci, John E. Bonevich, Joseph A. Dura, Lee J. Richter, Gery R. Stafford, Thomas P. Moffat, Journal of Solid State Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404636983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yihua Liu, M.C. Lafouresse, Ugo Bertocci, John E. Bonevich, Joseph A. Dura, Lee J. Richter, Gery R. Stafford, Thomas P. Moffat</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-06130-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prebiotic formation of enantiomeric excess D-amino acids on natural pyrite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54481-x</link>
      <description>Ruiqi Li, Quanzheng Deng, Lu Han, Tianwei Ouyang, Shunai Che, Yuxi Fang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404639395

                D-amino acids, found in excess in a minority of organisms and crucial for marine invertebrates, contrast with the more common L-amino acids in most life forms. The local prebiotic origin of D-amino acid enantiomeric excess in natural systems remains an unsolved conundrum. Herein, we demonstrate the formation of enantiomeric excess (ee) D-amino acids through photocatalytic reductive amination of &#945;-keto acids on natural pyrite. Various amino acids with ee values in the range of 14.5&#8211;42.4%, are formed. The wavy arrangement of atoms on the surface of pyrite is speculated to lead to the preferential formation of D-amino acids. This work reveals the intrinsic asymmetric photocatalytic activity of pyrite, which could expand understandings on mechanism of asymmetric catalysis and chirality of inorganic crystals. Furthermore, it provides a plausible pathway for the prebiotic formation of D-amino acids, adding further evidence to the origin of D-amino acids enantiomeric excess in natural systems. Enantiomeric excess D-amino acids form via photocatalytic reductive amination of &#945;-keto acids on natural pyrite. This provides a plausible pathway for the prebiotic formation of D-amino acids.</description>
      <author>Ruiqi Li, Quanzheng Deng, Lu Han, Tianwei Ouyang, Shunai Che, Yuxi Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54481-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical ozone production: from fundamental mechanisms to advanced applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00204k</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Xiaoge Peng, Xiaosa Wang, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang, EES Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404640974

                This work explores the mechanism of electrochemical ozone production (EOP), focusing on electrocatalyst development, standardized testing, EOP electrolyzer design and application. By addressing challenges and summarizing progress, it aims to promote practical EOP application in diverse fields.</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Xiaoge Peng, Xiaosa Wang, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00204k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and kinetic analysis of the oxygen evolution reaction on TiO2 (100) and (101) surfaces: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122654</link>
      <description>Felipe Marinho Fernandes, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, M&#225;rcio Soares Pereira, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404642081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Felipe Marinho Fernandes, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, M&#225;rcio Soares Pereira, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolating Cu-Zn active-sites in Ordered Intermetallics to Enhance Nitrite-to-Ammonia Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53897-9</link>
      <description>Jiao Lan, Sheng Wang, Cheng&#8208;Wei Kao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Feng Xie, Yongwen Tan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404643314

                Electrocatalytic nitrite reduction to the valuable ammonia is a green and sustainable alternative to the conventional Haber-Bosch method for ammonia synthesis, while the activity and selectivity for ammonia production remains poor at low nitrite concentrations. Herein, we report a nanoporous intermetallic single-atom alloy CuZn (np/ISAA-CuZn) catalyst with completely isolated Cu-Zn active-sites, which achieves neutral nitrite reduction reaction with a remarkable NH3 Faradaic efficiency over 95% and the highest energy efficiency of &#8776; 59.1% in wide potential range from &#8722;0.2 to &#8722;0.8 V vs. RHE. The np/ISAA-CuZn electrocatalyst was able to operate stably at 500 mA cm&#8722;2 for 220 h under membrane electrode assembly conditions with a stabilized NH3 Faraday efficiency of ~80% and high NO2&#8210; removal rate of ~100%. A series of in situ experimental studies combined with density functional theory calculations reveal that strong electronic interactions of isolated Cu-Zn active-sites altered the protonation adsorption species, effectively alleviating the protonation barrier of *NO2 and thus greatly facilitating the selective reduction of NO2&#8722; into NH3. Electrocatalytic nitrite reduction is a green alternative to the Haber-Bosch process, but its ammonia production remains inefficient at low nitrite levels. Here the authors report an intermetallic single atom alloy CuZn catalyst for nitrite reduction to ammonia with high efficiency and stability at low nitrite concentration of 1&#8722;10 mM.</description>
      <author>Jiao Lan, Sheng Wang, Cheng&#8208;Wei Kao, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Feng Xie, Yongwen Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53897-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis beyond the Reversible Hydrogen Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101611</link>
      <description>Dipam Manish Patel, Anjana Tripathi, Vivianne K. Ocampo-Restrepo, Georg Kastlunger, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404651800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dipam Manish Patel, Anjana Tripathi, Vivianne K. Ocampo-Restrepo, Georg Kastlunger</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101611</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing effects of edge-N in Pt-based carbon support on hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105499</link>
      <description>Xianyou Luo, Bokai Cao, Muhammad Fayaz, Wende Lai, Baodong Du, Heng Zheng, Xunhui Xiong, Yong Chen, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404653390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianyou Luo, Bokai Cao, Muhammad Fayaz, Wende Lai, Baodong Du, Heng Zheng, Xunhui Xiong, Yong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using CrN4 Moiety to Weaken the Dissociation Barrier of Hydroxyl on Adjacent Single Iron Atom for Efficient Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103927</link>
      <description>Li-Lian Wang, Lei Zhu, Xinyu Zhao, Hang Ma, Bingjie Pang, Lingyan Duan, Kun Zeng, Lu Liu, Anran Chen, Hong Guo, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404655119

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li-Lian Wang, Lei Zhu, Xinyu Zhao, Hang Ma, Bingjie Pang, Lingyan Duan, Kun Zeng, Lu Liu, Anran Chen, Hong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Reconstructed Fe&#8208;CoOOH Semi&#8208;Crystalline Electrocatalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408854</link>
      <description>Abdul Qayum, Karim Harrath, Rui Li, Abebe Reda Woldu, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Fushen Lu, Xiangdong Yao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657010

                Abstract The development of robust and efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been the main focus of water electrolysis but remains a great challenge. Here, the synthesis of a highly active and ultra&#8208;stable Fe&#8208;CoOOH electrocatalyst is reported by steering raw cobalt foam via an in situ solution combustion method assisted by a galvanic replacement reaction and subsequent electrochemical reconstruction of the CoFeO x pre&#8208;catalyst. In/ ex situ electrochemical analysis and physicochemical characterizations show that the CoFeO x undergoes quick chemical and slow morphological reconstruction to Fe&#8208;CoOOH nanosheets. The Fe&#8208;CoOOH possesses a semi&#8208;crystalline nature with distinct short&#8208;range ordering and outstanding OER activity with overpotentials as low as 271 and 291 mV at current densities of 500 and 1,000 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The remarkable stability under 1,000 mA cm &#8722;2 for at least 700 h is achieved. Theoretical calculations confirm the crucial role of Fe doping in facilitating surface reconstruction, enhancing OER activity, and improving the stability of the Fe&#8208;CoOOH. Comparative analysis with other transition metals doping reveals the unique ability of Fe to adsorb onto the CoOOH surface, thereby modulating the electronic density and facilitating faster adsorption of reaction intermediates. This work represents valuable insights into the surface reconstruction and doping processes.</description>
      <author>Abdul Qayum, Karim Harrath, Rui Li, Abebe Reda Woldu, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Fushen Lu, Xiangdong Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of biaxial strain and sulfur/boron doping on the photocatalytic performance of the g-C3N5 system: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113560</link>
      <description>Yongde Yao, Fujian Tang, Shangtong Yang, Computational Materials Science. 247(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657649

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongde Yao, Fujian Tang, Shangtong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Ni-coordinated MOF on stainless steel via electrodeposition as efficient and stable oxygen evolution electrode for alkaline water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145416</link>
      <description>Valentina Maria Volanti, Andrea Zaffora, Leonardo Iannucci, Sabrina Grassini, Elisabetta Inico, Clara Saetta, Giovanni Di Liberto, Monica Santamaria, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657854

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Valentina Maria Volanti, Andrea Zaffora, Leonardo Iannucci, Sabrina Grassini, Elisabetta Inico, Clara Saetta, Giovanni Di Liberto, Monica Santamaria</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical behavior of LiNiCo oxide cathodes as catalyst for lithium-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-06149-1</link>
      <description>E. Meza, Francisco Herrera, Juan Luis Gautier, Journal of Solid State Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404662045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. Meza, Francisco Herrera, Juan Luis Gautier</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-06149-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing the carbon nano-belt (8-CNB) loaded late second-row transition metal (TM) single-atom catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution during water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109139</link>
      <description>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Shimna Biju, Remabai Balachandran, Khurshid Ayub, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 187(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404670172

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Shimna Biju, Remabai Balachandran, Khurshid Ayub, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo-assisted highly efficient electrocatalytic N2 fixation on nonmetal-metal dual atom catalysts through the reversable evolution of active center</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114712</link>
      <description>Zheng Xu, Yi Ding, Song Lu, Tiancun Liu, Hailing Liu, Yong Jun Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu, Molecular Catalysis. 571(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404676999

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheng Xu, Yi Ding, Song Lu, Tiancun Liu, Hailing Liu, Yong Jun Wu, Yafei Zhao, Zhixin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the performance of g-C3N4 loaded silver nanoparticles (Ag4, Ag8, Ag13) catalysts and their electrocatalytic reduction mechanism of CO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114705</link>
      <description>Xin-Long Zhang, Ya-Yuan Shi, Xiao&#8208;Min Liang, Laicai Li, Molecular Catalysis. 571(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404678818

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin-Long Zhang, Ya-Yuan Shi, Xiao&#8208;Min Liang, Laicai Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Pt Active Sites on Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Nanocages for Industrial Hydrogen Evolution with Ultralow Pt Usage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11445</link>
      <description>Jingyi Tian, Minqi Xia, Xueyi Cheng, Chenghui Mao, Yiqun Chen, Yan Zhang, Changkai Zhou, Fengfei Xu, Lijun Yang, Xizhang Wang, Qiang Wu, Zheng Hu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404681858

                Engineering microstructures of Pt and understanding the related catalytic mechanism are critical to optimizing the performance for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Herein, Pt dispersion and coordination are precisely regulated on hierarchical nitrogen-doped carbon nanocages (hNCNCs) by a thermal-driven Pt migration, from edge-hosted Pt&#8211;N2Cl2 single sites in the initial Pt1/hNCNC-70 &#176;C catalyst to Pt clusters/nanoparticles and back to in-plane Pt&#8211;NxC4&#8211;x single sites. Thereinto, Pt&#8211;N2Cl2 presents the optimal HER activity (6 mV@10 mA cm&#8211;2) while Pt&#8211;NxC4&#8211;x shows poor HER activity (321 mV@10 mA cm&#8211;2) due to their different Pt coordination. Operando characterizations demonstrate that the low-coordinated Pt&#8211;N2 intermediates derived from Pt&#8211;N2Cl2 under the working condition are the real active sites for HER, which enable the multi-H adsorption mechanism with an ideal H* adsorption energy of nearly 0 eV, thereby the high activity, as revealed by theoretical calculations. In contrast, the high-coordinated Pt&#8211;NxC4&#8211;x sites only allow the single-H adsorption with a positive adsorption energy and thereby the low HER activity. Accordingly, with an ultralow Pt loading of only 25 &#956;gPt cm&#8211;2, the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer assembled using Pt1/hNCNC-70 &#176;C as the cathodic catalyst achieves an industrial-level current density of 1.0 A cm&#8211;2 at a low cell voltage of 1.66 V and high durability, showing great potential applications.</description>
      <author>Jingyi Tian, Minqi Xia, Xueyi Cheng, Chenghui Mao, Yiqun Chen, Yan Zhang, Changkai Zhou, Fengfei Xu, Lijun Yang, Xizhang Wang, Qiang Wu, Zheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epoxidized Single-Atom Co&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalysts Promote the Oxygen Reduction Reaction via a Two-Electron Pathway</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17354</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Jingyu Feng, Tao Yang, Yao Qin, Jiacheng Xie, Zengxi Wei, Shuangliang Zhao, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404686505

                Coordination structure and group modifications of single-atom catalysts are essential for regulating superficial electronic structures and reaction activities. Epoxy group-modified single-atom Co-N-C configuration demonstrates exceptional catalytic performance for hydrogen peroxide production. Through the manipulation of the coordination structure of Co-N-C and the doped epoxy groups, we elucidate the origin of catalytic activity in epoxygroup-modified Co-N-C configurations. Theoretical results indicate that the second coordination sphere of the Co-N-C structure is essential for the regulation of the two-electron pathway by the epoxy groups acting as cocatalysts. This cocatalytic mechanism originates from hydrogen bonding interactions between the epoxy groups and the OOH intermediates. Three epoxy groups within the second coordination sphere of Co-N-C configuration lead to the achievement of the optimal</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Jingyu Feng, Tao Yang, Yao Qin, Jiacheng Xie, Zengxi Wei, Shuangliang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complex Oxide Containing Inherent Peroxide Ions for Catalyzing Oxygen Evolution Reactions in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11477</link>
      <description>Jie Dai, Zihan Shen, Yu Chen, Mengran Li, Vanessa K. Peterson, Jiayi Tang, Xixi Wang, Yu Li, Daqin Guan, Chuan Zhou, Hainan Sun, Zhiwei Hu, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Guangming Chen, Yinlong Zhu, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404690511

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers powered by sustainable energy represent a cutting-edge technology for renewable hydrogen generation, while slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics still remains a formidable obstacle that necessitates basic comprehension for facilitating electrocatalysts' design. Here, we report a low-iridium complex oxide La</description>
      <author>Jie Dai, Zihan Shen, Yu Chen, Mengran Li, Vanessa K. Peterson, Jiayi Tang, Xixi Wang, Yu Li, Daqin Guan, Chuan Zhou, Hainan Sun, Zhiwei Hu, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Guangming Chen, Yinlong Zhu, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General-purpose neural network potential for Ti-Al-Nb alloys towards large-scale molecular dynamics with &lt;i&gt;ab initio&lt;/i&gt; accuracy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.184115</link>
      <description>Zhiqiang Zhao, Min Yi, Wanlin Guo, Zhuhua Zhang, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 110(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404693962

                High Nb-containing TiAl alloys exhibit exceptional high-temperature strength and room-temperature ductility, making them widely used in hot-section components of automotive and aerospace engines. However, the lack of accurate interatomic interaction potential for large-scale modeling severely hampers a comprehensive understanding of the failure mechanism of Ti-Al-Nb alloys and the development of strategies to enhance the mechanical properties. Here, we develop a general-purpose machine-learned potential (MLP) for the Ti-Al-Nb ternary system by combining the neural evolution potential framework with an active learning scheme. The developed MLP, trained on extensive first-principles datasets, demonstrates remarkable accuracy in predicting various lattice and defect properties as well as high-temperature characteristics such as thermal expansion and melting point for TiAl systems. Notably, this potential can effectively describe the key effect of Nb doping on stacking fault energies and formation energies. Of practical importance is that our MLP enables large-scale molecular dynamics simulations involving tens of millions of atoms with ab initio accuracy, achieving an outstanding balance between computational speed and accuracy. These results pave the way for elucidating micromechanical behaviors and failure mechanism TiAl lamellar structures and developing high-performance TiAl alloys towards applications at elevated temperatures.</description>
      <author>Zhiqiang Zhao, Min Yi, Wanlin Guo, Zhuhua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.110.184115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Automated Pynta-based Curriculum for ML-Accelerated Calculation of Transition States</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-7d1z1</link>
      <description>Trevor Price, Saurabh Sivakumar, Matthew Johnson, Judit Z&#225;dor, Ambarish Kulkarni, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404697307

                Microkinetic models (MKMs) are widely used within the computational heterogeneous catalysis community to investigate complex reaction mechanisms, rationalize experimental trends, and to accelerate the rational design of novel catalysts. However, constructing these models requires computationally expensive and manually tedious density functional theory (DFT) calculations for identifying transition states for each elementary reaction within the MKM. To address these challenges we demonstrate a novel protocol that uses the open-source kinetics workflow tool Pynta to automate the iterative training of a reactive machine learning potential (rMLP). Specifically, using the silver-catalyzed partial oxidation of methanol as a prototypical example, we first demonstrate our workflow by training an rMLP to accelerate the parallel calculation of DFT-quality transition states for all 53 reactions, achieving a 7x speedup compared to a DFT-only strategy. Detailed analysis of our training curriculum reveals the shortcomings of using an adaptive sampling scheme with a single rMLP model to describe all reactions within the MKM simultaneously. We show that these limitations can be overcome using a balanced "reaction class" approach that uses multiple rMLP models, each describing a single class of similar transition states. Finally, we demonstrate that our Pynta-based workflow is also compatible with large pre-trained foundational models. For example, by fine-tuning a top-performing graph neural network potential trained on the OC20 dataset, we observe an impressive 20x speedup with an 89\% success rate in identifying transition states. This work highlights the synergistic potential of integrating automated tools with machine learning to advance catalysis research.</description>
      <author>Trevor Price, Saurabh Sivakumar, Matthew Johnson, Judit Z&#225;dor, Ambarish Kulkarni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-7d1z1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Carbon-Based Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction: Insights into Mechanisms and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12120303</link>
      <description>Jing Guo, Yuqi Yao, Xin Yan, Xue Meng, Qing Wang, Yahui Zhang, Shengxue Yan, Xue Zhao, Shaohua Luo, Inorganics. 12(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404697886

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), as a key electrode process in fuel cells and metal-air batteries, plays a pivotal role in advancing clean energy technologies. However, the slow kinetics and high overpotential of the ORR significantly limit the efficiency of these energy devices. Therefore, the development of efficient, stable, and cost-effective ORR catalysts has become a central focus of current research. Carbon-based catalysts, with their excellent conductivity, chemical stability, and tunable structural features, have emerged as promising alternatives to traditional precious metal catalysts. Nevertheless, challenges remain in the design of active sites, the tuning of electronic structures, and the large-scale synthesis of carbon-based catalysts. This review systematically introduces the fundamental mechanisms and key factors influencing the ORR, providing an analysis of the critical variables that affect catalyst performance. Furthermore, it summarizes several common methods for synthesizing carbon-based catalysts, including pyrolysis, deposition, and ball milling. Following this, the review categorizes and discusses the latest advancements in metal-free carbon-based catalysts, single-atom and dual-atom catalysts, as well as metal-based nanoparticle catalysts, with a particular focus on their mechanisms for enhancing the ORR performance. Finally, the current state of research on carbon-based ORR catalysts is summarized, and future development directions are proposed, emphasizing the optimization of active sites, improvements in catalyst stability, and potential strategies for large-scale applications.</description>
      <author>Jing Guo, Yuqi Yao, Xin Yan, Xue Meng, Qing Wang, Yahui Zhang, Shengxue Yan, Xue Zhao, Shaohua Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12120303</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological semimetals with intrinsic chirality as spin-controlling electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01674-9</link>
      <description>Xia Wang, Qun Yang, Sukriti Singh, Horst Borrmann, Vicky Hasse, Changjiang Yi, Yongkang Li, Marcus Schmidt, Xiaodong Li, Gerhard H. Fecher, Dong Zhou, Binghai Yan, Claudia Felser, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404699558

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting is a promising approach for clean hydrogen production, but the process is hindered by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) owing to the spin-dependent electron transfer process. Efforts to control spin through chirality and magnetization have shown potential in enhancing OER performance. Here we harnessed the potential of topological chiral semimetals (RhSi, RhSn and RhBiS) and their spin-polarized Fermi surfaces to promote the spin-dependent electron transfer in the OER, addressing the traditional volcano-plot limitations. We show that OER activities follow the trend RhSi &lt; RhSn &lt; RhBiS, corresponding to the increasing extent of spin&#8211;orbit coupling (SOC). The chiral single crystals outperform achiral counterparts (RhTe 2 , RhTe and RuO 2 ) in alkaline electrolyte, with RhBiS exhibiting a specific activity two orders of magnitude higher than RuO 2 . Our work reveals the pivotal roles of chirality and SOC in spin-dependent catalysis, facilitating the design of ultra-efficient chiral catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xia Wang, Qun Yang, Sukriti Singh, Horst Borrmann, Vicky Hasse, Changjiang Yi, Yongkang Li, Marcus Schmidt, Xiaodong Li, Gerhard H. Fecher, Dong Zhou, Binghai Yan, Claudia Felser</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01674-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating C-C coupling pathway in electrochemical CO2 reduction for selective ethylene and ethanol production over single-atom alloy catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54636-w</link>
      <description>Shifu Wang, Fuhua Li, Jian Zhao, Yaqiong Zeng, Yifan Li, Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Tsung-Ju Lee, Shu-Hui Liu, Xinyi Ren, Weijue Wang, Yusen Chen, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yi Cui, Xiaofeng Yang, Xuning Li, Yanqiang Huang, Bin Liu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404709191

                Manipulation C-C coupling pathway is of great importance for selective CO2 electroreduction but remain challenging. Herein, two model Cu-based catalysts, by modifying Cu nanowires with Ag nanoparticles (AgCu NW) and Ag single atoms (Ag1Cu NW), respectively, are rationally designed for exploring the C-C coupling mechanisms in electrochemical CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR). Compared to AgCu NW, the Ag1Cu NW exhibits a more than 10-fold increase of C2 selectivity in CO2 reduction to ethanol, with ethanol-to-ethylene ratio increased from 0.41 over AgCu NW to 4.26 over Ag1Cu NW. Via a variety of operando/in-situ techniques and theoretical calculation, the enhanced ethanol selectivity over Ag1Cu NW is attributed to the promoted H2O dissociation over the atomically dispersed Ag sites, which effectively accelerated *CO hydrogenation to form *CHO intermediate and facilitated asymmetric *CO-*CHO coupling over paired Cu atoms adjacent to single Ag atoms. Results of this work provide deep insight into the C-C coupling pathways towards target C2+ product and shed light on the rational design of efficient CO2RR catalysts with paired active sites. Manipulating the carbon-carbon coupling pathway in CO2 electroreduction is vital yet challenging. Here, by studying two model copper-based catalysts with distinct ethylene and ethanol selectivity, authors investigate the mechanistic origins for symmetric and asymmetric carbon-carbon coupling.</description>
      <author>Shifu Wang, Fuhua Li, Jian Zhao, Yaqiong Zeng, Yifan Li, Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Tsung-Ju Lee, Shu-Hui Liu, Xinyi Ren, Weijue Wang, Yusen Chen, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Yi Cui, Xiaofeng Yang, Xuning Li, Yanqiang Huang, Bin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54636-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multidimensional Neural Network Interatomic Potentials for CO on NaCl(100)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05765</link>
      <description>Shreya Sinha, Bruno Mladineo, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, Peter Saalfrank, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718463

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shreya Sinha, Bruno Mladineo, Ivor Lon&#269;ari&#263;, Peter Saalfrank</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-learning-accelerated density functional theory screening of Cu-based high-entropy alloys for carbon dioxide reduction to ethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161919</link>
      <description>Meena Rittiruam, Pisit Khamloet, Sirapat Tiwtusthada, Annop Ektarawong, Tinnakorn Saelee, Chayanon Atthapak, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404724512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meena Rittiruam, Pisit Khamloet, Sirapat Tiwtusthada, Annop Ektarawong, Tinnakorn Saelee, Chayanon Atthapak, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing photocatalytic hydrogen generation by achieving Long-Lasting shallow trapping states in distorted covalent triazine frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115859</link>
      <description>Yun Zheng, Wei Liu, Guosheng Li, Yilin Chen, Ya&#8208;Yun Wang, Fang Lei, Xiaoping Rao, Kang Sun, Chaochao Qin, Jianchun Jiang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404727166

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yun Zheng, Wei Liu, Guosheng Li, Yilin Chen, Ya&#8208;Yun Wang, Fang Lei, Xiaoping Rao, Kang Sun, Chaochao Qin, Jianchun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diatomic nitrogen-fixing electrocatalysts supported on graphitic carbon nitride achieve significantly low over potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113888</link>
      <description>Zheng-Yun Xiong, Wen-qing Hong, Wangdong Zeng, Zhimin Ao, Ying Xu, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404734552

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheng-Yun Xiong, Wen-qing Hong, Wangdong Zeng, Zhimin Ao, Ying Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct observation of structural disorder effects on iridium dioxide nanocrystal dissolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2024.11.003</link>
      <description>Matteo Fratarcangeli, S. Avery Vigil, Ziqing Lin, Conner J. Soderstedt, Ivan A. Moreno&#8208;Hernandez, Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404747367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matteo Fratarcangeli, S. Avery Vigil, Ziqing Lin, Conner J. Soderstedt, Ivan A. Moreno&#8208;Hernandez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2024.11.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Catalytic Hydrogen Transfer Cascade Reactions via Tandem Catalyst Design by Coupling Co Single Atoms with Adjacent Co Clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05569</link>
      <description>Zhanwei Chen, Shaowei Yang, Jie Yang, Bo Zhang, Hao Jiang, Runze Gao, Tianshuai Wang, Qiuyu Zhang, Hepeng Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404749349

                The catalytic hydrogen transfer (CHT) cascade reaction coupling alcohols with nitro compounds to synthesize imines is highly significant due to its remarkable efficiency and atom economy. However, the complicated multistep reaction process makes single-site catalysts exhibit unsatisfactory catalytic performance for the CHT cascade reaction. Herein, inspired by the findings of DFT calculations that Co nanocluster (CoNC) and Co single atom (CoSA) can act as the optimal active sites for alcohol oxidation and nitro reduction, respectively, one dual-active site catalyst (CoSA-CoNC/CN), containing CoSA and CoNC sites, was synthesized by a two-step vacuum pyrolysis strategy. Benefiting from the relay-like tandem catalysis of CoNC and CoSA, CoSA-CoNC/CN achieved an impressive 93% nitrobenzene conversion and 99% imine selectivity at 160 &#176;C in 4 h, with a record turnover frequency of 20.9 h&#8211;1. This work provides insights into the functions of single-atom and nanocluster active sites in the CHT cascade reaction and sheds light on the rational preparation of tandem catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhanwei Chen, Shaowei Yang, Jie Yang, Bo Zhang, Hao Jiang, Runze Gao, Tianshuai Wang, Qiuyu Zhang, Hepeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive analysis of the production of H2 and value-added chemicals from the electrolysis of biomass and derived feedstocks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biombioe.2024.107510</link>
      <description>Ali Gunerhan, &#214;nder Altunta&#351;, Emin A&#231;&#305;kkalp, Biomass and Bioenergy. 192(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404751778

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ali Gunerhan, &#214;nder Altunta&#351;, Emin A&#231;&#305;kkalp</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biombioe.2024.107510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparse Gaussian process based machine learning first principles potentials for materials simulations: Application to batteries, solar cells, catalysts, and macromolecular systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231265</link>
      <description>Soohaeng Yoo Willow, Amir Hajibabaei, Miran Ha, D. ChangMo Yang, Chang Woo Myung, Seung Kyu Min, Geunsik Lee, Kwang S. Kim, Chemical Physics Reviews. 5(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404759416

                To design new materials and understand their novel phenomena, it is imperative to predict the structure and properties of materials that often rely on first-principles theory. However, such methods are computationally demanding and limited to small systems. This topical review investigates machine learning (ML) approaches, specifically non-parametric sparse Gaussian process regression (SGPR), to model the potential energy surface (PES) of materials, while starting from the basics of ML methods for a comprehensive review. SGPR can efficiently represent PES with minimal ab initio data, significantly reducing the computational costs by bypassing the need for inverting massive covariance matrices. SGPR rank reduction accelerates density functional theory calculations by orders of magnitude, enabling accelerated simulations. An optimal adaptive sampling algorithm is utilized for on-the-fly regression with molecular dynamics, extending to interatomic potentials through scalable SGPR formalism. Through merging quantum mechanics with ML methods, the universal first-principles SGPR-based ML potential can create a digital-twin capable of predicting phenomena arising from static and dynamic changes as well as inherent and collective characteristics of materials. These techniques have been applied successfully to materials such as solid electrolytes, lithium-ion batteries, electrocatalysts, solar cells, and macromolecular systems, reproducing their structures, energetics, dynamics, properties, phase-changes, materials performance, and device efficiency. This review discusses the built-in library universal first-principles SGPR-based ML potential, showcasing its applications and successes, offering insights into the development of future ML potentials and their applications in advanced materials, catering to both educational and expert readers.</description>
      <author>Soohaeng Yoo Willow, Amir Hajibabaei, Miran Ha, D. ChangMo Yang, Chang Woo Myung, Seung Kyu Min, Geunsik Lee, Kwang S. Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic mechanism for overall water splitting to produce sustainable hydrogen by 2D Janus MoSH monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-024-00516-2</link>
      <description>Deobrat Singh, Nisha Singh, Yogesh Sonvane, npj 2D Materials and Applications. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404761563

                Abstract In the present work, we investigates the potential of two dimensional (2D) Janus MoSH monolayer as an electrocatalyst for overall water splitting using first-principles calculations. Our results shows that 2D Janus MoSH monolayer exhibits excellent structural stability and electronic properties, which are essential for efficient electrocatalysis. We find that the charge transfer mechanism between Mo and S atoms plays a crucial role in the electrocatalytic activity of 2D Janus MoSH monolayer. Due to the asymmetric structure of MoSH monolayer, it has intrinsic electric field with dipole moment of 0.24 D. Moreover, we demonstrate that 2D Janus MoSH monolayer exhibits high catalytic activity for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with overpotential 0.04 V and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with overpotential 0.11 V, making it a promising candidate for overall water splitting. Our findings have significant implications for the design and optimization of 2D monolayered materials for renewable energy production. By providing insights into the underlying mechanisms of HER and OER on 2D Janus MoSH monolayer, our study paves the way for the development of efficient and sustainable electrocatalysts for water splitting. We hope that current work will be helpful in understanding the electrocatalytic mechanism of 2D Janus MoSH monolayer and its potential applications in renewable energy production.</description>
      <author>Deobrat Singh, Nisha Singh, Yogesh Sonvane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-024-00516-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Uncertainty Estimation of Graph Neural Network Potentials Using Engineered Latent Space Distances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04972</link>
      <description>Joseph Musielewicz, Janice Lan, Matt Uyttendaele, John R. Kitchin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404762044

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joseph Musielewicz, Janice Lan, Matt Uyttendaele, John R. Kitchin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Investigation of 2D Phase Separated Graphene/Hexagonal Boron Nitride Monolayers; Band Gap, Band Edge Positions, and Photo Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06121</link>
      <description>E.D O'Sullivan, Nicole Grobert, Marcel Swart, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404767013

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E.D O'Sullivan, Nicole Grobert, Marcel Swart</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen substitution of bilayer penta-carbides: high solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency and excellent electrocatalytic activity for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03887h</link>
      <description>Yaowen Long, Hong Zhang, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404767581

                Vertical intrinsic electric field enhanced solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency to 31% and enabled almost zero overpotential for the hydrogen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Yaowen Long, Hong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03887h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of thermal annealing on phase structure and hydrogen evolution reaction of molybdenum carbide thin films prepared by co-sputtering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2024.140579</link>
      <description>Ling Jin, Zhihu Pan, Li Wang, Xiaohong Ji, Thin Solid Films. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404771673

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Jin, Zhihu Pan, Li Wang, Xiaohong Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2024.140579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni supported on Al2O3-La2O3 derived from layered double hydroxides for efficient thermal catalytic decomposition of ammonia to hydrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.121000</link>
      <description>Zheng Li, Guang&#8208;Hui Chen, Xiuqun Gong, Junjun Yao, Jun&#8208;Kang Guo, Lang Chen, Chao Peng, Xingyi Huang, Qing&#8208;Miao Hu, Juan Xiong, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404771783

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheng Li, Guang&#8208;Hui Chen, Xiuqun Gong, Junjun Yao, Jun&#8208;Kang Guo, Lang Chen, Chao Peng, Xingyi Huang, Qing&#8208;Miao Hu, Juan Xiong, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.121000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction Really Need To Be Suppressed in O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Tolerant CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Catalyzed by DAE-BPy-CoPor and Co-TAPP?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02957</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404771815

                This letter chooses DAE-BPy-CoPor [DAE, 1,2-bis(5'-formyl-2'-methylthien-3'-yl)cyclopentene; BPy, 2,2'-bipyridine-5,5'-dicarbaldehyde; and CoPor, two-dimensional cobalt porphyrin-based covalent organic framework] and Co-TAPP [10,15,20-tetrakis(4-aminophenyl)porphinatocobalt] as two model catalysts to investigate the effect of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in the O</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implications for Oxygen Evolution Spinel-based Electrocatalyst in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyser: A Review from Structural Engineering perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177819</link>
      <description>Iswary Letchumanan, Wei Shi Ng, Mohd Shahbudin Masdar, Azim Fitri Zainul Abidin, Nurul Akidah Baharuddin, Rozan Mohamad Yunus, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404794496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Iswary Letchumanan, Wei Shi Ng, Mohd Shahbudin Masdar, Azim Fitri Zainul Abidin, Nurul Akidah Baharuddin, Rozan Mohamad Yunus</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heusler-based topological quantum catalyst Fe2VAl with obstructed surface states for the hydrogen-evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416773</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Physica B Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404802796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Catalytic Activity of i-MXenes for CO2 Reduction Reaction by Ordered Metal Atomic Vacancies: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105535</link>
      <description>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404804106

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huichun Xue, Yitong Chen, Lin Zhu, An Du</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and challenges in N2O valorization for alkane oxidative dehydrogenation to olefins</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gce.2024.11.005</link>
      <description>Y.M. Wu, Xuanhao Wu, Haiqiang Wang, Zhongbiao Wu, Green Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404812774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y.M. Wu, Xuanhao Wu, Haiqiang Wang, Zhongbiao Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gce.2024.11.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Rhodium Doping for Photocatalytic Activity of Barium Titanate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.omx.2024.100382</link>
      <description>G. A. Kaptagay, B. M. Satanova, &#1040;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Marina Ko&#326;uhova, Zh.Ye. Zakiyeva, U. Zh. Tolegen, N. Koilyk, &#1060;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Optical Materials X. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404812888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. A. Kaptagay, B. M. Satanova, &#1040;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Marina Ko&#326;uhova, Zh.Ye. Zakiyeva, U. Zh. Tolegen, N. Koilyk, &#1060;. &#1059;. &#1040;&#1073;&#1091;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.omx.2024.100382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and Comparative Analysis of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Absorption Columns in Electrochemical and Thermochemical Carbon Capture Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c01523</link>
      <description>Katelyn M. Ripley, Fikile R. Brushett, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404787306

                Deployment of post-combustion carbon dioxide (CO2) capture technologies is needed to reduce emissions from power and industrial sources. Comparisons between existing thermochemical CO2 capture methods and emerging electrochemical concepts can help contextualize the promise of these new approaches. Here, we investigate the required absorber sizes for three capture systems: amine scrubbing using monoethanolamine (MEA), direct electrochemical (redox-active sorbent), and indirect electrochemical (pH swing). For the electrochemical systems, we study how column size varies as a function of molecular properties and operating conditions, finding that parameters most closely related to CO2 uptake rates (i.e., rate constants and pKa) have the greatest impact. Through a Monte Carlo analysis, we find that the direct process can be designed to have column sizes similar to the thermochemical process; however, the CO2 uptake rate in the indirect process is too slow to enable smaller columns. Broadly, this work connects system input parameters to absorber performance for electrochemical CO2 capture and provides a foundation for techno-economic and engineering analyses.</description>
      <author>Katelyn M. Ripley, Fikile R. Brushett</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c01523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal language and graph learning of adsorption configuration in catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s42256-024-00930-7</link>
      <description>Janghoon Ock, Srivathsan Badrinarayanan, Rishikesh Magar, Akshay Antony, Amir Barati Farimani, Nature Machine Intelligence. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404764557

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Janghoon Ock, Srivathsan Badrinarayanan, Rishikesh Magar, Akshay Antony, Amir Barati Farimani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s42256-024-00930-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catechol-derived Mannich bases: radical regulatory properties, cytotoxicity and interaction with biomolecules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10715762.2024.2433985</link>
      <description>Maxim Y. Gvozdev, Iveta S. Turomsha, Natalia V. Loginova, E. Yu. Varfolomeeva, R. A. Kovalev, N. D. Fedorova, &#1043;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1089;&#1077;&#1085;&#1076;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, N.P. Osipovich, &#1056;. &#1051;. &#1057;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1076;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, Free Radical Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404790404

                Free radicals are ubiquitous in biological systems, being responsible for pathogenesis of degenerative diseases and participating in vitally important biochemical processes, which are mediated by radical regulatory agents. The effects of the aliphatic amine substituents in the catechol-derived Mannich bases on their antioxidant and pro-oxidant activity were investigated. It has been found that the presence of catechol moiety in the structure of Mannich bases allows them to act as Cu(II) reductants, efficient Fe(II) chelators and potent DPPH radical scavengers. It has been found that the plausible mechanism of the DPPH radical scavenging proceeds via quinone formation, followed by their interaction with ethanol via the Michael addition reaction. In the neutrophil respiratory burst assay, several compounds have demonstrated a weak antioxidant activity at the micromolar level (0.1&#8211;10 &#181;M), whereas at the millimolar level (0.1 m&#1052;) a strong pro-oxidant effect has been observed. Additionally, at the highest used concentrations a pronounced cytotoxicity against dermal fibroblasts DF-2 and an immunosuppressive effect against T-lymphocytes have been observed for all the synthesized compounds. It has been demonstrated that the oxidation of catechols in the presence of low-molecular thiols results in the formation of covalent adducts, which provides an insight into their cytotoxicity and detoxification pathways.</description>
      <author>Maxim Y. Gvozdev, Iveta S. Turomsha, Natalia V. Loginova, E. Yu. Varfolomeeva, R. A. Kovalev, N. D. Fedorova, &#1043;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1089;&#1077;&#1085;&#1076;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, N.P. Osipovich, &#1056;. &#1051;. &#1057;&#1074;&#1077;&#1088;&#1076;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/10715762.2024.2433985</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
