<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers that cite my papers</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/Papers-that-cite-my-papers.xml</link>
    <description>Citations to my papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 01:25:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>C2N supported single Fe3 cluster for efficient electrocatalytic urea synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168128</link>
      <description>Zhongwei Wang, Nan Xia, Yan Gao, Hongsheng Liu, Junfeng Gao, Haifeng Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. 522(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414164336

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongwei Wang, Nan Xia, Yan Gao, Hongsheng Liu, Junfeng Gao, Haifeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-Level Insight into Ni Clusters Supported on N-Terminated Diamond (111) Surface for HER, OER, and ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02155</link>
      <description>Wei Cheng, Nan Gao, Shaoheng Cheng, Hongdong Li, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414166732

                Single-cluster catalysts (SCCs), an emerging frontier between single-atom catalysts and conventional metal nanoparticle catalysts, have attracted significant attention due to their unique geometric and electronic structures. Herein, we systematically investigate the structural models and the hydrogen-evolution reaction (HER), oxygen-evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen-reduction reaction (ORR) performances for Nix clusters (x = 2-9) anchored on a N-terminated diamond (111) surface (Nix@ND) through Crystal structure AnaLYsis by Particle Swarm Optimization (CALYPSO)-based structural prediction and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The Ni-H bonding strength serves as a critical descriptor for HER activity, where a balanced relative strength of ad-/desorption is beneficial for enhancing it. The Gibbs free energy change (&#916;G*H) of the Ni7@ND catalyst is -0.25 eV, demonstrating optimal HER performance with an efficiency approaching that of highly efficient Pt-based catalysts. Furthermore, Ni4@ND and Ni2@ND catalysts demonstrate superior OER and ORR performance with low overpotentials (&#951;), which are significantly lower than those of single-atom catalyst Ni1@ND. Volcano curve analysis reveals that the OER performance is maximized at the intermediate adsorption strength of key reaction species (*O, *OH). A pronounced linear correlation is found between &#951;ORR and adsorption energies of intermediate *OH. Furthermore, size effects in SCCs narrow the band gap and increase the number of active sites, thus promoting the catalytic performance (optimizing charge redistribution and reducing the rate-determining step barrier). This design strategy provides atomic-level insights into highly efficient diamond-based SCCs for HER, OER, and ORR.</description>
      <author>Wei Cheng, Nan Gao, Shaoheng Cheng, Hongdong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Tuning of Carbon-Based Nanostructure Surfaces Toward Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction Reaction: Inquiry to Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41061-025-00521-z</link>
      <description>Y. Anjali, Rijo Rajeev, Manoj Balachandran, Tom Cherian, Anitha Varghese, Topics in Current Chemistry. 383(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414167248

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y. Anjali, Rijo Rajeev, Manoj Balachandran, Tom Cherian, Anitha Varghese</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41061-025-00521-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of spin states and electronic excitation via molecular doping with Fe(II)-porphyrin in 2D gallium nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0285574</link>
      <description>Yachao Zhang, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414169291

                2D gallium nitride possesses distinctive electronic states, making it ideal for future optoelectronic devices because of the quantum confinement and enhanced many-body interactions inherent in its atomically thin form. This study explores the impact of molecular doping with Fe(II)-porphyrin (FeP) on these characteristics using first-principle calculations. Contact of the magnetic center Fe with the nitrogen site causes a 17% decrease in the energy barrier for the transition from intermediate spin (S = 1) to high spin (S = 2) state, highlighting the sensitivity of spin dynamics to doping sites. Molecular diffusion barriers increase by 9.6 kJ/mol upon spin transition, suggesting that the spin state influences molecular mobility within the material. Exploring spectral functions reveals that FeP doping introduces spin-dependent molecule levels within the bandgap, which may play a role in electron-hole separation and spin injection. In addition, we show that the molecule-substrate coupling lowers the exciton binding energy by 0.1 eV, with further reduction during spin transitions. This weakening is attributed to increased electron mobility, quantified by static polarizability. These results indicate that the molecular spin state can control electronic excitations within substrate materials, presenting a promising strategy for designing spintronic devices.</description>
      <author>Yachao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0285574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface and Interface Engineering of Noble Metal Heterostructures for Superior ORR Performance: Unlocking Ultralow Loading and Maximum Catalyst Utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202506018</link>
      <description>Dinesh Bhalothia, Amisha Beniwal, Hariom Gurjar, Khushabu Shekhawat, Ashima Bagaria, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414169444

                The quest for sustainable and high-efficiency energy conversion technologies has driven intense research into oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts, particularly those based on noble metals, due to the harsh redox environment of these devices. Despite their unparalleled activity, the scarcity and high cost of noble metals like platinum remain significant bottlenecks for large-scale application. Recent advances in surface and interface engineering of noble metal heterostructures offer a promising pathway to address these challenges. By precisely tailoring surface atomic arrangements, modulating interfacial electronic structures, and constructing synergistic heterojunctions, researchers have unlocked unprecedented catalytic efficiencies with dramatically reduced metal loading. This review systematically explores the latest strategies in designing surface- and interface-optimized noble metal heterostructures for ORR, highlighting how these innovations enable maximum utilization of active sites while enhancing activity and durability. We delve into various synthesis techniques, structural modulation approaches, and mechanistic insights gained from advanced characterization and theoretical modeling. Special emphasis is placed on understanding the critical role of heterointerfaces in tuning adsorption energies, charge transfer dynamics, and reaction pathways. Finally, we outline current challenges and propose future directions for the rational design of next-generation ORR catalysts that combine minimal noble metal usage with exceptional performance.</description>
      <author>Dinesh Bhalothia, Amisha Beniwal, Hariom Gurjar, Khushabu Shekhawat, Ashima Bagaria, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202506018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reserved charges in a long-lived NiOOH phase drive catalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01942-5</link>
      <description>Xin Cui, Yunxuan Ding, Feiyang Zhang, Xing Cao, Yu Guo, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang, Nature Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414183253

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Cui, Yunxuan Ding, Feiyang Zhang, Xing Cao, Yu Guo, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41557-025-01942-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Hydrogen/Liquid Fuel Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch08</link>
      <description>Ran Wang, Huan Pang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414186089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ran Wang, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch08</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch07</link>
      <description>Yifan Ma, Junhua Li, Ying Tang, Hang An, Xiaopeng Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414186120

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yifan Ma, Junhua Li, Ying Tang, Hang An, Xiaopeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch07</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch09</link>
      <description>An&#8208;Liang Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414186224

                No abstract</description>
      <author>An&#8208;Liang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch09</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constant&#8208;potential Modeling in Electrochemical CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch03</link>
      <description>Yaqiong Su, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414186330

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaqiong Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527849291.ch03</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of hydrogen diffusion mechanism and enhanced catalytic activity in monolayer &#946;12-type borophene for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168499</link>
      <description>Jiahao Gao, Yong Pan, I.P. Jain, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414187843

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahao Gao, Yong Pan, I.P. Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;Orbitals Modulation for Tailoring Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P Interfacial Adsorption Behavior: Boosting Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202504036</link>
      <description>Lei Wang, Xian&#8208;Wei Lv, Haoyu Wang, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Yi Feng, Minglei Sun, Zhong&#8208;Yong Yuan, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414188929

                Abstract Rational design of an efficient catalyst that simultaneously accelerates water splitting, promotes hydroxyl conversion, and facilitates hydrogen desorption presents a significant challenge for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). To address this challenge, a series of coordinating metals selected from elements of the 4th&#8208; and 5th&#8208;period is incorporated into dicobalt phosphide (Co 2 P), thereby tuning the interfacial adsorption. Among these elements&#8208;coordinated catalysts, simultaneously considering both d &#8208;band filling and spin polarization, the iron&#8208;coordinated catalyst (Fe&#8208;CPNCF) exhibits appropriate adsorption energy, activates interfacial inert H 2 O molecules and locates at the optimal position on the volcano plot for the H 2 O dissociation barrier, owing to the rational d &#8208;orbitals modulation of active sites by Fe coordination. Thus, the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzers based on Fe&#8208;CPNCF achieve a current density of 2 A cm &#8722;2 at a low cell voltage of 2.04 V and maintain stable electrolysis for 1160 h, demonstrating great potential in commercial applications. This work underscores the importance of rationally tuning the d&#8208; orbitals of active sites for modulating interfacial adsorption behavior, providing relevant insights for the development of efficient hydrogen evolution catalysts.</description>
      <author>Lei Wang, Xian&#8208;Wei Lv, Haoyu Wang, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Yi Feng, Minglei Sun, Zhong&#8208;Yong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202504036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized selectivity in CO2 electrochemical reduction using amorphous CuNi catalysts: insights from density functional theory and machine learning simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.08.089</link>
      <description>Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Enrico Pedretti, Maria Clelia Righi, Devis Di Tommaso, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414189857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akshayini Muthuperiyanayagam, Enrico Pedretti, Maria Clelia Righi, Devis Di Tommaso</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2025.08.089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weighted active space protocol for multireference machine-learned potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2513693122</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Seal, Simone Perego, Matthew R. Hennefarth, Umberto Raucci, Luigi Bonati, Andrew L. Ferguson, Michele Parrinello, Laura Gagliardi, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(38)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414195114

                Multireference methods such as multiconfiguration pair-density functional theory accurately capture electronic correlation in systems with strong multiconfigurational character, but their cost precludes direct use in molecular dynamics. Combining these methods with machine-learned interatomic potentials (MLPs) can extend their reach. However, the sensitivity of multireference calculations to the choice of the active space complicates the consistent evaluation of energies and gradients across structurally diverse nuclear configurations. To overcome this limitation, we introduce the weighted active space protocol (WASP), a systematic approach to assign a consistent active space for a given system across uncorrelated configurations. By integrating WASP with MLPs and enhanced sampling techniques, we propose a data-efficient active learning cycle that enables the training of an MLP on multireference data. We demonstrated the approach on the TiC+-catalyzed C-H activation of methane, a reaction that poses challenges for Kohn-Sham density functional theory due to its significant multireference character. This framework enables accurate and efficient modeling of catalytic dynamics, establishing a paradigm for simulating complex reactive processes beyond the limits of conventional electronic-structure methods.</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Seal, Simone Perego, Matthew R. Hennefarth, Umberto Raucci, Luigi Bonati, Andrew L. Ferguson, Michele Parrinello, Laura Gagliardi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2513693122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibrational Energy Dissipation in Noncontact Single-Molecule Junctions Governed by Local Geometry and Electronic Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00931</link>
      <description>Lukas H&#246;rmann, Reinhard J. Maurer, JACS Au. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414199780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lukas H&#246;rmann, Reinhard J. Maurer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacsau.5c00931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Surface Engineering of RuPd Nanocatalysts: Orchestrating Reactive Hydrogen Formation, and 2-Chlorophenol Adsorption Dynamics for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Hydrodechlorination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestengg.5c00535</link>
      <description>Hehe Qian, T. Ma, Lili Shi, Shu Yan, Huijuan Cui, Xueqing Luo, Fang Chen, Yuetan Su, Zhongbiao Wu, Xiaole Weng, ACS ES&amp;T Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414200201

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hehe Qian, T. Ma, Lili Shi, Shu Yan, Huijuan Cui, Xueqing Luo, Fang Chen, Yuetan Su, Zhongbiao Wu, Xiaole Weng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestengg.5c00535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Platinum FePt Nanoalloys with Nanoconfinement Effects for Durable Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02931</link>
      <description>Wei Liu, Guangxu Bao, Yihan Xu, Xiaoyi Chen, Jianlong Lin, Zhanpeng Liang, Xiao Wang, Wenquan Cui, Sheng Zhang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414205033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Liu, Guangxu Bao, Yihan Xu, Xiaoyi Chen, Jianlong Lin, Zhanpeng Liang, Xiao Wang, Wenquan Cui, Sheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c02931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge&#8208;Deficient PtCu Clusters&#8208;Stabilized Vacancy&#8208;Engineered Mo&lt;sub&gt;4/3&lt;/sub&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;z&lt;/sub&gt; MBene Flake Synergistically Boosts Efficient Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202515741</link>
      <description>Penghao Zhu, Jinhai Yang, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Xichan He, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414205353

                Abstract In this work, a robust method is presented for synthesizing homogeneously distributed, ultrafine PtCu atomic clusters supported on Cu&#8208;modified, vacancy&#8208;engineered Mo 4/3 B 2 T z MBene nanosheets (PtCu AC @Cu&#8208;Mo 4/3 B 2 T z ). The material serves as highly efficient pH&#8208;universal hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalyst, which demonstrates impressively low overpotentials of 4 and 15 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 and 1.0 M KOH, respectively, as well as sustained operational stability. Through comprehensive analysis of in situ Raman spectroscopy and density functional theory, it is realizes that Cu incorporation optimizes the electronic configuration of Pt sites and significantly enhances proton transfer and interfacial water activation. In addition, the active metal&#8208;MBene interactions also leads to modulation in the d&#8208;band center of Pt d&#8208;orbitals, fine&#8208;tuning the adsorption energy of H * and reducing the energy barrier for water dissociation, thus promoting H 2 evolution. The practical tests demonstrate high&#8208;performance anion exchange membrane single&#8208;cell stack based on PtCu AC @Cu&#8208;Mo 4/3 B 2 T z(&#8722;) ||RuO 2(+) configuration, reaching current densities of 0.5/1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.75/1.86 V and stable performance for over 600 h at 0.5 A cm &#8722;2 in 1.0 M KOH at 60 &#176;C. This research underscores the importance of active metal&#8208;supported MBene in enhancing catalytic functions and demonstrates the key role of next&#8208;generation MBene&#8208;based hybrid materials as durable support for electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Penghao Zhu, Jinhai Yang, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Xichan He, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202515741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isopotential Electron Titration: Hydrogen Adsorbate-Metal Charge Transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c00851</link>
      <description>J. Hopkins, Benjamin Page, Shengguang Wang, Jesse Canavan, Jason Chalmers, Susannah L. Scott, Lars C. Grabow, James R. McKone, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Omar Abdelrahman, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414206588

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. Hopkins, Benjamin Page, Shengguang Wang, Jesse Canavan, Jason Chalmers, Susannah L. Scott, Lars C. Grabow, James R. McKone, Paul J. Dauenhauer, Omar Abdelrahman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.5c00851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Decomposition over Carbon for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Free Hydrogen Production: A Combined DFT and Experimental Investigation on the Role of Carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04541</link>
      <description>Peng Zhao, Chee Kok Poh, Jiajian Gao, Jiren Zeng, Saifudin Abubakar, Guang Sheng Cao, Lili Zhang, Jia Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414213810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Zhao, Chee Kok Poh, Jiajian Gao, Jiren Zeng, Saifudin Abubakar, Guang Sheng Cao, Lili Zhang, Jia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c04541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive multiscale modeling to bridge atomic properties and electrochemical performance in Li-CO2 battery design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126693</link>
      <description>Mohammed Lemaalem, S. Selva Chandrasekaran, Ilias Papailias, Naveen Dandu, Arash Namaeighasemi, Larry A. Curtiss, Amin Salehi&#8208;Khojin, Anh T. Ngo, Applied Energy. 401(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414223727

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammed Lemaalem, S. Selva Chandrasekaran, Ilias Papailias, Naveen Dandu, Arash Namaeighasemi, Larry A. Curtiss, Amin Salehi&#8208;Khojin, Anh T. Ngo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing charge equilibration-based machine learning potentials to their limits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01791-3</link>
      <description>Martin Vondr&#225;k, Karsten Reuter, Johannes T. Margraf, npj Computational Materials. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414224048

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Martin Vondr&#225;k, Karsten Reuter, Johannes T. Margraf</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-025-01791-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallic bismuth-embedded mesoporous carbon hollow spheres for highly selective electrocatalytic hydrogen peroxide production via two-electron oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136799</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Wang, Kun Li, Junling Hu, Meixin Wang, Yanzhi Sun, Pingyu Wan, Yang Tang, Haomin Jiang, Yongmei Chen, Fuel. 406(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414225638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Wang, Kun Li, Junling Hu, Meixin Wang, Yanzhi Sun, Pingyu Wan, Yang Tang, Haomin Jiang, Yongmei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.136799</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing for cooperative grain boundary segregation in multicomponent alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2511930122</link>
      <description>Malik Wagih, Yannick Naunheim, Tianjiao Lei, Christopher A. Schuh, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(38)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414229049

                Tailoring the nanoscale distribution of chemical species at grain boundaries is a powerful method to dramatically influence the properties of polycrystalline materials. However, classical approaches to the problem have tacitly assumed that only competition is possible between solute species. In this paper, we show that solute elements can cooperate in the way they segregate to grain boundaries: In properly targeted alloys, the different chemical species cooperate to each fill complementary grain boundary sites disfavored by the other. By developing a theoretical &#8220;spectral&#8221; approach to this problem based on quantum-accurate grain boundary site distributions, we show how grain boundaries can be cooperatively alloyed, whether by depletion or enrichment. We provide machine-learned cosegregation information for over 700 ternary aluminum-based alloys and experimentally validate the concept in one ternary alloy where cosegregation is not expected by prior models but is expected based on the cooperative model.</description>
      <author>Malik Wagih, Yannick Naunheim, Tianjiao Lei, Christopher A. Schuh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2511930122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface synergy engineering in CoFe@NiFe LDH hierarchical heterostructures for bifunctional water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.183765</link>
      <description>Yu Zhong, Zhaoyue Zhang, Xiaoying Chen, Qi Chen, Le Chen, Huanan Wang, Jili Wen, Xiaying Kuang, Jianwen Zhang, Jiang Wu, Jia Lin, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1041(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414229888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Zhong, Zhaoyue Zhang, Xiaoying Chen, Qi Chen, Le Chen, Huanan Wang, Jili Wen, Xiaying Kuang, Jianwen Zhang, Jiang Wu, Jia Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.183765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning-Driven Mechanism Prediction and New Electrocatalyst Generation for Metal-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/227654-ms</link>
      <description>Maimuna U. Zarewa, Tawfik A. Saleh, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414232856

                Abstract In this work, copper-doped Electrocatalyst was synthesized via pyrolysis, and the electrocatalyst was characterized by XRD, FTIR, and XPS, followed by electrochemical testing. Also, a new electrocatalyst for metal-air batteries was designed, and reaction processes are predicted using large language models (LLMs) such as ChemBERT and ChemGPT. To train the models, RDKit was used to process SMILES representations of functional groups, doping techniques, and electrolyte media. While ChemGPT produced new electrocatalysts with an accuracy of 0.83, ChemBERT, which had been optimized to 0.8, was used to predict mechanisms. To speed up catalyst identification, the methodology incorporates reaction pathway predictions.</description>
      <author>Maimuna U. Zarewa, Tawfik A. Saleh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/227654-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion of Reversible Fuel-Power Generation in Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cell via Water-Mediated Ex-Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02146</link>
      <description>Sejong Ahn, Dongyeon Kim, Incheol Jeong, HeeChan Kang, Ivy Lim, GaEun Heo, Dae&#8208;Kwang Lim, Jun Kyu Kim, Ki&#8208;Min Roh, Bonjae Koo, Jun Hyuk Kim, Kang Taek Lee, WooChul Jung, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414245341

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sejong Ahn, Dongyeon Kim, Incheol Jeong, HeeChan Kang, Ivy Lim, GaEun Heo, Dae&#8208;Kwang Lim, Jun Kyu Kim, Ki&#8208;Min Roh, Bonjae Koo, Jun Hyuk Kim, Kang Taek Lee, WooChul Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Reaction Kinetics of Highly Selective Oxidation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural to 2,5-Furandicarboxylic Acid over NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c04048</link>
      <description>Linlin Wang, Lin Chen, Ruirui Xu, Mohd Adnan Khan, Jun Zhao, Xinti Yu, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jinguang Hu, Zhangxin Chen, Heng Zhao, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414245687

                Selective valorization of biomass feedstocks and their derivatives, using renewable electricity to produce value-added chemicals, is a promising route to decarbonize the chemical industry. Herein, we demonstrate the selective production of 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) from the electrocatalytic oxidation of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF). NiCo2S4 as an anode electrode exhibits almost 100% yield of FDCA with &gt;90% Faradaic efficiency (FE) and high stability at optimized conditions, which outperforms pure NiSx and CoSx. Theoretical calculations reveal that the enhanced reaction kinetics for HMF conversion to FDCA on NiCo2S4 arises from an optimal OH coverage and a more exergonic rate-limiting step compared with its monometallic counterparts. A techno-economic analysis (TEA) for a 100-ton/day FDCA industrial scale production facility reveals that the NiCo2S4 catalyst could drive economic feasibility of the process. This work provides an economically feasible approach to sustainably produce FDCA from HMF oxidation by electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Linlin Wang, Lin Chen, Ruirui Xu, Mohd Adnan Khan, Jun Zhao, Xinti Yu, Jonas Bj&#246;rk, Johanna Ros&#233;n, Jinguang Hu, Zhangxin Chen, Heng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5c04048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-Free Doping Strategies in Two-Dimensional Carbon Nitride C&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05773</link>
      <description>Bruno Ipaves, Jo&#227;o F. Justo, J. Almeida, L. V. C. Assali, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414249256

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bruno Ipaves, Jo&#227;o F. Justo, J. Almeida, L. V. C. Assali, Pedro Alves da Silva Autreto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c05773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into the Enhanced OER Activity of Single-Atom Iron Catalysts Compared to Metal Clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c02119</link>
      <description>Partha Pratim Borah, Kalishankar Bhattacharyya, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414250168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Partha Pratim Borah, Kalishankar Bhattacharyya</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c02119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Relations and Catalytic Descriptor for the Nitrogen Reduction on Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147389</link>
      <description>Matteo Spotti, Kevin Maineri, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414255615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Matteo Spotti, Kevin Maineri, Francesc Vi&#241;es, Francesc Illas, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147389</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NepTrain and NepTrainKit: Automated Active Learning and Visualization Toolkit for Neuroevolution Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109859</link>
      <description>Chengbing Chen, Yutong Li, Rui Zhao, Zhoulin Liu, Zheyong Fan, Gang Tang, Zhiyong Wang, Computer Physics Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414255949

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chengbing Chen, Yutong Li, Rui Zhao, Zhoulin Liu, Zheyong Fan, Gang Tang, Zhiyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2025.109859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mild selective hydrogenolysis of lignin-derived aryl ethers over Ni/CeO2 catalyst: Targeted cleavage of C-O bonds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115486</link>
      <description>Shiyuan Lu, Lan Zhou, Xu Gao, Li-Ying Sun, Yuan&#8208;Yuan Kang, Xu-Hui Han-ye, Zong-Pin Fu, Jing Liang, Yue-Lun Wang, Le&#8208;Le Qiu, Jian Xiao, Yun&#8208;Peng Zhao, Molecular Catalysis. 587(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414257763

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiyuan Lu, Lan Zhou, Xu Gao, Li-Ying Sun, Yuan&#8208;Yuan Kang, Xu-Hui Han-ye, Zong-Pin Fu, Jing Liang, Yue-Lun Wang, Le&#8208;Le Qiu, Jian Xiao, Yun&#8208;Peng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active and Durable Double-Layered Hydroxide Electrocatalysts by Tungsten and Sulfur Modification for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c05106</link>
      <description>Yan Sun, Yushen Liu, Fei Xiao, Fatima El Bachraoui, Guimei Liu, Guanghao Chen, Xitang Qian, Lanlu Lu, Yian Wang, Mohammad Farhadpour, Cunpu Li, Zidong Wei, Wei Xing, Minhua Shao, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414257959

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Sun, Yushen Liu, Fei Xiao, Fatima El Bachraoui, Guimei Liu, Guanghao Chen, Xitang Qian, Lanlu Lu, Yian Wang, Mohammad Farhadpour, Cunpu Li, Zidong Wei, Wei Xing, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c05106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Insights into Structure&#8208;Driven Selectivity in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogenation Over Cu&#8208;Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501115</link>
      <description>Kaustav Niyogi, Pedro S.F. Mendes, Matteo Maestri, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414259125

                Abstract Recent experiments indicate that the methanol selectivity in the CO 2 hydrogenation to methanol on copper is sensitive toward the catalyst structure, yet the mechanistic origins of such an effect remain unclear. In this study, we employ DFT calculations and statistical thermodynamics to elucidate the role of different copper catalyst facets in governing the product selectivity toward CO or methanol. Our analysis shows that both MeOH and rWGS reactions are structure&#8208;sensitive, agreeing with UHV experiments on clean copper surfaces. More interestingly, our study reveals that the competition between the two catalytic cycles is dependent on the catalyst structure: Cu(110) promotes methanol formation via a formate&#8208;mediated mechanism without any CO*&#8208;based intermediates, while Cu(111) favors CO formation via a newly proposed formate&#8208;to&#8208;carboxyl isomerization route. This distinction arises from the different activation tendencies of the key HCOOH* surface intermediate on each surface, driven by different adsorbate and transition&#8208;state stabilization effects. Our findings rationalize the experimental observations by supporting the hypothesis that different Cu facets exhibit a strong propensity toward enabling distinct catalytic cycles, leading to different product formation on them. As such, this work highlights the importance of accounting for structural information in the microkinetic analysis of CO 2 hydrogenation pathways.</description>
      <author>Kaustav Niyogi, Pedro S.F. Mendes, Matteo Maestri</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202501115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Cations for Carbon Dioxide Electroreduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500749</link>
      <description>Federico Dattila, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414259150

                Abstract The electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide () allows both the reduction of anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions and the storage of intermittent renewable energy. While modeling studies have focused on the catalyst for at least two decades, recently the electrolyte&#8211;electrode interface has attracted significant attention, especially metal cations. In this Perspective, we propose simple rules to predict the extent of cation effects on and water reduction depending on the transition metal catalyst, which we later extend to the case of alkali cation&#8208;induced surface dissolution. First, we highlight the difficulty of activating and the crucial boost that cations provide for late transition metals. Then we re&#8208;interpret state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art results in terms of a unique descriptor, i.e ., cation&#8208;induced electrostatic potential. Finally, we suggest a possible qualitative explanation for cation effects in cathodic dissolution and mention strategies to overcome cation&#8208;induced salt formation. The final Outlook lists directions that the modeling field should follow, i.e ., either simplicity (Computational Cation Electrode) or complexity (Multiscale models), showing the potential of simulations toward the understanding of novel electrochemical processes ( i.e ., in organic cations).</description>
      <author>Federico Dattila, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202500749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Linear Scaling Relations for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction with a Dual&#8208;Atom Catalyst Composed of a MnFe&#8208;Porphyrrole Aerogel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202514013</link>
      <description>Eliana Lebowitz, Prasenjit Das, &#321;ukasz Kielesi&#324;ski, Leigh Peles&#8208;Strahl, David A. Cullen, Ilya Grinberg, Daniel T. Gryko, Lior Elbaz, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414260611

                Abstract Bimetallic catalysts offer enhanced catalytic performance through synergistic interactions between the two metals, allowing them to break the linear scaling relations and reach high electrocatalytic activity. This study presents bimetallic aerogel&#8208;based catalyst synthesized as a covalent, three&#8208;dimensional framework containing neighboring iron and manganese sites. The aerogel structure provides a high surface area and porosity, facilitating an ultra&#8208;high active site density and efficient mass transport. The MnFe porphyrrole's unique structure is obtained by alternately linking Mn&#8208;porphyrin and Fe&#8208;corrole complexes. It exhibited outstanding performance with an onset potential of 0.99 V RHE . Comparative studies with a free&#8208;base Fe porphyrrole catalyst ( E onset 0.97 V RHE ) revealed that while Mn incorporation led to only a slight improvement in half&#8208;cell performance, it resulted in significantly enhanced performance in anion exchange membrane fuel cell. The MnFe catalyst achieved an OCV of 0.97 V and a peak power density of 0.27 W cm &#8722; 2 , outperforming the free&#8208;base Fe counterpart. Using density functional theory calculations, we show that the higher ORR activity of MnFe&#8208;porphyrrole is due to charge transfer between Mn and Fe atoms, which is absent in the reference free&#8208;base Fe&#8208;porphyrrole. These findings underscore the advantages of bimetallic catalysts in improving ORR activity and fuel cell efficiency by leveraging synergistic effects.</description>
      <author>Eliana Lebowitz, Prasenjit Das, &#321;ukasz Kielesi&#324;ski, Leigh Peles&#8208;Strahl, David A. Cullen, Ilya Grinberg, Daniel T. Gryko, Lior Elbaz</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202514013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient Formation of Single Layer Diamond During Friction Force Microscopy of SiC&#8208;Supported Epitaxial Graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500511</link>
      <description>Mohammad Zarshenas, Takuya Kuwahara, Bartosz Szczefanowicz, Andreas Klemenz, Leonhard Mayrhofer, Lars Pastewka, Gianpietro Moras, Roland Bennewitz, Michael Moseler, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414261640

                Abstract Carbon allotropes are crucial to advanced interfaces to control friction and wear because of their unique range of mechanical properties: from diamond's hardness to graphite's lubricity. Friction force microscopy (FFM) is reported for diamond tips sliding on SiC(0001)&#8208;supported epitaxial graphene. A sharp friction increase is observed at a threshold normal force, linked to an intermittent graphene rehybridization. Comparing the FFM response of a diamond tip to that of a previously studied silicon tip with a comparable radius reveals a similar abrupt friction increase, though at roughly half the threshold force. Atomistic simulations of SiC(0001)&#8208;supported graphene sliding against hydroxylated amorphous carbon (a&#8208;C) and silicon oxide show low shear stress at low pressures for both systems. The shear stress increases at higher pressures due to bond formation between graphene and the counterbody. For a&#8208;C, the transition threshold shifts to higher pressures, consistent with FFM results. In simulations with high normal pressures, epitaxial graphene undergoes a structural transformation into single&#8208;layer diamond, contributing to the abrupt increase in friction. The graphene structure recovers after lifting the a&#8208;C counterbody, demonstrating structural robustness under tribological stress. These findings provide insights into the stability of low&#8208;friction interfaces between epitaxial graphene and key materials for current micro&#8208;electro&#8208;mechanical systems (MEMS)</description>
      <author>Mohammad Zarshenas, Takuya Kuwahara, Bartosz Szczefanowicz, Andreas Klemenz, Leonhard Mayrhofer, Lars Pastewka, Gianpietro Moras, Roland Bennewitz, Michael Moseler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202500511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/Fe&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;S Composites Enable Efficient Asymmetric C&#8211;C Coupling for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalytic Reduction to C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;H&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.5c00511</link>
      <description>Huan Wang, Xinming Li, Lingling Peng, Yuexing Zhang, Renjie Li, Tianyou Peng, ACS Applied Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414262876

                CO2 electrocatalytic reduction (CO2ER) to multicarbon products is an effective method to reduce carbon emissions and achieve sustainable energy development. However, most CO2ER systems mainly convert CO2 into C1 products, while the main electrocatalysts for generating C2 products (such as C2H4, C2H6, C2H5OH, etc.) are Cu-based materials. Herein, a Fe-based composite (Fe3O4/Fe1&#8211;xS) is constructed via in situ sulfidation of Fe2O3. Using 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium hexafluorophosphate ([Bmim]PF6) acetonitrile (MeCN) solution as the electrolyte, the resultant Fe3O4/Fe1&#8211;xS with an optimal component ratio exhibits excellent CO2ER activity and stability with a current density of 35 mA cm&#8211;2 and C2H6 Faradaic efficiency (FE(C2H6)) of up to 67.5% at &#8722;1.60 V vs Ag/AgCl, which is much higher than the maximum values of pure Fe3O4 (3.5%) and Fe1&#8211;xS (36.7%). Experimental and theoretical results demonstrate that [Bmim]PF6 can reduce the activation energy of CO2 molecules and stabilize the *CO intermediate, while the synergistic effect of the electroactive Fe3+-substitution defects (FeFe&#8226;) in nonstoichiometric Fe1&#8211;xS and the Fe3O4/Fe1&#8211;xS interface plays a critical role in promoting the protonation of the *CO intermediate to form *CHO, asymmetric *CO&#8211;*CHO coupling, and then continuous dehydration and protonation to generate C2H6. These findings provide valuable insights for improving the CO2ER performance of Fe-based catalysts for the production of multicarbon products.</description>
      <author>Huan Wang, Xinming Li, Lingling Peng, Yuexing Zhang, Renjie Li, Tianyou Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.5c00511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;Blooming on rods&#8221; design 3D heterostructure toward boost electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151513</link>
      <description>Yang Wang, Zhen Cao, Hong Lan, Bo Li, Qiuxia Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 176(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414267040

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Wang, Zhen Cao, Hong Lan, Bo Li, Qiuxia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.151513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated design of iridium-based catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64787-5</link>
      <description>Jiahao Yang, Zhaoping Shi, Minhua Shao, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 77(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414275480

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahao Yang, Zhaoping Shi, Minhua Shao, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(25)64787-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic properties and ORR/OER catalytic activity of MOF-74 metal-organic frameworks: A theoretical study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147371</link>
      <description>Victor Hoyos-Sinchi, Walter Orellana, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414277570

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Victor Hoyos-Sinchi, Walter Orellana</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2025.147371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity of Carbon-Supported Pt-Co Catalysts Prepared by Electroless Deposition and Galvanic Replacement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15090895</link>
      <description>Angeliki Banti, Ivalina Avramova, S. Sotiropoulos, J. Georgieva, Catalysts. 15(9)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414282102

                The development of effective catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for improving the performance of fuel cells. Efficient carbon-supported Pt-Co nanocatalysts were successfully prepared by a generic two-step method: (i) electroless deposition of a Co-P coating on Vulcan XC72R carbon powder and (ii) subsequent spontaneous partial galvanic replacement of Co by Pt, upon immersion of the Co/C precursor in a chloroplatinate solution. The prepared Pt-Co particles (of a core-shell structure) are dispersed on a Vulcan XC-72 support, forming agglomerates made of nanoparticles smaller than 10 nm. The composition and surface morphology of the samples were characterized by scanning electron microscopy and energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (SEM/EDS) as well as transmission electron microscopy (TEM). The crystal structures of the Co-P/C precursor and Pt-Co/C catalyst were investigated by X-ray diffraction (XRD). XPS analysis was performed to study the chemical state of the surface layers of the precursor and catalyst. The electrochemical behavior of the Pt-Co/C composites was evaluated by cyclic voltammetry (CV). Linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) experiments were used to assess the catalytic activity towards the ORR and compared with that of a commercial Pt/C catalyst. The Pt-Co/C catalysts exhibit mass-specific and surface-specific activities (of jm = 133 mA mg&#8722;1 and jesa = 0.661 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively) at a typical overpotential value of 380 mV (+0.85 V vs. RHE); these are superior to those of similar electrodes made of a commercial Pt/C catalyst (jm = 50.6 mA mg&#8722;1; jesa = 0.165 mA cm&#8722;2). The beneficial effect of even small (&lt;1% wt.%) quantities of Co in the catalyst on Pt ORR activity may be attributed to an optimum catalyst composition and particle size resulting from the proposed preparation method.</description>
      <author>Angeliki Banti, Ivalina Avramova, S. Sotiropoulos, J. Georgieva</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15090895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-atom catalysts based on PN-co-doped graphene: a comparative study of iron, cobalt, and nickel for ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-025-02617-0</link>
      <description>Pegah Ghafouri Mirsaraei, Maryam Anafcheh, Elaheh Ahmadi, Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414284226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pegah Ghafouri Mirsaraei, Maryam Anafcheh, Elaheh Ahmadi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11224-025-02617-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of p&#8211;d orbital hybridization in Pt-M(p-block) dual-atom catalysts to promote the activity of electrocatalytic nitrobenzene reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164657</link>
      <description>Mingqiang Liu, Xiaoqing Gong, Yi Yang, Liang Yu, Xiaohong Song, Kefeng Xie, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414285678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingqiang Liu, Xiaoqing Gong, Yi Yang, Liang Yu, Xiaohong Song, Kefeng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.164657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Independent switchable atomic silver quantum transistor via potential-driven surface reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0280677</link>
      <description>Minghao Hua, Shuo Li, Xuelei Tian, Guoxiang Li, Xiaohang Lin, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414290227

                Atomic-scale quantum conductance switches based on metallic quantum point contacts allow controlled binary switching of the electrical current between a conducting &#8220;on state&#8221; and a non-conducting &#8220;off state&#8221; via an independent gate electrode. Although silver-based quantum switches operate via electrochemical conductance modulation, the underlying atomic-scale mechanisms remain unclear. In this study, we employed density functional theory combined with the computational hydrogen electrode (CHE) framework to investigate nitrate anion adsorption on Ag(100), Ag(111), and Ag(511) surfaces under varying electrochemical potentials. The stable configurations of nitrate adsorption on the electrode surfaces as a function of electrode potential are determined using the grand canonical approach within the CHE framework, revealing the surface reconstruction of Ag(511) analogous to the formation of nascent Ag&#8211;NO3 complexes. The thermodynamic analysis indicates that the critical phase transition occurs in agreement with the experimental switching threshold. Electronic structure calculations reveal metallic to semiconducting transitions in the reconstructed Ag&#8211;NO3 complex layers, elucidating the mechanism of conductance modulation. The &#8220;off state&#8221; corresponds to insulating Ag&#8211;NO3 surface complexes, while the &#8220;on state&#8221; arises from metallic Ag&#8211;Ag bridging at lower nitrate coverage under lower control voltage. This study establishes a general framework for anion-mediated quantum switching in transition metals and provides a design for nanoscale electrochemical devices.</description>
      <author>Minghao Hua, Shuo Li, Xuelei Tian, Guoxiang Li, Xiaohang Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0280677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrahigh Carrier Mobility and Enhanced Photocatalytic Activity in 2D GaSe/ZrTeS&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;4&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructures for Solar Water Splitting: A DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c02570</link>
      <description>Yi-Lin Lu, Chun-Chieh Lin, P.S. Cho, Fangchu Chen, Chia&#8208;Cheng Lee, Chen&#8208;Hao Yeh, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414295508

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi-Lin Lu, Chun-Chieh Lin, P.S. Cho, Fangchu Chen, Chia&#8208;Cheng Lee, Chen&#8208;Hao Yeh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.5c02570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Investigation of Mechanical Properties and Anisotropy of Argyrodite Li&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;PS&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;Cl Crystal Electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c05116</link>
      <description>Masato Torii, Yuki Okita, Kota Motohashi, Atsushi Sakuda, Akitoshi Hayashi, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414295550

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Masato Torii, Yuki Okita, Kota Motohashi, Atsushi Sakuda, Akitoshi Hayashi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c05116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Resolved Mechanistic Insights into OER-Selective Seawater Electrolysis on Co3O4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125974</link>
      <description>M.O. Abdel-Salam, Dasol Bae, Mostafa M. Omran, Yao Kang, Ehab N. El Sawy, Minkyu Kim, Tiem Leong Yoon, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414299904

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M.O. Abdel-Salam, Dasol Bae, Mostafa M. Omran, Yao Kang, Ehab N. El Sawy, Minkyu Kim, Tiem Leong Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing the Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis: Perspective on the Affordable Hydrogen Production Cost</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.etran.2025.100481</link>
      <description>Junyu Zhang, Mingye Yang, Gongquan Wang, Jian Dang, Hao Xu, Depeng Kong, Fuyuan Yang, Minggao Ouyang, eTransportation. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414301343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junyu Zhang, Mingye Yang, Gongquan Wang, Jian Dang, Hao Xu, Depeng Kong, Fuyuan Yang, Minggao Ouyang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.etran.2025.100481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in non-precious metal electrocatalysts for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis: Mechanistic insights, catalyst design, and structural regulation strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168587</link>
      <description>Qing Wang, Yuan Wang, Hon Man Luk, Jin-Ling Tang, Shuang Wu, Dongyang Wu, Zhongyuan Hu, Da Cui, Jinghui Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414304588

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Wang, Yuan Wang, Hon Man Luk, Jin-Ling Tang, Shuang Wu, Dongyang Wu, Zhongyuan Hu, Da Cui, Jinghui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.168587</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Mn intercalation and diffusion in NbSe&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e101" altimg="si4.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; bilayers through DFTB simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2025.116355</link>
      <description>Bruno Ipaves, Raphael Benjamim de Oliveira, Guilherme da Silva Lopes Fabris, Matthias Batzill, Douglas S. Galv&#227;o, Physica E Low-dimensional Systems and Nanostructures. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414307455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bruno Ipaves, Raphael Benjamim de Oliveira, Guilherme da Silva Lopes Fabris, Matthias Batzill, Douglas S. Galv&#227;o</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2025.116355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Photocatalytic, Mechanical, and Optical Performance of Rare&#8208;Earth&#8211;Doped Mg&#8322;Si: First&#8208;Principles Calculations and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.70396</link>
      <description>Jun-Hao Ye, Xinhai Wang, Dehai Yu, Fuqiang Ai, Songguo Yu, Jie Shen, Lu Shen, Qingquan Xiao, Li Shen, Quan Xie, Applied Organometallic Chemistry. 39(10)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414308363

                ABSTRACT Broadband light absorption, mechanical resilience, and efficient surface catalysis are all crucial for photocatalytic semiconductors, yet they are rarely improved together in one material. We combine first&#8208;principles calculations with machine&#8208;learning interpretability and Pearson correlation analyses to reveal that rare&#8208;earth (La, Er) doping of Mg&#8322;Si can synergistically enhance its optoelectronic, mechanical, and hydrogen&#8208;evolution performance. La doping introduces conduction&#8208;band impurity states via La&#8208;5d/Si&#8208;3p orbital hybridization, boosting sub&#8208;bandgap (infrared) absorption by 60&#8208;fold (~0.6 &#215; 10 5 cm &#8722;1 ) and extending the absorption edge into the near&#8208;infrared&#8212;translating to a solar&#8208;to&#8208;hydrogen conversion efficiency of up to 39.86%. It also percolates a metallic bond network that doubles the Poisson's ratio (0.23 &#8594; 0.46), transforming Mg&#8322;Si from brittle to ductile. Er doping, in contrast, localizes 4f orbitals, yielding exciton&#8208;like absorption peaks (~10 5 cm &#8722;1 ) in the ultraviolet and inducing a distinct electronic and mechanical response. Both dopants push the Fermi level into the conduction band (degenerate n&#8208;type doping), fundamentally altering carrier characteristics. Catalytically, La doping generates delocalized sp 3 d 2 orbitals that give near&#8208;thermoneutral hydrogen adsorption (&#916; G H* &#8776; &#8722;0.04 eV), outperforming noble&#8208;metal catalysts, whereas Er's extended electron density enhances H binding at the cost of slower H&#8322; desorption. SHAP (SHapley Additive exPlanations) analysis further identifies the key orbital and elastic descriptors governing these trends, providing a mechanistic blueprint.</description>
      <author>Jun-Hao Ye, Xinhai Wang, Dehai Yu, Fuqiang Ai, Songguo Yu, Jie Shen, Lu Shen, Qingquan Xiao, Li Shen, Quan Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.70396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic performance in direct ethanol fuel cells: Contributions of monometallic, bimetallic, and trimetallic catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100124</link>
      <description>Pariksha Bishnoi, Kirti Bhushan Mishra, U&#287;ur &#350;en, Samarjeet Singh Siwal, Materials Today Catalysis. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414309165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pariksha Bishnoi, Kirti Bhushan Mishra, U&#287;ur &#350;en, Samarjeet Singh Siwal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid pathways for methane production: Merging thermodynamic insights with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146662</link>
      <description>Azita Etminan, Peter J. Holliman, Peyman Karimi, Mahshid Majd, Ian Mabbett, Mary Larimi, Ciar&#225;n Martin, Anna R. L. Carter, Journal of Cleaner Production. 526(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414309522

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Azita Etminan, Peter J. Holliman, Peyman Karimi, Mahshid Majd, Ian Mabbett, Mary Larimi, Ciar&#225;n Martin, Anna R. L. Carter</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Electrosynthesis: A Perspective on Mechanistic Questions, Methodological Approaches, and Elucidating the Role of the Electrical Double Layer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04993</link>
      <description>John H. Hymel, Chloe Anne Renfro, Shahriar N. Khan, John P. Pederson, Jesse G. McDaniel, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414314825

                In this perspective, we discuss how modern computational chemistry techniques are utilized to elucidate electrosynthesis reaction mechanisms via the computation of kinetic rate parameters that depend on reaction conditions. The specific focus is on elementary reaction steps that occur within the electrical double layer (EDL) environment at the working electrode/electrolyte interface, for which the governing free energy profiles and rate constants can be explicitly computed from classical molecular dynamics and hybrid quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) computer simulations with atomistic resolution of the EDL environment. We focus on direct electrolysis reactions at inert electrodes with prototypical "E-C-E" mechanisms, in which the reaction yield and selectivity may depend on whether the full process occurs heterogeneously within the EDL, or rather the steps following the initial electron transfer proceed homogeneously with the second electron transfer occurring via disproportionation (DISP pathway). For short-lived radical intermediates with lifetimes of &#8764;10&#8211;10&#8211;10&#8211;7 s, branching between heterogeneous E-C-E and homogeneous DISP pathways is dictated by rate constants for substrate/intermediate desorption from the electrode surface (e.g., kD &#8764; 107&#8211;1010 s&#8211;1), which are difficult to determine experimentally but can be computed from molecular dynamics simulations. We discuss how strong solvophobic forces within electrolytes lead to significant association free energies between electrogenerated radical ion intermediates and the working electrode surface, resulting in residence times within the EDL that are on par with time constants of fast radical ion reactions. For electrosynthesis reactions that proceed entirely heterogeneously, the EDL environment can substantially modulate the reaction kinetics via electrostatic, solvophobic, and steric forces. We present several case studies highlighting modulated reaction kinetics within the EDL for nucleophilic coupling and deprotonation reactions of cation radical intermediates in anodic electrosynthesis. We expect that computational techniques will play an increasingly valuable role in optimizing electrosynthesis reactions via mechanistic descriptions of how key kinetic rate parameters are modulated by electrochemical reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>John H. Hymel, Chloe Anne Renfro, Shahriar N. Khan, John P. Pederson, Jesse G. McDaniel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-capacity, reversible hydrogen storage using H &lt;sup&gt;&#8211;&lt;/sup&gt; -conducting solid electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adw1996</link>
      <description>Takashi Hirose, Naoki Matsui, Takashi Itoh, Yoyo Hinuma, Kazutaka Ikeda, Kazuma Gotoh, Guangzhong Jiang, Kota Suzuki, Masaaki Hirayama, Ryoji Kanno, Science. 389(6766)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414321624

                Hydrogen absorption and desorption in solids are pivotal reactions involved in batteries and hydrogen storage devices. However, conventional thermodynamic and electrochemical hydrogen storage using high-capacity materials suffers from high hydrogen-desorption temperatures and instability of electrolytes. In this work, we explored electrochemical hydride ion (H &#8211; )&#8211;driven hydrogen storage and developed a solid electrolyte, anti&#8211;&#945;-AgI&#8211;type Ba 0.5 Ca 0.35 Na 0.15 H 1.85 , which exhibits excellent H &#8211; conductivity and electrochemical stability. This electrolyte is compatible with several metal-hydrogen electrodes, such as titanim hydride and magnesium hydride (MgH 2 ), allowing for high-capacity, reversible hydrogen storage at low temperatures. Specifically, Mg&#8211;H 2 cells operating as hydrogen storage devices (Mg + H 2  &#8644;  MgH 2 ) achieved a reversible capacity of 2030 milliampere hours per gram at 90&#176;C, offering safe and efficient hydrogen-electricity conversion and hydrogen storage devices.</description>
      <author>Takashi Hirose, Naoki Matsui, Takashi Itoh, Yoyo Hinuma, Kazutaka Ikeda, Kazuma Gotoh, Guangzhong Jiang, Kota Suzuki, Masaaki Hirayama, Ryoji Kanno</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adw1996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Water in Modulating the Fe&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt;/Fe&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; Redox Couple in Iron-Based Complexes and Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02424</link>
      <description>Alessandro Bonardi, Shuai Xu, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414323102

                A key challenge in modeling electrocatalysis with single-atom catalysts (SACs) is accurately capturing the redox behavior of transition metals across oxidation states. This is particularly true for iron, a widely used element in such systems. Iron phthalocyanine (FePc) serves as a model compound for graphene-based Fe SACs and is commonly used in reactions like the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). While FePc initially contains Fe(II), the active species under oxidative conditions is Fe(III), with an Fe(II)/Fe(III) transition occurring at intermediate potentials. Density functional theory (DFT) simulations must reflect this redox change. However, standard DFT predicts that oxidation removes an electron from the ligand, leaving the iron in the II state. This limitation arises not from DFT itself, but from an incomplete model. We show that adding at least one (preferably two) water molecules to the axial coordination sites of iron corrects this issue. The water ligands raise the energy of iron orbitals, making electron removal from the metal more favorable. This finding has two key implications: (1) the redox properties of transition metal complexes and graphene-based SACs are strongly influenced by the coordination environment, including solvent molecules; and (2) accurate description of the atomistic structure of the catalyst requires the explicit inclusion of axial water ligands, not just the in-plane ligands, to capture the true redox behavior.</description>
      <author>Alessandro Bonardi, Shuai Xu, Giovanni Di Liberto, Gianfranco Pacchioni</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.5c02424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Prediction to Performance: A Roadmap for Single-Atom Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02226</link>
      <description>Dennis Meier, E. Charles H. Sykes, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414323236

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dennis Meier, E. Charles H. Sykes</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactivity of Carbonate Solvent Electrolytes on Lithium Silicon Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c08232</link>
      <description>Heonjae Jeong, Christopher S. Johnson, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414323290

                Silicon (Si) is promising for lithium-ion battery (LIB) anodes due to their high theoretical capacity and low electrochemical potential. However, significant challenges remain, including severe volumetric expansion during cycling and the electrochemical instability of electrolytes, which leads to the formation of a nonuniform solid electrolyte interphase (SEI). To investigate SEI formation mechanisms, computational molecular dynamics simulations offer valuable insights. In this study, we examine the trajectories and charge transfer behavior of lithium hexafluorophosphate (LiPF6) salt with various solvent compositions using density functional theory (DFT) and ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD). Among the tested electrolyte systems, LiPF6 with vinylene carbonate (VC) added to ethyl methyl carbonate (EMC) exhibits the lowest reactivity with the Si anode. In contrast, the effects of fluoroethylene carbonate (FEC) and VC depend on whether the primary solvent is EMC alone or a mixture of ethylene carbonate (EC) and EMC. Moreover, we show that electrolyte reactivity varies with the degree of lithiation of the Si anode (LiSi vs Li15Si4) and under different charge states. To decouple electrolyte reactivity from surface effects, we analyze the dissociation and formation energies of individual species from solvated configurations. Overall, these first-principles-based findings provide a strategic foundation for electrolyte design to improve cycling stability and extend calendar life in LIBs using Si anodes.</description>
      <author>Heonjae Jeong, Christopher S. Johnson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c08232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) Lubrication of Rolling Point Contacts by Double Transfer Films: Relationships between Friction and Lubricant Film Distribution Revealed by Spacer Layer Imaging and Molecular Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10402004.2025.2513933</link>
      <description>Thomas Reichenbach, Stephan von Goeldel, Stefan Peeters, Georgios Vokolos, Florian K&#246;nig, Georg Jacobs, Gianpietro Moras, Michael Moseler, Tribology Transactions. 68(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414325619

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thomas Reichenbach, Stephan von Goeldel, Stefan Peeters, Georgios Vokolos, Florian K&#246;nig, Georg Jacobs, Gianpietro Moras, Michael Moseler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/10402004.2025.2513933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six-dimensional quantum dynamics of dissociation of HCl on bimetallic surfaces: Cu/Ag(111) &lt;i&gt;vs&lt;/i&gt;. Cu/Au(111)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/1674-0068/cjcp2505062</link>
      <description>Tianhui Liu, Bina Fu, Dong H. Zhang, Chinese Journal of Chemical Physics. 38(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414325891

                In this study, six-dimensional (6D) time-dependent wave packet calculations were employed to investigate the dissociation of HCl molecules on two bimetallic surfaces, Cu/Ag(111) and Cu/Au(111). These calculations were based on two accurate potential energy surfaces (PESs) constructed using neural network methodology. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed that the static barrier heights for HCl on Cu/Ag(111) and Cu/Au(111) were 0.32 eV and 0.28 eV, respectively. These values are significantly lower than the barrier height on pure Cu(111) (0.52 eV), primarily due to surface strain effects. However, it was found that the 6D dissociation probability of HCl in (v=0, 1, j=0) states on Cu/Au(111) was considerably lower, despite its barrier height being 0.04 eV lower than that for Cu/Ag(111). The underlying mechanism for this observation was attributed to the non-monotonic dependence of the minimum energy path (MEP) on the molecular orientation, which was induced by charge transfer effect for HCl+Cu/Au(111). In contrast, HCl+Cu/Ag(111) exhibited a monotonic dependence. These contrasting behaviors led to distinct differences in rotational alignment and excitation effects for the two reactions.</description>
      <author>Tianhui Liu, Bina Fu, Dong H. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/1674-0068/cjcp2505062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of Isobutylene from Syngas &#8211; Isosynthesis Over Zirconia-Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02184-y</link>
      <description>Niko Heikkinen, Laura Keskiv&#228;li, Krista Kuutti, Rasmus Ikonen, Bhumi A. Baraiya, Ville Korpelin, Manu Lahtinen, Jaana Kanervo, Mikko Heikkil&#228;, Xinwei Ye, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Karoliina Honkala, Juha Lehtonen, Matti Reinikainen, Topics in Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414329573

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Niko Heikkinen, Laura Keskiv&#228;li, Krista Kuutti, Rasmus Ikonen, Bhumi A. Baraiya, Ville Korpelin, Manu Lahtinen, Jaana Kanervo, Mikko Heikkil&#228;, Xinwei Ye, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Karoliina Honkala, Juha Lehtonen, Matti Reinikainen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-025-02184-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed transition metal phosphides: recent progress and frontiers in secondary batteries and supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5nr01892g</link>
      <description>Chandan Kumar Maity, Sayak Roy, Amrita De Adhikari, Khusboo Kumari, Myung Jong Kim, Sumanta Sahoo, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414331499

                Metal phosphides, which have been extensively explored for energy storage applications such as batteries and supercapacitors, possess unique physicochemical, morphological, and electrochemical properties.</description>
      <author>Chandan Kumar Maity, Sayak Roy, Amrita De Adhikari, Khusboo Kumari, Myung Jong Kim, Sumanta Sahoo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5nr01892g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doxorubicin Intercalated Co&#8208;Al Layered Double Hydroxide Nanocarrier With pH&#8208;Responsive Controlled Release and Selective Melanoma Suppression: Toward Next&#8208;Generation Nanotherapeutics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202506499</link>
      <description>Swapan Maity, Akshita Upreti, Shantanu Chowdhury, Dipesh Kumar Dubey, Hitesh Harsukhbhai Chandpa, Jairam Meena, Manas Kumar Santra, Pralay Maiti, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414333095

                Abstract Clinical oncology grapples with persistent challenges, particularly the rapid onset of tumor resistance and the systemic limitations of conventional chemotherapeutics such as doxorubicin (Dox). Despite its potency, Dox suffers from poor solubility, non&#8208;specific distribution, and severe toxicity, often compromising therapeutic efficacy. Addressing these obstacles, this study explores cobalt&#8208;aluminium layered double hydroxides (Co&#8208;Al LDHs) as smart nanocarriers for targeted melanoma therapy. Capitalizing on their tunable structure, high drug&#8208;loading capacity, and biocompatibility, Co&#8208;Al LDHs facilitate enhanced encapsulation, sustained release, and selective tumor accumulation of Dox. Density Functional Theory (DFT) analyses confirm robust molecular interactions between Dox and the LDH matrix, ensuring structural stability and favorable energetics for drug delivery. In vitro assays reveal significant cytotoxicity (&#8776;80%) against melanoma cells and with minimal toxicity (&#8776;8%) to normal muscle cells. Furthermore, in vivo evaluations using luciferase&#8208;tagged B16&#8208;F10 melanoma models demonstrate pronounced tumor inhibition and excellent systemic biocompatibility. Augmented by machine learning&#8208;guided force field modelling, this platform also offers a predictive framework for engineering next&#8208;generation nanotherapeutics. Together, these findings position Co&#8208;Al LDHs as a promising frontier in nanomedicine, merging targeted delivery, controlled release, and computational precision to overcome current therapeutic barriers in melanoma treatment and beyond.</description>
      <author>Swapan Maity, Akshita Upreti, Shantanu Chowdhury, Dipesh Kumar Dubey, Hitesh Harsukhbhai Chandpa, Jairam Meena, Manas Kumar Santra, Pralay Maiti</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202506499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Entropy Perovskite Nanofibers for Bifunctional Air Electrodes in Reversible Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202517768</link>
      <description>Hyeong-Geun Kim, Incheol Jeong, Seeun Oh, Dongyeon Kim, Kang Taek Lee, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414334495

                Abstract Protonic ceramic electrochemical cells (PCECs) offer a promising platform for efficient energy conversion and storage at reduced temperatures (&lt;650 &#176;C). However, the commercial viability of PCECs remains hindered by the limited durability and sluggish oxygen electrocatalysis at the air electrode. Herein, a high&#8208;entropy perovskite oxide (HEPO), Pr 0.2 Ba 0.2 Sr 0.2 La 0.2 Nd 0.2 CoO 3&#8208;&#948; (PBSLNC), in a nanofiber architecture is presented as a bifunctional air electrode material for reversible PCEC operation. The unique A&#8208;site compositional complexity promotes defect tolerance, abundant oxygen vacancies, rapid surface exchange kinetics while maintaining exceptional phase stability in harsh environments. Density functional theory calculations elucidate the entropically modulated Co environment that enhances hydroperoxide adsorption&#8212;a key step for oxygen electrocatalysis, thereby facilitating both oxygen reduction and evolution reactions. When deployed into a PCEC configuration, the PBSNLC nanofiber electrode achieves a peak power density of 1.4 W cm &#8722;2 at 650 &#176;C and electrolysis current density of 3.98 A cm &#8722;2 at 650 &#176;C, along with outstanding operational stability during continuous operation for over 1000 h. These findings provide valuable guidance for the strategic design of highly efficient and stable bifunctional air electrodes for PCECs.</description>
      <author>Hyeong-Geun Kim, Incheol Jeong, Seeun Oh, Dongyeon Kim, Kang Taek Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202517768</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Engineering of Zr&#8211;MOFs with Hemin Molecules and Diacetylene Linkages along the Topological Structure for the Tandem Catalysis of Nitrate to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202517067</link>
      <description>Anqi Lv, Jiahao Ma, Kexin Liu, Z.Y. Ma, Yi&#8208;Fei Deng, Qiuyu Zhang, Changhong Wang, Sifei Zhuo, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414334609

                Abstract A tandem electrocatalyst with dual&#8208;active&#8208;sites is anticipated to organize the coupling reaction between various intermediates from nitrate to ammonia. Herein, by engineering the metal nodes and ligands of Zr&#8208;based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (Zr&#8208;MOFs) with Fe&#8208;porphyrins (Hemins) and diacetylene linkages, respectively, a tandem catalyst of diacetylene&#8208;linked Zr&#8211;MOFs anchored Hemins has been achieved. The key point here is that the diacetylene linkages could serve as cofactors of Hemins to manage the nitrate to ammonia process via NO 2 &#8722; intermediates. In addition, the ultrathin Zr&#8211;MOFs nanosheet with a well&#8208;defined open framework allows it to organize the shuttle diffusion and coupling reaction of various reactants between Hemins and diacetylene linkages in its deep interior. In detail, the NO 2 &#8722; desorbed from the Hemins could diffuse onto the diacetylene linkages to finish the following hydrogenation process to NH 3 . Therefore, such an ultrathin hybrid of diacetylene&#8208;linked Zr&#8211;MOF@Hemin achieves a Faradaic efficiency of 95.6% with an ammonia yield of 240.9 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 at &#8722;0.5 V versus RHE. This work indicates the activity of diacetylene linkage in catalysis independent of graphdiyne&#8208;based 2D structures by organizing it into the topological structure of Zr&#8211;MOFs, which expands the scope of graphdiyne in structure.</description>
      <author>Anqi Lv, Jiahao Ma, Kexin Liu, Z.Y. Ma, Yi&#8208;Fei Deng, Qiuyu Zhang, Changhong Wang, Sifei Zhuo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202517067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Organic Frameworks Anchoring Single&#8208;Atom Pt for Three&#8208;Phase Interface&#8208;Assisted Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202515397</link>
      <description>Tingting Sun, Hao Zhang, Ya Wang, Nannan Zhang, Luhua Shao, Hong Dong, Fengming Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414334765

                Abstract Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are promising photocatalysts for overall water splitting (OWS) due to their high crystallinity, porosity and tunable structures. However, current COF&#8208;based systems rely on cocatalysts, which suffer from low atomic utilization and poor distribution due to aggregation. In addition, the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) backward reaction severely undermines catalytic efficiency and stability in long time reaction. Herein, we present a strategy that combines atomically dispersed Pt sites anchored via N/O coordination within triazine&#8208;based COFs and a gas&#8208;liquid&#8208;solid three&#8208;phase interface&#8208;assisted photocatalytic system to enhance both performance and durability. As a result, the Pt&#8208;TBPyT&#8208;COF achieves superior OWS performance with H 2 and O 2 evolution rates of 469.8 and 234.9 &#181;mol&#183;g &#8722;1 &#183;h &#8722;1 , respectively, and an apparent quantum yield of 8.91% at 450 nm. Notably, the OWS via gas&#8208;liquid&#8208;solid three&#8208;phase interface&#8208;assisted method effectively suppresses ORR backward reaction and reaches average rates as high as 568.7 and 284.3 &#181;mol&#183;g &#8722;1 &#183;h &#8722;1 for H 2 and O 2 in 5 h, respectively, and maintained stable photocatalytic activity over a 30 h continuous reaction. Further, density functional theory calculations and in situ experiments reveal that the single&#8208;atoms Pt coordination accelerates *H desorption, while the triazine units in COFs benefits charge separation and reduced energy barriers of OER rate&#8208;determining step.</description>
      <author>Tingting Sun, Hao Zhang, Ya Wang, Nannan Zhang, Luhua Shao, Hong Dong, Fengming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202515397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Organic Frameworks Anchoring Single&#8208;Atom Pt for Three&#8208;Phase Interface&#8208;Assisted Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202515397</link>
      <description>Tingting Sun, Hao Zhang, Ya Wang, Nannan Zhang, Luhua Shao, Hong Dong, Fengming Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414335263

                Abstract Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are promising photocatalysts for overall water splitting (OWS) due to their high crystallinity, porosity and tunable structures. However, current COF&#8208;based systems rely on cocatalysts, which suffer from low atomic utilization and poor distribution due to aggregation. In addition, the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) backward reaction severely undermines catalytic efficiency and stability in long time reaction. Herein, we present a strategy that combines atomically dispersed Pt sites anchored via N/O coordination within triazine&#8208;based COFs and a gas&#8208;liquid&#8208;solid three&#8208;phase interface&#8208;assisted photocatalytic system to enhance both performance and durability. As a result, the Pt&#8208;TBPyT&#8208;COF achieves superior OWS performance with H 2 and O 2 evolution rates of 469.8 and 234.9 &#181;mol&#183;g &#8722;1 &#183;h &#8722;1 , respectively, and an apparent quantum yield of 8.91% at 450 nm. Notably, the OWS via gas&#8208;liquid&#8208;solid three&#8208;phase interface&#8208;assisted method effectively suppresses ORR backward reaction and reaches average rates as high as 568.7 and 284.3 &#181;mol&#183;g &#8722;1 &#183;h &#8722;1 for H 2 and O 2 in 5 h, respectively, and maintained stable photocatalytic activity over a 30 h continuous reaction. Further, density functional theory calculations and in situ experiments reveal that the single&#8208;atoms Pt coordination accelerates *H desorption, while the triazine units in COFs benefits charge separation and reduced energy barriers of OER rate&#8208;determining step.</description>
      <author>Tingting Sun, Hao Zhang, Ya Wang, Nannan Zhang, Luhua Shao, Hong Dong, Fengming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202515397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Crystal Phases Mediate &lt;i&gt;o&lt;/i&gt;-Semiquinone Radical Generation for Selective Aniline Contaminant Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.5c08657</link>
      <description>Xuewen Luo, Zhuofeng Hu, Han Xiao, Yangjian Zhou, Xin Yang, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414341411

                Traditional advanced oxidation processes (AOPs) often face significant challenges in contaminant degradation due to strong interference from complex water matrices. In this study, o-semiquinone radicals (o-SQ&#8226;-)-driven AOP was established by MnO2-mediated catechol oxidation, achieving selective degradation of aniline contaminants (e.g., sulfamethoxazole (SMX)) in real water matrices. Four MnO2 crystal phases (&#945;-, &#946;-, &#947;-, and &#948;-MnO2) were evaluated, and the degradation efficiency of SMX followed the order &#947; &gt; &#945; &gt; &#946; &gt; &#948;-MnO2. Both MnO2 surface-bound o-SQ&#8226;- and aqueous-phase Mn(II)-o-SQ&#8226;- contributed to the SMX degradation. Crystal phases dictated o-SQ&#8226;- generation&#9472;&#945;-, &#946;-, and &#947;-MnO2&#9472;favored the MnO2 solids surface binding of o-SQ&#8226;-, while &#948;-MnO2 promoted the interaction of o-SQ&#8226;- with Mn(II) in the aqueous phase. Higher MnO2 redox potentials and Mn(IV) content correlated with enhanced o-SQ&#8226;- generation and faster SMX degradation. Mechanistic studies revealed that o-SQ&#8226;- attacks SMX through radical addition, forming low-toxicity products. Given that dihydroxyphenyl is a prevalent component of natural aquatic environments, this work advances the design of selective, eco-friendly AOPs with anti-interference capabilities.</description>
      <author>Xuewen Luo, Zhuofeng Hu, Han Xiao, Yangjian Zhou, Xin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.5c08657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper Sulfide Nanospheres Were Prepared as Efficient Water-Splitting Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-025-07737-w</link>
      <description>Qian Li, Wenpei Wang, Yaqing Weng, Lili Gao, Xihong He, Jinjing Du, Xiaojun Zhao, JOM. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414349285

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Li, Wenpei Wang, Yaqing Weng, Lili Gao, Xihong He, Jinjing Du, Xiaojun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-025-07737-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic anion leaching-readsorption in Ni3S2@MoO3 heterostructures boosts the electrocatalytic activity of anion exchange membrane water electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.139055</link>
      <description>Jie Han, Shifan Yang, Weiwei Bao, Taotao Ai, Zhifeng Deng, Peng Jiang, Xueling Wei, Xiangyu Zou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414351067

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jie Han, Shifan Yang, Weiwei Bao, Taotao Ai, Zhifeng Deng, Peng Jiang, Xueling Wei, Xiangyu Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.139055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Pt&#8208;Based Bimetallic Active Sites for Efficient Oxygen Reduction Reaction on C&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; Skeleton</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503969</link>
      <description>Jing Jia, Li&#8208;Ming Yang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414364710

                Abstract In this work, Pt&#8208;based bimetal catalysts PtM@C 6 N 6 (M = 3d, 4d, 5d) for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is systematically investigated by comprehensive consideration of different coordination modes and anchored sites of Pt and M atoms on experimentally synthesized C 6 N 6 substrate, different adsorption configuration of O 2 molecule from both above and below the catalyst surface, different reaction pathway, and structure&#8208;activity relationship via computer&#8208;aided screening and density functional theory (DFT) computations. Comprehensive search and in&#8208;deep analysis reveal that seven representative electrocatalysts (i.e., PtAg@, PtCd@, PtCu@, PtIr@, PtRh@, PtHf@, and PtZr@C 6 N 6 ) demonstrate high ORR catalytic activities under both acidic and basic conditions with favorable overpotentials. Full reaction pathway search demonstrates that the ORR follows a 4&#8208;electron mechanism with the final product H 2 O/OH &#8722; . PtCd@, PtCu@, PtIr@, PtRh@, and PtZr@C 6 N 6 exhibit superior activities with low &#951; ORR due to their moderate adsorption strength of *OH, while PtAg@ and PtHf@C 6 N 6 exhibit excellent catalytic performance is attributed to moderate O 2 adsorption Furthermore, a series of descriptors (e.g., &#916;G 0 a , &#916;G 4 a , &#916;G 4 a &#8211;d(Pt&#8208;M), and [d(Pt&#8208;O2)&#215;d(M&#8208;O2)]&#215;[d(M&#8208;O2)/d(M&#8208;O1)], etc) are uncovered to unveil the origin of catalyst activity. These findings pave a significant path for the development of efficient ORR catalysts and are expected to stimulate experimental efforts in this direction.</description>
      <author>Jing Jia, Li&#8208;Ming Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy and Resource Generation via Electrochemical Ammonia Oxidation: From Materials Design to System Integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503846</link>
      <description>Mengdi Wang, Haotian Tan, Xiaoqing Liu, Xiao Yan, Ji Liang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414364826

                Abstract Nitrogen is an essential nutrient for all life forms, rendering the nitrogen looping one of the most critical biogeochemical processes on Earth. However, global industrial and agricultural activities have severely disrupted natural nitrogen cycling, causing environmental impact and energy consumption through conventional processes such as the Haber&#8211;Bosch and Ostwald method. Addressing this imbalance requires innovative technologies that reconcile efficient nitrogen utilization with environmental sustainability. Electrochemical nitrogen transformation, especially the electrochemical oxidation of ammonia under mild conditions, has emerged as a promising solution, enabling the conversion of reactive nitrogen species into energy and valuable products while mitigating environmental impacts. This review comprehensively examines recent advances in ammonia&#8208;centric nitrogen utilization technologies, focusing on their roles as: 1) carbon&#8208;neutral energy vectors (ammonia fuel cells), 2) efficient hydrogen carriers (ammonia cracking), and 3) precursors for high&#8208;value nitrogenous chemicals via controlled oxidation pathways under mild conditions. The full&#8208;chain design framework, namely, from material innovations to practical system integration, is analyzed, while elucidating fundamental reaction mechanisms, performance benchmarks, and scale&#8208;up methodologies. The review aims to provide a foundational reference for developing sustainable electrochemical solutions for establishing a nitrogen&#8208;based and net&#8208;zero energy/resource economics, and in the meantime, addressing the potential nitrogen pollution control and resource recovery.</description>
      <author>Mengdi Wang, Haotian Tan, Xiaoqing Liu, Xiao Yan, Ji Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Honeycomb Borophene for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution via Substrate-Induced &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-Band Center Modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c12479</link>
      <description>Wenjun Tang, Haiyuan Chen, Xiaobin Niu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414371432

                Developing efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is crucial for enabling sustainable hydrogen production through water electrolysis. Two-dimensional (2D) boron allotropes, particularly honeycomb borophene (hc-B), have emerged as promising candidates due to their electron-deficient nature and rich active sites. However, this same electron deficiency compromises their structural stability, limiting practical applications. In this study, we employ first-principles calculations to investigate a donor&#8211;acceptor hc-B/V2CS2 heterostructure, where the V2CS2 substrate plays a dual role in stabilizing hc-B and modulating its catalytic properties. Machine learning-accelerated molecular dynamics simulations in an explicit water environment confirm the heterostructure's exceptional structural integrity and aqueous tolerance over 50 ps. Remarkably, the hc-B side of the heterostructure exhibits hydrogen adsorption Gibbs free energy values near the thermoneutral point, outperforming benchmark catalysts such as Pt and the MoS2 S-edge. Electronic structure analyses reveal that the enhanced HER activity arises from substrate-induced modulation of the boron p-band center, which promotes an optimal binding environment for H intermediates through interfacial orbital hybridization and stabilized B&#8211;H coordination. Furthermore, reaction pathway analysis incorporating explicit solvation identifies the Volmer&#8211;Tafel mechanism as the kinetically preferred route on hc-B/V2CS2. These findings highlight the synergistic role of substrate engineering and interfacial electronic tuning in activating borophene-based HER catalysts, offering new directions for designing high-performance 2D catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Wenjun Tang, Haiyuan Chen, Xiaobin Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5c12479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rose-like NiFe-LDH/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysts Achieve 1000 mA cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8211;2&lt;/sup&gt; OER with Enhanced Charge Transfer and Seawater Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c01006</link>
      <description>Xin Li, Yue Qin, Boyang Zhang, Boyao Zhang, Rongda Zhao, Jia Li, Depeng Zhao, Lihua Miao, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414373839

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Li, Yue Qin, Boyang Zhang, Boyao Zhang, Rongda Zhao, Jia Li, Depeng Zhao, Lihua Miao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.5c01006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Laser Writing of Bioinspired High&#8208;Entropy Oxide Nanoarrays for Practical Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503929</link>
      <description>Lin Cheng, Qi Wang, Haojie Liu, Yi Rao, Junfeng Cui, Hanwen Liu, Jinli Chen, W. Shi, Lei Zhang, Bo Song, Yonggang Yao, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414376769

                Abstract Industrial water electrolysis faces a triple challenge at high current densities (&#8805;500 mA cm &#8722;2 ): reconciling catalytic activity, stability, and severe gas&#8208;liquid transport. While high&#8208;entropy oxides (HEOs) show catalytic promise, conventional methods predominantly focus on elemental regulation and neglect critical morphological optimization, thus failing to unify composition&#8208;architecture&#8208;transport functionality to prevail at industrial conditions. Here, the morphological HEO electrode is introduced, a bioinspired framework integrating multielement mixing, architectural hierarchy, and surface adaptation. High&#8208;throughput optimization identifies a critical nanosecond laser parameter window where rapid quenching traps metastable FeCoNiMoCrO x HEO nanoparticles foliage while Marangoni flows sculpt Ti microcone trunks. This structure exhibits superaerophobic&#8208;superhydrophilic properties and exceptional oxygen evolution performance (&#951; 10 = 188 mV). In an anion&#8208;exchange membrane electrolyzer, the electrode achieves 1 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.82 V (surpassing commercial IrO 2 &#8208;coated Ti mesh), while maintaining stable operation for 600 h at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 (degradation rate: 38.33 &#181;V h &#8722;1 ). DFT calculations confirm that Mo/Cr electronically modulates the primary OER active Ni sites via the M&#8208;O&#8208;M network, optimizing the d&#8208;band center and favoring the Adsorbate Evolution Mechanism (AEM). This work establishes a paradigm for industrial electrocatalysts by encoding compositional complexity, structural coherence, and interfacial adaptability through morphological design, where multifunctionality emerges from multiscale synergy rather than isolated optimization.</description>
      <author>Lin Cheng, Qi Wang, Haojie Liu, Yi Rao, Junfeng Cui, Hanwen Liu, Jinli Chen, W. Shi, Lei Zhang, Bo Song, Yonggang Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202503929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic reconstruction unlocks concurrent ultra-auxeticity and platinum-competing catalysis in MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111807</link>
      <description>Yucheng Zhu, Miao Pan, Shuaijun Yang, Jianbo Zhu, Ruidong Li, Zhong Chen, Jun Hu, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414220983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yucheng Zhu, Miao Pan, Shuaijun Yang, Jianbo Zhu, Ruidong Li, Zhong Chen, Jun Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Screening of Single-Atom Anchored All-Boron Cage (B&lt;sub&gt;28&lt;/sub&gt;) for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04669</link>
      <description>Kunyang Cheng, Xiujuan Cheng, Mingyang Shi, Xuying Zhou, Jiahao Deng, Gang Jiang, Jiguang Du, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414370642

                The electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is a crucial step in the production of hydrogen through the electrolysis of H2O. Platinum-based materials are regarded as the most effective catalysts for HER due to their low overpotential and high stability. However, the scarcity and high cost of platinum limit its application on a large scale. In this study, we employed first-principles methods to investigate the HER performance of a series of single-atom catalysts based on the B28 cluster. This cage-like B28 cluster shows instability for only five out of 40 metal atom candidates, which can be attributed to the presence of hexagonal and octagonal holes that allow for effective anchoring of single atoms. We utilized the integrated crystal orbital Hamiltonian population (ICOHP) as a vital descriptor to assess the strength of the interaction between the metal atoms and the B28 cluster, demonstrating a linear correlation with binding energy. By calculating changes in Gibbs free energy (&#916;GH*) for hydrogen absorption, we identified four species (Ge@B28, Cu@B28, Ni@B28, and Pt@B28) that exhibit superior HER catalytic activity with |&#916;GH*| around 0.2 eV. Moreover, our results indicate that these four species are more likely to produce H2 through the Tafel reaction. This study provides evidence that boron clusters have the potential to serve as single-atom supports and as catalysts for HER. These findings establish a theoretical foundation for the experimental design of novel nanocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Kunyang Cheng, Xiujuan Cheng, Mingyang Shi, Xuying Zhou, Jiahao Deng, Gang Jiang, Jiguang Du</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkali Metal Cations Induce Pseudo-outer-sphere Oxygen Reduction Reaction Mechanism in Electrolyte-Catalyst Synergy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12947</link>
      <description>Yumiao Tian, Pengfei Hou, Yuanyuan Zhou, Quan Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414168040

                Alkali metal cations (AMCs) are known to play pivotal roles in modulating electrocatalytic systems, significantly affecting the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). While their macroscopic effects are well recognized, the molecular-level interactions of AMCs at the electrochemical interface remain poorly understood. Here, using constant-potential ab initio molecular dynamics simulations, we uncover that AMCs (Li+, Na+, and K+) act as molecular switches that trigger a pseudo-outer-sphere ORR mechanism. In this mechanism, surface-adsorbed water molecules serve as dynamic bridges that simultaneously mediate interfacial electron transfer and proton transport. As a result, the reactive zone extends beyond the catalyst surface, overcoming the spatial constraints of traditional inner-sphere pathways. Crucially, H2O2 is generated directly within the outer Helmholtz plane via reduction of AMC-O2 complexes, effectively bypassing the catalyst surface and avoiding over-reduction. This results in significantly enhanced selectivity and production efficiency. Our results demonstrate that AMCs activate interfacial coupling to unlock alternative reaction pathways, while concurrently elucidating the critical yet often overlooked role of solute molecules in governing electrocatalytic behavior. This work establishes a framework for the understanding of electrolyte-catalyst coupling and provides principles for designing next-generation electrochemical systems.</description>
      <author>Yumiao Tian, Pengfei Hou, Yuanyuan Zhou, Quan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c12947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A double-U approach to more accurate metal adsorption energies on ceria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0279619</link>
      <description>Ye Xu, Nusrat Jahan Rifat, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 163(11)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414168252

                An empirical approach based on density functional theory (DFT)+U is proposed to provide adsorption energies for atoms of transition metals adsorbed on ceria that are more accurate than those found in the existing DFT literature. It involves applying an intermediate Hubbard U value to the Ce 4f states and another U value to the d states of the metal adatom that is optimized for each metal to match its calculated bulk cohesive energy with the experimental value. The results compare favorably with Campbell's calorimetric measurements of metal adsorption heats on CeO2(111). Thus, this approach produces metal adsorption energies on ceria that are more accurate in both the single-atom and the bulk limits. Furthermore, it preserves a common reference for Ce so that calculations involving different metals adsorbed on ceria, e.g., bimetallic and multimetallic clusters, can be analyzed on the same footing.</description>
      <author>Ye Xu, Nusrat Jahan Rifat</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0279619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic modulation of oxygen anion intercalated perovskite oxides for pseudocapacitance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3560-5</link>
      <description>Tingting Liang, Ruilin Hou, Wei Li, Fengjiang Chen, Shan Xu, Xingbin Yan, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414302137

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Liang, Ruilin Hou, Wei Li, Fengjiang Chen, Shan Xu, Xingbin Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-025-3560-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of CO2/N2 separation capabilities for various amine-functionalized organosilica membranes: synthesis and sorption study evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-025-06933-z</link>
      <description>Ufafa Anggarini, Devi Rahayu, Fauzul Azizah Oktaviola, Ndaru Candra Sukmana, Weiwei Yan, Hiroki Nagasawa, Toshinori Tsuru, Masakoto Kanezashi, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414166625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ufafa Anggarini, Devi Rahayu, Fauzul Azizah Oktaviola, Ndaru Candra Sukmana, Weiwei Yan, Hiroki Nagasawa, Toshinori Tsuru, Masakoto Kanezashi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-025-06933-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical multilayer perceptron for lithium batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238334</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Yang, Daniel M. Tartakovsky, Journal of Power Sources. 659(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414223961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Yang, Daniel M. Tartakovsky</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.238334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemistry of Bis(trifluoromethyl)amines: Synthesis, Properties, and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.5c00154</link>
      <description>Nikolai V. Ignat&#8217;ev, Maik Finze, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414239925

                Fluorinated groups are widely applied substituents in medicinal and agricultural chemistry as well as materials sciences because the introduction of per- and polyfluorinated substituents allow the targeted tuning of molecules and materials properties, in general. In addition to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substituents, especially trifluoromethylheteroatom substituents have attracted increasing interest in recent years. The bis(trifluoromethyl)amino group (CF3)2N is an example for a trifluoromethylheteroatom substituent. It has been known since the middle of the last century and it has been used and tested in different fields of applications. This review summarizes the chemistry of the bis(trifluoromethyl)amino group since its beginning up to the end of 2024. It focuses on the synthesis of (CF3)2N-containing compounds, precursors for the introduction of the (CF3)2N group, and follow-up reactions of (CF3)2N-containing molecules. The physicochemical properties of the (CF3)2N group and of bis(trifluoromethyl)amines are collected and potential applications that have been described are summarized, as well.</description>
      <author>Nikolai V. Ignat&#8217;ev, Maik Finze</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.5c00154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Br&#248;nsted and Lewis Acid Sites for Selective Catalytic Valorization of Isopropanol from VOC Streams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2025.09.003</link>
      <description>Honghong Zhang, Zhiwei Wang, Lu Wei, Zhiquan Hou, Yuxi Liu, Jiguang Deng, Zhenxia Zhao, Jiguang Deng, Green Energy &amp; Environment. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414302271

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Honghong Zhang, Zhiwei Wang, Lu Wei, Zhiquan Hou, Yuxi Liu, Jiguang Deng, Zhenxia Zhao, Jiguang Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gee.2025.09.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetically responsive intelligent fibers: nano-engineered materials and multifunctional integration for advanced applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5mh01383f</link>
      <description>Wenping Cheng, Jie Dong, Wei Liang, Guodong Shen, Qiushi Wang, Runjun Sun, Materials Horizons. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4414251551

                Magnetically responsive intelligent fibers represent a new class of smart materials that integrate magnetic components into flexible fiber systems, enabling remote actuation, real-time sensing, and self-powered operation under external magnetic fields. With advantages in flexibility, adaptability, and multifunctionality, they hold promise for wearable electronics, soft robotics, biomedical devices, and energy harvesting. This review highlights recent progress in their design, fabrication, and applications. We summarize magnetic materials used in fiber integration-including ferrites, metal alloys, rare-earth compounds, and 2D materials-focusing on structural and magnetic properties. Multi-physics coupling mechanisms such as magneto-mechanical, magnetoelectric, and magneto-optical effects are discussed as the basis of intelligent responses. Fabrication strategies, including extrusion-based printing, magnetic-field-assisted alignment, and surface modification, are evaluated for scalability, resolution, and material integration. Key challenges for commercialization, such as dispersion, biocompatibility, and mechanical stability under dynamic conditions, are also addressed. Finally, future directions are outlined, emphasizing multifunctional fibers with combined stimuli-responsiveness and integration into adaptive systems. This review aims to provide a framework for advancing magnetically responsive fibers and inspiring future innovations in smart fiber technologies.</description>
      <author>Wenping Cheng, Jie Dong, Wei Liang, Guodong Shen, Qiushi Wang, Runjun Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d5mh01383f</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
