<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 01:15:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic and porous structure engineering of coordination polymer-derived carbon for enhanced bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.022</link>
      <description>Zihan Meng, Fangfang Wan, Jiawei Wu, Yifei Xiong, Yuanxin Chen, Mingjuan Wu, Rui Wang, Haibo Tang, Tian Tian, Jun Ma, Haolin Tang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406506165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihan Meng, Fangfang Wan, Jiawei Wu, Yifei Xiong, Yuanxin Chen, Mingjuan Wu, Rui Wang, Haibo Tang, Tian Tian, Jun Ma, Haolin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Electronic Structure of IrO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Sub-2 nm Clusters via Tunable Metal Support Interaction for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06411</link>
      <description>Qingzhao Chu, Yanpu Niu, Haolan Tao, Honglai Liu, Quan Li, Cheng Lian, Jingkun Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406511916

                Iridium-based electrocatalysts are the most promising candidates for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Considering their high cost and scarcity, it is imperative to maximize atom utilization and enhance the intrinsic activity of iridium. In this work, IrOx sub-2 nm clusters are stabilized on TiO2 supports via metal support interaction (MSI) induced by vacancy defects in TiO2. The strength of MSI is readily tuned by the type of vacancies: oxygen vacancies in TiO2 (VO-TiO2) induce the adsorbed MSI with relatively weak strength, while titanium vacancies in TiO2 (VTi-TiO2) lead to the strong embedded MSI. The tunable MSI further modulates the electronic structure of IrOx sub-2 nm clusters. IrOx/VO-TiO2 with adsorbed MSI exhibits an optimized electronic structure with a downshifted d-band center of IrOx, resulting in a reduced binding energy with oxygen and a low energy barrier of the rate-determining step for OER. Consequently, IrOx/VO-TiO2 delivers an activity twice that of commercial IrO2 and a good stability for 120 h in a practical proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Our study provides a guideline for the rational design of acidic OER catalysts based on modulating the electronic structure of IrOx sub-2 nm clusters via tunable MSI.</description>
      <author>Qingzhao Chu, Yanpu Niu, Haolan Tao, Honglai Liu, Quan Li, Cheng Lian, Jingkun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c06411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Hydrated Electrocatalysis: To Boost the Selectivity for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Seawater Electrolysis&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00141</link>
      <description>P. Vignesh Raja, P G Vishnu, Tanmay Kumar Panigrahi, Ravi Sankannavar, Sai Phani Kumar Vangala, Ijjada Mahesh, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406514637

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. The Journal of Physical Chemistry CASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse ORIGINAL ARTICLE. This notice is a correction.Addition/CorrectionJanuary 17, 2025Correction to "Hydrated Electrocatalysis: To Boost the Selectivity for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Seawater Electrolysis"Click to copy article linkArticle link copied!P. Vignesh RajaP. Vignesh RajaMore by P. Vignesh RajaPadinjarethil VishnuPadinjarethil VishnuMore by Padinjarethil VishnuTanmay Kumar PanigrahiTanmay Kumar PanigrahiMore by Tanmay Kumar PanigrahiRavi SankannavarRavi SankannavarMore by Ravi Sankannavarhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-1590-5609Sai Phani VangalaSai Phani VangalaMore by Sai Phani VangalaIjjada Mahesh*Ijjada MaheshMore by Ijjada Maheshhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-4274-9138Open PDFThe Journal of Physical Chemistry CCite this: J. Phys. Chem. C 2025, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00141https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00141Published January 17, 2025 Publication History Received 8 January 2025Published online 17 January 2025correction&#169; 2025 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2025 American Chemical SocietyAn error has been identified in the y-axis label of Figures 3(b) and 3(d). The y-axis label in Figures 3(b) and 3(d) should be ln(iOER(&#956;A)) and ln(iCER(&#956;A)), respectively. The modified Figure 3 is provided below. The reported Tafel lines and the corresponding charge transfer coefficient (1-&#945;) values for OER and CER in the published manuscript, Hydrated Electrocatalysis: To Boost the Selectivity for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Seawater Electrolysis (DOI: 10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06083), are accurate and unaffected.Figure 3Figure 3. OER's (a) current vs potential profiles, (b) corresponding Tafel plots, and CER's (c) current vs potential profiles, (d) corresponding Tafel plots of the three PBAs. RRDE voltammetry was performed in Ar-saturated 0.5 M NaCl + 50 mM H2SO4 electrolyte at a scan rate of 10 mV/s with 1000 rpm of electrode rotation rate.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideAuthor InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorIjjada Mahesh; https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4274-9138AuthorsP. Vignesh RajaPadinjarethil VishnuTanmay Kumar PanigrahiRavi Sankannavar; https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1590-5609Sai Phani VangalaCited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferences Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsThe Journal of Physical Chemistry CCite this: J. Phys. Chem. C 2025, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00141Published January 17, 2025 Publication History Received 8 January 2025Published online 17 January 2025&#169; 2025 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesFigure 3Figure 3. OER's (a) current vs potential profiles, (b) corresponding Tafel plots, and CER's (c) current vs potential profiles, (d) corresponding Tafel plots of the three PBAs. RRDE voltammetry was performed in Ar-saturated 0.5 M NaCl + 50 mM H2SO4 electrolyte at a scan rate of 10 mV/s with 1000 rpm of electrode rotation rate.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThis publication has no References.</description>
      <author>P. Vignesh Raja, P G Vishnu, Tanmay Kumar Panigrahi, Ravi Sankannavar, Sai Phani Kumar Vangala, Ijjada Mahesh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c00141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Undoped ruthenium oxide as a stable catalyst for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56188-z</link>
      <description>Jiayi Tang, Daqin Guan, Hengyue Xu, Leqi Zhao, Ushtar Arshad, Zhongxiang Fang, Tianjiu Zhu, Manjin Kim, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Zhiwei Hu, Junjie Ge, Zongping Shao, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406515746

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayi Tang, Daqin Guan, Hengyue Xu, Leqi Zhao, Ushtar Arshad, Zhongxiang Fang, Tianjiu Zhu, Manjin Kim, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Zhiwei Hu, Junjie Ge, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56188-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of &#946;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Ir/Ru Co-substitution for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</link>
      <description>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406534076

                The efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic media is severely limited by the poor stability, low activity, and high cost of available catalysts. Enhancing intrinsic activity while maintaining stability and reducing reliance on precious metals is crucial. The typical adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) leads to high overpotentials and low activity, making the transition to alternative mechanisms, such as the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) or oxide path mechanism (OPM), highly desirable due to their lower overpotentials. Here, we combine density functional theory (DFT) calculations with experimental validation to enhance the activity and stability of &#946;-MnO2 via co-substitution with ruthenium (Ru) and iridium (Ir), enabling the transition from AEM to OPM. DFT calculations reveal that AEM is hindered by the weak nucleophilicity of water, while LOM suffers from high kinetic barriers due to structural distortions. In contrast, OPM demonstrates a significantly lower kinetic barrier, facilitated by the synergistic interaction between Ru and Ir. Experimentally, IrRuMnOx was synthesized through co-precipitation and hydrothermal methods, showing an 80-fold improvement in mass activity and a 96-fold increase in stability compared to commercial IrO2, with minimal noble metal leaching, as confirmed by inductively coupled plasma optical emission spectroscopy (ICP-OES). IrRuMnOx exhibited an ultralow overpotential of 475 mV at 1 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 44.26 mV&#183;dec&#8211;1 in 0.5 M H2SO4, maintaining stable performance for over 100 h. Moreover, the IrRuMnOx-based membrane electrode, with a low Ir loading of 0.075 mgIr&#183;cm&#8211;2, achieved remarkable current densities of 1.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.66 V and 2.0 A&#183;cm&#8211;2 at 1.91 V at 80 &#176;C. This performance surpasses that of both unsupported and conventional supported Ir-based catalysts at comparable Ir loading levels. This study offers critical insights into OER mechanisms in acidic media and paves the way for developing efficient and durable OER electrocatalysts for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Runxu Deng, Feng Liu, Shixin Gao, Zhenwei Xia, Runjie Wu, Jincheng Kong, Jin Yang, Ju Wen, X. Peter Zhang, Chade Lv, Yuhao Wang, Xiaoguang Li, Zheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase&#8208;Engineered Bi&#8208;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Single&#8208;Atom Alloy Oxide Boosting Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417777</link>
      <description>Zhichao Yang, Yutian Ding, Wen Chen, Shuiping Luo, Daofan Cao, Xin Long, Lei Xie, Xincheng Zhou, Xinyi Cai, Ke Liu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406543620

                Abstract Engineering nanomaterials at single&#8208;atomic sites can enable unprecedented catalytic properties for broad applications, yet it remains challenging to do so on RuO 2 &#8208;based electrocatalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE). Herein, the rational design and construction of Bi&#8208;RuO 2 single&#8208;atom alloy oxide (SAAO) are presented to boost acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), via phase engineering a novel hexagonal close packed ( hcp ) RuBi single&#8208;atom alloy. This Bi&#8208;RuO 2 SAAO electrocatalyst exhibits a low overpotential of 192 mV and superb stability over 650 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , enabling a practical PEMWE that needs only 1.59 V to reach 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 under industrial conditions. Operando differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy analysis, coupled with density functional theory studies, confirmed the adsorbate&#8208;evolving mechanism on Bi&#8208;RuO 2 SAAO and that the incorporation of Bi 1 improves the activity by electronic density optimization and the stability by hindering surface Ru demetallation. This work not only introduces a new strategy to fabricate high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts at atomic&#8208;level, but also demonstrates their potential use in industrial electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Zhichao Yang, Yutian Ding, Wen Chen, Shuiping Luo, Daofan Cao, Xin Long, Lei Xie, Xincheng Zhou, Xinyi Cai, Ke Liu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeOOH-NiV LDH Heterostructure as Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04894-6</link>
      <description>Shuming Liu, Sol-Ji Song, Yi Feng, Catalysis Letters. 155(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406549739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuming Liu, Sol-Ji Song, Yi Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04894-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFeP@CoCr-LDH: A novel bifunctional catalyst for high-performance hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105941</link>
      <description>Rahadian Zainul, Ali B.M. Ali, Prakash Kanjariya, Pawan Sharma, Rahul Thakur, Iskandar Shernazarov, Mohammed Al&#8208;Bahrani, A. Hussein, Abdulrahman A. Almehizia, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 169(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406557218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahadian Zainul, Ali B.M. Ali, Prakash Kanjariya, Pawan Sharma, Rahul Thakur, Iskandar Shernazarov, Mohammed Al&#8208;Bahrani, A. Hussein, Abdulrahman A. Almehizia</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of hollow cubic MnCoFe PBA-P for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102530</link>
      <description>Tao Pan, Songtao Zhang, Ying Wei, Guangxun Zhang, Meng Du, Hao Gong, Mingbo Zheng, Huan Pang, Materials Today Chemistry. 44(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406563215

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Pan, Songtao Zhang, Ying Wei, Guangxun Zhang, Meng Du, Hao Gong, Mingbo Zheng, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction through improved lattice oxygen activity via carbon dots incorporation into MOFs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.133</link>
      <description>Zi Kang Tang, Delun Chen, Weiwei Li, Hai Li, Jinchun Tu, Xiaolin Zhang, Bingrong Wang, Rentong Yu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zi Kang Tang, Delun Chen, Weiwei Li, Hai Li, Jinchun Tu, Xiaolin Zhang, Bingrong Wang, Rentong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ growth of Ni2.86Te2 and Mo6Te8 telluride catalysts on foam NiMo substrates for enhanced oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</link>
      <description>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406570335

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational construction and design of bimetallic Co-Ni species by pulsed laser irradiation for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118011</link>
      <description>Wenzhe Cao, Xiaohui Ren, Ying Wen, Tian Zhang, W.Y. Chu, Zhaoyang Liu, Haoran Zou, Qianying Guo, Rongsheng Chen, Feng Ma, Hongwei Ni, Materials Science and Engineering B. 314(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406583868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenzhe Cao, Xiaohui Ren, Ying Wen, Tian Zhang, W.Y. Chu, Zhaoyang Liu, Haoran Zou, Qianying Guo, Rongsheng Chen, Feng Ma, Hongwei Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridinic-N-enriched mesoporous carbon coated carbon cloth for efficient oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162444</link>
      <description>Y.S. Li, Chi Li, Qing Zhou, Yongfu Lian, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406586469

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y.S. Li, Chi Li, Qing Zhou, Yongfu Lian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Steel mesh coated Cobalt Tungstate Microflowers as Efficient Binder-Free Electrode Materials for Supercapacitors and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112579</link>
      <description>Neha C. Patil, Umesh V. Shembade, Mayuri G. Magadum, Jaywant V. Mane, Dnyandevo N. Zambare, Tanaji R. Bhosale, A.V. Moholkar, Sandeep B. Wategaonkar, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406590900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Neha C. Patil, Umesh V. Shembade, Mayuri G. Magadum, Jaywant V. Mane, Dnyandevo N. Zambare, Tanaji R. Bhosale, A.V. Moholkar, Sandeep B. Wategaonkar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial amine-assisted electrodeposition of superhydrophilic/superaerophobic metal hydroxides for robust oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2483-8</link>
      <description>Qing Chen, Keyu Wang, Shiyi Li, Yixing Wang, Linfeng Lei, Minghui Zhu, Linzhou Zhuang, Zhi Xu, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406591464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Chen, Keyu Wang, Shiyi Li, Yixing Wang, Linfeng Lei, Minghui Zhu, Linzhou Zhuang, Zhi Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2483-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium&#8208;Doped NiBP Micro&#8208;Sphere Electrocatalysts for Green Hydrogen Production under Industrial Operational Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401939</link>
      <description>Md Ahasan Habib, Shusen Lin, Sumiya Akter Dristy, Mehedi Hasan Joni, Rutuja Mandavkar, Jae&#8208;Hun Jeong, Jihoon Lee, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406593946

                Abstract Wide spread adaptation of green hydrogen can help to mitigate the serious climate issues, increasing global energy demands and the development of advanced electrocatalysts robust under industrial conditions is one of the key technological challenges. Herein, chromium&#8208;doped nickel&#8208;boride&#8208;phosphide (Cr/NiBP) micro sphere (MS) electrocatalyst is demonstrated via a two&#8208;step hydrothermal approach along with post&#8208;annealing. The Cr/NiBP MS demonstrates low hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evaluation reaction over potentials of 78 and 250 mV at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH, out performing most of the reported catalysts. The Cr/NiBP &#449; Cr/NiBP exhibits only 1.54 V at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH and surpasses the benchmark of RuO 2 (+) &#449; Pt/C (&#8722;) up to 2000 mA cm &#8722;2 , which sets it as one of the best bifunctional electrocatalysts. Impressively, it maintains stable performance for over 240 h at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in 6 m KOH at 60&#176;C, demonstrating rapid response, anti&#8208;corrosion resistance, and robust structural integrity to meet the industrial operational conditions. Further, Cr/NiBP &#449; Pt/C exhibits a super&#8208;low cell&#8208;voltage of 2.25 V at 2000 mA cm &#8722;2 . The small amount of Cr atoms incorporation can significantly enhance active sites and intrinsic properties, accelerating water dissociation and rapid intermediate formation.</description>
      <author>Md Ahasan Habib, Shusen Lin, Sumiya Akter Dristy, Mehedi Hasan Joni, Rutuja Mandavkar, Jae&#8208;Hun Jeong, Jihoon Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401939</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridinic&#8208;N Seized Co in Biphasic Nanoarchitecture for Reversible Oxygen Electrocatalysis Enabling Longevous (&amp;gt;1200 h) Aqueous and Dual&#8208;Anion Kosmotropic Electrolyte Stabilized High Power Quasisolid&#8208;State Zn&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401874</link>
      <description>Srijib Das, Saikat Bolar, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, A. J. Pathak, Ranjit Thapa, Ujjwal Phadikar, Haradhan Kolya, Chun&#8211;Won Kang, Tapas Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Aniruddha Kundu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406593979

                Abstract Integration of different active sites by heterostructure engineering is pivotal to optimize the intrinsic activities of an oxygen electrocatalyst and much needed to enhance the performance of rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, a biphasic nanoarchitecture encased in in situ grown N&#8208;doped graphitic carbon (MnO/Co&#8208;NGC) with heterointerfacial sites are constructed. The density functional theory model reveals formation of lattice oxygen bridged heterostructure with pyridinic nitrogen atoms anchored Co species, which facilitate adsorption of oxygen intermediates. Consequently, the well&#8208;designed catalyst with accessible active sites, abundant oxygen vacant sites, and heterointerfacial coupling effects, simultaneously accelerate the electron/mass transfer and thus promotes the trifunctional electrocatalysis. The assembled aqueous ZAB delivers maximum power density of &#8776;268 mW cm &#8722;2 and a specific capacity of 797.8 mAh g zn &#8722;1 along with excellent rechargeability and extremely small voltage gap decay rate of 0.0007 V h &#8722;1 . Further, the fabricated quasisolid&#8208;state ZAB owns a remarkable power density of 163 mW cm &#8722;2 and long cycle life, outperforming the benchmark air&#8208;electrode and many recent reports, underlining its robustness and suitability for practical utilization in diverse portable applications.</description>
      <author>Srijib Das, Saikat Bolar, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, A. J. Pathak, Ranjit Thapa, Ujjwal Phadikar, Haradhan Kolya, Chun&#8211;Won Kang, Tapas Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Aniruddha Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Carbon nanotube directed synthesis of blue TiO2 with oxygen vacancy for sonocatalytic H2 production&#8221; [Renew. Energy, (241), March 2025, 122379]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122446</link>
      <description>Huaqiang Zhuang, Xiangge Wang, Miaoling Huang, Xiao&#8208;Bing Lian, Xiaobin Liu, Xiaoyang Pan, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406596751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaqiang Zhuang, Xiangge Wang, Miaoling Huang, Xiao&#8208;Bing Lian, Xiaobin Liu, Xiaoyang Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating design of tunable CuCo2O4@NiMnO3 heterostructure towards superior oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06645-w</link>
      <description>Adel El&#8208;marghany, Muhammad Khalil, Abdul Wahab Haroon, Fawad Ahmad, Ome Parkash Kumar, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem, Zobia Siddique, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406598016

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adel El&#8208;marghany, Muhammad Khalil, Abdul Wahab Haroon, Fawad Ahmad, Ome Parkash Kumar, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem, Zobia Siddique</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06645-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cucurbit[&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;]uril-Derived Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution, Oxygen Reduction, and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17510</link>
      <description>Nan Jiang, Yirong Cao, Hang Cong, Qingmei Ge, Wenfeng Zhao, Bo You, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406605909

                Various sustainable energy conversion techniques like water electrolyzers, fuel cells, and metal-air battery devices are promising to alleviate the issues in fossil fuel consumption. However, their broad employment has been mainly inhibited by the lack of advanced electrocatalysts to accelerate the sluggish kinetics of the three involved half-reactions including oxygen evolution reaction (OER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Recent advances have witnessed the cucurbit[n]uril (CB[n])-directed strategy as a prominent tool to develop high performance electrocatalysts with either OER, ORR, or HER activities. In this review, the recent progress on CB[n]-derived electrocatalysts ranging from molecular complexes to heterogeneous nanostructures and single-atoms for the three half-reactions are reviewed, and future opportunities are discussed. A concise introduction to the fundamentals of CB[n]s regarding their synthesis, structure, and chemistry is given first. Subsequently, the systematic summary of CB[n]-derived electrocatalysts and their performance for the OER/ORR/HER are discussed in detail, with a specific emphasis on correlating their structure and activities by combining diverse physiochemical characterizations, electrochemical experiments, and theory simulations. Finally, a brief conclusion and perspective for future opportunities regarding CB[n]-derived electrocatalysts for many other electrocatalytic applications are proposed.</description>
      <author>Nan Jiang, Yirong Cao, Hang Cong, Qingmei Ge, Wenfeng Zhao, Bo You</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homologous metal-organic complexes reconstructed oxy-hydroxide heterostructures as efficient oxygen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.181</link>
      <description>Yuting Chen, Haikuo Lan, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Kang Liu, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406606851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuting Chen, Haikuo Lan, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Kang Liu, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General design of self-supported Co-Ni/nitrogen-doped carbon nanotubes array for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.159</link>
      <description>Mengfei Mou, Yameng Wang, Wenjie Yu, Huimin Jiang, Shuo Zhang, Yanchao Zhao, Jingyun Ma, Liting Yan, Xiang-Jun Kong, Xuebo Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406606893

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengfei Mou, Yameng Wang, Wenjie Yu, Huimin Jiang, Shuo Zhang, Yanchao Zhao, Jingyun Ma, Liting Yan, Xiang-Jun Kong, Xuebo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of NiFe alloy foams at high oxygen evolution reaction rates using a dry anode setup in alkaline environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236245</link>
      <description>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406609398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Coated CeO2-CoFe Core-Shell electrocatalysts derived from Prussian blue analogues for high-performance oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131699</link>
      <description>Huu Thang Nguyen, Kimin Chae, Deng&#8208;Guang Yu, Nguyen Anh Thu Tran, Tran Minh Khoi, Jin Goo Kim, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Younghyun Cho, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615373

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huu Thang Nguyen, Kimin Chae, Deng&#8208;Guang Yu, Nguyen Anh Thu Tran, Tran Minh Khoi, Jin Goo Kim, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Younghyun Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131699</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formamide-Assisted Synthesis of Phosphate-Intercalated Ni(Oh)2/Niooh Electrode for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5104122</link>
      <description>Yuexiang Li, Qiang Li, Shaoqin Peng, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615628

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuexiang Li, Qiang Li, Shaoqin Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5104122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational synthesis of MOF-Derived Cobalt-Based binary selenides nanocrystals for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162479</link>
      <description>Faozia Nasser Al-Shaibah, Muhammad Arif Ibrahim, Aymen S. Abu Hatab, Ahmed Abotaleb, Alessandro Sinopoli, Atef Zekri, Yahia H. Ahmad, Siham Y. Al-Qaradawi, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406616868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faozia Nasser Al-Shaibah, Muhammad Arif Ibrahim, Aymen S. Abu Hatab, Ahmed Abotaleb, Alessandro Sinopoli, Atef Zekri, Yahia H. Ahmad, Siham Y. Al-Qaradawi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the local S coordination environment on Ru single atoms to boost the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04706k</link>
      <description>Yiling Ran, Rong Z. Gan, Qin Zhao, Quanlei Ma, Yijing Liao, Yinwei Li, Yi Wang, Yanwei Wang, Yan Zhang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406617530

                A single atom Ru-NiS 2 catalyst with a controlled S-coordination environment for OER was prepared by a simple atom capture strategy. Fine-tuned local S coordination environment can optimize the electronic structure of Ru active sites.</description>
      <author>Yiling Ran, Rong Z. Gan, Qin Zhao, Quanlei Ma, Yijing Liao, Yinwei Li, Yi Wang, Yanwei Wang, Yan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04706k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;Layered Double Hydroxide Heterostructures as Efficient Alkaline Water Splitting (Photo)Electro&#8208;catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409097</link>
      <description>Kayvan Moradi, Maysam Ashrafi, Abdollah Salimi, Marko Melander, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406617906

                Abstract Designing cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts with fast reaction kinetics and high stability is an outstanding challenge in green hydrogen generation through overall water splitting (OWS). Layered double hydroxide (LDH) heterostructure materials are promising candidates to catalyze both oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the two OWS half&#8208;cell reactions. This work develops a facile hydrothermal route to synthesiz hierarchical heterostructure MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;LDH and MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH electrocatalysts, which exhibit extremely good OER and HER performance as witnessed by their low IR&#8208;corrected overpotentials of 156 and 61 mV with at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 under light assistance. The MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH&#8208;MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;LDH OWS cell achieves a low cell voltage of 1.46V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 during light&#8208;assisted water electrolysis. Both materials exhibited exceptional stability under industrially relevant HER and OER conditions, maintaining a current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 with minimal alterations in their potential and performance. The experimental and computational results demonstrate that doping the LDH matrix with high&#8208;valence Mo atoms and MoS 2 quantum dots improves the electrocatalytic activity by 1) enhancing electron transfer, 2) making the electrocatalyst metallic, 3) increasing the number of active sites, 4) lowering the thermodynamic overpotential, and 5) changing the OER mechanism. Overall, this work develops a facile synthesis method to design highly active and stable MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH heterostructure electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Kayvan Moradi, Maysam Ashrafi, Abdollah Salimi, Marko Melander</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-tunable cobalt borides with amorphous shell toward highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236255</link>
      <description>Yuxin Gao, Xiaowei Yang, Yuyang Zong, Lihong Bao, Ruguang Ma, Jijun Zhao, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406618795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Gao, Xiaowei Yang, Yuyang Zong, Lihong Bao, Ruguang Ma, Jijun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrostatic and Electronic Effects on Doped Nickel Oxide Nanofilms for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14493</link>
      <description>Ina &#216;str&#248;m, Marco Favaro, Moein Seyfouri, Patrick A. Burr, Bram Hoex, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406632531

                An ideal water-splitting electrocatalyst is inexpensive, abundant, highly active, stable, selective, and durable. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the main bottleneck for H2 production with a complex and not fully resolved mechanism, slow kinetics, and high overpotential. Nickel oxide-based catalysts (NiOx) are highly active and cheaper than precious metal catalysts. However, rigorous catalyst tests and DFT calculations are still needed to rationally optimize NiOx catalysts. In this work, we combine plasma-enhanced atomic layer deposition (PE-ALD) and density functional theory (DFT) to address the role of dopants in promoting NiOx OER activity. Ultrathin films of NiOx doped with Zn2+, Al3+, and Sn4+ presented improved intrinsic activity, stability, and durability for the OER. The results show a low to high catalytic performance of ZnNiOx &lt; NiOx &lt; AlNiOx &lt; SnNiOx, which we attribute to an increase in the concentration of valence band (VB) holes combined with conduction band (CB) electron conductivity, characterized by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The influence of doping on the electronic structure and catalytic activity was investigated using advanced characterization techniques and density functional theory (DFT) calculations (PEB0/pob-TZVP). DFT complements the experimental results, showing that the dopant charge states and orbital hybridization enhance the OER by improving the charge carrier concentration and mobility, thus allowing optimal binding energies and charge dynamics and delocalization. Our findings demonstrate the potential of PE-ALD-doped nanofilms NiOx and DFT to rationally design and develop catalysts for sustainable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Ina &#216;str&#248;m, Marco Favaro, Moein Seyfouri, Patrick A. Burr, Bram Hoex</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver-decorated titanium dioxide micro-tablets as a photocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00990-w</link>
      <description>Liszulfah Roza, Gerald Ensang Timuda, Elvy Rahmi Mawarnis, Rany Miranti, Abdul Wafi, Toto Sudiro, Nono Darsono, Sudiyarmanto, Mahfujur Rahman, Emergent Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406637806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liszulfah Roza, Gerald Ensang Timuda, Elvy Rahmi Mawarnis, Rany Miranti, Abdul Wafi, Toto Sudiro, Nono Darsono, Sudiyarmanto, Mahfujur Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00990-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Investigation of Sr Segregation Effects on the High-temperature Oxygen Evolution Reaction Rate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee05056h</link>
      <description>Weicheng Feng, Geng Zou, Tianfu Liu, Rongtan Li, Jingcheng Yu, Yige Guo, Qingxue Liu, Xiaomin Zhang, Junhu Wang, Na Ta, Mingrun Li, Peng Zhang, Xingzhong Cao, Runsheng Yu, Yuefeng Song, M. Liu, Guoxiong Wang, Xinhe Bao, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406641499

                While the effects of Sr segregation on the performance and stability of perovskite electrodes in solid oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs) have been widely studied, most attention has been focused on...</description>
      <author>Weicheng Feng, Geng Zou, Tianfu Liu, Rongtan Li, Jingcheng Yu, Yige Guo, Qingxue Liu, Xiaomin Zhang, Junhu Wang, Na Ta, Mingrun Li, Peng Zhang, Xingzhong Cao, Runsheng Yu, Yuefeng Song, M. Liu, Guoxiong Wang, Xinhe Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee05056h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced oxygen evolution catalysis: SnS&#8322; and MoS&#8322; decorated titania nanostructures in alkaline electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.204</link>
      <description>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Youngae Lee, Sadanand Pandey, Younghwan Im, Mohammad Altaf, Misook Kang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 105(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406641511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Youngae Lee, Sadanand Pandey, Younghwan Im, Mohammad Altaf, Misook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Significantly Improved Electrocatalytic Activity of Pr1.1ba0.9co2o5+ &#916; Induced by Ba-Site Sr Doping Toward Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5106619</link>
      <description>Enhui Hou, Xiang Li, Jingping Wang, Tian Xia, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406641514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enhui Hou, Xiang Li, Jingping Wang, Tian Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5106619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA Origami-Assembled Gold Nanobipyramid Dimer Electrocatalyst for Ultrahigh Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05951</link>
      <description>Charanleen Kaur, Imtiaz Ahmed, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Tapasi Sen, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406645211

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Charanleen Kaur, Imtiaz Ahmed, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Tapasi Sen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05951</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a hybrid electrocatalyst by impregnating the CuS/CdFe2O4 composite heterostructure into the carbon nanofiber network for improved electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.126988</link>
      <description>N. Ch. Ramgopal, Nipa Roy, Gedi Sreedevi, Salh Alhammadi, Razan A. Alshgari, Mohammed Sheikh Saleh Mushab, K. Prasad, Sai Kumar Arla, Sang Woo Joo, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406661431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. Ch. Ramgopal, Nipa Roy, Gedi Sreedevi, Salh Alhammadi, Razan A. Alshgari, Mohammed Sheikh Saleh Mushab, K. Prasad, Sai Kumar Arla, Sang Woo Joo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.126988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous carbon nanosheets integrated with graphene-wrapped CoO and CoNx as efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.170</link>
      <description>Chang Ma, Binji Zhu, Yue Wang, Shuwen Ma, Jingli Shi, Xiangwu Zhang, Yan Song, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406661536

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang Ma, Binji Zhu, Yue Wang, Shuwen Ma, Jingli Shi, Xiangwu Zhang, Yan Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3d Core-Shell Structured Nico2o4 Nanoneedle Array Encased in N-Doped Carbon for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Electrocatalytic Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5106177</link>
      <description>Na Li, Jiawei Yang, Runduo Zhang, Yaxuan Wei, Kun Yang, Xiaoqiang Du, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406661622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Li, Jiawei Yang, Runduo Zhang, Yaxuan Wei, Kun Yang, Xiaoqiang Du</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5106177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin Magnetic Effect Activate Dual Site Intramolecular O&#9472;O Bridging for Nickel&#8208;Iron Hydroxide Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202415525</link>
      <description>Haohai Dong, Lanke Luo, Shaobing Zhou, Lin Chen, Xinyu Wu, Yitao Yang, Zhensheng Liao, Fu Liao, Ming Chen, Yuxin Zhu, Peiyuan Su, Haomin Jiang, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin, Qingsong Hua, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406664421

                Abstract The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) involves the recombination of diamagnetic hydroxyl (OH) or water (H 2 O) into the paramagnetic triplet state of oxygen (O 2 ). The spin conservation of oxygen intermediates plays a crucial role in OER, however, research on spin dynamics during the catalytic process remains in its early stages. Herein, &#946; &#8208;Ni(OH) 2 and Fe&#8208;doped &#946; &#8208;Ni(OH) 2 (Ni 5 Fe 1 (OH) 2 ) are utilized as model catalysts to understand the mechanism of spin magnetic effects at iron (III) sites during OER. Combined with magnetic characterization, it is founded that the introduction of Fe transforms the antiferromagnetic Ni(OH) 2 into a ferromagnetic material. Testing the magnetic response of the catalyst under an external magnetic field, the OER activity of Ni 5 Fe 1 (OH) 2 is significantly enhanced in comparison to Ni(OH) 2 . This improvement is likely due to the introduction of iron sites, which promote spin magnetic effects and enhance reaction kinetics, thereby increasing catalytic efficiency. Combining experimental and theoretical characterization, it is discovered that the iron sites accelerate the formation of heterogeneous dual&#8208;site O&#9472;O bridging, represented as &#9472;Ni&#9472;O&#9472;O&#9472;Fe&#9472;, thereby effectively enhancing the kinetics of the OER reaction. This study provides a magnetic perspective on the structure&#8208;function relationship of magnetic iron&#8208;based catalysts and has significant implications for the design of new catalysts.</description>
      <author>Haohai Dong, Lanke Luo, Shaobing Zhou, Lin Chen, Xinyu Wu, Yitao Yang, Zhensheng Liao, Fu Liao, Ming Chen, Yuxin Zhu, Peiyuan Su, Haomin Jiang, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin, Qingsong Hua</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202415525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Morphing of Hydroxyl Groups on Covalency Competing Spinel Oxides Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07014</link>
      <description>Jiali Gou, Xin Lei, Bifa Ji, Shanshan Zhang, Yongping Zheng, Yongbing Tang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406668219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Gou, Xin Lei, Bifa Ji, Shanshan Zhang, Yongping Zheng, Yongbing Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe, Co, N-doped composite as an efficient catalyst for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102531</link>
      <description>Junyuan Zhang, Jingjing Chen, Jing Yi, Xiaolong Xu, Changyu Liu, Jianbo Jia, Materials Today Chemistry. 44(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406669422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junyuan Zhang, Jingjing Chen, Jing Yi, Xiaolong Xu, Changyu Liu, Jianbo Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of IrCu/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; hybrid nanostructures and their enhanced catalytic properties toward oxygen evolution reaction under both acidic and alkaline conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt03079f</link>
      <description>Xiaomei Xu, Taekyung Yu, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406669837

                IrCu/Co 3 O 4 hybrid nanostructures were prepared under mild conditions using NaBH 4 through an anti-solvent crystallization method.</description>
      <author>Xiaomei Xu, Taekyung Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt03079f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Molybdenum-Doped Cobalt-Iron Layered Double Hydroxide Hollow Nanorods Via a &#8216;One-Stone-Two-Birds&#8217; Strategy for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5105624</link>
      <description>Lingyu Kong, Ningzhao Shang, Tingyu Zhang, Ming Su, Yufan Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406677032

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingyu Kong, Ningzhao Shang, Tingyu Zhang, Ming Su, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5105624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Induced Crystal-Amorphous Interface in Nife Ldh Catalyst for Enhanced Oer Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5105606</link>
      <description>Yiwang Chen, Jun Guo, Buming Chen, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406677034

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiwang Chen, Jun Guo, Buming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5105606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron phosphide microwires based on-chip electrocatalytic oxygen evolution microdevice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2025.111859</link>
      <description>Hongwei Su, Qingguo Chi, Hongtao Li, Alei Li, Yunlei Zhong, Xu Zhang, Lin Geng, Shuai Liu, Liuqi Dong, Xiaohang Pan, Lin Wang, Lixing Kang, iScience. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406681688

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongwei Su, Qingguo Chi, Hongtao Li, Alei Li, Yunlei Zhong, Xu Zhang, Lin Geng, Shuai Liu, Liuqi Dong, Xiaohang Pan, Lin Wang, Lixing Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2025.111859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guided Heterostructure Growth of CoFe LDH on Ti&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; MXene for Durably High Oxygen Evolution Activity (Small 3/2025)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202570016</link>
      <description>Jiali Sheng, Jiahui Kang, Pan Jiang, Kristoffer Meinander, Xiaodan Hong, Hua Jiang, Nonappa Nonappa, Olli Ikkala, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Bo Peng, Zhong&#8208;Peng Lv, Small. 21(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406693393

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Sheng, Jiahui Kang, Pan Jiang, Kristoffer Meinander, Xiaodan Hong, Hua Jiang, Nonappa Nonappa, Olli Ikkala, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Bo Peng, Zhong&#8208;Peng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202570016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isomerization of Covalent Organic Frameworks for Efficiently Activating Molecular Oxygen and Promoting Hydrogen Peroxide Photosynthesis (Small 3/2025)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202570017</link>
      <description>Wenjiao Wang, Rui Zhang, Hongqi Chu, Zhen Zhan, Qi Huang, Zhenzi Li, Xuepeng Wang, Fu&#8208;Quan Bai, Wei Zhou, Small. 21(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406693408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjiao Wang, Rui Zhang, Hongqi Chu, Zhen Zhan, Qi Huang, Zhenzi Li, Xuepeng Wang, Fu&#8208;Quan Bai, Wei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202570017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d</link>
      <description>Li Liao, Rui Wang, Zerong Zhang, Jianfeng Zhang, Shibin Huang, Wenhao Xie, Y. Wang, Ming Xue, Qianrong Fang, Shilun Qiu, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406695542

                The development of covalent organic frameworks (COFs) as bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), coupled with precise control over their active sites, is...</description>
      <author>Li Liao, Rui Wang, Zerong Zhang, Jianfeng Zhang, Shibin Huang, Wenhao Xie, Y. Wang, Ming Xue, Qianrong Fang, Shilun Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confining Surface Oxygen Redox in Double Perovskites for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404560</link>
      <description>Natasha Hales, Jinzhen Huang, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Ivano E. Castelli, Radim Skoup&#253;, Adam H. Clark, Micha&#322; Andrzejewski, Nicola Casati, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706492

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;based double perovskites AA&#8242;BB&#8242;O 6 are an underexplored class of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, in which B&#8208;site substitution is used to tune electronic and structural properties. BaSrNiWO 6 , with a B&#8208;site comprised of alternating Ni and W, exhibits high oxygen evolution activity, attributed to the evolution of a highly OER active surface phase. The redox transformation of Ni 2+ (3d 8 ) to Ni 3+ (3d 7 ) combined with partial W dissolution into the electrolyte from the linear Ni(3d)&#8208;O(2p)&#8208;W(5d) chains drives an in situ reconstruction of the surface to an amorphized, NiO&#8208;like layer, promoting oxygen redox in the OER mechanism. However, the high valence W 6+ (5d 0 ) acts as a stabilizing electronic influence in the bulk, preventing the mobilization of lattice oxygen which is bound in highly covalent W&#9472;O bonds. It is proposed that the surface generated during the OER can support a lattice oxygen evolution mechanism (LOEM) in which oxygen vacancies are created and preferentially refilled by electrolytic OH &#8722; , while bulk O species remain stable. This surface LOEM (sLOEM) allows BaSrNiWO 6 to retain structural integrity during OER catalysis. With a Tafel slope of 45 mV dec &#8722;1 in 0.1 m KOH, BaSrNiWO 6 illustrates the potential of Ni&#8208;based double perovskites to offer both OER efficiency and bulk stability in alkaline electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Natasha Hales, Jinzhen Huang, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Ivano E. Castelli, Radim Skoup&#253;, Adam H. Clark, Micha&#322; Andrzejewski, Nicola Casati, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Side Reaction Turned Positive: Synchronous OER Manipulating the Electrocatalytic Properties of Anodic Electrodeposited Lead Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410556</link>
      <description>Hua Guo, Xinyuan Li, Mingtao Li, Yang Liu, Wei Yan, Hao Xu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706719

                Abstract The preparation and modification of porous electrodes are an important component of the new generation electrochemical oxidation technology. Rapid preparation of porous electrodes can be easily achieved by synchronous oxygen bubble electrodeposition. However, according to the reaction mechanism of lead dioxide anodic electrodeposition, there is bound to be a competitive reaction of adsorbed hydroxyl radicals in the oxygen bubble template method, which means that synchronous OER impacts both the surface morphology and potentially the crystalline structure of the metal oxides. Clarifying the comprehensive influence of synchronous OER on the morphology and microstructure of the coating is important. In this work, the electrodeposition process of porous lead dioxide coating is regulated by the way of linear potential increase and realized the rapid preparation of high&#8208;performance porous lead dioxide coating within 40 s. The morphology and microstructure, electrical, and electrochemical properties are characterized, combined with theoretical calculation and orthogonal analysis, to investigate the regulatory mechanism of the rapid growth of the porous lead dioxide by the electric potential. It is demonstrated that synchronous OER confers porous morphology and a large number of defects to the coating in situ, and enhancing the electrocatalytic oxidation performance of the electrode.</description>
      <author>Hua Guo, Xinyuan Li, Mingtao Li, Yang Liu, Wei Yan, Hao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Distortions Promoting the In-Depth Reconstruction of Ni-Based Electrocatalysts with Enriched Oxygen Vacancies for the Electrochemical Oxidation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural toward 2,5-Furandicarboxylic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03764</link>
      <description>Y KOU, Fanan Wang, Yun Lin, Di Liu, Qian Wang, Yan Zhang, Wenting Wen, Junhong Huang, Rengui Weng, Gang Xu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406708098

                The electrocatalytic 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation reaction (HMFOR) toward 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) has been considered a promising approach for the substitution of the energy-consuming and hazardous oxygen evolution reaction and for the valorization of renewable biomass. However, it is limited by the susceptibility of HMF to the oxidative environment and requires efficient electrocatalysts. Herein, a NiMo complex (NiMo-N) is provided as the precatalyst for the HMFOR, exhibiting favorable performances with a current density of 450 mA&#183;cm-2 achieved at an anodic potential of 1.4 V vs RHE (similarly hereinafter) with 50 mmol/L (mM) HMF and over 95% HMF conversion and FDCA FE for at least five cycles. Combined with quasi situ and in situ analysis, it is confirmed that the extensive lattice distortions in the precatalyst facilitate the in-depth reconstruction, increasing the accessible Ni sites and defective oxygen vacancies (Ov), which would promptly convert to high-valence Ni and active O species during the reaction. The improved performance is then attributed to the incorporation of the improved chemisorption and dehydrogenation ability of HMF by the as-evolved active sites.</description>
      <author>Y KOU, Fanan Wang, Yun Lin, Di Liu, Qian Wang, Yan Zhang, Wenting Wen, Junhong Huang, Rengui Weng, Gang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Situ Phosphorus Doping Derived P-Metal-N Coordination Configuration to Boost the Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5108001</link>
      <description>Zhenlu Zhao, Zeqi Wu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406716107

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenlu Zhao, Zeqi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5108001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Single-Crystal Cobalt Carbonate Hydroxide via Surface Fe Doping and Facet Dependence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03018</link>
      <description>Shenghua Ye, Zhi&#8208;Jun Ou, Weibin Chen, Shuyuan Wu, D. Xiao, Jie Zhang, Lirong Zheng, Wenda Chen, Yuanguo Xu, Yongliang Li, Xiangzhong Ren, Xiaoping Ouyang, Xueqing Yan, Jianhong Liu, Qianling Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406716855

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical half-reaction in water splitting and metal&#8211;air cells. The sensitivity of the OER to the composition and structure of the electrocatalyst presents a significant challenge in elucidating the structure&#8211;property relationship. In this study, highly stable single-crystal cobalt carbonate hydroxide [Co2(OH)2CO3, CoCH] was used as a model to investigate the correlations among structure, composition, and reactivity. Single-crystal CoCH nanowires (denoted as CoCH NWs) and Fe-doped CoCH nanowires (denoted as Fe-CoCH NWs) with an exposed (210) facet and Fe-doped CoCH nanosheets (denoted as Fe-CoCH NSs) with an exposed (2&#8211;13) facet were synthesized using electrochemical and one-step hydrothermal strategies, respectively. Their OER activity decreased in the following order: Fe-CoCH NWs &gt; Fe-CoCH NSs &gt; CoCH NWs. Theoretical investigation suggested that the doped Fe sites serve as active sites, and the crystal-facet dependence can finely adjust the 3d configuration of Fe sites, resulting in the optimal adsorption strengths and energy barriers for potential-determining steps on the (210) facet of CoCH. This renders the as-prepared Fe-CoCH NWs as some of the most promising Co-based OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shenghua Ye, Zhi&#8208;Jun Ou, Weibin Chen, Shuyuan Wu, D. Xiao, Jie Zhang, Lirong Zheng, Wenda Chen, Yuanguo Xu, Yongliang Li, Xiangzhong Ren, Xiaoping Ouyang, Xueqing Yan, Jianhong Liu, Qianling Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ identification and dynamic transformation of FeOOH with different phases for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109319</link>
      <description>Ze&#8208;Feng Xu, Chuan-Wu Chen, Ya&#8208;Nan Jing, Da-Qiang Liu, Leilei Li, Xing-Liang Yin, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 190(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406725386

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ze&#8208;Feng Xu, Chuan-Wu Chen, Ya&#8208;Nan Jing, Da-Qiang Liu, Leilei Li, Xing-Liang Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese doped Ni-MOF derived porous carbon-based bifunctional oxygen electrode catalyst for metal air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130448</link>
      <description>Naseem Iqbal, Rabia Ahmad, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Nadia Shahzad, Muhammad Imran Shahzad, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406739276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naseem Iqbal, Rabia Ahmad, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Nadia Shahzad, Muhammad Imran Shahzad</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating oxygen-vacancy of IrOx@Ti via controllably partial pressures by magnetron sputtering for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162525</link>
      <description>Shurong Zhang, Lei Yu, Feng Guo, Xinghua Ma, Bo Gao, Jin Wang, Xiaoye Du, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741645

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shurong Zhang, Lei Yu, Feng Guo, Xinghua Ma, Bo Gao, Jin Wang, Xiaoye Du</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GC-DFT simulation of coverage and potential effect for oxygen evolution reaction on RuO2-based electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</link>
      <description>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT, molecular docking, antimicrobial activity, dye degradation, and oxygen evolution reaction of functionalized chitosan integrated eudragit-stannous selenide nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105907</link>
      <description>Areej Fatima, Misbah Naz, Adnan Ali, Iram Shahzadi, Anwar Ul-Ham&#305;d, Hameed Ullah, Ghafar Ali, Sawaira Moeen, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Muhammad Ikram, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741955

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Areej Fatima, Misbah Naz, Adnan Ali, Iram Shahzadi, Anwar Ul-Ham&#305;d, Hameed Ullah, Ghafar Ali, Sawaira Moeen, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Muhammad Ikram</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expansion counteraction effect assisted vanadate with rich oxygen vacancies as a high cycling stability cathode for aqueous zinc-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03410d</link>
      <description>Xiao-Luan Xie, Yifan Li, Cheng Wang, Da&#8208;Wei Gu, Wenxin Wang, Qiao Qiao, Yang Zou, Zhi-Yuan Yao, Linjiang Shen, Xiaoming Ren, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406503331

                In this study, a novel tunnel structure vanadate NaVO (Na 0.4 V 2 O 4.96 ) cathode for aqueous zinc ion batteries (AZIBs), is facilely fabricated by thermal decomposition of polyoxovanadate containing NH 4 + ions. The NaVO ...</description>
      <author>Xiao-Luan Xie, Yifan Li, Cheng Wang, Da&#8208;Wei Gu, Wenxin Wang, Qiao Qiao, Yang Zou, Zhi-Yuan Yao, Linjiang Shen, Xiaoming Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03410d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multifunctional Isostructural Bilayer Oxygen Evolution Electrode for Durable Intermediate-Temperature Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2496225</link>
      <description>Kevin Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406512910

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kevin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2496225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial properties of gold and cobalt oxyhydroxide in plasmon-mediated oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46569/47429k58s</link>
      <description>Janet Zhen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406722969

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Janet Zhen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46569/47429k58s</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Investigations of the Au and NiOOH Interface in the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46569/7w62fj62g</link>
      <description>Guoqing Guan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406723328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoqing Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46569/7w62fj62g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406750049

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406750268

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406750364

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406750703

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ measurement of photosynthetic oxygen production in the water column</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/0967-0653(95)96557-l</link>
      <description>, Oceanographic literature review. 42(8)] 1995. https://openalex.org/W4406532375

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 1995 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/0967-0653(95)96557-l</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Stacking Faults in Fe2B Induces a High-Performance Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010089</link>
      <description>Haoyu Li, Xin Liu, Xiaoyan Liu, Jian Cao, Lili Yang, Huilian Liu, Pinwen Zhu, Qiang Zhou, Xingbin Zhao, Yanli Chen, Maobin Wei, Qiang Tao, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406669871

                Fe2B is a potentially promising electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to its excellent electronic conductivity, which is superior to that of traditional oxide catalysts. However, the activity of Fe2B is still not satisfactory. In this study, meta-stable microstructure stacking faults (SFs) were incorporated into Fe2B through a one-step high-pressure and high-temperature (HPHT) method. Pressure suppressed atomic diffusion but formed SFs when the grain grew. Fe2B with SFs exhibited remarkable OER activity, with low overpotential values of only 269 and 344 mV required to reach current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively; because of the presence of SFs, the overpotential for the OER was reduced to only 67.7% of that of Fe2B without SFs at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Theoretical and experimental investigations confirmed that these SFs regulate the d-band center of Fe2B toward the Fermi level, optimizing the catalytic site activity. Furthermore, SFs reduced the charge transfer between Fe atoms and boron (B) atoms, increasing the number of free electrons in the structure and thereby increasing conductivity. Finally, this study suggests a strategy to construct microstructures in crystals, providing new insights into designing excellent catalysts via microstructure engineering.</description>
      <author>Haoyu Li, Xin Liu, Xiaoyan Liu, Jian Cao, Lili Yang, Huilian Liu, Pinwen Zhu, Qiang Zhou, Xingbin Zhao, Yanli Chen, Maobin Wei, Qiang Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mg-Evaporation Induced Amorphous Multi-Principal Element Alloys for Advanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110686</link>
      <description>Jianghong Zhang, Yu Lu, Mingzhen Xiu, Jiuyang Xia, H. Denny Kamaruddin, Liang Yu, Ke Li, Kang Huang, Bowei Zhang, Bowen Huang, Junsheng Wu, Yizhong Huang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406603583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianghong Zhang, Yu Lu, Mingzhen Xiu, Jiuyang Xia, H. Denny Kamaruddin, Liang Yu, Ke Li, Kang Huang, Bowei Zhang, Bowen Huang, Junsheng Wu, Yizhong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Heterogeneous Surface/Interface Reconstruction of Nickel Molybdate Nanofiber by In Situ Prussian Blue Analogs Etching Strategy for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12882</link>
      <description>Xinyao Ding, Lirong Zhang, Peng Yu, Ruibai Cang, Mingyi Zhang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406733316

                Bimetallic oxides are promising electrocatalysts due to their rich composition, facile synthesis, and favorable stability under oxidizing conditions. This paper innovatively proposes a strategy aimed at constructing a one&#8208;dimensional heterostructure (Fe&#8211;NiO/NiMoO 4 nanoparticles/nanofibers). The strategy commences with the meticulous treatment of NiMoO 4 nanofibers, utilizing in situ etching techniques to induce the formation of Prussian Blue Analog compounds. In this process, [Fe(CN) 6 ] 3&#8722; anions react with the NiMoO 4 host layer to form a steady NiFe PBA. Subsequently, the surface/interface reconstituted NiMoO 4 nanofibers undergo direct oxidation, leading to a reconfiguration of the surface structure and the formation of a unique Fe&#8211;NiO/NiMoO 4 one&#8208;dimensional heterostructure. The catalyst showed markedly enhanced electrocatalytic performance for the oxygen evolution reaction. Density functional theory results reveal that the incorporation of Fe as a dopant dramatically reduces the Gibbs free energy associated with the rate&#8208;determining step in the oxygen evolution reaction pathway. This pivotal transformation directly lowers the activation energy barrier, thereby significantly enhancing electron transfer efficiency.</description>
      <author>Xinyao Ding, Lirong Zhang, Peng Yu, Ruibai Cang, Mingyi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological and surface chemical composition disorder induced efficient oxygen evolution and supercapacitor processes into Co3O4 nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112577</link>
      <description>Abdul Jaleel Laghari, Umair Aftab, Huma Shaikh, Antonia Infantes&#8208;Molina, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406580798

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Jaleel Laghari, Umair Aftab, Huma Shaikh, Antonia Infantes&#8208;Molina, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112577</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron doping boosts the catalytic activity of Pd single-atom catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction of lithium peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2025.115433</link>
      <description>Luhong Chen, Qiang Ke, Xueling Lei, Journal of Energy Storage. 111(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406573720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luhong Chen, Qiang Ke, Xueling Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2025.115433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degree of span control to determine the impact of different mechanisms and limiting steps: Oxygen evolution reaction over Co3O4(001) as a case study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115970</link>
      <description>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406732898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Shell Thickness on the Oxygen Evolution Activity of Core@shell Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01784</link>
      <description>Iryna Makarchuk, Benjamin Rotonnelli, Lisa Royer, Simon Hettler, Jean&#8208;Jacques Gallet, Fabrice Bournel, Julie Guehl, Amandine Brige, Andrea Zitolo, Gw&#233;na&#235;lle K&#233;rangu&#233;ven, Antoine Bonnefont, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Elena R. Savinova, Tristan Asset, Beno&#238;t P. Pichon, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406702474

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Iryna Makarchuk, Benjamin Rotonnelli, Lisa Royer, Simon Hettler, Jean&#8208;Jacques Gallet, Fabrice Bournel, Julie Guehl, Amandine Brige, Andrea Zitolo, Gw&#233;na&#235;lle K&#233;rangu&#233;ven, Antoine Bonnefont, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Elena R. Savinova, Tristan Asset, Beno&#238;t P. Pichon</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for the evolution of an oxygen minimum layer at the beginning of S-1 sapropel deposition in the eastern Mediterranean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0967-0653(98)80333-5</link>
      <description>K Strohle, Michael D. Krom, Oceanographic literature review. 45(1)] 1998. https://openalex.org/W4406538265

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K Strohle, Michael D. Krom</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1998 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0967-0653(98)80333-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient chromium-based transition metal nitrides catalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115385</link>
      <description>Muhammad Faizan, Humaira A. Bibi, Erum Aamir, Roheen Saeed, Sieh Kiong Tiong, Hua Song, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 212(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406605754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Faizan, Humaira A. Bibi, Erum Aamir, Roheen Saeed, Sieh Kiong Tiong, Hua Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406750446

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethane Oxidative Dehydrogenation over TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and M/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts: Unraveling the Surface Structure Evolution, Oxygen Species Type, and Role of Doped Metal in Tuning Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07213</link>
      <description>Mifeng Xue, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406708054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mifeng Xue, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique hierarchical NiFe-LDH/Ni/NiCo2S4 heterostructure arrays on nickel foam for the improvement of overall water splitting activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr05248j</link>
      <description>Xiong Gong, Jian Zhou, Xianya Liu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406624608

                The development of environmental-friend, high-efficiency, good stability, earth-abundant and non-precious metal-based electro-catalysts with the fast kinetics and low overpotential of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is...</description>
      <author>Xiong Gong, Jian Zhou, Xianya Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr05248j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom Tungsten Doping Induced Chemical-electrochemical Coupled Pathway on Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Enables Efficient Urea Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee05340k</link>
      <description>Lebin Cai, Haoyun Bai, Jilong Li, Feng Xie, Kang Jiang, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Hui Pan, Yongwen Tan, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406702468

                Electrocatalytic urea oxidation reaction (UOR) has emerged as a promising alternative to oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for wastewater recycling and energy recovery. However, traditional UOR pathway on NiOOH surface faces...</description>
      <author>Lebin Cai, Haoyun Bai, Jilong Li, Feng Xie, Kang Jiang, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Hui Pan, Yongwen Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee05340k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secondary Coordination Effects of Adjacent Metal Center in Metal&#8211;Nitrogen-Carbon Improve Scaling Relation of Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03285</link>
      <description>Ke Ye, Yulan Han, Min Hu, P. Hu, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406614507

                Heterogenous single-atom catalysts (SACs) are reminiscent of homogeneous catalysts because of the similarity of structural motif of active sites, showing the potential of using the advantage of homogeneous catalysts to tackle challenges in hetereogenous catalysis. In heterogeneous oxygen electrocatalysis, the homogeneity of adsorption patterns of reaction intermediates leads to scaling relationships that limit their activities. In contrast, homogeneous catalysts can circumvent such limits by selectively altering the adsorption of intermediates through secondary coordination effects (SCEs). This inspired us to explore potential SCEs in metal&#8211;nitrogen-carbon (M&#8211;N-C), a promising type of oxygen evolution electrocatalyst. We introduced SCEs with a neighboring metal site that can modulate the adsorption strengths of oxygen-containing intermediates. First-principles calculations show that the second site in the heteronuclear duo four-nitrogen-coordinated metal center can induce SCEs that selectively stabilize the OOH intermediate but with minor effects on the OH intermediate and, thereby, disrupt the scaling relation between oxygen species and eventually increase the catalytic activity in oxygen evolution reactions. Additionally, the activity of oxygen reduction reaction of selected M&#8211;N-C is also enhanced by such SCE. Our computational work underscored the critical role SCEs can have in shaping activities of SACs, particularly in favorably altering scaling relationships, and demonstrated its potential to address catalytic challenges in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Ke Ye, Yulan Han, Min Hu, P. Hu, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uniform Sub-5 nm Crystalline Nickel-Based Heterojunctions for Overall Water Splitting Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03097</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Wang, Rui Yin, Lei Yuan, Xingmei Guo, Xiangjun Zheng, Qianqian Fan, Zhongyao Duan, Yuanjun Liu, Junhao Zhang, Shenglin Xiong, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406504388

                Exploring a general method for constructing uniform heterostructures with sub-5 nm crystallites and dense interfaces is crucial yet challenging for advancing water electrocatalysis. Herein, a bottom-up cocrystallization strategy, involving in situ transformation of amorphous Ni&#8211;P through gas&#8211;solid reactions, is proposed to synthesize a series of nickel-based heterojunctions on carbon cloth (CC). Thereinto, interface-wealthy NiS2-Ni2P/CC with densely packed 3&#8211;4 nm crystallites demonstrates superb catalytic performance for both hydrogen and oxygen evolution. The electrolyzer merely requires cell voltages of 1.79 and 1.89 V to propel overall water splitting currents of 200 and 400 mA cm&#8211;2, respectively, outperforming the vast majority of reported nickel-based heterojunctions. Theoretical calculations reveal that charge redistribution and electronic structure modulation optimize the hydrogen and oxygen evolution pathways at the NiS2 and Ni2P sides of the interfaces, respectively. Moreover, uniform hybridization with densely distributed heterointerfaces offers abundant active sites for electrocatalysis, pioneering an extendable approach for constructing advanced heterojunction catalysts for green hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Wang, Rui Yin, Lei Yuan, Xingmei Guo, Xiangjun Zheng, Qianqian Fan, Zhongyao Duan, Yuanjun Liu, Junhao Zhang, Shenglin Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c03097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of dopants in mitigating the chemo&#8208;mechanical degradation of Ni&#8208;rich cathode: A critical review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.92</link>
      <description>Imesha Rambukwella, Hanisha Ponnuru, Cheng Yan, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406619840

                Abstract Ni&#8208;rich cathodes are more promising candidates to the increasing demand for high capacity and the ability to operate at high voltages. However, the high Ni content creates a trade&#8208;off between energy density and cycling stability, mainly caused by the chemo&#8208;mechanical degradation. Oxygen evolution, cation mixing, rock salt formation, phase transition, and crack formation contribute to the degradation process. To overcome this problem, strategies such as doping, surface coating, and core&#8208;shell structures have been employed. The advantage of doping is to engineer the cathode surface, structure, and particle morphology simultaneously. This review aims to summarize recent advances in understanding chemo&#8208;mechanical degradation mechanism and the role of different dopants in enhancing the thermal stability and overall electrochemical performance. The pinning and pillaring effects of dopants on suppressing oxygen evolution, cation mixing, and phase transition are introduced. It is found that the higher ionic radii enable dopants to reside on cathode particles, preserving the particle surface and refining particle morphology to suppress crack formation. Finally, the effect of doping on Li ion diffusion, rate capability, and long&#8208;term stability are discussed.</description>
      <author>Imesha Rambukwella, Hanisha Ponnuru, Cheng Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.92</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 min synthesis of phase pure nanocrystalline high&#8208;entropy sulfides for efficient water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.91</link>
      <description>Judith Zander, Roland Marschall, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406534464

                Abstract The development of noble&#8208;metal free electrocatalysts with low production cost is of utmost importance for sustainable water electrolysis. Herein, we present a fast flexible synthesis pathway for the preparation of a variety of different medium&#8208; and high&#8208;entropy spinel sulfides of various compositions, using a non&#8208;aqueous microwave&#8208;assisted synthesis without any H 2 S. Nanoparticulate high&#8208;entropy sulfides containing up to 8 different metal cations can be obtained after an extremely short synthesis time of only 1 min and comparatively low temperatures of 200&#8211;230&#176;C. We further demonstrate the high activity of the obtained sulfides for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Judith Zander, Roland Marschall</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.91</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Charge Distribution at Organic&#8208;inorganic Interface via Optimizing Substituents for Sustainable Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423145</link>
      <description>Ling Jiang, Yixin Hao, Mingzheng Gu, Liming Deng, Qiao Chen, Xiaojun Zhang, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Guangfeng Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406512540

                The space charge effect induced by high-quality heterojunctions is essential for efficient electrocatalytic processes. Herein, we delicately manipulate intermolecular charge transfer by modifying substituents (-g = -CH3, -H, -NO2) with various electron donating/withdrawing capabilities in CoPc-g/CoS organic-inorganic heterostructures. CoPc-CH3, as a typical electron donor, transfers more electrons to CoS due to the presence of -CH3, forming the strongest space electric field and thus regulating the dual active sites at the interface. Furthermore, oxygen-containing intermediates preferentially adsorb on the positively charged CoPc-CH3 side, and the rapid accumulation of electrons on the CoS side decelerates catalyst dissolution at the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) potential, ensuring the stable OER process under the optimized adsorbate evolution mechanism. As a result, CoPc-CH3/CoS catalyst exhibits the lowest overpotential and remains stable for 150 h at 0.5 A cm-2 in the membrane electrode assembly electrolyzer. The method provides a novel strategy for accurately regulating the space electric field of heterojunctions.</description>
      <author>Ling Jiang, Yixin Hao, Mingzheng Gu, Liming Deng, Qiao Chen, Xiaojun Zhang, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Guangfeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Charge Distribution at Organic&#8208;inorganic Interface via Optimizing Substituents for Sustainable Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423145</link>
      <description>Ling Jiang, Yixin Hao, Mingzheng Gu, Liming Deng, Qiao Chen, Xiaojun Zhang, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Guangfeng Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406513121

                The space charge effect induced by high&#8208;quality heterojunctions is essential for efficient electrocatalytic processes. Herein, we delicately manipulate intermolecular charge transfer by modifying substituents (&#8208;g = &#8208;CH3, &#8208;H, &#8208;NO2) with various electron donating/withdrawing capabilities in CoPc&#8208;g/CoS organic&#8208;inorganic heterostructures. CoPc&#8208;CH3, as a typical electron donor, transfers more electrons to CoS due to the presence of &#8208;CH3, forming the strongest space electric field and thus regulating the dual active sites at the interface. Furthermore, oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates preferentially adsorb on the positively charged CoPc&#8208;CH3 side, and the rapid accumulation of electrons on the CoS side decelerates catalyst dissolution at the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) potential, ensuring the stable OER process under the optimized adsorbate evolution mechanism. As a result, CoPc&#8208;CH3/CoS catalyst exhibits the lowest overpotential and remains stable for 150 h at 0.5 A cm&#8208;2 in the membrane electrode assembly electrolyzer. The method provides a novel strategy for accurately regulating the space electric field of heterojunctions.</description>
      <author>Ling Jiang, Yixin Hao, Mingzheng Gu, Liming Deng, Qiao Chen, Xiaojun Zhang, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Guangfeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional mixed-valence ruthenium heterostructure for robust electrocatalytic water splitting in acid media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-025-01234-z</link>
      <description>Xinyu Xie, Yixiao Zhang, Yang Qin, Jianbo Wu, Ming Lei, Kai Huang, Ruyue Wang, Peng Du, Advanced Composites and Hybrid Materials. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406562991

                The incorporation of non-metal dopants can significantly enhance catalytic activity and improve stability. Furthermore, the creation of heterostructures is particularly advantageous to facilitate charge transfer and optimize electronic properties. This study presents an effective bifunctional mixed-valence Ruthenium heterostructure synthesized through a cascading process involving grinding with carbon nitride and subsequent thermal treatment. The catalyst exhibits outstanding electrocatalytic performance with remarkably low overpotentials of 197 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and 24.8 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), respectively, with the stability exceeding 24 h at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315;2 in acidic media. Additionally, when employed in an acidic oxygen water splitting (OWS) electrolyzer, the bifunctional catalyst demonstrates excellent activity, achieving an ultralow cell voltage of 1.53 V to sustain 10 mA cm&#8315;2. Enhanced performance is attributed to efficient charge transfer and increased exposure of active sites, providing valuable insights for the development of effective acidic water-electrolysis catalysts for sustainable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Xie, Yixiao Zhang, Yang Qin, Jianbo Wu, Ming Lei, Kai Huang, Ruyue Wang, Peng Du</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-025-01234-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Nitrate to Ammonia Conversion on Bifunctional IrCu&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Alloy Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c15234</link>
      <description>Ning He, Yuan Zhi, Chao Wu, Shibo Xi, Jingjing Xiong, Yucong Huang, Guanwu Lian, Zuliang Du, Laihao Liu, Dawei Wu, Zhongxin Chen, Wenguang Tu, Zhigang Zou, S. Y. Tong, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406558617

                Electrochemical nitrate reduction (NO3RR) to ammonia presents a promising alternative strategy to the traditional Haber-Bosch process. However, the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) reduces the Faradaic efficiency toward ammonia, while the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) increases the energy consumption. This study designs IrCu4 alloy nanoparticles as a bifunctional catalyst to achieve efficient NO3RR and OER while suppressing the unwanted HER. This is achieved by operating the NO3RR at positive potentials using the IrCu4 catalyst, which allows a Faradaic efficiency of 93.6% for NO3RR. When applied to OER catalysis, the IrCu4 alloy also shows excellent results, with a relatively low overpotential of 260 mV at 10 mA cm-2. Stable ammonia production can be achieved for 50 h in a 16 cm2 flow electrolyzer in simulated working conditions. Our research provides a pathway for optimizing NO3RR through bifunctional catalysts in a tandem approach.</description>
      <author>Ning He, Yuan Zhi, Chao Wu, Shibo Xi, Jingjing Xiong, Yucong Huang, Guanwu Lian, Zuliang Du, Laihao Liu, Dawei Wu, Zhongxin Chen, Wenguang Tu, Zhigang Zou, S. Y. Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c15234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuCu Nanorod Arrays Synergistically Promote Efficient Water-Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010098</link>
      <description>Tao Chen, Xiangkai Kong, Qiangchun Liu, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406698375

                In the realm of green hydrogen energy, utilizing ruthenium (Ru) as a precious metal electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) instead of platinum (Pt/C) is an excellent choice. Unfortunately, there are not enough active sites or electronic structures on a single Ru-based catalyst to significantly improve the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Therefore, creating bifunctional water electrolysis catalysts that are stable and highly active in a variety of media continues to be a major challenge. The study describes a new method for creating an electrocatalyst (RuCuCl/NF-2) by using Ru to regulate an inert CuCl precursor. The enhanced mass transfer performance of the distinctive coral structure and the synergistic effect of RuCu emphasize its excellent water electrolysis activity, which is based on the self-assembly of Cu nanoparticles into a conical membrane structure. Overtaking the commercial benchmark Pt/C (~38 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2), the RuCuCl/NF-2 displays HER activity (~25 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2) in 1M KOH. This sheds light on how to create more sophisticated bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Chen, Xiangkai Kong, Qiangchun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrids of Deep HOMO Organic Cyanoacrylic Acid Dyes and Graphene Nanomaterials for Water Splitting Photoanodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18020463</link>
      <description>Alejandro Ans&#243;n&#8208;Casaos, Ana M. Benito, Wolfgang K. Maser, J. Orduna, Bel&#233;n Villacampa, Mar&#237;a&#8208;Jes&#250;s Blesa, Materials. 18(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615496

                Dye-sensitization is a promising strategy to improve the light absorption and photoactivity abilities of wide-bandgap semiconductors, like TiO2. For effective water-splitting photoanodes with no sacrificial agents, the electrochemical potential of the dye must exceed the thermodynamic threshold needed for the oxygen evolution reaction. This study investigates two promising organic cyanoacrylic dyes, designed to meet that criterion by means of theoretical calculations. Both yellow-colored dyes were synthesized and characterized by optical and photoelectrochemical techniques, demonstrating strong light absorption in the visible region, suitable experimental reduction potentials, and adsorption from the organic solvent onto mesoporous TiO2 layers. In addition, to promote immobilization in aqueous electrolytes, the dyes were hybridized with graphene oxide or multi-walled carbon nanotubes. Photoelectrochemical analysis of the dye-sensitized photoelectrodes demonstrated efficient charge transfer from the dyes to the TiO2 photoanode under simulated solar light. While the starting photocurrent notably surpassed the blank TiO2, a subsequent decay points to kinetic obstacles that still need to be overcome.</description>
      <author>Alejandro Ans&#243;n&#8208;Casaos, Ana M. Benito, Wolfgang K. Maser, J. Orduna, Bel&#233;n Villacampa, Mar&#237;a&#8208;Jes&#250;s Blesa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18020463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical deposition of bimetallic sulfides on novel BDD electrode for bifunctional alkaline seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-87104-6</link>
      <description>Mingxu Li, Genjie Chu, Jiyun Gao, Xiaolei Ye, Ming Hou, Shenghui Guo, Yunchuan Li, Ziqi Zhou, Yang Li, Pascal Briois, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406690346

                Seawater electrolysis is an ideal technology for obtaining clean energy&#8212;green hydrogen. Developing efficient bifunctional catalysts is crucial for hydrogen production through direct seawater electrolysis. Currently, metal substrates loaded with active catalysts are widely employed as electrodes for seawater electrolysis. However, the challenge of metal corrosion cannot be ignored. In this work, the boron-doped diamond (BDD) with excellent corrosion resistance was explored as a substrate for loading active catalysts in seawater electrolysis. A step-by-step electrodeposition method was used to fabricate the FeCoS/Ni/BDD electrode, effectively addressing the poor adhesion of the FeCoS active layer to the BDD substrate. The resulting electrode demonstrated interesting bifunctional catalytic performance, achieving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) overpotentials of 425 mV and 360 mV, respectively, in alkaline simulated seawater (1 M KOH and 3.5 wt% NaCl) at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722; 2. Furthermore, by increasing the KOH concentration in the alkaline simulated seawater to 3 M, the OER and HER overpotentials of the electrode significantly decreased to 383 and 300 mV, respectively. This work offers a novel approach for utilizing BDD substrates in the design of corrosion-resistant electrodes for alkaline seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Mingxu Li, Genjie Chu, Jiyun Gao, Xiaolei Ye, Ming Hou, Shenghui Guo, Yunchuan Li, Ziqi Zhou, Yang Li, Pascal Briois</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-87104-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Spray Combustion Enabling Hierarchical Porous Carbon-Supported FeCoNi Alloy Catalyst for Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c19069</link>
      <description>Hongrui Huang, Qianqian Liang, Guangchao Li, Huajun Guo, Zhixing Wang, Guochun Yan, Xinhai Li, Hui Duan, Jiexi Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406708075

                Rechargeable Zn-air batteries (RZABs) are poised for industrial application, yet they require low-cost, high-performance catalysts that efficiently facilitate both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The pivotal challenge lies in designing multimetal active sites and optimizing the carbon skeleton structure to modulate catalyst activity. In this study, we introduce a novel hierarchical porous carbon-supported FeCoNi bifunctional catalyst, synthesized via a spray combustion method. The carbon, derived from sucrose, was tailored into a hierarchical porous morphology through etching with NO3- ions and NaCl, thereby significantly increasing the surface area for the interaction of the O2 and electrolyte interaction. The in situ formation of FeCoNi alloy nanoparticles ensures their uniform dispersion and anchoring, facilitating electron transport. The strong interaction and charge transfer at the heterogeneous FeCoNi alloy interfaces, along with nitrogen doping, which enhances the OER/ORR activity, endow the FeCoNi/N-PC catalyst with exceptional bifunctional catalytic properties, characterized by an activity parameter of 0.73 V. Furthermore, the RZAB assembled with this catalyst demonstrates outstanding cycling stability and reversibility, with a minimal round-trip efficiency decay of 7.6% over 1380 cycles (460 h) at 10 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Hongrui Huang, Qianqian Liang, Guangchao Li, Huajun Guo, Zhixing Wang, Guochun Yan, Xinhai Li, Hui Duan, Jiexi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c19069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The prediction of X2B6 monolayers with ultrahigh carrier mobility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fphy.2024.1534301</link>
      <description>Xuesen Du, Zhaoming Huang, Frontiers in Physics. 12(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406628409

                Two-dimensional (2D) materials present novel electronic and catalytic performances, showing a promising application as nano-device. In this investigation, a family of 2D material, X 2 B 6 (X = K, Na and Rb), is predicted with puckered crystal structure by elemental mutation method. The dynamic and thermal stability of the X 2 B 6 monolayer is addressed. The anisotropic mechanical properties of the X 2 B 6 monolayer is obtained by the Young&#8217;s modulus (296&#8211;406 N/m) and the Poisson&#8217;s ratio (0.36&#8211;0.35). Interestingly, the K 2 B 6 and Rb 2 B 6 monolayers demonstrate a metallic band structure, while the Na 2 B 6 monolayer is a semiconductor with an ultra-narrow bandgap only about 0.42 eV. Then, the ultra-high electron mobility in the Na 2 B 6 monolayer is calculated as about 9942 cm 2 .V &#8722;1 .s &#8722;1 , and the excellent optical performance of the Na 2 B 6 monolayer is also addressed. More importantly, the advantageous catalytic activity in hydrogen evolution reduction (HER) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER) is explored in these X 2 B 6 monolayers. Our work suggests a theoretical guidance to use the X 2 B 6 monolayer as a high-speed electronic devices and highly efficient catalyst.</description>
      <author>Xuesen Du, Zhaoming Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fphy.2024.1534301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding the Hume&#8211;Rothery Rule in a Bifunctional Tetra-metallic Alloy for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c04412</link>
      <description>Surajit Mondal, Supriti Dutta, Vishwadeepa Hazra, Swapan K. Pati, Sayan Bhattacharyya, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406526628

                The 90-year-old Hume&#8211;Rothery rule was adapted to design an outstanding bifunctional tetra-metallic alloy electrocatalyst for water electrolysis. Following the radius mismatch principles, Fe (131 pm) and Ni (124 pm) are selectively incorporated at the Pd (139 pm) site of Mo0.30Pd0.70 nanosheets. Analogously, Cu (132 pm) alloys with only Pd, while Ag (145 pm) alloys with both Pd and Mo (154 pm). The face-centered cubic Mo0.30Pd0.35Ni0.23Fe0.12 nanosheets with 10&#8211;12 atomic layers, featuring in-plane compressive strain along the {111} basal plane, show 1/3 (422) reflection from local hexagonal symmetry. The more electronegative Pd attracts electron density from Ni/Fe in Mo0.30Pd0.35Ni0.23Fe0.12, synergistically boosting the mass activities for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions to 89 &#177; 5 and 38.6 &#177; 3.1 A g&#8211;1 at &#177;400 mV versus RHE, respectively. Full water electrolysis continues for &#8805;550 h, requiring cell voltages of 1.51 and 1.63 V at 10 and 100 mA cm&#8211;2, delivering 45 mL h&#8211;1 green H2.</description>
      <author>Surajit Mondal, Supriti Dutta, Vishwadeepa Hazra, Swapan K. Pati, Sayan Bhattacharyya</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c04412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst&#8208;Anchored 3D Framework Electrodes: A Breakthrough in Large&#8208;Scale Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ppsc.202400226</link>
      <description>Samruddhi V. Chauhan, Kinjal K. Joshi, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh, Particle &amp; Particle Systems Characterization. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406628653

                Abstract The idea of grid&#8208;scale hydrogen production by water electrolysis has been made possible by developing catalyst&#8208;anchored three&#8208;dimensional (3D) foam&#8208;based electrodes. Catalytic performance in hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions is improved by incorporating catalyst in 3D interlinked porous architecture, which enhances electrical conductivity and speeds up the discharge of gas bubbles. The detailed study on the role&#8208;play of 3D frameworks in energy generation is explained in this article. The review also focuses on the recent development in utilizing these 3D substrates in the field of electrochemistry. Furthermore, it is imperative to enhance their compatibility with renewable energy systems and high&#8208;temperature electrolysis for the sustainable production of hydrogen. Therefore, this review briefly explores the innovative design of self&#8208;supported 3D framework electrodes using heterostructures and doping techniques to develop stable, durable, and efficient electrocatalysts. These catalysts aim to provide near&#8208;zero overpotential, high selectivity, and long&#8208;term stability for hydrogen production through water electrolysis, paving the way for commercial&#8208;scale green energy production. 3D foam&#8208;based electrodes can emerge as a key technology in the field of electrochemistry.</description>
      <author>Samruddhi V. Chauhan, Kinjal K. Joshi, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ppsc.202400226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput calculations of two-dimensional auxetic $M_4X_8$ with
  magnetism, electrocatalysis, and alkali metal battery applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.11242</link>
      <description>Haidi Wang, Xu Li, Weiduo Zhu, Zhao Chen, Zhongjun Li, Xiaofeng Liu, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406734960

                Two-dimensional (2D) materials with multifunctional properties, such as negative Poisson's ratio (NPR), magnetism, catalysis, and energy storage capabilities, are of significant interest for advanced applications in flexible electronics, spintronics, catalysis, and lithium-ion batteries. However, the discovery of such materials, particularly in low-dimensional forms, remains a challenge. In this study, we perform high-throughput density-functional theory (DFT) calculations to explore a new class of 2D V-shaped monolayers with remarkable physicochemical properties. Among 18 stable $M_4X_8$ (M = transition metal; X = halogen) compounds, we identify 9 auxetic monolayers, with \ce{Pd4I8} standing out for its exceptionally high NPR of -0.798. Notably, 4 of these materials exhibit half semiconductor properties, while 5 others are bipolar magnetic semiconductors, offering a unique combination of electronic and magnetic behavior. Additionally, these materials demonstrate promising catalytic activity for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) and show potential as anodes for rechargeable metal-ion batteries, particularly in alkali-ion systems. This work not only expands the family of 2D NPR materials but also introduces new candidates with multifunctional capabilities for a wide range of applications in nanoelectronics, catalysis, and energy storage.</description>
      <author>Haidi Wang, Xu Li, Weiduo Zhu, Zhao Chen, Zhongjun Li, Xiaofeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.11242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Engineering of Ru&#8211;Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Ni Nanoalloy Encapsulated with Carbon Nanotubes for Efficient Anion and Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420517</link>
      <description>Abhisek Majumdar, Tran Khoa Dang, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706028

                Abstract Alloying atomically dispersed noble metals with earth&#8208;abundant transition metal nanoparticles (NPs) presents a promising approach to enhance the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water electrolysis. However, the challenge remains of reducing the size of the NPs without sacrificing high activity and durability. In this study, Ru&#8211;Co 2 Ni nanoalloy particles (NAPs) encapsulated in nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes (NCNTs) are introduced, forming a core&#8208;shell electrocatalyst (Ru&#8211;Co 2 Ni@NCNT). This design leverages Ru site optimization, CNT density control, strain engineering, efficient water dissociation, and outstanding bubble release dynamics within the core&#8208;shell structure. These factors significantly improve catalytic performance with low overpotentials of 35 and 57 mV overpotential in 1.0 m KOH and 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 solutions, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that while Ru sites serve as active sites, they also modify the electronic structure of Co and Ni, optimizing their hydrogen adsorption energies and improving HER efficiency. The Ru&#8211;Co 2 Ni@NCNT catalyst is successfully integrated into both anion exchange membrane (AEM) and proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzers, demonstrating stable operation at 0.5 A cm &#8722;2 for 500 h, underscoring its potential for efficient and durable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Abhisek Majumdar, Tran Khoa Dang, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyper-Cross-Linked Polymer-Derived Carbon-Coated Fe&#8211;Ni Alloy/CNT as a Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03361</link>
      <description>Arindam Modak, Ankita Phutela, Aniruddha Kundu, Srijib Das, Vidha Bhasin, D. Bhattacharyya, Saswata Bhattacharya, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406722932

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are considered to be the most important processes in metal&#8211;air batteries and regenerative fuel cell devices. Metal&#8211;organic polymers are attracting interest as promising precursors of advanced metal/carbon electrocatalysts because of their hierarchical porous structure along with the integrated metal&#8211;carbon framework. We developed carbon-coated CNTs with Ni/Fe and Cu/Fe as active sites. Experimental observations from X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and X-ray absorption analysis suggest that C@CNT[Ni] outperforms C@CNT[Cu] in the ORR and OER, which is further supported by density functional theory calculations. C@CNT[Ni] exhibits a higher onset potential (0.99 V vs RHE) and a smaller Tafel slope (40.2 mV decade&#8211;1) compared to those of C@CNT/[Cu] in an alkaline electrolyte (0.94 V vs RHE and 46.5 mV decade&#8211;1, respectively). Such circumstances are attributed to the alloying effect between Ni and Fe in C@CNT[Ni], in contrast to the existing copper iron oxide phase in C@CNT/[Cu]. It is noteworthy that C@CNT[Ni] also displayed an improved OER, demanding its bifunctional property. As a proof of concept, C@CNT[Ni] was utilized in zinc&#8211;air batteries, which shows a high energy efficiency of &#8764;60%, a small charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap of 0.78 V, and excellent cycling performance (&#8764;120 h) at 5 mA cm&#8211;2 and 25 &#176;C. This protocol expands the utility of novel metal&#8211;organic hyper-cross-linked polymer-derived bimetallic electrocatalysts for clean energy research.</description>
      <author>Arindam Modak, Ankita Phutela, Aniruddha Kundu, Srijib Das, Vidha Bhasin, D. Bhattacharyya, Saswata Bhattacharya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partially Substituted La for Sm in Sm&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;NiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;: An Efficient Electrocatalyst Towards Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405118</link>
      <description>Reena Parihar, Prakhar Mishra, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Narendra Kumar Singh, ChemistrySelect. 10(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406694906

                Abstract Perovskite&#8208;type oxides having composition La x Sm 0.8&#8722; x Sr 0.2 NiO 3 (0 &#8804; x &#8804; 0.6) were explored for their ability to act as facilitators for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. Synthesis of the materials was conducted through a sol&#8208;gel procedure via malic acid. The materials underwent advanced physicochemical characterization utilizing techniques, namely transmission electron microscope (TEM), scanning electron microscope/energy dispersive X&#8208;ray spectroscopy (SEM/EDS), inductively coupled plasma &#8211; mass spectrometry (ICP&#8208;MS) and X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD). These analyses provided crucial details about the material&#8217;s particle size, surface morphology/chemical composition and crystalline structure, opening up exciting possibilities for their diverse applications. From TEM analysis, the average particle size of the oxide materials has been estimated and found to be 5.9 nm for Sm 0.8 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 and 4.8 nm for La 0.6 Sm 0.2 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 . The particle size of the oxide material decreases when La was partially substituted for Sm in Sm 0.8 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 . Cyclic voltammetry and Tafel plot were observed for the electrochemical analysis in 1 M KOH (25 &#176;C). An investigation on the anodic polarization of oxides revealed an increased electrocatalytic activity when La was partially substituted for Sm in Sm 0.8 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 . La 0.6 Sm 0.2 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 was found to be most active at 800 mV with a current density, j = 184.1 mA/cm 2 . The Tafel experiment was conducted in 1M KOH at varying temperatures to determine thermodynamic properties like standard electrochemical energy of activation (), standard enthalpy of activation (&#916; H &#176; # ), and standard entropy of activation (&#916; S &#176; # ).</description>
      <author>Reena Parihar, Prakhar Mishra, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Narendra Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Interior Structure and Thermal Evolution of Super-Earth GJ
  486b</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.09963</link>
      <description>Chandan Sahu, Liton Majumdar, Sudipta Mridha, H. Anantha Krishna, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406603967

                Recent ground- and space-based surveys have shown that planets between Earth and Neptune in size, known as "super-Earths," are among the most frequently found planets in the Galaxy. Although the JWST era has provided high-quality atmospheric data on several such super-Earths, modeling tools are crucial for understanding their unobservable interiors. Consequently, interior studies represent the next essential step in gaining a comprehensive understanding of this class of exoplanets. This study investigates the interior structure, thermal evolution, and atmospheric dynamics of the super-Earth GJ 486b using SERPINT, a 1-D self-consistent coupled interior structure and evolution model, aiming to understand the planet's thermal evolution based on an Earth-like structure. Our results indicate that GJ 486b's core is approximately 1.34 times larger than Earth's, with a core pressure of about 1171 GPa. The thermal evolution model predicts that the planet's mantle cools and solidifies over approximately 0.93 million years. As the magma ocean cools, water is released from the melt, forming a water-rich atmosphere during early solidification. Photolysis of water vapor and subsequent hydrogen escape lead to oxygen accumulation, forming a water- and oxygen-rich secondary atmosphere. Future high-sensitivity JWST observations, with improved wavelength coverage and the detection of additional trace gases, will enable a detailed analysis of the planet's atmospheric composition, providing crucial insights into the interior, surface, and subsurface properties of GJ 486b.</description>
      <author>Chandan Sahu, Liton Majumdar, Sudipta Mridha, H. Anantha Krishna</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.09963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial carbon oxidation in seawater below the hypoxic threshold</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-82438-z</link>
      <description>Sarah Wolf, Clare Jayawickrama, Craig A. Carlson, Curtis Deutsch, Edward W. Davis, Benjamin N. Daniels, Francis Chan, Stephen J. Giovannoni, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406695513

                Global oxygen minimum zones (OMZs) often reach hypoxia but seldom reach anoxia. Recently it was reported that Michaelis Menten constants (Km) of oxidative enzymes are orders of magnitude higher than respiratory Km values, and in the Hypoxic Barrier Hypothesis it was proposed that, in ecosystems experiencing falling oxygen, oxygenase enzyme activities become oxygen-limited long before respiration. We conducted a mesocosm experiment with a phytoplankton bloom as an organic carbon source and controlled dissolved oxygen (DO) concentrations in the dark to determine whether hypoxia slows carbon oxidation and oxygen decline. Total oxygen utilization (TOU) in hypoxic treatment (ca. 7.1 &#181;M O2) was 21.7% lower than the oxic treatment (ca. 245.1 &#181;M O2) over the first 43 days of the experiment. In addition, following the restoration of fully oxic conditions to the hypoxic treatment, TOU accelerated, demonstrating that oxidative processes are sensitive to DO concentrations found in large volumes of the ocean. Microbial amplicon-based community composition diverged between oxic treatments, indicating a specialized microbiome that included Thioglobaceae (SUP05 Gammaproteobacteria), OM190 (Planctomycetota), ABY1 (Patescibacteria), and SAR86 subclade D2472, thrived in the hypoxic treatment, while the genus Candidatus Actinomarina and SAR11 alphaproteobacteria were sharply inhibited. Our findings support the hypothesis that oxygenase kinetics might slow the progression of ocean deoxygenation in oxygen-poor regions and be a factor in the evolution of microbial taxa adapted to hypoxic environments.</description>
      <author>Sarah Wolf, Clare Jayawickrama, Craig A. Carlson, Curtis Deutsch, Edward W. Davis, Benjamin N. Daniels, Francis Chan, Stephen J. Giovannoni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-82438-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Densely populated macrocyclic dicobalt sites in ladder polymers for low-overpotential oxygen reduction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56066-8</link>
      <description>Zhen Zhang, Zhenyu Xing, Xianglin Luo, Chong Cheng, Xikui Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406686912

                Dual-atom catalysts featuring synergetic dinuclear active sites, have the potential of breaking the linear scaling relationship of the well-established single-atom catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction; however, the design of dual-atom catalysts with rationalized local microenvironment for high activity and selectivity remains a great challenge. Here we design a bisalphen ladder polymer with well-defined densely populated binuclear cobalt sites on Ketjenblack substrates. The strong electron coupling effect between the fully-conjugated ladder structure and carbon substrates enhances the electron transfer between the cobalt center and oxygen intermediates, inducing the low-to-high spin transition for the 3d electron of Co(II). In situ techniques and theoretical calculations reveal the dynamic evolution of Co2N4O2 active sites and reaction intermediates. In alkaline conditions, the catalyst exhibits impressive oxygen reduction reaction activity featuring an onset potential of 1.10 V and a half-wave potential of 1.00 V, insignificant decay after 30,000 cycles, pushing the overpotential boundaries of ORR electrocatalysis to a low level. This work provides a platform for designing efficient dual-atom catalysts with well-defined coordination and electronic structures in energy conversion technologies. Designing dual-atom catalysts with high activity and selectivity for oxygen reduction reactions is a challenging task. Here, the authors report a bisalphen ladder polymer with densely populated binuclear cobalt sites on Ketjenblack substrates, which improves oxygen reduction performance and stability.</description>
      <author>Zhen Zhang, Zhenyu Xing, Xianglin Luo, Chong Cheng, Xikui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56066-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerobic hydrocarbon oxidation in a novel archaeal lineage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5714735/v1</link>
      <description>Andy O Leu, Ben J. Woodcroft, Simon Jon McIlroy, Gene W. Tyson, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406690330

                Abstract Over the last decade, there has been significant advances in our understanding of anaerobic hydrocarbon oxidation in Archaea. While Bacteria are known to oxidise hydrocarbons aerobically, no aerobic hydrocarbon oxidation pathway has been found in Archaea. Here, we report the first aerobic hydrocarbon oxidizing archaeon in a novel order of the Syntropharchaeia. This order is represented by six metagenome-assembled genomes (MAGs) spanning three genera that are found in terrestrial and marine ecosystems. Our analysis revealed that MAGs belonging to one newly defined genus, Candidatus &#8216;Aerovita&#8217;, encode a bacterial copper monooxygenase complex with homology to bacterial hydrocarbon monooxygenases. The presence of other oxygen-dependent enzymes, such as haem-copper oxygen reductase, and the absence of the Wood-Ljungdahl pathway, indicate an aerobic lifestyle for the Ca. &#8216;Aerovita&#8217; lineage. These findings support horizontal gene transfer between archaeal and bacterial domains facilitating the evolution of aerobic hydrocarbon-oxidizing archaea.</description>
      <author>Andy O Leu, Ben J. Woodcroft, Simon Jon McIlroy, Gene W. Tyson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5714735/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electro-composting: an emerging technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.16.633320</link>
      <description>Christian Abendroth, Ahmad Shabir Hozad, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406532072

                The present study focuses on electrical stimulation for composting. Using the PSALSAR method, a systematic review resulted in 24 relevant articles. For each system, the review describes key materials, composter design, operating conditions, temperature evolution, compost maturity, microbial community, and outcome. The examined studies fall into four main systems: electric field-assisted aerobic composting (EAAC), electrolytic oxygen aerobic composting (EOAC), microbial fuel cells (MFC), and thermoelectric generators (TEG). Apart from the main systems highlighted above, there is a rare case, which remains hardly studied. This includes bioelectrochemically assisted anaerobic composting (AnCBE, III). EAAC and EOAC systems biologically balance microbial activity and organic matter decomposition, whereas MFC and TEG systems have dual functioning due to energy generated alongside waste degradation. These innovative systems significantly improve composting efficiency by speeding up organic matter breakdown, increasing oxygen supply, and facilitating energy recovery. Together, they overcome the drawbacks of conventional composting systems and promote more environmentally friendly waste management solutions.</description>
      <author>Christian Abendroth, Ahmad Shabir Hozad</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2025.01.16.633320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adipose-Derived Stem Cell Therapy Combined With Platelet-Rich Plasma for the Treatment of Avascular Necrosis of the Talus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.77578</link>
      <description>Rui A. Sousa, Jaime Babulal, Paulo Vin&#237;cius Amado, Cureus. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406532460

                Avascular necrosis (AVN) is characterized by compromised blood supply to bone tissue, often resulting in significant pain and functional impairment. Conservative treatment options for early-stage AVN of the talus are scarce, with non-weight-bearing protocols and hyperbaric oxygen therapy showing limited efficacy. This report presents a potential novel approach to managing non-traumatic AVN of the talus using a combination of adipose-derived stromal vascular fraction (SVF) and platelet-rich plasma (PRP). A 60-year-old male presented with progressive right ankle pain of a two-year evolution. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) revealed stage II AVN of the talus with extensive bone infarctions occupying almost all of its volume but with no collapse. A single injection of SVF and PRP was performed after diagnostic arthroscopy, followed by a tailored rehabilitation protocol. The patient experienced significant pain relief, with no further need for analgesics, and was able to return to non-impact sports. At the 18-month follow-up, functional scores showed significant improvement, and MRI showed stable AVN with no evidence of collapse. This report highlights SVF and PRP as a potential effective conservative option for non-traumatic talar AVN.</description>
      <author>Rui A. Sousa, Jaime Babulal, Paulo Vin&#237;cius Amado</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.77578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NaHSO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; as a Key Component in Developing Enhanced Performance Electrolytes for All&#8208;Iron Redox Flow Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240059</link>
      <description>A. Concheso, Daniel Barreda, Zoraida Gonz&#225;lez, Patricia &#193;lvarez, Rosa Men&#233;ndez, Clara Blanco, Victoria G. Rocha, Ricardo Santamar&#305;&#769;a, Battery energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406545572

                ABSTRACT Redox flow batteries (RFBs) are attractive electrochemical systems for large&#8208;scale energy storage. Despite the most developed ones being those based on vanadium, the search for new chemistries is essential to overcome several problems associated with this metal identified as a critical raw material. All&#8208;iron redox flow battery (A&#8208;IRFB) is an interesting device due to iron abundance and worldwide distribution. However, the poor performance of its negative half&#8208;cell, due to the sluggish plating/stripping processes related to the Fe 2+ /Fe 0 redox pair, negatively impacts its energy efficiency and long&#8208;term performance. Here, it is demonstrated that the addition of a low concentration of NaHSO 3 (10 mM), as a novel additive, to an electrolyte formulation based on 0.5 M FeCl 2 , 3 M NaCl, and 10 mM citric acid (H 3 Cit) remarkably improves the electrochemical behavior of the negative half&#8208;cell. The enhanced performance can be explained as the additive guarantees a low oxygen solution content (reductant agent), promotes the plating/stripping reactions (improving the kinetics of the Fe 0 deposit through the formation of a FeHSO 3 + complex), and diminishes the contribution of the competitive hydrogen evolution reaction. The use of this key additive opens up a promising scenario for the development of A&#8208;IRFBs with significantly enhanced electrochemical performance, thus boosting their potential commercial development.</description>
      <author>A. Concheso, Daniel Barreda, Zoraida Gonz&#225;lez, Patricia &#193;lvarez, Rosa Men&#233;ndez, Clara Blanco, Victoria G. Rocha, Ricardo Santamar&#305;&#769;a</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Solar Transition Region: Effects of Spatial Resolution on
  the Atmospheric Structure, Emission and Non-Equilibrium Ionization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.11237</link>
      <description>Takuma Matsumoto, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406734956

                The solar transition region (TR) is a narrow interface between the chromosphere and corona, where emitted radiation contains critical information pertinent to coronal heating processes. We conducted 2-dimensional radiation magnetohydrodynamics simulations using adaptive mesh refinement to spatially resolve the fine structure of the TR while simultaneously capturing the larger-scale dynamics originating from surface convection. The time evolution of ionization fractions for oxygen ions is computed alongside the simulations. A minimum grid size of 1.25 km is achieved in the TR, enabling adequate resolution of the upper TR (log$_{10}T \gtrsim$ 5), although the lower TR (log$_{10}T \lesssim$ 5) remains under-resolved. Doppler shifts and nonthermal widths synthesized from TR lines exhibit convergence with grid sizes as coarse as 40 km, though some discrepancies persist between our results and observed TR line properties. A notable enhancement in emission from \ion{O}{6} lines, converging at a grid size of 2.5 km, shows an intensity 1.2 times that expected under ionization equilibrium, attributable to shock interactions with the TR. While model refinements are still required, our ability to resolve the TR offers critical insights into TR line characteristics arising from non-equilibrium ionization states, advancing our understanding of the coronal heating problem.</description>
      <author>Takuma Matsumoto</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.11237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photothermal&#8208;Catalyzed Hydrogen Peroxide Production Enabled by Gold&#8208;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420941</link>
      <description>Ping Wu, Fangming Du, Qiang Xue, Hanxi Li, Ming&#8208;Chen Fu, Xukai Zhou, Feng Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406618009

                Abstract Gold catalysts are extensively utilized in photothermal processes that rely on localized surface plasmon resonance effects. However, the development of novel gold(I)&#8208;organic frameworks that function as highly efficient photothermal catalysts for the production of hydrogen peroxide from water and oxygen presents a fascinating and challenging research opportunity. Herein, three gold(I) cyclic trinuclear complexes (Au&#8208;CTCs) based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) are prepared, exhibiting good photothermal conversion efficiency and H 2 O 2 evolution rates. Utilizing the optimized Au&#8208;TFPT, the production rates of H&#8322;O&#8322; can reach as high as 51,987 &#181; m g&#8315;&#185; h&#8315;&#185;, surpassing the performance of most reported metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), even with the use of sacrificial agents to accelerate the reaction. The thermal&#8208;assisted photocatalytic mechanism is comprehensively studied by transient photocurrent response, electrochemical impedance, electron paramagnetic resonance, rotating ring disk electrode test, catalytic performance and among others, demonstrating thermal energy can enhance the mobility of photogenerated carriers and apparent quantum yield, regulate the reactive species ratio and H 2 O 2 selectivity, reduce the apparent activation energy of photocatalysis, and improve mass transfer rates, thereby accelerating the reaction process. This study offers new insights into the thermal&#8208;assisted photocatalytic production of H 2 O 2 .</description>
      <author>Ping Wu, Fangming Du, Qiang Xue, Hanxi Li, Ming&#8208;Chen Fu, Xukai Zhou, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retina-Inspired Flexible Visual Synaptic Device for Dynamic Image Processing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16378</link>
      <description>Yuhang Ji, Meng Yao, Xueli Geng, Jiacheng Sun, Qin Gao, Hao Yin, Juan Gao, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang, Mei Wang, Zhisong Xiao, Yuyan Wang, Anping Huang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406695418

                Exploiting biomimetic perception of invisible spectra in flexible artificial human vision systems (HVSs) is crucial for real-time dynamic information processing. Nevertheless, the fast processing of motion objects in natural environments poses a challenge, necessitating that these artificial HVSs simultaneously have swift photoresponse and nonvolatile memory. Here, inspired by the human retina, we propose a flexible UV neuromorphic visual synaptic device (NeuVSD) based on GaOx@GaN-composited nanowires for dynamic visual perception. Benefiting from the combined action of oxygen adsorption kinetics on the GaOx shell and photoelectronic excitation in the GaN core, the NeuVSD can achieve rapid photoresponse and long-term plasticity simultaneously, a feature that surpasses traditional devices based on persistent photoconductivity mechanisms. Beyond the optoelectronic synaptic plasticity, the flexible NeuVSD on the PET/PI substrate exhibits good performance stability after 1000 bending cycles, profiting from the high adaptability of nanowires. Furthermore, target recognition and motion detection with weak light intensities are achieved through the establishment of neuromorphic visual neural networks, relying on dynamic exposures and edge information processing, respectively. Real-time edge detection can still be realized under a 40% noise factor and effectively remove the noise background. The flexible NeuVSD array-based artificial visual system can enhance the capability of dynamic visual information processing in low-light and high-noise conditions, thereby fostering the evolution of in-sensor computing and artificial intelligence.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Ji, Meng Yao, Xueli Geng, Jiacheng Sun, Qin Gao, Hao Yin, Juan Gao, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang, Mei Wang, Zhisong Xiao, Yuyan Wang, Anping Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MUSE observations of V1425 Aql reveal an arc-shaped nova shell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.09780</link>
      <description>L. Celed&#243;n, C. Tappert, L. Schmidtobreick, F. Selman, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406603723

                Nova shells are the remnants of a nova eruption in a cataclysmic variable system. By studying their geometry we can better understand the physical mechanisms that shape them during the nova eruption. A nova shell that challenges our current understanding of these processes is the shell observed around V1425 Aql. It has at least two different components: an inner and symmetric shell, and an outer and asymmetric shell, with the latter expanding faster than the former. The physical reason behind the asymmetric ejecta is not clear. We aim to characterize the properties and differences between these two components to understand the origin behind the unusual shape. We acquired MUSE data to study the spatial position and kinematics of the expanding gas across the shell. Our analysis includes channel maps, position-velocity diagrams, and the reconstruction of the 3D geometry of the nova shell. Several emission lines are detected within the MUSE wavelength coverage, including but not limited to Balmer, Oxygen, Nitrogen, and Helium lines. There are significant differences in the spectra of the inner and outer shells, with the latter being observed only in forbidden transitions, while the inner shows a mix of forbidden and allowed ones. Our analysis reveals that the outer shell has a geometry consistent with an arc-shaped structure that partially encircles the more spherical inner shell. Within the inner shell, clumpy structures start to be noticeable in the lines of H$\alpha$+[Nii]. We have constrained the geometry of the outer shell to an arc-shaped structure, although the physical reason behind its origin is still eluding us. Further monitoring of the evolution of both shells in this object might help to clarify the mechanism behind this unusual configuration.</description>
      <author>L. Celed&#243;n, C. Tappert, L. Schmidtobreick, F. Selman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.09780</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition and Mineralogical Features of Ultramafic Rocks of Eastern Part of Southern Kraka Massif (South Urals)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18599/grs.2024.4.9</link>
      <description>D. E. Saveliev, Ainur Biembetov, Timur Denisovich Shabutdinov, Aidar Alfridovich Samigullin, Ruslan Azatovich Gataullin, Georesursy. 26(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406600873

                The paper presents new data on the structure and composition of ultramafic rocks in the eastern part of the South Kraka massif. It is shown that the studied area is composed predominantly of spinel peridotites, among which the main role belongs to lherzolites with a low content of clinopyroxene (2&#8211;5%) and harzburgites, among which lens-shaped and bandshaped inclusions of monomineral olivine rocks &#8211; dunites &#8211; are quite often observed. The leading role in the structure of the rocks belongs to high-Mg olivine (Fo 87-94 ), a secondary role (2016). Nature of the lithospheric mantle beneath the Arabian Shield and genesis of Al-spinel micropods: Evidence from the mantle xenoliths of Harrat is played by high-Mg orthopyroxene (enstatite) and Ca-Mg clinopyroxene diopside. Rare minerals of the mantle stage are amphibole and plagioclase. A typical accessory mineral of ultramafic rocks is spinel, the composition of which varies from high-Al in lherzolites (Cr# = 0.16&#8211;0.3), to moderate-Al in harzburgites (Cr# = 0.3&#8211;0.55) and to high-Cr in dunites (Cr# = 0.6&#8211;0.85). Of the rare accessory minerals in the rocks, the following were identified: native copper, pentlandite, awaruite and PGM (laurite, irarsite, Os-Ir-Ru-alloys). The section of mantle ultramafic rocks of the Sargan Range completed its high-temperature evolution to the levels of the plagioclase peridotite facies, partly in the transition zone from spinel to plagioclase facies. An assessment of oxygen fugacity allows us to speak about more reducing conditions for the formation of rocks of the studied area compared to other similar formations of upper mantle origin and allows us to classify the studied ultramafic rocks as moderately depleted restites of the upper mantle under the riftogenic structure of the Paleo-Ural basin. The geochemical specialization of PGM also indicates a restite origin of ultramafic rocks. At the stage of cooling and tectonic transformations in the crust, ultramafic rocks underwent serpentinization.</description>
      <author>D. E. Saveliev, Ainur Biembetov, Timur Denisovich Shabutdinov, Aidar Alfridovich Samigullin, Ruslan Azatovich Gataullin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18599/grs.2024.4.9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REBELS-IFU: Evidence for metal-rich massive galaxies at z~6-8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.10559</link>
      <description>Lucie E. Rowland, Mauro Stefanon, R. J. Bouwens, Jacqueline Hodge, Hiddo Algera, Rebecca Fisher, Pratika Dayal, A. Pallottini, Dan Stark, K. E. Heintz, M. Aravena, R. A. A. Bowler, Karin Cescon, Ryan Endsley, Andrea Ferrara, Valentino Gonz&#225;lez, Luca Graziani, Cindy Gulis, Thomas Herard-Demanche, Hanae Inami, A. Laza-Ramos, Ivana van Leeuwen, I. De Looze, Themiya Nanayakkara, Pascal A. Oesch, Katherine Ormerod, Nina S. Sartorio, Sander Schouws, Renske Smit, Laura Sommovigo, Sune Toft, John R. Weaver, P. van der Werf, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406695599

                Metallicity is a crucial tracer of galaxy evolution, providing insights into gas accretion, star formation, and feedback. At high redshift, these processes reveal how early galaxies assembled and enriched their interstellar medium. In this work, we present rest-frame optical spectroscopy of 12 massive ($\log(M_*/\mathrm{M_{\odot}})&gt;9$) galaxies at $z\sim 6$-$8$ from the REBELS ALMA large program, observed with JWST NIRSpec/IFU in the prism mode. These observations span emission lines from [OII]$\lambda$3727,9 to [SII]$\lambda$6716,31, providing key information on nebular dust attenuation, ionisation states, and chemical abundances. We find lower O32 ratios (average $\sim3.7$) and [OIII]$\lambda$5007 equivalent widths (average ${EW_{[OIII]}}\sim390$\AA) than are generally found in existing large spectroscopic surveys at $z&gt;6$, indicating less extreme ionising conditions. Strong-line diagnostics suggest that these systems are some of the most metal-rich galaxies observed at $z&gt;6$ (average $Z_{\mathrm{gas}}\sim 0.4 Z_{\odot}$), including sources with near-solar oxygen abundances, in line with their high stellar masses (average $\log{M_*/\mathrm{M_{\odot}}}\sim9.5$). Supplementing with literature sources at lower masses, we investigate the mass-metallicity and fundamental metallicity relations (MZR and FMR, respectively) over a 4 dex stellar mass range at $63$ studies.</description>
      <author>Lucie E. Rowland, Mauro Stefanon, R. J. Bouwens, Jacqueline Hodge, Hiddo Algera, Rebecca Fisher, Pratika Dayal, A. Pallottini, Dan Stark, K. E. Heintz, M. Aravena, R. A. A. Bowler, Karin Cescon, Ryan Endsley, Andrea Ferrara, Valentino Gonz&#225;lez, Luca Graziani, Cindy Gulis, Thomas Herard-Demanche, Hanae Inami, A. Laza-Ramos, Ivana van Leeuwen, I. De Looze, Themiya Nanayakkara, Pascal A. Oesch, Katherine Ormerod, Nina S. Sartorio, Sander Schouws, Renske Smit, Laura Sommovigo, Sune Toft, John R. Weaver, P. van der Werf</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.10559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A responsabilidade do estado por danos marinhos em atividades governamentais</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.11606/t.2.2023.tde-23082023-154716</link>
      <description>Marcos Soares Cust&#243;dio, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4406627140

                The role of the State in the exercise of typical state activity in the face of international responsibility and sovereignty.The thesis aims to analyze the theme of international responsibility of the State in the exercise of empire activity.In the work, contextualizes the theme, relating it to the new challenges of DIMA and the protection of the marine environment.Discusses the sea and its importance for life, as a source of food and in the production of spare oxygen, in addition to its use for various human activities, especially in the transport of goods, in general, and oil, to demonstrate the importance of this study.It addresses the sea strips.It is a division for legal purposes, behold, the sea, in the general sense, understand the oceans and seas, is unique, thus only having the objective of establishing territoriality, sovereignty and sovereignty rights.This study is important for a better understanding of the attribution of the international responsibility of the State.Briefly, the territorial sea, the contiguous zone, the exclusive economic zone, the continental shelf, the high sea and the Area are analyzed.Several conventions of importance to the DIMA and to the Law of the Sea are analyzed about their implications to the State when using ships in the exercise of governmental activity or warships.As a rule, the various conventions addressed are important in the protective system of the marine environment, but have reservations regarding the application to warships or that are at the service of the State in carrying out typical activity, constituting true immunity to states when exercising empire activity.Among the conventions analyzed, we highlight the OILPOL Convention, 1954; the Convention on Intervention in the High Seas in Cases of Oil Pollution Casualties, 1969; the International Convention on Civil Liability for Oil Pollution Damage, 1969; the SOLAS Convention, 1974, and the ISPS, IMDG, ISM and HSC Codes; the MARPOL 73/78 Convention and theMontego Bay Convention, among others.Issues related to sovereignty and international accountability are addressed: current studies and projects related to the theme.In relation to sovereignty, the objective is to punctuate its evolution to the current times and the change of its nature, no longer seen as an obstacle to the responsability of the State but as an institute to assign responsibilities.At work, we seek to bring several institutes that can assist in the international responsability of the State more effectively or that there is greater commitment to the protective system of the marine environment, such as cooperation; the possible application of proportionality and reasonableness, although they are institutes of internal law focused on the application of principles of constitutional law; emphasis on the principles of prevention and precaution, as mitigating possible responsability; valuing soft law and sources of international law; a reading of the application of human rights from the perspective of environmental protection and the analysis of rhetoric in DIMA.And, finally, the conclusion whether or not there is the international responsibility of the state for the act of empire.The development of the work will have as main approach method the dialectic, in order to identify possible contradictions between conventions and principles of DIMA.Inductive, deductive, hypothetical-deductive and systemic methods will also be used.</description>
      <author>Marcos Soares Cust&#243;dio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.11606/t.2.2023.tde-23082023-154716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameter optimization of membrane mlectrode assembly in Fuel Cell based on improved differential evolution algorithm: biomechanical stress and strain considerations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62617/mcb1035</link>
      <description>Ting Lu, Yan Liu, Molecular &amp; cellular biomechanics. 22(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406713223

                The membrane electrode assembly in a proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) functions as the electrochemical reaction region, where the generated electric current relies on the diffusion of reactant gases and electron conduction. Drawing inspiration from biomechanics, this study embarked on constructing a database of PEMFC performance data. Similar to how biomechanical studies use advanced imaging and sensing techniques to map the internal workings of organisms, three-dimensional computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations were employed to capture the intricate fluid and gas behaviors within the fuel cell. The data was then used to train data-driven surrogate models based on artificial neural network (ANN) and improved differential evolution for rapid prediction and optimization. When considering the biomechanical aspects, we analyze the mechanical stresses and strains that occur within the membrane electrode assembly during operation. These biomechanical factors can affect the durability and performance of the fuel cell. The gas diffusion layer (GDL) is similar to the pore structure in biological tissues. The pore structure of biological organisms, such as bones, not only ensures the diffusion and transport of nutrients, but also provides space for the attachment of cells to maintain the growth and metabolism of bones. The optimization results revealed that the pores of the GDL, just like the pores of biological tissues, affect the diffusion efficiency of the reactant gases (similar to nutrients) to the catalytic layer, and an appropriate porosity ensures the supply of the reactants required for the electrochemical reactions inside the cell, and improves the PEMFC performance of the cell. By utilizing the random forest algorithm (RF) to conduct feature importance evaluation, we can gain further understanding and interpretation of the factors influencing coupling relationships. The researchers successfully identified the optimal values of GDL porosity and thickness, resulting in an 8.75% increase in power density and significant improvement in oxygen distribution uniformity. To validate the effectiveness and accuracy of the optimization, the optimized structural parameters were incorporated into CFD simulations. The validation results demonstrated close alignment between the optimized model's performance and actual values, confirming the efficacy and reliability of the optimization framework. Overall, this data-driven optimization approach provides an effective tool for multi-variable optimization of complex systems and holds significant importance in enhancing the performance and power density of PEMFC, while also taking into account the biomechanical factors that influence its long-term operation and stability.</description>
      <author>Ting Lu, Yan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62617/mcb1035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12-Hydroxy-Lauric Acid Tethered Self-Assembled Heterochiral Diphenylalanine-Based Mechanoresponsive and Proteolytically Stable Hydrogel: A Dual Player for Handling Cancer and Bacterial Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01438</link>
      <description>Rishabh Ahuja, Manju Singh, Anita DuttKonar, ACS Applied Bio Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406668429

                Deciphering the most promising strategy for the evolution of cancer patient management remains a multifaceted, challenging affair to date. Additionally, such approaches often lead to microbial infections as side effects, probably due to the compromised immunity of the patients undergoing such treatment. Distinctly, this work delineates a rational combinatorial strategy harnessing stereogenic harmony in the diphenylalanine fragment, tethering it to an amphiphile 12-hydroxy-lauric acid at the N-terminus (compounds I-III) such that a potential therapeutic could be extracted out from the series. Aligned to the goal, the cytotoxic properties and cell viability of the compounds were investigated using two distinct cell lines: MCF-7 (human breast cancer cell) and HEK 293 (human embryonic kidney). Our rigorous investigations revealed that compounds I-III exhibited substantial cytotoxic impact on the MCF7 cell line. But from a pool of three constructs, compound III (12-hydroxy-lauric acid -d-Phe-l-Phe-OH) showed better selectivity toward cancerous MCF7 over normal HEK 293 in comparison to others, backed by computational calculations. Henceforth, it was fished out from the series and used for its elaborate anticancer activities using cell reactive oxygen species generation, DNA fragmentation, and caspase-dependent gene expression employing extrinsic and intrinsic apoptotic factors as well as inflammatory biomarkers, namely, TNF-&#945; and IL1-&#946;. We anticipated that compound III, possessing mechanoresponsiveness and a nanofibrillar network, could be administered in patients with injections because of its shear-thinning properties. Moreover, the optimum partition coefficient of compound III might have allowed the scaffold to penetrate the cellular membranes and form a dilactate complex (compound VI) when exposed to the accumulated lactates/lactic acids, a common phenomenon observed within the hypoxic cancerous tumor cores, in accordance with the Warburg mechanism, thereby evading the cytotoxicity within normal cells. Besides, the supramolecular &#946;-sheets of compound III manifest substantial antimicrobial efficacy against the common pathogens, two Gram-positive bacteria, S. aureus and B. subtilis, two Gram-negative bacteria, E. coli and P. aeruginosa, and a fungus, C. albicans, along with proteolytic stability and high mechanical strength at physiological pH. Overall, we speculate that the discovery of these multifunctional bioinspired materials holds future promise as preferential therapeutics for the remediation of immune-susceptible cancer patients, afflicted by microbial infections arising alone or as side effects of chemotherapeutic medications.</description>
      <author>Rishabh Ahuja, Manju Singh, Anita DuttKonar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01438</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
