<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 01:14:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;POM&lt;/scp&gt; &#8208;based Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527842711.ch7</link>
      <description>V&#237;ctor K. Abdelkader&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Pablo Garrido&#8208;Barros, Marta Nunes, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402030693

                Chapter 7 explores the significant impact of polyoxometalates (POMs) on the dynamic field of water oxidation electrocatalysis, also known as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). POMs exhibit fascinating redox properties, diverse compositions and structures and remarkable versatility, making them pivotal players in the advancement of efficient OER electrocatalysts and a key element in the shift towards green energy conversion. This chapter serves as a valuable resource, offering insights into the application of POMs in OER, ranging from mechanistic studies using water-soluble POM platforms to investigations focused on the electrochemical characterization of POM-based nanostructured materials. To facilitate understanding, Chapter 7 is intuitively divided into five main sections. The first section provides an introduction to the fundamental aspects of the OER process, including the description of standard performance indicators. The second section delves into research on pure POMs, exploring their roles in both homogeneous and heterogeneous catalytic systems and paying particular attention to mechanistic aspects. Moving forward, the third section examines the OER electrocatalytic behaviour of various POM-based nanocomposites. These composites involve the integration of diverse POM clusters with other materials, such as nanocarbons, metals, metal (hydro)oxides and metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), in search of synergistic enhancements. In Section 7.4, we showcase highly promising OER electrocatalysts derived from POM-containing precursors. In these cases, the original POM structure is sacrificed to achieve improved dispersion of metals while still maintaining high catalytic activity. Lastly, the concluding remarks summarize the most significant findings and provide an overview of the most effective approaches for synthesizing efficient noble-metal-free electrocatalysts for water oxidation.</description>
      <author>V&#237;ctor K. Abdelkader&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Pablo Garrido&#8208;Barros, Marta Nunes, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527842711.ch7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Strain and Electronic Structure of Indium Tin Oxide Supported IrO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysts for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09431</link>
      <description>Weiwei Han, Xinuo Cai, Jinyun Liao, Yi He, Chunlin Yu, Xingwang Zhang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402031032

                The development of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis is a promising technology for hydrogen production, which has always been restricted by the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Although IrO</description>
      <author>Weiwei Han, Xinuo Cai, Jinyun Liao, Yi He, Chunlin Yu, Xingwang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the electrochemical oxygen evolution performance of CuS by using P element as an anionic dopant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176166</link>
      <description>Xue&#8217;er Ming, Ning Liu, Qi Wang, Lefu Mei, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402036176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue&#8217;er Ming, Ning Liu, Qi Wang, Lefu Mei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectonics of few-layer Ni3Fe nanosheets embedded porous nitrogen-doped carbon derived from asphalt waste: an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176258</link>
      <description>Wenlong Zhao, Huangbin Shangguan, Zhiyi Liu, Jing Lin, Congshu Huang, Hongyi Chen, Xiaoxiao Zhang, Jianzhi Wang, Fa quan Yu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402040351

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenlong Zhao, Huangbin Shangguan, Zhiyi Liu, Jing Lin, Congshu Huang, Hongyi Chen, Xiaoxiao Zhang, Jianzhi Wang, Fa quan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BN Promoted Heterojunction Ni&#9472;Fe&#9472;P/BN Electrocatalyst with Excellent Performance of Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/6072886</link>
      <description>Han Guoqiang, Sheng Wang, Shen Zhao, Wei Wang, Guangwen Xie, Xin Liu, Luhua Jiang, International Journal of Energy Research. 2024(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402050039

                In this research, we have successfully synthesized a Ni&#9472;Fe&#9472;P/h&#8208;BN catalyst through a simple one&#8208;step electrodeposition method for efficient water splitting in a KOH electrolytic cell. Our prepared Ni&#9472;Fe&#9472;P/h&#8208;BN catalyst showcased exceptional electrocatalytic activity for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), with an overpotential of only 210 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 . Notably, this value is significantly lower compared to 248 mV observed for Ni&#9472;Fe&#9472;P/Fe without h&#8208;BN and also superior to the results reported for other catalysts. Furthermore, through the ball milling, we further enhanced the OER performance of the catalyst, achieving an impressive overpotential of 200 mV at the same density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . The exceptional OER performance displayed by the Ni&#9472;Fe&#9472;P/h&#8208;BN composite is attributable to the synergistic effects of Ni&#9472;Fe&#9472;P and h&#8208;BN. Furthermore, the introduction of a heterojunction between h&#8208;BN and Ni&#9472;Fe&#9472;P serves to further enhance the OER capability of the catalyst. This investigation introduces a straightforward and effective approach for fabricating cost&#8208;effective and high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts intended for water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Han Guoqiang, Sheng Wang, Shen Zhao, Wei Wang, Guangwen Xie, Xin Liu, Luhua Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/6072886</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;Electrodes by Tailored Conditioning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400318</link>
      <description>Clara Gohlke, Julia Gallenberger, Nico Niederpr&#252;m, Hannah Ingendae, J&#252;rgen KAUTZ, Jan P. Hofmann, Anna K. Mechler, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402055136

                Abstract To meet the rising demand for green hydrogen, efficient alkaline water electrolysis demands highly active and low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We address this issue by focusing our work on optimizing the conditioning of promising Ni&#8208;(Fe)&#8208;based electrodes to improve their electrocatalytic performances. Systematic parameter variation for cyclic voltammetry conditioning revealed that a large potential window, low scan rate, and a high number of cycles result in improved activation. If the conditioning time is fixed, a high scan rate was found beneficial. A remarkable 47&#177;6 mV potential drop at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 was achieved for Ni 70 Fe 30 when conditioning between &#8722;0.35&#8211;1.6 V at 100 mV s &#8722;1 for just 30 min. We could demonstrate that this activation persisted over 100 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , underscoring its enduring efficacy. We suggest that this activation effect results from the growth of a hydrous hydroxide layer, which is supported by energy dispersive X&#8208;ray spectroscopy and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Fe incorporation or dissolution played only a minor role in the differences in electrode activation, as demonstrated by variation of the Fe content in the electrolyte. Our work stresses the importance of conditioning in enhancing OER performance and explores how to improve the catalysts&#8242; effectiveness by tailoring oxides.</description>
      <author>Clara Gohlke, Julia Gallenberger, Nico Niederpr&#252;m, Hannah Ingendae, J&#252;rgen KAUTZ, Jan P. Hofmann, Anna K. Mechler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the Precursor Metal Salt on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction for NiFe Oxide Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400151</link>
      <description>A. Zuber, Ilias M. Oikonomou, Lee Gannon, I. I. Chunin, L.A. Reith, Berrin Zeliha Can, Mailis Lounasvuori, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Cormac McGuinness, Prashanth W. Menezes, Valeria Nicolosi, Michelle P. Browne, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402055549

                Abstract Bimetallic nickel&#8208;iron based oxides are regarded as one of the most promising catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, we show that the precursor metal salts can affect the OER activity of the resulting Ni/Fe oxide under the same hydrothermal synthesis conditions. Pure sulfate, pure nitrate and mixed sulfate/nitrate metal salts were used to fabricate NiFe based oxide materials and to study the importance of the precursor choice for the OER. The results show that the nature of the precursor used in the synthesis of the bimetallic nickel&#8208;iron materials can influence different multi&#8208;phase catalysts to form which effects the OER.</description>
      <author>A. Zuber, Ilias M. Oikonomou, Lee Gannon, I. I. Chunin, L.A. Reith, Berrin Zeliha Can, Mailis Lounasvuori, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Cormac McGuinness, Prashanth W. Menezes, Valeria Nicolosi, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo&#8208;induced Intercalation of Cobalt(II) Tellurium Oxide as an Oxygen Evolution (Photo)electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400047</link>
      <description>R. J. Kriek, Oluwaseun A. Oyetade, Nyengerai Zingwe, Emanuela Carleschi, B. P. Doyle, Jaco Koch, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402055885

                Abstract Herein, we report on (a) the application of cobalt(II) tellurium oxide (Co 3 TeO 6 ) as a photo&#8208;electrocatalyst, to enhance the photo&#8208;electrocatalytic (PEC) oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, compared to the electrocatalytic (EC) OER (in the absence of light), and (b) to store charge upon illumination and release charge upon the termination of illumination under OER potential bias conditions. These nanomaterials were synthesized employing the sol&#8208;gel method and calcined at temperatures ranging from 400 to 1100 &#176;C. They were physically characterized and tested for their capacity to (i) act as a catalyst towards the OER, under EC and PEC conditions, and (ii) to convert and store light&#8208;energy as chemical&#8208;energy. Under PEC conditions CTO&#8208;900, which predominantly consisted of Co 3 TeO 6 , exhibited a five&#8208;fold increase in activity compared to EC conditions as current density increased from 0.58 mA cm &#8722;2 (EC) to 3.10 mA cm &#8722;2 (PEC) at 1.8 V ( vs . RHE). Additionally, CTO&#8208;900 displayed the ability to not only store charge (upon illumination), but to also release this stored charge (after the termination of illumination), realising a current density of 2.07 mA cm &#8722;2 in the dark (under OER potential bias conditions). Photo&#8208;induced charge storage is due to the intercalation of potassium ions into Co 3 TeO 6 .</description>
      <author>R. J. Kriek, Oluwaseun A. Oyetade, Nyengerai Zingwe, Emanuela Carleschi, B. P. Doyle, Jaco Koch</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Textured RuIrAgMnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxides With Preferentially Orientated (110) Facet by Concerted Shaping of Ag and Mn for Stable Acid Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411766</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Yanhui Sun, Feng Liu, Jun Gan, Shixin Gao, Jingjun Liu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402068872

                Abstract Entropy&#8208;based polymetallic oxides with configurational entropy, structure flexibility, and crystallographic orientation have been regarded as promising catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), due to their electronic energy band occupation, composition ligand stabilization, and &#8220;cocktail&#8221; effect. Herein, a rutile RuIrAgMnO 2 oxide with an orientation along the (110) facets is first fabricated by a low&#8208;temperature directional co&#8208;pyrolysis strategy of metal salts on Ti foil at 300 &#176;C. The quaternary oxide exhibits a texture coefficient of 1.13 along (110) facet, resulting from concerted shaping of Ag and Mn components presenting a vibrational entropy of 1.13 R (R is the gas content). In 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 , it displays an overpotential of 171 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER, running at a voltage for 340 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . The remarkably improved performance can be associated with the presence of the preferred (110) facets with in&#8208;plane strains, which activate and stabilize OER process via electronic energy band reconstruction. More interestingly, the preferential orientation prevents the diffusion or dissolution of active metal ions caused by entropy&#8208;dependent energy barriers, ensuring long&#8208;term stability. This work can pave the way for entropy&#8208;driven polymetallic oxides with optimal structures, disrupting the trade&#8208;off between activity and stability in water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Yanhui Sun, Feng Liu, Jun Gan, Shixin Gao, Jingjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record-breaking bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst accomplished by a data-driven approach for zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.040</link>
      <description>Deviprasath Chinnadurai, Zhi Wei Seh, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402071756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deviprasath Chinnadurai, Zhi Wei Seh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MnS doping regulating Co active sites on fibrous cobalt nitride as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for high-performance Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176153</link>
      <description>Xinmeng Yu, Xiaorong Chen, Dandan Yue, Fenghua Zheng, Qingyu Li, Zhaoling Ma, Hongqiang Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402072787

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinmeng Yu, Xiaorong Chen, Dandan Yue, Fenghua Zheng, Qingyu Li, Zhaoling Ma, Hongqiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium Promotes Phase Transformation to Active Oxyhydroxide for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03974</link>
      <description>Yong Wang, Sijia Liu, Yunpu Qin, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Jianfang Liu, Yadong Liu, Aimin Chu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079069

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for renewable energy technologies like metal&#8211;air batteries and water splitting. However, it suffers from sluggish kinetics, necessitating a high-activity and stable catalyst. In this study, we used Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations to demonstrate that Cr doping favors the phase transition of metal (Fe, Co, Ni) hydroxide to the active phase oxyhydroxide. We synthesized FeCoNiCr hydroxide using an aqueous sol&#8211;gel method, ensuring that the four elements Fe, Co, Ni, and Cr are uniformly distributed at the atomic level. As an OER catalyst, FeCoNiCr hydroxide exhibits a very low overpotential of 224 mV in alkaline media, which is 52 mV lower than that of FeCoNi hydroxide, placing it among the best nonprecious metal catalysts reported so far. Additionally, it demonstrates long-term catalytic stability of 150 h. An assembled Zn-Air battery with FeCoNiCr hydroxides was cycled stably for 160 h with a low discharge/charge voltage difference of 0.70 V. DFT calculations and microkinetic modeling demonstrated that Cr doping significantly optimized the adsorption energies of OER intermediates at the Ni and Co sites, thereby enhancing overall OER activity. Bader charge calculations further revealed that Ni and Co in the catalysts consistently maintained a +3 valence throughout the OER process, which is beneficial for OER catalysis.</description>
      <author>Yong Wang, Sijia Liu, Yunpu Qin, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Jianfang Liu, Yadong Liu, Aimin Chu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing the structural evolution of cobalt hydroxide in electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc03173c</link>
      <description>Chun-Lei Yang, Tingyu Lu, Liming Zhang, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079593

                Transition-metal hydroxides are a category of earth-abundant and stable electrocatalysts for energy storage and conversion devices involving sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Understanding dynamic evolution at the solid/liquid interface of...</description>
      <author>Chun-Lei Yang, Tingyu Lu, Liming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc03173c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the evolution of interfacial species via B, N-codoped Pt sites for oxygen reduction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155311</link>
      <description>Baojie Li, Wanlin Zhou, Xuan Sun, Qian Zhang, Qian Zhang, Jianglong Guo, Jingjing Jiang, Qizheng An, Shuowen Bo, Jing Wang, Qinghua Liu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402080095

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baojie Li, Wanlin Zhou, Xuan Sun, Qian Zhang, Qian Zhang, Jianglong Guo, Jingjing Jiang, Qizheng An, Shuowen Bo, Jing Wang, Qinghua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155311</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum triggers the bifunctional mechanism of oxygen evolution reaction of Fe34-xNi25Co25MoxB8P8amorphous alloy with boosted catalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118612</link>
      <description>Yong Wu, Xiaolong Guo, Chen Hong-guo, Yuci Xin, Xing&#8217;an Dong, Xiaolin Hu, L. Xia, Peng Yu, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402082543

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Wu, Xiaolong Guo, Chen Hong-guo, Yuci Xin, Xing&#8217;an Dong, Xiaolin Hu, L. Xia, Peng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfate modified Fe(OH)x/NF nanosheets with oxygen vacancies for enhanced oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.457</link>
      <description>Xiaoping Zhang, Guodong Shi, Yuanyuan Li, Yanzhi Bai, Chao Wang, Junwen Si, Liya Zhu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402092633

                The development of cost-effective and high-performance electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) would be beneficial to future renewable energy storage. Herein, sulfate modified Fe(OH)x nanosheets grown on nickel foam (S&#8211;Fe(OH)x/NF) with rich undercoordinated atom centers and oxygen vacancies were fabricated through a facile hydrothermal method. The optimal sample S2&#8211;Fe(OH)x/NF exhibits outstanding OER activity with an ultralow overpotential of 261 mV to obtain a current density of 200 mA cm&#8722;2. The impressive catalytic activity is primarily attributed to the introduction of the undercoordinated atom (Fe) center, which offer rich active sites, as well as the creation of oxygen vacancies (Vo) that enhance the electron density and the intrinsic conductivity. This work opens up an in-depth understanding of transition metal oxides for OER mechanism by sulfate-decorated and a new prospect for designing highly efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaoping Zhang, Guodong Shi, Yuanyuan Li, Yanzhi Bai, Chao Wang, Junwen Si, Liya Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Engineering Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis in Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401186</link>
      <description>Le Li, Meisheng Han, Penggang Zhang, Donglei Yang, Meng Zhang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402096056

                Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as one of the most promising candidates for oxygen electrocatalysis due to their maximized atom utilization efficiency, high intrinsic activity, and strong metal&#8208;support interaction. Significant progress has been made in engineering Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C SACs for oxygen electrocatalysis in Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). This review provides a comprehensive overview of the recent advancements in Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C SACs, with a special focus on effective engineering strategies, their performance in oxygen electrocatalysis, and their potential applications in ZABs. The review also discusses the key challenges and future directions in the development of Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C SACs for efficient and durable oxygen electrocatalysis in ZABs. This review aims to offer valuable insights into the current state of research in this field and to guide future efforts in the development of advanced oxygen electrocatalysts for ZABs.</description>
      <author>Le Li, Meisheng Han, Penggang Zhang, Donglei Yang, Meng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of S-doped CuCoO2 nanosheets with more oxygen defects for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03425b</link>
      <description>Chao Jiang, Jilin Bai, Qian Shen, Xin Ku, Wei Wang, Dehua Xiong, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402119955

                Noble metal catalysts are excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, but the expensive price and scarce reserves constrain the development of water splitting. CuCoO2 is known as a promising catalytic...</description>
      <author>Chao Jiang, Jilin Bai, Qian Shen, Xin Ku, Wei Wang, Dehua Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03425b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancies and interfacial engineering of RuO2/CeO2-NC heterojunction for pH-universal hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.436</link>
      <description>Jiansheng Wu, Ying Chang, Shaohong Guo, Aiju Xu, Jingchun Jia, Meilin Jia, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402120271

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiansheng Wu, Ying Chang, Shaohong Guo, Aiju Xu, Jingchun Jia, Meilin Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible noble-metal-free Fe-based metallic glasses as highly efficient oxygen evolution electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnoncrysol.2024.123208</link>
      <description>Ye Yue, Dongpeng Wang, Meng Han, Mengwei Du, Yingchun Lin, Zhenzhen Dong, Yan Zhang, Yuxin Wang, Journal of Non-Crystalline Solids. 646(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402121730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ye Yue, Dongpeng Wang, Meng Han, Mengwei Du, Yingchun Lin, Zhenzhen Dong, Yan Zhang, Yuxin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnoncrysol.2024.123208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An efficient electrode for reversible oxygen reduction/evolution and ethylene electro-production on protonic ceramic electrochemical cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.09.001</link>
      <description>Yangsen Xu, Kang Xu, Hua Zhang, Feng Zhu, Fan He, Meilin Liu, Yu Chen, Science Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402125602

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yangsen Xu, Kang Xu, Hua Zhang, Feng Zhu, Fan He, Meilin Liu, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scib.2024.09.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of carbon dots supported on Zr-MOFs nano-composites for effective oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111559</link>
      <description>Muhammad Yousaf Ur Rehman, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Sidra Nayer, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Norah Salem Alsaiari, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Adeel Hussain Chughtai, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402126069

                Efficient hydrogen generation from water splitting is a key component of the hydrogen economy. It has been extensively researched for decades how electrochemically splitting water using electrocatalysts might provide a sustainable and environmentally friendly hydrogen energy source. Sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) hinders the process of overall water splitting. Although metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) are attractive for generation of effective OER electrocatalysts, their activity is significantly hindered by their inherent lower conductivity. Here, we demonstrate a Zr-MOF-based composite with carbon dots (CDs) in order to increase their OER activity. Its exceptional morphology with higher porosity and greater surface area results in enhanced electrochemical activity. It reveals tremendously low onset potential, i.e., 1.40 V vs. RHE, and a remarkably small overpotential of 1.45 V vs. RHE to attain benchmark current density. It exhibited a minimal Tafel value of 37 mV/dec, conquering state-of-the-art catalysts for OER. The fabricated electrocatalyst demonstrated a lower charge transfer resistance (Rct) of 0.248 &#937;, with exceptional durability for about 20 h in chronoamperometric studies and for up to 1500 CV cycles. All these results demonstrated that as-fabricated Zr-MOF-based composite is a probable and potential candidate for OER.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Yousaf Ur Rehman, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Sidra Nayer, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Norah Salem Alsaiari, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Adeel Hussain Chughtai, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction enhancing electrochemical performance of V-doped Ni(OH)2 for aqueous asymmetric supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155429</link>
      <description>Ting Xiao, Hongxiang Lin, Tang Can, Xiuru Li, Yuting Mei, Gao Lin, Lihua Jiang, Peng Xiang, Shibing Ni, Yequan Xiao, Xinyu Tan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402126165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Xiao, Hongxiang Lin, Tang Can, Xiuru Li, Yuting Mei, Gao Lin, Lihua Jiang, Peng Xiang, Shibing Ni, Yequan Xiao, Xinyu Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying the dynamic behaviors in complete reconstruction of Co-based complex precatalysts during electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.043</link>
      <description>Jingfang Zhang, Xizhen Zhang, Linke Cai, Youluan Lu, F.T. Cheng, Lijuan Shi, Qun Yi, Yao Liu, Yi Huang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402126300

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingfang Zhang, Xizhen Zhang, Linke Cai, Youluan Lu, F.T. Cheng, Lijuan Shi, Qun Yi, Yao Liu, Yi Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Surface Reconstruction and Lattice Oxygen Mechanism of Nickel (Oxy)Hydroxide by Defect Engineering for Industrial Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4943880</link>
      <description>Xiangling Wang, Zhimin Li, Yu Tang, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Xiaoxue Li, Jingsong Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402126978

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangling Wang, Zhimin Li, Yu Tang, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Xiaoxue Li, Jingsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4943880</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Investigation of the Interface between Transition Metal Oxides (MnOx, FeOx, CoOx and NiOx)/MoO3 Composite Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12090241</link>
      <description>Karmegam Dhanabalan, Mrunal Bhosale, Ganesan Sriram, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, Tae Hwan Oh, Inorganics. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402129670

                This study presents the synthesis of a multicomponent metal oxide electrocatalyst that increases the activity of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We synthesized transition metal oxides (MnOx, FeOx, CoOx, and NiOx) with MoO3 heterostructures through a solid-state reaction approach at low cost. In comparison to the other compositions, CoOx garnered higher attention and demonstrated superior performance on account of its large surface area and varied crystal facets. The MnOx-MoO3, FeOx-MoO3, CoOx-MoO3, and NiOx-MoO3 compositions attained an overpotential of 390 mV, 350 mV, 310 mV, and 340 mV, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline solution. The performance of OER was enhanced in CoOx-MoO3 at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, while FeOx-MoO3 exhibited a lower current density at 100 mA cm&#8722;2 than other metal oxides. The CoOx-MoO3 material exhibited a favorable crystal interface transition due to the presence of MoO3 oxide. For the first time, we report on the MoO3-to-(MnOx, FeOx, CoOx, and NiOx) interface crystal transition and the active surface area for OER catalytic activity in water-splitting processes. This investigation intends to develop an electrocatalyst that is capable of producing hydrogen with the use of heterostructure metal oxides.</description>
      <author>Karmegam Dhanabalan, Mrunal Bhosale, Ganesan Sriram, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, Tae Hwan Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12090241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of active redox sites and charge transport resistance at reaction potentials in spinel ferrites for improved oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118613</link>
      <description>Subir Roy, Chandraraj Alex, N.K. Muhammed Safeer, Abhijit Paul, Neena S. John, S. Angappane, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402129849

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subir Roy, Chandraraj Alex, N.K. Muhammed Safeer, Abhijit Paul, Neena S. John, S. Angappane</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Design of Aligned&#8208;Channel Porous Carbon Electrodes for Efficient High&#8208;Current&#8208;Density Gas&#8208;Evolving Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409292</link>
      <description>Zhichao Gong, Pin Chen, Haisheng Gong, Kang Huang, Gonglan Ye, Huilong Fei, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402135037

                Abstract Gas&#8208;evolving reactions (GERs) are important in many electrochemical energy conversion technologies and chemical industries. The operation of GERs at high current densities is critical for their industrial implementation but remains challenging as it poses stringent requirements on the electrodes in terms of reaction kinetics, mass transfer, and electron transport. Here the general and rational design of self&#8208;standing carbon electrodes with vertically aligned porous channels, appropriate pore size distribution, and high surface area as supports for loading a variety of catalytic species by facile electrodeposition are reported. These electrodes simultaneously possess high intrinsic activity, large numbers of active sites, and efficient transport highways for ions, gases, and electrons, resulting in significant performance improvements at high current densities in diverse GERs such as urea oxidation, hydrogen evolution, and oxygen evolution reactions, as well as overall urea/water electrolyzers. As an example, the carbon electrode decorated with Ni(OH) 2 demonstrates a record&#8208;high current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.360 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode, largely outperforming the conventional nickel foam&#8208;based counterpart and the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art electrodes.</description>
      <author>Zhichao Gong, Pin Chen, Haisheng Gong, Kang Huang, Gonglan Ye, Huilong Fei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of high performance SnFe2O4@PANI electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evaluation Reaction (OER) by hydrothermal method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06495-6</link>
      <description>Mukhtiar Hussain, Abdelaziz Gassoumi, I. A. Weinstein, A. Kahshan, Khursheed Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402138242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukhtiar Hussain, Abdelaziz Gassoumi, I. A. Weinstein, A. Kahshan, Khursheed Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06495-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Feature: Effect of the Precursor Metal Salt on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction for NiFe Oxide Materials (ChemElectroChem 17/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202481702</link>
      <description>A. Zuber, Ilias M. Oikonomou, Lee Gannon, I. I. Chunin, L.A. Reith, Berrin Zeliha Can, Mailis Lounasvuori, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Cormac McGuinness, Prashanth W. Menezes, Valeria Nicolosi, Michelle P. Browne, ChemElectroChem. 11(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402139084

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Zuber, Ilias M. Oikonomou, Lee Gannon, I. I. Chunin, L.A. Reith, Berrin Zeliha Can, Mailis Lounasvuori, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Cormac McGuinness, Prashanth W. Menezes, Valeria Nicolosi, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202481702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe-(Oxy)Hydroxide@Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Core&#8211;Shell Nanorods on Nickel Foam for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03363</link>
      <description>Zhuo-Lin Qing, Hao Hu, Jianli Mi, Feihong Qi, Jun-Lin Li, Jidong Song, Beibei Xiao, Yang&#8208;Chun Yong, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402139368

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuo-Lin Qing, Hao Hu, Jianli Mi, Feihong Qi, Jun-Lin Li, Jidong Song, Beibei Xiao, Yang&#8208;Chun Yong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma&#8208;Induced Oxygen Defect Engineering in Perovskite Oxide for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404239</link>
      <description>Kaiteng Wang, Jun Zhou, Lei Fu, Yunqing Kang, Zilin Zhou, Zhengdong Wang, Kai Wu, Yusuke Yamauchi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402146252

                Abstract Perovskite oxides are considered highly promising candidates for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts due to their low cost and adaptable electronic structure. However, modulating the electronic structure of catalysts without altering their nanomorphology is crucial for understanding the structure&#8208;property relationship. In this study, a simple plasma bombardment strategy is developed to optimize the catalytic activity of perovskite oxides. Experimental characterization of plasma&#8208;treated LaCo 0.9 Fe 0.1 O 3 (P&#8208;LCFO) reveals abundant oxygen vacancies, which expose numerous active sites. Additionally, X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure analyses indicate a low Co valence state in P&#8208;LCFO, likely due to the presence of these oxygen vacancies, which contributes to an optimized electronic structure that enhances OER performance. Consequently, P&#8208;LCFO exhibits significantly improved OER catalytic activity, with a low overpotential of 294 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , outperforming commercial RuO 2 . This work underscores the benefits of plasma engineering for studying structure&#8208;property relationships and developing highly active perovskite oxide catalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Kaiteng Wang, Jun Zhou, Lei Fu, Yunqing Kang, Zilin Zhou, Zhengdong Wang, Kai Wu, Yusuke Yamauchi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tethering Cobalt Ions to BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Surface via Robust Organic Bifunctional Linker for Efficient Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403336</link>
      <description>Tahir Naveed Jahangir, Tauqir Ahmed, Nisar Ullah, Tarek A. Kandiel, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402147252

                In the quest for efficient and stable oxygen evolution catalysts (OECs) for photoelectrochemical water splitting, the surface modification of BiVO</description>
      <author>Tahir Naveed Jahangir, Tauqir Ahmed, Nisar Ullah, Tarek A. Kandiel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Carrier Oxygen Vacancies to Enhance Strong Oxide&#8208;Support Interaction in IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5&#8208;x&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for Promoting Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410193</link>
      <description>Yun Wu, Chuanming Guo, Rui Yao, Kaiyang Zhang, Jinping Li, Guang Liu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402148430

                Abstract Given the pronounced dissolution of electrocatalysts in acidic environments, the quest for effective oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts suitable for proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolyzers persists as a formidable challenge. In this investigation, catalysts are synthesized by creating oxygen vacancies within various metal oxides (Nb 2 O 5&#8208;x , Ta 2 O 5&#8208;x , ZrO 2&#8208;x , TiO 2&#8208;x ) through plasma&#8208;assisted method, thereby facilitating the immobilization of IrO 2 onto these defect&#8208;rich surfaces. The findings unveil that IrO 2 /Nb 2 O 5&#8208;x manifests reduced overpotentials during acidic OER, achieving an overpotential down to 225 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 , coupled with outstanding durability at multicurrent densities exceeding 200 h, attributed to strong oxide&#8208;support interaction (SOSI) between the IrO 2 catalyst and Nb 2 O 5&#8208;x substrate. Density functional theory (DFT) computations uncover intensified binding affinities between IrO 2 and Nb 2 O 5&#8208;x , thus modulating the central energy levels of Ir's d orbitals toward favorable OER conditions, consequently bolstering the electrocatalytic activity and stability of the composite catalyst. Furthermore, employing IrO 2 /Nb 2 O 5&#8208;x as a PEM electrolyzer anode enables consistent operation at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for 200 h, with an Ir content of only 0.2852 mg cm &#8722;2 and an energy consumption of 4.34 kWh Nm &#8722;3 H 2 . This achievement substantially lowers the cost of hydrogen production to US$ 0.96 per kilogram, underscoring its potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Yun Wu, Chuanming Guo, Rui Yao, Kaiyang Zhang, Jinping Li, Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a</link>
      <description>Sana Ullah, Abbas N. Hussain, Muhammad Asim Farid, Shaheen Irfan, Roohul Amin, Ahmed M. Fouda, Atif Nazir, Dehua Hou, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Shangfeng Du, Muhammad Tahir, RSC Advances. 14(38)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402148836

                The development of efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER) is pivotal for advancing cleaner and sustainable fuel production technologies.</description>
      <author>Sana Ullah, Abbas N. Hussain, Muhammad Asim Farid, Shaheen Irfan, Roohul Amin, Ahmed M. Fouda, Atif Nazir, Dehua Hou, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Shangfeng Du, Muhammad Tahir</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Production of Silicon Using Oxygen-Evolving Sno2 Anode in Molten Cacl2-Nacl</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4942638</link>
      <description>Sai Krishna Padamata, Gu&#240;r&#250;n S&#230;varsd&#243;ttir, Geir Martin Haarberg, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402163034

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sai Krishna Padamata, Gu&#240;r&#250;n S&#230;varsd&#243;ttir, Geir Martin Haarberg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4942638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decorated and reconstructed perovskite-oxide electrodes for oxygen electrocatalysis and Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.002</link>
      <description>Guichan Chen, Jiapeng Liu, Dengjie Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402163900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guichan Chen, Jiapeng Liu, Dengjie Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Catalysts: Exploring Discharge Product Growth and Intrinsic Overpotential in Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00789</link>
      <description>Zhengxuan Yin, Chuying Ouyang, Neil Qiang Su, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402167300

                The lithium&#8211;oxygen (Li&#8211;O2) battery, renowned for its exceptionally high theoretical energy density, is poised to revolutionize next-generation energy storage systems. However, its practical application depends on overcoming several challenges, particularly the high cathode overpotential, which significantly diminishes the battery's energy efficiency and durability. This study delves into the interactions at the cathode surface during oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER), extending the analysis beyond the initial reaction stages to encompass the extensive charge&#8211;discharge process. We introduce and define the concepts of intrinsic equilibrium potential and intrinsic overpotential, demonstrating that these critical parameters are predominantly influenced by the growth of discharge products, rather than the catalysts, thereby underscoring the inherent properties of the battery. This shift in focus from merely enhancing cathode catalysts to understanding and leveraging the intrinsic characteristics of the battery discharge process opens new avenues for optimizing and enhancing the performance of large-scale Li&#8211;O2 batteries. Furthermore, our findings indicate potential broader applications to other metal&#8211;oxygen systems, paving the way for the design of high-capacity, high-efficiency energy storage technologies.</description>
      <author>Zhengxuan Yin, Chuying Ouyang, Neil Qiang Su</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Compositions and Nanostructures of Trimetallic Prussian Blue Analog&#8208;Derived Carbides for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402916</link>
      <description>Lujiao Mao, Jie Liu, Rong Lin, Jinhang Xue, Yuandong Yang, Shaojie Xu, Qipeng Li, Jinjie Qian, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402168383

                Abstract The electrochemical splitting of water for hydrogen production faces a major challenge due to its anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), necessitating research on the rational design and facile synthesis of OER catalysts to enhance catalytic activity and stability. This study proposes a ligand&#8208;induced MOF&#8208;on&#8208;MOF approach to fabricate various trimetallic MnFeCo&#8208;based Prussian blue analog (PBA) nanostructures. The addition of [Fe(CN) 6 ] 3&#8722; transforms them from cuboids with protruding corners (MnFeCoPBA&#8208;I) to core&#8211;shell configurations (MnFeCoPBA&#8208;II), and finally to hollow structures (MnFeCoPBA&#8208;III). After pyrolysis at 800 &#176;C, they are converted into corresponding PBA&#8208;derived carbon nanomaterials, featuring uniformly dispersed Mn 2 Co 2 C nanoparticles. A comparative analysis demonstrates that the Fe addition enhances catalytic activity, while Mn&#8208;doped materials exhibit excellent stability. Specifically, the optimized MnFeCoNC&#8208;I&#8208;800 demonstrates outstanding OER performance in 1.0 m KOH solution, with an overpotential of 318 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , maintaining stability for up to 150 h. Theoretical calculations elucidate synergistic interactions between Fe dopants and the Mn 2 Co 2 C matrix, reducing barriers for oxygen intermediates and improving intrinsic OER activity. These findings offer valuable insights into the structure&#8208;morphology relationships of MOF precursors, advancing the development of highly active and stable MOF&#8208;derived OER catalysts for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Lujiao Mao, Jie Liu, Rong Lin, Jinhang Xue, Yuandong Yang, Shaojie Xu, Qipeng Li, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Polarization of Ni Sites at VO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&#8722;Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N Interface Boosts Ethanol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407473</link>
      <description>Min Zhou, Biao Jin, Weijie Kong, Anjie Chen, Yuhe Chen, Qian Zhang, Fei Lu, Xi Wang, Xianghua Zeng, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402170349

                Abstract Substituting thermodynamically favorable ethanol oxidation reaction (EOR) for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) engenders high&#8208;efficiency hydrogen production and generates high value&#8208;added products as well. However, the main obstacles have been the low activity and the absence of an explicit catalytic mechanism. Herein, a heterostructure composed of amorphous vanadium oxide and crystalline nickel nitride (VO x &#8722;Ni 3 N) is developed. The heterostructure immensely boosts the EOR process, achieving the current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 at the low potential of 1.38 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), far surpassing the sluggish OER (1.65 V vs RHE). Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy indicates that the as&#8208;fabricated heterostructure can promote the adsorption of OH &#8722; and the generation of the reactive species (O * ). Theoretical calculations further outline the dual polarization of the Ni site at the interface, specifically the asymmetric charge redistribution (interfacial polarization) and in&#8208;plane polarization. Consequently, the dual polarization modulates the d&#8208;band center, which in turn regulates the adsorption/desorption strength of key reaction intermediates, thereby facilitating the entire EOR process. Moreover, a VO x &#8722;Ni 3 N&#8208;based electrolyzer, coupling hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and EOR, attains 50 mA cm &#8722;2 at a low cell voltage of &#8776;1.5 V. This work thus paves the way for creating dual polarization through interface engineering toward broad catalysis.</description>
      <author>Min Zhou, Biao Jin, Weijie Kong, Anjie Chen, Yuhe Chen, Qian Zhang, Fei Lu, Xi Wang, Xianghua Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Properties Correlations on Nickel&#8208;Iron Oxide Catalysts Deposited by Atomic Layer Deposition for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400091</link>
      <description>Estelle Jozwiak, M. Piccinini, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Nicola Pinna, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402171208

                Thermal atomic layer deposition (ALD) is used for the first time to deposit iron&#8208;nickel oxides onto carbon nanotubes in a ternary process to produce a wide range of mixed oxide thin films. When using ferrocene (FeCp 2 ) and nickelocene (NiCp 2 ) with ozone (O 3 ) as metals and oxygen sources, respectively, a competition between the metal precursors and the growth modes is observed. Indeed, while ferrocene promotes a 2D&#8208;growth, nickelocene prefers a 3D&#8208;growth. Although both precursors are homoleptic metallocenes, they behave differently in the ALD of their respective metal oxide, leading to unexpected atomic ratios and films morphologies of the iron&#8208;nickel oxides. The 2Fe:1Ni sample displays the best performances in the electrochemical water oxidation (oxygen evolution reaction) exhibiting an overpotential of 267 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;1 , a Tafel slope of 36.8 mV dec &#8722;1 , as well as a good stability after 15 h of continuous operation.</description>
      <author>Estelle Jozwiak, M. Piccinini, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Nicola Pinna</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction Regulation of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N Through Heterostructure Engineering Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406465</link>
      <description>Ye Zeng, Jiaxian Zheng, Heru Zhang, Fen Yao, Dingrong Deng, Qi&#8208;Hui Wu, Peter R. Makgwane, Hanfeng Liang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402171405

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts generally experience structural and electronic modifications during electrocatalysis. This phenomenon, referred to as surface reconstruction, results in the formation of catalytically active species that act as real OER sites. Controlling surface reconstruction therefore is vital for enhancing the OER performance of electrocatalysts. In this study, a new approach is introduced of heterostructure engineering to facilitate the surface reconstruction of target catalysts. Using MnCo carbonate hydroxide (MnCo&#9472;CH)@Co 3 N as a demonstration, it is discovered that the surface reconstruction occurs more readily and rapidly on MnCo&#9472;CH@Co 3 N than on Co 3 N. More interestingly, during the reconstruction process, Mn species migrate to the surface, enabling the in situ formation of highly active Mn&#8208;doped CoOOH. Consequently, the MnCo&#9472;CH@Co 3 N catalyst after reconstruction exhibits a low overpotential of 257 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , compared to 379 mV of individual Co 3 N. This work offers fresh perspectives on understanding the enhanced OER performance of heterostructure electrocatalysts and the role of heterostructure in promoting surface reconstruction.</description>
      <author>Ye Zeng, Jiaxian Zheng, Heru Zhang, Fen Yao, Dingrong Deng, Qi&#8208;Hui Wu, Peter R. Makgwane, Hanfeng Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically Created Active Centers in a Bimetallic CoNi&#8208;Triazole Metal&#8208;Organic Framework for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400423</link>
      <description>Natchaya Phongsuk, Kanyaporn Adpakpang, Ladawan Pukdeejorhor, Thassanant Atithep, Panyapat Ponchai, ChemPlusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402194337

                Electrochemical water oxidation utilizing bimetallic CoNi&#8208;Tz (Tz = 1,2,4&#8208;triazole) framework is explored. Initially, CoNi&#8208;Tz possesses active tetrahedral Co center and electron&#8208;mediated octahedral Ni chain. After performing an electrochemical activation, the partial structural transformation on the Ni center occurs. This leads to the generation of excessive active centers which can promote catalytic activity of the framework. The activated CoNi&#8208;Tz catalyst displays a remarkably low OER overpotential of 293 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 with a small Tafel slope of 49.98 mV dec&#8208;1, outperforming the single metal Co&#8208;Tz and benchmark IrO2 catalysts.</description>
      <author>Natchaya Phongsuk, Kanyaporn Adpakpang, Ladawan Pukdeejorhor, Thassanant Atithep, Panyapat Ponchai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of SnWO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;, SnW&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;, and WO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Phases in Tin Tungstate Films on Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09713</link>
      <description>Farabi Bozheyev, Steffen Fengler, Jiri Kollmann, Daniel Abou&#8208;Ras, Nico Scharnagl, Mauricio Schieda, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402198323

                An essential step toward enabling the production of renewable and cost-efficient fuels is an improved understanding of the performance of energy conversion materials. In recent years, there has been growing interest in ternary metal oxides. Particularly, &#945;-SnWO4 exhibited promising properties for application to photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting. However, the number of corresponding studies remains limited, and a deeper understanding of the physical and chemical processes in &#945;-SnWO4 is necessary. To date, charge-carrier generation, separation, and transfer have not been exhaustively studied for SnWO4-based photoelectrodes. All of these processes depend on the phase composition, not only &#945;-SnWO4 but also on the related phases SnW3O9 and WO3, as well as on their spatial distributions resulting from the coating synthesis. In the present work, these processes in different phases of tin tungstate films were investigated by transient surface photovoltage (TSPV) spectroscopy to complement the analysis of the applicability of &#945;-SnWO4 thin films for practical PEC oxygen evolution. Pure &#945;-SnWO4 films exhibit higher photoactivities than those of films containing secondary SnW3O9 and WO3 phases due to the higher recombination of charge carriers when these phases are present.</description>
      <author>Farabi Bozheyev, Steffen Fengler, Jiri Kollmann, Daniel Abou&#8208;Ras, Nico Scharnagl, Mauricio Schieda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09713</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Decorated 3D Architectures Built from Nickel Carbonate Hydroxide Nanostructured Spheres as Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03651</link>
      <description>Jun Huang, Weiqiang Hao, Junwei Liu, Shunhong Chen, Xiaonan Liu, Wuyun Zhao, Xiaoqiang Wu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402198754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Huang, Weiqiang Hao, Junwei Liu, Shunhong Chen, Xiaonan Liu, Wuyun Zhao, Xiaoqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ti3C2 Quantum Dots-Modified Oxygen-Vacancy-Rich BiOBr Hollow Microspheres Toward Optimized Photocatalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143255</link>
      <description>Tao Cheng, Zipeng Xing, Qian Zhang, Peng Sun, Hui Peng, Zhenzi Li, Li Wang, Wei Zhou, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402199407

                The Ti3C2 quantum dots (QDs)/oxygen-vacancy-rich BiOBr hollow microspheres composite photocatalyst was prepared using solvothermal synthesis and electrostatic self-assembly techniques. Together, Ti3C2QDs and oxygen vacancies (OVs) enhanced photocatalytic activity by broadening light absorption and improving charge transfer and separation processes, resulting in a significant performance boost. Meanwhile, the photocatalytic efficiency of Ti3C2 QDs/BiOBr-OVs is assessed to investigate its capability for oxygen evolution and degradation of tetracycline (TC) and Rhodamine B (RhB) under visible-light conditions. The rate of oxygen production is observed to be 5.1 times higher than that of pure BiOBr-OVs, while the photocatalytic degradation rates for TC and RhB is up to 97.27% and 99.8%, respectively. The synergistic effect between Ti3C2QDs and OVs greatly enhances charge separation, leading to remarkable photocatalytic activity. Furthermore, the hollow microsphere contributes to the enhanced photocatalytic performance by facilitating multiple light scatterings and providing ample surface-active sites. The resultant Ti3C2QDs/BiOBr-OVs composite photocatalyst demonstrates significant potential for environmental applications.</description>
      <author>Tao Cheng, Zipeng Xing, Qian Zhang, Peng Sun, Hui Peng, Zhenzi Li, Li Wang, Wei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of Zeolitic Imidazolate Framework-L and Application of Its Derivatives in Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Recent Trends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176293</link>
      <description>Peng Shi, Sheng Wang, Sheng Wang, Xuefei Lei, Biao Wang, Xuanwen Liu, Junhua You, Rui Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402204521

                Electrochemical water splitting is a sustainable method to address current energy and climate issues. A significant number of research efforts are focused on the development of low-cost, high-efficiency, and high-durability water oxidation half-reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. Materials based on metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) possess porous structures and highly tunable compositions, making them a promising electrode material. As a subfamily of MOFs, Zeolitic Imidazolate Frameworks (ZIFs) have become promising electrode materials due to their porous morphologies and highly tunable compositions. ZIF-L, a member of the ZIF family, not only possesses many characteristics of MOFs but also has a unique 2D morphology, making it an ideal precursor material. However, there are few targeted reports on the application of ZIF-L and its derivatives in OER. In this review, we will focus on the structure, morphology, and phase transitions of ZIF-L, and summarize the applications and modification methods of ZIF-L in the OER field. Finally, we emphasize the development potential and future challenges of ZIF-L-derived electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Peng Shi, Sheng Wang, Sheng Wang, Xuefei Lei, Biao Wang, Xuanwen Liu, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile strategy for synthesis of flower-like FeNiS2 nanocomposite via integration of binary metal-organic framework and metal sulfide for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105049</link>
      <description>Hamideh Imanzadeh, Alireza Khataee, Mehran Nozari-Asbemarz, James J. Leahy, Mandana Amiri, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402205968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hamideh Imanzadeh, Alireza Khataee, Mehran Nozari-Asbemarz, James J. Leahy, Mandana Amiri</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A one-stone-three-birds strategy to construct Mo-FeS2/Ni3S2@C electrocatalyst with strong interfacial coupling effect to achieve efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161147</link>
      <description>Enhong Liu, Haoran Guo, Yanyan Li, Jiayang Zhao, Rui Song, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402206154

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enhong Liu, Haoran Guo, Yanyan Li, Jiayang Zhao, Rui Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Design Strategy for Highly Active Oxide Electrocatalysts by Incorporation of Oxygen&#8208;Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403415</link>
      <description>Narayan Acharya, Surendra B. Karki, Livia Giordano, Farshid Ramezanipour, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402207368

                Using both density functional theory (DFT+U) simulations and experiments, we show that the incorporation of an ordered array of oxygen-vacancies in a perovskite oxide can lead to enhancement of the electrocatalytic activity for the oxygen-evolution reaction (OER). As a benchmark, LaCoO</description>
      <author>Narayan Acharya, Surendra B. Karki, Livia Giordano, Farshid Ramezanipour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic micro-environment regulation of ZIF-67 with broadened pore structure and unsaturated coordination sites for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.368</link>
      <description>Lingxiang Liu, Li Wang, Shasha Cui, T. Li, Xiaomeng Yang, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402208249

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingxiang Liu, Li Wang, Shasha Cui, T. Li, Xiaomeng Yang, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction on AU Decorated Ni(Oh)2 Nanostructures: The Role of Alkaline Cations Solvation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4947018</link>
      <description>Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi, Gustavo Sampaio De Oliveira-Filho, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Lucas D. Germano, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402210293

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi, Gustavo Sampaio De Oliveira-Filho, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Lucas D. Germano</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4947018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-Induced Strain Effect to Synthesize an Iron-Doped Orthogonal Cobalt Selenide Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02522</link>
      <description>Yunhua Zheng, Huiting Hu, Qian Long, Yao Zhu, Tao Zhang, Dongya Yang, Fengxian Qiu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402220204

                The etching effect has the capability to control atom doping and trigger phase transformation, thereby enhancing the electrocatalytic reaction. Herein, iron-doped cobalt selenide (Fe-CoSe</description>
      <author>Yunhua Zheng, Huiting Hu, Qian Long, Yao Zhu, Tao Zhang, Dongya Yang, Fengxian Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Reconstruction on Coooh Active Species and Oxygen Evolution Performance for Co9s8/Cu2s Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4946707</link>
      <description>Fan He, Jing Wen, Ting Zhang, Yanyan Wang, Dongmei Zeng, Minmin Zou, You Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402225828

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan He, Jing Wen, Ting Zhang, Yanyan Wang, Dongmei Zeng, Minmin Zou, You Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4946707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectonics of Fe-Doped Ni3S2 Arrays on Ni Foam from MOF Precursors for Promoted Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14171445</link>
      <description>Jingchao Zhang, Yingping Bu, Zhuoyan Li, Ting Yang, Na Zhao, Guanghui Wu, Fujing Zhao, Ren&#8208;Chun Zhang, Daojun Zhang, Nanomaterials. 14(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402226563

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical half-reaction in electrochemical overall water splitting and metal&#8211;air battery fields; however, the exploitation of the high activity of non-noble metal electrocatalysts to promote the intrinsic slow kinetics of OER is a vital and urgent research topic. Herein, Fe-doped Ni3S2 arrays were derived from MOF precursors and directly grown on nickel foam via the traditional solvothermal way. The arrays integrated into nickel foam can be used as self-supported electrodes directly without any adhesive. Due to the synergistic effect of Fe and Ni elements in the Ni3S2 structure, the optimized Fe2.3%-Ni3S2/NF electrode delivers excellent OER activity in an alkaline medium. The optimized electrode only requires a small overpotential of 233 mV to reach the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and the catalytic activity of the electrode can surpass several related electrodes reported in the literature. In addition, the long-term stability of the Fe2.3%-Ni3S2/NF electrode showed no significant attenuation after 12 h of testing at a current density of 50 mA cm&#8722;2. The introduction of Fe ions could modulate the electrical conductivity and morphology of the Ni3S2 structure and thus provide a high electrochemically active area, fast reaction sites, and charge transfer rate for OER activity.</description>
      <author>Jingchao Zhang, Yingping Bu, Zhuoyan Li, Ting Yang, Na Zhao, Guanghui Wu, Fujing Zhao, Ren&#8208;Chun Zhang, Daojun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14171445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen&#8208;doped FeP on Ti Foil with Ti3O Interlayer for Efficient and Durable Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400649</link>
      <description>Yanqi Yuan, Boan Zhong, Li Wang, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Liyuan Han, Yan&#8208;Ting Sun, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402228720

                The development of electrocatalysts with low cost, high efficiency, and long&#8208;term durability is crucial for advancing green hydrogen production. Transition metal phosphides (TMPs) have been proved to be efficient electrocatalyst, while the improvement in the performance and durability of the TMPs remains a big challenge. Employing atmospheric pressure chemical vapor deposition (APCVD) and phosphorization, FeP/Ti electrodes are fabricated featuring controllable oxygen ingredients (O&#8208;FeP/Ti). This manipulation of oxygen content fine&#8208;tunes the electronic structure of the catalyst, resulting in improved surface reaction kinetics and catalytic activity. The optimized O&#8208;FeP&#8208;400/Ti exhibits outstanding HER activity with overpotentials of 142 and 159 mV at &#8208;10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and 1 M KOH, respectively. Notably, the obtained O&#8208;FeP/Ti cathode also displays remarkable durability of up to 200 h in acidic electrolyte with surface topography remaining intact. For the first time, the low&#8208;valence titanium oxide (Ti3O) interlayer is identified in the composite electrode and ascribed for the superior connection between Ti substrate and the surface O&#8208;FeP catalyst, as supported by experimental results and density functional theory (DFT) analysis. This work has expanded the potential applications of transition metal phosphides (TMPs) as a cost&#8208;effective, highly efficient and durable catalyst for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yanqi Yuan, Boan Zhong, Li Wang, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Liyuan Han, Yan&#8208;Ting Sun, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PTFE as a Multifunctional Binder for High&#8208;Current&#8208;Density Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408544</link>
      <description>Bohan Deng, He Xian, Peng Du, Wei Zhao, Yuanzheng Long, Zhuting Zhang, Hongyi Liu, Kai Huang, Hui Wu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402232469

                Abstract Binder plays a crucial role in constructing high&#8208;performance electrodes for water electrolysis. While most research has been focused on advancing electrocatalysts, the application of binders in electrode design has yet to be fully explored. Herein, the in situ incorporation of polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) as a multifunctional binder, which increases electrochemical active sites, enhances mass transfer, and strengthens the mechanical and chemical robustness of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrodes, is reported. The NiFe&#8208;LDH@PTFE/NF electrode prepared by co&#8208;deposition of PTFE with NiFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide onto nickel foam demonstrates exceptional long&#8208;term stability with a minimal potential decay rate of 0.034 mV h &#8722;1 at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for 1000 h. The alkaline water electrolyzer utilizing NiFe&#8208;LDH@PTFE/NF requires only 1.584 V at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 and sustains high energy efficiency over 1000 h under industrial operating conditions. This work opens a new path for stabilizing active sites to obtain durable electrodes for OER as well as other electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Bohan Deng, He Xian, Peng Du, Wei Zhao, Yuanzheng Long, Zhuting Zhang, Hongyi Liu, Kai Huang, Hui Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Surface Chemistry in 2D Layered BiOI by Facile Liquid&#8208;Phase Exfoliation for Enhanced Photoelectrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400275</link>
      <description>Mengjiao Wang, Jaime Gallego, Micaela Pozzati, Teresa Gatti, Small Structures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402233598

                BiOI is a promising photoelectrocatalyst for oxidation reactions. However, the limited photoelectrocatalytic (PEC) activity necessitates the development of new strategies to modify its surface chemistry and thus enhance functional properties. Herein, we present a simple method to increase photocurrent in a BiOI&#8208;based photoanode by exfoliating microspheres of the oxyhalide produced through hydrothermal synthesis. Following exfoliation in isopropanol, the resulting layered BiOI&#8208;based colloid contains a greater variety of species, including Bi 2 O 2 CO 3 , I 3 &#8722; , IO 3 &#8722; , Bi 5+ , and hydroxides, compared to the original BiOI. These additional species do not directly enhance the PEC oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Instead, they are consumed or converted during PEC OER, resulting in more active sites on the photoelectrode and reduced resistance, which ultimately improves the water oxidation performance of the exfoliated BiOI. Over long&#8208;term chronoamperometry, the exfoliated BiOI demonstrates a photocurrent twice as high as that of the BiOI microspheres. Analysis of the species after PEC OER reveals that the combination of IO 3 &#8722; , Bi 5+ , and I 3 &#8722; species on the BiOI is beneficial for charge transfer, thus enhancing the intrinsic PEC properties of the BiOI. This study offers new insights into the role of surface chemistry in determining PEC performance, aiding the optimization of 2D materials&#8208;based photoelectrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Mengjiao Wang, Jaime Gallego, Micaela Pozzati, Teresa Gatti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Asymmetrical Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se Bonds in Fe2O(SeO3)2 Boosting Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalytic Performance for Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412025</link>
      <description>Huimin Xu, Kaihang Yue, Lijun Song, Hongcheng Zhang, Hongrui Zhu, Zhijie Zhang, Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402244961

                Here Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC catalysts with high performance were fabricated for zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). The experimental results confirmed that the existence of Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se bonds in Fe2O(SeO3)2 crystal phase, and the Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se bonds could obviously enhance ORR and OER catalytic performance of Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC. Density functional theoretical calculations (DFT) confirmed that the Fe2O(SeO3)2 in Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC had a higher d&#8208;band center of Fe atom and a lower p&#8208;orbital coupling degree with its own lattice O atom than Fe2O3, which leads to Fe site of Fe2O(SeO3)2 being more likely to adsorb external oxygen intermediates. The Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se bonds in Fe2O(SeO3)2 results in the modification of coordination environment of Fe atoms and optimizes the adsorption energy of Fe site for oxygen intermediates. Compared with Fe2O3/Fe3C@NC, the Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC showed obvious enhancements of ORR/OER catalytic activities with a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.91 V for ORR in 0.1 M KOH electrolyte and a low overpotential of 345 mV for OER at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in a 1.0 M KOH electrolyte. The peak power density and specific capacity of Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC&#8208;based ZABs are higher than those of Pt/C+RuO2&#8208;ZABs. The above results demonstrate that the asymmetrical Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se bonds in Fe2O(SeO3)2 plays a key role in improving the bifunctional catalytic activities of ORR/OER for ZABs.</description>
      <author>Huimin Xu, Kaihang Yue, Lijun Song, Hongcheng Zhang, Hongrui Zhu, Zhijie Zhang, Gao&#8208;Ren Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen reduction reaction coupled electro&#8208;oxidation for highly&#8208;efficient and sustainable water treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414481</link>
      <description>Ran Xiao, Hehe Qin, Xiangyun Liu, Chengcheng Chu, Qiuju Li, Hongying Zhao, Shun Mao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402253229

                Electro-oxidation (EO) technology demonstrates significant potential in wastewater treatment. However, the high energy consumption has become a pivotal constraint hindering its large-scale implementation. Herein, we design an EO and 4-electron oxygen reduction reaction coupled system (EO-4eORR) to replace the traditional EO and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) coupled system (EO-HER). The theoretical cathodic potential of the electrolytic reactor is tuned from 0 V (vs. RHE) in HER to 1.23 V (vs. RHE) in 4eORR, which greatly decreases the required operation voltage of the reactor. Moreover, we demonstrate that convection can improve the mass transfer of oxygen and organic pollutants in the reaction system, leading to low cathodic polarization and high pollutant removal rate. Compared with traditional EO-HER system, the energy consumption of the EO-4eORR system under air aeration for 95% total organic carbon (TOC) removal is greatly decreased to 2.61 kWh/kgTOC (only consider the electrolyzer energy consumption), which is superior to previously reported EO-based water treatment systems. The reported results in this study offer a new technical mode for development of highly efficient and sustainable EO-based treatment systems to remove organic pollutants in waste water.</description>
      <author>Ran Xiao, Hehe Qin, Xiangyun Liu, Chengcheng Chu, Qiuju Li, Hongying Zhao, Shun Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Lamination Structure of Graphdiyne/Nickel Sulfide for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31635/ccschem.024.202404426</link>
      <description>Jinze Li, Yurui Xue, Xuchen Zheng, Han Wu, Yang Gao, Yuliang Li, CCS Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402260974

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinze Li, Yurui Xue, Xuchen Zheng, Han Wu, Yang Gao, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31635/ccschem.024.202404426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Engineering of Crystalline/Amorphous CoP/FeCoP&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoarrays for Efficient Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401139</link>
      <description>Jinyang Zhang, Yujing Zhang, Jiayi Zhou, Haoran Guo, Limin Qi, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402270534

                Abstract The development of bifunctional, non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) through morphology and electronic engineering is highly attractive for efficient water splitting. Herein, hierarchical nanoarrays consisting of crystalline cobalt phosphide nanorods covered by amorphous Fe&#8208;doped cobalt phosphide nanocuboids (CoP/FeCoP x ) are constructed as bifunctional catalysts for both HER and OER. Experimental results and theoretical calculations reveal that the catalysts exhibit balanced dual&#8208;catalytic properties due to simultaneous introduction of Fe doping and phosphorus vacancies, leading to an optimized electronic structure of the CoP/FeCoP x . Furthermore, the hierarchical nanoarrays made of crystalline/amorphous heterostructures significantly enhance the performance of the electrocatalysts. As a result, the CoP/FeCoP x catalyst demonstrates remarkable performance in both HER and OER, with overpotentials of 74 and 237 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH, respectively, as well as a low cell voltage of 1.53 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for alkaline overall water splitting. This work integrates the morphology engineering involving design of hierarchical crystalline/amorphous nanoarrays and the electronic engineering through Fe doping and phosphorus vacancies for efficient water electrolysis. It may open a new route toward rational design and feasible fabrication of high&#8208;performance, multifunctional, non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts for energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Jinyang Zhang, Yujing Zhang, Jiayi Zhou, Haoran Guo, Limin Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Promotion of Fe in Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst on Charge Transfer for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404060</link>
      <description>Weichao Li, Xiaolu Xiong, Jinxiao Gao, Yue Hu, Qun Yang, Dehua Zheng, Jingxuan Hao, Xiao Lin, Linjuan Zhang, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402270578

                Abstract In recent years, catalysts based on transition metal sulfides have garnered extensive attention due to their low cost and excellent electrocatalytic activity in the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction. Here, the preparation of Fe&#8208;doped Ni 3 S 2 via a one&#8208;step hydrothermal approach is reported by utilizing inexpensive transition metals Ni and Fe. In an alkaline medium, Fe&#8211;Ni 3 S 2 exhibits outstanding electrocatalytic activity and stability for the OER, and the current density can reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with an overpotential of 163 mV. In addition, Pt/C||Fe&#8211;Ni 3 S 2 is used as the membrane electrode of the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer, which is capable of providing a current density of 650 mA cm &#8722;2 at a cell voltage of 2.0 V, outperforming the benchmark Ir/C. The principle is revealed that the doping of Fe enhances the electrocatalytic water decomposition ability of Ni 3 S 2 by in situ Raman and in situ X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure. The results indicate that the doping of Fe decreases the charge density near Ni atoms, which renders Fe&#8211;Ni 3 S 2 more favorable for the adsorption of OH &#8722; and the formation of * OO &#8722; intermediates. This work puts forward an effective strategy to significantly improve both the alkaline OER activity and stability of low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Weichao Li, Xiaolu Xiong, Jinxiao Gao, Yue Hu, Qun Yang, Dehua Zheng, Jingxuan Hao, Xiao Lin, Linjuan Zhang, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of trimetallic metal-organic framework nanoarrays for efficient and stable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.005</link>
      <description>Guohao Na, Yuewen Wu, Zi Mei, Mingpeng Chen, Dequan Li, Huachuan Sun, Yun Chen, Taigang Zhou, Jian-Hong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Jin Zhang, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Qingju Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402274031

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guohao Na, Yuewen Wu, Zi Mei, Mingpeng Chen, Dequan Li, Huachuan Sun, Yun Chen, Taigang Zhou, Jian-Hong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Jin Zhang, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Er-Doping Enhances the Oxygen Evolution Performance of Cobalt Oxide in Acidic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03088</link>
      <description>San-Jiang Pan, Hang Li, Sheng Wang, Yang Fu, Shenao Wang, Zhong&#8208;Yang Xie, Li Wei, Hao Li, Nan Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402274848

                No abstract</description>
      <author>San-Jiang Pan, Hang Li, Sheng Wang, Yang Fu, Shenao Wang, Zhong&#8208;Yang Xie, Li Wei, Hao Li, Nan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full&#8208;Spectrum Light&#8208;Harvesting Solar Thermal Electrocatalyst Boosts Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412049</link>
      <description>Dehui Deng, Mengxuan Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402277278

                Enabling high&#8208;efficiency solar thermal conversion (STC) at catalytic active site is critical but challenging for harnessing solar energy to boost catalytic reactions. Herein, we report the direct integration of full&#8208;spectrum STC and high electrocatalytic oxygen evolution activity by fabricating a hierarchical nanocage architecture composed of graphene&#8208;encapsulated CoNi nanoparticle. This catalyst exhibits a near&#8208;complete 98% absorptivity of solar spectrum and a high STC efficiency of 97%, which is superior than previous solar thermal catalytic materials. It delivers a remarkable potential decrease of over 240 mV at various current densities for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution under solar illumination, which is practically unachievable via traditionally heating the system. The high&#8208;efficiency STC is enabled by a synergy between the regulated electronic structure of graphene via CoNi&#8208;carbon interaction and the multiple absorption of lights by the light&#8208;trapping nanocage. Theoretical calculations suggest that high temperature&#8208;induced vibrational free energy gain promotes the potential&#8208;limiting O* to OOH* step, which decreases the overpotential for oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Dehui Deng, Mengxuan Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full&#8208;Spectrum Light&#8208;Harvesting Solar Thermal Electrocatalyst Boosts Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412049</link>
      <description>Dehui Deng, Mingxia Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402277700

                Enabling high&#8208;efficiency solar thermal conversion (STC) at catalytic active site is critical but challenging for harnessing solar energy to boost catalytic reactions. Herein, we report the direct integration of full&#8208;spectrum STC and high electrocatalytic oxygen evolution activity by fabricating a hierarchical nanocage architecture composed of graphene&#8208;encapsulated CoNi nanoparticle. This catalyst exhibits a near&#8208;complete 98% absorptivity of solar spectrum and a high STC efficiency of 97%, which is superior than previous solar thermal catalytic materials. It delivers a remarkable potential decrease of over 240 mV at various current densities for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution under solar illumination, which is practically unachievable via traditionally heating the system. The high&#8208;efficiency STC is enabled by a synergy between the regulated electronic structure of graphene via CoNi&#8208;carbon interaction and the multiple absorption of lights by the light&#8208;trapping nanocage. Theoretical calculations suggest that high temperature&#8208;induced vibrational free energy gain promotes the potential&#8208;limiting O* to OOH* step, which decreases the overpotential for oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Dehui Deng, Mingxia Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Long&#8208;Range Disordering RuO2 Catalyst for Highly Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411603</link>
      <description>Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Manxiao Cheng, Xuewen Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402287090

                Non&#8208;iridium acid&#8208;stabilized electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial to reducing the cost of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). Here, we report a strategy to modulate the stability of RuO2 by doping boron (B) atoms, leading to the preparation of a RuO2 catalyst with long&#8208;range disorder (LD&#8208;B/RuO2). The structure of long&#8208;range disorder endowed LD&#8208;B/RuO2 with a low overpotential of 175 mV and an ultra&#8208;long stability, which can maintain OER for about 1.6 months at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 current density in 0.5 M H2SO4 with almost invariable performance. More importantly, a PEM electrolyzer using LD&#8208;B/RuO2 as the anode demonstrated excellent performance, reaching 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 at 1.63 V with durability exceeding 300 h at 250 mA cm&#8722;2 current density. The introduction of B atoms induced the formation of a long&#8208;range disordered structure and symmetry&#8208;breaking B&#8208;Ru&#8208;O motifs, which enabled the catalyst structure to a certain toughness while simultaneously inducing the redistribution of electrons on the active center Ru, which jointly promoted and guaranteed the activity and long&#8208;term stability of LD&#8208;B/RuO2. This study provides a strategy to prepare long&#8208;range disordered RuO2 acidic OER catalysts with high stability using B&#8208;doping to perturb crystallinity, which opens potential possibilities for non&#8208;iridium&#8208;based PEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Manxiao Cheng, Xuewen Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unusual photosynthetic oxygen evolution. I. Cerulenin-induced 3-(3,4-dichlorophenyl)-1,1-dimethylurea insensitive oxygen evolution in Chlorella pyrenoidosa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00633-0</link>
      <description>E. Lehoczki, Yu. Zeinalov, No host. 7(3)] 1984. https://openalex.org/W4402036701

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. Lehoczki, Yu. Zeinalov</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1984 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00633-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopic and functional characterization of a highly oxygen evolving Photosystem II reaction center complex from spinach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00383-0</link>
      <description>Lars&#8208;Gunnar Franz&#233;n, Stenbj&#246;rn Styring, Anne&#8208;Lise Etienne, &#214;rjan Hansson, Claudie Vemotte, No host. 13(1-2)] 1986. https://openalex.org/W4402037545

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lars&#8208;Gunnar Franz&#233;n, Stenbj&#246;rn Styring, Anne&#8208;Lise Etienne, &#214;rjan Hansson, Claudie Vemotte</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 1986 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00383-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of electron transport in oxygen evolving Photosystem II complexes from a thermophilic cyanobacterium Synechococcus sp.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00630-5</link>
      <description>G&#252;nther H. Schatz, H. T. Witt, No host. 7(2)] 1984. https://openalex.org/W4402037726

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G&#252;nther H. Schatz, H. T. Witt</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 1984 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00630-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fractionation of an oxygen-evolving Photosystem II preparation: characterization of the light-harvesting antennae and reaction center components</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00629-9</link>
      <description>Eric Lam, Barbara G. Baltimore, William Ortiz, Richard Malkin, No host. 7(2)] 1984. https://openalex.org/W4402037878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eric Lam, Barbara G. Baltimore, William Ortiz, Richard Malkin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 1984 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00629-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESR oxymetry: measurement of photosynthetic oxygen evolution by spin-probe technique</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00352-0</link>
      <description>Kazimierz Strza&#322;ka, Tadeusz Sama, James S. Hyde, No host. 12(1-2)] 1986. https://openalex.org/W4402200352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kazimierz Strza&#322;ka, Tadeusz Sama, James S. Hyde</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 1986 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00352-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuO/Co3O4 heterojunctions for catalytic nitroarenes reduction and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113106</link>
      <description>K. Arathi, K.L. Nagashree, Madhuri P. Rao, Kalyan Raj, P. Shivakumar, D. H. Nagaraju, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402280371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Arathi, K.L. Nagashree, Madhuri P. Rao, Kalyan Raj, P. Shivakumar, D. H. Nagaraju</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of CoFe2O4 decorated on polyaniline for optimizing oxygen evolution process in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41779-024-01082-y</link>
      <description>Zeid A. ALOthman, Suryyia Manzoor, Jafar Hussain Shah, S. Noor Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem, Journal of the Australian Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402054979

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeid A. ALOthman, Suryyia Manzoor, Jafar Hussain Shah, S. Noor Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41779-024-01082-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Analysis of Pristine and Microwave-Irradiated Czts Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4943979</link>
      <description>R. Manigandan, S. Aravindhan, S. Srinivasan, S. Ashok, Vattikondala Ganesh, L. J. Rao, D. Amaranatha Reddy, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402131494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R. Manigandan, S. Aravindhan, S. Srinivasan, S. Ashok, Vattikondala Ganesh, L. J. Rao, D. Amaranatha Reddy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4943979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Engineering of Non&#8208;van der Waals 2D Magnetene for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401157</link>
      <description>Pedro Guerra Demingos, Zhiwen Chen, Xiang Ni, Chandra Veer Singh, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402035785

                Non-van der Waals two-dimensional materials containing exposed transition metal atoms are promising catalysts for green energy storage and conversion. For instance, hematene and ilmenene have been successfully applied as catalysts. Building on these reports, this work is the first investigation of recently synthesized magnetene towards the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) and Oxygen Reduction Reaction (ORR). Using Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations, we unveil the mechanism, performance and ideal conditions for OER and ORR on magnetene. With overpotentials of &#951;OER = 0.50 V and &#951;ORR = 0.41 V, the material is not only a bifunctional catalyst, but also superior to state-of-the-art systems such as Pt and IrO2. Additionally, its catalytic properties can be further enhanced through engineering strategies such as point defects and in-plane compression. It reaches &#951;ORR = 0.28 V at a compressive strain of only 2%, while the presence of Ni boosts it to &#951;OER = 0.39 V and &#951;ORR = 0.31 V, comparable to many reported single-atom catalysts. Overall, this work demonstrates that magnetene is a promising bifunctional catalyst for applications such as regenerative fuel cells and metal-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Pedro Guerra Demingos, Zhiwen Chen, Xiang Ni, Chandra Veer Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Oxygen Evolution Kinetics via Sulfur/Phosphorus Dynamic Migration Induced Surface Enrichment in an Anion-Regulated Iron Selenide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01867b</link>
      <description>Bezawit Z. Desalegan, Reibelle Q. Raguindin, Guiwen Jiang, Hyung&#8208;Ho Park, Jeong Gil Seo, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402127480

                Optimizing the energetics of the elementary steps of Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) by tuning the electrode-intermediate/product interaction through d-band center energy tailoring is an essential yet under-explored concept in oxygen...</description>
      <author>Bezawit Z. Desalegan, Reibelle Q. Raguindin, Guiwen Jiang, Hyung&#8208;Ho Park, Jeong Gil Seo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01867b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microscopic Insight into the Polarization-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Reaction on the Surface of Intrinsic Ferroelectric Semiconductor &#946;-CuGaO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02073</link>
      <description>Donghao Lu, Lanlan Xu, Jiarong Dai, Xuemeng Guo, Qiang Shi, Xiaojuan Liu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402271746

                Ferroelectric semiconductors hold great promise in the field of photocatalysis due to their spontaneous polarization that can suppress the recombination of photogenerated charges, but the mechanism of the effect of ferroelectric polarization and the intensity of polarization on surface catalytic reactions have never been approached. Here, we have comparatively investigated the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic process on surfaces in polarized and unpolarized orientations of the intrinsic ferroelectric semiconductor &#946;-CuGaO</description>
      <author>Donghao Lu, Lanlan Xu, Jiarong Dai, Xuemeng Guo, Qiang Shi, Xiaojuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Performance of In-Situ Grown Carbon Nanomaterials &amp;amp; Fe/Al 2 O 3 Composites for Oxygen Evolution Reactioncatalytic Performance of In-Situ Grown Carbon Nanomaterials &amp;amp; Fe/Al 2 O 3 Composites for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4943980</link>
      <description>Li Tan, Qiuxia Liu, Min Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402126927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Tan, Qiuxia Liu, Min Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4943980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porphyrin-linked Graphdiyne as the substrate for constructing Single-atom Catalyst with transition metal towards Oxygen reduction reaction and Oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d</link>
      <description>Jiejie Ping, Mei Wu, Manyu Liu, Yan Jiang, Wenhui Shang, Menggai Jiao, John J. Ruan, Sheng Wang, Zhiyu Jia, Materials Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402094747

                Porphyrin-linked graphdiyne (PGDY) is a carbon-based material provides a platform for anchoring single-atom catalysts (SACs) with transition metals (TM). These SACs have the potential to boost the catalytic activity of...</description>
      <author>Jiejie Ping, Mei Wu, Manyu Liu, Yan Jiang, Wenhui Shang, Menggai Jiao, John J. Ruan, Sheng Wang, Zhiyu Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-templated fabrication of P-doped CoMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; hollow nanocages for the efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03347g</link>
      <description>Wenxiang Jia, Qian Lu, Tian Tian, Guoxiang Pan, Rui Tan, Bin He, Jiang Liu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402242814

                Finding reservoir-rich and e&#64259;cient electrocatalysts for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for further sustainable energy development. Despite the advantages of high earth abundance, easy availability, and tunable composition,...</description>
      <author>Wenxiang Jia, Qian Lu, Tian Tian, Guoxiang Pan, Rui Tan, Bin He, Jiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03347g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni Surface &amp;amp; Polyacryloyl Hydrazide Mediated Growth of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@NiCu Alloy Nanocuboids for Effective Methanol Oxidation and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400372</link>
      <description>Sunil Semwal, Aiswarya Samal, Saroj K. Nayak, Rajashri Urkude, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, Umaprasana Ojha, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402281514

                Abstract Strategies to control the size, shape, and lattice arrangement, introduce doping agents, and induce heterostructuring in electrocatalysts are strongly desirable to tailor their activities. Herewith, a one&#8208;pot strategy utilizing polyacryloyl hydrazide (PAHz) as the composition directing agent and metallic Ni surface as the shape directing agent is employed to grow Co 3 O 4 doped NiCu alloy nanocuboids on Ni foam (NF) under hydrothermal conditions for electrocatalytic H 2 production. The resulting bi&#8208;functional electrodes are suitable for methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) coupled green H 2 production with effective energy efficiency. The low overall potential (MOR+HER) of 1.78 V to realize the current density ( j ) value of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and extended durability (100 h@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) along with the selective conversion of methanol to formate support the viability of the NF&#8208;PAHz&#8208;Co 3 O 4 @NiCu for the said operation. The electrode also displays efficacy toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and j OER value of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 is realized at a potential value of 1.65 V RHE with adequate durability. Overall, the synthetic strategy is general, scalable and may be extended to grow other metal oxide doped alloy nanostructures in the future.</description>
      <author>Sunil Semwal, Aiswarya Samal, Saroj K. Nayak, Rajashri Urkude, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, Umaprasana Ojha</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Yolk@Shell-Heterostuctured Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanospheres as Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04799</link>
      <description>Yingxin Liu, Yan Hou, Mingyang Cai, Weishun Song, Xiao&#8208;Quan Yang, Junjie Fu, Liangshun Luo, Xueming Su, Xianggang Huang, Hongwei Gu, Xueqin Cao, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402272508

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingxin Liu, Yan Hou, Mingyang Cai, Weishun Song, Xiao&#8208;Quan Yang, Junjie Fu, Liangshun Luo, Xueming Su, Xianggang Huang, Hongwei Gu, Xueqin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04799</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the adsorption strength of oxygen intermediates on &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;NiC&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;O&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; by Fe doping to improve the oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.095801</link>
      <description>Xilin Zhang, Sheng Rui, Y. C. Zhai, Rui Zheng, Shan Wang, Zhongjun Ma, Zongxian Yang, Physical Review Materials. 8(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402168197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xilin Zhang, Sheng Rui, Y. C. Zhai, Rui Zheng, Shan Wang, Zhongjun Ma, Zongxian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.095801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402164392

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402179583

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402164096

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402180294

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot synthesis of supported PtCox bifunctional catalysts for oxygen reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.472</link>
      <description>Xin Zeng, Sushanta K. Mitra, Xianguo Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402081208

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Zeng, Sushanta K. Mitra, Xianguo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Sana Ullah, Asif Hussain, Muhammad Asim Farid, Shaheen Irfan, Roohul Amin, Ahmed M. Fouda, Atif Nazir, Dehua Hou, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Shangfeng Du, Muhammad Tahir, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402179694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sana Ullah, Asif Hussain, Muhammad Asim Farid, Shaheen Irfan, Roohul Amin, Ahmed M. Fouda, Atif Nazir, Dehua Hou, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Shangfeng Du, Muhammad Tahir</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402179868

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402180297

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Coordinated Cobalt Single Atom Steered by Doped-O and Coo for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution at Industrial Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4942439</link>
      <description>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Renyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Xue Z. Wang, P.X. Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402090352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Renyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Xue Z. Wang, P.X. Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4942439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Ti/Zr-SnO2/PbO2-Nd Electrode for Efficient Electrocatalytic Degradation of Alizarine Yellow R</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/0115734137325822240819050628</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Yang Bi, Guoqiang Gao, Qingdong Miao, Weiguo Hu, Jingang Yu, Current Nanoscience. 20(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402145152

                Introduction: A novel attempt to degrade alizarine yellow R (AYR) by lead dioxide (PbO2)/ neodymium (Nd) coated Ti anode was investigated. Method: Ti/Zr-SnO2/PbO2-Nd electrode showed high oxygen evolution potential, high current density, and neutral conditions, which favored the degradation of AYR. The PbO2-Nd layer on Ti/Zr-SnO2 was further characterized by scanning electron microscopy, and X-ray diffraction analysis, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. The electrochemical properties of Ti/Zr- SnO2/PbO2-Nd electrode were evaluated by cyclic voltammetry, AC impedance spectroscopy, and accelerated life test. Result: The relatively higher oxygen evolution overpotential (~1.80 V) of the developed electrode can effectively suppress the occurrence of surface side reactions and oxygen evolution. A relatively lower charge transfer resistance (Rct, 18.0 &#937;) of Ti/Zr-SnO2/PbO2-Nd electrode could be found. The Ti/Zr-SnO2/PbO2-Nd electrode exhibited an accelerated lifetime of 110 min under a very high current density of 10,000 A/m2. The doping of Nd could produce loosely-stacked sheet-like structures, thus, the number of active sites on the electrode surface increases. Conclusion: Moreover, an outstanding conductivity of Ti/Zr-SnO2/PbO2-Nd electrode was obtained, which favored the electron transfer and catalytic activity of the modified electrode. The Ti/Zr-SnO2/PbO2-Nd electrode exhibited improved electrochemical performances and higher oxygen evolution potential, and the highest oxygen evolution potential is 1.80 V. Under the current density of 30 mA/cm2, the electrocatalytic degradation of 92.3% could be achieved in 180 min. The electrochemical oxidation of AYR at the Ti/Zr-SnO2/PbO2-Nd electrode proved to be feasible and effective, indicating that it might be used for the elimination of AYR from wastewater. conclusion: The electrochemical oxidation of AYR at the Ti/Zr-SnO2/PbO2-Nd electrode proved to be feasible and effective, indicating that it might be used for the elimination of AYR from wastewater.</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Yang Bi, Guoqiang Gao, Qingdong Miao, Weiguo Hu, Jingang Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/0115734137325822240819050628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancy assisted Ru&#8211;Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for efficient ethylene glycol electrooxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01372g</link>
      <description>Yanyan Li, Haibo Liu, Wang Ketao, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Haifeng Lin, Lei Wang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402128453

                Ethylene glycol oxidation (EGOR) is an important step in polyethylene terephthalate (PET) recycling, and it is a thermodynamically more favorable anode reaction in comparison with the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Yanyan Li, Haibo Liu, Wang Ketao, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Haifeng Lin, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01372g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis over Superparamagnetic Ferrites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00170b</link>
      <description>Tiago G. Fernandes, Ramsundar Mohan, Laura Donk, Wei Wang, Chiara Biz, Mauro Fianchini, Yury V. Kolen&#8217;ko, Siavash Mohammad Alizadeh, Anna Kitayev, Aviv Ashdot, Miles Page, Laura M. Salonen, S. K&#246;pp, E. Tal-Gutelmacher, Jos&#233; Gracia, Marta C. Figueiredo, Yury V. Kolen&#8217;ko, Energy Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402071237

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is usually the bottleneck in water electrolysis due to its sluggish kinetics, there is a need of more efficient and stable catalysts, nowadays resulting in increased...</description>
      <author>Tiago G. Fernandes, Ramsundar Mohan, Laura Donk, Wei Wang, Chiara Biz, Mauro Fianchini, Yury V. Kolen&#8217;ko, Siavash Mohammad Alizadeh, Anna Kitayev, Aviv Ashdot, Miles Page, Laura M. Salonen, S. K&#246;pp, E. Tal-Gutelmacher, Jos&#233; Gracia, Marta C. Figueiredo, Yury V. Kolen&#8217;ko</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00170b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Structure Derived Phosphide Nanosheets for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406105</link>
      <description>Ying Dong, Jixiang Jiao, Yadong Wang, Jun Yu, Shichun Mu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402047325

                Avoiding the stacking of active sites in catalyst structural design is a promising route for realizing active oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, using a CoFe Prussian blue analoge cube with hollow structure (C-CoFe PBA) as a derived support, a highly effective Ni</description>
      <author>Ying Dong, Jixiang Jiao, Yadong Wang, Jun Yu, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect engineering for surface reconstruction of metal oxide catalysts during OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101091</link>
      <description>Jingxuan Zheng, Zhao Wang, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402194918

                The bigger pictureChallenges and opportunities:&#8226;The scarcity of active sites limits the large-scale application of metal oxides as commercial oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts. However, the rational design of defect structures can boost their catalytic activity&#8226;The precise design of catalyst defect structures requires a comprehensive understanding of the structure-activity relationship between defects and OER performance. Current research primarily focuses on the correlation between defects and thermodynamic parameters. However, our understanding of the intrinsic relationship between defects and the kinetics and mechanisms of OERs remains limited&#8226;In the adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM), defect structures can accelerate the evolution of active surfaces, promote OH&#8315; adsorption and deprotonation, and facilitate the desorption of the product O&#8322;. In the lattice oxygen intermediate mechanism (LOM), defect structures can enhance the covalency of metal&#8211;oxygen bonds and provide OH&#8315; adsorption sites, facilitating their involvement in lattice oxygen oxidation processesSummaryThe development of electrochemical processes, such as water electrolysis for hydrogen production and rechargeable metal-air batteries, offers promising solutions to the energy crisis and environmental pollution. However, challenges like sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics, high costs of precious metal catalysts, and scarce active sites in transition metal oxides hinder large-scale commercial applications. Defect engineering has emerged as a promising strategy to optimize transition metal oxides by improving their electronic structure, conductivity, and active site availability. Early research focused on static thermodynamic parameters, such as impedance, overpotential, and band gap, neglecting dynamic factors like catalyst surface restructuring and mechanism transformation during reactions. This perspective highlights the intrinsic connection between defect structures, catalyst surface reconstruction, and reaction mechanisms. It also discusses the need for advanced experimental and theoretical computational studies to better understand the surface evolution of catalysts during OERs.Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Jingxuan Zheng, Zhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Ni2+ on OER Kinetics and Photoluminescence Properties of ZnSnO3 Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113042</link>
      <description>B. Vishwalinga Prasad, H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, C. Ningappa, B. Daruka Prasad, R. Sahana, K.N. Sridhar, K. Manjunath, Sheng Yun Wu, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402105989

                Ni2+ doped ZnSnO3 nanoparticles (NPs) were synthesized using Aloe vera mediated solution combustion method, followed by an investigation into their luminescence and oxygen evolution reaction properties. The Bragg reflections of ZnSnO3: Ni(1-9 mol%) NPs revealed a cubic structure, with the addition of the dopant inducing lattice strain and resulting in peak shifting towards higher angles. No impurity-related peaks were observed. The estimated crystallite size and optical band gap decrease (3.1 to 2.94 eV) with an increase in dopant concentration. The surface morphology consists of irregular-sized and shaped NPs with hallows. The EDAX spectra show the purity of the sample. Photoluminescence emission spectra were recorded at a 230 nm excitation wavelength, where intense blue emission observed at 482 nm was attributed to a direct transition between the conduction band edge and the valence band edge, corresponding to the direct recombination of free excitons. Another satellite peak observed at 525 nm can be attributed to oxygen deficiency. Moreover, the nanoparticles exhibited outstanding performance in oxygen evolution reaction studies, showing low over potentials between 300 and 318 mV, a minimal Tafel slope of range 63-72 mV dec-1, and stable electrochemical behavior over 12 hours at a current density of 23 mA/cm2. These results highlight their effectiveness as electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>B. Vishwalinga Prasad, H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, C. Ningappa, B. Daruka Prasad, R. Sahana, K.N. Sridhar, K. Manjunath, Sheng Yun Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Research Progress on the Electrocatalytic Degradation of Organic Pollutants by PbO2-Based Electrode"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26717/bjstr.2024.58.009143</link>
      <description>Wenlong Liu, Biomedical Journal of Scientific &amp; Technical Research. 58(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402051867

                As an inactive electrode, PbO2-based electrode can produce abundant hydroxyl radicals which are beneficial to the degradation of organic pollutants. In recent years, as a widely used material in electrochemical oxidation technology, more and more PbO2-based electrodes have attracted much attention due to their high oxygen evolution potential, high catalytic activity and good stability. Presently, most of the articles are devoted to the modification of the electrode. To better understand electrochemical degradation of pollutants from waste water, this review summarizes the research progress of wastewater treatment in recent years.</description>
      <author>Wenlong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26717/bjstr.2024.58.009143</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Analysis of the Gradient Porous Transport Layer for the Proton-Exchange Membrane Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00006</link>
      <description>Yang Liu, Qiu Diankai, Zhutian Xu, Peiyun Yi, Linfa Peng, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402030786

                A reasonable porous transport layer (PTL) is crucial to decreasing the mass-transfer loss in proton-exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). In this study, it was experimentally demonstrated that the gradient porosity PTL is beneficial in improving the performance of electrolyzers. The research comprehensively investigates the impact of gradient porosity PTL structures on the performance of the PEMWE, considering mass transfer and interfacial contact. It offers insights into the two-phase (oxygen-water) flow transport mechanisms within the PTLs using a 2D numerical model based on the actual PTL geometry. At the microscopic level, it analyzes how the interfacial contact impacts proton and electron transport mechanisms, affecting not only the contact resistance but also the number of effective catalytic sites for the oxygen evolution reaction. Experimental results demonstrate that the cis-gradient porosity PTL leads to a performance enhancement of 9.3% at 2.2 A/cm</description>
      <author>Yang Liu, Qiu Diankai, Zhutian Xu, Peiyun Yi, Linfa Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of adipic acid with high faradaic efficiency within a wide potential window</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51951-0</link>
      <description>Xiang Liu, Yuquan Zhu, Jing Li, Ye Wang, Qiujin Shi, An-Zhen Li, Kaiyue Ji, Wenjun Wang, Xikang Zhao, Jinyu Zheng, Haohong Duan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402166971

                Electrosynthesis of adipic acid (a precursor for nylon-66) from KA oil (a mixture of cyclohexanone and cyclohexanol) represents a sustainable strategy to replace conventional method that requires harsh conditions. However, its industrial possibility is greatly restricted by the low current density and competitive oxygen evolution reaction. Herein, we modify nickel layered double hydroxide with vanadium to promote current density and maintain high faradaic efficiency (&gt;80%) within a wide potential window (1.5 ~ 1.9 V vs. reversible hydrogen electrode). Experimental and theoretical studies reveal two key roles of V modification, including accelerating catalyst reconstruction and strengthening cyclohexanone adsorption. As a proof-of-the-concept, we construct a membrane electrode assembly, producing adipic acid with high faradaic efficiency (82%) and productivity (1536 &#956;mol cm</description>
      <author>Xiang Liu, Yuquan Zhu, Jing Li, Ye Wang, Qiujin Shi, An-Zhen Li, Kaiyue Ji, Wenjun Wang, Xikang Zhao, Jinyu Zheng, Haohong Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51951-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured MnMoO4 as a trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129927</link>
      <description>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402199718

                Electrochemical water splitting and CO2 reduction are important processes to produce hydrogen and low&#8211;carbon fuels as renewable energy sources. Here, nanostructured MnMoO4, prepared by the reflux precipitation method, was investigated as a trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions. Using a combination of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results, a direct band gap of 3.05 eV was obtained experimentally for the prepared MnMoO4. An overpotential of 0.36 V at a current density of 5 mA cm-2 and a Tafel slope of 58 mV dec-1 were obtained for the oxygen evolution reaction. At a current density of 3 mA cm-2, overpotentials of 0.39 V and 0.58 V were achieved in the absence and presence of CO2 bubbling into a 0.1 M KOH solution, respectively, emphasizing the poisoning effect of CO2 reduction intermediates for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Based on the obtained results, MnMoO4 could be a promising electrocatalyst for water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions.</description>
      <author>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Investigation on Cr-Doped Sc&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; MXene under Strain for Electronic Properties, Quantum Capacitance, and Photocatalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02282</link>
      <description>Ruiwen Yan, Xiao&#8208;Hong Li, Rui-Zhou Zhang, Hong&#8208;Ling Cui, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402031714

                Sc2CO2 MXene has potential applications in energy storage and optoelectronics due to its superior structure and excellent properties. The electronic properties, quantum capacitance, and photocatalytic activity of Cr-doped Sc2CO2 under strain are studied by the density functional theory. Cr doping makes the system produce magnetism. The spin-down states of Sc2CO2&#8211;Cr under strain are direct semiconductors, while their spin-up states are indirect semiconductors. Sc2CO2&#8211;Cr under +5, &#8722;5, &#8722;3, and &#8722;2% strains in an aqueous system are suitable for cathode material. A large voltage drastically modulates the type of electrode materials. Sc2CO2&#8211;Cr under strains from 0 to +2% can perform the oxygen evolution reaction at an alkaline environment, while the Sc2CO2&#8211;Cr system under strain is a good for CO2 photocatalysis at pH 0 and 7.</description>
      <author>Ruiwen Yan, Xiao&#8208;Hong Li, Rui-Zhou Zhang, Hong&#8208;Ling Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of titanium at the interface of hematite photoanode in multisite mechanism: Reactive site or cocatalyst site?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60093-8</link>
      <description>Mei Xie, Xing Ji, Hanlu Meng, Nanbing Jiang, Zhenyu Luo, Qianqian Huang, Geng Sun, Yunhuai Zhang, Peng Xiao, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402122445

                Hematite (&#945;-Fe2O3) constitutes one of the most promising photoanode materials for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Recent research on Fe2O3 have found a fast OER rate dependence on surface hole density, suggesting a multisite reaction pathway. However, the effect of heteroatom in Fe2O3 on the multisite mechanism is still poorly understood. Herein we synthesized Fe2O3 on Ti substrates (Fe2O3/Ti) to study the oxygen intermediates of OER by light-dark electrochemical scans. We identified the Fe-OH species disappeared and Ti-OH intermediates appeared on Fe2O3/Ti when pH = 11&#8722;14, which significantly improved the OER performance of Fe2O3/Ti. Combined with the density functional theory calculations, we propose that Ti atom acts as cocatalyst site and captures proton from neighboring Fe-OH species under highly alkaline condition, thereby promoting the coupling of Fe=O and reducing the energy barrier of the non-electrochemical step. Our work provides a new insight into the role of heteroatom in OER multisite mechanism based on clarifying the reaction intermediates.</description>
      <author>Mei Xie, Xing Ji, Hanlu Meng, Nanbing Jiang, Zhenyu Luo, Qianqian Huang, Geng Sun, Yunhuai Zhang, Peng Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60093-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF&#8208;Derived FeCoO/N&#8208;Doped C Bifunctional Electrode for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production Through Water and Glucose Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400342</link>
      <description>Meysam Tayebi, Zohreh Masoumi, Hyungwoo Lee, Daehyeon Hong, Bongkuk Seo, Choong&#8208;Sun Lim, Daeseung Kyung, Hyeon&#8208;Gook Kim, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402134984

                Abstract The glucose oxidation reaction (GOR) is a potential alternative to water oxidation because of its relatively low thermodynamic potential and the high availability of glucose. Herein, a FeCoO/N&#8208;doped C electrode derived from metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) materials is applied, which is synthesized in several steps through the controlled deposition of Fe&#8211;Co oxide nanocatalysts onto Co &#8211;N&#8208;doped C nanofibers on a Ni foam substrate and demonstrate exceptional electrocatalytic activity for both the GOR and overall water splitting. Here, a bifunctional electrocatalyst derived from MOF, FeCoO/N&#8208;doped C is reported, for glucose oxidation reaction (GOR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The MOF&#8208;derived FeCoO/N&#8208;doped C (+/&#8208;) as a bifunctional electrocatalyst exhibits a cell voltage of 1.4 V for the GOR&amp;HER, to reach a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is 280 mV lower than that for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER)&amp;HER (1.68 V). This study reveals that GOR is an energy&#8208;efficient and affordable source of H 2 and value&#8208;added chemicals.</description>
      <author>Meysam Tayebi, Zohreh Masoumi, Hyungwoo Lee, Daehyeon Hong, Bongkuk Seo, Choong&#8208;Sun Lim, Daeseung Kyung, Hyeon&#8208;Gook Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soluble Lead Redox Flow Batteries: Status and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400267</link>
      <description>Satya Prakash Yadav, M. K. Ravikumar, Satish Patil, A. K. Shukla, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402053538

                Abstract Soluble lead redox flow battery (SLRFB) is an emergent energy storage technology appropriate for integrating solar and wind energy into the primary grid. It is an allied technology of conventional lead&#8208;acid batteries. This appraisal compares lead&#8208;acid batteries and SLRFB apropos their general characteristics. SLRFBs can overcome the inadequate cycle&#8208;life of Lead&#8208;Acid batteries as the electrodes of SLRFB do not participate in the reaction, which helps extending its durability. However, SLRFB has challenges of dendrite formation, oxygen evolution reaction, passivation of PbO 2 and shunt current. These problems need to be resolved before SLRFBs can be projected for large&#8208;scale energy storage applications. In this technical update, we have reviewed the recent studies pertinent to dendrite formation, mechanism of the lead electrode, and reversibility of the PbO 2 electrode in the state&#8208;of&#8208;art of SLRFB along with progress in advances while developing a 12 V &#8211; 250 Wh 8&#8208;cell SLRFB stack.</description>
      <author>Satya Prakash Yadav, M. K. Ravikumar, Satish Patil, A. K. Shukla</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus vacancies regulation and heterogeneous interfacial engineering of coral-like ZnO/FeCoPv@N-doped carbon hierarchical microspheres to boost overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.229</link>
      <description>Li-Hua Zhi, Mingming Zhang, Jibing Tu, Min Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402073110

                Vacancy engineering and heterostructure construction are regarded as potent approaches for synergistically boosting hydrogen production in renewable energy conversion. Herein, a selective phosphorization strategy was implemented to fabricate coral-like ZnO/FeCoP@N-doped carbon hierarchical microspheres (ZnO/FeCoP@NCHMS) via only controllably phosphorizing the Co and Fe atoms in a precursor, which was formed by generating ZnCoFe LDH on the surface of a zinc cobalt coordination polymer microsphere. Then, by adopting a reduction treatment for ZnO/FeCoP@NCHMS, the innovative ZnO/FeCoPv@NCHMS with abundant phosphorus vacancies (Pv) was realized. The introduction of phosphorus vacancy could optimize the electronic structures of metal phosphides and accelerate the reconstruction of active species, thus speeding up the reaction kinetic. Likewise, the plentiful heterointerfaces greatly expedite the transfer of electrons and protons, exposing ultra-high active sites. By virtue of these fascinating characters and the unique coral-like hierarchical architecture, the as-prepared ZnO/FeCoPv@NCHMS reveal preeminent electrocatalytic activities, and the overpotentials for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are as low as 177 and 173 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Li-Hua Zhi, Mingming Zhang, Jibing Tu, Min Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#945;&#8208;Bi2Mo3O12: A Dual&#8208;Functional material for electrocatalytic water splitting and supercapacitor applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402645</link>
      <description>P. Sujita, S. Swetha, S. Vadivel, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402072798

                This study explores the functionality of &#945;-Bi2Mo3O12 (BMO) as an electrocatalyst for water splitting and its suitability for supercapacitor applications. BMO was synthesized by the solvothermal method and characterized in pre-calcination [BMO (BC)], post-calcination [BMO (AC)], and base-etched forms [BMO (BE)]. Structural analysis confirmed the formation of &#945;-Bi2Mo3O12 with well-defined crystallographic planes. Electrochemical analysis revealed that BMO (AC) exhibited the lowest overpotential for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) and BMO (BC) exhibited the lowest overpotential for oxygen evolution reactions (OER), indicating its superior electrocatalytic activity. The Tafel slope and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results confirmed the superior kinetics and charge transfer properties of BMO material. Furthermore, BMO samples demonstrated excellent stability during prolonged chronoamperometry (CA) testing for 12 h. For supercapacitor performances, the BMO (BE) exhibits a superior specific capacitance value of 398 F/g at 2.0 A/g. Thus, the BMO material delivers prominent electrocatalytic activity as well as supercapacitor performance. Overall, this study demonstrates the potentiality of &#945;-Bi2Mo3O12 in different forms as a dual-functional material for efficient energy storage and conversion.</description>
      <author>P. Sujita, S. Swetha, S. Vadivel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalyst&#8211;Driven Hybrid Water Splitting for Energy&#8208;Saving Coproduction of Green H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Valuable Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394234110.ch10</link>
      <description>Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Bao Yu Xia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402030913

                Electrocatalytic water splitting to generate green H 2 with renewable energy inputs is attractive to relieve the environmental contamination and energy dilemma. Restricted by the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and single functionality of cathode/anode catalysts, conventional overall water splitting (OWS) suffers from high overpotentials and respective synthesis of monofunctional electrocatalysts, leading to high cost. Moreover, the generated O 2 bears low value and its possible mixing with H 2 poses safety issues. In response, hybrid water splitting (HWS) that integrates hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with favorable oxidative upgrading reactions over bifunctional electrocatalysts can generate H 2 and value-added chemicals simultaneously with lower energy input and avoid the explosive H 2 /O 2 mixtures. Hence, this chapter focuses on the recent progress in bifunctional electrocatalyst&#8211;driven HWS for energy-saving coproduction of highly valuable chemicals and green H 2 . Firstly, the fundamentals of HER, OER, OWS, and HWS are introduced, followed by a discussion on the electrochemical reconstruction of bifunctional electrocatalysts during OWS and HWS. Next, the HWS based on bifunctional electrocatalysts is summarized, wherein the alternative oxidation reactions include upgrading of alcohol, aldehydes, amines, biomass, and plastic waste. Finally, a brief overview of current challenges and perspective for bifunctional electrocatalyst&#8211;driven HWS is discussed.</description>
      <author>Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394234110.ch10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating the Kinetic Hysteresis of Co&#8208;free Ni&#8208;rich Cathodes via Gradient Penetration of Nonmagnetic Silicon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409764</link>
      <description>Yijun Song, Yongpeng Cui, Li Wang, Lina Ge, Li Zhou, Zhijian Qiu, Zhipeng Xie, Debin Kong, Xiaofang Li, Jianqiang Zhang, Lei Zhu, Pengyun Liu, Wei Xing, Zifeng Yan, Qingzhong Xue, Yongfu Tang, Wei Xing, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402128932

                Co&#8208;free Ni&#8208;rich layered oxides are considered a promising cathode material for next&#8208;generation Li&#8208;ion batteries due to their cost&#8208;effectiveness and high capacity. However, they still suffer from the practical challenges of low discharge capacity and poor rate capability due to the hysteresis of Li&#8208;ion diffusion kinetics. Herein, based on the regulation of the lattice magnetic frustration, the Li/Ni intermixing defects as the primary origin of kinetic hysteresis are radically addressed via the doping of the nonmagnetic Si element. Meanwhile, by adopting gradient penetration doping, a robust Si&#8208;O surface structure with reversible lattice oxygen evolution and low lattice strain is constructed on Co&#8208;free Ni&#8208;rich cathodes to suppress the formation of surface dense barrier layer. With the remarkably enhanced Li&#8208;ion diffusion kinetics in atomic and electrode particle scales, the as&#8208;obtained cathodes (LiNixMn1&#8208;xSi0.01O2, 0.6 &#8804; x &#8804; 0.9) achieve superior performance in discharge capacity, rate capability, and durability. This work highlights the coupling effect of magnetic structure and interfacial chemicals on Li&#8208;ion transport properties, and the concept will inspire more researchers to conduct an intensive study.</description>
      <author>Yijun Song, Yongpeng Cui, Li Wang, Lina Ge, Li Zhou, Zhijian Qiu, Zhipeng Xie, Debin Kong, Xiaofang Li, Jianqiang Zhang, Lei Zhu, Pengyun Liu, Wei Xing, Zifeng Yan, Qingzhong Xue, Yongfu Tang, Wei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Triazine&#8208;Based Frameworks with Ru&#8208;tda Based Catalyst Anchored via Coordination Bond for Photoinduced Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406375</link>
      <description>Martina Salati, Florian Dorchies, Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, Marta Ventosa, Soranyel Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Carrero, Carlota Bozal&#8208;Ginesta, Jan Holub, Olaf R&#252;diger, Julio Lloret&#8208;Fillol, Carolina Gimbert&#8208;Suri&#241;ach, James R. Durrant, Mehmed Z. Ertem, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, Antoni Llobet, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402270252

                Abstract Light&#8208;induced water splitting (h&#957;&#8208;WS) for the production of hydrogen as a solar fuel is considered a promising sustainable strategy for the replacement of fossil fuels. An efficient system for h&#957;&#8208;WS involves a photoactive material that, upon shining light, is capable of separating and transferring charges to catalysts for the hydrogen and oxygen evolution processes. Covalent triazine&#8208;based frameworks (CTFs) represent an interesting class of 2D organic light&#8208;absorbing materials that have recently emerged thanks to their tunable structural, optical and morphological properties. Typically, catalysts (Cat) are metallic nanoparticles generated in situ after photoelectroreduction of metal precursors or directly drop&#8208;casted on top of the CTF material to generate Cat&#8208;CTF assemblies. In this work, the synthesis, characterization and photocatalytic performance of a novel hybrid material, Ru&#8208;CTF , is reported, based on a CTF structure featuring dangling pyridyl groups that allow the Ru&#8208;tda (tda is [2,2&#8242;:6&#8242;,2&#8242;&#8220;&#8208;terpyridine]&#8208;6,6&#8242;&#8221;&#8208;dicarboxylic acid) water oxidation catalyst (WOC) unit to coordinate via covalent bond. The Ru&#8208;CTF molecular hybrid material can carry out the light&#8208;induced water oxidation reaction efficiently at neutral pH, reaching values of maximum TOF of 17 h &#8722;1 and TONs in the range of 220 using sodium persulfate as a sacrificial electron acceptor.</description>
      <author>Martina Salati, Florian Dorchies, Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, Marta Ventosa, Soranyel Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Carrero, Carlota Bozal&#8208;Ginesta, Jan Holub, Olaf R&#252;diger, Julio Lloret&#8208;Fillol, Carolina Gimbert&#8208;Suri&#241;ach, James R. Durrant, Mehmed Z. Ertem, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, Antoni Llobet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406375</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis with a Checkered Carbon Matrix Containing Ir&#8208;Ru Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402179</link>
      <description>T. B. Ngoc Huynh, Jihyeok Song, Hyo Eun Bae, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Myung Jun Kim, Oh Joong Kwon, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402070718

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) emerges as a promising avenue for storing excess renewable energy by generating H 2 gas without introducing additional carbon emissions. However, PEMWE systems still grapple with challenges related to energy efficiency, cell longevity, and maximum operational current density. Consequently, extensive research efforts have been directed toward enhancing the performance of electrocatalysts and refining system designs to overcome these limitations. Within this framework, this study introduces a novel synthetic approach for fabricating N&#8208;doped carbon matrices with a checkered pattern on the surface of porous transport layers (PTLs) composed of titanium (Ti). The resulting N&#8208;doped checkered carbon matrices serve as robust hosts for Ir&#8208;Ru nanoparticles during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), ensuring their stable integration. Additionally, the checkered pattern of the N&#8208;doped carbon matrices facilitates the efficient transport of both electrolyte and produced O 2 gas. Capitalizing on these advantages, the incorporation of checkered carbon matrices with Ir&#8208;Ru nanoparticles has achieved a cell current density of 6.82 A cm &#8722;2 at a unit cell voltage of 2.0 V. The benefits of this structural innovation extend beyond water electrolysis and can be extrapolated to other electrochemical systems involving the production and transport of gas bubbles, such as CO 2 reduction.</description>
      <author>T. B. Ngoc Huynh, Jihyeok Song, Hyo Eun Bae, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Myung Jun Kim, Oh Joong Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing photoelectrochemical performance and stability of Ti-doped hematite photoanode via pentanuclear Co-based MOF modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1454524</link>
      <description>Guofa Dong, Fengyan Xie, Fangxia Kou, Tingting Chen, Caihong Xiao, Shaowu Du, Jiaqi Liang, Chenfang Lou, Jiandong Zhuang, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402070648

                Modifying photoanodes with metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) as oxygen evolution reaction (OER) cocatalysts has emerged as a promising approach to enhance the efficiency of photoelectrochemical (PEC) water oxidation. However, designing OER-active MOFs with both high photo- and electrochemical stability remains a challenge, limiting the advancement of this research. Herein, we present a facile method to fabricate a MOF-modified photoanode by directly loading a pentanuclear Co-based MOF (Co-MOF) onto the surface of a Ti-doped hematite photoanode (Ti:Fe 2 O 3 ). The resulting Co-MOF/Ti:Fe 2 O 3 modified photoanode exhibits an enhanced photocurrent density of 1.80 mA&#8729;cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V, surpassing those of the Ti:Fe 2 O 3 (1.53 mA&#8729;cm &#8722;2 ) and bare Fe 2 O 3 (0.59 mA&#8729;cm &#8722;2 ) counterparts. Additionally, significant enhancements in charge injection and separation efficiencies, applied bias photon-to-current efficiency (ABPE), incident photon to current conversion efficiency (IPCE), and donor density (N d ) were observed. Notably, a minimal photocurrent decay of only 5% over 10 h demonstrates the extraordinary stability of the Co-MOF/Ti:Fe 2 O 3 photoanode. This work highlights the efficacy of polynuclear Co-based MOFs as OER cocatalysts in designing efficient and stable photoanodes for PEC water splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Guofa Dong, Fengyan Xie, Fangxia Kou, Tingting Chen, Caihong Xiao, Shaowu Du, Jiaqi Liang, Chenfang Lou, Jiandong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1454524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen production via alkaline seawater electrolysis using iron-doped nickel diselenide as an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102276</link>
      <description>Vipin Yadav, Naduvile Purayil Dileep, N. Nitin Nair, Pritish Kumar Behura, Manikoth M. Shaijumon, Materials Today Chemistry. 40(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402114391

                Green hydrogen production via seawater electrolysis is a promising pathway towards sustainable energy future. However, seawater splitting is hindered by the low stability and selectivity of electrocatalysts towards hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and faces severe electrode corrosion. Herein, we report the synthesis of highly active and durable Fe-doped nickel diselenide (Fe&#8211;NiSe2) nanoparticles supported on nickel foam as bifunctional electrocatalysts for efficient alkaline seawater electrolysis via an electrodeposition method followed by low-temperature annealing. The electrocatalytic properties of as-prepared Fe&#8211;NiSe2 toward HER and OER are investigated in different electrolytes. The optimized electrocatalyst (20-Fe-NiSe2) shows very low overpotential of 92 and 96 mV in alkaline (1.0 M KOH) and simulated seawater (1.0 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl) electrolytes, respectively, to reach the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for HER. For the OER, 20-Fe-NiSe2 exhibits an overpotential of 333 and 311 mV in alkaline and simulated seawater electrolytes, respectively, to attain a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2. Further, full-cell studies are carried out with 20-Fe-NiSe2 as bifunctional electrocatalysts, which requires cell potential of 1.83 V and 1.81 V to deliver a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline and simulated seawater electrolytes, respectively. Additionally, the electrode shows tremendous potential for use in alkaline seawater electrolysis with stability over 100 h, at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2, which is achieved at a low cell voltage of 1.87 V. The present work offers a simple, efficient, and cost-effective method for the development of heterogeneous Fe-doped nickel diselenide electrocatalysts for seawater electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Vipin Yadav, Naduvile Purayil Dileep, N. Nitin Nair, Pritish Kumar Behura, Manikoth M. Shaijumon</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Seconds to fabricate high-performance NiFe-based anode for seawater electrolysis via bidirectional pulse current method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155435</link>
      <description>Hui Wu, Qian Zhang, Qianfeng Liu, Min Li, Haibo Liu, Jie Fu, Erdong Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402125667

                Direct electrolysis of seawater to produce green hydrogen has attracted great attention. While the development of efficient and rapid manufacturing processes for high-performance electrodes, particularly for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), remains trail. Here, we introduce an innovative approach to fabricate high-performance NiFe-based OER electrodes using an ultrafast and eco-friendly bidirectional pulse current (BPC) method, which remarkably shortens the production time to only 20 s. Our BPC method alternates oxidation and reduction currents within a single period, promoting the in-situ formation of porous NiFe(oxy)hydroxide nanosheets through dissolution/deposition processes. Moreover, this methodology creatively utilizes the "Cl&#8722; induced effect", typically a hindrance in other electrochemical systems involving seawater or brine, to enhance the synthesis of electrodes from NaCl-based electrolyte devoid of additional Ni/Fe cations. The prepared NiFe-based electrode (NFF O-R 20 s) demonstrates remarkable OER catalytic activity, with optimal overpotentials (&#951;j) of 272, 308 and 367 mV at current densities (j) of 10, 100 and 1000 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. Impressively, it maintains a low cell voltage of 1.59 V after enduring 1000 h of operation under the industrially current density of 300 mA cm&#8722;2, with a direct current energy consumption of 3.8 kWh Nm&#8722;3 H2 for overall alkaline seawater electrolysis. Our BPC preparation approach provides a promising path to construction high-catalytic activity, good-stability electrode, and low-energy consumption direct seawater electrolyzer.</description>
      <author>Hui Wu, Qian Zhang, Qianfeng Liu, Min Li, Haibo Liu, Jie Fu, Erdong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Periodic variation of anomalous cosmic ray oxygen during solar cycles 23 and 24</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4859989/v1</link>
      <description>P.B. Kotz&#233;, &#1050;. &#1052;&#1091;&#1088;&#1089;&#1091;&#1083;&#1072;, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402123808

                Abstract We investigate the evolution of the Rieger periodicity at 152 &#8722; 156 days, the 27-day synodic rotation period as well as the 13.5 and 9-day harmonic periodicities in anomalous cosmic ray (ACR) oxygen (O) fluxes at the energy range between 8 - 25 MeV/n observed by the Advanced Composition Explorer(ACE) satellite during solar cycles 23 and 24. The ACR oxygen flux data is analysed using the Lomb-Scargle periodogram and Morlet wavelet spectral analysis techniques. Daily mean oxygen fluxes during solar quiet times are used to identify how the ACR oxygens at different energies vary at the Rieger periodicity and at the solar rotation periodicities in each year. This is the first investigation of the periodicity evolution of ACR oxygen ions. Previous investigations have mostly concentrated on the spectral behaviour of GCR particles during various solar cycles of opposite polarities, in particular the 27-day and 13.5-day periodicities. Our analysis revealed a significant temporal and energy dependence in the spectral behaviour of ACR oxygen during both cycles, with the most prominent Rieger periodicity occurring during the late declining phase of these solar cycles.</description>
      <author>P.B. Kotz&#233;, &#1050;. &#1052;&#1091;&#1088;&#1089;&#1091;&#1083;&#1072;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4859989/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Modulation of Oxygen Vacancy Concentration in Hf0.5Zr0.5O2&#8722;x Thin Films and the Mechanism of Its Impact on Ferroelectricity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14091121</link>
      <description>Shikai Liu, Xingyu Li, Gang Li, Shaoan Yan, Yingfang Zhu, Yujie Wu, Qin Jiang, Yang Zhan, Minghua Tang, Coatings. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402135411

                Oxygen vacancies play a crucial role in stabilizing the ferroelectric phase in hafnium (Hf) oxide-based thin films and in shaping the evolution of their ferroelectric properties. In this study, we directly manipulated the oxygen vacancy concentration in Hf0.5Zr0.5O2&#8722;x (HZO) ferroelectric thin films in situ using oxygen plasma treatment. We scrutinized the variations in the ferroelectric properties of HZO films across different oxygen vacancy concentrations by integrating the findings from ferroelectric performance tests. Additionally, we elucidated the mechanism underlying the influence of oxygen vacancies on the coercive field and polarization properties of HZO ferroelectric films through the first-principles density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Finally, to study the impact of oxygen vacancies on the practical application of HZO ferroelectric synaptic devices, leveraging the plasticity of the ferroelectric polarization, we constructed a multilayer perceptron (MLP) network. We simulated its recognition accuracy and convergence speed under different oxygen vacancy concentrations in the MNIST recognition task.</description>
      <author>Shikai Liu, Xingyu Li, Gang Li, Shaoan Yan, Yingfang Zhu, Yujie Wu, Qin Jiang, Yang Zhan, Minghua Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14091121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History and Social Implications of the Pulse Oximeter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.68250</link>
      <description>Dean K Zacharis, Dongye Zhao, Latha Ganti, Cureus. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402097669

                The pulse oximeter is a portable, bedside tool that allows for the measurement of oxygen saturation in a patient's red blood cells. The technology is based on oxygenated and deoxygenated hemoglobin absorbing light at different wavelengths. The device calculates the ratio of oxygenated to deoxygenated hemoglobin in the blood, and an algorithm produces a percentage oxygen saturation value. Due to its portability and ease of use, it is a ubiquitous medical tool that is commonly used in medical practice. This paper reviews the history and evolution of this tool, and the scientific laws behind oximetry. It also introduces the importance of the pulse oximeter and its basic functions. In addition, the limitations of pulse oximetry are discussed, especially as they pertain to pigmented skin.</description>
      <author>Dean K Zacharis, Dongye Zhao, Latha Ganti</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.68250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A machine-learning interatomic potential to study dry/wet oxidation process of silicon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219764</link>
      <description>Huyang Li, Yuhang Jing, Zhongli Liu, Lingzhi Cong, Junqing Zhao, Yi Sun, Weiqi Li, Jihong Yan, Jianqun Yang, Xingji Li, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402194389

                We developed an accurate and efficient machine learning potential with DFT accuracy and applied it to the silicon dry/wet oxidation process to investigate the underlying physics of thermal oxidation of silicon (001) surfaces. The accuracy of the potential was verified by comparing the melting point and structural properties of silicon, the structural properties of a-SiO2, and the adsorption properties on the silicon surface with experiment and DFT data. In subsequent thermal oxidation simulations, we successfully reproduced the accelerated growth phenomenon of the wet oxidation in the experiment, discussed the oxide growth process in detail, and elucidated that the accelerated growth is due to hydrogen in the system that both enhances the adsorption of oxygen on the silicon surface and promotes the migration of oxygen atoms. Finally, we annealed the oxidized structure, counted the defect information in the structure before and after annealing, and analyzed the defect evolution behavior during the annealing process.</description>
      <author>Huyang Li, Yuhang Jing, Zhongli Liu, Lingzhi Cong, Junqing Zhao, Yi Sun, Weiqi Li, Jihong Yan, Jianqun Yang, Xingji Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Verification of Key Physical Models in Oxide Fuel Performance Analysis Code FEATURE Based on COMSOL</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00295639.2024.2384225</link>
      <description>Rui Yu, Guan Wang, Wei Jiang, Yanlei Zhu, Changping Qin, Long Gu, Nuclear Science and Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402077524

                Nuclear performance analysis is of great significance for fuel design optimization and the safe operation of a reactor. Considering the design requirements of the China initiative Accelerator Driven System (CiADS) project, it is necessary to develop relevant fuel performance analysis tools to predict fuel performance evolution during service. The Fuel Element Analysis Tool for Undercritical Reactor Engineering (FEATURE) code, based on the advanced multiphysics coupling platform COMSOL software, is under development in this context, with a current focus on oxide fuel for fast reactors. This paper mainly conducts preliminary comparative verification of the oxygen redistribution, plutonium redistribution, and fission gas release modules of the FEATURE code through model examples, code-to-code evaluation, and experimental data. The results indicate that the FEATURE code exhibits good accuracy and reliability in simulating oxygen and plutonium redistribution, as well as fission gas release, making it suitable for integrated coupling calculations.</description>
      <author>Rui Yu, Guan Wang, Wei Jiang, Yanlei Zhu, Changping Qin, Long Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00295639.2024.2384225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational modelling of water-fuelled Hall Effect Thrusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4874324/v1</link>
      <description>J. Tejeda, Jes&#250;s Perales-D&#237;az, Aaron Knoll, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402146425

                Abstract This paper presents a Particle-In-Cell code designed for the simulation of water-fuelled Hall Effect Thrusters, including two different propellants: water vapour and oxygen (the latter being intended for water electrolysis propulsion with oxygen supplied through the anode and hydrogen through the cathode). The reactive model is structured in two stages, encompassing not only the initial reactions of water vapour and oxygen molecules (1st stage) but also the reactions of the diatomic and monoatomic products resulting from them (2nd stage). Specifically, the model accounts for 45 reactions in the case of water vapour and 18 reactions in the case of oxygen, including the most relevant excitation events for each species. The Particle-In-Cell code uses a combination of a 0-dimensional model with a 2-dimensional model. The 0-dimensional model provides initial neutral and electron densities, as well as the most significant reactions, to facilitate the convergence of the 2-dimensional model without the computational burden of starting a simulation from scratch. The 0-dimensional model reveals that the reactions considered within the 2nd stage are crucial for the plasma species composition of the discharge. The oxygen plasmas consist mainly of O+ and O2+ ions in a similar proportion, while double and negative ions do not play a significant role. Neutrals (O2 and O) also show similar distributions, depending on the thruster&#8217;s operating conditions. Water vapour plasmas are dominated by OH+ , H2O+ , H+ , and O+ ions, with other species such as H2+ , O++ , and negative ions being negligible. The neutral population is predominantly composed of monoatomic H particles. The O-dimensional model also demonstrates that all ionisation fractions of the species follow an exponentially increasing trend with the electron temperature. Finally, the 2-dimensional model provides additional insight into the plasma evolution, electron temperature, power losses coming from the reactive model and equilibrium points of the system.</description>
      <author>J. Tejeda, Jes&#250;s Perales-D&#237;az, Aaron Knoll</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4874324/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapid transition from subduction to Barrovian metamorphism: geochronology of mafic&#8211;ultramafic relicts of oceanic crust in the Central Alps, Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s00015-024-00462-7</link>
      <description>Kim Lemke, Daniela Rubatto, J&#246;rg Hermann, Swiss Journal of Geosciences. 117(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402055395

                Relicts of subducted oceanic lithosphere provide key information for the tectonic reconstructions of convergent margins. In the Central Alps, such relicts occur as isolated mafic-ultramafic lenses within the migmatites of the southern Adula nappe and Cima-Lunga unit. Analysis of the major-, minor-, and accessory minerals of these ophiolitic relicts, combined with zircon and rutile U-Pb ages and zircon oxygen isotopes, allows the reconstruction of different stages of their complex evolution. The mafic-ultramafic suite in Valle di Moleno consists of chlorite-harzburgites associated with metarodingites and retrogressed eclogites. Relic omphacite and kyanite in retrogressed eclogites provide evidence for subduction-related metamorphism. Increasing X</description>
      <author>Kim Lemke, Daniela Rubatto, J&#246;rg Hermann</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s00015-024-00462-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply on RC1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1983-cc1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402142152

                Abstract. The Devonian is a warmer-than-present geological period spanning from 419 to 359 million years ago (Ma) characterized by multiple identified ocean anoxic/hypoxic events. Despite decades of extensive investigation, no consensus has been reached regarding the drivers of these anoxic events. While growing geological evidence has demonstrated a temporal correlation between astronomical forcing and anoxia during this period, underlying physical mechanisms remain unknown, hence questioning causality. Here, we perform multiple sensitivity experiments, using an Earth system model of intermediate complexity (cGENIE), to isolate the influences of specific Devonian climate and palaeogeography components on ocean oxygen levels, contributing to the better understanding of the intricate interplay of factors preconditioning the ocean to anoxia. We quantify the impact of continental configuration, ocean-atmosphere biogeochemistry (global mean oceanic PO4 concentration and atmospheric pO2), climatic forcing (pCO2) and astronomical forcing on background oceanic circulation and oxygenation during the Devonian. Our results indicate that continental configuration is crucial for Devonian ocean anoxia, significantly influencing ocean circulation and oxygen levels while consistently modulating the effects of other Devonian climate components such as oceanic PO4 concentration, atmospheric pO2 and pCO2, and orbital forcing. The evolution of continental configuration provides a plausible explanation for the increased frequency of ocean anoxic events identified during the Middle and Late Devonian periods, as it contributed to the expansion of oxygen-depleted zones. Our simulations also show that both the decreased atmospheric pO2 and increased oceanic PO2 concentration exacerbate ocean anoxia, consistent with established knowledge. The variation of pCO2 reveals a wide range of ocean dynamics patterns, including stable oscillations, multiple convection cells, multistability and hysteresis; all leading to significant variations of the ocean oxygen levels, therefore strongly impacting the preconditioning of the ocean to anoxia. Furthermore, multistability and important hysteresis (particularly slow ocean time response) offer different mechanisms to account for the prolonged duration of some ocean anoxic events. Finally, we found that astronomical forcing substantially impacts ocean anoxia by altering ocean circulation and oxygen solubility, with obliquity consistently emerging as the primary orbital parameter driving ocean oxygen variations.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1983-cc1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline Oxygen-Modified Carbon Nitride Photocatalyst with Enhanced Internal Electric Field and Strong Resistance to Ionic Interference for Robust Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03031</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, N. Cao, Xiaoming Liu, Fengting He, Yang&#8208;Ming Lu, Shuling Wang, Chaocheng Zhao, Yongqiang Wang, Jinqiang Zhang, Shaobin Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079090

                Photocatalytic seawater splitting to produce clean hydrogen from nonpotable water using sunlight is a crucial endeavor. However, the scarcity of high-performance photocatalysts in the promising yet fledgling field presents a formidable challenge. Herein, we successfully synthesized a crystalline oxygen-modified carbon nitride (CCNO) polymeric semiconductor that served as an effective photocatalyst for seawater splitting. Comprehensive characterizations and theoretical calculations revealed that nitrogen vacancies and bridging oxygen in the CCNO lattice acted as potent Lewis acid&#8211;base pairs, creating an enhanced built-in electric field. This advancement significantly accelerated charge dynamics and bolstered resistance to ionic interference in seawater. Consequently, CCNO exhibited a robust photocatalytic H2 evolution activity of 29.51 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 in natural seawater, with an impressive apparent quantum efficiency of 66.86% under 420 nm monochromatic light. Seawater splitting for H2 production reached 16.83 mmol g&#8211;1 under natural light irradiation for 3 h (9&#8211;12 o'clock), showcasing its great potential for practical applications. This work presents strategies for developing a metal-free photocatalyst and elucidates its reaction mechanism in the seawater splitting process, laying the foundation for scalable production of clean hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, N. Cao, Xiaoming Liu, Fengting He, Yang&#8208;Ming Lu, Shuling Wang, Chaocheng Zhao, Yongqiang Wang, Jinqiang Zhang, Shaobin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen reduction reaction coupled electro&#8208;oxidation for highly&#8208;efficient and sustainable water treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414481</link>
      <description>Ran Xiao, Hehe Qin, Xiangyun Liu, Chengcheng Chu, Qiuju Li, Hongying Zhao, Shun Mao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402245388

                Electro&#8208;oxidation (EO) technology demonstrates significant potential in wastewater treatment. However, the high energy consumption has become a pivotal constraint hindering its large&#8208;scale implementation. Herein, we design an EO and 4&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction coupled system (EO&#8208;4eORR) to replace the traditional EO and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) coupled system (EO&#8208;HER). The theoretical cathodic potential of the electrolytic reactor is tuned from 0 V (vs. RHE) in HER to 1.23 V (vs. RHE) in 4eORR, which greatly decreases the required operation voltage of the reactor. Moreover, we demonstrate that convection can improve the mass transfer of oxygen and organic pollutants in the reaction system, leading to low cathodic polarization and high pollutant removal rate. Compared with traditional EO&#8208;HER system, the energy consumption of the EO&#8208;4eORR system under air aeration for 95% total organic carbon (TOC) removal is greatly decreased to 2.61 kWh/kgTOC (only consider the electrolyzer energy consumption), which is superior to previously reported EO&#8208;based water treatment systems. The reported results in this study offer a new technical mode for development of highly efficient and sustainable EO&#8208;based treatment systems to remove organic pollutants in waste water.</description>
      <author>Ran Xiao, Hehe Qin, Xiangyun Liu, Chengcheng Chu, Qiuju Li, Hongying Zhao, Shun Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidation Behavior of Lightweight Al0.2CrNbTiV High Entropy Alloy Coating Deposited by High-Speed Laser Cladding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14091104</link>
      <description>Tianhui Chen, Zhijiang Bi, Ji Zhou, Ruohui Shuai, Zhihai Cai, Liyan Lou, Haidou Wang, Zhiguo Xing, Coatings. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402135342

                High-temperature oxidation resistance is the major influence on the high-temperature service stability of refractory high entropy alloys. The oxidation behavior of lightweight Al0.2CrNbTiV refractory high entropy alloy coatings with different dilution ratios at 650 &#176;C and 800 &#176;C deposited by high-speed laser cladding was analyzed in this paper. The oxidation kinetic was analyzed, the oxidation resistance mechanism of the Al0.2CrNbTiV coating was clarified with the analysis of the formation and evolution of the oxidation layer, and the effect of the dilution rate on high-temperature performances was revealed. The results showed that the oxide layer was mainly composed of rutile oxides (Ti, Cr, Nb)O2 after isothermal oxidation at 650 &#176;C and 800 &#176;C for 50 h. The Al0.2CrNbTiV coating in low dilution exhibited better oxidation performance at 650 &#176;C, due to the dense oxide layer formed with the synergistic growth of fine AlVO3 particles and (Ti, Cr, Nb)O2, and higher percentage of Cr, Nb in (Ti, Cr, Nb)O2 strengthened the lattice distortion effect to inhibit the penetration of oxygen. The oxide layer formed at 800 &#176;C for the Al0.2CrNbTiV coating was relatively loose, but the oxidation performance of the coating in high dilution improved due to the precipitation of Cr2Nb-type Laves phases along grain boundaries, which inhibits the diffusion of oxygen.</description>
      <author>Tianhui Chen, Zhijiang Bi, Ji Zhou, Ruohui Shuai, Zhihai Cai, Liyan Lou, Haidou Wang, Zhiguo Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14091104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure Evolution and Oxidation Behavior of Thermal Barrier Coatings with Varying Cold Sprayed Bond Coats after Isothermal Heat Treatments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31399/asm.cp.itsc2024p0376</link>
      <description>S. Dosta, Carlos Roberto Camello Lima, V. Crespo, Jaume Nin, Genis Clav&#233;, Thermal spray. 84864(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402154422

                Abstract Bond coats are used to protect the superalloy from oxidation and to serve as a bond between the ceramic thermal barrier coating (TBC) layer and the superalloy. During high temperature exposures, a thermally grown oxide (TGO) layer forms between the bond coat and the topcoat due to oxygen diffusion, leading to coating failure in the components. This study aimed to investigate the microstructure evolution of three TBCs with different cold-sprayed bond coat alloys after undergoing isothermal heat treatments. The TBCs were heat treated at 1100 &#176;C for durations of 12, 25, and 50 hours to observe the effects of temperature on the microstructure and phase distribution. The microstructure of heat-treated bond coat alloys was examined using scanning electron microscopy and x-ray diffraction. The findings are discussed in relation to the characteristics of the coating alloy and the application process.</description>
      <author>S. Dosta, Carlos Roberto Camello Lima, V. Crespo, Jaume Nin, Genis Clav&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31399/asm.cp.itsc2024p0376</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversity and Ecological Functions of Anthocyanins</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.2272.v1</link>
      <description>Nele Gr&#252;nig, Jakob Maximilian Horz, Boas Pucker, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402116169

                Anthocyanins are well known as colorants of flowers, but many other invisible functions might have been more important during the evolution of complex biosynthesis networks in plants. The number of anthocyanin decorating enzymes, the subtle control of structural genes by numerous transcription factors, and routes of intracellular anthocyanin transport are reviewed here. Various ecological functions of anthocyanins hold the key to understanding evolutionary trajectories that lead to the success of these pigments. Proposed functions include carbon sinks that prevent excessive sugar levels, sun blockers protecting the photosynthesis apparatus, antioxidants scavenging reactive oxygen species, providing camouflage, and attraction of pollinators and seed dispersers. Anthocyanins clearly fulfill different functions in different plant organs. It is currently believed that protective functions in leaves gave rise to the biosynthesis network and that flower and fruit coloration evolved later.</description>
      <author>Nele Gr&#252;nig, Jakob Maximilian Horz, Boas Pucker</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.2272.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoacoustic Spectrum Analysis for Soft Tissues</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-61411-8_16</link>
      <description>Yingna Chen, Shiying Wu, Qian Zhang, Jiayan Li, Menglu Qian, Qian Cheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402193119

                Abstract Biomedical photoacoustics has shown great potential for precise medical diagnosis because it can provide structural, physiological/pathological characteristics, and metabolic information of biological tissues noninvasively in vivo. Photoacoustic imaging has made great breakthroughs in many preclinical studies, including microvascular imaging, blood oxygen detection, and tumor detection. However, compared with photoacoustic imaging, the photoacoustic spectrum can provide more information, such as the rich molecular information in the optical spectrum and the rich microstructural information in the ultrasonic spectrum, which is closely related to the disease evolution process. Recently, photoacoustic spectrum analysis (PASA) has demonstrated the ability to quantitatively extract physicochemical information from biological tissues to distinguish between normal and diseased tissues, especially for classifying, grading, and staging cancer tissue, making it one of the most promising methods for noninvasive, accurate diagnosis of clinical diseases. In this chapter, we introduce the methods of PASA for the diagnosis of soft tissue diseases.</description>
      <author>Yingna Chen, Shiying Wu, Qian Zhang, Jiayan Li, Menglu Qian, Qian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-61411-8_16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;POM&lt;/scp&gt; &#8208;based Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527842711.ch8</link>
      <description>In&#234;s S. Marques, Renata Matos, Diana M. Fernandes, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402030867

                This chapter is related to the application of polyoxometalates (POMs), POM-based composites and POM-derived electrocatalysts in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This reaction is a crucial part of the water splitting and, therefore, fundamental for hydrogen electroproduction. Given that POMs are made of transition-metal (TM) oxygen anion clusters with a d 0 electronic structure, they are the most promising class of hydrogen evolution electrocatalysts. Herein is presented a brief description of the HER process, while the important role of POMs electrocatalysts towards HER is discussed in detail. This chapter is organized in five sections, namely HER (Section 8.1), POMs electrocatalysts (Section 8.2), composites/hybrids materials (Section 8.3), POM-derived electrocatalysts (Section 8.4) and concluding remarks (Section 8.5). In the first section, the HER mechanism, state-of-the-art electrocatalysts and important electrochemical parameters to be evaluated are described. In the second section, the advantages of POMs as HER electrocatalysts are discussed, along with several examples of POMs application in HER. The third section is related to the most common POM-based composites used in HER electrocatalysis, namely POM/carbon, POM/metal organic frameworks (MOF), POM/metal and POM/polymers. The fourth section encompasses several classes of HER electrocatalysts obtained using POMs as metal precursor, including single-atom catalysts (SACs) and TM carbides, chalcogens, nitrates, phosphates and oxides. Lastly, the fifth section consists of an overview of the discussed electrocatalysts and the main results, also including some proposed future perspectives for POM-based/derived electrocatalysts towards HER.</description>
      <author>In&#234;s S. Marques, Renata Matos, Diana M. Fernandes</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527842711.ch8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A biomimetic upconversion nanoreactors for near-infrared driven H2 release to inhibit tauopathy in Alzheimer's disease therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioactmat.2024.08.029</link>
      <description>Qin Zhang, Chuanqi Li, Bohan Yin, Jiaxiang Yan, Yutian Gu, Yingying Huang, Jiareng Chen, Xinyue Lao, Jianhua Hao, Changqing Yi, Yi Zhou, James Chung&#8208;Wai Cheung, Siu Hong Dexter Wong, Mo Yang, Bioactive Materials. 42(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402052229

                Abnormal hyperphosphorylation of tau protein is a principal pathological hallmark in the onset of neurodegenerative disorders, such as Alzheimer's disease (AD), which can be induced by an excess of reactive oxygen species (ROS). As an antioxidant, hydrogen gas (H2) has the potential to mitigate AD by scavenging highly harmful ROS such as &#8226;OH. However, conventional administration methods of H2 face significant challenges in controlling H2 release on demand and fail to achieve effective accumulation at lesion sites. Herein, we report artificial nanoreactors that mimic natural photosynthesis to realize near-infrared (NIR) light-driven photocatalytic H2 evolution in situ. The nanoreactors are constructed by biocompatible crosslinked vesicles (CVs) encapsulating ascorbic acid and two photosensitizers, chlorophyll a (Chla) and indoline dye (Ind). In addition, platinum nanoparticles (Pt NPs) serve as photocatalysts and upconversion nanoparticles (UCNP) act as light-harvesting antennas in the nanoreacting system, and both attach to the surface of CVs. Under NIR irradiation, the nanoreactors release H2 in situ to scavenge local excess ROS and attenuate tau hyperphosphorylation in the AD mice model. Such NIR-triggered nanoreactors provide a proof-of-concept design for the great potential of hydrogen therapy against AD.</description>
      <author>Qin Zhang, Chuanqi Li, Bohan Yin, Jiaxiang Yan, Yutian Gu, Yingying Huang, Jiareng Chen, Xinyue Lao, Jianhua Hao, Changqing Yi, Yi Zhou, James Chung&#8208;Wai Cheung, Siu Hong Dexter Wong, Mo Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioactmat.2024.08.029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROS: A &#8220;booster&#8221; for chronic inflammation and tumor metastasis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbcan.2024.189175</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Li, Haifeng Huang, S. S. Fang, Qinglei Hang, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA) - Reviews on Cancer. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402091987

                Reactive oxygen species (ROS) are a group of highly active molecules produced by normal cellular metabolism and play a crucial role in the human body. In recent years, researchers have increasingly discovered that ROS plays a vital role in the progression of chronic inflammation and tumor metastasis. The inflammatory tumor microenvironment established by chronic inflammation can induce ROS production through inflammatory cells. ROS can then directly damage DNA or indirectly activate cellular signaling pathways to promote tumor metastasis and development, including breast cancer, lung cancer, liver cancer, colorectal cancer, and so on. This review aims to elucidate the relationship between ROS, chronic inflammation, and tumor metastasis, explaining how chronic inflammation can induce tumor metastasis and how ROS can contribute to the evolution of chronic inflammation toward tumor metastasis. Interestingly, ROS can have a "double-edged sword" effect, promoting tumor metastasis in some cases and inhibiting it in others. This article also highlights the potential applications of ROS in inhibiting tumor metastasis and enhancing the precision of tumor-targeted therapy. Combining ROS with nanomaterials strategies may be a promising approach to enhance the efficacy of tumor treatment.</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Li, Haifeng Huang, S. S. Fang, Qinglei Hang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbcan.2024.189175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of ultrahigh-performance barium titanate-based piezoelectrics: Stannum-induced intrinsic and extrinsic contributions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52031-z</link>
      <description>Bo Wu, Huijing Zheng, Yutao Wu, Zhicheng Huang, Hao&#8208;Cheng Thong, Tao Hong, Wei Wang, Chunlin Zhao, Ze Xu, Yixuan Liu, Zhipeng Xing, Naixin Liang, Fang&#8208;Zhou Yao, Chaofeng Wu, Ke Wang, Bing Han, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402245657

                Despite the pivotal role of stannum doping in achieving ultrahigh piezoelectric performance in barium titanate-based ceramics, the fundamental mechanisms underlying this enhancement remain elusive. Here, we introduce a single variable nonstoichiometric stannum strategy in lead-free barium titanate-based ceramics with giant piezoelectricity, revealing that stannum doping contributes intrinsically and extrinsically to enhance piezoelectricity. Density functional theory calculations elucidate the intrinsic enhancement of polarization arising from lattice distortion and increased space for titanium-oxygen bonds induced by optimal stannum doping, which is corroborated by Rayleigh analysis. A phase transition from ferroelectric multiphase coexistence to paraelectric phase is observed, alongside a rapid miniaturized and eventually disappeared domains with increasing stannum doping. This evolution in phase structure and domain configuration induces a nearly vanishing polarization anisotropy and low domain wall energy, facilitating easy polarization rotation and domain wall motion, thereby significantly contributing to the extrinsic piezoelectric response. Consequently, the origins of ultrahigh performance can be attributed to the synergistic effect of stannum-induced intrinsic and extrinsic contributions in barium titanate-based ceramics. This study provides fundamental insights into the role of doping elements and offers guidance for the design of high-performance piezoelectrics.</description>
      <author>Bo Wu, Huijing Zheng, Yutao Wu, Zhicheng Huang, Hao&#8208;Cheng Thong, Tao Hong, Wei Wang, Chunlin Zhao, Ze Xu, Yixuan Liu, Zhipeng Xing, Naixin Liang, Fang&#8208;Zhou Yao, Chaofeng Wu, Ke Wang, Bing Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52031-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction&#8208;Driven Migration Dynamics of Nano&#8208;Metal Particles Unraveled by Quantitative Electron Microscopies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405759</link>
      <description>Zhao Bing, Fan Zhang, Deyang Gao, Gang Meng, Hua Li, Wei Liu, Mao Ye, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402145368

                Abstract The stability of supported nano&#8208;metal catalysts holds significant importance in both scientific and economic practice, beyond the long pursuit of enhanced activity. While previous efforts have concentrated on augmenting the interaction between nano&#8208;metals and carriers, in the thermodynamic macro&#8208;perspective, to achieve optimized repression upon particle migration coalescence and Ostwald ripening, nevertheless, the microscale kinetics of migrating catalyst particles driven by the reaction remains unknown. In this work, the migration of nano&#8208;copper particles is investigated during hydrogen oxidation reaction by utilizing high spatiotemporal resolution of environmental transmission electron microscopy. It is shown that there exists a delicate correlation between the migration dynamics of nano&#8208;copper particles and the evolution of asymmetrically distributed Cu and Cu 2 O phases over the particle surface. It is found that the interplay of reduction and oxidation near the surface areas filled with Cu and Cu 2 O phases can facilitate the pressure gradient, which drives the migration of nano&#8208;particles. A driving force model is therefore established which is capable of qualitatively explaining the influences of reaction conditions such as temperature and hydrogen&#8208;to&#8208;oxygen ratio on the reaction&#8208;driven particle migration. This work adds a potential yet critical perspective to understanding particle migration and thus the nano&#8208;metal catalyst particle sintering in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Zhao Bing, Fan Zhang, Deyang Gao, Gang Meng, Hua Li, Wei Liu, Mao Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave&#8208;Assisted PtRu Alloying on Defective Tungsten Oxide: A Pathway to Improved Hydroxyl Dynamics for Highly&#8208;Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402372</link>
      <description>Bowen Zhou, Juping Wang, Lingfei Guo, Hongdong Li, Weiping Xiao, Guangrui Xu, Dehong Chen, Caixia Li, Yunmei Du, Hao Ding, Hongwei Huang, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402206759

                Abstract Platinum (Pt)&#8208;based compounds are the benchmarked catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) but exhibit slow kinetics in alkaline environments. The * OH accumulation on Pt surface can block active sites, affecting proton reduction and water re&#8208;adsorption. Alloying Ruthenium (Ru) with Pt sites can significantly modulate the adsorption and desorption of water dissociation intermediates. Choosing suitable supports and utilizing metal&#8208;support interaction (MSI) is crucial for active site optimization. PtRu alloy anchored on tungsten oxide (WO 3 ) with rich oxygen vacancies (O V ) is prepared through an ultrafast microwave&#8208;assisted approach. Benefiting from the coupling effects between alloying and MSI, PtRu/WO 3 &#8208;O V exhibits exceptionally high HER activity. In 1 m KOH, 1 m KOH + seawater, and 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 , it requires ultralow overpotentials of 9, 26, and 6 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The designed catalyst surpasses commercial Pt/C in mass activity and demonstrates considerable potential for intermittent energy integration. Density functional theory reveals that alloying Ru with Pt sites significantly reduces the energy barrier of dissociating * OH, modulating blockage on the surface and then promoting the overall alkaline HER process. This study offers insights into the rapid synthesis of non&#8208;carbon supported catalysts with Pt site modulation for alkaline hydrogen generation.</description>
      <author>Bowen Zhou, Juping Wang, Lingfei Guo, Hongdong Li, Weiping Xiao, Guangrui Xu, Dehong Chen, Caixia Li, Yunmei Du, Hao Ding, Hongwei Huang, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Re)mind the gap: A hiatus in star formation history unveiled by APOGEE DR17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450754</link>
      <description>E. Spitoni, F. Matteucc&#237;, R. Gratton, Bridget Ratcliffe, I. Minchev, G. Cescutti, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402038037

                Analysis of several spectroscopic surveys indicates the presence of a bimodality between the disc stars in the abundance ratio space of alpha /Fe versus Fe/H . The two stellar groups are commonly referred to as the high-alpha and low-alpha sequences. Some models capable of reproducing such a bimodality invoke the presence of a hiatus in the star formation history in our Galaxy, whereas other models explain the two sequences by means of stellar migration. Our aim is to show that the existence of the gap in the star formation rate between high-alpha and low-alpha is evident in the stars of APOGEE DR17, if one plots Fe/alpha versus alpha /H confirming previous suggestions. We then try to interpret the data by means of detailed chemical models. We compare the APOGEE DR17 red giant stars with the predictions of a detailed chemical evolution model based on the two-infall paradigm, taking into account also the possible accretion of dwarf satellites. The APOGEE DR17 abundance ratios Fe/alpha versus alpha /H exhibit a sharp increase in Fe/alpha at a nearly constant alpha /H (where alpha elements considered are Mg, Si, O) during the transition between the two disc phases. This observation strongly supports the hypothesis that a hiatus in star formation occurred during this evolutionary phase. Notably, the most pronounced growth in the Fe/alpha versus alpha /H relation is observed for oxygen, as this element is exclusively synthesised in core-collapse supernovae. The revised version of the two-infall chemical evolution model proposed in this study reproduces the APOGEE DR17 abundance ratios better than before. Particularly noteworthy is the model's ability to predict the hiatus in the star formation between the two infalls of gas, which form the thick and thin disc, respectively, and thus generate abundance ratios compatible with APOGEE DR17 data. We show that the signature of a hiatus in the star formation is imprinted in the APOGEE DR17 abundance ratios. A chemical model predicting a pause in the star formation of a duration of roughly 3.5 Gyr, and in which the high-alpha disc starts forming from pre-enriched gas by a previous encounter with a dwarf galaxy, could well explain the observations</description>
      <author>E. Spitoni, F. Matteucc&#237;, R. Gratton, Bridget Ratcliffe, I. Minchev, G. Cescutti</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human&#8211;exoskeleton interaction portrait</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12984-024-01447-1</link>
      <description>Mohammad Shushtari, Julia Foellmer, Arash Arami, Journal of NeuroEngineering and Rehabilitation. 21(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402240792

                Abstract Human&#8211;robot physical interaction contains crucial information for optimizing user experience, enhancing robot performance, and objectively assessing user adaptation. This study introduces a new method to evaluate human&#8211;robot interaction and co-adaptation in lower limb exoskeletons by analyzing muscle activity and interaction torque as a two-dimensional random variable. We introduce the interaction portrait (IP), which visualizes this variable&#8217;s distribution in polar coordinates. We applied IP to compare a recently developed hybrid torque controller (HTC) based on kinematic state feedback and a novel adaptive model-based torque controller (AMTC) with online learning, proposed herein, against a time-based controller (TBC) during treadmill walking at varying speeds. Compared to TBC, both HTC and AMTC significantly lower users&#8217; normalized oxygen uptake, suggesting enhanced user-exoskeleton coordination. IP analysis reveals that this improvement stems from two distinct co-adaptation strategies, unidentifiable by traditional muscle activity or interaction torque analyses alone. HTC encourages users to yield control to the exoskeleton, decreasing overall muscular effort but increasing interaction torque, as the exoskeleton compensates for user dynamics. Conversely, AMTC promotes user engagement through increased muscular effort and reduces interaction torques, aligning it more closely with rehabilitation and gait training applications. IP phase evolution provides insight into each user&#8217;s interaction strategy formation, showcasing IP analysis&#8217;s potential in comparing and designing novel controllers to optimize human&#8211;robot interaction in wearable robots.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Shushtari, Julia Foellmer, Arash Arami</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12984-024-01447-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fluid Evolution in the Skarn Stages of the Baoshan Skarn Cu-Polymetallic Deposit, South China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min14090907</link>
      <description>Ping Zheng, Ke Chen, Junke Zhang, Zhongfa Liu, Yongshun Li, Mingpeng He, Minerals. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402279431

                Baoshan is a world-class skarn Cu-polymetallic deposit located at the junction of the Nanling and Qin-Hang metallogenic belts in China. While there has been extensive research on the mineralogy and geochemistry of skarn deposits, studies on the fluid characteristics and evolutionary history from the early to late skarn stages in such deposits are still limited. In this study, we analyzed garnet and pyroxene from the early skarn stage and scheelite from the late skarn stage of the Baoshan deposit. We distinguished two generations of garnet (Grt1 and Grt2), one generation of pyroxene, and three generations of scheelite (Sch I, Sch II, and Sch III) on the basis of mineral assemblages and microscopic characteristics. Grt1 appears coarse-grained, and Grt2 cuts through Grt1 as veinlets. In Grt1, the andradite end-member increases from the core to the rim, while the grossular portion decreases (Ad35&#8211;36Gr59&#8211;61Sp3&#8211;4 to Ad59&#8211;61Gr36&#8211;37Sp2&#8211;3), and in Grt2, the andradite end-member significantly increases (Ad41&#8211;73Gr25&#8211;55Sp2&#8211;3). Grt1 and Grt2 have similar trace element compositions, with enrichment in Zr and depletion in Nb and Hf, depletion in LREE, enrichment in HREE, and weak negative Eu anomalies. Pyroxene coexists with Grt1 and is similarly cut by Grt2, with its composition mainly being diopside (Di82&#8211;99Hd0.6&#8211;15Jo0&#8211;3.2). Sch I and Sch II appear as anhedral to subhedral grains, while Sch III is predominantly found in veinlets. In Sch I and Sch II, most REEs enter the scheelite lattice via the Na-REE coupled substitution mechanism, with a smaller portion substituting Ca vacancies. In Sch III, the substitution mechanism involving Ca site vacancies may dominate. During the early skarn stage, the oxygen fugacity of the fluid gradually decreased from Grt1 and pyroxene to Grt2. In the late skarn stage, fluid oxygen fugacity remains stable from Sch I and Sch II to Sch III in shallow parts but significantly decreases in deeper parts. The garnet and pyroxene from the Baoshan deposit align with typical skarn Cu deposit compositions, while scheelite in the late skarn stage shows Sch I, Sch II, and shallow Sch III as skarn-type and deep Sch III as vein-type scheelite. Early skarn stage fluids were weakly acidic. Sch I, Sch II, and Sch III originated from fluids related to the Baoshan granite porphyry, with Sch III also showing evidence of water&#8211;rock interaction. This study reconstructed the fluid evolution history from the early to late skarn stages at the Baoshan deposit, providing insights into the ore-forming processes of other skarn deposits.</description>
      <author>Ping Zheng, Ke Chen, Junke Zhang, Zhongfa Liu, Yongshun Li, Mingpeng He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min14090907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic modelling of UVC and UVC/H2O2 oxidation of an aqueous mixture of antibiotics in a completely mixed batch photoreactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-34812-7</link>
      <description>Fernando J. Beltr&#225;n, Ana M. Ch&#225;vez, M.A. Jim&#233;nez-L&#243;pez, Pedro M. &#193;lvarez, Environmental Science and Pollution Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402168631

                Abstract The removal kinetics of an aqueous mixture of thirteen antibiotics (i.e., ampicillin, cefuroxime, ciprofloxacin, flumequine, metronidazole, ofloxacin, oxytetracycline, sulfadimethoxine, sulfamethoxazole, sulfamethazine, tetracycline, trimethoprim and tylosin) by batch UV C and UV C /H 2 O 2 processes has been modeled in this work. First, molar absorption coefficients (&#949;), direct quantum yields (&#934;) and the rate constants of the reaction of antibiotics with hydroxyl radical (k HO&#8226; ) (model inputs) were determined for each antibiotic and compared with literature data. The values of these parameters range from 0.3 to 21.8 mM &#8722;1 cm &#8722;1 for &#949;, &lt; 0.01 to 67.8 mmol&#183;E &#8722;1 for &#934; and 3.8 &#215; 10 9 to 1.7 &#215; 10 10 M &#8722;1 s &#8722;1 for k HO&#8226; . Second, a regression model was developed to compute the rate constants of the reactions of the antibiotics with singlet oxygen (k 1 O&#8322; ) from experimental data obtained in batch UV C experiments treating a mixture of the antibiotics. k 1 O&#8322; values in the 1&#8211;50 &#215; 10 6 M &#8722;1 s &#8722;1 range were obtained for the antibiotics studied. Finally, a semi-empirical kinetic model comprising a set of ordinary differential equations was solved to simulate the evolution of the residual concentration of antibiotics and hydrogen peroxide (model outputs) in a completely mixed batch photoreactor. Model predictions were reasonably consistent with the experimental data. The kinetic model developed might be combined with computational fluid dynamics to predict process performance and energy consumption in UV C and UV C /H 2 O 2 applications at full scale.</description>
      <author>Fernando J. Beltr&#225;n, Ana M. Ch&#225;vez, M.A. Jim&#233;nez-L&#243;pez, Pedro M. &#193;lvarez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-34812-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factors Associated With the Intubation of Patients With Acute Respiratory Failure and Their Impact on Mortality: a Retrospective Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4768432/v1</link>
      <description>F&#225;bio Barlem Hohmann, Thais Dias Midega, Ricardo Esper Treml, Vin&#237;cius Barbosa Galindo, G Veiga, Isla R.M. Machado, Manfred Kraft, Sandra Cust&#243;dio, E Paolinelli, Felipe Galdino, Jo&#227;o Manoel Silva, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402171003

                Abstract Introduction: Severe respiratory failure often requires intubation and invasive mechanical ventilation. Identifying the factors that lead to this need is crucial, but there are few studies on the evolution of these factors from the onset of symptoms to respiratory failure. This study aims to identify risk factors for invasive mechanical ventilation as well as clinical outcomes in patients with acute respiratory failure considering the time from the onset of symptoms to respiratory failure. Methods Retrospective cohort study with patients hospitalized between May 1, 2020 and May 1, 2021. Patients over 18 years of age admitted to Intermediate and Intensive Care Units with positive polymerase chain reaction for SARS-CoV-2, chest computed tomography and inflammatory markers performed within 72 hours of admission were included. Patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease using home oxygen, intubation not related to Covid-19, heart failure, previous tracheostomy and hospitalization of less than 24 hours were excluded. The main outcome was to identify the factors that determined tracheal intubation and the evolution of these patients. Results Of the 852 patients treated, 302 were excluded, leaving 550, of which 346 required intubation. Intubated patients had a higher body mass index (p = 0.02), a higher SAPS-3 (p &lt; 0.001) and a shorter time from symptom onset to hospitalization (p &lt; 0.001). Until the eighth day of hospitalization, these patients had higher levels of C-Reactive Protein (p &lt; 0.001), Interleukin-6 (p = 0.003) and D-dimer (p &lt; 0.001). Chest computed tomography scans revealed a larger area of &#8203;&#8203;lung injury since admission. In the Cox model, SAPS-3 (HR = 1.028, 95%CI 1.002&#8211;1.055, p = 0.038) and time to intubation (HR = 1.118, 95%CI 1.021&#8211;1.224, p = 0.016) were independent risk factors for mortality. Patients intubated 15 days after the onset of symptoms had a higher risk of mortality (OR = 2.13, 95% CI 1.07&#8211;4.23). At intubation, the average respiratory rate was 27.5 breaths per minute, with 85% of FiO2 and ROX index of 4.37. The use of non-invasive ventilatory support was longer in the quartile with more than 15 days until intubation (median of 5 [3&#8211;7] days) and the use of a high-flow nasal cannula was associated with a longer time to decide to intubate (p = 0.002). Conclusion In patients with Covid-19 and acute respiratory failure, later intubation was associated with higher mortality. Non-invasive ventilatory support strategies can be used as long as there is no delay in using an invasive strategy when necessary.</description>
      <author>F&#225;bio Barlem Hohmann, Thais Dias Midega, Ricardo Esper Treml, Vin&#237;cius Barbosa Galindo, G Veiga, Isla R.M. Machado, Manfred Kraft, Sandra Cust&#243;dio, E Paolinelli, Felipe Galdino, Jo&#227;o Manoel Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4768432/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstract PR006: Liquid biopsy enables identification of mechanisms of tumor evolution in patients with newly diagnosed high-risk neuroblastoma: A report from the Children&#8217;s Oncology Group</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1158/1538-7445.pediatric24-pr006</link>
      <description>Gabriela Virdzekova, Kelly S. Klega, Kenneth J Boss, Patrick Reynolds, Arlene Naranjo, Elaine R. Mardis, Trevor J. Pugh, Mark A. Applebaum, Rochelle Bagatell, Gad Getz, Steven DuBoi, Brian Cromtpon, Cancer Research. 84(17_Supplement)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402266427

                Abstract Background: Neuroblastoma is the most common extracranial solid tumor diagnosed in children. Outcomes for high-risk neuroblastoma (HR-NB) have improved but causes of treatment-refractory disease and relapse are poorly understood. ANBL1531 is a Children&#8217;s Oncology Group phase 3 study that enrolled over 700 patients with HR-NB. Longitudinal liquid biopsy samples were collected to identify prognostic biomarkers and study patterns of tumor evolution that contribute to treatment resistance. Assessment of circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA) allows for non-invasive serial sequencing of the tumor genome using peripheral blood samples. We describe sequencing approaches and the progress of this ongoing work. Methods: Serial plasma samples were submitted to the Crompton lab for cell-free DNA sequencing by ultra-low passage whole genome sequencing (ULP-WGS) to estimate ctDNA content. To date, the Crompton lab has received 2,184 serial plasma samples. Samples with detectable ctDNA were also sequenced by whole-exome sequencing and a pan-cancer panel targeting 400 genes. We have performed deep pan-cancer panel sequencing on 188 longitudinal blood samples collected from 71 patients. Matched germline and primary tumor sequencing data are available for 56 and 49 of these patients, respectively. Paired baseline and relapse plasma samples with ctDNA &amp;gt; 20% were also sequenced by whole genome sequencing to detect relapse-specific changes in nucleosome positioning. Results: ULP-WGS showed that 332/335 patients (99.1%) with a pre-treatment blood sample had detectable ctDNA ranging between 3-99% of total cell-free DNA. ctDNA remained detectable in 84%, 37%, 27%, 3.1%, 2.9% and 0.7% of cases at pre-induction and pre-cycle 2, 3, 4, end-induction, prior to post-consolidation therapy, and end post-consolidation respectively. Paired analysis of sequencing data revealed heterogeneity in the somatic variants detected between primary tumor and ctDNA samples. Five out of 47 patients assigned to a treatment arm for patients with ALK wild-type HR-NB with available tumor and pre-treatment ctDNA sequencing data had somatic mutations in the ALK gene, however, 3 of these mutations were only detectable in ctDNA. We also detected recurrent mutations in RAS/RAF pathway, DNA damage repair pathway, and NOTCH pathway genes. Signature analysis of pre-treatment and relapse samples revealed presence of mismatch repair deficiency and reactive oxygen species signatures. Using nucleosome positioning we detected recurrent changes in the activity of specific transcription factor programs in relapse samples. Functional validation of prioritized relapse-specific ctDNA variants is ongoing and will also be reported. Conclusions: In summary, this research project bridges critical gaps in understanding the primary resistance mechanisms of HR-NB by employing a non-invasive methodology and comprehensive analysis of genomic and translational contributors to tumor evolution. These data provide an opportunity for the discovery of new therapeutic targets that could improve the outcome for patients with HR-NB. Citation Format: Gabriela Virdzekova, Kelly Klega, Kristopher Boss, Patrick Reynolds, Arlene Naranjo, Elaine Mardis, Trevor Pugh, Mark Applebaum, Rochelle Bagatell, Gad Getz, Steven DuBoi, Brian Cromtpon. Liquid biopsy enables identification of mechanisms of tumor evolution in patients with newly diagnosed high-risk neuroblastoma: A report from the Children&#8217;s Oncology Group [abstract]. In: Proceedings of the AACR Special Conference in Cancer Research: Advances in Pediatric Cancer Research; 2024 Sep 5-8; Toronto, Ontario, Canada. Philadelphia (PA): AACR; Cancer Res 2024;84(17 Suppl):Abstract nr PR006.</description>
      <author>Gabriela Virdzekova, Kelly S. Klega, Kenneth J Boss, Patrick Reynolds, Arlene Naranjo, Elaine R. Mardis, Trevor J. Pugh, Mark A. Applebaum, Rochelle Bagatell, Gad Getz, Steven DuBoi, Brian Cromtpon</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1158/1538-7445.pediatric24-pr006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium Substitutions in Garnet at Magmatic, Granulite Facies, and High-Pressure Granulite Facies Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2138/am-2024-9442</link>
      <description>Jay J. Ague, Duncan S. Keller, Michael R. Ackerson, Megan Holycross, American Mineralogist. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402049737

                Abstract Crystallographically oriented lamellar to acicular rutile &#177; ilmenite inclusions in garnet may record important information about the pressure (P), temperature (T), and petrotectonic evolution of the lithosphere. However, reading this record requires a robust understanding of titanium (Ti) substitution mechanisms and solubility in garnet. To this end, we examine the Ti substitution systematics revealed by 87 garnet analyses from previously published experimental studies relevant for granulites, high-pressure granulites, and deep crustal magmatic rocks. The experimental P&#8211;T conditions range mostly between 850&#8211;1230 &#176;C and 1.0&#8211;2.7 GPa; four 3.2 GPa, 1075&#8211;1150 &#176;C ultrahigh-P, ultrahigh-T examples are also included. We find that normalizing garnet formulas based on 2 octahedral sites per 12 oxygens provides better Fe3+ estimates than the standard 8-total-cation scheme. The Fe3+ must be constrained as both it and Ti substitute on octahedral sites. Graphical analysis reveals that the main substitutions are Tschermak-Ti (VITi4+ + IVAl3+ &#8596; VIAl3+ + IVSi4+) and Andradite (VIAl3+ &#8596; VIFe3+), with lesser but nonetheless important contributions by Andradite-Ti (VITi4+ + IVAl3+ &#8596; VIFe3+ + IVSi4+) and alkali-Ti (VITi4+ + VIII(Na+,K+) &#8596; VIAl3+ + VIIIM2+). Here, VIIIM2+ denotes dodecahedrally coordinated divalent cations (Ca, Fe2+, Mg, Mn). We also posit a small role for Ti substitution coupled to dodecahedral vacancies. These inferences were independently tested using a Monte Carlo modeling procedure developed herein that quantitatively reproduces both the nature and extent of the observed substitutions. We also compared the experimental data with a representative suite of natural garnet analyses. In general, the natural garnets have far lower Ti and alkali (Na &#177; K) contents than the experimental ones. We attribute this to Ti and alkali loss in nature during exhumation and cooling by processes including diffusion and interface-coupled dissolution-reprecipitation. Some fraction of the lost Ti can be hosted by exsolved precipitates of crystallographically oriented rutile &#177; ilmenite. However, in many cases, these are absent and the Ti must have left the garnet structure entirely. The lost alkalis may be hosted by exsolved amphibole or mica precipitates, but these are relatively uncommon suggesting that alkalis are typically transferred from garnet to the matrix or to non-precipitate inclusions.</description>
      <author>Jay J. Ague, Duncan S. Keller, Michael R. Ackerson, Megan Holycross</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2138/am-2024-9442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rheumatic Carditis in Children Aged 3 to 15 in the Pediatric Services of the Zinder National Hospital: Epidemiological, Clinical, Paraclinical, Therapeutic and Evolutionary Aspects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59324/ejtas.2024.2(4).78</link>
      <description>S.M. M'baye Salissou, Amadou Garba, I. Georges Thomas, Therese Nestor, Mariama Abdoulaye, H.L. Mianroh, H. Lawan, Samaila Aboubacar, Lisa Yon, V. Ndobo, S.N. Garba, Z&#233;lika Salifou Lankoande, Amadou Tour&#233;, European Journal of Theoretical and Applied Sciences. 2(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402045119

                Introduction. Rheumatic carditis (RC) is the set of acute manifestations of heart damage during acute joint rheumatism (RAA). It is one of the most common cardiovascular diseasesIn children and young adults and is a major public health problem in developing countries. The purpose of our study was to describe the epidemiological, clinical, paraclinical, therapeutic and evolutionary aspects of CR in the pediatric departments of the Zinder National Hospital (HNZ). Patients and method. It was a cross-sectional descriptive study with retro-prospective data collection spread over a period of 4 years. It concernedAll children aged 3 to 15 years admitted during the study period to the pediatric departments of the HNZ, suffering from the RAA retained on the modified Jones criteria (2015) and on cardiac echocardiography data. Treatment and analYse data were made using Word, Excel and Epi Info 7.2.5.0. Results. Our sample consisted of 39 cases of rheumatic heart disease out of a total of 31,951 hospitalized patients, a hospital prevalence of 0.12%.The average annual prevalence was 7.8 cases with two peaks observed in 2021 (13 cases) and 2022 (20 cases). The average age of patients was 9.05&#177;3.3 with extremes of 3 and 15 years. The sex ratio Was Of 1.1 in faVeur of male patients. The majority of the children (54%) came from rural areas and 61% of the parents of the respondents were not in school. More than half (52%) of our patients' parents had a low socio-economic level. The principals X reasons for consultation were dyspnea (64.1%), edema of the lower limbs (10.2%), palpitations (5.1%), cough (41%) and fever (53.8%). The notion of repeated angina was found in 76% of cases. On the paraclinical level, the elevation N of the CRP was observed in 72% of cases, the ASLO rate was positive in 82% of cases. Most patients (78%) had cardiomegaly. The Mitral insufficiency (I M ) Was The most found valve lesion (46.41%).Diuretics (87%), oxygen therapy (41%), antibiotic therapy (100%), hygienic-dietary measures (100%) were the most widely used therapeutic means. The evolution was marked by clinical stabilization in 76% of patients and survey Naked deaths in 23.07% of cases. Conclusion. Rheumatic heart disease Exists in the Zinder region. Late consultations worsen the prognosis of these patients in whom the surgical indication comes up against a limited technical platform, hence the interest of setting up an effective prevention program against acute joint rheumatism through the correct management of throat angina.</description>
      <author>S.M. M'baye Salissou, Amadou Garba, I. Georges Thomas, Therese Nestor, Mariama Abdoulaye, H.L. Mianroh, H. Lawan, Samaila Aboubacar, Lisa Yon, V. Ndobo, S.N. Garba, Z&#233;lika Salifou Lankoande, Amadou Tour&#233;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59324/ejtas.2024.2(4).78</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JOYS+: The link between the ice and gas of complex organic molecules. Comparing JWST and ALMA data of two low-mass protostars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450706</link>
      <description>Yuan Julian Chen, W. R. M. Rocha, E. F. van Dishoeck, M. L. van Gelder, P. Nazari, K. Slavicinska, Logan Francis, B. Tabone, Michael E. Ressler, Pamela Klaassen, H. Beuther, A. C. A. Boogert, C. Gieser, Patrick Kavanagh, G. Perotti, Valentin J. M. Le Gouellec, Liton Majumdar, M. G&#252;del, Thomas Henning, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402217635

                A rich inventory of complex organic molecules (COMs) has been observed in high abundances in the gas phase toward Class 0 protostars. It has been suggested that these molecules are formed in ices and sublimate in the warm inner envelope close to the protostar. However, only the most abundant COM, methanol ( CH3OH ), had been firmly detected in ices before the era of the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST). Now, it is possible to detect the interstellar ices of other COMs and constrain their ice column densities quantitatively. We aim to determine the column densities of several oxygen-bearing COMs (O-COMs) in both gas and ice for two low-mass protostellar sources, NGC 1333 IRAS 2A (hereafter IRAS 2A) and B1-c, as case studies in our JWST Observations of Young protoStars (JOYS+) program. By comparing the column density ratios with respect to CH3OH between both phases measured in the same sources, we can probe the evolution of COMs from ice to gas in the early stages of star formation. The column densities of COMs in gas and ice were derived by fitting the spectra observed by the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) and the JWST/Mid-InfraRed Instrument-Medium Resolution Spectroscopy (MIRI-MRS), respectively. The gas-phase emission lines were fit using local thermal equilibrium models, and the ice absorption bands were fit by matching the infrared spectra measured in laboratories. The column density ratios of four O-COMs ( CH3CHO C2H5OH CH3OCH3 and CH3OCHO ) with respect to CH3OH were compared between ice and gas in IRAS 2A and B1-c. We were able to fit the fingerprint range of COM ices between 6.8 and 8.8 $ m$ in the JWST/MIRI-MRS spectra of B1-c using similar components to the ones recently used for NGC 1333 IRAS 2A. We claim detection of CH4 OCN^- HCOO^- HCOOH CH3CHO C2H5OH CH3OCH3 CH3OCHO and CH3COCH3 in B1-c, and upper limits have been estimated for SO2 CH3COOH and CH3CN . The total abundance of O-COM ices is constrained to be 15&lt;!PCT!&gt; with respect to H2O ice, 80&lt;!PCT!&gt; of which is dominated by CH3OH . The comparison of O-COM ratios with respect to CH3OH between ice and gas shows two different cases. On the one hand, the column density ratios of CH3OCHO and CH3OCH3 match well between the two phases, which may be attributed to a direct inheritance from ice to gas or strong chemical links with CH3OH . On the other hand, the ice ratios of CH3CHO and C2H5OH with respect to CH3OH are higher than the gas ratios by 1--2 orders of magnitude. This difference can be explained by gas-phase reprocessing following sublimation, or different spatial distributions of COMs in the envelope, which is an observational effect resulting from ALMA and JWST tracing different components in a protostellar system. The firm detection of COM ices other than CH3OH is reported in another well-studied low-mass protostar, B1-c, following the recent detection in NGC 1333 IRAS 2A. The column density ratios of four O-COMs with respect to CH3OH show both similarities and differences between gas and ice. Although the straightforward explanations would be the direct inheritance from ice to gas and the gas-phase reprocessing, respectively, other possibilities such as different spatial distributions of molecules cannot be excluded.</description>
      <author>Yuan Julian Chen, W. R. M. Rocha, E. F. van Dishoeck, M. L. van Gelder, P. Nazari, K. Slavicinska, Logan Francis, B. Tabone, Michael E. Ressler, Pamela Klaassen, H. Beuther, A. C. A. Boogert, C. Gieser, Patrick Kavanagh, G. Perotti, Valentin J. M. Le Gouellec, Liton Majumdar, M. G&#252;del, Thomas Henning</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovations in Battery Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03085</link>
      <description>Greco Gonz&#225;lez Miera, &#214;zge Heinz, Wenjing Hong, Gilbert C. Walker, Langmuir. 40(34)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402054526

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. LangmuirVol 40/Issue 34Article This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialAugust 27, 2024Innovations in Battery InterfacesClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Greco Gonz&#225;lez MieraGreco Gonz&#225;lez MieraAmerican Chemical Society, 1155 16th Street NW, Washington, D.C. 20036, United StatesMore by Greco Gonz&#225;lez Mierahttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-2856-5295Ozge HeinzOzge HeinzDepartment of Mechanical Engineering, University of Colorado Denver, Denver, Colorado 80204, United StatesMore by Ozge Heinzhttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-6050-994XWenjing HongWenjing HongCollege of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Xiamen University, 361005 Xiamen, ChinaMore by Wenjing Honghttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-4080-6175Gilbert C. Walker*Gilbert C. WalkerDepartment of Chemistry, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON M5S 3H6, CanadaMore by Gilbert C. Walkerhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-5248-5498Open PDFLangmuirCite this: Langmuir 2024, 40, 34, 17845&#8211;17848Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03085https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03085Published August 27, 2024 Publication History Received 7 August 2024Published online 27 August 2024Published in issue 27 August 2024editorialCopyright &#169; Published 2024 by American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS PublicationsCopyright &#169; Published 2024 by American Chemical SocietyWe are pleased to present our readers with a Collection on Interfaces and Interphases in Batteries with a selection of articles published in Langmuir between 2021 and the present. As highlighted in our previous collection on Electrode Interfaces, the Editorial Board of Langmuir observed that electrochemistry has gained importance within the interface science research community in recent years. As a community-driven journal with a strong commitment to meet the needs of our readership, in 2022, Langmuir expanded the journal scope to incorporate emerging topics that are currently or will become important waves of community interest. Topics such as interfacial electrochemistry, photocatalysis, nanomedicine, porous materials, and sustainability are becoming a predominant research interest, and our present and future Collections and Special Issues will match these needs and others that our readership may think necessary.Within the articles in this Collection, you will find a diverse set of materials and functionalities represented (Table 1). Often a high-performance standard (e.g., capacity or cyclability) or novelty achievement is the motivation of the authors. Among the materials that are highly represented within this collection of papers you will find graphene, other carbons, MXenes, polymer electrolytes, and various kinds of ion combinations, including frequently lithium-, sodium-ion, and lithium&#8211;sulfur and many oxides. The batteries can include different phases, air batteries, aerogels, and also all-solid state. Novel cathodes and anodes are introduced. Complex electrochemistry and simpler electron transfer processes that occur at interfaces may be found within. Some papers report evolutionary advances in storing energy, but some may even be revolutionary! Other papers present green chemistry advances in natural and recycled materials, e.g., from wastewater.Table 1. Full List of Articles in This CollectionFirst author/Corresponding authorTitleDOI[Lithium-based batteries]Q. Wu/R. Jiang (1)Encapsulation of a Core&#8211;Shell Porous Fe3O4@Carbon Material with Reduced Graphene Oxide for Li+ Battery Anodes with Long Cyclability10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c03126Y.Liu/R. Guo (2)Multi-Yolk-Shell MnO@Carbon Nanopomegranates with Internal Buffer Space as a Lithium Ion Battery Anode10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c03523Z. Wu/Q. Hao (3)CuCo2O4 Hollow Microspheres with Graphene Composite Targeting Superior Lithium-Ion Storage10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c00670S. Liu/Z. Tian (4)Structural Evolution of Graphitic Carbon Derived from Ionic Liquids-Dissolved Cellulose and Its Application as Lithium-Ion Battery Anodes10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02559J. Li/X. Huang (5)Cross-Linked Sodium Alginate-Sodium Borate Hybrid Binders for High-Capacity Silicon Anodes in Lithium-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02751H. Zheng/H.-S. Xu (6)Rodlike FeS/SnS@N&#8211;C Core&#8211;Shell Microparticles for Lithium-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c02988Y. Wang/L. Zhao (7)Ga2O3 Quantum Dots with N-Doped Amorphous Carbon Fixed for Efficient Storage and Transfer of Lithium Ions by Introduction of Dopamine Hydrochloride10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03166F. Chen/C.-B.Liu (8)Enhanced Cycling and Structure Stability of an Electron Transfer-Accelerating Polymer Poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene)(styrenesulfonate)-Covered Mn-Based Layered Cathode with Ga3+ Doping for a Li-Ion Battery10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03462B. Zhang/J. Yang (9)Enhancement of Li2ZrO3 Modification of the Cycle Life of N/S-Doped LiMn0.5Fe0.5PO4/C Composite Cathodes for Lithium Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00244D. He/G. He (10)Ultrafine FeF3&#183;0.33H2O Nanocrystal-Doped Graphene Aerogel Cathode Materials for Advanced Lithium-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00035N. Gao/X. Yang (11)Density Functional Theory Study of Bilayer Borophene-Based Anode Material for Rechargeable Lithium Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c01371H. M. You/K. Kim (12)Atomistic Scale Modeling of Anode/Electrolyte Interfaces in Li-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03060M. Li/X.-F. Wang (13)Metal (Ni, Pd, and Pt)-Doped BS Monolayers as a Gas Sensor upon Vented Gases in Lithium-Ion Batteries: A First-Principles Study10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03088Y.-W. Song/J. Lim (14)Effect of Nanoparticles in LiFePO4 Cathode Material Using Organic/Inorganic Composite Solid Electrolyte for All-Solid-State Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01499S. Sathya/A. M. Stephan (15)Influence of Additives on the Electrochemical and Interfacial Properties of SiOx-Based Anode Materials for Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02342Y. Huang/X. Tang (16)P-Doped Cotton Stalk Carbon for High-Performance Lithium-Ion Batteries and Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01336D. Jia/Q. Shen (17)Multifunctional Mesoporous Carbonaceous Materials Enable the High Performance of Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03446B. Dai/B. Han (18)Self-Templated Formation of Carbon Nanotubes Interpenetrating Ordered Microporous Carbon Nanospheres for High-Performance Li&#8211;S Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00811X. Zhou/J. Ding (19)Graphene Oxide Aerogel Foam Constructed All-Solid Electrolyte Membranes for Lithium Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c03432Nonlithium metal-ion batteries (Na+, K+, Mg2+, and Zn2+)X. Yu/H. Zhuo (20)Ionic Liquid-Acrylic Acid Copolymer Derived Nitrogen&#8211;Boron Codoped Carbon-Covered Na3 V2(PO4)2F3 as Cathode Material of High-Performance Sodium-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01028V. Nagmani/S. Puravankara (21)Jute-Fiber Precursor-Derived Low-Cost Sustainable Hard Carbon with Varying Micro/Mesoporosity and Distinct Storage Mechanisms for Sodium-Ion and Potassium-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c02575M. Li/Z. Dai (22)Study of Predominant Dynamics on the O3-Type Layered Transition-Metal Oxide Cathode by Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy for Sodium-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00931Y. He/D. Sun (23)De-Ammonium Ba0.18 V2O4.95/NH4 V4O10 Film Electrodes as High-Performance Cathode Materials for Magnesium-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00552F. M. H. Al Sulami/T.A. Hameed (24)Insight into the Electrochemical Behaviors of Magnesium&#8211;Manganese Oxides in Aqueous Magnesium-Ion Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c01265P. Yadav/D. Ghosh (25)Developing High-Performance In-Plane Flexible Aqueous Zinc-Ion Batteries with Laser-Scribed Carbon-Supported All Electrodeposited Electrodes10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03057Metal&#8211;air batteriesA. Chen/G. Tan (26)Mesoporous N&#8211;P Codoped Carbon Nanosheets as Superior Cathodic Catalysts of Neutral Metal&#8211;Air Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c01947Y. Lu/D. Dong (27)Fe, B, and N Codoped Carbon Nanoribbons Derived from Heteroatom Polymers as High-Performance Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysts for Zinc-Air Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02100X. Cao/J. Ding (28)3D TM&#8211;N-C Electrocatalysts with Dense Active Sites for the Membraneless Direct Methanol Fuel Cell and Zn-Air Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c00347X. Wang/W. Zhang (29)Porous Ni3S2&#8211;Co9S8 Carbon Aerogels Derived from Carrageenan/NiCo-MOF Hydrogels as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution in Rechargeable Zn-Air Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c00805L. Sun/W. Zhang (30)Synergistic Effect of Co9S8 and FeS2 Inlaid on N-Doped Carbon Nanofibers toward a Bifunctional Catalyst for Zn-Air Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01882Z. Shui/X. Chen (31)Flexible Aluminum-Air Battery Based on Ionic Liquid-Gel Polymer Electrolyte10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01178Y. Huang/V. Saji (32)Regulating the Anode Corrosion by a Tryptophan Derivative for Alkaline Al-Air Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00032Electrodes: Alternative materials and mechanistic insightsC. Wei/X. Liu (33)Ti2CT2MXene as Anodes for Metal Ion Batteries: From Monolayer to Bilayer to Pillar Structure10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01877W. Zhang/J. Zhang (34)Nb2CTx MXene as High-Performance Energy Storage Material with Na, K, and Liquid K&#8211;Na Alloy Anodes10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c02957X. Qui/R. Li (35)Pillaring Behavior of Organic Molecules on MXene: Insights from Molecular Dynamics Simulations10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c01682W. Li/Y.Sun (36)Rate Performance Modification of a Lithium-Rich Manganese-Based Material through Surface Self-Doping and Coating Strategies10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c00225S. Srivastav/S.K. Meher (37)Ribbon-like Nickel Cobaltite with Layer-by-Layer-Assembled Ordered Nanocrystallites for Next-Generation All-Solid-State Hybrid Supercapatteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02844X. Meng/G. Shang (38)Tracking Electrochemical-Cycle-Induced Surface Structure Evolutions of Cathode Material LiMn2O4 with Improved Operando Raman Spectroscopy10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c00149X. Sun/H. Li (39)First-Principles Simulations for the Surface Evolution and Mn Dissolution in the Fully Delithiated Spinel LiMn2O410.1021/acs.langmuir.1c00197F. Hao/P. P. Mukherjee (40)Chemomechanical Interactions Dictate Lithium Surface Diffusion Kinetics in the Solid Electrolyte Interphase10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c00017S. Tang/Z. Li (41)Microporous Carbon Nanospheres with Fast Sodium Storage Capability Enabled by Dominant Capacitive Behavior10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c00912Z. Wang/S. Ye (42)Observing Nonpreferential Absorption of Linear and Cyclic Carbonate on the Silicon Electrode10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03098S. Kitano/K.-i. Fukui (43)Voltammetric and In Situ Spectroscopic Investigations on the Redox Processes of Trioxotriangulene Neutral Radicals on Graphite Electrodes10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00438T. Dhara/S. DasGupta (44)Mechanistic Underpinnings of Morphology Transition in Electrodeposition under the Application of Pulsatile Potential10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c00066H. Gan/Z. Xue (45)Mechanically Strong and Electrochemically Stable Single-Ion Conducting Polymer Electrolytes Constructed from Hydrogen Bonding10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c01035N. Sun/Y. Huang (46)Reversible Li+ Storage in CFx-Based Cathodes through Transition Metal Decomposition10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03205C. T.-C. Wan/F. R. Brushett (47)Synthesis and Characterization of Dense Carbon Films as Model Surfaces to Estimate Electron Transfer Kinetics on Redox Flow Battery Electrodes10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03003SustainabilityB. S. Chikkatti/N. H.Ayachit (48)Graphene-Doped Hydrogels Promoting Ionic Conductivity in Gel-Valve-Regulated Lead Acid Batteries10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c02285Y. An/X. Wang (49)Adsorption Recycling and High-Value Reutilization of Heavy-Metal Ions from Wastewater: As a High-Performance Anode Lithium Battery10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c01275X. Li/S. Yang (50)Construction of a Preoxidation and Cation Doping Regeneration Strategy to Improve Rate Performance Recycling Spent LiFePO4 Materials10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c01530L. Qu/M. Li (51)A Perspective of Bioinspired Interfaces Applied in Renewable Energy Storage and Conversion Devices10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03679We invite you to enjoy reading about new ways to store and transduce electrical energy, as presented in this dynamic collection of papers.Find your favorite article and let us hear about it!Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorGilbert C. Walker, Department of Chemistry, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON M5S 3H6, Canada, https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5248-5498, Email: AuthorsGreco Gonz&#225;lez Miera, American Chemical Society, 1155 16th Street NW, Washington, D.C. 20036, United States, https://orcid.org/0000-0002-2856-5295Ozge Heinz, Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Colorado Denver, Denver, Colorado 80204, United States, https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6050-994XWenjing Hong, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Xiamen University, 361005 Xiamen, China, https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4080-6175NotesViews expressed in this editorial are those of the authors and not necessarily the views of the ACS.ReferencesClick to copy section linkSection link copied! This article references 51 other publications. 1Wu, Q.; Yu, R.; Zhou, Z.; Liu, H.; Jiang, R. Encapsulation of a Core-Shell Porous Fe3O4@Carbon Material with Reduced Graphene Oxide for Li+ Battery Anodes with Long Cyclability. Langmuir 2021, 37 (2), 785&#8211; 792, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c03126 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.2Liu, Y.; Sun, S.; Han, J.; Gao, C.; Fan, L.; Guo, R. Multi-Yolk-Shell MnO@Carbon Nanopomegranates with Internal Buffer Space as a Lithium Ion Battery Anode. Langmuir 2021, 37 (6), 2195&#8211; 2204, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c03523 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.3Wu, Z.; Ye, H.; Zhang, B.; Song, J.; Wang, Y.; Yao, D.; Wang, C.; Xia, X.; Lei, W.; Hao, Q. CuCo2O4 Hollow Microspheres with Graphene Composite Targeting Superior Lithium-Ion Storage. Langmuir 2021, 37 (28), 8426&#8211; 8434, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c00670 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.4Liu, S.; Ren, Z.; Fakudze, S.; Shang, Q.; Chen, J.; Liu, C.; Han, J.; Tian, Z. Structural Evolution of Graphitic Carbon Derived from Ionic Liquids-Dissolved Cellulose and Its Application as Lithium-Ion Battery Anodes. Langmuir 2022, 38 (1), 320&#8211; 331, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02559 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.5Li, J.; Hu, X.; Zhao, H.; Ren, Y.; Huang, X. Cross-Linked Sodium Alginate-Sodium Borate Hybrid Binders for High-Capacity Silicon Anodes in Lithium-Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2022, 38 (1), 402&#8211; 410, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02751 Google Scholar5Cross-Linked Sodium Alginate-Sodium Borate Hybrid Binders for High-Capacity Silicon Anodes in Lithium-Ion BatteriesLi, Jianbin; Hu, Xianchao; Zhao, Hongshun; Ren, Yurong; Huang, XiaobingLangmuir (2022), 38 (1), 402-410CODEN: LANGD5; ISSN:0743-7463. (American Chemical Society) Silicon is considered one of the most promising next-generation anode materials for lithium-ion batteries. It has the advantages of high theor. specific capacity (4200 mAh&#183;g-1), which is 10 times larger than that of a com. graphite anode (372 mAh&#183;g-1). However, there are some problems such as the pulverization of the electrode and an unstable solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) layer aroused by the huge bulk effect (&gt;300%) of Si during the repeated lithiation/delithiation process. A binder plays a vital role in the conventional lithium-ion batteries that can effectively relieve the bulk expansion stress of a silicon anode. In this work, the inorg. cross-linker sodium borate (SB) and the commonly used binder sodium alginate (SA) were condensed through an esterification reaction and the reaction product was marked as SA-SB. It is found that the mech. robustness and the peel strength of SA-SB are improved after crosslinking, which is conducive to maintaining the structural stability of the silicon anode in long cycle life. In consequence, the capacity retention of the silicon anode using the SA-SB binder (64.1%) is higher than that of SA (50.6%) after 100 cycles at 0.2 A&#183;g-1. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3MXivVCgsr%252FN&amp;md5=c9ce22cfb81b49d3c673a1f9ca5ac5026Zheng, H.; Hu, J.; Xie, W.; Sang, Y.; Xu, H.-S. Rodlike FeS/SnS@N-C Core-Shell Microparticles for Lithium-Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (7), 2609&#8211; 2617, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c02988 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.7Wang, Y.; Xiong, Z.; Zhao, Y.; Zhang, Z.; Qiu, G.; Liang, Z.; Mei, C.; Hou, S.; Li, S.; Gao, F.; Zhao, L. Ga2O3 Quantum Dots with N-Doped Amorphous Carbon Fixed for Efficient Storage and Transfer of Lithium Ions by Introduction of Dopamine Hydrochloride. Langmuir 2023, 39 (10), 3628&#8211; 3636, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03166 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.8Chen, F.; Dai, W.; Zhu, X.; Yao, C.; Qian, J.; Chen, Z.; Liu, C.-B. Enhanced Cycling and Structure Stability of an Electron Transfer- Accelerating Polymer Poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene):Poly(styrenesulfonate)-Covered Mn-Based Layered Cathode with Ga3+ Doping for a Li-Ion Battery. Langmuir 2023, 39 (13), 4662&#8211; 4675, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03462 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.9Zhang, B.; Wang, S.; Liu, L.; Liu, H.; Yang, J. Enhancement of Li2ZrO3Modification of the Cycle Life of N/S-Doped LiMn0.5Fe0.5PO4/C Composite Cathodes for Lithium Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (14), 5187&#8211; 5198, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00244 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.10He, D.; Cao, D.; Lu, J.; Zhu, Y.; Huang, J.; Zhang, Y.; He, G. Ultrafine FeF3&#183;0.33H2O Nanocrystal-Doped Graphene Aerogel Cathode Materials for Advanced Lithium-Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (17), 6029&#8211; 6037, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00035 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.11Gao, N.; Ye, P.; Chen, J.; Xiao, J.; Yang, X. Density Functional Theory Study of Bilayer Borophene-Based Anode Material for Rechargeable Lithium Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (29), 10270&#8211; 10279, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c01371 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.12You, H. M.; Yoon, Y.; Ko, J.; Back, J.; Kwon, H.; Han, J. W.; Kim, K. Atomistic Scale Modeling of Anode/Electrolyte Interfaces in Li-Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2024, 40 (4), 1961&#8211; 1970, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03060 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.13Li, M.; Wang, X.-F. Metal (Ni, Pd, and Pt)-Doped BS Monolayers as a Gas Sensor upon Vented Gases in Lithium-Ion Batteries: A First-Principles Study. Langmuir 2024, 40 (6), 2969&#8211; 2978, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c03088 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.14Song, Y.-W.; Kang, S.-W.; Heo, K.; Lee, J.; Kim, M.-Y.; Hwang, D.; Kim, S.-J.; Kim, J.; Lim, J. Effect of Nanoparticles in LiFePO4 Cathode Material Using Organic/Inorganic Composite Solid Electrolyte for All-Solid-State Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (1), 45&#8211; 52, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01499 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.15Sathya, S.; Angulakshmi, N.; Ahn, J.-H.; Kathiresan, M.; Stephan, A. M. Influence of Additives on the Electrochemical and Interfacial Properties of SiOx-Based Anode Materials for Lithium-Sulfur Batteries. Langmuir 2022, 38 (8), 2423&#8211; 2434, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02342 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.16Huang, Y.; Jia, D.; Wei, Y.; Cheng, W.; Liu, Z.; Sheng, R.; Wang, X.; Tang, X. P-Doped Cotton Stalk Carbon for High-Performance Lithium-Ion Batteries and Lithium-Sulfur Batteries. Langmuir 2022, 38 (38), 11610&#8211; 11620, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01336 Google Scholar16P-Doped Cotton Stalk Carbon for High-Performance Lithium-Ion Batteries and Lithium-Sulfur BatteriesWei, Yanbin; Cheng, Wenhua; Huang, Yudai; Liu, Zhenjie; Sheng, Rui; Wang, Xingchao; Jia, Dianzeng; Tang, XincunLangmuir (2022), 38 (38), 11610-11620CODEN: LANGD5; ISSN:0743-7463. (American Chemical Society) Biomass as a carbon material source is the characteristic of green chem. Herein, a series of hierarchical P-doped cotton stalk carbon materials (HPCSCMs) were prepd. from cheap and abundant biowaste cotton stalk. These materials possess a surface area of 3463.14 m2 g-1 and hierarchical pores. As lithium-ion battery (LIB) anodes, the samples exhibit 1100 mAh g-1 at 0.1 A g-1 after 100 cycles and hold 419 mAh g-1 at 1 A g-1 after 1000 cycles, with nearly 100% capacity retention. After HPCSCMs are loaded with sulfur (S/HPCSCMs), the samples (S/HPCSCMs-2) deliver a discharge capacity of 413 mAh g-1 at 0.1 A g-1 after 100 cycles as lithium-sulfur (Li-S) battery cathodes. This excellent electrochem. performance can be attributed to P in carbon networks, which not only provides more active sites, but also improves elec. cond. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB38XitlOitrvJ&amp;md5=3db5123344fd03e08be089b46924f0a517Jia, D.; Shen, Q. Multifunctional Mesoporous Carbonaceous Materials Enable the High Performance of Lithium-Sulfur Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (9), 3173&#8211; 3178, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03446 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.18Dai, B.; Liu, Y.; Zhang, H.; Wang, S.; Wang, Y.; Jin, Z.; Zhang, J.; Guo, J.; Li, J.; Han, B. Self-Templated Formation of Carbon Nanotubes Interpenetrating Ordered Microporous Carbon Nanospheres for High-Performance Li-S Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (26), 9094&#8211; 9099, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00811 Google Scholar18Self-Templated Formation of Carbon Nanotubes Interpenetrating Ordered Microporous Carbon Nanospheres for High-Performance Li-S BatteriesDai, Binting; Liu, Yuxi; Zhang, Hongsen; Wang, Shaobo; Wang, Yali; Jin, Zhanshuang; Zhang, Jiudi; Guo, Jianhua; Li, Junjie; Han, BingLangmuir (2023), 39 (26), 9094-9099CODEN: LANGD5; ISSN:0743-7463. (American Chemical Society) Lithium-sulfur (Li-S) batteries are known as a prospective new generation of battery systems owing to their high energy d., low cost, non-toxicity, and environmental friendliness. Nevertheless, several issues remain in the practical application of Li-S batteries, such as low sulfur usage, poor rate performance, and poor cycle stability. Ordered microporous carbon materials and carbon nanotubes (CNTs) can effectively limit the diffusion of polysulfides (LiPSs) and have high elec. cond., resp. Here, inspired by the evapn. of zinc at high temps., we constructed CNTs interpenetrating ordered microporous carbon nanospheres (CNTs/OMC NSs) by high-temp. calcination and used them as a sulfur host material. With the benefit from the excellent elec. cond. of CNTs and OMC achieving uniform sulfur dispersion and effectively limiting LiPS dissoln., the S@CNTs/OMC NS cathodes show outstanding cycling stability (initial discharge capacity of 879 mAh g-1 at 0.5 C, maintained at 629 mAh g-1 for 500 cycles) and excellent rate performance (521 mAh g-1 at 5.0 C). Furthermore, the current study can serve as a significant ref. for the synthesis of CNTs that interpenetrate various materials. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3sXht1ehtbfM&amp;md5=65356ce3513f53e4cfbf3f9d525e9d3819Zhou, X.; Lv, P.; Li, M.; Xu, J.; Cheng, G.; Yuan, N.; Ding, J. Graphene Oxide Aerogel Foam Constructed All-Solid Electrolyte Membranes for Lithium Batteries. Langmuir 2022, 38 (10), 3257&#8211; 3264, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c03432 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.20Yu, X.; Lu, T.; Li, X.; Qi, J.; Yuan, L.; Man, Z.; Zhuo, H. Ionic Liquid-Acrylic Acid Copolymer Derived Nitrogen-Boron Codoped Carbon-Covered Na3V2(PO4)2F3 as Cathode Material of High-Performance Sodium-Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2022, 38 (25), 7815&#8211; 7824, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c01028 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.21Nagmani; Verma, P.; Puravankara, S. Jute-Fiber Precursor-Derived Low-Cost Sustainable Hard Carbon with Varying Micro/Mesoporosity and Distinct Storage Mechanisms for Sodium-Ion and Potassium-Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2022, 38 (50), 15703&#8211; 15713, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c02575 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.22Li, M.; Qiu, X.; Wei, T.; Dai, Z. Study of Predominant Dynamics on the O3-Type Layered Transition-Metal Oxide Cathode by Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy for Sodium-Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (25), 8865&#8211; 8878, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00931 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.23He, Y.; Xu, H.; Liu, F.; Bian, H.; Li, D.; Wang, A.; Sun, D. De-Ammonium Ba0.18V2O4.95/NH4V4O10 Film Electrodes as High-Performance Cathode Materials for Magnesium-Ion Batteries. Langmuir 2023, 39 (18), 6580&#8211; 6591, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00552 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.24Al Sulami, F. M. H.; Alsabban, M. M.; Al-Sulami, A. I.; Farrag, M.; Vedraine, S.; Huang, K.-W.; Sheha, E.; Hameed, T. A. Nanosynthesis and Characterization of Cu1.8Se0.6S0.4 as a Potential Cathode for Magnesium Battery Applications. Langmuir 2023, 39 (37), 13038&#8211; 13049, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c01265 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.25Yadav, P.; Naik, P. B.; Beere, H. K.; Reddy, N. S.; Samanta, K.; Kotrappanavar, N. S.; Algethami, J. S.; Faisal, M.; Harraz, F. A.; Ghosh, D. Developing High-Performance In-Plane Flexible Aqueous Zinc-Ion Batteries with Laser-Scribed Carbon-Supported All Electrodeposited Electrodes. Langmuir 2022, 38 (51), 16203&#8211; 16213, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c03057 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.26Chen, A.; Yi, Q.; Sheng, K.; Wang, Y.; Chen, J.; Zhang, Q.; Xiang, K.; Tan, G. Mesoporous N&#8211;P Codoped Carbon Nanosheets as Superior Cathodic Catalysts of Neutral Metal&#8211;Air Batteries. Langmuir 2021, 37 (43), 12616&#8211; 12628, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c01947 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.27Lu, Y.; Zou, S.; Li, J.; Li, C.; Liu, X.; Dong, D. Fe, B, and N Codoped Carbon Nanoribbons Derived from Heteroatom Polymers as High-Performance Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysts for Zinc-Air Batteries. Langmuir 2021, 37 (44), 13018&#8211; 13026, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02100 Google Scholar27Fe, B, and N Codoped Carbon Nanoribbons Derived from Heteroatom Polymers as High-Performance Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysts for Zinc-Air BatteriesLu, Yue; Zou, Shanbao; Li, Jiajie; Li, Chenyu; Liu, Xundao; Dong, DehuaLangmuir (2021), 37 (44), 13018-13026CODEN: LANGD5; ISSN:0743-7463. (American Chemical Society) For zinc-air batteries, it is of great importance to heighten the oxygen redn. reaction (ORR) activity of cathode electrocatalysts. Herein, we synthesized carbon nanoribbons doped with Fe, B, and N as high-activity ORR electrocatalysts by a templating method. Benefiting from the melamine fiber (MF) and B doping, the as-prepd. carbon nanoribbon has a high sp. surface area, and the improved turnover frequency of Fe sites increases the ORR activity. The as-synthesized Fe-B-N-C electrocatalyst shows an improved half-wave potential and limited c.d. compared to Fe-N-C, B-N-C, and N-C. Moreover, zinc-air batteries with the Fe-B-N-C electrocatalyst exhibit a higher specific capacity and better long-term durability compared to those with com. Pt/C. This work provides an effective strategy to synthesize noble-metal-free electrocatalysts for wide applications of zinc-air batteries. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3MXitlSjsb3E&amp;md5=d4b7075c320e35b0614c22dd52eee14228Cao, X.; Song, R.; Zhou, X.; Wang, X.; Dong, X.; Yuan, N.; Ding, J. 3D TM-N-C Electrocatalysts with Dense Active Sites for the Membraneless Direct Methanol Fuel Cell and Zn-Air Batteries. Langmuir 2022, 38 (16), 4948&#8211; 4957, DOI: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.2c00347 Google Scholar283D TM-N-C Electrocatalysts with Dense Active Sites for the Membraneless Direct Methanol Fuel Cell and Zn-Air BatteriesCao, Xiaoting; Song, Ruili; Zhou, Xiaoshuang; Wang, Xi; Dong, Xu; Yuan, Ningyi; Ding, JianningLangmuir (2022), 38</description>
      <author>Greco Gonz&#225;lez Miera, &#214;zge Heinz, Wenjing Hong, Gilbert C. Walker</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NANO-SIZED PARTICLES IN THE MINERAL RESOURCE EXPLOITATION: OBRAZOVANIE TRANSIT AND DEPOSITION IN THE EARTH'S ATMOSPHERE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25791/infizik.07.2018.088</link>
      <description>Sergei Vasil'evich Viktorov, &#1070;.&#1055;. &#1043;&#1040;&#1051;&#1063;&#1045;&#1053;&#1050;&#1054;, No host. None(7)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4402231361

                &#1042; &#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1090;&#1100;&#1077; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085; &#1084;&#1077;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1084; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1074;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1086;&#1090;&#1073;&#1086;&#1081;&#1082;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074;&#1086;&#1074; &#1080; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1072; &#1090;&#1077;&#1086;&#1088;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1072;&#1103; &#1080; &#1101;&#1082;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1072;&#1103; &#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1072; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1072; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1090;&#1080;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;&#1099;&#1096;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1042;&#1042;. &#1056;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1091;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1075;&#1086;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1086;&#1084; &#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1074; &#1086;&#1073;&#1086;&#1079;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1077; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1095;&#1090;&#1080; &#1074;&#1089;&#1077;&#1093; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1103;&#1077;&#1084;&#1099;&#1093; &#1075;&#1077;&#1086;&#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1081;, &#1082;&#1072;&#1082; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1087;&#1086;&#1076;&#1079;&#1077;&#1084;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081;, &#1090;&#1072;&#1082; &#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1086;&#1090;&#1082;&#1088;&#1099;&#1090;&#1086;&#1081; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1082;&#1077; &#1088;&#1091;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1080; &#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1095;&#1072;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1091;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1084;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1078;&#1076;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1081;. &#1069;&#1090;&#1086;&#1090; &#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1073; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1091;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1096;&#1077;&#1083; &#1076;&#1083;&#1080;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1087;&#1091;&#1090;&#1100; &#1101;&#1074;&#1086;&#1083;&#1102;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1080; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080; &#1086;&#1073;&#1077;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085; &#1096;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1082;&#1080;&#1084; &#1085;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;, &#1095;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077; &#1074;&#1089;&#1077;&#1075;&#1086;, &#1101;&#1084;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1088;&#1077;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1081;, &#1082;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1099;&#1077; &#1086;&#1073;&#1099;&#1095;&#1085;&#1086; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1099; &#1085;&#1072; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1099;&#1093; &#1092;&#1080;&#1079;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1080; &#1075;&#1077;&#1086;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1081;. &#1044;&#1086;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1088;&#1091;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086;&#1076;&#1093;&#1086;&#1076;&#1099; &#1082; &#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1087;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074; &#1086;&#1090;&#1073;&#1086;&#1081;&#1082;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077;&#1089;&#1091;&#1090; &#1074; &#1089;&#1077;&#1073;&#1077; &#1074;&#1085;&#1091;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1077;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1086;&#1088;&#1077;&#1095;&#1080;&#1077; &#1084;&#1077;&#1078;&#1076;&#1091; &#1086;&#1073;&#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1086;&#1073;&#1098;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084;&#1080; &#1079;&#1072;&#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080; &#1075;&#1077;&#1086;&#1084;&#1077;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1080; &#1080; &#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1073;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;&#1084;&#1080; &#1075;&#1077;&#1086;&#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1072;&#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1077;&#1081; &#1079;&#1086;&#1085; &#1087;&#1086;&#1075;&#1083;&#1086;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080;, &#1089; &#1086;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1085;&#1099;, &#1080; &#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074;&#1077; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074; &#8211; &#1089; &#1076;&#1088;&#1091;&#1075;&#1086;&#1081;. &#1055;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1083;&#1086;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072; &#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100; &#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1095;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1096;&#1080;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1081;&#1096;&#1080;&#1093; &#1042;&#1042;, &#1089;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1088;&#1078;&#1072;&#1097;&#1080;&#1093; &#1074; &#1089;&#1074;&#1086;&#1077;&#1084; &#1089;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1076;&#1077;&#1085;&#1089;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1082;&#1086;&#1084;&#1087;&#1086;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1099;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1099; &#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1091;&#1102;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1076;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1081;&#1096;&#1080;&#1093; &#1042;&#1042; &#1089;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1088;&#1078;&#1072;&#1097;&#1080;&#1093; &#1072;&#1083;&#1102;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1081;, &#1072; &#1090;&#1072;&#1082;&#1078;&#1077; &#1042;&#1042;, &#1089;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1088;&#1078;&#1072;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076; &#1080; &#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1094;&#1072;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1082;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1073;&#1072;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1083;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086; &#1072;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077; &#1088;&#1077;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1079;&#1072;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1096;&#1080;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;. &#1056;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086; &#1080;&#1079;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1101;&#1092;&#1092;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1074;&#1086;&#1079;&#1084;&#1086;&#1078;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1080;&#1093; &#1080;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080;&#1079; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1103; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1079;&#1072;&#1074;&#1080;&#1089;&#1080;&#1090; &#1086;&#1090; &#1089;&#1086;&#1086;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1074;&#1088;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1080; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1074;&#1088;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080; &#1074;&#1099;&#1083;&#1077;&#1090;&#1072; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;. &#1060;&#1080;&#1079;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;-&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1073;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1074;&#1088;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1077;&#1097;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1072; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1072; &#1084;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1090; &#1073;&#1099;&#1090;&#1100; &#1085;&#1077; &#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1077;&#1077; &#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080;&#1084;&#1099;&#1084; &#1092;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;, &#1090;&#1072;&#1082; &#1082;&#1072;&#1082; &#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086; &#1086;&#1085;&#1080; &#1092;&#1086;&#1088;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1091;&#1102;&#1090; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1074; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074; &#1080; &#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1103;&#1102;&#1090; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1082;&#1080; &#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1076;&#1080;&#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1072; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1091;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1090;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074;&#1072; &#1074; &#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1094;&#1077;&#1083;&#1103;&#1093;. &#1042;&#1099;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1085;&#1072; &#1088;&#1091;&#1076;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1072;&#1093; &#1044;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1077;&#1075;&#1086; &#1042;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072; &#1101;&#1082;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1086;&#1079;&#1074;&#1086;&#1083;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080; &#1101;&#1084;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080; &#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1090;&#1100; &#1079;&#1072;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1090;&#1099; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1084;&#1077;&#1088;&#1099; &#1079;&#1086;&#1085;&#1099; &#1073;&#1088;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1076;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1090;&#1080;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074; &#1042;&#1042; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1086;&#1090;&#1073;&#1086;&#1081;&#1082;&#1077; &#1078;&#1080;&#1083; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1088;&#1077;&#1079;&#1082;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080; &#1087;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102;. &#1054;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1101;&#1082;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1099; &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077;&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1080;&#1079;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1093;&#1086;&#1076; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074; &#1079;&#1086;&#1085;&#1077; &#1073;&#1088;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1076;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1072; &#1085;&#1072;&#1093;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1103;&#1084;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1094;&#1080;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1089;&#1074;&#1103;&#1079;&#1080; &#1089;&#1086; &#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100;&#1102; &#1076;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1042;&#1042;. &#1041;&#1099;&#1083;&#1086; &#1090;&#1072;&#1082;&#1078;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1085;&#1072;&#1080;&#1073;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1077; &#1073;&#1083;&#1072;&#1075;&#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1103;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103;&#1084; &#1086;&#1090;&#1073;&#1086;&#1081;&#1082;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1077; &#1076;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1075;&#1072;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1082;&#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1090;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; (&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1081;&#1096;&#1080;&#1093;) &#1042;&#1042; &#1089;&#1086; &#1089;&#1084;&#1077;&#1089;&#1077;&#1074;&#1099;&#1084; &#1084;&#1077;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1084;&#1086;&#1084; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1074;&#1088;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1082;&#1080;&#1084; &#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1084;, &#1074;&#1099;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1089;&#1091;&#1097;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1091;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1076;&#1099; &#1091;&#1087;&#1088;&#1072;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1086;&#1084; &#1074; &#1080;&#1085;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1089;&#1072;&#1093; &#1075;&#1086;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1081; &#1086;&#1093;&#1074;&#1072;&#1090;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072;&#1102;&#1090; &#1074; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1099; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1072; &#1074;&#1099;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080; &#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080; &#1074; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;. &#1055;&#1088;&#1080; &#1101;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084; &#1087;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077; &#1079;&#1072;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1075;&#1080;&#1074;&#1072;&#1102;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1099; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1090;&#1086;&#1081; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1091;&#1096;&#1072;&#1077;&#1084;&#1086;&#1084; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074;&#1077;. The article deals with the mechanism of development of energy processes during blasting off of rock massifs and gives a theoretical and experimental assessment of the nature of the explosion energy distribution using different types of industrial EXPLOSIVES. The destruction of rocks by explosion will remain in the foreseeable future the basis of almost all applied geotechnologies, both in the underground and in the open development of ore and a signifi cant part of non-metallic deposits. This method of destruction has gone a long way of evolution and is methodologically provided with a wide range of, most often, empirical solutions, which are usually based on the use of extremely simple physical and geometric models. The dominant approaches to the defi nition of the parameters of blasting are an internal contradiction between due to objective laws of geomechanics and geotechnology requirements of the asymmetry of the zones of energy absorption, on the one hand, and the symmetrical character of the distribution in the array of the explosion energy is concentrated charges on the other. The proposed model thermodynamic calculations of the work of expansion of the explosion products and cheap Explosives, containing in its composition of the condensed components. Such products are formed by detonation of the simplest BB containing aluminum, as well as BB containing carbon and having a negative oxygen balance. An analytical solution is obtained under a given condition of expansion of the charging cavity. The changes in the efficiency of explosion products with the possibility of their expiration from the charging cavity are considered. It is shown that the useful work of explosion products depends on the ratio of the characteristic time of the explosion and the characteristic time of departure of gases. Physico-chemical characteristics of the explosive transformation of the substance of the charge can be no less significant factor, since they form the conditions for the transfer of explosion energy to the array and determine the characteristics of the initial stage of the process of explosive destruction of this array in the technological purposes. Made on the mines of the Far East experimental study allowed us to empirically assess the cost of energy and the size of the zone of blasting action of the explosion of different types of explosives when blasting prirezkami lived along strike. Evaluation experiments showed that technologically unproductive consumption of energy in the blasting area of validity the charge is in direct proportional relationship with the speed of detonation. It was also shown that the most favorable energy distribution in the space under the conditions of rejection is achieved by using low-recoil (simplest) EXPLOSIVES with a mixed reaction mechanism of explosive transformation. Thus, studies have shown that the existing methods for managing the explosion in the interest of mining technologies cover mainly different aspects of the process of the release and transfer of energy charges to the array. At the same time, the processes of distribution of this energy in the destructible array are practically not affected.</description>
      <author>Sergei Vasil'evich Viktorov, &#1070;.&#1055;. &#1043;&#1040;&#1051;&#1063;&#1045;&#1053;&#1050;&#1054;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25791/infizik.07.2018.088</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
