<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 01:06:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assembled Conjugated Coordination Polymer Nanorings: Role of Morphology and Redox Sites for the Alkaline Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00609</link>
      <description>Vishwakarma Ravikumar Ramlal, Kinjal B. Patel, Savan K. Raj, Divesh N. Srivastava, Amal Kumar Mandal, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760067

                Electrocatalytic water splitting provides a sustainable method for storing intermittent energies, such as solar energy and wind, in the form of hydrogen fuel. However, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), constituting the other half-cell reaction, is often considered the bottleneck in overall water splitting due to its slow kinetics. Therefore, it is crucial to develop efficient, cost-effective, and robust OER catalysts to enhance the water-splitting process. Transition-metal-based coordination polymers (CPs) serve as promising electrocatalysts due to their diverse chemical architectures paired with redox-active metal centers. Despite their potential, the rational use of CPs has faced obstacles including a lack of insights into their catalytic mechanisms, low conductivity, and morphology issues. Consequently, achieving success in this field requires the rational design of ligands and topological networks with the desired electronic structure. This study delves into the design and synthesis of three novel conjugated coordination polymers (CCPs) by leveraging the full conjugation of terpyridine-attached flexible tetraphenylethylene units as electron-rich linkers with various redox-active metal centers [Co(II), Ni(II), and Zn(II)]. The self-assembly process is tuned for each CCP, resulting in two distinct morphologies: nanosheets and nanorings. The electrocatalytic OER performance efficiency is then correlated with factors such as the nanostructure morphology and redox-active metal centers in alkaline electrolytes. Notably, among the three morphologies studied, nanorings for each CCP exhibit a superior OER activity. Co(II)-integrated CCPs demonstrate a higher activity between the redox-active metal centers. Specifically, the Co(II) nanoring morphology displays exceptional catalytic activity for OER, with a lower overpotential of 347 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Vishwakarma Ravikumar Ramlal, Kinjal B. Patel, Savan K. Raj, Divesh N. Srivastava, Amal Kumar Mandal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00609</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface plasmon enhancement of 1D Ag nanowires modified electro-treated BiVO4 photoanode with abundant oxygen vacancies for solar water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131847</link>
      <description>Song Zhang, Hongjun Zhang, Yuantong Gu, Xiangling Mao, Xiaoying Gao, Dongbo Xu, Fuel. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396764166

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Song Zhang, Hongjun Zhang, Yuantong Gu, Xiangling Mao, Xiaoying Gao, Dongbo Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#945;-Mn2O3 porous fibers synthesized by air-heated solution blow spinning (A-HSBS) technique: electrochemical assessment for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112086</link>
      <description>Rondinele N. Araujo, Rafael A. Raimundo, Gelmires de Ara&#250;jo Neves, Valmor Roberto Mastelaro, Daniel A. Macedo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, Marco A. Morales, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396768572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rondinele N. Araujo, Rafael A. Raimundo, Gelmires de Ara&#250;jo Neves, Valmor Roberto Mastelaro, Daniel A. Macedo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, Marco A. Morales, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Incorporated Metal-Organic Cobalt Hydroxide Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00871-0</link>
      <description>Tao Jiang, Yuechao Yao, Feiyan Wu, Iram Aziz, Wenjing Zhang, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396769418

                Abstract Metal-organic cobalt hydroxide emerges as a cost-effective electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in energy conversion. However, the limited active sites and poor conductivity hinder their large-scale application. This study employed salicylate as a bridging ligand to synthesize iron-incorporated metal-organic cobalt hydroxide. The influence of Fe intercalation on Co(OH)(Hsal) (where Hsal denotes o -HOC 6 H 4 COO &#8722; ) was investigated using X-ray diffraction (XRD) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). Fe 0.2 Co 0.8 (OH)(Hsal) demonstrates remarkable electrocatalytic activity, displaying an OER overpotential of 298 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 57.46 mV dec &#8722;1 . This enhancement can be attributed to improved charge transfer kinetics and increased active sites. This work highlights the crucial role of Fe in improving the efficiency of Co-based oxygen-evolving catalysts (OECs) and its potential for boosting efficient hydrogen generation in alkaline environments. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Jiang, Yuechao Yao, Feiyan Wu, Iram Aziz, Wenjing Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00871-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Design and Insights into Lanthanum and Strontium Perovskite Oxides for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions (Small 19/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202470144</link>
      <description>Sagar Ingavale, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Carolin Mercy Enoch, Chanon Pornrungroj, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Kasadit Nootong, Rojana Pornprasertsuk, Soorathep Kheawhom, Small. 20(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396770128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sagar Ingavale, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Carolin Mercy Enoch, Chanon Pornrungroj, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Kasadit Nootong, Rojana Pornprasertsuk, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202470144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge Redistribution of Lattice&#8208;Mismatched Co&#9472;Cu&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;P Boosting pH&#8208;Universal Water/Seawater Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400244</link>
      <description>Yu Zhang, Kun Li, Yongkang Li, Jianli Mi, Caixia Li, Hongdong Li, Lei Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396771909

                Abstract Practical applications of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) rely on the development of highly efficient, stable, and low&#8208;cost catalysts. Tuning the electronic structure, morphology, and architecture of catalysts is an important way to realize efficient and stable HER electrocatalysts. Herein, Co&#8208;doped Cu 3 P&#8208;based sugar&#8208;gourd structures (Co&#9472;Cu 3 P/CF) are prepared on copper foam as active electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution. This hierarchical structure facilitates fast mass transport during electrocatalysis. Notably, the introduction of Co not only induces a charge redistribution but also leads to lattice&#8208;mismatch on the atomic scale, which creates defects and performs as additional active sites. Therefore, Co&#9472;Cu 3 P/CF requires an overpotential of only 81, 111, 185, and 230 mV to reach currents of 50, 100, 500, and 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline media and remains stable after 10 000 CV cycles in a row and up to 110 h i&#8211;t stability tests. In addition, it also shows excellent HER performance in water/seawater electrolytes of different pH values. Experimental and DFT show that the introduction of Co modulates the electronic and energy level structures of the catalyst, optimizes the adsorption and desorption behavior of the intermediate, reduces the water dissociation energy barrier during the reaction, accelerates the Volmer step reaction, and thus improves the HER performance.</description>
      <author>Yu Zhang, Kun Li, Yongkang Li, Jianli Mi, Caixia Li, Hongdong Li, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Performances of Activated Carbon-Decorated Vanadium Pentoxide Nanocomposites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9953038</link>
      <description>Sejoon Lee, P. Ilanchezhiyan, Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Youngmin Lee, Seung Joo Lee, International journal of energy research. 2024(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396777489

                Developing the ecofriendly and high-fidelity electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential to foster effective production of environmentally friendly hydrogen. Herein, we fabricated the highly efficient OER electrocatalysts of the activated carbon-decorated vanadium pentoxide (AC-V2O5) nanocomposites using a facile hydrothermal technique. The AC-V2O5 nanocomposites displayed an aggregated structure of the AC nano-sheet-anchored orthorhombic V2O5 nanorods. When performing the OER process in an alkaline electrolyte at 10 mA/cm2, AC-V2O5 exhibited the low overpotential (~230 mV), small Tafel slope (~54 mV/dec), and excellent stability. These substantial OER performances of AC-V2O5 could be ascribed to the synergistic effects from both the electrochemically active V2O5 nanorods and the highly conductive AC nanosheets. The results infer that the AC-V2O5 nanocomposites possess a substantial aptitude as a high-performance OER electrocatalyst for production of the future green energy source&#8212;hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Sejoon Lee, P. Ilanchezhiyan, Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Youngmin Lee, Seung Joo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9953038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoSe2 and MoSe2 co-assembled durable bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction and urea oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.001</link>
      <description>Li Zhu, Youwei Cheng, Yaqiong Gong, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396785571

                The development of dual-function electrocatalysts has a very broad application prospect in renewable energy conversion technology. Herein, bifunctional Co0&#183;9Mo0.1-Se/Cu7Se4 heterojunction electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR) were prepared. Notably, selenization by strong reducibility triggered the generation of abundant Co3+ active sites and heterogeneous structures, as well as improved electrical conductivity. The Co0&#183;9Mo0.1-Se/Cu7Se4 electrocatalyst showed excellent OER activity, requiring only 202 mV overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and the Tafel slope was only 78.91 mV dec&#8722;1. Overpotential of the catalyst did not change significantly during the 38 h stability test, indicating that the electrocatalyst had excellent long-term stability. Moreover, when Co0&#183;9Mo0.1-Se/Cu7Se4 was used as the UOR electrode, the heterojunction required 1.29 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The cost-effective bifunctional metal selenide heterojunctions introduced in this study provide a research strategy for the prepared green electrode materials for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Li Zhu, Youwei Cheng, Yaqiong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field Enhanced Cobalt Iridium Alloy Catalyst for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01623</link>
      <description>Lamei Li, Wei Wang, Renat R. Nazmutdinov, Rustem Zairov, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789802

                Magnetic field mediated magnetic catalysts provide a powerful pathway for accelerating their sluggish kinetics toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) but remain great challenges in acidic media. The key obstacle comes from the production of an ordered magnetic domain catalyst in the harsh acidic OER. In this work, we form an induced local magnetic moment in the metallic Ir catalyst via the significant 3d&#8211;5d hybridization by introducing cobalt dopants. Interestingly, CoIr nanoclusters (NCs) exhibit an excellent magnetic field enhanced acidic OER activity, with the lowest overpotential of 220 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and s long-term stability of 120 h under a constant magnetic field (vs 260 mV/20 h without a magnetic field). The turnover frequency reaches 7.4 s&#8211;1 at 1.5 V (vs RHE), which is 3.0 times higher than that without magnetization. Density functional theory results show that CoIr NCs have a pronounced spin polarization intensity, which is preferable for OER enhancement.</description>
      <author>Lamei Li, Wei Wang, Renat R. Nazmutdinov, Rustem Zairov, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe site regulation and activity deciphering by selective phase transformation in the confined FeNi nanoparticles for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152113</link>
      <description>Zongyuan Ma, Jiawei Wu, Feng Yang, Shuli Wang, Huan Wen, Ligang Feng, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396796451

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongyuan Ma, Jiawei Wu, Feng Yang, Shuli Wang, Huan Wen, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a potential electrocatalyst: highly multi-porous Co3O4 nanostructures to enhance electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05576-4</link>
      <description>Sathyanarayanan Shanmugapriya, Aneesha Singh, Ratiram Gomaji Chaudhary, Sudip Mondal, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Pranali Hadole, Aniruddha Mondal, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396801878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sathyanarayanan Shanmugapriya, Aneesha Singh, Ratiram Gomaji Chaudhary, Sudip Mondal, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Pranali Hadole, Aniruddha Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05576-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attaining Substantially Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Rates on Ni Foam Catalysts in a Gas Diffusion Electrode Setup</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400050</link>
      <description>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz, Advanced energy and sustainability research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396806504

                Water electrolysis plays a central role in the transition to a fossil&#8208;free society, but there are significant challenges to overcome in order to increase its availability on a large scale. Alkaline water electrolysis is a mature and scalable technology, although it has several disadvantages compared to electrolyzers working in acidic environments. In particular, the use of highly alkaline aqueous electrolytes can lead to corrosion, and the achieved current densities are relatively low. This study addresses the latter limitation by introducing a gas diffusion electrode (GDE) setup as a novel development tool that bridges the gap between research and practical applications in commercial devices such as fuel cells and electrolyzers. A high surface area Ni foam catalyst that can sustain exceptional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) current densities of up to 4 A cm &#8722;2 in a quasi&#8208;steady&#8208;state within our GDE setup operating in an alkaline environment is presented. The high performance of this Ni&#8208;based benchmark catalyst is attributed to its deposition onto a mesh&#8208;like porous transport layer (PTL) via hydrogen&#8208;templated electrodeposition. This forms a porous foam&#8208;like structure that augments the mass transport of the gaseous reactants at the GDE.</description>
      <author>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co3O4 derived ZnO: An effective electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.087</link>
      <description>Abdul Hanan, Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Rashmi Walvekar, Mohd Ubaidullah, Abdullah A. Al&#8208;Kahtani, Mohammad Khalid, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396809600

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Hanan, Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Rashmi Walvekar, Mohd Ubaidullah, Abdullah A. Al&#8208;Kahtani, Mohammad Khalid</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerium doping modulates the surface electronic structure of IrOx/TiN to promote the stability of acid oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144418</link>
      <description>Xingxing Duan, Huiyuan Liu, Weiqi Zhang, Qiang Ma, Qian Xu, Lindiwe Khotseng, Huaneng Su, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396812876

                The stability of supported Ir-based catalysts in acid oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a pressing challenge, which hinders the commercial viability of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) technology. Herein, we propose a cerium doping strategy to enhance the stability of supported Ir-based catalyst toward OER. The Ce-doped supported catalysts, designated as Ce-IrOx/TiN, were synthesized using an organic colloidal method. Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) analysis reveals highly dispersed IrOx nanoparticles averaging 1.5 nm on the TiN support. X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS) investigations further elucidate that Ce doping effectively stabilizes the Ir species predominantly in states below 4+, crucial for modulating the surface electronic structure and thereby improving both the activity and stability of the catalysts. Electrochemical characterization highlights the superior performance of the optimized catalyst, 6%-Ce-IrOx/TiN, with an impressively low overpotential of 242 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 57.5 mV dec&#8722;1, showcasing its significance in facilitating OER. Moreover, its mass activity surpasses that of commercial IrO2 by 5.1 times at 1.7 V. Prolonged constant current testing further demonstrates the exceptional stability of the catalyst, affirming the critical role of Ce doping as a pivotal strategy for enhancing the stability of supported Ir-based catalysts and advancing the prospects for robust OER performance in PEMWE systems.</description>
      <author>Xingxing Duan, Huiyuan Liu, Weiqi Zhang, Qiang Ma, Qian Xu, Lindiwe Khotseng, Huaneng Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-Induced Electronic Structure Modulation of Self-Evolved Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets for the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01051</link>
      <description>Liujun Jin, Chengying Yang, Shuyi Chen, Jili Hou, P. Liu, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396815156

                Modulating the electronic structure of the electrocatalyst plays a vital role in boosting the electrocatalytic performance of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this work, we introduced a one-step solvothermal method to fabricate 1,1-ferrocene dicarboxylic acid (FcDA)-decorated self-evolved nickel sulfide (Ni3S2) nanosheet arrays on a nickel foam (NF) framework (denoted as FcDA-Ni3S2/NF). Benefiting from the interconnected ultrathin nanosheet architecture, ligand dopants induced and facilitated in situ structural reconstruction, and the FcDA-decorated Ni3S2 (FcDA-Ni3S2/NF) outperformed its singly doped and undoped counterparts in terms of OER activity. The optimized FcDA-Ni3S2/NF self-supported electrode presents a remarkably low overpotential of 268 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 for the OER and demonstrates robust electrochemical stability for 48 h in a 1.0 M KOH electrolyte. More importantly, in situ electrochemical Raman spectroscopy reveals the generation of catalytically active oxyhydroxide species (NiOOH) derived from the surface construction during the OER of pristine FcDA-Ni3S2/NF, contributing significantly to its superior electrocatalytic performance. This study concerns the modulation of electronic structure through ligand engineering and may provide profound insight into the design of cost-efficient OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Liujun Jin, Chengying Yang, Shuyi Chen, Jili Hou, P. Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superior Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalyst based on Ni&#8208;Ellagic Acid Coordination Polymer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400871</link>
      <description>Rui&#8208;Lin Chai, Qian Zhao, Jie Li, Zhaogang Dong, Yuxin Sun, Xiaocong Wang, Penglin Zhang, Wenting Wu, Guangyue Li, Jin Zhao, Sheng&#8208;Hua Li, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396826797

                Abstract The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is central to energy conversion technologies, but the high cost and scarcity of commercial noble metal catalysts limit their widespread application. Natural products exhibit great potential in preparing high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts due to their cost&#8208;effectiveness and sustainability. Here, a kind of 1D polymers [M&#8208;EA (M&#9552;Co, Cu, Ni)] for oxygen evolution reaction via the complexation of ellagic acid (EA) with metal ions are reported. It is found that Ni&#8208;EA displays a low overpotential (190 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and an ultralow Tafel slope (28 mV dec &#8722;1 ), with a production cost of only 3.6 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 % of IrO 2 . Density functional theory investigations reveal the electrocatalytic mechanism of the OER. A rechargeable Zn&#8208;Air battery using Ni&#8208;EA+Pt/C as the air electrode shows a lower charging potential and better cycling stability than the IrO 2 +Pt/C&#8208;based battery. This work provides a train for the development of state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Rui&#8208;Lin Chai, Qian Zhao, Jie Li, Zhaogang Dong, Yuxin Sun, Xiaocong Wang, Penglin Zhang, Wenting Wu, Guangyue Li, Jin Zhao, Sheng&#8208;Hua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400871</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Oxygen Vacancies in In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; with Enhanced Polysulfides Immobilization and Selective Catalytic Capability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401567</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Huanhuan Li, Jie Ji, Jingjie Liu, Qing Zhang, Sheng Ma, Jun L&#252;, Zhengyu Bai, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396827079

                Abstract Lithium&#8211;sulfur (Li&#8211;S) battery is identified as an ideal candidate for next&#8208;generation energy storage systems in consideration of its high theoretical energy density and abundant sulfur resources. However, the shuttling behavior of soluble polysulfides (LiPSs) and their sluggish reaction kinetics severely limit the practical application of the current Li&#8211;S battery. In this work, a series of In 2 O 3 nanocubes with different oxygen vacancy concentrations are designed and prepared via a facile self&#8208;template method. The introduced oxygen vacancy on In 2 O 3 can effectively rearrange the charge distribution and enhance sulfiphilic property. Moreover, the In 2 O 3 with high oxygen vacancy concentration (H&#8208;In 2 O 3 ) can slightly slow down the solid&#8211;liquid conversion process and significantly accelerate the liquid&#8211;solid conversion process, thus reducing the accumulation of LiPSs in electrolyte and inhibiting the shuttle effect. Contributed by the unique selective catalytic capability, the prepared H&#8208;In 2 O 3 exhibits excellent electrochemical performance when used as sulfur host. For instance, a high reversible capacity of 609 mAh g &#8722;1 is obtained with only 0.044% capacity decay per cycle over 1000 cycles at 1.0 C. This work presents a typical example for designing advanced sulfur hosts, which is crucial for the commercialization of Li&#8211;S battery.</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Huanhuan Li, Jie Ji, Jingjie Liu, Qing Zhang, Sheng Ma, Jun L&#252;, Zhengyu Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Doping Regulates Electrocatalysts Restructuring during Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400332</link>
      <description>Maoyu Wang, Brian A. Muhich, Zizhou He, Zhenzhen Yang, Dongqi Yang, Marcos Lucero, Hoan K.K. Nguyen, George E. Sterbinsky, L&#237;ney &#193;rnad&#243;ttir, Hua Zhou, Ling Fei, Zhenxing Feng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396827991

                High&#8208;efficiency and low&#8208;cost catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are critical for electrochemical water splitting to generate hydrogen, which is a clean fuel for sustainable energy conversion and storage. Among the emerging OER catalysts, transition metal dichalcogenides have exhibited superior activity compared to commercial standards such as RuO2, but inferior stability due to uncontrolled restructuring with OER. In this study, we create bimetallic sulfide catalysts by adapting the atomic ratio of Ni and Co in CoxNi1&#8208;xSy electrocatalysts to investigate the intricate restructuring processes. Surface&#8208;sensitive X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and bulk&#8208;sensitive X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy confirmed the favorable restructuring of transition metal sulfide material following OER processes. Our results indicate that a small amount of Ni substitution can reshape the Co local electronic structure, which regulates the restructuring process to optimize the balance between OER activity and stability. This work represents a significant advancement in the development of efficient and noble metal&#8208;free OER electrocatalysts through a doping&#8208;regulated restructuring approach.</description>
      <author>Maoyu Wang, Brian A. Muhich, Zizhou He, Zhenzhen Yang, Dongqi Yang, Marcos Lucero, Hoan K.K. Nguyen, George E. Sterbinsky, L&#237;ney &#193;rnad&#243;ttir, Hua Zhou, Ling Fei, Zhenxing Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Destabilization of Oxidized Lattice Oxygen in Layered Oxide Cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03643</link>
      <description>Chunjing Hu, Xiaobing Lou, Wei Xiang, Jingxin Li, Zhenhuang Su, Nian Zhang, J Li, Bingwen Hu, Chao Li, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396828286

                Integrating anion-redox capacity with orthodox cation-redox capacity is deemed as a promising solution for high-energy-density battery cathodes surmounting the present technical bottlenecks. However, the evolution of oxidized oxygen species during the electrochemical or chemical process easily jeopardizes the reversibility of oxygen redox and remains poorly understood. Herein, we showcase the gradual conversion of the &#960;-interacting oxygen (localized hole states on O) to the &#963;-interacting oxygen upon resting at a high voltage for P3-type Na0.6Li0.2Mn0.8O2 with nominally stable ribbon-like superstructure, accompanied by the O&#8211;O dimerization and the local structural reorganization. We further pinpoint an abnormal Li+ migration process from the alkali&#8211;metal layer to the transition-metal layer for desodiated P3&#8211;Na0.6Li0.2Mn0.8O2, thereby leading to a partial reconstruction of the ribbon superstructure. The high-voltage plateau of oxygen-redox cathodes is concluded to be exclusively controlled by the oxygen stabilization mechanism rather than the superstructure ordering. In addition, there exists a kinetic competition between &#960; and &#963; interaction during the uninterrupted electrochemical process.</description>
      <author>Chunjing Hu, Xiaobing Lou, Wei Xiang, Jingxin Li, Zhenhuang Su, Nian Zhang, J Li, Bingwen Hu, Chao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the pH-Dependent Catalytic Activity for the Layered Li&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;CoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00413</link>
      <description>Huiyan Zeng, Jiajun Chen, Chao Wang, Jun Qi, Zhongfei Liu, Mengxian Li, Long Gu, Jian Wen Wang, Enna Hong, Yan Zhang, Jin Xu, Chunzhen Yang, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830301

                Many highly active catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) demonstrate strong pH-dependent catalytic activities. However, the exact mechanism behind this phenomenon is still a subject of debate. In this study, delithiated Li0.5CoO2 is utilized as a model catalyst due to its tunable chemical states and layered structure that can facilitate reversible intercalation and deintercalation of cations. By increasing the pH to 14 using a 1.0 M CsOH solution, rapid intercalation of Cs+ cations and water molecules induce notable lattice expansion up to 9.9 &#197;, resulting in an order of magnitude higher OER intrinsic activity comparing to that in 0.1 M CsOH. It is hypothesized that lattice water in layered structure facilitates the dynamic intercalation and deintercalation of Cs+ cations, promoting the so-called "electrochemical-chemical" reaction mechanism. These findings provide valuable insights into the intricate nature of surface dynamics and the redox chemistry on the catalyst/electrolyte interface during the OER.</description>
      <author>Huiyan Zeng, Jiajun Chen, Chao Wang, Jun Qi, Zhongfei Liu, Mengxian Li, Long Gu, Jian Wen Wang, Enna Hong, Yan Zhang, Jin Xu, Chunzhen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-High Performance of In Situ Constructed Trimetallic (Pd, Fe, Co) Nanoparticles on Carbon Paper as an Electrocatalyst for Large Current Density Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4a0c</link>
      <description>Theophile Niyitanga, Gyawali Ghanashyam, Dieudonne Tanue Nde, Haekyoung Kim, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830767

                Abstract Seawater electrocatalysis holds significant promise as a technology for hydrogen production. A simple and low-cost impregnation-hydrothermal and thermal reduction strategy was used to synthesis in-situ constructed three-dimensional porous trimetallic (Pd, Fe, and Co) anchored on a cheap and high-conducting carbon paper (CP) electrode for water electrolysis in alkaline media. The fabricated PdFeCo1&#8722;xONPs@CP electrode had superhydrophilic and superaerophobic properties, allowing for efficient removal of oxygen bubbles from the electrode surface due to the close interaction between the electrode and electrolyte. Furthermore, the synergistic effect of trimetallics and CP-fibers significantly increased OER intrinsic activity. PdFeCo1&#8722;xONPs@CP catalyst demonstrated critical low overpotentials of 220 and 300 mV, resulting in an extraordinarily high current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2. For the full cell overall water splitting performance, cell overpotentials as low as 140 and 151 mV were needed to drive 10 mA cm-2 in seawater and alkaline solution electrolytes.</description>
      <author>Theophile Niyitanga, Gyawali Ghanashyam, Dieudonne Tanue Nde, Haekyoung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4a0c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noble metal clusters substitution in porous Ni substrate renders high mass-specific activities toward oxygen evolution reaction and methanol oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109989</link>
      <description>Fenglin Wang, Chengwei Kuang, Zhicheng Zheng, Dan Wu, Hao Wan, Gen Chen, Ning Zhang, Xiaohe Liu, Renzhi Ma, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831064

                The sluggish reaction kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) remain obstacles to the commercial promotion of water splitting and direct methanol fuel cells. Considering the vital role of noble metals in electrocatalytic activity, this work focuses on the rational synthesis of Ni-noble metal composite nanocatalysts for overcoming the drawbacks of high cost and susceptible oxidized surfaces of noble metals. The inherent catalytic activity is improved by the altered electronic structure and effective active sites of the catalyst induced by the size effect of noble metal clusters. In particular, a series of Ni-noble metal nanocomposites are successfully synthesized by partially introducing noble metal into Ni with porous interfacial defects derived from Ni-Al layered double hydroxide (LDH). The Ni10Pd1 nanocomposite exhibits high OER catalytic activity with an overpotential of 0.279 V at 10 mA/cm2, surpassing Ni10Ag1 and Ni10Au1 counterparts. Furthermore, the average diameter of Pd clusters gradually increases from 5.57 nm to 44.44 nm with the increased proportion of doped Pd, leading to the passivation of catalytic activity due to the exacerbated surface oxidation of Pd in the form of Pd2+. After optimization, Ni10Pd1 delivers significantly enhanced OER and MOR electroactivities and long-term stability compared to that of Ni2Pd1, Ni1Pd1 and Ni1Pd2, which is conducive to the effective utilization of Pd and alleviation of surface oxidation.</description>
      <author>Fenglin Wang, Chengwei Kuang, Zhicheng Zheng, Dan Wu, Hao Wan, Gen Chen, Ning Zhang, Xiaohe Liu, Renzhi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time&#8208;Resolved Oxidation State Changes Are Key to Elucidating the Bifunctionality of Perovskite Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12737</link>
      <description>Casey E. Beall, Emiliana Fabbri, Adam H. Clark, Vivian Meier, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Dino Aegerter, Thomas Graule, Thomas Schmidt, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831905

                In a unified regenerative fuel cell (URFC) or reversible fuel cell, the oxygen bifunctional catalyst must switch reversibly between the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), fuel cell mode, and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), electrolyzer mode. However, it is often unclear what effect alternating between ORR and OER has on the electrochemical behavior and physiochemical properties of the catalyst. Herein, operando X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) is utilized to monitor the continuous and dynamic evolution of the Co, Mn, and Fe oxidation states of perovskite catalysts Ba 0.5 Sr 0.5 Co 0.8 Fe 0.2 O 3&#8208;&#948; (BSCF) and La 0.4 Sr 0.6 MnO 3&#8208;&#948; (LSM), while the potential is oscillated between reducing and oxidizing potentials with cyclic voltammetry. The results reveal the importance of investigating bifunctional catalysts by alternating between fuel cell and electrolyzer operation and highlight the limitations and challenges of bifunctional catalysts. It is shown that the requirements for ORR and OER performance are divergent and that the oxidative potentials of OER are detrimental to ORR activity. These findings are used to give guidelines for future bifunctional catalyst design. Additionally, it is demonstrated how sunlight can be used to reactivate the ORR activity of LSM after rigorous cycling.</description>
      <author>Casey E. Beall, Emiliana Fabbri, Adam H. Clark, Vivian Meier, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, Ivano E. Castelli, Dino Aegerter, Thomas Graule, Thomas Schmidt</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finite element modeling simulation of oxygen evolution during charging in lithium-oxygen batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107752</link>
      <description>Shuji Hanada, Shuji Nakanishi, Yoshiharu Mukouyama, Electrochemistry communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834585

                The quest for advanced energy storage solutions has intensified the focus on developing next-generation secondary batteries, with lithium-oxygen batteries (LOB) standing out for their superior theoretical gravimetric energy density. This study introduces a novel model-based approach to battery development, enabling the detailed analysis of charge&#8211;discharge cycles and oxygen evolution efficiency within a virtual environment. Our model distinctively simulates the oxidative decomposition of lithium peroxide (Li2O2) and differentiates between its formation through solution and surface pathways, addressing the complexities of the charging process and its multiple elementary steps. The developed model further categorizes the oxidative decomposition species into four distinct types, facilitating a comprehensive understanding of their interactions, voltage profile changes, and O2 evolution within the battery's porous cathode. This approach not only enhances the understanding of battery behavior but also aids in refining the design of component materials, thereby propelling forward the development of LOBs with improved energy density and cycle performance.</description>
      <author>Shuji Hanada, Shuji Nakanishi, Yoshiharu Mukouyama</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Electrocatalytic Activity Of Selenide Nanoparticle For Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174797</link>
      <description>H.H. Somaily, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835403

                Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) plays a vital role in water electrolysis, but its slow kinetics and expensive catalysts are obstacles to widespread use. To improve the OER activity, it is crucial to create a well-structured design for electrocatalysts based on transition metals, which may be applied to a conducting polymer substrate. This research reports a facile hydrothermal synthesis and remarkable catalytic behavior of NbSe2/g-CN as an OER catalyst in an alkaline condition. The fabricated electrocatalysts were examined utilizing numerous analytical techniques to assess their crystallinity, oxidation states and morphology. NbSe2/g-CN shows enhanced electro-catalytic behavior to OER in alkaline solution (1.0 KOH) with minor overpotential (196 mV) and Tafel slop (38 mV/dec) than pristine NbSe2 electrocatalyst was associated with the exceptional conductivity of NF and its highly porous structure, along with a greater SSA. In addition, the durability of the electrocatalyst was examined via cyclic stability and chronoamperometry study over 40 h. This study demonstrates that TMSe with specific morphology can improve electrocatalytic activity when combined with g-CN, demonstrating its potential for reliable and eco-friendly energy generation</description>
      <author>H.H. Somaily</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a bifunctional BiVO4 based S-scheme heterojunction for enhancing photothermal-photocatalytic oxygen generation and benzaldehyde production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131813</link>
      <description>Pengpeng He, Lijuan Sun, Shahid Ali Khan, Shaobin Mei, Yuan Wu, Lele Wang, Zhibao Li, Fenghua Wang, Qinqin Liu, Fuel. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396841849

                In order to address the main challenges in photocatalysis, such as the recombination of photo-generated carriers and the limited absorption range of light, a successful strategy was developed by creating a photothermal-photocatalytic S-scheme heterojunction through the combination of CdS nanoparticles with BiVO4 nanorods. XPS analysis, as well as SPV results, revealed the establishment, direction, and strength of the internal electric field (IEF) in the created CdS/BiVO4 heterojunction. Due to the matched band structure and the strong IEF, the heterojunction followed the S-scheme transfer mode under light, inducing the strong redox ability and fast separation of photo-generated carriers. Besides that, the heat generated by incorporating a photothermal-effect during illumination also helped to boost the photocatalytic reaction. As a result, the engineered CdS/BiVO4 heterojunction exhibited an impressive benzaldehyde production of 17.45 mmol g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1, approximately four times higher than that of pure BiVO4 (3.70 mmol g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1). Furthermore, the oxygen evolution rate of the CdS/BiVO4 heterojunction was 3146.68 &#181;mol&#183;g&#8722;1, much higher than that of BiVO4 (1042.98 &#181;mol&#183;g&#8722;1). This study introduces a novel approach to overcome the fundamental obstacles in semiconductor photocatalysis, paving the way for enhanced overall performance.</description>
      <author>Pengpeng He, Lijuan Sun, Shahid Ali Khan, Shaobin Mei, Yuan Wu, Lele Wang, Zhibao Li, Fenghua Wang, Qinqin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn-doped nickel-copper phosphides as oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalyst in alkaline seawater solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.094</link>
      <description>Yanhong Wang, Qiang Dong, Xiaoqiang Du, Xiaoshuang Zhang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396841857

                Compared with traditional water electrolysis, electrolysis of seawater has larger resources and a brighter future. However, seawater contains more elements that have greater corrosive effects on electrodes; especially chloride ions (seawater contains more chloride ions) have the greatest impact. The existence of the corrosion problem creates greater difficulties in electrolyzing seawater, further limiting the efficiency of the electrocatalyst for electrolysis of seawater. In this paper, we report a Mn-doped Ni2P/Cu3P as an environmentally friendly monofunctional electrode for seawater electrolysis, which was made by a simple hydrothermal phosphatization operation method. The experimental results show that Mn-doped Ni2P/Cu3P presents overpotential of only 161 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at iR compensation of 90 and a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. It has a small Tafel slope (25.15 mV dec&#8722;1) and a large capacitance (9.58 mF cm&#8722;2 on 1 &#215; 1 nickel foam), which exceeds most reported oxygen evolution activities of non-precious metal-based electrocatalysts for electrolysis of alkaline seawater. The performance of Ni2P/Cu3P was probably significantly enhanced due to Mn doping by some characterization means. Through Density functional theory (DFT) analysis, it is known that the doping of Mn gives a large enhancement in the adsorption energy of water when Ni2P/Cu3P is electrolyzed with seawater. This paper provides train of thought for the exploration of excellent electrocatalysts for electrolysis of alkaline seawater.</description>
      <author>Yanhong Wang, Qiang Dong, Xiaoqiang Du, Xiaoshuang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Sm dopant on electrocatalytic activity of AgNbO3 perovskite fabricated by sonication method for Oxygen Evaluation Reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.122</link>
      <description>Mukhtiar Hussain, Meznah M. Alanazi, Saeed D. Alahmari, Muhammad Abdullah, Khurshid Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Gul N. Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396844440

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukhtiar Hussain, Meznah M. Alanazi, Saeed D. Alahmari, Muhammad Abdullah, Khurshid Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Gul N. Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triple-Function Mn Regulation of NiFe (oxy)hydroxide for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.04.026</link>
      <description>Wan Hui, Meng&#8208;Yuan Xie, Ying Zhang, Jianhang Nie, Tao Huang, Lei Li, Jinghui Shi, Minghua Xian, Jianhui Huang, Wangyu Hu, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Fei Gao, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396846576

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wan Hui, Meng&#8208;Yuan Xie, Ying Zhang, Jianhang Nie, Tao Huang, Lei Li, Jinghui Shi, Minghua Xian, Jianhui Huang, Wangyu Hu, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Fei Gao, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.04.026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Approach for Efficient Water Oxidation and Supercapacitor Applications Based on Morphologically Transformed, Surface Rich Oxygen Vacancies of Co3o4 Nanostructures Co-Synthesized with Potato Starch Peel Extract</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10876-024-02631-y</link>
      <description>Abdul Jaleel Laghari, Umair Aftab, Aneela Tahira, Muhammad Yameen Solangi, Ahmed Ali Hulio, Ghulam Mustafa Thebo, Muhammad Ishaque Abro, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Susheel Kumar, Elmuez A. Dawi, Ayman Nafady, Antonia Infantes&#8208;Molina, M&#233;lanie Emo, Brigitte Vigolo, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, Journal of cluster science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396847427

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Jaleel Laghari, Umair Aftab, Aneela Tahira, Muhammad Yameen Solangi, Ahmed Ali Hulio, Ghulam Mustafa Thebo, Muhammad Ishaque Abro, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Susheel Kumar, Elmuez A. Dawi, Ayman Nafady, Antonia Infantes&#8208;Molina, M&#233;lanie Emo, Brigitte Vigolo, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10876-024-02631-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning nanoflower-like Fe/Co hybrids with high content oxyhydroxide accelerating oxygen evolution kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.034</link>
      <description>Lixia Wang, Jia Huang, Qiuping Gan, Jeng&#8208;Yi Huang, Xing Hu, Dongcheng Liu, Tayirjan Taylor Isimjan, Yuting Yang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396847450

                Iron hydroxide (FeOOH) is a potential active component in iron-based electrocatalysts for water electrolysis. However, its catalytic performance is constrained by its slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics. Herein, we synthesized a nanoflower-like FeCo-hydro(oxy)oxides composite with tunable Fe/Co ratios (Fex-Coy) on nickel foam (NF) via a one-step electrodeposition technique. This method allows for precise control over the morphology and composition of the hybrid nanoflowers. The optimized Fe9-Co1 discloses favorable OER performance with a low overpotential of 222 mV at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 and demonstrates good stability exceeding 60 h at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Further, an assembled Fe9-Co1(+) || Pt/C(&#8722;) dual-electrode configuration achieves a low cell voltage of 1.73 V at the current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 for water splitting, with long-term stability for 70 h and minimal degradation. Studies indicate that the distinctive nanoflower morphology of Fe9-Co1 enhances active site exposure, while both FeOOH and reconstructed CoOOH serve as catalytic centers, contributing to the observed OER performance. This work introduces a facile approach for synthesizing OER electrocatalysts, underscoring the role of the high-valence state of Fe/Co as active sites in the OER process.</description>
      <author>Lixia Wang, Jia Huang, Qiuping Gan, Jeng&#8208;Yi Huang, Xing Hu, Dongcheng Liu, Tayirjan Taylor Isimjan, Yuting Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing high entropy alloy/MoC heterostructure as efficient and stable catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119780</link>
      <description>Jianqiang Zhao, Chengxu Zhang, Zihan Zhang, Qianglong Qi, Yue Zhang, Jue Hu, Applied catalysis. A, General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396847497

                Due to the expensive cost of precious metals, there is an urgent need to develop cheap and efficient catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As a novel catalyst, high-entropy alloy (HEA) has found widespread application in the field of hydrogen production through water electrolysis. However, a significant portion of HEA catalysts prepared by traditional solvothermal methods are challenging due to their high cost, extended compound cycle, and relatively difficult electronic structure adjustment in the catalytic center. In this study, a heterostructure catalyst composed of MoC and FeCoNiMo HEA alloy (denoted as FeCoNiMo-M) was synthesized by the microwave method. Catalysts produced via the microwave method typically exhibit MoC encloses the spherical heterostructure of the internal high entropy alloy, MoC not only protects the true active center Ni-OOH, but even further regulates the electronic structure of the catalyst. Notably, the FeCoNiMo-M sample synthesized using microwave demonstrates an overpotential of merely 232 mV (@10 mA cm-2) in 1 M KOH, nearly 20 mV lower compared to the traditional hydrothermally-synthesized FeCoNiMo-H HEA catalyst. Furthermore, the FeCoNiMo-M catalyst demonstrates impressive durability in OER with a significant current density of 100 mA cm-2 for a duration of 240 hours. The in-situ Raman results indicate that the FeCoNiMo-M catalyst undergoes the conversion of the actual reaction intermediate Ni-OOH and accelerates the OER with only a very low overpotential. These findings suggest that our approach could open up possibilities for the advancement of OER catalysts that are both more convenient and efficient.</description>
      <author>Jianqiang Zhao, Chengxu Zhang, Zihan Zhang, Qianglong Qi, Yue Zhang, Jue Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119780</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous iridium oxide coating on TiO2 for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.114</link>
      <description>Kaiyang Zhang, Guo Chen, Yun Wu, Rui Yao, Qiang Zhao, Jinping Li, Guang Liu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396851686

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaiyang Zhang, Guo Chen, Yun Wu, Rui Yao, Qiang Zhao, Jinping Li, Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating active motifs in Ni-Fe oxide by introducing dual-defect for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.078</link>
      <description>Yucheng Wu, Yanli Yu, Wei Shen, Yimin Jiang, Rongxing He, Ming Li, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396856653

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yucheng Wu, Yanli Yu, Wei Shen, Yimin Jiang, Rongxing He, Ming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel&#8211;Cobalt Bimetal Hierarchical Hollow Nanosheets for Efficient Oxygen Evolution in Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102298</link>
      <description>Rui An, Guoling Li, Zhiliang Liu, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857550

                The electrochemical splitting of seawater is promising but also challenging for sustainable hydrogen gas production. Herein, ZIF-67 nanosheets are grown on nickel foam and then etched by Ni2+ in situ to obtain a hierarchical hollow nanosheets structure, which demonstrates outstanding OER performance in alkaline seawater (355 mV at 100 mA cm&#8722;2). Diven by a silicon solar panel, an overall electrolysis energy efficiency of 62% is achieved at a high current of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in seawater electrolytes. This work provides a new design route for improving the catalytic activity of metal organic framework materials.</description>
      <author>Rui An, Guoling Li, Zhiliang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Based Composites for Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysts: Design, Fabrication, and Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102265</link>
      <description>Chang Gao, Haoyu Yao, Peijie Wang, Min Zhu, Xue&#8208;Rong Shi, Shusheng Xu, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396857660

                The four-electron oxidation process of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) highly influences the performance of many green energy storage and conversion devices due to its sluggish kinetics. The fabrication of cost-effective OER electrocatalysts via a facile and green method is, hence, highly desirable. This review summarizes and discusses the recent progress in creating carbon-based materials for alkaline OER. The contents mainly focus on the design, fabrication, and application of carbon-based materials for alkaline OER, including metal-free carbon materials, carbon-based supported composites, and carbon-based material core&#8211;shell hybrids. The work presents references and suggestions for the rational design of highly efficient carbon-based OER materials.</description>
      <author>Chang Gao, Haoyu Yao, Peijie Wang, Min Zhu, Xue&#8208;Rong Shi, Shusheng Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Acidic Electrosynthesis of Hydrogen Peroxide at Industrial&#8208;Level Current Densities Promoted by Alkali Metal Cations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406452</link>
      <description>Peike Cao, Xueyang Zhao, Yanming Liu, Haiguang Zhang, Kun Zhao, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu, Dongrui Fan, Nathaniel N. Nichols, Jingguang G. Chen, Quan Xie, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396868774

                Acidic H2O2 synthesis through electrocatalytic 2e&#8211; oxygen reduction presents a sustainable alternative to the energy&#8208;intensive anthraquinone oxidation technology. Nevertheless, acidic H2O2 electrosynthesis suffers from low H2O2 Faradaic efficiencies primarily due to the competing reactions of 4e&#8211; oxygen reduction to H2O and hydrogen evolution in environments with high H+ concentrations. Here, we demonstrate the significant effect of alkali metal cations, acting as competing ions with H+, in promoting acidic H2O2 electrosynthesis at industrial&#8208;level currents, resulting in an effective current densities of 50&#8210;421 mA cm&#8210;2 with 84&#8210;100% Faradaic efficiency and a production rate of 856&#8210;7842 &#956;mol cm&#8208;2 h&#8208;1 that far exceeds the performance observed in pure acidic electrolytes or low&#8208;current electrolysis. Finite&#8208;element simulations indicate that high interfacial pH near the electrode surface formed at high currents is crucial for activating the promotional effect of K+. In situ attenuated total reflection Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations reveal the central role of alkali metal cations in stabilizing the key *OOH intermediate to suppress 4e&#8211; oxygen reduction through interacting with coordinated H2O.</description>
      <author>Peike Cao, Xueyang Zhao, Yanming Liu, Haiguang Zhang, Kun Zhao, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu, Dongrui Fan, Nathaniel N. Nichols, Jingguang G. Chen, Quan Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Coordination of Bimetallic Fe&#8211;Co Single-Atom Pairs toward Enhanced Bifunctional Activity for Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01342</link>
      <description>Zhitong Li, Xiongwei Zhong, Lei Gao, Junjie Hu, Wenbo Peng, Xingzhu Wang, Guangmin Zhou, Baomin Xu, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396870661

                The advancement of rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (RZABs) faces challenges from the pronounced polarization and sluggish kinetics of oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER). Single-atom catalysts offer an effective solution, yet their insufficient or singular catalytic activity hinders their development. In this work, a dual single-atom catalyst, FeCo-SAs, was fabricated, featuring atomically dispersed N3&#8211;Fe&#8211;Co&#8211;N4 sites on N-doped graphene nanosheets for bifunctional activity. Introducing Co into Fe single-atoms and secondary pyrolysis altered Fe coordination with N, creating an asymmetric environment that promoted charge transfer and increased the density of states near the Fermi level. This catalyst achieved a narrow potential gap of 0.616 V, with a half-wave potential of 0.884 V for ORR (vs the reversible hydrogen electrode) and a low OER overpotential of 270 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2. Owing to the superior activity of FeCo-SAs, RZABs exhibited a peak power density of 203.36 mW cm&#8211;2 and an extended cycle life of over 550 h, exceeding the commercial Pt/C + IrO2 catalyst. Furthermore, flexible RZABs with FeCo-SAs demonstrated the promising future of bimetallic pairs in wearable energy storage devices.</description>
      <author>Zhitong Li, Xiongwei Zhong, Lei Gao, Junjie Hu, Wenbo Peng, Xingzhu Wang, Guangmin Zhou, Baomin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Phenalenyl-Based Dinuclear Ni(II) Complex: An Electrocatalyst with Two Single Ni Sites for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00078</link>
      <description>Nisha Kamboj, Ramesh K. Metre, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396871546

                A new dinuclear Ni(II) complex 1, [Ni2II(dtbh-PLY)2], is synthesized from 9-(2-(3,6-di-tert-butyl-2-hydroxybenzylidene)hydrazineyl)-1H-phenalen-1-one, dtbh-PLYH2 ligand, and structurally characterized by various analytical tools including the single-crystal X-ray diffraction (SCXRD) technique. In the solid state, both Ni(II) metal centers in complex 1 exist in a distorted square planar geometry and display the presence of rare Ni&#183;&#183;&#183;H&#8211;C anagostic interactions to form a one-dimensional (1-D) linear motif in the supramolecular array. Complex 1 is further stabilized in the solid state by &#960;&#8211;&#960;-stacking interactions between the highly delocalized phenalenyl rings. The redox features of complex 1 have been analyzed by the cyclic voltammetry (CV) technique in solution as well as in the solid state, revealing the crucial involvement of both the Ni(II) metal centers for undergoing quasi-reversible oxidation reactions on the application of an anodic sweep. A complex 1-modified glassy carbon electrode, GC-1, is employed as an electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in 1.0 M KOH, giving an OER onset at 1.45 V, and very low OER overpotential, 300 mV vs the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) to reach 10 mA cm&#8211;2 current density. Furthermore, GC-1 displayed fast OER kinetics with a Tafel slope of 40 mV dec&#8211;1, a significantly lower Tafel slope value than those of previously reported molecular Ni(II) catalysts. In situ electrochemical experiments and postoperational UV&#8211;vis, Fourier transform infrared (FT-IR), scanning electron microscopy-energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (SEM-EDS), and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) studies were performed to analyze the stability of the molecular nature of complex 1 and to gain reasonable insights into the true OER catalyst.</description>
      <author>Nisha Kamboj, Ramesh K. Metre</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dense heterogeneous interfaces boost the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124148</link>
      <description>Shuai Liu, Fumin Wang, Jiawei Wang, Weitao Zheng, Xinyuan He, Tongxue Zhang, Zhiwei Zhang, Qian Liu, Xijun Liu, Xubin Zhang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396873831

                Efficient and cost-effective catalysts are essential to drive the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in sustainable hydrogen production through water splitting. In this study, we introduce an innovative strategy aimed at constructing heterogeneous structure that form abundant Fe2O3/NiSe2 interfaces on the FeOOH surface. The resulting catalyst exhibits extraordinary performance with an excellently low overpotential of 169 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Notably, this catalyst also demonstrates impressive long-term stability in alkaline seawater. Compared to traditional heterogeneous catalysts with core-shell structures, Fe2O3/NiSe2 possesses a closely heterogeneous interface, which plays a role in modulating the interface electron. Supported by complementary spectroscopy and theoretical calculations, it has been further demonstrated that the distinctive Fe-O-Ni-Se structure can effectively modulate the electronic state of Ni, thereby enhancing the adsorption of oxygen-containing intermediates and facilitating oxygen desorption. Overall, this research presents a promising avenue for enhancing the electrocatalytic performance by amplifying active sites at interfaces.</description>
      <author>Shuai Liu, Fumin Wang, Jiawei Wang, Weitao Zheng, Xinyuan He, Tongxue Zhang, Zhiwei Zhang, Qian Liu, Xijun Liu, Xubin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting oxygen/hydrogen evolution catalysis via ruthenium doping in perovskite oxide for efficient alkaline water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160278</link>
      <description>Zhida Zhang, Min Xue, Xinyu Zhang, Conghui Si, Chunqing Tai, Qifang Lu, Mingzhi Wei, Xiujun Han, Jingyun Ma, Shunwei Chen, Erjun Guo, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396873897

                Recently, perovskite oxides have acquired a rapidly growing research interest in energy storage and conversion systems, especially the electrolysis of water. Rational doping is an extremely effective strategy to enhance the hydrogen evolution reaction/oxygen evolution reaction (HER/OER) of the perovskite oxides. Herein, a series of novel bi-functional electrocatalysts were synthesized by doping Ru in SrFeO3-&#948; perovskite oxide (SrFe1-xRuxO3-&#948;, x = 0, 0.15, 0.30, 0.45) which exhibit remarkable enhancements of HER/OER activities and long-term stabilities in the alkaline solution (1.0 M KOH). Among them, SrFe0.7Ru0.3O3-&#948; (SFR30) shows the best electrocatalytic activities for overall water splitting, exhibiting low overpotentials for HER (&#8764;41 mV) and OER (&#8764;334 mV) at &#8722;10 and 10 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively, generating current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline electrolytic cell using the potential of 1.58 V. In addition, the SFR30 electrocatalyst exhibits remarkable stability which can be operated continuously for 96 h without significant delay. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that Ru doping can effectively modulate the adsorption of intermediates on the active sites to achieve excellent electrocatalytic performance. Many new prospects have been opened for the development of bi-functional electrocatalysts for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Zhida Zhang, Min Xue, Xinyu Zhang, Conghui Si, Chunqing Tai, Qifang Lu, Mingzhi Wei, Xiujun Han, Jingyun Ma, Shunwei Chen, Erjun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Selective Review on Synthetic Oxo - Bridged Polynuclear High - Valent Manganese Centers related to Oxygen Evolving Complex of Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21275/sr24428142853</link>
      <description>S. K. Chatterjee, International journal of science and research. 13(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396875265

                The oxygen -evolving complex (OEC) oxidises water to molecular dioxygen in photosystem II (PS II) at the redox catalytic centre on the lumenal side of PS II, which includes four manganese ions, a calcium ion and a chloride ion. Exact structure or mechanistic pathways charge transfer inside of OEC is still subject to research. Many inorganic complexes have been synthesised which show structural or functional resemblance with OEC. Theses complexes helps us in understanding election transfer mechanisms operating in different steps of the oxygen -evolving complex.</description>
      <author>S. K. Chatterjee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21275/sr24428142853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Morphology Structures on Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performances of Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Mxene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/1674-0068/cjcp2401006</link>
      <description>, Chinese Journal of Chemical Physics/Chinese journal of chemical physics. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4396798559

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/1674-0068/cjcp2401006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic exploration of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</link>
      <description>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng, Computational and theoretical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396807019

                The reaction rate of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an important factor restricting its application. In this work, we have systematic explorated of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for ORR and OER. Firstly, a variety of stability analysis methods show that most of the catalysts have excellent stability. Secondly, a series of excellent bifunctional catalysts are screened by volcanic maps, ORR overpotential (&#951;ORR), OER overpotential (&#951;OER), and bifunctional index (BI), such as, RhN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.28 V, &#951;OER = 0.34 V, BI = 0.62 V) and CoN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.33 V, &#951;OER = 0.37 V, BI = 0.70 V). In particular, RhN3O1-1 has the smallest BI value, indicating that it has the best bifunctional catalytic activity. This study offers insights into how the coordination environment affects the activity of OER/ORR.</description>
      <author>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic NiCoP catalysts anchored on phosphorus-doped lignin-based carbon for robust oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02718-5</link>
      <description>Lingyingzi Xiong, Bowen Liu, Lan Du, Yanping Zhou, Xuliang Lin, Huan Wang, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396869218

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingyingzi Xiong, Bowen Liu, Lan Du, Yanping Zhou, Xuliang Lin, Huan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02718-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction by in situ growth PMo12@ZIF-67 on MWCNTs via perylene bisimide-based dispersant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174762</link>
      <description>Xinlun Song, Junshuo Cui, Zhenning Lou, Wei Shan, Hai Yu, Xiaogeng Feng, Yuejiao Wang, Ying Xiong, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396797177

                The combination of metal organic frameworks (MOFs) and multi-walled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) can significantly improve their electrochemical performance. However, in most cases, chemical pre-treatment of MWCNTs is inevitable, which may compromise the ideal performance of the final composites. Herein, via a noncovalent functionalization method, PMo12@ZIF-67 was in situ grown on the surfaces of MWCNTs with the assistance of a new dispersant containing two triethylenetetramine (TETA) segments. In order to enhance the coordination of Co metal ions with the surface of MWCNTs, phenolic hydroxyl groups were incorporated into the dispersant through reaction with gallic acid (GA). After annealing, homogeneous CNT/Co6Mo6C2/Co composites were obtained, and they showed excellent performance on oxygen evolution reaction (OER). At a current density of 10 mA cm-2, the lowest overpotential is 263 mV, of which the performance is superior to that achieved by other in situ growth methods. The uniform distribution of coordination sites and subsequent in situ growth of MOFs on MWCNTs improved the electrical conductivity of the derivatives, thereby enhanced the utilization of catalytic active sites. This study presents a novel approach for synthesizing carbon-doped electrocatalytic materials, which demonstrates significant potential in various electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Xinlun Song, Junshuo Cui, Zhenning Lou, Wei Shan, Hai Yu, Xiaogeng Feng, Yuejiao Wang, Ying Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174762</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed hexavalent iridium oxide from MnO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction for oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adg5193</link>
      <description>Ailong Li, Shiao&#8208;Tong Kong, Kiyohiro Adachi, Hideshi Ooka, Kazuna Fushimi, Qike Jiang, Hironori Ofuchi, Satoru Hamamoto, M. Oura, Kentaro Higashi, Takuma Kaneko, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura, Science. 384(6696)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396759836

                Hexavalent iridium (Ir</description>
      <author>Ailong Li, Shiao&#8208;Tong Kong, Kiyohiro Adachi, Hideshi Ooka, Kazuna Fushimi, Qike Jiang, Hironori Ofuchi, Satoru Hamamoto, M. Oura, Kentaro Higashi, Takuma Kaneko, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adg5193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the potential of (CoFeNiMnCr)3O4 high-entropy oxide synthesized from CoFeNiMnCr high-entropy alloy for efficient oxygen-evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09710-5</link>
      <description>Barbara Ljubec Bo&#382;i&#269;ek, Jitka Hre&#353;&#269;ak, Monika Ku&#353;ter, Janez Kova&#269;, Iztok Nagli&#269;, Bo&#353;tjan Markoli, Barbara &#352;etina Bati&#269;, Martin &#352;ala, Sandra Drev, &#381;iva Marinko, Miran &#268;eh, Belisa A. Marinho, Journal of materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396851772

                Abstract Electrochemical water-splitting is a promising green technology for the production of hydrogen. One of the bottlenecks, however, is the oxygen evolution half-reaction (OER), which could be overcome with the development of a suitable electrocatalyst. Recently, non-noble metal, high-entropy oxides (HEO) have been investigated as potential OER electrocatalysts, but complex synthesis approaches that usually produce the material in powder form limit their wider utilization. Here, an innovative synthesis strategy of formulating a nanostructured (CoFeNiMnCr) 3 O 4 HEO thin film on a CoFeNiMnCr high entropy alloy (HEA) using facile electrochemical and thermal treatment methods is presented. The CoFeNiMnCr HEA serves as exceptional support to be electrochemically treated in an ethylene glycol electrolyte with ammonium fluoride to form a rough and microporous structure with nanopits. The electrochemically treated CoFeNiMnCr HEA surface is more prone to oxidation during a low-temperature thermal treatment, leading to the growth of a spinel (CoFeNiMnCr) 3 O 4 HEO thin film. The (CoFeNiMnCr) 3 O 4 HEO exhibits a superior overpotential of 341 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 50 mV dec &#8722;1 along with remarkable long-term stability in alkaline media. The excellent catalytic activity and stability for the OER can serve as a promising platform for the practical utilization of (CoFeNiMnCr) 3 O 4 HEO. Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Barbara Ljubec Bo&#382;i&#269;ek, Jitka Hre&#353;&#269;ak, Monika Ku&#353;ter, Janez Kova&#269;, Iztok Nagli&#269;, Bo&#353;tjan Markoli, Barbara &#352;etina Bati&#269;, Martin &#352;ala, Sandra Drev, &#381;iva Marinko, Miran &#268;eh, Belisa A. Marinho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09710-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZnCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/NC Hollow Polyhedra for Bisphenol A Disposal and the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01442</link>
      <description>Jiao Wang, Xizhi Huang, Lei Bai, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396804842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiao Wang, Xizhi Huang, Lei Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrO2-ZrO2-SiO2 ternary oxide composites- based DSAs: Activity toward oxygen evolution reaction with long-term stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105548</link>
      <description>Mir Majid Hosseini, Mir Ghasem Hosseini, Iraj Ahadzadeh, Reza Najjar, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 161(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822732

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mir Majid Hosseini, Mir Ghasem Hosseini, Iraj Ahadzadeh, Reza Najjar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The oxygen fugacity of intermediate shergottite NWA 11043: implications for Martian mantle evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.008</link>
      <description>J F Chen, Yuyan Zhao, Qin Shu, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Du, Jian Yang, Geochimica et cosmochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835137

                Shergottite meteorites, classified as depleted, intermediate, or enriched based on incompatible trace elements and specific radiogenic isotope compositions (Sr, Nd, and Hf isotope ratios), point to multiple Martian mantle source regions. The oxygen fugacity (fO2) of these mantle regions, determined from early crystallizing minerals using the olivine-pyroxene-spinel oxybarometer, appears to correlate with incompatible trace element enrichment and isotope compositions. However, values derived from the vanadium-in-olivine oxybarometer challenge this correlation, hinting at potential biases in oxybarometry or complexities in the redox conditions of the Martian mantle. By analyzing the intermediate shergottite Northwest Africa (NWA) 11043 with various oxybarometers, this study deduced its origin from a reduced mantle source, with an average fO2 value of &#8722;0.77 &#177; 0.35 relative to the iron-w&#252;stite (IW) buffer. Notably, these values coincide with those of depleted shergottites, which represent the depleted Martian mantle region. This redox similarity between intermediate and depleted shergottites contrasts with earlier notions that postulated intermediate shergottites as a mix of depleted and enriched mantle derivatives. Moreover, intermediate shergottites such as NWA 11043, Elephant Moraine (EETA) 79001A, and Allan Hills (ALH) 77005 display 176Hf/177Hf values akin to those of depleted shergottites, suggesting that intermediate mantle components can be separated from the depleted mantle source at approximately 2.2 Ga based on model age calculations. Therefore, there presents a consistent redox state between mantle magma sources of both intermediate and depleted shergottites since the Hesperian period, while enriched shergottites lean toward more oxidized conditions past source formation. This study prompts a reassessment of conventional theories, emphasizing the nuanced redox evolution of the Martian mantle across distinct mantle source regions and underscoring the complexity of the redox evolution of the Martian mantle. The emergence of chemically diverse mantle reservoirs might predominantly arise from early magma ocean differentiation processes, albeit with inherent oxidation nuances. The differences in fO2 observed between intermediate and depleted shergottites underscore the need for more in-depth studies to decipher Martian mantle differentiation and evolution.</description>
      <author>J F Chen, Yuyan Zhao, Qin Shu, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Du, Jian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Engineering of Pt&#8211;Ni Alloy NPs by Coupling of Gold Single Atoms on N&#8208;Doped Carbon for Highly Efficient Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311971</link>
      <description>Tuyen D. Le, Dong&#8208;Seog Kim, Tuong Van Tran, U. Bharagav, Gi&#8208;Seung Shin, Geun&#8208;Jae Oh, Yeon&#8208;Tae Yu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396799524

                Abstract Improving the catalytic activity and durability of platinum&#8208;based alloy catalysts remains a formidable challenge in the context of renewable energy electrolysis applications. Herein, a facile and rapid photochemical deposition strategy for the synthesis of gold single atoms (Au SAs) anchored on N&#8208;doped carbon is presented. These Au SAs serve as a charge redistribution support for Pt&#8211;Ni alloy nanoparticles (PtNi NPs /Au SA &#8208;NDC), creating an extended electron&#8208;donating interface with Pt&#8211;Ni alloy sites. Consequently, the PtNi NPs /Au SA &#8208;NDC hybrid catalyst manifests exceptional catalytic performance and durability in both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under acidic conditions. Specifically, in ORR, it exhibits a half&#8208;wave potential (0.92 V vs RHE), with a mass activity 20.4 times superior to Pt/C at 0.9 V. In HER, PtNi NPs /Au SA &#8208;NDC demonstrates a notably reduced overpotential of 19.1 mV vs RHE at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a mass activity 38 times higher than Pt/C (at 0.25 mV). Furthermore, this hybrid catalyst displays outstanding durability, with only an 8.0 mV decay observed for ORR and a 6.9 mV decay for HER after 10 000 cycles. Theoretical calculations provide insight into the mechanism, demonstrating that isolated Au sites effectively modulate the electronic structure of Pt&#8211;Ni alloy sites, facilitating intermediate adsorption and enhancing reaction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Tuyen D. Le, Dong&#8208;Seog Kim, Tuong Van Tran, U. Bharagav, Gi&#8208;Seung Shin, Geun&#8208;Jae Oh, Yeon&#8208;Tae Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and Characterization of Metal Organic Framework and Their Application of Water Splitting for Oer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824489</link>
      <description>M. Yaseen, Faheem Ashiq, Sheereen Afaq, Haithm Yahya Mohammed Almuaalemi, Ammar Saleem, K. H. Khan, Muhammad Shafiq, Junbo Gong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396837712

                Electrochemical water splitting technology enables the production of next-generation fuels, with enhancements in energy conversion achievable through the development of superior oxygen evolution electrocatalysts. Within the spectrum of electrocatalysts, metal tellurides emerge as promising candidates due to their cost-effectiveness and exceptional performance in facilitating the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Within the present study, an FeTe2/MoO3 nano-electrocatalyst is synthesized via anion exchange reaction, directly deposited onto a nickel foam (NF) substrate within a 1.0 M KOH electrolyte medium, specifically tailored for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysis. The electrochemical assessments are conducted employing customized electrodes and evaluated under alkaline conditions utilizing cyclic voltammetry (CV), linear sweep voltammetry (LCV), and constant potential chronoamperometry (CA). Due to its distinctive morphology, characterized by enlarged electrochemically active regions and increased active sites without requiring a binding agent, the FeTe2/MoO3 composite exhibited a reduced excess of 294 mV, accompanied by a diminished Tafel slope measuring 71 mV dec&#8722;1, and demonstrated notable consistency over a duration of 40 hours for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Furthermore, this investigation confirms the enhanced activity of the FeTe2/MoO3 hybrid in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Theoretical computations corroborate these findings, suggesting the potential for developing multi-metal telluride-based materials as long-lasting and very effective OER electrocatalysts, with promising implications for future applications.</description>
      <author>M. Yaseen, Faheem Ashiq, Sheereen Afaq, Haithm Yahya Mohammed Almuaalemi, Ammar Saleem, K. H. Khan, Muhammad Shafiq, Junbo Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principle calculations study of ORR/OER electrocatalytic activity of ruthenium polyphthalocyanine axially modified with aliphatic thiol groups</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00424h</link>
      <description>Guilin Wang, Rongrong Ren, Xiao Feng, Wei Wang, Jie Meng, Jianfeng Jia, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396826041

                In this study, the catalytic activity of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) of ruthenium polyphthalocyanine axially modified with different aliphatic thiol groups RuPPc-SR (SR = -SCH 3 ,...</description>
      <author>Guilin Wang, Rongrong Ren, Xiao Feng, Wei Wang, Jie Meng, Jianfeng Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00424h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PtAu alloying-modulated hydroxyl and substrate adsorptions for glycerol electrooxidation to C3 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee00485j</link>
      <description>Yan Li, Xinfa Wei, Rui Pan, Y. Wang, Juanjuan Luo, Lanxin Li, Li&#8208;Song Chen, Jianlin Shi, Energy &amp; environmental science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396771467

                Substituting for oxygen evolution reaction with the thermodynamically favorable glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) in water splitting offers a promising approach to produce high-value chemicals in addition to hydrogen, which, however,...</description>
      <author>Yan Li, Xinfa Wei, Rui Pan, Y. Wang, Juanjuan Luo, Lanxin Li, Li&#8208;Song Chen, Jianlin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee00485j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect-balanced Active and Stable Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4-x&lt;/sub&gt; for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis at Ampere-level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee00977k</link>
      <description>Chengli Rong, Shuhao Wang, Xin Shen, Chen Jia, Qingjiang Sun, Qiang Zhang, Chuan Zhao, Energy &amp; environmental science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396876912

                Active and stable noble metal-free catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are essential for realizing large-scale hydrogen production using proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzers. Herein, we discover that engineering the...</description>
      <author>Chengli Rong, Shuhao Wang, Xin Shen, Chen Jia, Qingjiang Sun, Qiang Zhang, Chuan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee00977k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental investigation on the electrodeposited nickel-based dichalcogenides for the efficient overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.120645</link>
      <description>Sajjad Hussain, Dhanasekaran Vikraman, Zulfqar Ali Sheikh, Zeesham Abbas, Sikandar Aftab, Ghazanfar Nazir, Deok&#8208;kee Kim, Hyun&#8208;Seok Kim, Jongwan Jung, Renewable energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396836076

                Layered transition metal dichalcogenides are effective electrocatalysts for water splitting due to their unique properties such as high electrical conductivity, active site density, and catalytic properties. This study focused on the deposition of Ni-based dichalcogenides (NiX2, where X = S, Se, Te) onto a carbon cloth substrate using a simple one-step electrodeposition method at room temperature with different deposition times (10, 15, and 20 minutes). The optimized NiS2-15, NiSe2-15, and NiTe2-15 electrocatalysts showed excellent bifunctional electrocatalytic activity for both hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media. The overpotential values for hydrogen evolution were &#8764;56 mV, &#8764;37 mV, and &#8764;75 mV for NiS2-15, NiSe2-15, and NiTe2-15, respectively, while the overpotential values for oxygen evolution were &#8764;220 mV, &#8764;170 mV, and &#8764;210 mV, respectively. The electrocatalysts maintained stability for 24 hours during the evolution reactions. The density functional theory calculations suggested that NiSe2 had a lower &#916;GH* value due to its smaller bandgap and inherent metallic characteristics, which is consistent with the experimental results. These findings provide a new direction for designing NiX2 (X = S, Se, Te) nanosheets for electrocatalysis applications.</description>
      <author>Sajjad Hussain, Dhanasekaran Vikraman, Zulfqar Ali Sheikh, Zeesham Abbas, Sikandar Aftab, Ghazanfar Nazir, Deok&#8208;kee Kim, Hyun&#8208;Seok Kim, Jongwan Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.120645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical dealloying derived nanoporous FeCoNiCuTi high-entropy bifunctional electrocatalysts for highly efficient overall water splitting under alkaline conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152145</link>
      <description>Yezeng He, Jing Qin, Fangyu Hu, Liang Mao, Baoxing Shen, Tejraj M. Aminabhavi, Yasser Vasseghian, Akbar Hojjati&#8211;Najafabadi, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831012

                In response to society's urgent drive to significantly decrease its reliance on fossil fuels in the future, there has been continuing efforts to utilize hydrogen (H2) generated by water electrolysis as clean and sustainable substitute for the traditional fossil fuels. A significant challenge in water electrolysis revolves around creating affordable and efficient electrocatalysts to speed up the chemical reactions involved. Our new study introduces a bifunctional catalyst made from a high-entropy alloy (HEA), capable of efficiently catalyzing both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The findings reveal that a complex chemical composition of FeCoNiCuTi HEA can significantly modify its electronic structure, resulting in an impressive electrocatalytic performance. Specifically, FeCoNiCuTi HEA catalyst exhibits an overpotential of 64.9 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution with a Tafel slope of 36.81 mV dec&#8722;1 and double-layer capacitance (Cdl) of 34.1 mF cm&#8722;2. For oxygen evolution, HEA achieves an overpotential of 175 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a Tafel slope of 44.31 mV dec&#8722;1, exhibiting the performance superior to noble catalysts. Theoretical calculations support that the intricate chemical composition of high-entropy alloy plays vital role to enhance its electrocatalytic capabilities. This research represents a straightforward efficient method to create electrocatalysts for water electrolysis using non-noble metals by leveraging high-entropy effect.</description>
      <author>Yezeng He, Jing Qin, Fangyu Hu, Liang Mao, Baoxing Shen, Tejraj M. Aminabhavi, Yasser Vasseghian, Akbar Hojjati&#8211;Najafabadi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction of Hierarchical Conip@Ni2p Nanoarray to Promote Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824428</link>
      <description>Jing Mao, Jinwei Kang, Wenlan Wang, Yong Shao, Junhua Yuan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396837300

                Efficient water splitting remains a challenge to produce clean and pure H2 in an industrial scale for the lack of high-performance cost-effective stable electrocatalysts of hydrogen and oxygen evolution (HER and OER). Surface engineering is a novel proposal to upgrade the electrocatalytic performances of HER and OER during the water splitting with energy-saving. Herein, a hierarchical architecture composed of carbon-supported CoNiP nanoplates (NPs) on Ni2P nanowire was constructed. The nanoarray of CoNiP@Ni2P heterostructure shows a high bifunctional activity of HER and OER. The overpotential is 46 mV required for HER at 10 mA&#183;cm-2 and 292 mV for OER at 100 mA&#183;cm-2 in 1 mol&#183;L-1 KOH. In addition, the nanoarray of CoNiP@Ni2P heterostructure also shows a high stability for HER. The HER activity can be maintained at 11 mA&#183;cm-2 without loss after 50 h cathode polarization at the overpotential of 100 mV, while the OER activity continuously increases from 26 to 64 mA&#183;cm-2 at an overpotential of 400 mV after 50 h anode polarization. The enhancement of the oxygen evolution performance can be ascribed to the surface reconstruction of CoNiP/Ni2P heterostructure nanoarray, which can offer more active sites to OER. Density functional theory (DFT) reveals surface reconstruction can create an oxygen-rich surface in favor of intermediate adsorption, thus enabling a fast OER kinetics at the interface of NiCoOOH/Ni2P heterostructure. This work highlights surface reconstruction adaptability to design advanced catalysts of efficient water splitting for commercial H2 production.</description>
      <author>Jing Mao, Jinwei Kang, Wenlan Wang, Yong Shao, Junhua Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toxicity of the sunscreen UV filter benzophenone-3 (OBZ) to the microalga Selenastrum capricornutum: An insight into OBZ&#8217;s damage to photosynthesis and respiration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.116441</link>
      <description>Yongfu Li, Tian Zhao, Meng Qin, Xingkai Che, Aihua Zhang, Ecotoxicology and environmental safety. 278(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396791907

                Oxybenzone (OBZ; benzophenone-3, CAS# 131&#8211;57&#8211;7), as a new pollutant and ultraviolet absorbent, shows a significant threat to the survival of phytoplankton. This study aims to explore the acute toxic effects of OBZ on the growth of the microalga Selenastrum capricornutum, as well as the mechanisms for its damage to the primary metabolic pathways of photosynthesis and respiration. The results demonstrated that the concentrations for 50 % of maximal effect (EC50) of OBZ for S. capricornutum were 9.07 mg L&#8722;1 and 8.54 mg L&#8722;1 at 72 h and 96 h, respectively. A dosage of 4.56 mg L&#8722;1 OBZ significantly lowered the photosynthetic oxygen evolution rate of S. capricornutum in both light and dark conditions for a duration of 2 h, while it had no effect on the respiratory oxygen consumption rate under darkness. OBZ caused a significant decline in the efficiency of photosynthetic electron transport due to its damage to photosystem II (PSII), thereby decreasing the photosynthetic oxygen evolution rate. Over-accumulated H2O2 was produced under light due to the damage caused by OBZ to the donor and acceptor sides of PSII, resulting in increased peroxidation of cytomembranes and inhibition of algal respiration. OBZ's damage to photosynthesis and respiration will hinder the conversion and reuse of energy in algal cells, which is an important reason that OBZ has toxic effects on S. capricornutum. The present study indicated that OBZ has an acute toxic effect on the microalga S. capricornutum. In the two most important primary metabolic pathways in algae, photosynthesis is more sensitive to the toxicity of OBZ than respiration, especially in the dark.</description>
      <author>Yongfu Li, Tian Zhao, Meng Qin, Xingkai Che, Aihua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.116441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Formation of Coooh/Co(Iii)-Mof Active Phase for Boosting Electrocatalytic Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4825166</link>
      <description>Inmaculada M&#225;rquez, Silvia Guti&#233;rrez&#8208;Tarri&#241;o, Arismendy Portorreal-Bottier, Jose Luis del R&#237;o-Rodr&#237;guez, Sergio Hern&#225;ndez-Salvador, Juan Jos&#233; Calvente, Pascual O&#241;a&#8208;Burgos, Jos&#233; Luis Olloqui&#8208;Sariego, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396824730

                Surface reconstituted metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) offer appealing properties for electrocatalysis due to their unique structural and compositional advantages. In this work, a controlled potential-induced reconstruction of a two-dimensional cobalt metal-organic framework for boosting oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media is reported. The current MOF is shown to undergo a partial structural transformation that generates a heterogeneous system, where the original MOF coexists with an oxyhydroxide phase. It has been found that the potential-induced stabilization of Co(III) metal centers in the MOF is crucial for delaying its full degradation in alkaline media. This partial retention of the Co(III)MOF phase in the so-derived heterogeneous catalyst has been demonstrated to be decisive for boosting the alkaline electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), displaying superior OER activity in terms of both thermodynamic and kinetic merits compared to the benchmark IrO2 and RuO2 electrocatalysts and the prototypical cobalt (oxy)hydroxides, with a Tafel slope of 52 mV dec-1 and a turnover frequency (TOF) of 6.8 s-1 at 450 mV. It is also proved that the generated final product is stable, exhibiting a high robustness and long durability for long term OER electrolysis. This work provides new insight into the impact of the reconstruction of a MOF for alkaline OER under the typical electrochemical conditions, which ultimately benefits the rational design of MOF-based catalysts with high electrocatalytic activity for oxidation reactions.</description>
      <author>Inmaculada M&#225;rquez, Silvia Guti&#233;rrez&#8208;Tarri&#241;o, Arismendy Portorreal-Bottier, Jose Luis del R&#237;o-Rodr&#237;guez, Sergio Hern&#225;ndez-Salvador, Juan Jos&#233; Calvente, Pascual O&#241;a&#8208;Burgos, Jos&#233; Luis Olloqui&#8208;Sariego</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4825166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A kinetics-based approach to the steady state and impedance response of photoelectrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144422</link>
      <description>Laurence M. Peter, Kirk H. Bevan, E. A. Ponomarev, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830425

                A kinetics-based analytical model is developed to describe the steady state and impedance response of photoelectrodes in the case where charge carrier build-up modifies the potential distribution across the semiconductor-electrolyte junction. The predictions of the steady state model are compared with numerical calculations. It is shown that carrier build up should accelerate interfacial hole transfer by increasing the potential drop across the Helmholtz layer. This effect may explain observations of higher reaction orders with respect to hole concentration during photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution. The analytical model is extended to photoelectrochemical impedance spectroscopy (PEIS). The calculations indicate that interpretation of PEIS measurements becomes more complicated if high illumination intensities are used. The modelling of the analytically calculated PEIS response using equivalent circuits is discussed with the aim of understanding the physical significance of the resistive and capacitive elements.</description>
      <author>Laurence M. Peter, Kirk H. Bevan, E. A. Ponomarev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acanthosphere-like bimetallic sulfide Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF as bifunctional catalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118338</link>
      <description>Na Qin, Feifei Dai, Yanxue Xue, Da Gao, Y.-S Liu, Yayuan Zhang, Jianhua Chen, Qian Yang, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835212

                Reducing the overpotential of water splitting is an important strategy for achieving low-cost and large-scale production of hydrogen (H2) and oxygen (O2). It is shown that bimetallic sulfide combines the advantages of a single component and an ideal structure for efficient electrocatalysis. Hence, an acanthosphere-like bimetallic sulfide electrocatalyst Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF with high catalytic performance and superior durability was prepared by a simple one-pot method. In the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF achieved a Tafel slope of 62.7 mV dec-1, and an overpotential of 224 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Concomitantly, it also possesses a small overpotential of 96 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and low Tafel slope of 81.6 mV dec-1 at the used of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst. Moreover, the two-electrode system Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF||Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF single cell requires only 1.55 V to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in overall water splitting. This work highlights the advantages of bimetallic sulfide combines structural for overpotential of water splitting and provides an idea for modifying the catalytic performance of single metal sulfides and preparing high-performance bimetallic sulfide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Na Qin, Feifei Dai, Yanxue Xue, Da Gao, Y.-S Liu, Yayuan Zhang, Jianhua Chen, Qian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Ni&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; Content in Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Boost Hydrogen Peroxide Production for Electrochemical Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00436</link>
      <description>Wenjing Wang, Huaizhong Shi, Haizhou Huang, Hongying Liu, Chengxiang Li, Ya-jie Han, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396779118

                Hydrogen peroxide is a green oxidizing chemical with wide applications in industry. Its production heavily relies on the industrial anthraquinone process, which involves a large number of organic pollutants, challenging green and sustainable development. The recently developed pulsed electrochemical approach holds great potential for the green synthesis of hydrogen peroxide, but it is limited by the absence of highly efficient catalysts. Here, we report a strategy to improve the performance of Ni3S2 catalyst by tuning the content of Ni3+ species. The Ni3S2 catalyst exhibits good performance in oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction processes at the same time, leading to the formation of hydrogen peroxide. The enrichment of Ni3+ ensures the adsorption of reaction intermediates *O, *OH, and *OOH and promotes electron transfer during the reaction, thus facilitating hydrogen peroxide generation. By tuning the Ni3+ ratio in the Ni3S2 catalyst, the productivity of hydrogen peroxide was enhanced. The prepared hydrogen peroxide was used for propylene oxidation, resulting in pH-dependent products. This study highlights the significance of the design and rational synthesis of electrochemical catalysts for synthesizing hydrogen peroxide, which may be used for the electrochemical synthesis of chemicals.</description>
      <author>Wenjing Wang, Huaizhong Shi, Haizhou Huang, Hongying Liu, Chengxiang Li, Ya-jie Han</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photoelectrochemical water splitting coupled with pharmaceutical pollutants degradation on Zr:BiVO4 photoanodes by synergetic catalytic activity of NiFeOOH nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2024.05.012</link>
      <description>Prabhakarn Arunachalam, Maged N. Shaddad, Mabrook S. Amer, Abdulhadi AL-Qadi, Alexandria Engineering Journal /Alexandria Engineering Journal. 99(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396841236

                Globally, the emergence of drug-resistant bacteria has created an urgent need for an effective method to remove antibiotics from pharmaceutical wastewater. Engineering Bismuth vanadate (BiVO4) with an oxygen evolution cocatalyst (OEC) holds a promising potential for enhancing water splitting efficiency in the production of hydrogen (H2) using free solar energy. Here, we successfully developed a Zr:BiVO4/NiFeOOH heterojunction by electrodeposition and photoelectrochemical transformation. Zr:BiVO4/NiFeOOH photoanodes exhibit 5 fold superior photocurrent response at 1.23 V compared with Zr:BiVO4 electrodes, since NiFeOOH acts as an oxygen-releasing catalyst. Furthermore, the attained heterojunctioned electrode can effectively degrade TCH, riboflavin, and streptomycin in PEC. The degradation rate of TCH acquired 96% within 1 h, which is 3 times superior than the efficiency reported for pristine Zr:BiVO4 photoelectrodes. By introducing NiFeOOH into BiVO4, electron life-time was increased and electron-hole recombination was suppressed. In this study, we present a solar-driven, sustainable and effective way of treating wastewater and provide new insights into the process.</description>
      <author>Prabhakarn Arunachalam, Maged N. Shaddad, Mabrook S. Amer, Abdulhadi AL-Qadi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2024.05.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical and dielectric analysis of Multifunctional GQDs@PEG@Mg-ZnFe2O4 Ternary nanohybrid for low-frequency electronics, water splitting, and sustainable energy storage applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174746</link>
      <description>Saima Perveen, Sonadia, Saiqa Hafeez, Muhammad Zarrar Khan, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Fahad Azad, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834656

                This work explores the potential of GQDs@PEG@Mg-ZnFe2O4 nanocomposite in water splitting and energy storage applications. The synthesized hybrid showed remarkable dielectric properties indicating its potential for low-frequency telecommunications and electronics applications. The impedance spectroscopy disclosed the contribution of grains and grain boundaries in the realization of colossal permittivity (104) in GQDs@PEG@Mg-ZnFe2O4. Moreover, GQDs@PEG@Mg-ZnFe2O4 showed excellent energy storage performance, indicated by its specific capacitance of 100 Fg-1 and a retention ratio of 99% over 1000 cycles at a 1 Ag-1 current density. GQDs@PEG@Mg-ZnFe2O4 nanohybrid also showed remarkable electrocatalytic activity, both for hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. The determined Tafel slope value was found to be 90 mVdec-1 and 110 mVdec-1 at a 10 mA/cm2 current density respectively. These results highlight the multifunctional nature of the GQDs@PEG@Mg-ZnFe2O4 nanocomposite and its potential as a versatile material to address challenges in both energy storage and conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Saima Perveen, Sonadia, Saiqa Hafeez, Muhammad Zarrar Khan, Anwar Ul&#8208;Hamid, Fahad Azad</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Glucaric Acid Using Electrocatalyst Glucose Oxidation by the Ta NiFe LDH Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02260</link>
      <description>Meysam Tayebi, Zohreh Masoumi, Bongkuk Seo, Choong&#8208;Sun Lim, Chae Hwan Hong, Hye Jin Kim, Daeseung Kyung, Hyeon&#8208;Gook Kim, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396805281

                The slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) significantly limits electrocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen production. We proposed the electrocatalyst for glucose oxidation by Ta-doping NiFe LDH nanosheets to simultaneously obtain glucaric acid (GRA) and hydrogen gas as a useful byproduct. Superior glucose oxidation reaction (GOR) activity is demonstrated by the optimized Ta&#8211;NiFe LDH, which has a low overpotential of 192 mV, allowing for a small Tafel slope of 70 mV dec&#8211;1 and a current density of 50 mA cm&#8211;2. The Ta NiFe LDH-oxidized glucose to GRA with a 72.94% yield and 64.3% Faradaic efficiency at 1.45 VRHE. Herein, we report the Ta NiFe LDH/NF electrode for the GOR&amp;hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), which exhibits a cell voltage of 1.62 V to reach a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2, which is 250 mV lower compared to OER&amp;HER (1.87 V). This study reveals that GOR is an energy-efficient and cost-effective method for producing H2 and valorizing biomass.</description>
      <author>Meysam Tayebi, Zohreh Masoumi, Bongkuk Seo, Choong&#8208;Sun Lim, Chae Hwan Hong, Hye Jin Kim, Daeseung Kyung, Hyeon&#8208;Gook Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium-cobalt nano-oxide coupler with enhanced water dissociation for oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119795</link>
      <description>Weiwei Quan, Yuxi Hou, Jiaheng Luo, Dinghui Yang, Yingbin Lin, Zhensheng Hong, Yiyin Huang, Hu&#8208;Rong Yao, Rui Yang, Applied catalysis. A, General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834708

                Heterogeneous oxide couplers represent a type of emerging composite materials with inherently outstanding interface properties for electrocatalytic applications. In this study, we fabricate a Ru-Co nano-oxide coupler that enables internal electron transfer between Ru and Co elements. The catalyst exhibits superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance compared to commercial RuO2, with mere 260 mV overpotential at 10 mA cm-2. The exchange current density (i0) for RuO2/Co3O4 is enhanced by three orders of magnitude compared to commercial RuO2. Electrochemical characterizations and computational analysis reveal that the coupling of Co3O4 and RuO2 enhances the surface's capability for water dissociation on the interface Ru sites, thereby initiating OER. The exceptional performance of RuO2/Co3O4 enables water splitting via a single-cell AA battery configuration that utilizes a RuO2/Co3O4 anode || Pt/C cathode setup. This accomplishment underscores the potential of RuO2/Co3O4 for effective and sustainable electrochemical water splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Weiwei Quan, Yuxi Hou, Jiaheng Luo, Dinghui Yang, Yingbin Lin, Zhensheng Hong, Yiyin Huang, Hu&#8208;Rong Yao, Rui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategies of regulating Zn2+ solvation structures toward advanced aqueous zinc-based batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103451</link>
      <description>Hengwei Wang, Keliang Wang, Enze Jing, Manhui Wei, Jianyin Xiong, Daiyuan Zhong, Yayu Zuo, Bin Liang, Pucheng Pei, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835192

                Rechargeable aqueous zinc-based batteries not only pave the way for environmentally friendly and safe energy storage devices but also hold great promise for reducing the manufacturing costs of next-generation batteries, positioning them as the most promising energy storage system to replace lithium-ion batteries. However, the commercial application of aqueous zinc-based batteries (AZBs) is severely constrained by issues such as zinc dendrites, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and electrode corrosion. While significant efforts have been devoted to exploring electrode materials and their storage mechanisms in this system in recent years, research on the nature of Zn2+ solvation in electrolytes remains insufficient. Therefore, this review primarily provides a comprehensive and in-depth elucidation of the existing issues such as dendrite formation, hydrogen/oxygen evolution, electrode corrosion and passivation interactions. Additionally, from the perspective of electrolyte optimization, this review emphasizes existing strategies to address Zn2+ solvation, including adjusting electrolyte concentration, incorporating functional additives or co-solvents, utilizing ionic liquids, and developing hydrogel electrolytes, and summarizes approaches and mechanisms for improving their relevant performance. Finally, prospects for electrolyte modification and innovation directions of AZBs are proposed, providing guidance for future AZB studies.</description>
      <author>Hengwei Wang, Keliang Wang, Enze Jing, Manhui Wei, Jianyin Xiong, Daiyuan Zhong, Yayu Zuo, Bin Liang, Pucheng Pei</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Electrodeposition of Iron-Doped Nimo Alloys as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824059</link>
      <description>Ting Ren, Chen Tang, Xiao-Hui Huang, Jiangjin Chen, Guodong Feng, Fuxi Bao, Wen Guo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396817268

                Nickel-molybdenum (NiMo) alloy has been widely concerned in the field of electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution because of its excellent hydrogen evolution performance, but at the same time, NiMo alloy also faces the problem of poor oxygen evolution activity and molybdenum dissolution. Unlike other processes involving high-temperature and high-pressure reactions, electrodeposition has the advantages of a simple preparation device, controllable synthesis conditions and a shorter synthesis time. Herein, NiMo alloys with different iron content were prepared by a simple one-step electrodeposition method. The results of XRD and TEM demonstrate the successful doping of Fe. Doping Fe affects the electronic structure of NiMo, accelerates electron transfer and increases the number of active sites. Fe0.2-NiMo shows the best catalytic performance with HER/OER overpotential of 85 mV and 269 mV respectively at 10 mA cm-2. Fe0.2-NiMo can also be applied in large current, and HER/OER overpotential is only 319 mV and 316 mV when the current density is 500 mA cm-2. The resulting cell requires only 1.9 V voltage to achieve a current density of 500 mA cm-2. This work proves that Fe doping strategy is an efficient and feasible strategy for designing bifunctional NiMo alloy based electrocatalysts with high activity.</description>
      <author>Ting Ren, Chen Tang, Xiao-Hui Huang, Jiangjin Chen, Guodong Feng, Fuxi Bao, Wen Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Strontium Cobalt Molybdenum Oxide (Sr2CoMoO6) Perovskite as an Efficient Catalyst for Electrochemical Water Splitting Reactions in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400217</link>
      <description>Shahan Atif, Abhisek Padhy, Pawan Kumar Jha, Deepika Sachdeva, Prabeer Barpanda, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835567

                Developing earth&#8208;abundant low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts is of prime research interest towards the need for clean energy technology, such as water&#8208;splitting reactions. Herein, we have explored the electrocatalytic activity of the double perovskite&#8208;based strontium cobalt molybdenum oxide (SCMO) towards water&#8208;splitting reactions, both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Prepared by scalable autocombustion synthesis, the as&#8208;synthesised bulk SCMO perovskite exhibited impressive electrocatalytic performance attributed to its substantial electrochemical active surface area. For the OER, it exhibited an overpotential of 350 mV with a Tafel slope value of 76 mV/dec. Concurrently, it showed proficient activity in the HER, revealing an overpotential of 270 mV and a Tafel slope of 112 mV/dec. Further, this perovskite material was stable during continuous electrocatalysis over a 24 h period with a negligible increase in observed overpotential value. The electronic density of states confirmed that the Co plays a pivotal role in enhancing electrocatalytic activities. This is achieved by a substantial reduction in the band gap and enhancement of the d&#8208;band centre to an optimal level, rendering the system more favourable for electrocatalytic reactions. Our study contributes insights to the advancement of the design and utilization of perovskite&#8208;based catalysts in the realm of sustainable energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Shahan Atif, Abhisek Padhy, Pawan Kumar Jha, Deepika Sachdeva, Prabeer Barpanda</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400217</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Metal Particles Encapsulated in Carbon Shells as Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Urea-Assisted Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824485</link>
      <description>Zhuoxun Yin, Yu Zhang, Weimeng Chi, Xinzhi Ma, Yang Zhou, Wanqiang Liu, Jinlong Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396837647

                Urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is considered an ideal water splitting reaction with the potential to replace oxygen evolution reaction (OER), as it lowers the anodic potential and utilizes urea as a renewable and abundant resource. However, creating stable, effective bifunctional catalysts is still challenging. In this work, we report a novel bifunctional catalyst of core-shell structure Ni-500 Nano-particle. The carbon coating not only offers numerous active sites and facilitates rapid charge transfer but also shields the nickel core from corrosion. Moreover, By replenishing the urea concentration, the current density can be recovered and sustained for 50 h with only an 8% decrease. It is significantly less than pure water electrolysis that the urea-assisted water electrolyzer with Ni-500 as both cathode and anode achieves cell-voltage of 1.55 V at 100 mA cm-2. This work demonstrates the potential of Ni-500 as a inexpensive and effective catalyst for urea-based hydrogen production, and offers new perspectives into the design and optimization for core-shell structure electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Zhuoxun Yin, Yu Zhang, Weimeng Chi, Xinzhi Ma, Yang Zhou, Wanqiang Liu, Jinlong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt telluride regulated by nickel for efficient electrooxidation of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.050</link>
      <description>Jiahui Li, Genyan Hao, Gang Jin, Tao Zhao, Dandan Li, Dazhong Zhong, Jinping Li, Qiang Zhao, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834562

                Replacing the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water splitting with 5-hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation reaction (HMFOR) can not only reduce the energy required for hydrogen production but also yield the valuable chemical 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA). Co-based catalysts are known to be efficient for HMFOR, with high-valent Co being recognized as the main active component. However, efficiently promoting the oxidation of Co2+ to produce high-valent reactive species remains a challenge. In this study, Ni-doped CoTe (CoNiTe) nanorods were prepared as efficient catalysts for HMFOR, achieving a high HMFOR current density of 65.3 mA cm&#8722;2 at 1.50 V. Even after undergoing five successive electrolysis processes, the Faradaic efficiency (FE) remained at approximately 90.7 %, showing robust electrochemical durability. Mechanistic studies indicated that Ni doping changes the electronic configuration of Co, enhancing its charge transfer rate and facilitating the oxidation of Co2+ to high-valent CoO2 species. This work reveals the effect of Ni doping on the reconfiguration of the active phase during HMFOR.</description>
      <author>Jiahui Li, Genyan Hao, Gang Jin, Tao Zhao, Dandan Li, Dazhong Zhong, Jinping Li, Qiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped Ni/Co-Based Selenide Hierarchical Nanosheet Arrays as Self-Supporting Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01126</link>
      <description>Xinli Fan, Hui Ding, Ting&#8208;Ting Huang, Xia Liu, Juan Xiao, Mengyuan Xie, Guancheng Xu, Li Zhang, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835337

                It is necessary to optimize the electrocatalytic activity of an electrocatalyst by means of morphology and composition regulation. Herein, Fe-doped bimetallic selenide hierarchical nanosheet arrays grown on nickel foam (Fe-NiCoSe/NiCoSe/NF) are obtained for overall water splitting. The Fe-NiCoSe/NiCoSe/NF is fabricated by selenizing the NiCoFe Prussian blue analogue (NiCoFe-PBA) growing on a NiCo-layered double hydroxide (NiCo-LDH). Benefiting from the hierarchical nanosheet arrays, the synergistic effect of the bimetallic selenides, as well as the electronic structure rearrangement caused by Fe-doping, the Fe-NiCoSe/NiCoSe/NF catalyst exhibits low overpotentials of 120 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 199 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH. In addition, when used as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting, the Fe-NiCoSe/NiCoSe/NF requires a cell voltage of 1.93 V (1.82 V) to reach 100 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 (50 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2). Additionally, Fe-NiCoSe/NiCoSe/NF exhibits prolonged durability lasting for 150 h at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2. This work provides a reasonable idea for designing a hierarchical nanostructured bifunctional electrocatalyst toward overall water splitting by regulating the structure and composition.</description>
      <author>Xinli Fan, Hui Ding, Ting&#8208;Ting Huang, Xia Liu, Juan Xiao, Mengyuan Xie, Guancheng Xu, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prussian blue analogue-derived Co-Ni5P4 porous nanosheet arrays composite coal-based carbon nanofibers as efficient self-supported electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111189</link>
      <description>Xiaolan Fan, Tingting Huang, Hui Ding, Xia Liu, Xiao Yan Liu, Guancheng Xu, Li Zhang, Diamond and related materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831350

                The development of economical, earth-rich, and high-performance transition metal phosphides electrocatalysts is crucial for water splitting. Herein, the NiCo PBA/Ni(OH)2 hierarchical nanostructure arrays are in situ grown on the coal-based carbon nanofibers (C-CNFs) using hydrothermal and co-precipitation methods. Subsequently, the Co-doped Ni5P4 porous nanosheet arrays composite coal-based carbon nanofibers electrocatalyst (Co-Ni5P4@C-CNFs) is obtained through low-temperature phosphorization process. Benefiting from cation-doped, porous nanosheet arrays structure and self-supported conductive substrates, the Co-Ni5P4@C-CNFs has excellent electrocatalytic performance for overall water splitting. It provides low overpotentials of 75 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 231 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to achieve the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 M KOH electrolyte. Furthermore, the Co-Ni5P4@C-CNFs demonstrates a low overall water splitting cell voltage of 1.537 V at current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and remarkable long-term stability for over 160 h. It outperforms the most transition metal phosphide bifunctional electrocatalysts reported to date. This research provides a novel strategy for synthesizing high-performance transition metal phosphides bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaolan Fan, Tingting Huang, Hui Ding, Xia Liu, Xiao Yan Liu, Guancheng Xu, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique sandwich-cookie-like nanosheet array heterojunction bifunctional electrocatalyst towards efficient overall water/seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.061</link>
      <description>Qian Long, Yao Zhu, Huiting Hu, Yunhua Zheng, Zhulin Yuan, Yutang Dai, Tao Zhang, Dongya Yang, Songlin Xue, Fengxian Qiu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831354

                Construction of multi-component heterostructures is an effective strategy for electrocatalysts to improve both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity at the anode. Herein, an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst towards overall water/seawater splitting (OW/SS) is reported with strategy of heterostructure construction (ruthenium/nickel phosphorus) on nickel hydroxide (Ni(OH)2). With the unique hydrolysis layer (Ni(OH)2), the processes of H2O hydrolysis and the adsorption/desorption of H*/O-containing intermediates (OH, O, OOH) were greatly boosted by Ru and P sites, which acted as the catalytic active centers of OER and HER, respectively. In addition, the electronic structure reconfiguration was realized through the strong interaction between multi-interfaces. For alkaline HER at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, the overpotential of Ru-P-Ni(OH)2/NF (denoted as RNPOH/NF) was 98 mV, whereas just 230 mV of overpotential was essential to stimulate alkaline OER at the current density of 20 mA cm&#8722;2. Specifically, as a bifunctional electrocatalyst towards overall water splitting, RNPOH/NF deserves cell voltages of 1.7/1.92 V and 1.75/1.94 V, respectively, to activate current densities of 50/100 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline water/seawater systems, together with a good durability of 12 h. This work contributes insights to the development of bifunctional electrocatalysts for overall water/seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>Qian Long, Yao Zhu, Huiting Hu, Yunhua Zheng, Zhulin Yuan, Yutang Dai, Tao Zhang, Dongya Yang, Songlin Xue, Fengxian Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Synthesis of Electrocatalysts Base on Catalysis&#8208;Unit Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403549</link>
      <description>Zhe Zhang, Ziqi Zhang, Cailing Chen, Rong Xu, Xiaobo Chen, Haiyan Lu, Zhan Shi, Yangyang Han, Shouhua Feng, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780553

                It is a pressing need to develop new energy materials to address the existing energy crisis. However, screening optimal targets out of thousands of materials candidates remains a great challenge. Herein, we propose and validate an alternative concept for highly effective materials screening based on dual-atom salphen catalysis units. Such an approach simplifies the design of catalytic materials and reforms the trial-and-error experimental model into a building-blocks-assembly like process. Firstly, density functional theory (DFT) calculations were performed on a series of potential catalysis units which were possible to synthesize. Then, machine learning (ML) was employed to define the structure-performance relationship and acquire chemical insights. Afterwards, the projected catalysis units were integrated into covalent organic frameworks (COFs) to validate the concept Electrochemical tests confirm that Ni-SalphenCOF and Co-SalphenCOF are promising conductive agent-free oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts. This work provides a fast-tracked strategy for design and development of functional materials, which serves as a potentially workable framework for seamlessly integrating DFT calculations, ML, and experimental approaches. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Zhe Zhang, Ziqi Zhang, Cailing Chen, Rong Xu, Xiaobo Chen, Haiyan Lu, Zhan Shi, Yangyang Han, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-deposition of different mixed nanoparticle concentrations with nickel as efficient OER electrocatalysts in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.090</link>
      <description>Wei Jiang, Fankai Zhu, Junjie Li, Jiayu Shi, Xin Wen, Yuanlong Chen, Yuanxia Lao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396841329

                The catalytic efficiency of water electrolysis is directly affected by the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). DFT simulation was used to calculate the doping of SiC nanoparticles into Ni&#8211;Co alloys. The results indicate that doping nano SiC particles enhances the intrinsic activity of Ni&#8211;Co&#8211;SiC in OER by introducing a separate RDS at each of the four reaction sites. Then, magnetic field-induced jet electrodeposition was used to manufacture Ni&#8211;Co&#8211;SiC catalytic electrodes. To obtain a larger specific surface area of the micro/nano structure, nickel nanoparticles, and SiC nanoparticles were mixed in the form of mixed nanoparticles and then added to the electrolyte. The effect of mixed nanoparticle concentration on OER performance of Ni&#8211;Co&#8211;SiC catalytic electrodes was investigated. Research showed that the Ni&#8211;Co&#8211;SiC catalytic electrode exhibits micro/nano dense cellular protrusion structures with higher surface roughness with a magnetic field. OER performance of the Ni&#8211;Co&#8211;SiC catalytic electrode further increased with the concentration of nanoparticles, the catalytic electrode has excellent catalytic performance when the concentration of mixed nanoparticles reaches 6 g/L in the electrolyte. The overpotential of the Ni&#8211;Co&#8211;SiC/Ni catalytic electrode decreased to 309 mV, and the Tafel slope was 54.5 mV/dec.</description>
      <author>Wei Jiang, Fankai Zhu, Junjie Li, Jiayu Shi, Xin Wen, Yuanlong Chen, Yuanxia Lao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.090</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Component Regulation On Flower-Like Fe X Conip/C Nanohybrids As Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4825176</link>
      <description>Gan Wang, Xiang Ji, Heng Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396838763

                Doping bi-metal transition metal phosphides (TMPs) with high-valent metal is a powerful method to obtain highly efficient and low-cost bifunctional electrocatalysts in alkaline media for overall water splitting. However, the composition-activity relationship of such doping has not been investigated yet due to the challenge in constructing tri-metal TMPs with continuously variable composition while maintaining a homogenous elemental distribution. In this study, we proposed a strategy using a trimetal oleta composite with a homogenous elemental distribution at the molecular scale as an ideal precursor. This precursor was then used to fabricate Fe-doped Ni-Co phosphide on a flower-like carbon substrate, resulting in a continuously changeable Fe content (FexNiCoP/C). Benefiting from the fully exposed structure and the doping effects of Fe, the flower-like FexNiCoP/C hybrids exhibited excellent electrocatalytic performance for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). By optimizing the Fe content, the flower-like Fe0.4NiCoP/C hybrid achieved 10 mA/cm2 at a low overpotential of 243 mV for the OER and 107 mV for the HER, respectively. When the optimal Fe0.4NiCoP/C electrodes were employed as the anode and cathode for water electrolysis in an alkaline electrolyte, the electrolyzer achieved 10 mA/cm2 at a low cell voltage of 1.59 V. This work provides an inexpensive, highly active, and durable electrocatalyst, while revealing the composition-activity relationship of FexNiCoP/C for overall water splitting in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Gan Wang, Xiang Ji, Heng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4825176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmentally benign synthesis and characterization of Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Sb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; nanocomposite: Investigation of its potential as electrode material in energy storage and generation applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7516</link>
      <description>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Lin Wang, Ram K. Gupta, Essam A. Al&#8208;Ammar, Ghulam Abbas Ashraf, Applied organometallic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396775304

                A shift to alternate energy sources is needed at the present time to address rising environmental concerns. The current research work aims to use a chemical&#8208;free and green route to synthesize nanocomposite for their application as an electrode in the generation as well as storage of energy. Subsequently, the green synthesis of Bi 2 O 3 &#8208;Sb 2 O 3 nanocomposite was carried out using the leaf extract of Amaranthus viridis . The synthesized nanocomposite revealed a well&#8208;arranged pattern of spherical nanoparticles with a crystal size of 29.43 nm and a band gap value of 2.5 eV. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) potentials of Bi 2 O 3 &#8208;Sb 2 O 3 were studied through linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), whereas the energy storage studies were performed using cyclic voltammetry (CV) and galvanostatic charge discharge (GCD) techniques. The synthesized nanomaterial showed promising results for HER with an overpotential value of 205 mV as compared with OER, where an overpotential value of 450 mV was observed. However, excellent cyclic stability was witnessed for both reactions up to 1000 cycles. CV studies revealed an outstanding capacitance value of 348 F/g at a scan rate of 2 mV/s, whereas a specific capacitance of 269.5 F/g at a current density of 0.5 A/g was observed using GCD. The 15 h of electrode stability further endorsed the potential of synthesized material for energy&#8208;based applications.</description>
      <author>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Lin Wang, Ram K. Gupta, Essam A. Al&#8208;Ammar, Ghulam Abbas Ashraf</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the Catalytic Mechanism of Ni-Alloyed Co4n Nanowire Arrays Towards Photo-Assisted Electrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823059</link>
      <description>Chengming Long, Sirui Liu, Di Wang, Zhaoqi Lu, Qiulan Zhang, Qiong Gao, Mingyi Zhang, Xinzhi Ma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396783208

                Photoelectrochemical hydrogen production technology holds promise for directly and swiftly generating green hydrogen, which is pivotal for human welfare; however, it faces challenges posed by the energetically sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Cobalt-based nitrides are considered excellent photoelectrochemical OER (PEOER) catalysts, and their conductivity and photoconversion efficiency remain relatively low. Additionally, the role of nitrogen elements in the OER process is often overlooked. This paper presents the fabrication of Ni-alloyed Co4N nanowire arrays on carbon cloth ((Co1-xNix)4N NWAs/CC) as PEOER catalysts. By analyzing advanced in-situ Raman and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) results, we discovered that Ni not only enhances the conductivity of the catalyst but, more importantly, also creates more photoexcited Co2+ OER centers and favors its reconstruction to CoOOH to charge PEOER. Furthermore, nitrogen plays a critical role in transforming pyridinic nitrogen into other forms of nitrogen to stabilize the catalyst's structure. These advantages endow (Co0.7Ni0.3)4N NWAs/CC with remarkable PEOER enhancement (988%), which drives the standard current density of 10 mA cm-2 with only 283 mV overpotential along with good durability. This research provides insights into the PEOER mechanisms of cobalt-based transition metal nitrides, providing a way for designing next-generation PEOER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chengming Long, Sirui Liu, Di Wang, Zhaoqi Lu, Qiulan Zhang, Qiong Gao, Mingyi Zhang, Xinzhi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Nitric Oxide as a Regulator in Salt Tolerance: Insights into Photosynthetic Efficiency in Maize</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13101312</link>
      <description>Georgi D. Rashkov, Martin Stefanov, Ekaterina Yotsova, Preslava Borisova, Anelia G. Dobrikova, Emilia Apostolova, Plants. 13(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396801950

                The growing issue of salinity is a significant threat to global agriculture, affecting diverse regions worldwide. Nitric oxide (NO) serves as an essential signal molecule in regulating photosynthetic performance under physiological and stress conditions. The present study reveals the protective effects of different concentrations (0&#8211;300 &#181;M) of sodium nitroprusside (SNP, a donor of NO) on the functions of the main complexes within the photosynthetic apparatus of maize (Zea mays L. Kerala) under salt stress (150 mM NaCl). The data showed that SNP alleviates salt-induced oxidative stress and prevents changes in the fluidity of thylakoid membranes (Laurdan GP) and energy redistribution between the two photosystems (77K chlorophyll fluorescence ratio F735/F685). Chlorophyll fluorescence measurements demonstrated that the foliar spray with SNP under salt stress prevents the decline of photosystem II (PSII) open reaction centers (qP) and improves their efficiency (&#934;exc), thereby influencing QA&#8722; reoxidation. The data also revealed that SNP protects the rate constants for two pathways of QA&#8722; reoxidation (k1 and k2) from the changes caused by NaCl treatment alone. Additionally, there is a predominance of QA&#8722; interaction with plastoquinone in comparison to the recombination of electrons in QA QB&#8722; with the oxygen-evolving complex (OEC). The analysis of flash oxygen evolution showed that SNP treatment prevents a salt-induced 10% increase in PSII centers in the S0 state, i.e., protects the initial S0&#8211;S1 state distribution, and the modification of the Mn cluster in the OEC. Moreover, this study demonstrates that SNP-induced defense occurs on both the donor and acceptor sides of the PSII, leading to the protection of overall photosystems performance (PIABS) and efficient electron transfer from the PSII donor side to the reduction of PSI end electron acceptors (PItotal). This study clearly shows that the optimal protection under salt stress occurs at approximately 50&#8211;63 nmoles NO/g FW in leaves, corresponding to foliar spray with 50&#8211;150 &#181;M SNP.</description>
      <author>Georgi D. Rashkov, Martin Stefanov, Ekaterina Yotsova, Preslava Borisova, Anelia G. Dobrikova, Emilia Apostolova</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13101312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of Surface Wettability of Aromatic Polymers (PET, PS, PEEK, and PPS) upon Treatment with Neutral Oxygen Atoms from Non-Equilibrium Oxygen Plasma</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16101381</link>
      <description>Alenka Vesel, Rok Zaplotnik, Gregor Primc, Miran Mozeti&#269;, Polymers. 16(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396865129

                The wettability of polymers is usually inadequate to ensure the appropriate spreading of polar liquids and thus enable the required adhesion of coatings. A standard ecologically benign method for increasing the polymer wettability is a brief treatment with a non-equilibrium plasma rich in reactive oxygen species and predominantly neutral oxygen atoms in the ground electronic state. The evolution of the surface wettability of selected aromatic polymers was investigated by water droplet contact angles deposited immediately after exposing polymer samples to fluxes of oxygen atoms between 3 &#215; 1020 and 1 &#215; 1023 m&#8722;2s&#8722;1. The treatment time varied between 0.01 and 1000 s. The wettability evolution versus the O-atom fluence for all aromatic polymers followed similar behavior regardless of the flux of O atoms or the type of polymer. In the range of fluences between approximately 5 &#215; 1020 and 5 &#215; 1023 m&#8722;2, the water contact angle decreased exponentially with increasing fluence and dropped to 1/e of the initial value after receiving the fluence close to 5 &#215; 1022 m&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Alenka Vesel, Rok Zaplotnik, Gregor Primc, Miran Mozeti&#269;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/polym16101381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New insights into oxidation mechanism and kinetics of 9Cr&#8211;1Mo ferritic-martensitic steel in oxygen-saturated liquid lead-bismuth eutectic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174825</link>
      <description>Zhikun Zhou, Chenwen Tian, Juan Du, Xiaogang Peng, Yunpeng Liu, Xiaofei Yu, Xue Mi, Zhenwei Pu, Honglan Xie, Magd Abdel Wahab, Ziguang Chen, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396873904

                The evolution of oxide scales on a 9Cr&#8211;1Mo ferritic-martensitic steel (T91) in oxygen-saturated liquid LBE at 500 &#176;C was investigated. While taken out at around 500 &#176;C, the T91 steel, after corrosion, shows clean surface with little LBE adhesion due to the poor wettability induced by surface oxides, due to the formation of an oxide layer. The results reveal the evolution of surface oxides from irregular strip shapes to regular crystalline grains, and stack-packed equiaxed crystals in the outer magnetite layer. Thermally-induced cracks were captured in the oxide scale on T91 steel after 1,000 h exposure to LBE. A new oxidation mechanism is proposed, with consideration of the formation of the outer layer by metal dissolution/oxide precipitation, and a thin film of chromium oxide at the inner/outer layers interface. The dependency of temperature and oxygen concentration on the oxidation kinetics of T91 steel in LBE at the present condition is discussed.</description>
      <author>Zhikun Zhou, Chenwen Tian, Juan Du, Xiaogang Peng, Yunpeng Liu, Xiaofei Yu, Xue Mi, Zhenwei Pu, Honglan Xie, Magd Abdel Wahab, Ziguang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174825</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the epitaxial direction control and mechanism of polycrystalline diamond grains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/26941112.2024.2346083</link>
      <description>Junpeng Li, Zeyang Ren, Jinfeng Zhang, Jincheng Zhang, Shoichi Kai, Juan Meng, Zhu Liaoliang, Yijiang Li, Junfei Chen, Wang Hanxue, Yue Hao, Functional diamond. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831403

                The control of diamond film growth is crucial for the application of diamond films. In this article, different diamond film samples were prepared by adding nitrogen and oxygen in different proportions during the growth process. The key conditions for controlling the growth of diamond film with preferred orientation were obtained using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and Raman spectroscopy characterizations. During the growth process, the growth of the diamond film with (100) preferred orientation could be achieved by adjusting nitrogen content. It was necessary to introduce nitrogen and oxygen in the growth process, and precisely regulate the ratio of the two to obtain the (111) preferred orientation of the diamond film. When only oxygen was introduced during growth, the preferred orientation of the diamond could not be achieved, leading to a smaller grain size and poorer crystal quality. From the perspective of grain morphology to film morphology evolution, this study obtained the crystal orientation control conditions during the diamond film growth, which has important guiding significance for the application of the diamond film. This study seeks to drive progress in the large-scale growth of readily machinable diamond and the evolution of diamond-grain optical fiber sensing through comprehensive investigations into the correlation between the preferred orientation in polycrystalline diamonds and reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Junpeng Li, Zeyang Ren, Jinfeng Zhang, Jincheng Zhang, Shoichi Kai, Juan Meng, Zhu Liaoliang, Yijiang Li, Junfei Chen, Wang Hanxue, Yue Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/26941112.2024.2346083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Fabrication of SrTiO3/In2O3 on Carbon Fibers via a Self-Assembly Strategy for Enhanced Photocatalytic Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16103988</link>
      <description>Jiantao Niu, Qi Hu, Sustainability. 16(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803765

                Photocatalytic water splitting by semiconductors is considered a promising and cost-effective method for achieving sustainable hydrogen production. In this study, a CF/SrTiO3/In2O3 photocatalytic material with a double-layer core&#8211;shell structure was developed. The experimental results indicated that the produced CF/SrTiO3/In2O3 composite fiber displayed superior photocatalytic hydrogen production performance, achieving a hydrogen evolution rate of approximately 320.71 &#956;mol/g&#183;h, which is roughly seven times higher than that of the CF/SrTiO3 fiber alone. The enhanced photocatalytic activity of the CF/SrTiO3/In2O3 fiber can be attributed to the heterojunction structure enriched with oxygen vacancies. It was found that these oxygen vacancies created defective states that served as traps for photogenerated electrons, facilitating their migration to the surface defect states and enabling the reduction of H+ in water to produce hydrogen. Furthermore, the synergy between the heterojunction structure and the conductivity of the carbon fiber promoted the generation and migration of photogenerated electrons, reduced the recombination of photogenerated electron&#8211;hole pairs, and ultimately improved photocatalytic hydrogen production. This study presents a new approach for designing efficient photocatalysts with surface oxygen vacancies on carbon fibers, providing new insights into the sustainable application of photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiantao Niu, Qi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16103988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Acidic Electrosynthesis of Hydrogen Peroxide at Industrial&#8208;Level Current Densities Promoted by Alkali Metal Cations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406452</link>
      <description>Peike Cao, Xueyang Zhao, Yanming Liu, Haiguang Zhang, Kun Zhao, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu, Dongrui Fan, Nathaniel N. Nichols, Jingguang G. Chen, Quan Xie, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396868721

                Acidic H2O2 synthesis through electrocatalytic 2e&#8211; oxygen reduction presents a sustainable alternative to the energy&#8208;intensive anthraquinone oxidation technology. Nevertheless, acidic H2O2 electrosynthesis suffers from low H2O2 Faradaic efficiencies primarily due to the competing reactions of 4e&#8211; oxygen reduction to H2O and hydrogen evolution in environments with high H+ concentrations. Here, we demonstrate the significant effect of alkali metal cations, acting as competing ions with H+, in promoting acidic H2O2 electrosynthesis at industrial&#8208;level currents, resulting in an effective current densities of 50&#8210;421 mA cm&#8210;2 with 84&#8210;100% Faradaic efficiency and a production rate of 856&#8210;7842 &#956;mol cm&#8208;2 h&#8208;1 that far exceeds the performance observed in pure acidic electrolytes or low&#8208;current electrolysis. Finite&#8208;element simulations indicate that high interfacial pH near the electrode surface formed at high currents is crucial for activating the promotional effect of K+. In situ attenuated total reflection Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations reveal the central role of alkali metal cations in stabilizing the key *OOH intermediate to suppress 4e&#8211; oxygen reduction through interacting with coordinated H2O.</description>
      <author>Peike Cao, Xueyang Zhao, Yanming Liu, Haiguang Zhang, Kun Zhao, Shuo Chen, Hongtao Yu, Dongrui Fan, Nathaniel N. Nichols, Jingguang G. Chen, Quan Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; 3D-ED in gas and liquid environments for following structural evolutions during reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1107/s2053273323095840</link>
      <description>D. Vandemeulebroucke, Amirhossein Hajizadeh, M. Batuk, J. Hadermann, Acta crystallographica. Section A, Foundations and advances. 79(a2)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4396818151

                Many functional materials are applied in the form of nanosized particles.To follow their structural evolution during reactions, in situ X ray powder diffraction or in situ neutron powder diffraction can miss out on details due to this small particle size.In such cases, in situ 3DED (three dimensional electron diffraction) would allow to gather single crystal type information on the structural changes.However, currently there are still many open questions on how the results from in situ 3DED relate to ex situ results and results from bulk experiments.Using closed cell environmental holders (gas, liquid, electrochemistry), combined with heating and cooling holders, we have studied their structural evolutions during redox reactions during heating in O2 and H2 versus vacuum of a range of perovskite based materials and have systematically related the resulting reduced structures to those obtained by other techniques.For Sr2Fe2O5 (Pcmb), investigated for solid oxide fuel cells, chemical looping and heterogeneous catalysis, in situ XRD and in situ NPD in gas environments only observed transformations between brownmillerite and perovskite type (Pm-3m) structures, while in situ 3DED allowed to also observe an intermediate Cmmm phase known from ex situ and electrochemistry experiments before reaching the perovskite type phase.In situ 3DED also showed the manifestation of nanotwins upon oxidation.After reducing the oxidized phase again in hydrogen at 700&#176;C, the ordering of the tetrahedral chains between planes was lost but the order within planes remained.Cooling instead the oxidized phase in oxygen resulted in an intergrowth of brownmillerite and perovskite.[1] The reduction of the Ruddlesden-Popper structure La0.5Sr1.5MnO4,also a candidate for solid oxide fuel cell cathodes, resulted in the creation of a perovskite layer at the surface which was not noticed before in bulk in situ experiments involving redox reactions in gas.Parallel ex situ reductions showed also faint superstructure reflections in the 3DED datasets pointing towards a surface reconstruction with ordered oxygen vacancies, which could not be detected in the in situ 3DED experiments.Differences in surface layers are important as they are the most active parts in catalytic reactions.Sr2MnO 4 could not be reduced using an in situ reaction with H2 into the supercell with oxygen-vacancy order from literature, while this did succeed during parallel ex situ reduction experiments as well as during in situ heating in vacuum.CaMnO3, a material for chemical looping applications, was successfully reduced using in situ reduction both by heating in hydrogen gas as well as by heating in vacuum, achieving not only the well characterized CaMnO2.5 phase, but also the intermediate CaMnO2.75, which was thus far not solved and had contradicting models in literature.Using the results from the in situ 3DED experiments, the CaMnO2.75 was solved in a Pmmm space group.These results were then compared to in situ 3DED results on the evolution of the Fe and Sr doped compounds which show better chemical looping properties.In situ 3DED in gas environments has thus already given new, complementary information to what was observed with in situ XRD and in situ NPD for each perovskite based material we have studied so far.We therefore believe that in future studies in situ 3DED will unlock a vast amount of new information on functional materials in general.</description>
      <author>D. Vandemeulebroucke, Amirhossein Hajizadeh, M. Batuk, J. Hadermann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1107/s2053273323095840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The use of photodynamic therapy in medical practice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fonc.2024.1373263</link>
      <description>David Aebisher, Kacper Rog&#243;&#380;, Angelika My&#347;liwiec, Klaudia Dynarowicz, Rafa&#322; Wiench, Grzegorz Cie&#347;lar, Aleksandra Kawczyk&#8208;Krupka, Dorota Bartusik&#8208;Aebisher, Frontiers in oncology. 14(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396859375

                Cancer therapy, especially for tumors near sensitive areas, demands precise treatment. This review explores photodynamic therapy (PDT), a method leveraging photosensitizers (PS), specific wavelength light, and oxygen to target cancer effectively. Recent advancements affirm PDT&#8217;s efficacy, utilizing ROS generation to induce cancer cell death. With a history spanning over decades, PDT&#8217;s dynamic evolution has expanded its application across dermatology, oncology, and dentistry. This review aims to dissect PDT&#8217;s principles, from its inception to contemporary medical applications, highlighting its role in modern cancer treatment strategies.</description>
      <author>David Aebisher, Kacper Rog&#243;&#380;, Angelika My&#347;liwiec, Klaudia Dynarowicz, Rafa&#322; Wiench, Grzegorz Cie&#347;lar, Aleksandra Kawczyk&#8208;Krupka, Dorota Bartusik&#8208;Aebisher</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fonc.2024.1373263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Preparation of Co-Based Catalysts Doped with Cu and Mo for Boosting Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824493</link>
      <description>Junhui Liu, Mengting Li, Wenke Zhang, Xiang Li, Yuan Zhao, Chunyou Zhu, Shikun Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396837802

                Hydrogen evolution from ammonia borane hydrolysis is a promising way for utilization of clean energy. Development of efficient and stable non-noble catalysts for improvement of hydrogen generation rate is essential but still a challenge. Herein, the heterostructured Co-based catalysts were controllably designed by combining the synergistic effect with oxygen vacancy engineering to improve the hydrogen generation rate. CoCu1Mo3-NC-O-15 exhibits the TOF value of 24.44 min-1 at 298 K with addition of 0.44 M NaOH, which is nearly 68 times that of Co-NC. The activation energy over CoCu1Mo3-NC-O-15 is 28.44 kJ mol-1. The CoCu1Mo3-NC-O-15 catalyst presents the good stability in ammonia borane hydrolysis reaction due to the carbon-coated structure. The strong synergistic effect and oxygen vacancy are favorable to the adsorption and dissociation of NH3BH3 and H2O molecules, leading to an astonishing improvement of catalytic activity. This study provides a novel way to design the heterostructured catalysts and a rational way to boost the dehydrogenation rate from AB.</description>
      <author>Junhui Liu, Mengting Li, Wenke Zhang, Xiang Li, Yuan Zhao, Chunyou Zhu, Shikun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halite-Structured (MgCoNiMnFe)O High Entropy Oxide (HEO) for Chemical Looping Dry Reforming of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124191</link>
      <description>Yu Shao, Chao Wu, Shibo Xi, Preston Tan, Xia Wu, Syed Saqline, Wen Liu, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835290

                The configurational disorder of high entropy oxides (HEOs) promotes the reversible exsolution&#8211;redissolution of constituent metal species. This unique feature could be exploited to facilitate cyclic lattice oxygen storage and exchange. Herein, we report an in situ generated, halite-structured (MgCoNiMnFe)Ox HEO, which simultaneously functions as a redox catalyst and an oxygen carrier for dry reforming of methane in a chemical looping process (CL&#8211;DRM). Accordingly, the (MgCoNiMnFe)Ox/ZrO2 HEO catalyst exhibits outstanding DRM activity, syngas selectivity and cyclic stability compared to medium-entropy oxides and bimetallic oxides over 100 CL&#8211;DRM cycles at 800 &#176;C. XRD analysis verified the entropy-mediated preservation of the alloy/HEO/ZrO2 catalytic structure over CL&#8211;DRM cycles. XAFS studies revealed the reversible and cyclic evolution&#8211;dissolution of Ni, Fe, Co over redox cycles. The exsolved NiFeCo nanoalloy exhibited high efficiency in activating CH4. This study has demonstrated the potential applications of HEO-based catalysts in efficient chemical looping processes.</description>
      <author>Yu Shao, Chao Wu, Shibo Xi, Preston Tan, Xia Wu, Syed Saqline, Wen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The study of gamma-radiation induced displacement damage in &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e372" altimg="si4.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msup&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;+&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msup&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;-in-&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e382" altimg="si5.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;p&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; silicon diodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nima.2024.169432</link>
      <description>Marcela Mikestikova, Pavla Federi&#269;ov&#225;, P. Gallus, R. Jir&#225;sek, J. Koz&#225;kov&#225;, J. Kroll, J Kvasni&#269;ka, V&#283;ra Lato&#328;ov&#225;, I. Mandi&#263;, K. Ma&#353;ek, Petr Novotn&#253;, R. P&#345;&#237;vara, Petr T&#367;ma, I. Zato&#269;ilov&#225;, Nuclear instruments and methods in physics research. Section A, Accelerators, spectrometers, detectors and associated equipment/Nuclear instruments &amp; methods in physics research. Section A, Accelerators, spectrometers, detectors and associated equipment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835849

                The bulk damage of p-type silicon sensors caused by gamma irradiation with high total ionizing doses has been investigated. The study was carried out on different types of n+-in-p silicon diodes with different oxygen concentrations and silicon bulk resistivities. The Secondary-Ion Mass Spectrometry technique was used to determine the relative concentration of oxygen in the individual samples. The measured diodes were irradiated by a 60Co gamma source to total ionizing doses ranging from 0.50 up to 8.28 MGy, and annealed for 80 min at 60 &#176;C. The main goal of the study was to characterize the gamma-radiation induced displacement damage by measuring I&#8211;V and C&#8211;V characteristics, and the evolution of the full depletion voltage with the total ionizing dose. The Transient Current Technique was used to verify the full depletion voltage and to extract the electric field distribution and the sign of the space charge in the silicon diodes irradiated to the lowest and the highest delivered total ionizing doses. The results show a linear increase of the bulk leakage current with the total ionizing dose, with the damage coefficient being dependent on initial resistivity and oxygen concentration of the silicon diode. The effective doping concentration and full depletion voltage decrease significantly with an increasing total ionizing dose, before starting to increase again at a specific dose. We assume that the initial decrease in the effective doping concentration is caused by the effect of acceptor removal. An additional notable finding of this study is that the bulk leakage current and C&#8211;V characteristics of the gamma-irradiated diodes do not show any evidence of an annealing effect.</description>
      <author>Marcela Mikestikova, Pavla Federi&#269;ov&#225;, P. Gallus, R. Jir&#225;sek, J. Koz&#225;kov&#225;, J. Kroll, J Kvasni&#269;ka, V&#283;ra Lato&#328;ov&#225;, I. Mandi&#263;, K. Ma&#353;ek, Petr Novotn&#253;, R. P&#345;&#237;vara, Petr T&#367;ma, I. Zato&#269;ilov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nima.2024.169432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydroclimate of the Messinian Salinity Crisis constrained from paleo-water triple oxygen, hydrogen, and strontium isotopes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.007</link>
      <description>Katharina Deu&#946;en, Claudia Voigt, Michael Staubwasser, Carsten M&#252;nker, Mohammed El-Shenawy, Swea Klipsch, Daniel Herwartz, Geochimica et cosmochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396828342

                Giant evaporite deposits formed during the Messinian Salinity Crisis (MSC) in the Mediterranean Sea during the upper Miocene. The primary cause is a restricted Atlantic-Mediterranean connection, but the detailed hydroclimate evolution of this event is still a matter of debate. Here we reconstruct the triple oxygen and hydrogen isotopic composition of paleo brines from structurally bonded water in Messinian gypsum from Cyprus. A two-stage evaporation model is constructed to best approximate the hydrological conditions at which Messinian gypsum formed in marginal basins of the Mediterranean Sea. Subsequently, hydroclimatic parameters like paleo relative humidity (RH) are modelled using an iterative curve fitting isotope model approach. The results of our limited dataset reveal a slightly lower RH during the third compared to the second stage of the MSC. This apparent drop in RH is consistent with previous observations from the literature. Besides absolute values of RH, our model allows reconstructing the triple oxygen and hydrogen isotopic composition of the open Mediterranean Sea. This provides an estimate for the proportions of continental water vs. Atlantic seawater flowing into the basin, serving as a proxy for the size of the strait of Gibraltar. The model implies a continental water fraction of around 75&#8211;81 % both for the second and third stage of the MSC. In addition, we determined the 87Sr/86Sr of our samples to: i) confirm their stratigraphy; and ii) estimate the relative proportion of continental water vs. Atlantic seawater entering the Mediterranean using Sr mass balance calculations. The combined oxygen and Sr isotope records indicate a persistent connection to the Atlantic supporting the hypothesis that the striking drop in 87Sr/86Sr at the beginning of MSC stage 3 is mainly related to an increased contribution of continental water with low 87Sr/86Sr and high Sr concentrations from the Paratethys. Our results show that the combination of triple oxygen, hydrogen, and Sr isotope data provides a powerful tool to disentangle paleo-hydroclimate even in such complicated hydrological settings as the Mediterranean Sea during the MSC.</description>
      <author>Katharina Deu&#946;en, Claudia Voigt, Michael Staubwasser, Carsten M&#252;nker, Mohammed El-Shenawy, Swea Klipsch, Daniel Herwartz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly rotating Population III stellar models as a source of primary nitrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449156</link>
      <description>Sophie Tsiatsiou, Yves Sibony, Devesh Nandal, Luca Sciarini, Yutaka Hirai, Sylvia Ekstr&#246;m, Eoin Farrell, Laura Bennett Murphy, Arthur Choplin, Rapha&#235;l Hirschi, Cristina Chiappini, Boyuan Liu, Volker Bromm, J. H. Groh, Georges Meynet, Astronomy &amp; astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396820935

                The first stars might have been fast rotators. This would have important consequences for their radiative, mechanical, and chemical feedback. We discuss the impact of fast initial rotation on the evolution of massive Population III models and on their nitrogen and oxygen stellar yields. We explore the evolution of Population III stars with initial masses in the range of 9 msol ini msol starting with an initial rotation on the zero-age main sequence equal to 70&lt;!PCT!&gt; of the critical one. We find that with the physics of rotation considered here, our rapidly rotating Population III stellar models do not follow a homogeneous evolution. They lose very little mass in the case in which mechanical winds are switched on when the surface rotation becomes equal to or larger than the critical velocity. The impact on the ionising flux appears to be modest when compared to moderately rotating models. Fast rotation favours, in models with initial masses above sim 20 msol the appearance of a very extended intermediate convective zone around the H-burning shell during the core He-burning phase. This shell has important consequences for the sizes of the He- and CO-cores, and thus impacts the final fate of stars. Moreover, it has a strong impact on nucleosynthesis, boosting the production of primary 14N. Fast initial rotation significantly impacts the chemical feedback of Population III stars. Observations of extremely metal-poor stars and/or starbursting regions are essential to provide constraints on the properties of the first stars.</description>
      <author>Sophie Tsiatsiou, Yves Sibony, Devesh Nandal, Luca Sciarini, Yutaka Hirai, Sylvia Ekstr&#246;m, Eoin Farrell, Laura Bennett Murphy, Arthur Choplin, Rapha&#235;l Hirschi, Cristina Chiappini, Boyuan Liu, Volker Bromm, J. H. Groh, Georges Meynet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Temperature dry sliding wear behaviour of Selective laser Melted Ti-6Al-4V alloy surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2024.118439</link>
      <description>K. Praveenkumar, Jithin Vishnu, Calvin Samuel, Vasanth Gopal, M. Arivarasu, J.M. Lackner, Benjamin Meier, D. Karthik, Satyam Suwas, S. Swaroop, Konda Gokuldoss Prashanth, Mayank Yadav, Geetha Manivasagam, Journal of materials processing technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396873887

                The present study investigates the sparsely documented tribological performance of selective laser-melted Ti-6Al-4V over a wide range of temperatures (room temperature to 450 &#176;C). The evolution of wear mechanism was traced by examining the phase changes, chemical composition, and morphology of wear tracks in the material. The native oxide layer developed on the surface of the material was found to mitigate adhesive wear during dry sliding at room temperature. At elevated temperatures, this oxide layer contributed to oxidative wear, as evidenced by the formation of a tribo-oxide layer with increased oxygen penetration. Further, abrasive wear was found to increase with increasing temperatures, which could be attributed to the presence of entrapped oxidized wear particles (third-body wear) and material softening.</description>
      <author>K. Praveenkumar, Jithin Vishnu, Calvin Samuel, Vasanth Gopal, M. Arivarasu, J.M. Lackner, Benjamin Meier, D. Karthik, Satyam Suwas, S. Swaroop, Konda Gokuldoss Prashanth, Mayank Yadav, Geetha Manivasagam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2024.118439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factors responsible for Witwatersrand gold mineralisation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25131/sajg.127.0023</link>
      <description>Axel Hofmann, South African journal of geology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780236

                Abstract The exceptional gold mineralisation in quartz pebble conglomerates of the Witwatersrand Basin is attributed to a combination of factors. These factors are linked to the co-evolution of the atmosphere, hydrosphere, lithosphere and biosphere, at a very specific time in Archaean geological history and the evolution of the Kaapvaal Craton. Following craton stabilisation and its subaerial emergence, intense chemical weathering and erosion of large volumes of granitoid-greenstone basement released detrital and dissolved gold. Shallow-marine reworking in a long-lived and slowly subsiding basin subjected to episodic compressional deformation and relative sea-level oscillations led to sedimentary concentration of detrital gold. The interaction between acidic, anoxic, and sulfurous surface runoff and more oxidizing marine waters in a near-coastal oxygen oasis supported microbially mediated diagenetic pyrite formation and incorporation of dissolved gold in the pyrite crystal lattice. Erosion and reworking of diagenetic pyrite gave rise to detrital pyrite that characterise most reefs. Abundance of detrital uraninite in conglomerates, derived from erosion of Mesoarchaean granites, and episodes of hydrocarbon migration through sedimentary strata during deep burial set the scene for further enhancement of gold grades in the reefs. Granular and seam pyro-bitumen formed by radiation-induced polymerisation of hydrocarbons around detrital uraninite. Gold dissolved in migrating hydrothermal fluids was then reduced and precipitated upon interaction with the reef pyro-bitumen during hydrothermal placer modification.</description>
      <author>Axel Hofmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25131/sajg.127.0023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The special adaptation to hypoxia facilitated the expansion of the Asian house rat (&lt;i&gt;Rattus tanezumi&lt;/i&gt;) into Tibet but not other &lt;i&gt;Rattus&lt;/i&gt; species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1749-4877.12829</link>
      <description>Rongxuan Cao, Ming Zhang, Yi Chen, Guangdong Hou, Qianying Liu, Jinhua Zhang, Y. Zhang, Integrative Zoology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396811676

                Abstract Rattus species are thought to live only at altitudes less than 2500 m, but the Asian house rat ( R. tanezumi ) (RT) has recently expanded to altitudes greater than 3500 m in China. Other Rattus species, especially brown rats ( R. norvegicus ) (RN), still reach only low altitudes on the Tibetan Plateau. Comparative genomics revealed the positive selection of hypoxia&#8208;inducible transcription factors 1 and 2 (HIFs) in RT, with the rapid evolution of HIF pathway genes in RT and Mus musculus (MM) but not RN or R. rattus . Population genomics revealed that genes associated with energy metabolism and oxygen transport were positively selected in RT compared with the other four Rattus species, and two specific substitutions (arginine 31 serine and leucine 33 methionine) were identified in the hemoglobin subunit beta (HBB) in RT. The above results suggested that RT possesses unique genetic adaptations to hypoxia, which was further confirmed by behavioral experiments on RT and RN. Normobaric hypoxia significantly reduced locomotion in RN but not in RT. Moreover, through intraspecific transcriptome analysis, the expression of Hbb and genes related to angiogenesis, oxygen transport, and glycolysis was upregulated, and the expression of genes associated with immunological functions in the liver, lungs, and/or sperm was downregulated in RT compared to those in RN. Interspecific transcriptome analysis further revealed that HIF&#8208;1&#945; plays a role in modulating the hypoxic adaptation of RT rather than RN. Our work provides genomic, behavioral, and physiological insights into why RT, but not other Rattus species, could invade the Tibetan Plateau.</description>
      <author>Rongxuan Cao, Ming Zhang, Yi Chen, Guangdong Hou, Qianying Liu, Jinhua Zhang, Y. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1749-4877.12829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overlooked shelf sediment reductive sinks of dissolved rhenium and uranium in the modern ocean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48297-y</link>
      <description>Qingquan Hong, Yuehua Cheng, Yegao Qu, Wei Lin, Y. Liu, Jianfeng Gao, Pinghe Cai, Tianyu Chen, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396792600

                Abstract Rhenium (Re) and uranium (U) are essential proxies in reconstructing past oceanic oxygenation evolution. However, their removal in continental shelf sediments, hotspots of early diagenesis, were previously treated as quantitatively unimportant sinks in the ocean. Here we examine the sedimentary reductive removal of Re and U and their coupling with organic carbon decomposition, utilizing the 224 Ra/ 228 Th disequilibria within the East China Sea shelf. We identified positive correlations between their removal fluxes and the rates of sediment oxygen consumption or organic carbon decomposition. These correlations enable an evaluation of global shelf reductive sinks that are comparable to (for Re) or higher than (~4-fold for U) previously established suboxic/anoxic sinks. These findings suggest potential imbalances in the modern budgets of Re and U, or perhaps a substantial underestimation of their sources. Our study thus highlights shelf sedimentary reductive removal as critical yet overlooked sinks for Re and U in the modern ocean.</description>
      <author>Qingquan Hong, Yuehua Cheng, Yegao Qu, Wei Lin, Y. Liu, Jianfeng Gao, Pinghe Cai, Tianyu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48297-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A promising strontium and cobalt-free Ba1-xCaxFeO3-&#948; air electrode for reversible protonic ceramic cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124176</link>
      <description>Guangjun Zhang, Ting Chen, Jizhao Zou, Chenxiao Wang, Xiaonan Bao, Guozhu Zheng, Zuzhi Huang, Wei Zhang, Kui Liu, Li&#8208;Yan Xu, Yucun Zhou, Shaorong Wang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396812202

                The air electrode with strontium and cobalt elements has the elemental diffusion or delamination issue on the air electrode/electrolyte interface in reversible protonic ceramic cells (RPCCs). Hence the development of strontium and cobalt-free triple conducting (H+/O2-/e-) air electrodes with high electrochemical activity and stability is urgent. Here, we report a strontium and cobalt-free Ba0.8Ca0.2FeO3-&#948; (BCF82) air electrode with high catalytic activity and electrochemical stability for oxygen reduction/evolution reactions. A RPCC with the BCF82 air electrode shows a high peak power density of 1.14 W cm-2 in the fuel cell mode and a current density of 3.49 A cm-2 under 1.3 V in the electrolysis mode at 700 &#176;C. Furthermore, the cell demonstrates suitable stability in the fuel cell, electrolysis and reversible modes at 600 &#176;C for hundreds of hours without elemental segregation and delamination issue. This work offers an efficient approach to develop low-cost and durable air electrodes for RPCCs.</description>
      <author>Guangjun Zhang, Ting Chen, Jizhao Zou, Chenxiao Wang, Xiaonan Bao, Guozhu Zheng, Zuzhi Huang, Wei Zhang, Kui Liu, Li&#8208;Yan Xu, Yucun Zhou, Shaorong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charting the Electronic Structure for Discovering Low-cost Intermetallic Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-fq66l</link>
      <description>Zhengda He, Bin Ouyang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396799859

                Discovering affordable, high-performance, and stable catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is essential for the commercialization of clean hydrogen technology. In this study, we utilized a high-throughput screening approach combined with electronic structure descriptors to identify new intermetallic catalysts that minimize noble metal contents while maintaining high performance and stability. We screened 2,358 binary and ternary intermetallic compounds constructed from 31 common transition metal elements. From the 462 bulk compositions that are synthetically accessible, we enumerated all possible low-Miller-index surfaces (12,057 surfaces in total) with density functional theory calculations. Seven electronic-structure-based descriptors are then applied to pinpoint aqueously stable surfaces offering performance comparable to the renowned Pt (111) and Ir (111) surfaces. This process led to the identification of several previously known noble-metal-containing catalysts, as well as a selection of new intermetallic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhengda He, Bin Ouyang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-fq66l</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monocyte bioenergetics: An immunometabolic perspective in metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrm.2024.101564</link>
      <description>Moris Sangineto, Martina Ciarnelli, Tommaso Colangelo, Archana Moola, Vidyasagar Naik Bukke, Loren Duda, Rosanna Villani, Antonino Davide Romano, Stefania Giandomenico, Hina Kanwal, Gaetano Serviddio, Cell reports medicine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396813576

                Monocytes (Mos) are crucial in the evolution of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD) to metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis (MASH), and immunometabolism studies have recently suggested targeting leukocyte bioenergetics in inflammatory diseases. Here, we reveal a peculiar bioenergetic phenotype in circulating Mos of patients with MASH, characterized by high levels of glycolysis and mitochondrial (mt) respiration. The enhancement of mt respiratory chain activity, especially complex II (succinate dehydrogenase [SDH]), is unbalanced toward the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and is sustained at the transcriptional level with the involvement of the AMPK-mTOR-PGC-1&#945; axis. The modulation of mt activity with dimethyl malonate (DMM), an SDH inhibitor, restores the metabolic profile and almost abrogates cytokine production. Analysis of a public single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) dataset confirms that in murine models of MASH, liver Mo-derived macrophages exhibit an upregulation of mt and glycolytic energy pathways. Accordingly, the DMM injection in MASH mice contrasts Mo infiltration and macrophagic enrichment, suggesting immunometabolism as a potential target in MASH.</description>
      <author>Moris Sangineto, Martina Ciarnelli, Tommaso Colangelo, Archana Moola, Vidyasagar Naik Bukke, Loren Duda, Rosanna Villani, Antonino Davide Romano, Stefania Giandomenico, Hina Kanwal, Gaetano Serviddio</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrm.2024.101564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electromagnetic observables of open-shell nuclei from coupled-cluster
  theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05608</link>
      <description>Francesca Bonaiti, Sonia Bacca, G. Hagen, G. R. Jansen, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822211

                We develop a new method to describe electromagnetic observables of open-shell nuclei with two nucleons outside a closed shell. This approach combines the equation-of-motion coupled-cluster method for such systems and the Lorentz integral transform technique, expanding the applicability of coupled-cluster theory for these properties beyond closed-shell nuclei. To validate this new approach, we compute the non-energy-weighted dipole sum rule and the dipole polarizability of $^{16,24}$O in both the closed-shell and the new equation-of-motion coupled-cluster frameworks, finding agreement within error bars. We then analyze the evolution of the dipole polarizability along the oxygen and calcium isotopic chains. Our predictions agree well with available experimental data and other available theoretical calculations for the closed-shell $^{16,22}$O and the open-shell $^{18}$O. In the calcium isotopes, we observe that our dipole polarizability predictions for open-shell nuclei are lower than those of closed-shell nuclei. Our predictions for $^{24}$O and $^{54,56}$Ca will motivate future experimental studies at the dripline.</description>
      <author>Francesca Bonaiti, Sonia Bacca, G. Hagen, G. R. Jansen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas Adsorption Mechanism on 2D Materials: The Hyperpolarizability Evolution Analyzed by Nonlinear Optics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406005</link>
      <description>Ting&#8208;Yu Yen, Yang&#8208;Hao Hung, Y. C. Lee, Yingchieh Ho, Yann&#8208;Wen Lan, Chau-Chung Wu, Kuan&#8208;Ming Hung, Kuang Yao Lo, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396813213

                Abstract While understanding the competitive adsorption behavior of gas sensor is important, it is yet to be unraveled. Especially for the influence of water molecules to the gas adsorbed on 2D materials. This study explores the potential of layered 2D materials as a candidate material for gas sensing, employing non&#8208;destructive measurement, and second harmonic generation (SHG). The investigation focuses on analyzing oxygen, ammonia, and water vapor adsorbed on a WS 2 surface by studying the evolutions in electric dipole and electric field. Leveraging the simplified bond hyperpolarizability model (SBHM), a foundation is established for gas sensors utilizing high&#8208;quality 2D materials. This approach facilitates the detection of material modifications in response to environmental influences, including the inevitable water molecules. The obtained hyperpolarizability from SBHM exhibits remarkable consistency with Langmuir's adsorption model, confirming the physical adsorption in the system. In addition, the competitive effects between gases are explored by comparing experimental results with theoretical predictions based on Boltzmann distribution and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. This highlights the effectiveness of SHG and SBHM in studying gas adsorption on layered van der Waals materials.</description>
      <author>Ting&#8208;Yu Yen, Yang&#8208;Hao Hung, Y. C. Lee, Yingchieh Ho, Yann&#8208;Wen Lan, Chau-Chung Wu, Kuan&#8208;Ming Hung, Kuang Yao Lo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous enhanced photocatalytic overall water splitting on AlO/WSi2N4 vdW heterojunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160247</link>
      <description>C. H. Li, Liang Xu, Zehua Jin, Qiongchao Wang, Bin Xiao, Zhengquan Li, Lingling Wang, Kun Dong, Tong Chen, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834524

                Completely achieving spontaneous water splitting without sacrificing co-catalysts poses a significant challenge, as factors such as electrical, optical, and catalytic activity can limit the conversion efficiency of solar energy to hydrogen. Herein, we propose a type-II van der Waals heterostructure composed of vertically stacked AlO and WSi2N4, and systematically investigate its mechanism and potential for catalyzing water splitting. Photon-induced photocatalytic water splitting takes advantage of the staggered energy bands of the heterojunction, effectively promoting the separation of photogenerated carriers and thus enhancing catalytic efficiency. In neutral water environment, the band edge position of AlO/WSi2N4 aligns with the redox potential required for water decomposition. Thermodynamic analysis of the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions indicates that the external potential provided by photogenerated carriers is expected to trigger spontaneous water decomposition. Moreover, with its high electron mobility (4800.62 cm2/Vs) and a solar-to-hydrogen energy conversion efficiency of up to 19.98 %, the AlO/WSi2N4 heterojunction demonstrates substantial potential as a photoelectric catalyst. This research introduces a promising avenue for efficient photocatalytic production of clean energy.</description>
      <author>C. H. Li, Liang Xu, Zehua Jin, Qiongchao Wang, Bin Xiao, Zhengquan Li, Lingling Wang, Kun Dong, Tong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White dwarf eccentricity fluctuation and dissipation by AGB convection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.03745</link>
      <description>Yair Cohen, Sivan Ginzburg, M. Levy, Tal Bar Shalom, Yoav Siman Tov, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396786787

                Millisecond pulsars with white dwarf companions have typical eccentricities $e\sim 10^{-6}-10^{-3}$. The eccentricities of helium white dwarfs are explained well by applying the fluctuation-dissipation theorem to convective eddies in their red giant progenitors. We extend this theory to more massive carbon-oxygen (CO) white dwarfs with asymptotic giant branch (AGB) progenitors. Due to the radiation pressure in AGB stars, the dominant factor in determining the remnant white dwarf's eccentricity is the critical residual hydrogen envelope mass $m_{\rm env}$ required to inflate the star to giant proportions. Using a suite of MESA stellar evolution simulations with $\Delta m_{\rm c}=10^{-3}\,{\rm M}_\odot$ core-mass intervals, we resolved the AGB thermal pulses and found that the critical $m_{\rm env}\propto m_{\rm c}^{-6}$. This steep dependence causes the $e(m_{\rm c})$ relation to turn over, such that $e\sim 3\times 10^{-3}$ almost independently of the remnant CO white dwarf's mass $m_{\rm c}$. Nearly all of the measured eccentricities lie below this robust theoretical limit, indicating that the eccentricity is damped during the common-envelope inspiral that follows the unstable Roche-lobe overflow of the AGB star. Specifically, we focused on white dwarfs with median masses $m_{\rm c}&gt;0.6\,{\rm M}_\odot$. These massive white dwarfs begin their inspiral with practically identical orbital periods and eccentricities, eliminating any dependence on the initial conditions. For this sub-sample, we find an empirical relation $e\propto P^{3/2}$ between the final period and eccentricity that is much tighter than previous studies - motivating theoretical work on the eccentricity evolution during the common envelope phase.</description>
      <author>Yair Cohen, Sivan Ginzburg, M. Levy, Tal Bar Shalom, Yoav Siman Tov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.03745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Core&#8211;Shell Au/ZnO Hybrid Nanostars for Photochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01015</link>
      <description>Gagandeep Kaur, Rathindranath Biswas, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Tuhinadri Sen, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834693

                Nanostructured hybrids that combine metals and semiconductors exhibit significant potential as photocatalysts for various reactions. Among these, core&#8211;shell plasmonic noble metal&#8211;semiconductor nanostructures, such as Au/ZnO nanostars (NSs), are highly effective catalysts for photocatalytic water splitting. This study presents a simple method for synthesizing Au/ZnO NSs and comprehensively characterizes them by using various spectroscopic and microscopic techniques. The synthesized Au/ZnO NSs exhibit very high efficiencies in hydrogen (H2) and oxygen (O2) evolution when used as a catalyst for photocatalytic water splitting. This heightened photocatalytic activity can be attributed to the efficient suppression of the scavenging activity of Au nanoparticles. Additionally, the anisotropic star-shaped morphology of the Au component in the catalyst contributes to an increased surface area that promotes an enhanced interaction between the catalyst's components. This interaction facilitates facile interfacial charge transfer at the interface, resulting in an improved performance. Moreover, the plasmonic response of the Au core surrounded by ZnO nanostructures enhances the catalyst's light utilization capability, contributing to its superior performance. This synthesis method represents a significant advancement and paves the way for future developments in the design of plasmon-semiconductor nanostructures for energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Gagandeep Kaur, Rathindranath Biswas, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Tuhinadri Sen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depth-resolved Characterization of Meissner Screening Breakdown in
  Surface Treated Niobium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05451</link>
      <description>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. Andrew MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822030

                We report direct measurements of the magnetic field screening at the limits of the Meissner phase for two superconducting Nb samples. The samples are processed with two different surface treatments that have been developed for superconducting radio-frequency cavity applications -- a "baseline" treatment and an oxygen-doping ("O-doping") treatment. The measurements show: 1) that the screening length is significantly longer in the "O-doping" sample compared to the "baseline" sample; 2) that the screening length near the limits of the Meissner phase increases with applied field; 3) the evolution of the screening profile as the material transitions from the Meissner phase to the mixed phase; and 4) a demonstration of the absence of any screening profile for the highest applied field, indicative of the full flux entering the sample. Measurements are performed utilizing the $\beta$-detected nuclear magnetic resonance ($\beta$-NMR) technique that allows depth resolved studies of the local magnetic field within the first 100 nm of the surface. The study takes advantage of the $\beta$-SRF beamline, a new facility at TRIUMF, Canada, where field levels up to 200 mT are available parallel to the sample surface to replicate radio frequency (RF) fields near the Meissner breakdown limits of Nb.</description>
      <author>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. Andrew MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The microRNA408&#8211;plantacyanin module balances plant growth and drought resistance by regulating reactive oxygen species homeostasis in guard cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/plcell/koae144</link>
      <description>Yan&#8208;Fei Yang, Lijia Xu, Chunxiang Hao, Miaomiao Wan, Yihan Tao, Yan Zhuang, Yanning Su, Lei Li, &#152;The &#156;Plant cell. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396759807

                The conserved microRNA (miRNA) miR408 enhances photosynthesis and compromises stress tolerance in multiple plants, but the cellular mechanism underlying its function remains largely unclear. Here, we show that in Arabidopsis (Arabidopsis thaliana), the transcript encoding the blue copper protein PLANTACYANIN (PCY) is the primary target for miR408 in vegetative tissues. PCY is preferentially expressed in the guard cells, and PCY is associated with the endomembrane surrounding individual chloroplasts. We found that the MIR408 promoter is suppressed by multiple abscisic acid (ABA)-responsive transcription factors, thus allowing PCY to accumulate under stress conditions. Genetic analysis revealed that PCY elevates reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels in the guard cells, promotes stomatal closure, reduces photosynthetic gas exchange, and enhances drought resistance. Moreover, the miR408-PCY module is sufficient to rescue the growth and drought tolerance phenotypes caused by gain- and loss-of-function of MYB44, an established positive regulator of ABA responses, indicating that the miR408-PCY module relays ABA signaling for regulating ROS homeostasis and drought resistance. These results demonstrate that miR408 regulates stomatal movement to balance growth and drought resistance, providing a mechanistic understanding of why miR408 is selected during land plant evolution and insights into the long-pursued quest of breeding drought-tolerant and high-yielding crops.</description>
      <author>Yan&#8208;Fei Yang, Lijia Xu, Chunxiang Hao, Miaomiao Wan, Yihan Tao, Yan Zhuang, Yanning Su, Lei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/plcell/koae144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3,8-Diaromatic-1,10-Phenanthroline Derivatives: Structure and Photophysical Properties as a Function of Their Arms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4826458</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Mu&#241;&#243;z, Felipe Pe&#241;aloza, Kevin Guajardo, Roxana Arce, Nancy Pizarro, Andr&#233;s Vega, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396878171

                The molecules of 3,8-diphenyl-1,10-phenanthroline (L1), 3,8-di(naphthalen-1-yl)-1,10-phenanthroline (L2), 3,8-di(naphthalen-2-yl)-1,10-phenanthroline (L3), 3,8-di(anthracen-9-yl)-1,10-phenanthroline (L4) and 3,8-di(pyren-1-yl)-1,10-phenanthroline (L5) were prepared in good yield from the reaction of 3,8-dibromo-1,10-phenanthroline and the corresponding boronic acid catalyzed by [Pd(PPh3)4]. Computational DFT modelling suggest than the aromatic substituent arms are not coplanar with the central phenanthroline core, and that the HOMO-LUMO gap diminishes as the number of fused carbon rings in the arms increased. Cyclic voltammograms for the ligands show between one and two oxidation and one to three reduction waves, which are believed to be centered on the arms and the central phen fragments respectively, suggesting some small electronic mixing. The absorption and emission properties depend on the electronic interaction between the polyaromatic substituents and the phenanthroline core. Different emissive &#960;&#960;* excited states for the molecules bearing anthryl and pyrenyl substituents conferring them a more charge transfer character, and a consequent major sensitive to the increase of solvent polarity. The photosensitizing capacity of singlet oxygen generation upon excitation of L1-L5 in solution is consistent with a significant evolution of the former singlet excited state towards a triplet excited state.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Mu&#241;&#243;z, Felipe Pe&#241;aloza, Kevin Guajardo, Roxana Arce, Nancy Pizarro, Andr&#233;s Vega</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4826458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solution-Based Synthesis of Oxide-Free MoS2 Film: Exploring Interface Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4320986/v1</link>
      <description>Mahboob Alam, Rikiya Sumichika, Junichi Tsuchimotoi, Tadahiro Komeda, Akinobu Teramoto, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830206

                Abstract We report a solution-based approach for the synthesis of oxidation-free MoS2 films, focusing on interface mechanisms. Through a sulfurization-free solution process and single-step annealing, the oxidation-free MoS2 film is successfully prepared on Si3N4 surfaces, showing improved uniformity with a surface roughness below 0.5 nm and a thickness of 4 nm at a precursor solution concentration of 30 mM, annealed between 700 and 800&#186;C. The MoS2 films exhibit a hexagonal lattice structure with crystallographic orientations of (1 1 0 0) and (1 2 1 0) with lattice spacings of 0.27 nm and 0.16 nm respectively. Interfacial analysis by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) on SiO2 reveals migration of oxygen species as evidenced by a shift in the Si 2p spectrum at binding energies between 102.6eV and 102.8eV. MoS2 films on Si3N4 show a complex Si 2p peak evolution at binding energies between 100.9 and 101.8 eV, providing valuable insights into the synthesis of oxide-free MoS2 films for potential applications in advanced electronic devices.</description>
      <author>Mahboob Alam, Rikiya Sumichika, Junichi Tsuchimotoi, Tadahiro Komeda, Akinobu Teramoto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4320986/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shear Coaxial Methane&#8211;Oxygen Injector Mixing and Combustion Examined by Laser Absorption Tomography</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2514/1.b39463</link>
      <description>Alex R. Keller, R. Mitchell Spearrin, Fabio A. Bendana, Journal of propulsion and power. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396867795

                Mixing length scales for methane&#8211;oxygen shear-coaxial single-element rocket injectors were experimentally assessed using laser absorption tomography. The laser spectroscopy technique enables quantitative and spatially resolved measurements of carbon monoxide (CO) and temperature within the near-field region, probing rovibrational absorption lines of CO near [Formula: see text]. Multiple injector designs were examined with differing oxidizer post recess depths to compare mixing characteristics. All tests were performed at an oxidizer-to-fuel ratio of 3 with a total propellant flow rate of 0.350 g/s. Planar measurements were taken at 16 axial positions, which collectively captured the first 57 mm of each flame. A tomographic inversion method was applied to obtain radially resolved distributions of temperature and CO mole fraction for each axial position, from which two-dimensional images of the thermochemical structure were generated. Characteristic mixing parameters are defined and extracted from features within the species and temperature profiles to visualize the spatial evolution of CO production. Increasing oxidizer post recess improved mixing due to enhanced shear-induced turbulence and associated radial diffusion of species and temperature; however, the enhancement was nonlinear. This work establishes the first use of laser absorption tomography to directly measure mixing length scales associated with temperature and species profiles in coaxial flames.</description>
      <author>Alex R. Keller, R. Mitchell Spearrin, Fabio A. Bendana</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2514/1.b39463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modification of WS2 thin film properties using high dose gamma irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad4901</link>
      <description>Pravin Jadhav, P. T. Kolhe, V.S. Ghemud, P. N. Shelke, Shashikant P. Patole, S.D. Dhole, S.S. Dahiwale, Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760690

                The tunability of the Transition Metal Dichalcogenide (TMD) properties has gained attention from numerous researchers due to their wide application in various fields including quantum technology. In the present work, WS2 has been deposited on fluorine doped tin oxide (FTO) substrate and its properties have been studied systematically. These samples were irradiated using gamma radiation for various doses, and the effect on structural, morphological, optical and electrical properties has been reported. The crystallinity of the material is observed to be decreased, and the results are well supported by X-ray diffraction, Raman spectroscopy techniques. The increase in grain boundaries has been supported by the agglomeration observed in the scanning electron microscopy micrographs. The XPS results of WS2 after gamma irradiation show evolution of oxygen, carbon, C=O, W-O and SO42- peaks, confirming the addition of impurities and formation of point defect. The gamma irradiation creates point defects, and their density increases considerably with increasing gamma dosage. These defects crucially altered the structural, optical and electrical properties of the material. The reduction in the optical band gap with increased gamma irradiation is evident from the absorption spectra and respective Tauc plots. The I-V graphs show a 1000-fold increase in the saturation current after 100 kGy gamma irradiation dose. This work has explored the gamma irradiation effect on the WS2 and suggests substantial modification in the material and enhancement in electrical properties. 
.</description>
      <author>Pravin Jadhav, P. T. Kolhe, V.S. Ghemud, P. N. Shelke, Shashikant P. Patole, S.D. Dhole, S.S. Dahiwale</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad4901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive interacting binaries as an enrichment source for multiple
  populations in star clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05687</link>
      <description>Michelle Nguyen, Alison Sills, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822298

                We present a suite of binary evolution models with massive primaries (10 $\leq$ M$_1$ $\leq$ 40 M$_\odot$) and periods and mass ratios chosen such that the systems undergo non-conservative mass transfer while the primaries have helium cores. We track the total mass and chemical composition of the ejecta from these systems. This material shows the abundance signatures of hot hydrogen burning which are needed to explain the abundance patterns seen in multiple populations in massive star clusters. We then calculate the total yield of a population of binary stars with masses, mass ratios, and periods consistent with their distribution in a field population. We show that the overall abundance of this material is enriched in helium, nitrogen, sodium, and aluminum, and depleted in carbon, oxygen, and magnesium, by amounts that are consistent with observations. We also show that such a population of binaries will return approximately 25% of its mass in this ejecta (compared to 4% if all the stars were single), over a characteristic timescale of about 12 Myr. We argue that massive binaries must be seriously considered as a contributor to the source of enriched material needed to explain the multiple populations in massive clusters, since essentially all massive stars are formed in binaries or higher order multiples, massive binaries are primarily formed in clusters, and massive binaries naturally produce material of the right composition.</description>
      <author>Michelle Nguyen, Alison Sills</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05687</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the dose-rate effect on loop characteristics in Kr+-irradiated CeO2 by in-situ TEM study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.167</link>
      <description>Fanyi Yang, Ziqi Cao, Dan Cui, Yong Xin, Yuanming Li, Dan Sun, Guang Ran, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831373

                Irradiation of CeO2 with heavy ions is commonly used to accelerate the evaluation of the irradiation performance of UO2 nuclear fuel. However, the differences in damage rates between ions and neutrons have led to doubts about this method, making it especially important to study the dose rate effect. Here, two kinds of dose rates were used to in-situ irradiate CeO2 using 400 keV Kr+ at 550 &#176;C and 700 &#176;C to study the dose rate effect on loop characteristics. High dose rate (HR) led to low-density and small-sized dislocation loops compared to low dose rate (LR), which was attributed to the initial high concentration of oxygen vacancies and enhanced recombination of point defects. HR was found to promote the direct nucleation of perfect dislocation loops (PDLs), while under LR irradiation, the PDLs tended to be formed by the transformation of Frank dislocation loops (FDLs) through a typical unfaulting. At a same dose, the proportion of PDL under HR condition was much higher than that under LR condition. Temperature greatly affected the loop characteristics. High temperature caused large sized and small dense loops, as well as high PDL proportion. Moreover, the newly nucleated PDL tended to close to the pre-existing PDLs and had the same Burgers vector as the adjacent PDL under HR irradiation at 700 &#176;C. Current results provide underlying insights for assessing the effect of dose rate on irradiation-induced loop evolution and a reference for understanding the dose rate effect.</description>
      <author>Fanyi Yang, Ziqi Cao, Dan Cui, Yong Xin, Yuanming Li, Dan Sun, Guang Ran</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-roughness effect on the interfacial thermal oxidation and surface catalytical recombination characteristics for silicon carbide based materials under non-equilibrium flow</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160263</link>
      <description>He Li, Jin Zhao, Guice Yao, Jianzhou Tang, Yunpeng Cao, Dongsheng Wen, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834745

                With the rapid development of high-speed aircraft, the demanding for light, strong, reliable and high temperature resistive thermal protection material (TPM) is becoming urgent. High temperature material interface, such as silicon carbide (SiC) ceramic matrix composite, has received strong interest recently due to its high mechanical and thermochemical stability. For reactive interface development with nano-roughness under extremely hyperthermal non-equilibrium flow conditions for TPM applications, however, has not been reported yet. This work performs a systematic reactive molecular dynamics (RMD) study of the SiC surface morphology effect withstanding hyperthermal atomic oxygen (AO) impact via a gas&#8211;solid interface reaction model. The results show that a self-healing trend of the defect-rich silicon carbide surface with original nano-roughness is revealed towards a flatter interface accompanying with the oxidation process. The surface catalytic recombination coefficient is more sensitivity to the surface defects when wall temperature Tw &gt; 500 K. Nano-roughness structure can also vary the main thermochemical reaction path at the thermochemical reactive interface: For the nano-groove surface model, the thermal oxidation reaction becomes dominant, while more pronounced surface catalytic recombination characteristics are revealed for the flat surface model. The mechanisms of roughness effect, surface temperature and gas impacting angle on the surface catalytic recombination, surface oxidation, and interface evolution are revealed, which advance our microscopic understanding of SiC interfacial performance with nano-roughness under non-equilibrium flow conditions.</description>
      <author>He Li, Jin Zhao, Guice Yao, Jianzhou Tang, Yunpeng Cao, Dongsheng Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mystery of rich human gut antibiotic resistome in the Yellow River with hyper-concentrated sediment-laden flow</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121763</link>
      <description>Yuan Gao, Qian Chen, Shufeng Liu, Jiawen Wang, Alistair G.L. Borthwick, Jinren Ni, Water research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780510

                Human gut antibiotic resistome widely occur in anoxic environments characterized by high density of bacterial cells and frequent transmission of antibiotic resistance genes (ARGs). Such resistome is greatly diluted, degraded, and restrained in the aerobic habitats within most natural rivers (regarded as "terrestrial guts") connecting continents and the oceans. Here we implemented a large-scale monitoring campaign extending 5,200 km along the Yellow River, and provide the first integral biogeographic pattern for both ARGs and their hosts. We identified plentiful ARGs (24 types and 809 subtypes) and their hosts (24 phyla and 757 MAGs) in three media (water, suspended particulate matter (SPM), and sediment). Unexpectedly, we found diverse human gut bacteria (HGB) acting as supercarriers of ARGs in this oxygen-rich river. We further discovered that numerous microhabitats were created within stratified biofilms that surround SPMs, particularly regarding the aggregation of anaerobic HGB. These microhabitats provide numerous ideal sinks for anaerobic bacteria and facilitate horizontal transfer of ARGs within the stratified biofilms, Furthermore, the stratification of biofilms surrounding SPMs has facilitated synergy between human gut flora and denitrifiers for propagation of ARGs in the anoxic atmospheres, leading to high occurrence of human gut antibiotic resistome. SPMs play active roles in the dynamic interactions of river water and sediment, thus accelerating the evolution of riverine resistome and transmission of human gut antibiotic resistome. This study revealed the special contribution of SPMs to the propagation of ARGs, and highlighted the necessity of making alternative strategies for sustainable management of large rivers with hyper-concentrated sediment-laden flows.</description>
      <author>Yuan Gao, Qian Chen, Shufeng Liu, Jiawen Wang, Alistair G.L. Borthwick, Jinren Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbiota and metabolic adaptation shape&lt;i&gt;Staphylococcus aureus&lt;/i&gt;virulence and antimicrobial resistance during intestinal colonization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.11.593044</link>
      <description>Chunyi Zhou, Miranda B Pawline, Alejandro Pironti, Sandra Morales, Andrew I. Perault, Robert J. Ulrich, Magdalena Podkowik, Alannah Lejeune, Ashley Dumont, Fran&#231;ois-Xavier Stubbe, Aryeh Korman, Drew R. Jones, Jonas Schluter, Anthony R. Richardson, Paul D. Fey, Karl Drlica, Ken Cadwell, Victor J. Torres, Bo Shopsin, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396846969

                Depletion of microbiota increases susceptibility to gastrointestinal colonization and subsequent infection by opportunistic pathogens such as methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). How the absence of gut microbiota impacts the evolution of MRSA is unknown. The present report used germ-free mice to investigate the evolutionary dynamics of MRSA in the absence of gut microbiota. Through genomic analyses and competition assays, we found that MRSA adapts to the microbiota-free gut through sequential genetic mutations and structural changes that enhance fitness. Initially, these adaptations increase carbohydrate transport; subsequently, evolutionary pathways largely diverge to enhance either arginine metabolism or cell wall biosynthesis. Increased fitness in arginine pathway mutants depended on arginine catabolic genes, especially nos and arcC, which promote microaerobic respiration and ATP generation, respectively. Thus, arginine adaptation likely improves redox balance and energy production in the oxygen-limited gut environment. Findings were supported by human gut metagenomic analyses, which suggest the influence of arginine metabolism on colonization. Surprisingly, these adaptive genetic changes often reduced MRSA's antimicrobial resistance and virulence. Furthermore, resistance mutation, typically associated with decreased virulence, also reduced colonization fitness, indicating evolutionary trade-offs among these traits. The presence of normal microbiota inhibited these adaptations, preserving MRSA's wild-type characteristics that effectively balance virulence, resistance, and colonization fitness. The results highlight the protective role of gut microbiota in preserving a balance of key MRSA traits for long-term ecological success in commensal populations, underscoring the potential consequences on MRSA's survival and fitness during and after host hospitalization and antimicrobial treatment.</description>
      <author>Chunyi Zhou, Miranda B Pawline, Alejandro Pironti, Sandra Morales, Andrew I. Perault, Robert J. Ulrich, Magdalena Podkowik, Alannah Lejeune, Ashley Dumont, Fran&#231;ois-Xavier Stubbe, Aryeh Korman, Drew R. Jones, Jonas Schluter, Anthony R. Richardson, Paul D. Fey, Karl Drlica, Ken Cadwell, Victor J. Torres, Bo Shopsin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.11.593044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First detection of CO isotopologues in a high-redshift main-sequence
  galaxy: evidence of a top-heavy stellar initial mass function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05317</link>
      <description>Ziyi Guo, Zhi-Yu Zhang, Zhiqiang Yan, Eda Gjergo, Allison Man, R. J. Ivison, Xiaoting Fu, Yong Shi, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396821932

                Recent observations and theories have presented a strong challenge to the universality of the stellar initial mass function (IMF) in extreme environments. A notable example has been found for starburst conditions, where evidence favours a top-heavy IMF, i.e. there is a bias toward massive stars compared to the IMF that is responsible for the stellar mass function and elemental abundances observed in the Milky Way. Local starburst galaxies have star-formation rates similar to those in high-redshift main-sequence galaxies, which appear to dominate the stellar mass budget at early epochs. However, the IMF of high-redshift main-sequence galaxies is yet to be probed. Since $^{13}$CO and C$^{18}$O isotopologues are sensitive to the IMF, we have observed these lines towards four strongly-lensed high-redshift main-sequence galaxies using the Atacama Large Millimeter/sub-millimeter Array. Of our four targets, SDSS J0901+1814, at $z \approx 2.26$, is seen clearly in $^{13}$CO and C$^{18}$O, the first detection of CO isotopologues in the high-redshift main-sequence galaxy population. The observed $^{13}$C/$^{18}$O ratio, $2.4 \pm 0.8$, is significantly lower than that of local main-sequence galaxies. We estimate the isotope ratio, oxygen abundance and stellar mass using a series of chemical evolution models with varying star-formation histories and IMFs. All models favour an IMF that is more top-heavy than that of the Milky Way. Thus, as with starburst galaxies, main-sequence galaxies in the high-redshift Universe have a greater fraction of massive stars than a Milky-Way IMF would imply.</description>
      <author>Ziyi Guo, Zhi-Yu Zhang, Zhiqiang Yan, Eda Gjergo, Allison Man, R. J. Ivison, Xiaoting Fu, Yong Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase evolution during solid-state synthesis of disordered rocksalt cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1107/s205327332309575x</link>
      <description>Kevin H. Stone, Yijin Liu, Dimosthenis Sokaras, William C. Chueh, Johanna Nelson Weker, Acta crystallographica. Section A, Foundations and advances. 79(a2)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4396818227

                Cation-disordered rocksalt (DRX) materials have recently garnered attention for their potential as cathodes in lithiumion batteries.These materials are lithium transition metal oxides which assume a rocksalt type structure with a disordering of the lithium and one or more transition metals on the cation sublattice.The disordering results in several desirable properties such as good lithium transport and small volume changes with cycling.Unlike layered transition metal oxides that are inherently unstable when significant lithium is removed, limiting practical compositions to combinations of cobalt, nickel, and manganese, DRX cathodes can also be synthesized with widely available transition metals to avoid expensive or critical materials.[1]Additional fluorine substitution for oxygen can increase stability for higher lithium content and improve long term capacity retention during cycling.[2,3]Solid-state synthesis, where solid precursors are mixed together, sometimes through ball-milling, then heated either in air or inert gas to high temperatures (typically ~1000&#730;C), has been one of the chief methods for fabricating disordered or partially disordered cathod e materials.For solid-state synthesis, the reaction can go through multiple intermediates before the reaction is completed.These intermediates are not always known and could be desirable end products in themselves, however, without in situ methods, only the endpoints of the synthesis can be studied.X-ray diffraction is a powerful approach for tracking crystalline structures in situ during solid state synthesis.At the Stanford Synchrotron Radiation Lightsource (SSRL), we have used in situ X-ray diffraction to study the solidstate synthesis of disordered rocksalt cathode materials.After careful preparation of the precursor mixture, it is possible to monitor the reaction as the sample is heated to and held at the reaction temperature.From this data it is possible to monitor the phase evolution of the precursors and the formation of the disordered rocksalt product.This in situ data provides important mechanistic insight into the formation reaction of the disordered rocksalt material and allows for easy determination of the impact of changes to the precursor materials or the annealing process.In combination with detailed structural characterization of the product ex situ, we accurately determine the final product composition, level of order/disorder, and performance as a cathode material for lithium-ion batteries.</description>
      <author>Kevin H. Stone, Yijin Liu, Dimosthenis Sokaras, William C. Chueh, Johanna Nelson Weker</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1107/s205327332309575x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volatile atmospheres of lava worlds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202347749</link>
      <description>Maxime Maurice, Rajdeep Dasgupta, Pedram Hassanzadeh, Astronomy &amp; astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396872878

                A magma ocean (MO) is thought to be a ubiquitous stage in the early evolution of rocky planets and exoplanets. During the lifetime of the MO, exchanges between the interior and exterior envelopes of the planet are very efficient. In particular, volatile elements that initially are contained in the solid part of the planet can be released and form a secondary outgassed atmosphere. We determine trends in the H-C-N-O-S composition and thickness of these secondary atmospheres for varying planetary sizes and MO extents, and the oxygen fugacity of MOs, which provides the main control for the atmospheric chemistry. We used a model with coupled chemical gas-gas and silicate melt-gas equilibria and mass conservation to predict the composition of an atmosphere at equilibrium with the MO depending on the planet size and the extent and redox state of the MO. We used a self-consistent mass-radius model for the rocky core to inform the structure of the planet, which we combined with an atmosphere model to predict the transit radius of lava worlds. The resulting MOs have potential temperatures ranging from 1415 to 4229 K, and their outgassed atmospheres have total pressures from 3.3 to 768 bar. We find that MOs (especially the shallow ones) on small planets are generally more reduced, and are thus dominated by H$_2$-rich atmospheres (whose outgassing is strengthened at low planetary mass), while larger planets and deeper MOs vary from CO to CO$_2$-N$_2$-SO$_2$ atmospheres, with increasing $f_ O $. In the former case, the low molecular mass of the atmosphere combined with the low gravity of the planets yields a large vertical extension of the atmosphere, while in the latter cases, secondary outgassed atmospheres on super-Earths are likely significantly shrunk. Both N and C are largely outgassed regardless of the conditions, while the S and H outgassing is strongly dependent on the $f_ O $, as well as on the planetary mass and MO extent for the latter. We further use these results to assess how much a secondary outgassed atmosphere may alter the mass-radius relations of rocky exoplanets.</description>
      <author>Maxime Maurice, Rajdeep Dasgupta, Pedram Hassanzadeh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202347749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if youth is not enough? Acute coronary syndrome in young patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ehjacc/zuae036.032</link>
      <description>Manuel V&#225;zquez, E Minguez De La Guia, Nuria Vallejo Calcerrada, A Abell&#225;n, S. Lopez, P. Ca&#241;eque Garc&#237;a, Felipe Mart&#237;nez, Miguel Corb&#237; Pascual, Laura Exp&#243;sito Calamardo, R Ramos Martinez, Mariano Pastor, Alejandro Lobato, JJ. Portero Portaz, Jes&#250;s Jim&#233;nez Mazuecos, S Diaz Lancha, European heart journal. Acute cardiovascular care. 13(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396782016

                Abstract Funding Acknowledgements None. Background Acute Coronary Syndromes (ACS) are the leading cause of mortality in Spain. Further research is needed in order to know risk factors and outcomes in young patients so that medicians could optimize their management and prevention. Purpose Identifying risk factors, clinical characteristics and short-term outcomes in Acute Coronary Syndrome in patients aged 40 and under. Methods A retrospective analysis of patients under 40 years of age who were admitted for ACS, out of 3,859 ACS admissions in Cardiology Intensive Care Unit (CICU) in our hospital between 2012 and 2022. Results 67 patients (1.73%) were included, most of them were males (83.6%). Baseline characteristics are summarized in Table 1. 77.6% had hypertension (HTA), 22.4% had diabetes (DM) and 34.3% had dyslipidemia (DLP). 79.1% were smokers, 9.1% had a history of alcoholism and 29.9% were cocaine users. None of them had a history of stroke, atrial fibrillation (AF). Only 3% had ischemic heart disease. 68.7% of them were ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) and inferior STEMI was the most common (38.7%). In anterior STEMI (22 patients), 15 had a severe lesion in the mid-left anterior descending artery (LAD), and 6 in the left main stem (LM). Single-vessel disease was the most common (70.8%), with 3-vessel disease in 4.6%. 75.8% received percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI), and 3% underwent bypass surgery. During admission, 10.5% progressed to Killip class III-IV. The ICU mortality was 1.5%. 9% received vasoactive drugs and 4.5% were intubated. Non-invasive ventilation was used in 3% and high-flow nasal cannula oxygen therapy in 5.3%. 3% received intra-aortic balloon pump support and 1.5% underwent dialysis or ultrafiltration. 4.5% received an implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (ICD), although none of them developed bundle branch block or atrioventricular node block, nor AF. After discharge, 11.1% had recurrent ACS, and up to 5.6% underwent PCI again, with a mortality rate of 11.8%. Conclusion Approximately 2% of ACS occur in people younger than 40 years of age. Substance abuse (smoking, cocaine and alcoholism) becomes more prevalent in this group. Prevalence of comorbidities (such as diabetes and nephropathy) are lower, making them less prone to short-term heart failure. However, they are more susceptible to recurrent ischemic events. There is a high incidence of inferior STEMI and LM-STEMI. For these reasons, medicians may need to find out a substance abuse in this group and further research into other risk factors, such as coronary disease family history.Basal characteristicsClinical evolution of patients</description>
      <author>Manuel V&#225;zquez, E Minguez De La Guia, Nuria Vallejo Calcerrada, A Abell&#225;n, S. Lopez, P. Ca&#241;eque Garc&#237;a, Felipe Mart&#237;nez, Miguel Corb&#237; Pascual, Laura Exp&#243;sito Calamardo, R Ramos Martinez, Mariano Pastor, Alejandro Lobato, JJ. Portero Portaz, Jes&#250;s Jim&#233;nez Mazuecos, S Diaz Lancha</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ehjacc/zuae036.032</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
