<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 01:10:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting the bifunctional oxygen catalytic activity of the perovskite and Co3O4 heterostructure by introducing oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.193</link>
      <description>Bingen Yuan, Jiaqun Zou, Jian Jia, Jiatang Wang, Heng Xu, Jia Li, Chunfei Zhang, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400762167

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingen Yuan, Jiaqun Zou, Jian Jia, Jiatang Wang, Heng Xu, Jia Li, Chunfei Zhang, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ fabrication of low-crystallinity (Ni,Fe)xSy nanosheet arrays via room-temperature corrosion engineering toward efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124415</link>
      <description>Mingyue Chen, Wenhui Li, Y. Lu, Pengcheng Qi, Hao Wu, Kunyu Hao, Yiwen Tang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. 358(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400762733

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyue Chen, Wenhui Li, Y. Lu, Pengcheng Qi, Hao Wu, Kunyu Hao, Yiwen Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Oxides as Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Mini Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02061</link>
      <description>Yueqi Huang, Dan Wang, Yihang Yu, Zenghui Li, Xiaojing Wen, Zhiyuan Wang, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400763937

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yueqi Huang, Dan Wang, Yihang Yu, Zenghui Li, Xiaojing Wen, Zhiyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>p-Block Anion Compressed d/p Band Center of Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Durable Aqueous Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103654</link>
      <description>Kejian Ding, Yi Yang, Jiugang Hu, Liming Zhao, Huanan Yu, Zejie Zhu, Yunpeng Liu, Shan Cai, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Xiaobo Ji, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400767685

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kejian Ding, Yi Yang, Jiugang Hu, Liming Zhao, Huanan Yu, Zejie Zhu, Yunpeng Liu, Shan Cai, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Xiaobo Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the cationic vacancy structure of NiO to optimize its d band center and accelerate oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.194</link>
      <description>Wen-Zhuo Zhang, Xiang Li, Guangyi Chen, Junyuan Xu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400767816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen-Zhuo Zhang, Xiang Li, Guangyi Chen, Junyuan Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese Doped Tailored Cobalt Sulfide as an Accelerated Catalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898894</link>
      <description>Junbai Li, Hafiz Muhammad Naeem Ullah, Nouraiz Mushtaq, Sajid ur Rehman, Zeeshan Tariq, Shafaqat Ali, Muhammad Tahir, Chuanbo Li, Xiaoming Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400769895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junbai Li, Hafiz Muhammad Naeem Ullah, Nouraiz Mushtaq, Sajid ur Rehman, Zeeshan Tariq, Shafaqat Ali, Muhammad Tahir, Chuanbo Li, Xiaoming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B&#8208;site Doping Boosts the OER and ORR Performance of Double Perovskite Oxide as Air Cathode for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400531</link>
      <description>Cagla Ozgur, Tuncay Erdil, Uygar Geyikci, &#304;lker Y&#305;ld&#305;z, Ersu LOKCU, &#199;i&#287;dem Toparl&#305;, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400769965

                Double perovskite oxides are key players as electrocatalytic oxygen catalysts in alkaline media. In this study, we synthesized B&#8208;site doped NdBaCoaFe2&#8208;aO5+&#948; (a= 1.0, 1.4, 1.6, 1.8) electrocatalysts, systematically to probe their bifunctionality and assess their performance in zinc&#8208;air batteries as air cathodes. X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy analysis reveals a correlation between iron reduction and increased oxygen vacancy content, influencing electrocatalyst bifunctionality by lowering the work function. The electrocatalyst with highest cobalt content, NdBaCo1.8Fe0.2O5+&#948; exhibited a bifunctional index of 0.95 V, outperforming other synthesized electrocatalysts. Remarkably, NdBaCo1.8Fe0.2O5+&#948;, demonstrated facilitated charge transfer rate in oxygen evolution reaction with four&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction process. As an air cathode in a zinc&#8208;air battery, NdBaCo1.8Fe0.2O5+&#948; demonstrated superior performance characteristics, including maximum capacity of 428.27 mA h at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 discharge current density, highest peak power density of 64 mW cm&#8208;2, with an outstanding durability and stability. It exhibits lowest voltage gap change between charge and discharge even after 350 hours of cyclic operation with a rate capability of 87.14%.</description>
      <author>Cagla Ozgur, Tuncay Erdil, Uygar Geyikci, &#304;lker Y&#305;ld&#305;z, Ersu LOKCU, &#199;i&#287;dem Toparl&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-bridging Fe, Co dual-metal dimers boost reversible oxygen electrocatalysis for rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2404013121</link>
      <description>Qixing Zhou, Wendan Xue, Xun Cui, Pengfei Wang, Sijin Zuo, Fan Mo, Chengzhi Li, G. Liu, Shaohu Ouyang, Sihui Zhan, Juan Chen, Chao Wang, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400772891

                Rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) are regarded as a remarkably promising alternative to current lithium-ion batteries, addressing the requirements for large-scale high-energy storage. Nevertheless, the sluggish kinetics involving oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) hamper the widespread application of ZABs, necessitating the development of high-efficiency and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts. Here, we report oxygen atom&#8211;bridged Fe, Co dual-metal dimers (FeOCo-SAD), in which the active site Fe&#8211;O&#8211;Co&#8211;N 6 moiety boosts exceptional reversible activity toward ORR and OER in alkaline electrolytes. Specifically, FeOCo-SAD achieves a half-wave potential ( E 1/2 ) of 0.87 V for ORR and an overpotential of 310 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8211;2 for OER, with a potential gap (&#916; E ) of only 0.67 V. Meanwhile, FeOCo-SAD manifests high performance with a peak power density of 241.24 mW cm &#8722;2 in realistic rechargeable ZABs. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that the introduction of an oxygen bridge in the Fe, Co dimer induced charge spatial redistribution around Fe and Co atoms. This enhances the activation of oxygen and optimizes the adsorption/desorption dynamics of reaction intermediates. Consequently, energy barriers are effectively reduced, leading to a strong promotion of intrinsic activity toward ORR and OER. This work suggests that oxygen-bridging dual-metal dimers offer promising prospects for significantly enhancing the performance of reversible oxygen electrocatalysis and for creating innovative catalysts that exhibit synergistic effects and electronic states.</description>
      <author>Qixing Zhou, Wendan Xue, Xun Cui, Pengfei Wang, Sijin Zuo, Fan Mo, Chengzhi Li, G. Liu, Shaohu Ouyang, Sihui Zhan, Juan Chen, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2404013121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural, Magnetic and Electrocatalytic Properties of Rock Salt Oxide Nanofibers (Ni0.2mg0.2zn0.2cu0.2-Xco0.2+X)O Produced by Air-Heated Solution Blow Spinning (A-Hsbs) for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898639</link>
      <description>Rubens Maciel Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Medeiros, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400776985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rubens Maciel Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Medeiros, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898639</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the oxygen evolution activity of biomass-derived porous carbon plate as self-supported metal-free electrocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.07.007</link>
      <description>Xinghe Zhang, Yujie Wang, Jin Zou, Shichao Zhao, Hongbo Hou, Fengmei Zhang, Huaipeng Wang, Progress in Natural Science/Progress in natural science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400780005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinghe Zhang, Yujie Wang, Jin Zou, Shichao Zhao, Hongbo Hou, Fengmei Zhang, Huaipeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.07.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts: Efficient and Ultrastable Interstitial W&#8208;Doped NiFe&#8208;LDHs/MOFs through Controlled Topological Conversion of Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401909</link>
      <description>Y. W. Bao, Xiongyi Liang, Hao Zhang, Xiuming Bu, Ziyan Cai, Yikai Yang, Di Yin, Yuxuan Zhang, L Chen, Yang Cheng, Xiulan Hu, Xiao Cheng Zeng, Johnny C. Ho, Ding Wang, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400782710

                Abstract Although metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) show promise as electrocatalysts due to their unique intrinsic features, their activity and stability often fall short. Herein, NiFe&#8208;MOFs is used as a model to introduce group VIB metalates (Na 2 WO 4 , Na 2 CrO 4 , and Na 2 MoO 4 ) into the topological conversion process of layer double hydroxide (LDHs)/MOFs, creating a series of interstitial VIB element&#8208;doped LDHs/MOFs catalysts. The metalates engage in the alkaline hydrolysis process of MOF, generating LDHs on the MOF surface. Furthermore, altering the pH value in the reaction environment can modify the catalysts' morphology, dopant/LDHs content, and electronic structure. Consequently, the prepared interstitial W&#8208;doped NiFe&#8208;LDHs/MOFs catalyst displays superior catalytic performance, with overpotentials of only 250 mV at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . Moreover, a homemade anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) system featuring the fabricated electrocatalyst as the anode can operate stably for 500 hours at 1 A cm &#8722;2 . The exceptional catalytic activity and stability stem from optimized intermediate adsorption/desorption behavior and the unique LDHs/MOFs nanostructure. This work not only highlights the potential of the catalysts for practical applications but also offers a new design approach for modulating MOFs using an alkaline hydrolysis strategy.</description>
      <author>Y. W. Bao, Xiongyi Liang, Hao Zhang, Xiuming Bu, Ziyan Cai, Yikai Yang, Di Yin, Yuxuan Zhang, L Chen, Yang Cheng, Xiulan Hu, Xiao Cheng Zeng, Johnny C. Ho, Ding Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401909</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineering and Carbon Supporting to Achieve Ni-Doped CoP3 with High Catalytic Activities for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01471-9</link>
      <description>Daowei Zha, Ruoxing Wang, Shijun Tian, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Zejun Xu, Chu Qin, Xiaoning Tian, Lin Zhao, Nano-micro letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400784939

                Abstract This work reports the use of defect engineering and carbon supporting to achieve metal-doped phosphides with high activities and stabilities for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. Specifically, the nitrogen-doped carbon nanofiber-supported Ni-doped CoP 3 with rich P defects (Pv&#183;) on the carbon cloth (p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC) is synthesized through a plasma-assisted phosphorization method. The p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC is an efficient and stable catalyst for the HER and the OER. It only needs overpotentials of 107 and 306 mV to drive 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for the HER and the OER, respectively. Its catalytic activities are higher than those of other catalysts reported recently. The high activities of the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC mainly arise from its peculiar structural features. The density functional theory calculation indicates that the Pv&#183; richness, the Ni doping, and the carbon supporting can optimize the adsorption of the H atoms at the catalyst surface and promote the strong electronic couplings between the carbon nanofiber-supported p-NiCoP with the surface oxide layer formed during the OER process. This gives the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC with the high activities for the HER and the OER. When used in alkaline water electrolyzers, the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC shows the superior activity and excellent stability for overall water splitting. Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Daowei Zha, Ruoxing Wang, Shijun Tian, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Zejun Xu, Chu Qin, Xiaoning Tian, Lin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01471-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complementary Multisite Turnover Catalysis toward Superefficient Bifunctional Seawater Splitting at Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405852</link>
      <description>Liling Liao, Dongyang Li, Yan Zhang, Yong Zhang, Fang Yu, Lun Yang, Xiuzhang Wang, Dongsheng Tang, Haiqing Zhou, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400789454

                Abstract The utilization of seawater for hydrogen production via water splitting is increasingly recognized as a promising avenue for the future. The key dilemma for seawater electrolysis is the incompatibility of superior hydrogen&#8208; and oxygen&#8208;evolving activities at ampere&#8208;scale current densities for both cathodic and anodic catalysts, thus leading to large electric power consumption of overall seawater splitting. Here, in situ construction of Fe 4 N/Co 3 N/MoO 2 heterostructure arrays anchoring on metallic nickel nitride surface with multilevel collaborative catalytic interfaces and abundant multifunctional metal sites is reported, which serves as a robust bifunctional catalyst for alkaline freshwater/seawater splitting at ampere&#8208;level current density. Operando Raman and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopic studies combined with density functional theory calculations corroborate that Mo and Co/Fe sites situated on the Fe 4 N/Co 3 N/MoO 2 multilevel interfaces optimize the reaction pathway and coordination environment to enhance water adsorption/dissociation, hydrogen adsorption, and oxygen&#8208;containing intermediate adsorption, thus cooperatively expediting hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions in base. Inspiringly, this electrocatalyst can substantially ameliorate overall freshwater/seawater splitting at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 with low cell voltages of 1.65/1.69 V, along with superb long&#8208;term stability at 500&#8211;1500 mA cm &#8722;2 for over 200 h, outperforming nearly all the ever&#8208;reported non&#8208;noble electrocatalysts for freshwater/seawater electrolysis. This work offers a viable approach to design high&#8208;performance bifunctional catalysts for seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>Liling Liao, Dongyang Li, Yan Zhang, Yong Zhang, Fang Yu, Lun Yang, Xiuzhang Wang, Dongsheng Tang, Haiqing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La-induced nanosheet intercalated spheroid hierarchical structure with abundant oxygen vacancy promotes electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00653d</link>
      <description>Di Wang, Jianguo Tang, Wenguang Cui, Chaozheng He, Zhongkui Zhao, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400798723

                The electron coupling effect at the interface, as well as the introduction of oxygen vacancy (Ov), play critical roles in the electrocatalytic activity. The key to lowering the energy barrier...</description>
      <author>Di Wang, Jianguo Tang, Wenguang Cui, Chaozheng He, Zhongkui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00653d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce- and La-doped polymetallic layered double hydroxides for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction performance at high current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-1952-9</link>
      <description>Mukesh Ratnaparkhi, Ping Wang, Miao He, Senyao Meng, Jiasai Yao, Huawei Li, Cuicui Yang, Zhenxing Li, Science China. Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400800404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukesh Ratnaparkhi, Ping Wang, Miao He, Senyao Meng, Jiasai Yao, Huawei Li, Cuicui Yang, Zhenxing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-1952-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering assisted La1-xSrxCoO3/FeOOH heterostructure as a high-performance electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.201</link>
      <description>Juan Yu, Shuai Zhao, Bing Li, Chunyu Zhu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400800503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juan Yu, Shuai Zhao, Bing Li, Chunyu Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and solvation of Key Intermediates of Oxygen Evolution on TiO2, RuO2, IrO2 (110) Surfaces: A Comparative DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400813</link>
      <description>Giovanni Di Liberto, Giovanni Di Liberto, Livia Giordano, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400802784

                Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) is a fundamental process, with gold standards like RuO2 and IrO2. Recently, it was suggested that OER could go through unconventional intermediates, &#8208;O&#8208;H, &#8208;OO&#8208;H. &#8208;O&#8208;H is formed by the direct interaction of an adsorbed O species to a metal surface atom and a proton bound to a surface oxygen. Similarly, in &#8208;OO&#8208;H, an adsorbed &#8208;OO adduct interacts with a proton bound to a surface oxygen. This work compares the nature of key intermediates of OER on TiO2, RuO2, and IrO2(110) surfaces by Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations and Ab&#8208;Initio Molecular Dynamics (AIMD). We rationalized the nature, the relative stability trends in vacuum, the effect of water solvation of the species. &#8208;OO&#8208;H is preferred than &#8208;OOH. &#8208;OH is preferred than &#8208;O&#8208;H except for RuO2. We investigated the nature of the catalyst/water interfaces and the interaction of intermediates with water based on AIMD. On RuO2, &#8208;OH and &#8208;O&#8208;H display a different interaction with water. &#8208;OO&#8208;H is quite rigid on RuO2, while it is dynamic on IrO2 as the proton is shared between &#8208;OO and a surface oxygen atom. This study provides insights on the role of solvation to the nature of OER intermediates, that may help future studies.</description>
      <author>Giovanni Di Liberto, Giovanni Di Liberto, Livia Giordano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large-current polarization-engineered FeOOH@NiOOH electrocatalyst with stable Fe sites for large-current oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60062-8</link>
      <description>Qingyun Lv, Weiwei Zhang, Zhipeng Long, Jiantao Wang, Xingli Zou, Wei Ren, Long Hou, Xionggang Lu, Yufeng Zhao, Yu Xing, Xi Li, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400807136

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingyun Lv, Weiwei Zhang, Zhipeng Long, Jiantao Wang, Xingli Zou, Wei Ren, Long Hou, Xionggang Lu, Yufeng Zhao, Yu Xing, Xi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60062-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immiscible Ruthenium&#8211;Cadmium Alloy for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01412</link>
      <description>Tiantian Yang, Min Wang, Fei-Fei Zhang, Cong Xi, Liyang Xiao, Xueru Zhao, Jiaqi Wang, Weibo Hua, Cunku Dong, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400807961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tiantian Yang, Min Wang, Fei-Fei Zhang, Cong Xi, Liyang Xiao, Xueru Zhao, Jiaqi Wang, Weibo Hua, Cunku Dong, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ fabrication of oxygen deficient Bi2MoO6/InVO4/CeVO4 dual S-scheme ternary heterostructure for robust photocatalytic H2 and H2O2 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104824</link>
      <description>Sibun Kumar Pradhan, Ranjit Bariki, Adarsh Kumar, Swagat Kumar Nayak, Saumyaranjan Panda, Nikhil Kumar Das, Braja Gopal Mishra, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400839387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sibun Kumar Pradhan, Ranjit Bariki, Adarsh Kumar, Swagat Kumar Nayak, Saumyaranjan Panda, Nikhil Kumar Das, Braja Gopal Mishra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase Engineering and Surface Reconstruction of FeNiMo Alloys as High Efficient Electrode for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.07.109</link>
      <description>Si-Cheng Zhong, Jia Li, Zhe Cui, GY Tian, F Zhao, Zhong-Hong Zhou, Hongfei Jiao, Danyang Liu, Jiefu Xiong, Li&#8208;Chen Wang, Jun Xiang, Fufa Wu, Rongda Zhao, Journal of materials research and technology/Journal of Materials Research and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400839752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Si-Cheng Zhong, Jia Li, Zhe Cui, GY Tian, F Zhao, Zhong-Hong Zhou, Hongfei Jiao, Danyang Liu, Jiefu Xiong, Li&#8208;Chen Wang, Jun Xiang, Fufa Wu, Rongda Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.07.109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrocatalytic performance of CoFe hydroxide catalyst by P-doping for oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105664</link>
      <description>Guanming Huang, Yufei Wang, Xiaofeng Ma, Yanpeng Cao, Baogang Wei, Jian He, Wenbo Chen, Feng Ye, Chao Xu, Xiaoze Du, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 163(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400842033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanming Huang, Yufei Wang, Xiaofeng Ma, Yanpeng Cao, Baogang Wei, Jian He, Wenbo Chen, Feng Ye, Chao Xu, Xiaoze Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction over IrO2: Essential Role of Hydronium Cation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409526</link>
      <description>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jingguang G. Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400842354

                The development of active, stable, and more affordable electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is of great importance for the practical application of electrolyzers and the advancement of renewable energy conversion technologies. Currently, IrO2 is the only catalyst with high stability and activity, but a high cost. Further optimization of the catalyst is limited by the lack of understanding of catalytic behaviors at the acid-IrO2 interface. Here, in strong interaction with the experiment, we develop an explicit model based on grand-canonical density function theory (GC-DFT) calculations to describe acidic OER over IrO2. Compared to the explicit models reported previously, hydronium cations (H3O+) are introduced at the electrochemical interface in the current model. As a result, a variation in stable IrO2 surface configuration under the OER operating condition from previously proposed complete *O-coverage to a mixture coverage of *OH and *O is revealed, which is well supported by in situ Raman measurements. In addition, the accuracy of predicted overpotential is increased in comparison with the experimentally measured. More importantly, an alteration of the potential limiting step from previously identified *O &#8594; *OOH to *OH &#8594; *O is observed, which opens new opportunities to advance the IrO2-based catalysts for acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jingguang G. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dual Gain Strategy of Introducing Nickel Doping and Anchoring Amorphous Iron Oxyhydroxide Nanosheets on Zif-67 Achieves an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4900554</link>
      <description>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Gao Y, Shigang Shen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400844039

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Gao Y, Shigang Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4900554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalyst Spinel Oxide Co2GeO4 and Ni2GeO4 with High Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11320-5</link>
      <description>Yanjie Wang, Yumin Guo, Jingjing Wu, H. Y. Liu, Xin Tang, Journal of electronic materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400851289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanjie Wang, Yumin Guo, Jingjing Wu, H. Y. Liu, Xin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11320-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction over IrO2: Essential Role of Hydronium Cation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409526</link>
      <description>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jingguang G. Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400852162

                The development of active, stable, and more affordable electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is of great importance for the practical application of electrolyzers and the advancement of renewable energy conversion technologies. Currently, IrO2 is the only catalyst with high stability and activity, but a high cost. Further optimization of the catalyst is limited by the lack of understanding of catalytic behaviors at the acid&#8208;IrO2 interface. Here, in strong interaction with the experiment, we develop an explicit model based on grand&#8208;canonical density function theory (GC&#8208;DFT) calculations to describe acidic OER over IrO2. Compared to the explicit models reported previously, hydronium cations (H3O+) are introduced at the electrochemical interface in the current model. As a result, a variation in stable IrO2 surface configuration under the OER operating condition from previously proposed complete *O&#8208;coverage to a mixture coverage of *OH and *O is revealed, which is well supported by in situ Raman measurements. In addition, the accuracy of predicted overpotential is increased in comparison with the experimentally measured. More importantly, an alteration of the potential limiting step from previously identified *O &#8594; *OOH to *OH &#8594; *O is observed, which opens new opportunities to advance the IrO2&#8208;based catalysts for acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jingguang G. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed Ru doped on IrOx sub-nano clusters for the enhanced oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01998a</link>
      <description>Yan Dong, Yanle Li, Yichao Lin, Anyang Chen, Mengting Deng, Linjuan Zhang, Zhiyi Lu, Ziqi Tian, Liang Chen, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400854602

                High-performance anodic electrocatalysts are urgently required for proton exchange membrane (PEM)-based water electrolysis. Here, a simple one-step approach is introduced to produce atomically dispersed Ru on iridium oxide (Ru-IrOx) sub-nano...</description>
      <author>Yan Dong, Yanle Li, Yichao Lin, Anyang Chen, Mengting Deng, Linjuan Zhang, Zhiyi Lu, Ziqi Tian, Liang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01998a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photosynthetic performance of the red algae &lt;i&gt;Gracilariopsis lemaneiformis&lt;/i&gt; under high seawater &lt;scp&gt;pH&lt;/scp&gt;: Excess reactive oxygen production due to carbon limitation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/php.13968</link>
      <description>Hongjun Xu, Tong Pang, Litao Zhang, Jianguo Liu, Photochemistry and photobiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400856154

                Abstract The red algae Gracilariopsis lemaneiformis is extensively cultivated at high densities, leading to significant increases in regional seawater pH due to its photosynthetic removal of inorganic carbon. We conducted a study on G. lemaneiformis cultured under various pH conditions (normal pH, pH 9.3, and pH 9.6) and light levels (dark and 100 &#956;mol photons m &#8722;2 s &#8722;1 ) to investigate how high pH seawater environments affect the metabolic processes of G. lemaneiformis . The high pH did not directly damage the photosynthetic light reactions or the Calvin cycle. Instead, the observed reduction in photosynthetic rates was primarily due to CO 2 limitation. However, under illuminated conditions, a high pH environment leads to a decrease in electron transport efficiency (ETo/RC) and reaction center density (RC/CSo), while simultaneously increasing the levels of hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ), malondialdehyde (MDA), and the activity of antioxidant enzymes. Under illuminated conditions, the limitation of inhibit the photosynthetic electron transport process, leading to energy imbalance and excessive production of reactive oxygen species, which in turn resulted in lipid peroxidation of the cell membrane. This might be one of the inducing factors responsible for the bleaching in sea&#8208;farmed G. lemaneiformis plants.</description>
      <author>Hongjun Xu, Tong Pang, Litao Zhang, Jianguo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/php.13968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &amp;lt;&#8217;Facile synthesis of CuZrO3@PPY nanohybrid balls embedded 3-dimensional network with synergistic effect for efficient oxygen evolution reaction&#8217;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;[Surfaces and Interfaces Volume 36, February 2023, 102607]&amp;gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104827</link>
      <description>Salma Aman, Soumaya Gouadria, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Abdullah, Rabia Yasmin Khosa, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Mohd Zahid Ansari, Akram Alfantazi, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400858551

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Salma Aman, Soumaya Gouadria, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Abdullah, Rabia Yasmin Khosa, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Mohd Zahid Ansari, Akram Alfantazi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood derived carbon embedded with shell-core CoP@CoFe for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118514</link>
      <description>Kai Li, Ya-Ping Sun, Xiaoguang Zhang, Linzheng Ma, Jinxue Guo, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400858930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Li, Ya-Ping Sun, Xiaoguang Zhang, Linzheng Ma, Jinxue Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles Anchored in Cation-Vacancies NiFe-LDH toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reactions in Green Sustainable Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c02912</link>
      <description>Zhaokun Wang, Li Wang, Liang Chu, Mu Yang, Ge Wang, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400863995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaokun Wang, Li Wang, Liang Chu, Mu Yang, Ge Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c02912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Engineered P-doped MoO3/Ce2Mo4O15 Bimetallic Heterojunction Nanosheet Array for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144747</link>
      <description>Peng Chen, Hengfu Shui, Sheng Wang, Feng&#8208;Cui Shen, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400865829

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Chen, Hengfu Shui, Sheng Wang, Feng&#8208;Cui Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Oxygen Vacancies to tune Cobalt Oxide by Mn doped for High-effective Overall Water-Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109887</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, Fenghua Wei, Yukui Zhang, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400867149

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, Fenghua Wei, Yukui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extremely Active and Robust Ir&#8208;Mn Dual&#8208;Atom Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Oxygen&#8208;Oxygen Radical Coupling Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411014</link>
      <description>Wenbo Liu, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400869068

                A novel Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom electrocatalyst is synthesized by a facile ion&#8208;exchange method by incorporating Ir in SrMnO3, which yields an extremely high activity and stability for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The ion exchange process occurs in a self&#8208;limitation way, which favors the formation of Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom in the IrMnO9 unit. The incorporation of Ir modulates the electronic structure of both Ir and Mn, thereby resulting in a shorter distance of the Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom (2.41 &#197;) than the Mn&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom (2.49 &#197;). The modulated Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom enables the same spin direction O (&#8593;) of the adsorbed *O intermediates, thus facilitating the direct coupling of the two adsorbed *O intermediates to release O2 via the oxygen&#8208;oxygen radical coupling mechanism. Electrochemical tests reveal that the Ir&#8208;SrMnO3 exhibits a superior OER's activity with a low overpotential of 207 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and achieves a mass specific activity of 1100 A gIr&#8208;1 at 1.5 V. The proton&#8208;exchange&#8208;membrane water electrolyzer with the Ir&#8208;SrMnO3 catalyst exhibits a low electrolysis voltage of 1.63 V at 1.0 A cm&#8208;2 and a stable 2000&#8208;h operation with a decay of only 15 &#956;V h&#8208;1 at 0.5 A cm&#8208;2.</description>
      <author>Wenbo Liu, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic NiFe MOF with ultra-thin two-dimensional nanosheet structure effectively accelerates oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01656d</link>
      <description>Jiaqi He, Xin Deng, Wenting Sun, Wenjing Shang, Yongbing Lou, Jinxi Chen, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400787777

                To address the shortage of fossil energy, the development of affordable and efficient non-precious metal catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) from electrocatalytic water splitting is still a crucial challenge....</description>
      <author>Jiaqi He, Xin Deng, Wenting Sun, Wenjing Shang, Yongbing Lou, Jinxi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01656d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances of the catalysts for photoelectrocatalytic oxygen evolution and CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60053-7</link>
      <description>Hongrui Zhu, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Zhijie Zhang, Qi&#8208;Ni Zhan, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Gao&#8208;Ren Li, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806504

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongrui Zhu, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Zhijie Zhang, Qi&#8208;Ni Zhan, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Gao&#8208;Ren Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60053-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extremely Active and Robust Ir&#8208;Mn Dual&#8208;Atom Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Oxygen&#8208;Oxygen Radical Coupling Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411014</link>
      <description>Wenbo Liu, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400869196

                A novel Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom electrocatalyst is synthesized by a facile ion&#8208;exchange method by incorporating Ir in SrMnO3, which yields an extremely high activity and stability for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The ion exchange process occurs in a self&#8208;limitation way, which favors the formation of Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom in the IrMnO9 unit. The incorporation of Ir modulates the electronic structure of both Ir and Mn, thereby resulting in a shorter distance of the Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom (2.41 &#197;) than the Mn&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom (2.49 &#197;). The modulated Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom enables the same spin direction O (&#8593;) of the adsorbed *O intermediates, thus facilitating the direct coupling of the two adsorbed *O intermediates to release O2 via the oxygen&#8208;oxygen radical coupling mechanism. Electrochemical tests reveal that the Ir&#8208;SrMnO3 exhibits a superior OER's activity with a low overpotential of 207 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and achieves a mass specific activity of 1100 A gIr&#8208;1 at 1.5 V. The proton&#8208;exchange&#8208;membrane water electrolyzer with the Ir&#8208;SrMnO3 catalyst exhibits a low electrolysis voltage of 1.63 V at 1.0 A cm&#8208;2 and a stable 2000&#8208;h operation with a decay of only 15 &#956;V h&#8208;1 at 0.5 A cm&#8208;2.</description>
      <author>Wenbo Liu, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition Heterogeneity of Metal Ions Bound at the Oxygen-Evolving Center of Photosystem II in Living Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.biochem.4c00261</link>
      <description>Jimin Wang, Biochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400870406

                Recent resolution advancement of</description>
      <author>Jimin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.biochem.4c00261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous carbon modulated-Quantum Dots NiO for Efficient Oxygen Evolution in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124437</link>
      <description>Benjin Jin, Qian Wang, Jani Sainio, Viktoriia A. Saveleva, Hua Jiang, Junjie Shi, Basit Ali, Antti&#8208;Jussi Kallio, Simo Huotari, Dage Sundholm, Nana Han, Tanja Kallio, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400871939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benjin Jin, Qian Wang, Jani Sainio, Viktoriia A. Saveleva, Hua Jiang, Junjie Shi, Basit Ali, Antti&#8208;Jussi Kallio, Simo Huotari, Dage Sundholm, Nana Han, Tanja Kallio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Doped into Layered Double Hydroxide as Efficient Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901876</link>
      <description>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400872888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Fluffy Sphere-Like Nicocu-Carbonate Hydroxide Based Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Ph Neutral Electrolyte Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902010</link>
      <description>Li Yu, Xiaocai Ma, Qin Liang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400872985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Yu, Xiaocai Ma, Qin Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruo2/Feco2o4 as an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901885</link>
      <description>Jiale Li, Weigang Gu, Dajun Wu, Xuekun Hong, Tao Shi, Bin Qian, Shaohui Xu, Paul K. Chu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400873086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiale Li, Weigang Gu, Dajun Wu, Xuekun Hong, Tao Shi, Bin Qian, Shaohui Xu, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901885</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Realistic Models of the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00171</link>
      <description>Travis E. Jones, Detre Teschner, Simone Piccinin, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400875520

                The electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) supplies the protons and electrons needed to transform renewable electricity into chemicals and fuels. However, the OER is kinetically sluggish; it operates at significant rates only when the applied potential far exceeds the reversible voltage. The origin of this overpotential is hidden in a complex mechanism involving multiple electron transfers and chemical bond making/breaking steps. Our desire to improve catalytic performance has then made mechanistic studies of the OER an area of major scientific inquiry, though the complexity of the reaction has made understanding difficult. While historically, mechanistic studies have relied solely on experiment and phenomenological models, over the past twenty years</description>
      <author>Travis E. Jones, Detre Teschner, Simone Piccinin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir-Doped Core&#8211;Shell Hollow Heterogeneous Nanospindles for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02285</link>
      <description>Wanyu Liang, Yanghanqi Li, Nannan Zhang, Jie Li, Shujin Li, Zhengying Wu, Yukou Du, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400876349

                By utilizing Metal-organic framework (MOF) materials as a base, constructing electrocatalysts with heterogeneous structures offers advantages for catalyzing water splitting. In this study, a hollow heterogeneous nanocatalyst, Ir-MIL-88A@NiFe-LDHs, was prepared by growing a layered double hydroxides (LDHs) shell on MIL-88A substrate. The catalyst shows excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance in a 1.0 M KOH solution, requiring only 217 mV overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Wanyu Liang, Yanghanqi Li, Nannan Zhang, Jie Li, Shujin Li, Zhengying Wu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prochlorococcus marinus responses to light and oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0307549</link>
      <description>Mireille Savoie, Aurora Mattison, Laurel Genge, J. S. Nadeau, Sylwia &#346;liwi&#324;ska&#8208;Wilczewska, Maximilian Berthold, Naaman M. Omar, Ond&#345;ej Pr&#225;&#353;il, Amanda M. Cockshutt, Douglas A. Campbell, PLoS ONE. 19(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400878328

                Prochlorococcus marinus , the smallest picocyanobacterium, comprises multiple clades occupying distinct niches, currently across tropical and sub-tropical oligotrophic ocean regions, including Oxygen Minimum Zones. Ocean warming may open growth-permissive temperatures in new, poleward photic regimes, along with expanded Oxygen Minimum Zones. We used ocean metaproteomic data on current Prochlorococcus marinus niches, to guide testing of Prochlorococcus marinus growth across a matrix of peak irradiances, photoperiods, spectral bands and dissolved oxygen. MED4 from Clade HLI requires greater than 4 h photoperiod, grows at 25 &#956;mol O 2 L -1 and above, and exploits high cumulative diel photon doses. MED4, however, relies upon an alternative oxidase to balance electron transport, which may exclude it from growth under our lowest, 2.5 &#956;mol O 2 L -1 , condition. SS120 from clade LLII/III is restricted to low light under full 250 &#956;mol O 2 L -1 , shows expanded light exploitation under 25 &#956;mol O 2 L -1 , but is excluded from growth under 2.5 &#956;mol O 2 L -1 . Intermediate oxygen suppresses the cost of PSII photoinactivation, and possibly the enzymatic production of H 2 O 2 in SS120, which has limitations on genomic capacity for PSII and DNA repair. MIT9313 from Clade LLIV is restricted to low blue irradiance under 250 &#956;mol O 2 L -1 , but exploits much higher irradiance under red light, or under lower O 2 concentrations, conditions which slow photoinactivation of PSII and production of reactive oxygen species. In warming oceans, range expansions and competition among clades will be governed not only by light levels. Short photoperiods governed by latitude, temperate winters, and depth attenuation of light, will exclude clade HLI (including MED4) from some habitats. In contrast, clade LLII/III (including SS120), and particularly clade LLIV (including MIT9313), may exploit higher light niches nearer the surface, under expanding OMZ conditions, where low O 2 relieves the stresses of oxidation stress and PSII photoinhibition.</description>
      <author>Mireille Savoie, Aurora Mattison, Laurel Genge, J. S. Nadeau, Sylwia &#346;liwi&#324;ska&#8208;Wilczewska, Maximilian Berthold, Naaman M. Omar, Ond&#345;ej Pr&#225;&#353;il, Amanda M. Cockshutt, Douglas A. Campbell</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0307549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure deformation of Ni&#8211;Fe&#8211;Se enables efficient oxygen evolution via RE atoms doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02900-9</link>
      <description>Hong-Rui Zhao, Cheng&#8208;Zong Yuan, Cong&#8208;Hui Li, Wenkai Zhao, Fuling Wu, Xin Lei, Hong Yin, Shufeng Ye, Xiaomeng Zhang, Yunfa Chen, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400878897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong-Rui Zhao, Cheng&#8208;Zong Yuan, Cong&#8208;Hui Li, Wenkai Zhao, Fuling Wu, Xin Lei, Hong Yin, Shufeng Ye, Xiaomeng Zhang, Yunfa Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02900-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic modulation and dual-defect construction of NiMoP/Ni2P heterointerfaces for sustainable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02784-9</link>
      <description>Qingqing Zhang, Yuehang Xu, Derong Duan, Hongbo Su, Tao Wang, Xiaojun Zeng, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400879075

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingqing Zhang, Yuehang Xu, Derong Duan, Hongbo Su, Tao Wang, Xiaojun Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02784-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NANOCARBONS&#8208;BASED TRIFUNCTIONAL ELECTROCATALYSTS FOR OVERALL WATER SPLITTING AND METAL&#8208;AIR BATTERIES: &#8208; METAL&#8208;FREE AND HYBRID ELECTROCATALYSTS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400712</link>
      <description>Viswanathan S. Saji, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400880734

                Trifunctional electrocatalysts, an exciting class of materials that can simultaneously catalyze hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), can significantly enhance the performance and economic viability of electrochemical energy storage and conversion technologies such as water&#8208;splitting electrolyzers, metal&#8208;air batteries, fuel cells and their integrated devices. Such multifunctional electrocatalysts encompass multiple active sites that can simultaneously catalyze two or more different electrochemical reactions and are feasible routes for addressing global energy and environmental challenges. This review accounts for nanocarbons&#8208;based trifunctional electrocatalysts reported for electrolyzers, metal&#8208;air batteries and integrated electrolyzer&#8208;battery systems, providing a practical perspective. Metal&#8208;free and hybrid (hybrids of nanocarbons and transition metals/compounds) trifunctional electrocatalysts are covered. Given the growing importance of green technologies, we discuss biomass&#8208;derived carbon&#8208;based trifunctional electrocatalysts separately. The collective information provided in the review could help researchers derive more effective and durable trifunctional electrocatalysts suitable for commercial use.</description>
      <author>Viswanathan S. Saji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring transition metal hydroxides performance in membrane-free electrolyzer based decoupled water splitting for step-wise production of hydrogen and oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154215</link>
      <description>Subramanian Rajalekshmi, Sakkarapalayam Murugesan Senthil Kumar, Alagarsamy Pandikumar, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subramanian Rajalekshmi, Sakkarapalayam Murugesan Senthil Kumar, Alagarsamy Pandikumar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten, copper and cobalt-single metal atom oxides embedded CeO2-MnO2-rGO nanorods as electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105653</link>
      <description>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Tae Hwan Oh, Yueshuai Wang, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, S. Sadhasivam, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, Madhavan Swaminathan, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 163(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Tae Hwan Oh, Yueshuai Wang, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, S. Sadhasivam, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, Madhavan Swaminathan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105653</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrochemical performance of NbSe2/rGO nanocomposite for oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06431-8</link>
      <description>Arooj Fatima, B. M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, A.M.A. Henaish, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885314

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arooj Fatima, B. M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, A.M.A. Henaish</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06431-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicarbonate is a key regulator but not a substrate for O2 evolution in Photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01111-8</link>
      <description>David J. Vinyard, Govindjee Govindjee, Photosynthesis Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885384

                Abstract Photosystem II (PSII) uses light energy to oxidize water and to reduce plastoquinone in the photosynthetic electron transport chain. O 2 is produced as a byproduct. While most members of the PSII research community agree that O 2 originates from water molecules, alternative hypotheses involving bicarbonate persist in the literature. In this perspective, we provide an overview of the important roles of bicarbonate in regulating PSII activity and assembly. Further, we emphasize that biochemistry, spectroscopy, and structural biology experiments have all failed to detect bicarbonate near the active site of O 2 evolution. While thermodynamic arguments for oxygen-centered bicarbonate oxidation are valid, the claim that bicarbonate is a substrate for photosynthetic O 2 evolution is challenged.</description>
      <author>David J. Vinyard, Govindjee Govindjee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01111-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Temperature Plasma-Constructed Ni-Doped W&lt;sub&gt;18&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;49&lt;/sub&gt; Nanorod Arrays for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution and Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05120</link>
      <description>Qingdong Ruan, Jin&#8208;Yuan Liu, Dan Li, Xiaolin Zhang, Liangliang Liu, Chao Huang, Bin Wang, Paul K. Chu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400886716

                Surface engineering by doping and amorphization is receiving widespread attention from the perspective of the regulation of the electrocatalytic activities of electrocatalysts. However, the effective modulation of active sites on catalysts is still challenging. Herein, a straightforward and efficient method combining hydrothermal treatment with low-temperature plasma processing is presented to synthesize Ni-doped W</description>
      <author>Qingdong Ruan, Jin&#8208;Yuan Liu, Dan Li, Xiaolin Zhang, Liangliang Liu, Chao Huang, Bin Wang, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Superior Bifunctional Electrocatalyst in Which Directional Electron Transfer Occurs Between a Co/Ni Alloy and Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401730</link>
      <description>Ziyi Xu, Shihao Wang, Wenmao Tu, Ling Shen, Wu Lu, Shilong Xu, Yong Qiu, Hongfei Pan, Xiaoyu Yang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400891163

                Abstract Stable, efficient, and economical bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are needed for rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries. In this study, a directional electron transfer pathway is exploited in a spatial heterojunction of Co y Ni x @Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C heterogeneous catalyst for effective bifunctional electrolysis (OER/ORR). Thereinto, the Co/Ni alloy is strongly coupled to the Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C support through Co/Ni&#9472;N bonds. DFT calculations and experimental findings confirm that Co/Ni&#9472;N bonds play a bridging role in the directional electron transfer from Co/Ni alloy to the Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C support, increasing the content of pyridinic nitrogen in the ORR&#8208;active support. In addition, the discovered directional electron transfer mechanism enhances both the ORR/OER activity and the durability of the catalyst. The Co 0.66 Ni 0.34 @Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C with the optimal Ni/Co ratio exhibits satisfying bifunctional electrocatalytic performance, requiring an ORR half&#8208;wave potential of 0.90 V and an OER overpotential of 317 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline electrolytes. The assembled rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) incorporating Co 0.66 Ni 0.34 @Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C cathode exhibits a charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap comparable to the Pt/C||IrO 2 assembly and high robustness for over 60 h at 20 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Ziyi Xu, Shihao Wang, Wenmao Tu, Ling Shen, Wu Lu, Shilong Xu, Yong Qiu, Hongfei Pan, Xiaoyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Evolution Reaction Promoted by Iron and Brass Under Alkaline Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01262</link>
      <description>Meysam Maazallahi, Subhajit Nandy, P. Aleshkevych, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400891252

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meysam Maazallahi, Subhajit Nandy, P. Aleshkevych, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating &lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;OOH Adsorption on RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Efficient and Durable Acidic Water Oxidation Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404092</link>
      <description>Tingting Yin, Mengying Yang, Meng Tian, Wei Wang, Guigao Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400891281

                Abstract Acidic water electrolysis is of considerable interest due to its higher current density operation and energy conversion efficiency, but its real industrial application is highly limited by the shortage of efficient, stable, and cost&#8208;effective acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. Here, an electrocatalyst consisting of Ni&#8208;implanted RuO 2 supported is reported on &#945;&#8208;MnO 2 (MnO 2 /RuO 2 &#8208;Ni) that shows high activity and remarkable durability in acidic OER. Precisely, the MnO 2 /RuO 2 &#8208;Ni catalyst shows an overpotential of 198 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and can operate continuously and stably for 400 h (j = 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) without any obvious attenuation of activity, making it one of the best&#8208;performing acid&#8208;stable OER catalysts. Experimental results, in conjunction with density functional theory calculations, demonstrate that the interface electron transfer effect from RuO 2 to MnO 2 , further enhanced by Ni incorporation, effectively modulates the adsorption of OOH * and significantly reduces the overpotential, thereby enhancing catalytic activity and durability.</description>
      <author>Tingting Yin, Mengying Yang, Meng Tian, Wei Wang, Guigao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonized Wood Plate Decorated with a N-Doped Carbon Nanomushroom Encapsulating FeNiS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/(Co, Ni, Fe)&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; Heteroparticle for Efficiently Catalyzing Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01295</link>
      <description>Yuntang Zhuang, Sheng Wang, Guihua Yang, Zhengjun Shi, Shouxin Zhang, Ming He, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400891365

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuntang Zhuang, Sheng Wang, Guihua Yang, Zhengjun Shi, Shouxin Zhang, Ming He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Reconstruction of a Cobalt- and Ferrocene-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework during the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03262</link>
      <description>Thomas Doughty, Andrea Zingl, Maximilian W&#252;nschek, Christian M. Pichler, Matthew B. Watkins, Souvik Roy, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400899320

                Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) are increasingly being investigated as electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their unique modular structures that present a hybrid between molecular and heterogeneous catalysts, featuring well-defined active sites. However, many fundamental questions remain open regarding the electrochemical stability of MOFs, structural reconstruction of coordination sites, and the role of</description>
      <author>Thomas Doughty, Andrea Zingl, Maximilian W&#252;nschek, Christian M. Pichler, Matthew B. Watkins, Souvik Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction catalysis with polythiophene-based composite electrodes incorporating NiCo-LDH and NiCo2S4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.226</link>
      <description>Rahadian Zainul, Ali Basem, Dheyaa J. Jasim, Subhash Chandra, Julio Cesar L&#243;pez Ayala, Mohammed Al&#8208;Bahrani, Nizomiddin Juraev, Mamata Chahar, Yasser Elmasry, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 81(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400900759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahadian Zainul, Ali Basem, Dheyaa J. Jasim, Subhash Chandra, Julio Cesar L&#243;pez Ayala, Mohammed Al&#8208;Bahrani, Nizomiddin Juraev, Mamata Chahar, Yasser Elmasry</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two&#8208;Dimensional MXene&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts: Challenges and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400047</link>
      <description>Muhammad Kaleem Shabbir, Fozia Arif, Haleema Asghar, Sanam Irum Memon, Urooj Khanum, Javeed Akhtar, Akbar Ali, Zeeshan Ramzan, Abdul Aziz Abdul Raman, Ayaz Ali Memon, Khalid Hussain Thebo, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400901939

                Abstract MXene, regarded as cutting&#8208;edge two&#8208;dimensional (2D) materials, have been widely explored in various applications due to their remarkable flexibility, high specific surface area, good mechanical strength, and interesting electrical conductivity. Recently, 2D MXene has served as a ideal platform for the design and development of electrocatalysts with high activity, selectivity, and stability. This review article provides a detailed description of the structural engineering of MXene&#8208;based electrocatalysts and summarizes the uses of 2D MXene in hydrogen evolution reactions, nitrogen reduction reactions, oxygen evolution reactions, oxygen reduction reactions, and methanol/ethanol oxidation. Then, key issues and prospects for 2D MXene as a next&#8208;generation platform in fundamental research and real&#8208;world electrocatalysis applications are discussed. Emphasis will be given to material design and enhancement techniques. Finally, future research directions are suggested to improve the efficiency of MXene&#8208;based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Kaleem Shabbir, Fozia Arif, Haleema Asghar, Sanam Irum Memon, Urooj Khanum, Javeed Akhtar, Akbar Ali, Zeeshan Ramzan, Abdul Aziz Abdul Raman, Ayaz Ali Memon, Khalid Hussain Thebo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoNi alloy catalyzed N-doped carbon nanotube-anchored CoMn2O4 as highly efficient oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112976</link>
      <description>Zhe Xiong, Zheng Zhang, Xiaoxue Jiang, Yan Li, Cuiqin Li, Keliang Wang, Journal of Energy Storage. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400904179

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhe Xiong, Zheng Zhang, Xiaoxue Jiang, Yan Li, Cuiqin Li, Keliang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112976</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Facets&#8208;Activity Correlation for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Compositional Complex Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202404095</link>
      <description>Hongwei Zhao, J.Q. Yao, Ya&#8208;Song Wang, Gao Niu, Tao Zhang, Li Li, Yuyao Liu, Zheng&#8208;Jie Chen, Jing Peng, Xinwang Liu, Hai&#8208;Bin Yu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400905267

                Compositional complex alloys, including high and medium-entropy alloys (HEAs/MEAs) have displayed significant potential as efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), but their structure-activity relationship remains unclear. In particular, the basic question of which crystal facets are more active, especially considering the surface reconstructions, has yet to be answered. This study demonstrates that the lowest index {100} facets of FeCoNiCr MEAs exhibit the highest activity. The underlying mechanism associated with the {100} facet's low in-plane density, making it easier to surface reconstruction and form amorphous structures containing the true active species is uncovered. These results are validated by experiments on single crystals and polycrystal MEAs, as well as DFT calculations. The discoveries contribute to a fundamental comprehension of MEAs in electrocatalysis and offer physics-based strategies for developing electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongwei Zhao, J.Q. Yao, Ya&#8208;Song Wang, Gao Niu, Tao Zhang, Li Li, Yuyao Liu, Zheng&#8208;Jie Chen, Jing Peng, Xinwang Liu, Hai&#8208;Bin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202404095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilot Study on the Production of Negative Oxygen Ions Based on Lower Voltage Ionization Method and Application in Air Purification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15070860</link>
      <description>Haotian Weng, Yao-Zhong Zhang, Xiaolu Huang, Xuan Liu, Yunhui Tang, Hewei Yuan, Xu Yang, Kun Li, Yafei Zhang, Atmosphere. 15(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400905982

                In the current highly industrialized living environment, air quality has become an increasing public health concern. Natural environments like forests have excellent air quality due to high concentrations of negative oxygen ions originating from low-voltage ionization, without harmful ozone. Traditional negative oxygen ion generators require high voltage for corona discharge to produce ions. However, high voltage can increase electron collisions and excitations, leading to more dissociation and recombination of oxygen molecules and consequently higher ozone production. To address the challenge of generating negative oxygen ions without accompanying ozone production, this study designed and constructed a low-voltage negative oxygen ion generator based on nanometer-tip carbon fiber electrodes. The advantage of this device lies in the high curvature radius of carbon fibers, which provides high local electric field strength. This allows for efficient production of negative oxygen ions at low operating voltages without generating ozone. Experiments demonstrated that the device can efficiently generate negative oxygen ions at a working voltage as low as 2.16 kV, 28% lower than the lowest voltage reported in similar studies. The purification device manufactured in this study had a total decay constant for PM2.5 purification of 0.8967 min&#8722;1 within five minutes, compared to a natural decay constant of only 0.0438 min&#8722;1, resulting in a calculated Clean Air Delivery Rate (CADR) of 0.1535 m3/min. Within half an hour, concentrations of PM2.5, PM1, PM10, formaldehyde, and TVOC were reduced by 99.09%, 99.40%, 99.37%, 94.39%, and 99.35%, respectively, demonstrating good decay constants and CADR. These findings confirm its effectiveness in improving indoor air quality, highlighting its significant application value in air purification.</description>
      <author>Haotian Weng, Yao-Zhong Zhang, Xiaolu Huang, Xuan Liu, Yunhui Tang, Hewei Yuan, Xu Yang, Kun Li, Yafei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15070860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural engineering evoked multifunctionality in molybdate nanosheets for industrial oxygen evolution and dual energy storage devices inspired by multi-method calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.128</link>
      <description>Mengru Huang, Haiyu Yao, Feng Cao, Peijie Wang, Xue&#8208;Rong Shi, Min Zhang, Shusheng Xu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 676(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400906452

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengru Huang, Haiyu Yao, Feng Cao, Peijie Wang, Xue&#8208;Rong Shi, Min Zhang, Shusheng Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Nanoporous NiMn oxide Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction through Defect Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02679a</link>
      <description>Arpit Thomas, Ambrish Kumar, Ram K. Sharma, Edgar C. Buck, Bharat Gwalani, Meha Bhogra, Harpreet Singh Arora, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400913184

                The sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a major bottleneck in hydrogen generation through electrolysis, particularly at large current operations. Thus, there is a huge interest in the development of...</description>
      <author>Arpit Thomas, Ambrish Kumar, Ram K. Sharma, Edgar C. Buck, Bharat Gwalani, Meha Bhogra, Harpreet Singh Arora</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02679a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of morphology and charge transfer mechanism: Oxygen vacancy-rich Mn0.2Cd0.8S/CoMoO4 S-type heterojunction promoting photocatalytic hydrogen production through hydrothermal in-situ synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175692</link>
      <description>Yan Shang, Jing Xu, Jia Li, Mingxia Zheng, Xutao Ning, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400913998

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Shang, Jing Xu, Jia Li, Mingxia Zheng, Xutao Ning</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnesium-promoted rapid self-reconstruction of NiFe-based electrocatalysts toward efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.183</link>
      <description>Boxuan Jin, Wenwen Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Kai Zhang, Li Wang, Guihua Liu, Jingde Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400914862

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boxuan Jin, Wenwen Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Kai Zhang, Li Wang, Guihua Liu, Jingde Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State-of-the-Art In Situ Technologies for Unravelling the Dynamic Structure Evolution during Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03623</link>
      <description>Qinglei Meng, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, Jianbing Zhu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400915861

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qinglei Meng, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, Jianbing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering multicomponent alloys with unique nanostructure for exceptional oxygen evolution performance through self-replenishment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.023</link>
      <description>Zhibin Li, Ruoyu Wu, Dabo Duan, Xiongjun Liu, Rui Li, Jing Wang, Houwen Chen, Shiwei Chen, Yuan Wu, Hai Wang, Suihe Jiang, Xiaobin Zhang, Xiongjun Liu, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400916666

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhibin Li, Ruoyu Wu, Dabo Duan, Xiongjun Liu, Rui Li, Jing Wang, Houwen Chen, Shiwei Chen, Yuan Wu, Hai Wang, Suihe Jiang, Xiaobin Zhang, Xiongjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Morphology and Oxygen Vacancy Content in Ni, Fe co-doped Ceria for Efficient Electrocatalyst Based Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00500g</link>
      <description>Abhaya Kumar Mishra, Joshua Willoughby, Shanna L. Estes, Kelliann Koehler, Kyle S. Brinkman, Nanoscale Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400917039

                Designing a highly efficient, low-cost, sustainable electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) through water splitting is a current challenge for renewable energy technologies. This...</description>
      <author>Abhaya Kumar Mishra, Joshua Willoughby, Shanna L. Estes, Kelliann Koehler, Kyle S. Brinkman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00500g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Metal-Oxygen Covalency of Tio2 by Ru Doping and Phase Transition for Boosted Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902818</link>
      <description>Fengting Li, Nannan Cui, Yanan Zhou, Shuangqing Sun, Chunling Li, Zhikun Wang, Songqing Hu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400917844

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengting Li, Nannan Cui, Yanan Zhou, Shuangqing Sun, Chunling Li, Zhikun Wang, Songqing Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly(3&#8208;hexylthiophene) film coated on plastic substrate as an organic photoanode for water oxidation/oxygen evolution with light illumination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pat.6524</link>
      <description>H. Shinohara, Hiroyuki Nishide, Polymers for Advanced Technologies. 35(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400921986

                Abstract Poly(3&#8208;hexylthiophene) (P3HT) film was applied as a photoanode on an electron&#8208;extracting layer&#8208;coated upon a current&#8208;collecting plastic substrate. The film soaked in an aqueous solution (pH 12) exhibited an enhanced anodic current with light illumination, and the photocurrent density ( J ) reached almost 100 &#956;A/cm 2 for its wound cylinder, which was accompanied by oxygen bubble evolution. The light ON/OFF response, light&#8208;intensity proportion, and wavelength&#8208;dependency of the J value supported the photo&#8208;electrolytic function of the P3HT film. The hole&#8208;injection efficiency of the film estimated for water oxidation using a solution involving a sacrificial reagent, was relatively high in the range of 46%&#8211;86%. Although an apparent activation energy of 39 kJ/mol for the electrolytic water oxidation in the dark suggested a chemical but catalytic pathway for the film anode, the temperature independence of the photocurrent indicated direct hole&#8208;injection into water or hydroxide ions. The photoanode performance of the P3HT film for water oxidation was discussed in relation to the energy diagram including the highest occupied molecular orbital level.</description>
      <author>H. Shinohara, Hiroyuki Nishide</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pat.6524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Crystalline Cobalt Iron Oxide-Supported Single Ru Atoms and Ru Clusters for 2,5-Hydroxymethylfurfural Electro-Oxidation Coupled with Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03806</link>
      <description>Shasha Cui, Fen Wang, Guangjin Wang, Tingting Li, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400925789

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shasha Cui, Fen Wang, Guangjin Wang, Tingting Li, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insulator&#8208;transition&#8208;induced Degradation of Pyrochlore Ruthenates in Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution and Stabilization through Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412139</link>
      <description>Haibo Liu, Hengyu Guo, Qingren Zhang, Masatsugu Fujishige, Morinobu Endo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400930376

                Ru&#8208;based pyrochlores (e.g., Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d) are promised to replace IrO2 in polymer electrolyte membrane (PEM) electrolyzers. It is significant to reveal the cliff attenuation on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of these pyrochlores. In this work, we monitor the structure changes and electrochemical behavior of Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d over the OER process, and it is found that the reason of decisive OER inactivation is derived from an insulator transition occurred within Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d due to its inner &#178;perfecting&#178; lattice induced by continuous atom rearrangement. Therefore, a stabilization strategy of the Ir&#8208;substituted Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d is proposed to alleviate this undesirable behavior. The double&#8208;exchange interaction between Ru and Ir in [RuO6] and [IrO6] octahedra leads the charge redistribution with simultaneous spin configuration adjustment. The electronic state in newly formed octahedrons centered with Ru 4d3 (with the state of eg'2&#173;&#173;a1g&#173;1 eg0) and Ir 5d6 (eg'4a1g&#173;2 eg0) relieves the uneven electron distributions in [RuO6] orbital. The attenuated Jahn&#8208;Teller effect alleviates atom rearrangement, represented as the mitigation of insulator transition, surface reconstruction, and metal dissolution. As results, the Ir&#8208;substituted Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d presents the greatly improved OER stability and PEM durability. This study unveils the OER degradation mechanism and stabilization strategy for material design of Ru&#8208;based OER catalysts for electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Haibo Liu, Hengyu Guo, Qingren Zhang, Masatsugu Fujishige, Morinobu Endo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insulator&#8208;transition&#8208;induced Degradation of Pyrochlore Ruthenates in Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution and Stabilization through Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412139</link>
      <description>Haibo Liu, Hengyu Guo, Qingren Zhang, Masatsugu Fujishige, Morinobu Endo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400930451

                Ru&#8208;based pyrochlores (e.g., Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d) are promised to replace IrO2 in polymer electrolyte membrane (PEM) electrolyzers. It is significant to reveal the cliff attenuation on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of these pyrochlores. In this work, we monitor the structure changes and electrochemical behavior of Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d over the OER process, and it is found that the reason of decisive OER inactivation is derived from an insulator transition occurred within Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d due to its inner &#178;perfecting&#178; lattice induced by continuous atom rearrangement. Therefore, a stabilization strategy of the Ir&#8208;substituted Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d is proposed to alleviate this undesirable behavior. The double&#8208;exchange interaction between Ru and Ir in [RuO6] and [IrO6] octahedra leads the charge redistribution with simultaneous spin configuration adjustment. The electronic state in newly formed octahedrons centered with Ru 4d3 (with the state of eg'2&#173;&#173;a1g&#173;1 eg0) and Ir 5d6 (eg'4a1g&#173;2 eg0) relieves the uneven electron distributions in [RuO6] orbital. The attenuated Jahn&#8208;Teller effect alleviates atom rearrangement, represented as the mitigation of insulator transition, surface reconstruction, and metal dissolution. As results, the Ir&#8208;substituted Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d presents the greatly improved OER stability and PEM durability. This study unveils the OER degradation mechanism and stabilization strategy for material design of Ru&#8208;based OER catalysts for electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Haibo Liu, Hengyu Guo, Qingren Zhang, Masatsugu Fujishige, Morinobu Endo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Ni-Doped Dual Mof-Derived Urchin-Like Co-Fe Layered Double Hydroxides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902826</link>
      <description>Zikang Tang, Ningzhao Shang, Mingjie Hu, Huan Wang, Yufan Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400932947

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zikang Tang, Ningzhao Shang, Mingjie Hu, Huan Wang, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Transition Metals (Mn, Co, Ni, and Zn) in Size-Controlled Metal Ferrite Nanocrystals on the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03007</link>
      <description>Vijayakrishnan Jeyavani, Shanmugasundaram Manoj, Shatabdi Porel Mukherjee, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400935288

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vijayakrishnan Jeyavani, Shanmugasundaram Manoj, Shatabdi Porel Mukherjee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe,Ce Co&#8208;Doped Ni3S2/NiS Polymorphism Nanosheets with Improved Electrocatalytic Activity and Stability for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400896</link>
      <description>Shaoxia Wang, Huihui Li, Shifeng Li, Yonghong Ni, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400936838

                Balancing the relationship between electrocatalytic activity and stability of sulfide catalysts during oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been attracting extensive research interest. Here, a simple electrodeposition&#8208;vulcanization two&#8208;step route was designed to successfully construct nickel foam supported sheet&#8208;like Fe,Ce&#8208;codoped Ni3S2/NiS polymorphism catalyst (labeled as Fe,Ce&#8208;Ni3S2/NiS/NF). Electrochemical measurements showed that the as&#8208;obtained Fe,Ce&#8208;Ni3S2/NiS/NF electrode presented excellent OER electrocatalytic performances. In 1 M KOH solution, merely 173 and 234 mV of overpotentials were required to deliver the current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8208;2, respectively. Further investigations revealed that the Fe,Ce co&#8208;doping regulated the electron density around Ni, which promoted the conversion of Ni towards the higher valence state and simultaneously, avoided the stability decrease of the catalyst caused by excessive oxidation corrosion. Moreover, the defects generated during vulcanization also contributed to promoting water oxidation. The present work provides a facile and feasible approach to balance the relationship between the stability and the activity of sulfide catalysts for OER.</description>
      <author>Shaoxia Wang, Huihui Li, Shifeng Li, Yonghong Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400896</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen deficient BaTiO3 loading sub-nm PtOx for photocatalytic biological wastewater splitting to green hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154261</link>
      <description>Guilin Chen, Yujin Ji, Xintong Shi, Pengfei An, Jing Zhang, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400942716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guilin Chen, Yujin Ji, Xintong Shi, Pengfei An, Jing Zhang, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Hydrogel with Immobilized Mn-Porphyrin for Reactive Oxygen Species Scavenging, Oxygen Generation, and Risedronate Delivery in Bone Defect Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08350</link>
      <description>Kim M, Soo Bin Yoon, Han Bi Ji, Cho Rim Kim, Jae Hoon Han, Sena Kim, Chang Hee Min, Chul Lee, Lan Sook Chang, Young Bin Choy, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400948237

                We propose a hydrogel immobilized with manganese porphyrin (MnP), a biomimetic superoxide dismutase (SOD), and catalase (CAT) to modulate reactive oxygen species (ROS) and hypoxia that impede the repair of large bone defects. Our hydrogel synthesis involved thiolated chitosan and polyethylene glycol-maleimide conjugated with MnPs (MnP-PEG-MAL), which enabled</description>
      <author>Kim M, Soo Bin Yoon, Han Bi Ji, Cho Rim Kim, Jae Hoon Han, Sena Kim, Chang Hee Min, Chul Lee, Lan Sook Chang, Young Bin Choy</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium oxide supported molybdenum-nickel-iron oxide electrocatalyst for efficient and durable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132509</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Xiangchao Meng, Haisheng Han, Guihua Liu, Fuel. 375(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400952027

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Xiangchao Meng, Haisheng Han, Guihua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Efficiency Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Effect of Phosphorus Doped on the Surface Reconstruction of High-Entropy Spinel Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175696</link>
      <description>Ziming Bai, Ghulam Mustafa, Zhe Zhang, Changgong Meng, Yuzhen Pan, Zhen Chen, Wei Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400953696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziming Bai, Ghulam Mustafa, Zhe Zhang, Changgong Meng, Yuzhen Pan, Zhen Chen, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cofe-Ldhs Were Grown on Co-Layered Hydroxides to Achieve 3d-Hierarchical Flower Like Architecture for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4903722</link>
      <description>Haibo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Gao Y, Huan Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400966452

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Gao Y, Huan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4903722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting oxygen evolution with amine-induced reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132545</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhou, Wei Zi, Ziliang Kang, Hina Naz, Yashu Liu, Zhenyuan Ji, Guoxing Zhu, Fuel. 374(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400849006

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhou, Wei Zi, Ziliang Kang, Hina Naz, Yashu Liu, Zhenyuan Ji, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/crystalline AgS@CoS core@shell catalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110275</link>
      <description>Yangping Zhang, Tianpeng Liu, Jun Yu, Zhengying Wu, Dongqiong Wang, Yukou Du, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400843962

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yangping Zhang, Tianpeng Liu, Jun Yu, Zhengying Wu, Dongqiong Wang, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quenching controlled spin exchange interactions and spin selective electron transfer for oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154216</link>
      <description>Zhihan Gao, Jinhua Liu, Shuaijie Wang, Wen-Cai Lu, Wenyue Wang, Lingyun Li, Hui Guo, Jie Zheng, Seeram Ramakrishna, Shouxin Zhang, Jing Wang, Yun&#8208;Ze Long, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhihan Gao, Jinhua Liu, Shuaijie Wang, Wen-Cai Lu, Wenyue Wang, Lingyun Li, Hui Guo, Jie Zheng, Seeram Ramakrishna, Shouxin Zhang, Jing Wang, Yun&#8208;Ze Long</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-by-step enhancing oxygen evolution ability of CoFe2O4 by hybrid structure engineering and fluorine doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154211</link>
      <description>Yi&#8208;Gang Ji, Jiawei Wu, Huan Wen, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi&#8208;Gang Ji, Jiawei Wu, Huan Wen, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zipper&#8208;Like Interlocked Heterostructure of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide&#8208;WN for Super&#8208;Stable Oxygen Evolution over 4500 h</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409559</link>
      <description>Minghui Xing, Zelong Qiao, Shaoke Zhu, Gaohong Xu, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881423

                Abstract The nickel&#8208;iron based materials are widely studied as excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. However, its relatively poor OER stability limits its practical applications. Herein, a zipper&#8208;like interlocked heterostructure of NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH)&#8208;WN is constructed. The NiFe LDH&#8208;WN exhibits not only ultrahigh OER activity of 228 mV overpotential at a current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 , but also extremely long&#8208;term stability over 4500 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 and over 550 h at an industrial current density &#8776;350 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is ascribed to its special zipper&#8208;like interlocked structure. Moreover, in situ Raman confirms that the presence of WN can efficiently achieve NiFe LDH reconstruction to slower the metal dissolution during OER, and therefore boosts its stability. DFT calculations reveal that WN not only can increase the *O adsorption capability and conductivity of NiFe LDH layer, but also can anchor the metal atoms of NiFe LDH layer to improve the dissolution energy barrier. In short, this work presents a new method of constructing the interlocked heterostructure to improve the OER stability of Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;based catalysts, which would accelerate its practical application.</description>
      <author>Minghui Xing, Zelong Qiao, Shaoke Zhu, Gaohong Xu, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of 3d-Network Structure Based on Sepiolite Loaded Mn2coo4 Aerogel Powder and its Oxygen Evolution Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902235</link>
      <description>Rui Xu, Tianlei Wang, Xiudang Jing, Y Chen, Lei Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400898278

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Xu, Tianlei Wang, Xiudang Jing, Y Chen, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction activity of carbon aerogel supported Pd&#8211;Ni&#8211;Al catalysts synthesized by microwave irradiation method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.287</link>
      <description>A.M.P. Hussain, Muhammad Asim, Meryem Samanc&#305;, Naveed Kausar Janjua, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 81(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400900496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A.M.P. Hussain, Muhammad Asim, Meryem Samanc&#305;, Naveed Kausar Janjua, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonized wood fiber-supported S, N-codoped carbon layer-coated multinary metal sulfide nanoarchitecture for efficient oxygen evolution reaction at ampere-level current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.178</link>
      <description>Ying Wu, Hongwei Liao, Sha Chen, Jianjie Cao, Wanjuan Zeng, Yuanyuan Liao, Yan Qing, Han Xu, Yiqiang Wu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400871849

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Wu, Hongwei Liao, Sha Chen, Jianjie Cao, Wanjuan Zeng, Yuanyuan Liao, Yan Qing, Han Xu, Yiqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the origins and evolution of oxygenic and anoxygenic photosynthesis in deeply branched Cyanobacteriota.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msae151</link>
      <description>Sha Tan, Lan Liu, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Mengmeng Li, Chao-Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yanling Qi, Yuxian Li, Yang-Zhi Rao, Yan-Ni Qu, Hongchen Jiang, Rochelle M. Soo, Paul N. Evans, Zheng-Shuang Hua, Wenjun Li, PubMed. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400932417

                Cyanobacteriota, the sole prokaryotes capable of oxygenic photosynthesis (OxyP), occupy a unique and pivotal role in Earth's history. While the notion that OxyP may have originated from Cyanobacteriota is widely accepted, its early evolution remains elusive. Here, by using both metagenomics and metatranscriptomics, we explore 36 metagenome-assembled genomes (MAGs) from hot spring ecosystems, belonging to two deep-branching cyanobacterial orders: Thermostichales and Gloeomargaritales. Functional investigation reveals that Thermostichales encode the crucial thylakoid membrane biogenesis protein, Vipp1. Based on the phylogenetic results, we infer that the evolution of the thylakoid membrane predates the divergence of Thermostichales from other cyanobacterial groups and that Thermostichales may be the most ancient lineage known to date to have inherited this feature from their common ancestor. Apart from OxyP, both lineages are potentially capable of sulfide-driven anoxygenic photosynthesis (AnoxyP) by linking sulfide oxidation to the photosynthetic electron transport chain. Unexpectedly, this AnoxyP capacity appears to be an acquired feature, as the key gene sqr was horizontally transferred from later-evolved cyanobacterial lineages. The presence of two D1 protein variants in Thermostichales suggests the functional flexibility of photosystems, ensuring their survival in fluctuating redox environments. Furthermore, all MAGs feature streamlined phycobilisomes with a preference for capturing longer-wavelength light, implying a unique evolutionary trajectory. Collectively, these results reveal the photosynthetic flexibility in these early-diverging cyanobacterial lineages, shedding new light on the early evolution of Cyanobacteriota and their photosynthetic processes.</description>
      <author>Sha Tan, Lan Liu, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Mengmeng Li, Chao-Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yanling Qi, Yuxian Li, Yang-Zhi Rao, Yan-Ni Qu, Hongchen Jiang, Rochelle M. Soo, Paul N. Evans, Zheng-Shuang Hua, Wenjun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msae151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural evolution and electronic properties of anionic plutonium-doped oxygen clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141484</link>
      <description>Zaifu Jiang, Peixin Fu, Siyu Jin, Panlong Kong, Panlong Kong, Wei Dai, Haiyan Lu, Cheng L&#252;, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400859860

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zaifu Jiang, Peixin Fu, Siyu Jin, Panlong Kong, Panlong Kong, Wei Dai, Haiyan Lu, Cheng L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A nanocoral like carbon composite based on dual-MOFs for catalytic reduction and evolution of oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102213</link>
      <description>Junyuan Zhang, Wei Liu, Linfeng Liang, Ziwei Deng, Changyu Liu, Xiaolong Xu, Jianbo Jia, Materials Today Chemistry. 40(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400966451

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junyuan Zhang, Wei Liu, Linfeng Liang, Ziwei Deng, Changyu Liu, Xiaolong Xu, Jianbo Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-organic frameworks-engineered reactive-oxygen catalytic materials: Enzyme-mimicking coordinations, structure evolutions, and biotherapeutic applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.06.017</link>
      <description>Fuzhen Li, Qinlong Wen, Li Wang, Sutong Xiao, Yang Gao, Mao Wang, Xiaohui Xu, Lang Ma, Qian Li, Materials today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400857927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuzhen Li, Qinlong Wen, Li Wang, Sutong Xiao, Yang Gao, Mao Wang, Xiaohui Xu, Lang Ma, Qian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.06.017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT and machine learning studies on a multi-functional single-atom catalyst for enhanced oxygen and hydrogen evolution as well as CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.244</link>
      <description>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-Zn single atoms anchored carbon nanotubes derived from anti-perovskite carbides for boosted hydrogen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154255</link>
      <description>Liangliang Feng, Mengfei Zhou, Danyang He, Hongyan Yin, Yixuan Huang, Liyun Cao, Yuan Fang, Dewei Chu, Yipu Liu, Hui Chen, Guodong Li, Jianfeng Huang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400934242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liangliang Feng, Mengfei Zhou, Danyang He, Hongyan Yin, Yixuan Huang, Liyun Cao, Yuan Fang, Dewei Chu, Yipu Liu, Hui Chen, Guodong Li, Jianfeng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial decoupling strategy boosted alkaline hydrogen evolution for an efficient solar-driven AEM electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03872j</link>
      <description>Minghui Cui, Yansong Zhou, Rongjing Guo, Wenqi Zhao, Ying Liu, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400907575

                Substrate modification achieves spatial decoupling of the oxygen evolution reaction process, thereby greatly improving the efficiency and stability of the catalyst.</description>
      <author>Minghui Cui, Yansong Zhou, Rongjing Guo, Wenqi Zhao, Ying Liu, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03872j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4f&#8211;2p&#8211;3d Orbital Coupling in Ce&#8211;Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Enhancing the Urea Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02111</link>
      <description>Wei Zheng, Niangao Duan, Yang Yang, Peichen Wang, Yafei Qu, Cichang Zong, Qianwang Chen, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400882057

                The electrocatalytic urea oxidation reaction (UOR) provides a promising alternative to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for various renewable energy-related systems owing to its lower thermodynamic barriers. However, its optimization and commercial utilization were hampered due to a lack of mechanistic understanding. Here, we demonstrate a Ce-doped Ni</description>
      <author>Wei Zheng, Niangao Duan, Yang Yang, Peichen Wang, Yafei Qu, Cichang Zong, Qianwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries: A Comprehensive Review of Cathode and Anode Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10080260</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Xue Meng, Qing Wang, Yahui Zhang, Shengxue Yan, Shaohua Luo, Batteries. 10(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400915387

                As modern society continues to advance, the depletion of non-renewable energy sources (such as natural gas and petroleum) exacerbates environmental and energy issues. The development of green, environmentally friendly energy storage and conversion systems is imperative. The energy density of commercial lithium-ion batteries is approaching its theoretical limit, and even so, it struggles to meet the rapidly growing market demand. Lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries have garnered significant attention from researchers due to their exceptionally high theoretical energy density. However, challenges such as poor electrolyte stability, short cycle life, low discharge capacity, and high overpotential arise from the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) during discharge and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) during charging. This article elucidates the fundamental principles of lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries, analyzes the primary issues currently faced, and summarizes recent research advancements in air cathodes and anodes. Additionally, it proposes future directions and efforts for the development of lithium&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Xue Meng, Qing Wang, Yahui Zhang, Shengxue Yan, Shaohua Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10080260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvothermal Synthesis of Quaternary Cu-Fe-Bi-S Nanostructure as a Promising Electrode Material for OER and Supercapacitor Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4654670/v1</link>
      <description>Muhammad Umer, Muhammad Awais, Sidra Aslam, Anas Bilal, Javaria Javaria, Waseem Abbas, Misbah Mirza, Muhammad Safdar, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400918067

                Abstract The rational development and synthesis of renewable nanostructured materials hold significant importance within the realm of energy storage applications. In this study, the quaternary chalcogenide of Cu2FeBiS4 was fabricated using a facile solvothermal method and evaluated for its performance in Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) and Supercapacitor applications. The material underwent characterization employing various analytical techniques, including X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDX), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), and Raman analysis. Cu2FeBiS4 demonstrates an improved super-capacitive performance, exhibiting an outstanding specific capacity (Cs) of 1530 F g&#8211;1 at 2 A g&#8211;1. The admirable electrochemical activity is mainly due to the synergistic effect of mixed metal sulfide nanostructure that can escalate the rapid diffusion of ions and electrons, which is beneficial to the electrode/electrolyte contact area, thereby boosting the rate of charge transfer. Additionally, Cu2FeBiS4 exhibits a commendable energy density of 43.17 Wh kg&#8722; 1 at a power density of 327.87 W kg&#8722; 1, accompanied by a retention rate of 96.2% after 1000 cycles. As a result, the Cu2FeBiS4 electrode developed in this study is evinced to be a promising electrode material for high-performance energy storage devices. Moreover, Cu2FeBiS4 demonstrates proficient electrocatalytic properties for the oxygen evolution reaction, displaying a minimal overpotential of 202 mV versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) at 10 mA cm&#8722; 2 and exhibiting operational stability for up to 10 hours.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Umer, Muhammad Awais, Sidra Aslam, Anas Bilal, Javaria Javaria, Waseem Abbas, Misbah Mirza, Muhammad Safdar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4654670/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intercalation-Induced Irreversible Lattice Distortion in Layered Double Hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04832</link>
      <description>Deok Ki Cho, Hyun Woo Lim, Andi Haryanto, Bingyi Yan, Chan Woo Lee, Jin Young Kim, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400882007

                Inducing strain in the lattice effectively enhances the intrinsic activity of electrocatalysts by shifting the metal's d-band center and tuning the binding energy of reaction intermediates. NiFe-layered double hydroxides (NiFe LDHs) are promising electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their cost-effectiveness and high catalytic activity. The distorted &#946;-NiOOH phase produced by the Jahn-Teller effect under the oxidation polarization is known to exhibit superior catalytic activity, but it eventually transforms to the undistorted &#947;-NiOOH phase during the OER process. Such a reversible lattice distortion limits the OER activity. In this study, we propose a facile boron tungstate (BWO) anion intercalation method to induce irreversible lattice distortion in NiFe LDHs, leading to significantly enhanced OER activity. Strong interactions with BWO anions induce significant stress on the LDH's metal-hydroxide slab, leading to an expansion of metal-oxygen bonds and subsequent lattice distortion.</description>
      <author>Deok Ki Cho, Hyun Woo Lim, Andi Haryanto, Bingyi Yan, Chan Woo Lee, Jin Young Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarification of Degradation Mechanisms of the OER Activity of Ir-Based Electrocatalyst with Potentiodynamic Accelerated Stress Test</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6716</link>
      <description>Raghunandan Sharma, P. Morgen, Darko Makovec, Sa&#353;o Gyergyek, Shuang Ma Andersen, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400937411

                Abstract It is vital to understand the degradation mechanisms for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity under acidic electrolyser operating conditions. To this end, we have studied a commercial benchmark Ir-Oxide electrocatalyst during an accelerated stress test (AST) of potential cycling (2000 cycles at 100 mV/s) between 1.0 and 1.7 V in 0.1 M HClO4. The OER activity degradation (&gt;60%) has been investigated due to (i) bulk structure changes from metal dissolution, (ii) particle growth and, (iii) surface chemical state changes. Microscopic images of the Ir-Oxide catalyst before and after the AST show no significant change in the particle size or agglomeration; moreover, negligible mass loss of the element. Therefore, the OER activity degradation is found to be dominantly (99%) associated with changes of the surface chemical state of Ir, i.e., increase in the Ir4+/Ir3+ ratio at the surface of Ir-Oxide during the AST.</description>
      <author>Raghunandan Sharma, P. Morgen, Darko Makovec, Sa&#353;o Gyergyek, Shuang Ma Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Enhancement of Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 Anode through Introduction of Tantalum&#8211;Titanium Interlayer via Double-Glow Plasma Surface Alloying Technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14141219</link>
      <description>Mingshuai Guo, Yueren Liu, Yonglei Xin, Likun Xu, Lili Xue, Tigang Duan, Rongrong Zhao, Junji Xuan, Li Li, Nanomaterials. 14(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400772789

                Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 electrodes are extensively utilized in the electrochemical industries such as copper foil production, cathodic protection, and wastewater treatment. However, their performance degrades rapidly under high current densities and severe oxygen evolution conditions. To address this issue, we have developed a composite anode of Ti/Ta-Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 with a Ta-Ti alloy interlayer deposited on a Ti substrate by double-glow plasma surface alloying, and the IrO2-Ta2O5 surface coating prepared by the traditional thermal decomposition method. This investigation indicates that the electrode with Ta-Ti alloy interlayer reduces the agglomerates of precipitated IrO2 nanoparticles and refines the grain size of IrO2, thereby increasing the number of active sites and enhancing the electrocatalytic activity. Accelerated lifetime tests demonstrate that the Ti/Ta-Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 electrode exhibits a much higher stability than the Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 electrode. The significant improvement in electrochemical stability is attributed to the Ta-Ti interlayer, which offers high corrosion resistance and effective protection for the titanium substrate.</description>
      <author>Mingshuai Guo, Yueren Liu, Yonglei Xin, Likun Xu, Lili Xue, Tigang Duan, Rongrong Zhao, Junji Xuan, Li Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14141219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation strategies of electrocatalysts for 5-hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation-assisted water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.93</link>
      <description>Tongxue Zhang, Hua Yin, Fumin Wang, Wenxian Liu, Xinyuan He, Qian Liu, Xubin Zhang, Xijun Liu, Microstructures. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400961728

                To address energy shortages and environmental issues, prioritizing renewable energy development and usage is crucial. Employing renewable sources for water electrolysis offers a sustainable method for hydrogen generation. Reducing the water electrolysis potential is vital for efficient clean energy conversion and storage. Substituting the anodic oxygen evolution reaction in conventional hydrogen production from water electrolysis with the more thermodynamically favorable 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation reaction can greatly decrease overpotential and yield the valuable product 2,5-furan dicarboxylic acid. The key to this process is developing effective electrocatalysts to minimize the potential of the HMF electrooxidation-hydrogen production system. Therefore, this review provides a comprehensive introduction to the modulation strategies that affect the electronic and geometric structure of electrocatalysts for HMF oxidation-assisted water splitting. The strategies encompass heteroatom doping, defect projection, interface engineering, structural design, and multi-metal synergies. The catalysts are assessed from various angles, encompassing structural characterization, reaction mechanisms, and electrochemical performance. Finally, current challenges in the catalyst design and potential development of this promising field are proposed.</description>
      <author>Tongxue Zhang, Hua Yin, Fumin Wang, Wenxian Liu, Xinyuan He, Qian Liu, Xubin Zhang, Xijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.93</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Enhancement Discharge Performance by Zinc-Coated Aluminum Anode for Aluminum&#8211;Air Battery in Sodium Chloride Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14146263</link>
      <description>Ruly Bayu Sitanggang, Syarifa Nur&#8217;aini, Susanto Susanto, W. Widiyastuti, Heru Setyawan, Applied sciences. 14(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400767124

                The main drawback of seawater batteries that use the aluminum (Al)&#8211;air system is their susceptibility to anode self-corrosion during the oxygen evolution reaction, which, in turn, affects their discharge performance. This study consist of an electrochemical investigation of pure Al, 6061 Al alloy, and both types coated with zinc as an anode in a 3.5% sodium chloride (NaCl) electrolyte. The electrolyte solution used for the deposition of zinc metal contained citrate, with and without EDTA as a complexing agent. Subsequently, the performance of the anode was tested in a seawater battery, using a carbon@MnO2 cathode and a 3.5% NaCl electrolyte. The performance of Al&#8211;air batteries has been significantly enhanced by applying a process of electrodepositing zinc (Zn) with a citrate deposition electrolyte solution in both pure aluminum and alloy 6061. The performance of the battery was further enhanced by adding EDTA as a chelating agent to the citrate-based electrolyte solution. The Al&#8211;air battery with aluminum alloy 6061 with Zn electrodeposition with an additional EDTA as the anode, carbon@MnO2 as the cathode, and NaCl 3.5% solution as the electrolyte has the highest battery performance, with a specific discharge capacity reaching 414.561 mAh.g&#8722;1 and a specific energy density reaching 0.255 mWh.g&#8722;1, with stable voltage at 0.55 V for 207 h.</description>
      <author>Ruly Bayu Sitanggang, Syarifa Nur&#8217;aini, Susanto Susanto, W. Widiyastuti, Heru Setyawan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14146263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@N&#8208;CNH as Bifunctional Hybrid Catalysts for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400415</link>
      <description>Sudheer Kumar Yadav, Daniel Deckenbach, Sandeep Yadav, Christian Njel, Vanessa Trouillet, J&#246;rg J. Schneider, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400935985

                Abstract Improving the efficiency of bifunctional electrocatalysts is a decisive challenge in the area of long&#8208;lasting rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries. Enhancing the catalysts' performance is crucial for advancing zinc&#8208;air batteries. Transition&#8208;metal oxides have emerged as promising non&#8208;precious, noble&#8208;metal&#8208;free catalysts. Herein, a unique precursor directed approach is introduced for preparing a cobalt ferrite@nitrogen doped carbon nanohorns (CoFe 2 O 4 @N&#8208;CNHs) nanohybrid catalyst in a single step annealing process involving stoichiometric amounts of single&#8208;source cobalt and iron molecular precursors and carbon nanohorns (CNHs) under an argon/ammonia (Ar/NH 3 ) atmosphere. This procedure enables a simultaneous CoFe 2 O 4 ferrite synthesis and nitrogen functionalization of CNHs. The precious metal free nanohybrid CoFe 2 O 4 @N&#8208;CNHs&#8208;30% containing 30% of carbon presents an oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) half wave potential and onset potential comparable to the standard ORR catalyst 20% Pt/C. CoFe 2 O 4 @N&#8208;CNHs&#8208;30% also establishes superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance with a low overpotential and a small Tafel slope than benchmark OER catalyst RuO 2 . Furthermore, the rechargeable zinc&#8208;air battery with the CoFe 2 O 4 @N&#8208;CNHs&#8208;30% nanohybrid as air electrode demonstrates steadier and more durable charge&#8211;discharge cycles, and outstanding energy density relative to the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art 20% Pt/C&#8208;RuO 2 catalyst.</description>
      <author>Sudheer Kumar Yadav, Daniel Deckenbach, Sandeep Yadav, Christian Njel, Vanessa Trouillet, J&#246;rg J. Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long&#8208;Durability, Surfactant&#8208;Free, and Bifunctional Ir&#8208;Doped Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co/MWCNTs Electrocatalysts towards ORR and OER in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202402029</link>
      <description>Yan Wang, Chuang Li, Guangwei Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Shiping Luo, Danmin Xing, Changhai Liang, ChemistrySelect. 9(28)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400948633

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective, high&#8208;performance, and durable electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is pivotal for advancing hydrogen energy conversion and storage technologies. Simultaneously, establishing scalable methods for their production is essential for the widespread adoption of these renewable energy solutions. In this study, we present a successful large&#8208;scale synthesis of surfactant&#8208;free iridium&#8208;doped Pt&#8722;cobalt nanoparticles supported on multiwalled carbon nanotubes (Ir&#8722;Pt 3 Co/MWCNTs). This composite demonstrates significantly enhanced ORR and OER activity compared to commercial Pt/C and IrO 2 in acidic environments. The Ir&#8722;Pt 3 Co/MWCNTs catalyst composite exhibits a low overpotential of 357 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a remarkable mass activity of 0.594 A/mg Pt . Investigating the influence of Ir doping content on ORR and OER, we found that Pt 3 Co 0.6 Ir 0.4 /MWCNTs showcased the most superior activity in both reactions. We present a reproducible protocol for the synthesis of surfactant&#8208;free Ir&#8722;Pt 3 Co nanoparticles supported on MWCNTs, yielding a bifunctional catalyst capable of efficiently catalyzing both ORR and OER with outstanding efficiency and stability in acidic media. Detailed X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis elucidates the electron transfer between atoms, optimizing the electronic structure and adjusting the position of the d&#8208;band. This optimization enhances the electrocatalytic activity and structural stability of the catalysts, contributing to their superior performance in ORR and OER.</description>
      <author>Yan Wang, Chuang Li, Guangwei Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Shiping Luo, Danmin Xing, Changhai Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202402029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhibiting the Deep Reconstruction of Ni&#8208;Based Interface by Coordination of Chalcogen Anions for Efficient and Stable Glycerol Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404290</link>
      <description>Shuo Wang, Yong Yan, Yongping Du, Yuguo Zhao, Tongxian Li, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400887098

                Abstract Recently, Ni&#8208;based chalcogenides havedemonstrated remarkable activity and selectivity for alcohol electrooxidation, but the mechanisms remain debated. This study synthesizes Ni&#8208;based electrodeswith different chalcogen anion coordination on nickel nanorod arrays (NiO x /Ni,NiS x /Ni, and NiSe x /Ni NRAs). NiSe x /Ni NRAsshowcases superior performance (Faradaic efficiency 92.9%) in glycerolelectrooxidation reaction (GOR). In situ spectroscopy reveals that NiSecoordination inhibits deep oxidative reconstruction of the Ni&#8208;based interface, preventingNiOOH phase formation during GOR, enhancing activity and stability of NiSe x /NiNRAs. Conversely, NiS and NiO coordination lead to deep reconstruction with NiOOHphase formation, limiting GOR performance. Differently, during competingreaction of GOR, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) leads to deepreconstruction of NiSex interface due to the instability of Ni&#8208;Sebonds, inducing performance degradation and dissolution of Se components. Furthermechanism investigation elucidates that the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) ofGOR at the NiSe x interface involves oxidation of *C 2 H 3 O 3 intermediatesthrough H 2 O adsorption, favoring stable formate production.Contrarily, the RDS at the NiS x , NiO x , and NiOOHinterfaces predominantly focus on the decarboxylation of multi&#8208;carbon intermediates, raisingenergy barriers and over&#8208;oxidizing formate to CO 2 . These results providenew insights for designing Ni&#8208;based non&#8208;oxide catalysts forefficient and stable electrocatalytic oxidation.</description>
      <author>Shuo Wang, Yong Yan, Yongping Du, Yuguo Zhao, Tongxian Li, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on hydrogen generation based on inorganic metal oxide nano-catalyst using water electrolysis approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/revic-2024-0026</link>
      <description>Muhammad Naeem Ayub, Kwang&#8208;Hyun Baek, Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Saad M. Al-Baqami, Khalid Ahmed Alzahrani, Md. Reazuddin Repon, Md. Rezaur Rahman, Mohammad Mizanur Rahman Khan, Muhammad Nadeem Arshad, Reviews in Inorganic Chemistry. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400836369

                Abstract Today world is looking for a cheap, environment friendly and efficient substitute of fossil fuel. Because due to large consumption of the fossil fuels on daily basis in whole world, emission of hazardous gases have produced lethal effects on human being. In this scenario hydrogen energy has emerged in form of clean, renewable and more efficient energy. Now the key challenge is that efficient production of the green hydrogen at commercial scale to meet demand of hydrogen. The electrolysis of water is the best pathway to achieve efficient hydrogen production. For this purpose the synthesis and improvement of low cast, active as well as stable catalysts or electrolysis is prerequisite for hydrogen production by electro-catalytic method for splitting of water. Main focus of this review is that, how we can perform the electrolysis of water by various techniques using novel methods especially electro-catalysts in term of activity, efficiency, large surface area, porosity, and stability. This will be performed by the method of two-half cell reaction one is the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) other one Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), where reaction proceeded in both medium acidic as well as alkaline phases. Particular attention is given to produce green clean hydrogen production from usable water and its physical and chemical storages for further uses for the support of human sustainability. Basically the recent strategy is to prepare, design and development of nanoscale materials/composite with non-noble metals and with also nanostructured with noble-metals will be discussed in this approach. The increased efficiency and utility have been the focal points of the use of diverse materials from different classes. To increase the electro-catalytic efficiency in OER and HER, we will discuss about new analyses methods and insights into studying the chemical compositions, shapes, surface area, porosity, and synergy of catalysts and the active sites of nanostructured electro-catalysts. This review will further provide the picture of current state of developments as well as recent progress for mechanized efficient production of clean hydrogen (i.e., HER) from water by electrocatalytic method using various nanoscale materials in a broad scale.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Naeem Ayub, Kwang&#8208;Hyun Baek, Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Saad M. Al-Baqami, Khalid Ahmed Alzahrani, Md. Reazuddin Repon, Md. Rezaur Rahman, Mohammad Mizanur Rahman Khan, Muhammad Nadeem Arshad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/revic-2024-0026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Modeling of the Local Reaction Environment in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00234</link>
      <description>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling, Accounts of chemical research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400851781

                ConspectusElectrocatalytic reactions, such as oxygen reduction/evolution reactions and CO</description>
      <author>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimodal trending in corrosion loss of magnesium alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5006/4548</link>
      <description>Robert E. Melchers, CORROSION. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400896543

                Abstract Data for mass loss of a variety of magnesium alloys as a function of exposure period show that corrosion loss follows bimodal trending with time for different exposure environments, both laboratory and field support these findings. For data sets sufficient to discriminate bimodal behaviour, the instantaneous rate of corrosion at the commencement of the second mode is (close to) 4 times the instantaneous rate of corrosion at the end of the first mode (i.e. through the transition period). This observation is consistent with the theoretical relative diffusivities of oxygen and hydrogen through the corrosion product layer as it exists during the transition period. These findings support the notion that the bimodal model has corrosion in Mode 1 rate-controlled by the cathodic oxygen reduction reaction and the inward diffusion of oxygen while in Mode 2 corrosion is rate-controlled by the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction and the outward diffusion of hydrogen. Similar findings have been made previously for various ferrous and other alloys and thus throws new light on the development of corrosion of magnesium alloys. It also provides reasons for measurements of hydrogen evolution and for electrochemical techniques underestimating magnesium corrosion rates. A new procedure for combining these is proposed.</description>
      <author>Robert E. Melchers</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5006/4548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial community evolution in the biofilm attached to sponge carriers in pulp mill effluent treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17533/udea.redin.20240730</link>
      <description>Emeline Melchiors, Camila Peitz, Jackeline Valendolf, Mac Wendell Barbosa da Silva, Izadora Cervelin-Fl&#244;r, V&#226;nia Aparecida Vicente, Cl&#225;udia Regina Xavier, Revista Facultad de Ingenier&#237;a Universidad de Antioquia. 113(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400876404

                This study investigates the evolution of the biofilm matrix responsible for treating effluent from a pulp mill and identifies the microbial community by 16S rRNA gene sequencing. In addition, a biocarrier promising a functional structure with better specific features for biofilm formation than traditional polyurethane carriers was explored. The average removal efficiencies were 43.7% for chemical oxygen demand (COD) and 62.7% for biochemical oxygen demand (BOD5). The color increased during the treatment, indicating anoxic zones being formed in the inner part of this type of carrier. Periodic micrographs showed the evolution of extracellular polymeric substances and materials like fungi and bacteria adhered to the carriers. Genetic sequencing confirmed the presence of Bacillus sp. and Paenibacillus glucanolyticus, species with the potential to degrade and discolor pulp industrial effluents. Results offer a potential basis to enhance treatment facilities of pulp and paper mills based on microbial activities.</description>
      <author>Emeline Melchiors, Camila Peitz, Jackeline Valendolf, Mac Wendell Barbosa da Silva, Izadora Cervelin-Fl&#244;r, V&#226;nia Aparecida Vicente, Cl&#225;udia Regina Xavier</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17533/udea.redin.20240730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen is Toxic in the Cold in C. elegans.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.17.603990</link>
      <description>Cameron M Suraci, Michael L Morrison, Mark B. Roth, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881915

                Temperature and oxygen are two factors that profoundly affect survival limits of animals; too much or too little of either is lethal. However, both humans and animals can exhibit exceptional survival when oxygen and temperature are simultaneously low. To better understand this apparent synergistic interaction between oxygen and temperature, we assayed the survival of Caenorhabditis elegans in experimental environments at different temperatures and oxygen concentrations. While nematodes cannot survive a day in room air at 2 degrees C (cold shock), we found that when oxygen is low, 200-fold less than room air, they can survive this temperature for 48 hours. Consistent with this, we found that worms exposed to high oxygen concentrations, 35 times greater than room air, are more sensitive to low temperature than worms in room air. These results show that normal atmospheric levels of oxygen are toxic in the cold. Using these survival assays, we found that cold acclimatization protects worms from lethal effects of high oxygen, mutations in the cold acclimatization pathway affect oxygen tolerance, and that the naturally occurring and physiologically relevant compounds glucose, manganese (II), and ascorbate improve survival limits in both low temperature and high oxygen when supplied early in life. These results show that the interdependence of temperature and oxygen on survival in C. elegans is based in part on shared physiological mechanisms involved in response to these two environmental stressors. The evolution and natural history of stress responses in animals suggest similar phenomena may function in humans.</description>
      <author>Cameron M Suraci, Michael L Morrison, Mark B. Roth</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.17.603990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Interfacial Interactions and Oxygen Vacancies in Tuning Magnetic Anisotropy in LaCrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/LaMnO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400243</link>
      <description>Xuanyi Zhang, Athby H. Al&#8208;Tawhid, P. Sch&#228;fer, Zhan Zhang, Divine P. Kumah, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400963754

                Abstract The interplay of lattice, electronic, and spin degrees of freedom at epitaxial complex oxide interfaces provides a route to tune their magnetic ground states. Unraveling the competing contributions is critical for tuning their functional properties. The relationship between magnetic ordering and magnetic anisotropy and the lattice symmetry, oxygen content, and film thickness in compressively strained LaMnO 3 (LMO)/LaCrO 3 (LCO) superlattices is investigated. Mn&#8211;O&#8211;Cr antiferromagnetic superexchange interactions across the heterointerface result in a net ferrimagnetic magnetic structure. Bulk magnetometry measurements reveal isotropic in&#8208;plane magnetism for as&#8208;grown oxygen&#8208;deficient thin samples due to equal fractions of orthorhombic a+a&#8208;c&#8208;, and a&#8208;a+c&#8208; twin domains. As the superlattice thickness is increased, in&#8208;plane magnetic anisotropy emerges as the fraction of the a+a&#8208;c&#8208; domain increases. On annealing in oxygen, the suppression of oxygen vacancies results in a contraction of the lattice volume, and an orthorhombic to rhombohedral transition leads to isotropic magnetism independent of the film thickness. The complex interactions are investigated using high&#8208;resolution synchrotron diffraction and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy. These results highlight the role of the evolution of structural domains with film thickness, interfacial spin interactions, and oxygen&#8208;vacancy&#8208;induced structural phase transitions in tuning the magnetic properties of complex oxide heterostructures.</description>
      <author>Xuanyi Zhang, Athby H. Al&#8208;Tawhid, P. Sch&#228;fer, Zhan Zhang, Divine P. Kumah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Origins of Self-sustained Kai Protein Circadian Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.23.604570</link>
      <description>Atsushi Mukaiyama, Yoshihiko Furuike, Kumiko Ito-Miwa, Yasuhiro Onoue, Kota Horiuchi, Eiki Yamashita, Shuji Akiyama, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400937324

                Light-dark cycles affect photosynthetic efficiency in autotrophic cyanobacteria; therefore, determining whether ancient cyanobacteria possessed a self-sustained circadian clock when oxygenic photosynthetic systems were established is an important issue in chronobiology. Here we examined the oscillation of the clock protein KaiC in modern cyanobacteria, as well as the function and structure of ancestral Kai proteins, to determine the evolutionary origin of the self-sustained Kai-protein oscillators. The results show that the oldest double-domain KaiC in ancestral bacteria lacked the factors functionally and structurally essential for rhythmicity. The ancestral Kai proteins had acquired these factors through molecular evolution that occurred around Global Oxidation and Snowball Earth events, and were eventually inherited as a self-sustained circadian oscillator by the most recent common ancestor of cyanobacteria capable of oxygenic photosynthesis. This autonomous Kai protein oscillator was further inherited by most freshwater and marine cyanobacteria present today as an autotrophic basis for time-optimal acquisition and consumption of energy from oxygenic photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Atsushi Mukaiyama, Yoshihiko Furuike, Kumiko Ito-Miwa, Yasuhiro Onoue, Kota Horiuchi, Eiki Yamashita, Shuji Akiyama</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.23.604570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selection for Photocatalytic Function through Darwinian Evolution of Synthetic Self-Replicators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x4fdr</link>
      <description>Kai Liu, Omer Markovitch, Chris van Ewijk, Yari Katar Knelissen, Armin Kiani, Marcel J. Eleveld, Wouter H. Roos, Sijbren Otto, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400830447

                The onset of Darwinian evolution represents a key step in the transition of chemical systems into living ones. Here, we show the emergence of Darwinian evolution in two systems of self-replicating molecules, where natural selection favors replicator mutants best capable of catalyzing the production of the precursors required for their own replication. Such selection for protometabolic activity was observed in a system where trimer and hexamer replicators compete for common resources, as well as in a system of different hexamer replicator mutants. An out-of-equilibrium replication-destruction regime was implemented in a flow reactor, where replication from continuously supplied dithiol building blocks needs to keep up with &#8220;destruction&#8221; by outflow. Selection occurred based on the ability of the mutants to activate a cofactor that photocatalytically produces singlet oxygen which, in turn, enhances the rate by which dithiol building blocks are converted into disulfide-based replicator precursors. Selection was based on a functional trait (catalytic activity) opening up Darwinian evolution as a tool for catalyst development. This work functionally integrates self-replication with protometabolism and Darwinian evolution and marks a further advance in the de-novo synthesis of life.</description>
      <author>Kai Liu, Omer Markovitch, Chris van Ewijk, Yari Katar Knelissen, Armin Kiani, Marcel J. Eleveld, Wouter H. Roos, Sijbren Otto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x4fdr</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of MELTS program to Fractional Crystallization of Low Alumina Alkaline Magma in Jeju Volcanic Island</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4651465/v1</link>
      <description>Huy L&#234;, Cheolwoo Chang, Sung-Hyo Yun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400918573

                Abstract Jeju Volcanic Island is the largest island in South Korea which is known as the continental shelf intraplate volcanic island. MELTS, one of the powerful programs utilizing for modeling magmatic evolution processes, is applied to simulate fractional crystallization process of low-alumina alkaline volcanic rock suite in Jeju Island. At many isobaric pressure conditions from 2.0 GPa to 0.1 GPa as well as different oxygen fugacities (fO2) from FMQ-3 to FMQ + 3 and H2O content, MELTS modeling were conducted as various calculations. The results demonstrate that the most suitable fractionation model for Jeju low-alumina alkaline magma would occur from 0.2 GPa to 0.1 GPa with oxygen fugacity FMQ buffer. These contain 0.5 wt.% H2O in the system leading to more consistent with evolution trending of as well as mineral composition in natural rock suite on Jeju Island. Although MELTS still possesses several limitations in the stability of calibration such as spinel overestimation as well as a lack of experiments for hydrous minerals which have been renovated, MELTS exhibits its affection on temperature and pressure prediction as well as assess other factor of fractional crystallization process on Jeju Island. Consequently, to evaluate a magmatic process in a particular region, it would be better to combine MELTS with other analyses rather than operating independently.</description>
      <author>Huy L&#234;, Cheolwoo Chang, Sung-Hyo Yun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4651465/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ TEM Investigation of the Lithiation and Delithiation Process Between Graphene Sheets in the Presence of Atomic Defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406034</link>
      <description>Yueliang Li, Felix B&#246;rrnert, Mahdi Ghorbani&#8208;Asl, Johannes Biskupek, Xuemei Zhang, Yongsheng Zhang, Stefano Passerini, Arkady V. Krasheninnikov, Ute Kaiser, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400782612

                Abstract Using advanced in situ transmission electron microscopy, the lithiation and delithiation processes into graphene sheets are studied and significant differences are detected in the structural evolution of the system. Thin fcc lithium crystals with faceted shapes are formed between graphene sheets during lithiation, but are transformed into irregular patches during delithiation. It is found that defects such as vacancies in graphene and impurity atoms play the key role in these processes. Specifically, during intercalation the lithium crystals nucleate at vacancies in graphene, while upon delithiation the impurity oxygen atoms initially embedded at octahedral interstitial positions inside the lithium crystals agglomerate at the edges of the crystals, thus giving rise to the formation of amorphous lithium oxide patches, where lithium ions are trapped.</description>
      <author>Yueliang Li, Felix B&#246;rrnert, Mahdi Ghorbani&#8208;Asl, Johannes Biskupek, Xuemei Zhang, Yongsheng Zhang, Stefano Passerini, Arkady V. Krasheninnikov, Ute Kaiser</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aging properties of spinel&#8208;type high&#8208;entropy oxides (Co&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;Cr&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;Mn&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;Zn&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for thermistors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14866</link>
      <description>Liangchen Fan, Jincheng Yao, Yuling Tuo, Aimin Chang, Zhaoyang Chen, Jingyi Wang, International journal of applied ceramic technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400778934

                Abstract Herein, a spinel&#8208;type high&#8208;entropy ceramics (Co .2 Cr .2 Fe .2 Mn .2 Zn .2 ) 3 O 4 is introduced. The obtained ceramics exhibit superior thermal stability under accelerated aging conditions at 125&#176;C for 500 h, that is, aging drift was less than .35% for all samples sintered at temperatures (1200or&#8211;1275or . The variation of resistance is mainly attributed to the oxidation of grain boundaries and the migration of oxygen vacancies. The relationship between crystal structure evolution and aging properties was investigated using structural analysis and P&#8211;V&#8211;L bonding theory. Theoretically, the Co/Cr/Mn/Fe&#8211;O bonds at the octahedral sites in the spinel structure are more important for controlling structural stability.</description>
      <author>Liangchen Fan, Jincheng Yao, Yuling Tuo, Aimin Chang, Zhaoyang Chen, Jingyi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14866</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Active Heterostructure Design for Enhanced Two Electron Oxygen Reduction via Chemical and Electrochemical Reconstruction of Heterosulfides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408508</link>
      <description>Kai Yu, Hongyuan Yang, Jie Xu, Weijie Yuan, Ruotao Yang, Meiling Hou, Zhenhui Kang, Yang Liu, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400800039

                Transition metal sulfides, particularly heterostructures, represent a promising class of electrocatalysts for two electron oxygen reduction (2e&#8722; ORR), however, understanding the dynamic structural evolution of these catalysts during alkaline ORR remains relatively unexplored. Herein, NiS2/In2.77S4 heterostructure was synthesized as a precatalyst and through a series of comprehensive ex&#8208;situ and in&#8208;situ characterizations, including X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, Raman spectroscopy, transient photo&#8208;induced voltage measurements, electron energy loss spectroscopy, and spherical aberration&#8208;corrected electron microscopy, it was revealed that nickel/indium (oxy)hydroxides (NiOOH/In(OH)3) could be evolved from the initial NiS2/In2.77S4 via both electrochemical and chemical&#8208;driven methods. The electrochemical&#8208;driven phase featured abundant bridging oxygen&#8208;deficient [NiO6]&#8208;[InO6] units at the interfaces of NiOOH/In(OH)3, facilitating a synergistic effect between active Ni and In sites, thus enabling an enhanced alkaline 2e&#8722; ORR capability than that of chemical&#8208;driven process. Remarkably, electrochemically induced NiOOH/In(OH)3 exhibited exceptional performance, achieving H2O2 selectivity of &gt;90% across the wide potential window (up to 0.4 V) with a peak selectivity of &gt;99%. Notably, within the flow cell, a current density exceeding 200 mA cm&#8722;2 was sustained for over 20 h, together with an impressive Faradaic efficiency of approximately 90% and a hydrogen peroxide production rate surpassing 4 mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1.</description>
      <author>Kai Yu, Hongyuan Yang, Jie Xu, Weijie Yuan, Ruotao Yang, Meiling Hou, Zhenhui Kang, Yang Liu, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408508</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Active Heterostructure Design for Enhanced Two Electron Oxygen Reduction via Chemical and Electrochemical Reconstruction of Heterosulfides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408508</link>
      <description>Kai Yu, Hongyuan Yang, Jie Xu, Weijie Yuan, Ruotao Yang, Meiling Hou, Zhenhui Kang, Yang Liu, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400839905

                Transition metal sulfides, particularly heterostructures, represent a promising class of electrocatalysts for two electron oxygen reduction (2e&#8722; ORR), however, understanding the dynamic structural evolution of these catalysts during alkaline ORR remains relatively unexplored. Herein, NiS2/In2.77S4 heterostructure was synthesized as a precatalyst and through a series of comprehensive ex&#8208;situ and in&#8208;situ characterizations, including X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, Raman spectroscopy, transient photo&#8208;induced voltage measurements, electron energy loss spectroscopy, and spherical aberration&#8208;corrected electron microscopy, it was revealed that nickel/indium (oxy)hydroxides (NiOOH/In(OH)3) could be evolved from the initial NiS2/In2.77S4 via both electrochemical and chemical&#8208;driven methods. The electrochemical&#8208;driven phase featured abundant bridging oxygen&#8208;deficient [NiO6]&#8208;[InO6] units at the interfaces of NiOOH/In(OH)3, facilitating a synergistic effect between active Ni and In sites, thus enabling an enhanced alkaline 2e&#8722; ORR capability than that of chemical&#8208;driven process. Remarkably, electrochemically induced NiOOH/In(OH)3 exhibited exceptional performance, achieving H2O2 selectivity of &gt;90% across the wide potential window (up to 0.4 V) with a peak selectivity of &gt;99%. Notably, within the flow cell, a current density exceeding 200 mA cm&#8722;2 was sustained for over 20 h, together with an impressive Faradaic efficiency of approximately 90% and a hydrogen peroxide production rate surpassing 4 mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1.</description>
      <author>Kai Yu, Hongyuan Yang, Jie Xu, Weijie Yuan, Ruotao Yang, Meiling Hou, Zhenhui Kang, Yang Liu, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408508</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High temperature oxidation regime transitions in hafnium carbide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20008</link>
      <description>Jonathan A. Scott, Xiaoqing He, David W. Lipke, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400779416

                Abstract Understanding the oxidation behavior of hafnium carbide is crucial to its application in extreme environments. In this work, the transition in high&#8208;temperature oxidation kinetics regimes in hafnium carbide is explained based on phase equilibria considerations supported by observed changes in oxide scale microstructure evolution associated with different transformation pathways. Below, a composition&#8208;dependent critical temperature and oxygen pressure, hafnium carbide first transforms to an amorphous material with nominal composition HfO 2 C followed by phase separation into carbon and hafnia domains. Subsequently, gaseous transport through a nanometric pore network formed by oxidative removal of phase&#8208;separated carbon becomes rate&#8208;limiting. Above this critical point, the oxidation sequence involves a direct transformation from hafnium carbide to hafnia and gaseous products, leading to dissimilar scale morphologies responsible for the reported transition from gaseous to solid&#8208;state diffusion&#8208;limited oxidation regimes at ultra&#8208;high temperatures.</description>
      <author>Jonathan A. Scott, Xiaoqing He, David W. Lipke</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous CuxO Nano-Skeletons from Waste Electronics for Enhanced Glucose Detection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01467-5</link>
      <description>Yexin Pan, Ruohan Yu, Yalong Jiang, Haosong Zhong, Qiaoyaxiao Yuan, Connie Kong Wai Lee, Rongliang Yang, Siyu Chen, Yi Chen, Wilson C. K. Poon, Guijun Li, Nano-micro letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400785664

                Abstract Electronic waste (e-waste) and diabetes are global challenges to modern societies. However, solving these two challenges together has been challenging until now. Herein, we propose a laser-induced transfer method to fabricate portable glucose sensors by recycling copper from e-waste. We bring up a laser-induced full-automatic fabrication method for synthesizing continuous heterogeneous Cu x O (h-Cu x O) nano-skeletons electrode for glucose sensing, offering rapid (&lt; 1 min), clean, air-compatible, and continuous fabrication, applicable to a wide range of Cu-containing substrates. Leveraging this approach, h-Cu x O nano-skeletons, with an inner core predominantly composed of Cu 2 O with lower oxygen content, juxtaposed with an outer layer rich in amorphous Cu x O (a-Cu x O) with higher oxygen content, are derived from discarded printed circuit boards. When employed in glucose detection, the h-Cu x O nano-skeletons undergo a structural evolution process, transitioning into rigid Cu 2 O@CuO nano-skeletons prompted by electrochemical activation. This transformation yields exceptional glucose-sensing performance (sensitivity: 9.893 mA mM &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 ; detection limit: 0.34 &#956;M), outperforming most previously reported glucose sensors. Density functional theory analysis elucidates that the heterogeneous structure facilitates gluconolactone desorption. This glucose detection device has also been downsized to optimize its scalability and portability for convenient integration into people&#8217;s everyday lives.</description>
      <author>Yexin Pan, Ruohan Yu, Yalong Jiang, Haosong Zhong, Qiaoyaxiao Yuan, Connie Kong Wai Lee, Rongliang Yang, Siyu Chen, Yi Chen, Wilson C. K. Poon, Guijun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01467-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOO&#8226; as the Chain Carrier for the Autocatalytic Photooxidation of Benzylic Alcohols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29143429</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, H. B. Lao, H. Zhang, Yi Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Jieqing Wu, Yu&#8208;Feng Li, Hongjun Zhu, Jianyou Mao, Yi Pan, Molecules. 29(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400876445

                The oxidation of benzylic alcohols is an important transformation in modern organic synthesis. A plethora of photoredox protocols have been developed to achieve the aerobic oxidation of alcohols into carbonyls. Recently, several groups described that ultraviolet (UV) or purple light can initiate the aerobic oxidation of benzylic alcohols in the absence of an external catalyst, and depicted different mechanisms involving the photoinduction of &#8226;O2&#8722; as a critical reactive oxygen species (ROS). However, based on comprehensive mechanistic investigations, including control experiments, radical quenching experiments, EPR studies, UV&#8211;vis spectroscopy, kinetics studies, and density functional theory calculations (DFT), we elucidate here that HOO&#8226;, which is released via the H2O2 elimination of &#945;-hydroxyl peroxyl radicals [ArCR(OH)OO&#8226;], serves as the real chain carrier for the autocatalytic photooxidation of benzylic alcohols. The mechanistic ambiguities depicted in the precedent literature are clarified, in terms of the crucial ROS and its evolution, the rate-limiting step, and the primary radical cascade. This work highlights the necessity of stricter mechanistic analyses on UV-driven oxidative reactions that involve aldehydes&#8217; (or ketones) generation.</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, H. B. Lao, H. Zhang, Yi Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Jieqing Wu, Yu&#8208;Feng Li, Hongjun Zhu, Jianyou Mao, Yi Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29143429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of hypogenesis in the evolution of karst in the Taurus Mountains Range, Turkey</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5038/1827-806x.53.2.2501</link>
      <description>Serdar Bayar&#305;, Naciye Nur &#214;zyurt, L&#252;tfi Nazik, Koray T&#246;rk, Noyan G&#252;ner, Emrah Pekkan, P&#305;nar Avc&#305;, International Journal of Speleology. 53(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400947810

                Field observations and laboratory data collected from the Taurus Mountains Range, Turkey during the last two decades provided evidence for the link between the evolution of hypogene karst and the geodynamic history. Major evidence includes; carbonate-hosted secondary ore deposits that are converted from primarily hypogene minerals by epigene, oxygen-rich groundwater circulating at local to intermediate depths. Another piece of evidence of hypogene karst in the Tauride is the K&#305;rkg&#246;z springs&#8217; huge submerged cave/conduit system, which formed the Antalya Travertine Plateau, which is the world&#8217;s largest deposit precipitated by cool karst groundwater. The obruks in central Tauride are giant collapse dolines formed by ascending hypogene fluids in the upper continental crust, rich in volcanogenic carbondioxide. The groundwater&#8217;s noble gas and carbon isotope data are helpful in determining the existing but asymptomatic hypogene activity in the upper crust. Hypogene karst development seems common in parts of the world with current or past geodynamic activity. However, a hydrogeological overview of the geodynamic history is essential to assess the hypogene processes and their reflections on the land surface.</description>
      <author>Serdar Bayar&#305;, Naciye Nur &#214;zyurt, L&#252;tfi Nazik, Koray T&#246;rk, Noyan G&#252;ner, Emrah Pekkan, P&#305;nar Avc&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5038/1827-806x.53.2.2501</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An in situ exploration of how Fe/N/C oxygen reduction catalysts evolve during synthesis under pyrolytic conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50629-x</link>
      <description>Shuhu Yin, H. Yi, Mengli Liu, Jian Yang, Shuangli Yang, Binwei Zhang, Long Chen, Xiaoyang Cheng, Huan Huang, Rui Huang, Yanxia Jiang, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400965814

                Abstract In pursuing cheap and effective oxygen reduction catalysts, the Fe/N/C system emerges as a promising candidate. Nevertheless, the structural transformations of starting materials into Fe- and N-doped carbon catalysts remains poorly characterized under pyrolytic conditions. Here, we explore the evolution of Fe species and track the formation of Fe&#8211;N 4 site development by employing diverse in-situ diagnostic techniques. In-situ heating microscopy reveals the initial formation of FeO x nanoparticles and subsequent internal migration within the carbon matrix, which stops once FeO x is fully reduced. The migration and decomposition of nanoparticles then leads to carbon layer reconstruction. Experimental and theoretical analysis reveals size-dependent behavior of FeO x where nanoparticles below 7 nm readily release Fe atoms to form Fe&#8211;N 4 while nanoparticles with sizes &gt;10 nm tend to coalesce and impede Fe&#8211;N 4 site formation. The work visualizes the pyrolysis process of Fe/N/C materials, providing theoretical guidance for the rational design of catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shuhu Yin, H. Yi, Mengli Liu, Jian Yang, Shuangli Yang, Binwei Zhang, Long Chen, Xiaoyang Cheng, Huan Huang, Rui Huang, Yanxia Jiang, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50629-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactively Processed Poly(butylene adipate terephthalate) Composite&#8211;Based Multilayered Films with Improved Properties for Sustainable Packaging Applications: Structural Characterization and Biodegradation Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/macp.202400067</link>
      <description>Jayita Bandyopadhyay, Orebotse Joseph Botlhoko, Caroline Mphahlele, Rakgoshi Lekalakala, Sudhakar Muniyasamy, Suprakas Sinha Ray, Macromolecular Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400903936

                Abstract In this study, it is attempted to enhance the properties and biodegradability of poly(butylene adipate terephthalate) (PBAT) using nanocomposite technology to meet the demand for sustainable packaging applications. Two nanoclays containing PBAT composites are reactively processed and integrated into the multilayered films. Reactive processing facilitates the dispersion and distribution of nanoclay particles in the PBAT matrix. The multilayered films comprising reactively processed PBAT composites exhibited a 24.5%&#8211;31.5% reduction in the oxygen transmission rate and improved dimensional stability and tensile properties. Moreover, the degradability of the multilayered film comprising reactively processed PBAT composites reached 82% in 180 days. In contrast, a neat PBAT film of similar thickness attained only 53% degradation in the same period. The biodegradation mechanism is proposed based on the topology of the disintegrated films studied using scanning electron microscopy, chemical bond vibrations determined by Fourier&#8208;transform infrared spectroscopy, and structural evolution by small&#8208; and wide&#8208;angle X&#8208;ray scattering (SWAXS). The SWAXS analysis is used to understand the changes in the degree of crystallinity, long&#8208;range periodic order, and crystalline and amorphous layer thickness of the multilayered films before and after degradation. Such multilayered films can find applications where packaging or biomedical devices cannot be recycled.</description>
      <author>Jayita Bandyopadhyay, Orebotse Joseph Botlhoko, Caroline Mphahlele, Rakgoshi Lekalakala, Sudhakar Muniyasamy, Suprakas Sinha Ray</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/macp.202400067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Element abundances of galactic RGB stars in the APO-K2 catalogue. Dissimilarity in the scaling with [alpha/Fe]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449755</link>
      <description>G. Valle, M. Dell&#8217;Omodarme, P. G. Prada Moroni, S. Degl&#8216;Innocenti, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400917527

                We conducted an investigation on the chemical abundances of 4,316 stars in the red giant branch (RGB) phase from the recently released APO-K2 catalogue. Our aim was to characterize the abundance trends of the single elements with afe , mainly focusing on C, N, and O, which are the most relevant for the estimation of stellar ages. The chemical analysis of the RGB sample involved cross-matching data from the APO-K2 catalogue with individual element abundances from APOGEE DR17. The analysis detected a statistically significant difference in the (C+N+O)/Fe -- afe trend with respect to the simple alpha -enhancement scenario. This difference remained robust across different choices for the reference solar mixture and potential zero-point calibrations of C and N abundances. The primary discrepancy was a steeper increase in O/Fe with afe , reaching a 0.1 dex difference at $ = 0.3$. Notably, the impact on the evolutionary timescale of such oxygen over-abundance with respect to the commonly adopted uniform alpha -enhancement is rather limited. We verified that stellar models computed using an ad hoc O-rich mixture sped up the evolution by only 1&lt;!PCT!&gt; at $ = 0.3$, due to the counterbalancing effects of O enrichment on both the evolutionary timescale and the Fe/H relationship.</description>
      <author>G. Valle, M. Dell&#8217;Omodarme, P. G. Prada Moroni, S. Degl&#8216;Innocenti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in atomic-scale interface engineering for flexible electronics: Enhancing flexibility and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad64db</link>
      <description>Di Wen, Ruige Yuan, Kun Cao, Jing Wang, Rong Chen, Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400763461

                Abstract Flexible electronics, such as wearable displays, implantable electronics, soft robots, and smart skin, have garnered increasing attention. Despite notable advancements in research, a bottleneck remains at the product level due to the prevalent use of polymer-based materials, requiring encapsulation films for lifespan extension and reliable performance. Multilayer composites, incorporating thin inorganic layers to maintain low permeability towards moisture, oxygen, ions, etc., exhibit potential in achieving highly flexible barriers but encounter challenges stemming from interface instability between layers. This perspective offers a succinct review of strategies and provides atomic-scale interface modulation strategy utilizing atomic layer integration technology focused on enhancing the flexibility of high-barrier films. It delves into bendable multilayers with atomic-scale interface modulation strategies, encompassing internal stress and applied stress modulation, as well as stretchable composite structural designs such as gradient/hybrid, wavy, and island. These strategies showcase significant improvements in flexibility from bendable to stretchable while maintaining high barrier properties. Besides, optimized manufacturing methods, materials, and complex structure design based on atomic-scale interface engineering are provided, better aligning with the future development of flexible electronics. By laying the groundwork for these atomic-scale strategies, this perspective contributes to the evolution of flexible electronics, enhancing their flexibility, durability, and functionality.</description>
      <author>Di Wen, Ruige Yuan, Kun Cao, Jing Wang, Rong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad64db</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Transient Reoxidation on Inclusions in Rare&#8208;Earth&#8208;Treated Bearing Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400169</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Boting Yan, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang, Xiangpeng Gao, Steel research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400863264

                The impact of transient reoxidation environments on the chemical morphology evolution of nonmetallic oxide inclusions in rare&#8208;earth&#8208;treated bearing steel is investigated using FactSage thermodynamic simulation calculations, vacuum induction furnace experiments, and high&#8208;temperature laser confocal microscopy experiments. Thermodynamic calculations indicate a direct correlation between the initial rare&#8208;earth content and the oxygen required to transform Ce 2 O 2 S to CeAlO 3 during secondary oxidation. Furthermore, a higher initial rare&#8208;earth content leads to a more extensive and complete conversion to CeAlO 3 . Vacuum induction furnace experiments reveal that the inclusions transform from Ce 2 O 2 S to CeAlO 3 and Al 2 O 3 and eventually into composite oxide clusters. This results in a significant increase in inclusions, with near&#8208;spherical Ce 2 O 2 S inclusions transforming into aggregated CeAlO 3 , leading to an increase in the average inclusion size from 2.4 to 4.2 &#956;m. Laser confocal scanning microscopy experiments show that CeAlO 3 exhibits a higher tendency to aggregate than Ce 2 O 2 S inclusions, the primary factor contributing to the observed increase in the average inclusion size after secondary oxidation. The results of this study provide theoretical guidance for mitigating the adverse effects of rare&#8208;earth secondary oxidation on bearing steels, particularly in terms of inclusion control.</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Boting Yan, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang, Xiangpeng Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfide and selenide PGE mineralization in chromitites of the Dunzhugur ophiolite massif (East Sayan, Russia)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0016777024020054</link>
      <description>Olga Kiseleva, E. V. Ayriyants, &#1057;. &#1052;. &#1046;&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1082;, Dmitriy Belyanin, Geologi&#226; rudnyh mestoro&#382;denij. 66(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400852046

                The paper presents the first data on PGE sulfide and selenide mineralization formed in podiform chromitites at different stages of evolution of the Dunzhugur ophiolite massif. The chromite bodies are local-ized in listvenitized aposerpentinites, which are part of the Dunzhugur ophiolite complex. The forms of occurrence, microstructural features and compositions of platinum-group minerals in chromitites were stud-ied by scanning electron microscopy. The enrichment of chromitites with a refractory platinum group-ele-ment (PGE) sulfides and alloys in the Os-Ir-Ru system (IPGE) testify that the for-mation of magmatic platinum-group minerals (PGMs) occurred under mantle conditions. Primary PGMs were replaced by iridium sulfoarsenides and sulfoantimonides due to the interaction of mantle peridotites and chromitites with As&#8211;Sb-bearing fluid generated during dehydration and melting of the subducting slab. Native osmium was formed as a result of desulfurization of magmatic PGE-bearing sulfides with the partic-ipation of reduced fluids at the serpentinization stage. The replacement of Ru&#8211;Os sulfides by selenides of these metals in chromitites could occur at the stages of subduction or obduction at high oxygen fugacity under the influence of acid hydrothermal/metamorphogenic fluids. A qualitative assessment of physicochemical parameters of the formation of ruthenium selenides was carried out. Oxygen fugacity values estimated from the mag-netite&#8211;hematite association are log fO2 (&#8211;30.5) at 300&#1413;C and log fO2 (&#8211;40.5) at 200&#1413;C. The minimum sulfur fugacity value was determined by the stability line of laurite at 300&#1413;C, log fS2 = &#8211;20; the maximum sulfur fugacity values&#8212;by the stability line of iron and nickel sulfides: log fS2 &#8211;4.5 at 300&#1413;C and log fS2 &#8211;10.5 at 200&#1413;C. The selenium fugacity at T = 300&#1413;C is log fSe2 (&#8211;8&#8230;&#8211;13); at T = 200&#1413;C, log fSe2 (&#8211;12&#8230;&#8211;17). Au&#8211;Ag selenides were formed at T = 200&#1413;C, log fS2 (&#8211;9&#8230;&#8211;10.5); log fSe2 is from &#8211;13.5 to &#8211;20.5, log fO2 (&#8211;40). An important factor for the possibility of replacement of Ru&#8211;Os sulfides by selenides is Se occurrence in the ore-forming system. The source of Se may be the substance of the subducting slab&#8212;volcanogenic&#8211;sedimentary rocks containing fragments of Se-rich hydrothermal&#8211;sedimentary sulfide ores. They were involved in the processes of magma genesis and accompanying hydrothermal circulation.</description>
      <author>Olga Kiseleva, E. V. Ayriyants, &#1057;. &#1052;. &#1046;&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1082;, Dmitriy Belyanin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0016777024020054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canine glioma stem-like cells demonstrate DNA methylation-dependent enhancement of cellular respiration following low oxygen tension</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4600799/v1</link>
      <description>Ryan G. Toedebusch, Chang&#8208;Il Hwang, Shafee Syed-Quadri, Orwa Aboud, Kevin Woolard, Daniel York, Maciej Parys, Peter J. Dickinson, Frederick J. Meyers, John M. McPherson, Christine M. Toedebusch, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400764115

                Abstract Glioma stem cells (GSCs) have been implicated in radio- and chemotherapeutic resistance of glioblastoma (GBM). Therapeutic targeting of GSCs has shown promise in immunocompromised rodent models but have not been translated into effective therapies for human patients. The limited success of translating therapies from rodent models to GBM patients may be attributed, in part, to the lack of co-evolution between tumors and the tumor microenvironment in immunocompromised rodent models. Thus, spontaneous canine high-grade gliomas (HGGs) may provide a complementary translational model for human therapeutic development. While described in canine HGGs, little is known about canine glioma stem cell biology. In this study, we evaluatedcellular metabolism, DNA methylation, gene expression, and functional tests of malignancy to interrogate differences between canine glioma stem-cell like (GSLC) lines and a traditional serum grown glioma cell line following exposure to hypoxia. Hypoxia increased oxygen consumption rates in GSLCs, which correlated with hypoxia-induced hypomethylation and increased mRNA levels of genes important in cellular metabolism and stemness (e.g., KCNN3, KDM4B, TCF7L2), as well as augmented features of malignancy in GSLCs. Importantly, we were able to demonstrate a positive correlation between up-regulated genes in human GBM GSCs and hypomethylation of orthologous canine genes following hypoxia. Together, these data highlight similarities between canine and human GBM GSC cellular metabolism and their epigenetic regulation.</description>
      <author>Ryan G. Toedebusch, Chang&#8208;Il Hwang, Shafee Syed-Quadri, Orwa Aboud, Kevin Woolard, Daniel York, Maciej Parys, Peter J. Dickinson, Frederick J. Meyers, John M. McPherson, Christine M. Toedebusch</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4600799/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An investigation into Venusian atmospheric chemistry based on an open-access photochemistry-transport model at 0-112 km</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450552</link>
      <description>Longkang Dai, Wencheng Shao, Biao Chen, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400932900

                Atmospheric chemistry plays a crucial role in the evolution of climate habitability on Venus. It has been widely explored by chemistry-transport models, but some characteristics are still poorly interpreted. This study is devoted to developing an open-access chemistry-transport model spanning both the middle and lower atmospheres of Venus. It provides a scheme for the structure of the chemistry, especially for the sulfur and oxygen, and investigates the influence of the cloud diffusivity and the SO$_ $ dissolution that are adopted in the clouds. The developed model is based on the VULCAN framework and was updated with the state-of-the-art Venusian atmospheric chemistry. It includes vertical eddy diffusion retrieved recently with the Venus Express observations, and it resolves radiative transfer containing gas absorption and scattering, Mie scattering of the cloud droplets, and absorption of the unknown UV absorber. The obtained abundance profiles of SO, SO$_ $, CO, COS, O, O$_ $, O$_ $, HCl, and NO are in overall agreement with the observations. The results show that the increase in cloud diffusivity has slight effects on the chemical structure. The SO$_ $ mainly dissolves in 50-90 km and evaporates below the clouds. The rapid dissolution-release cycle is responsible for the large upward flux of SO$_ $ at 58 km. At around 70 km, SO has a significant peak that is larger than that of previous studies by an order of magnitude, and S and SO$_ $ also show slight increases. They are attributed to the buffering effects of liquid SO$_ $ in the clouds. O$_ $ is significantly eliminated by SO in this layer. We emphasize the superior regulation of the sulfur cycle on O$_ $ at 70 km and its potential contributions to the long-standing problem of the overestimated O$_ $ abundance.</description>
      <author>Longkang Dai, Wencheng Shao, Biao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Nonmetallic Inclusion in High&#8208;Mn and High&#8208;Al Steel Caused by the Interfacial Reaction Between Steel and Ladle Filler Sand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400381</link>
      <description>Shengli Li, Xinliang Zang, Jun&#8208;Kai Zhang, Jie Yang, Ximin Zang, Guocheng Wang, Steel research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400863299

                The influence of chromium&#8208;bearing filler sand on the transformation of inclusions in high&#8208;Mn and high&#8208;Al steel under various reaction times and Mn content levels is studied, and the mechanism of filler sand intrusion into the steel matrix is analyzed. It is demonstrated that an inclusion containing Cr 2 O 3 is discovered. The evolution pathway of oxide inclusions is identified as Al 2 O 3 &#8211;MnO &#8594; Al 2 O 3 &#8211;MnO&#8211;SiO 2 &#8594; Al 2 O 3 &#8211;MnO&#8211;SiO 2 &#8211;Cr 2 O 3 (Cr 2 O 3 + MnO&#8211;SiO 2 ) &#8594; Al 2 O 3 &#8211;MnO&#8211;Cr 2 O 3 &#8211;MgO&#183;Al 2 O 3 . It is noteworthy that Cr 2 O 3 inclusions tend to diffuse from the outside inward, but the internal content remains almost unchanged, which is due to the strong diffusion hindrance of SiO 2 . The formation of a liquid phase in the filler sand is a necessary condition for its infiltration into the steel matrix. The critical liquid&#8208;phase content that results in the formation of Cr 2 O 3 inclusions is 42%, which contains 5&#8211;8% of Cr 2 O 3 . The formation of pore channels provides favorable conditions for sand penetration, with the maximum penetration depth reaching up to 29 mm. Large sand inclusion particles reach millimeter scale in size and are distributed quite randomly. Chemical reactions at the steel/sand interface can lead to an increase in the total oxygen (T.O) content in the steel. The reaction time has little effect on the T.O content, while the Mn content in the steel has a significant impact, with an increase of up to 41 ppm. During the smelting stage, the filler sand can enter the molten steel, thereby affecting the quality of the product.</description>
      <author>Shengli Li, Xinliang Zang, Jun&#8208;Kai Zhang, Jie Yang, Ximin Zang, Guocheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eROSITA narrowband maps at the energies of soft X-ray emission lines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449398</link>
      <description>Xueying Zheng, G. Ponti, Nicola Locatelli, A. Merloni, Werner Becker, Johan Comparat, K. Dennerl, M. J. Freyberg, Chandreyee Maitra, M. Sasaki, A. W. Strong, M. C. H. Yeung, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400917386

                Hot plasma plays a crucial role in regulating the baryon cycle within the Milky Way, flowing from the energetic sources in the Galactic center and plane, to the corona and the halo. This hot plasma represents an important fraction of the Galactic baryons, plays a key role in galactic outflows and is an important ingredient in galaxy evolution models. Taking advantage of the Spectrum-Roentgen-Gamma (SRG first all-sky survey (eRASS1), in this work our aim is to provide a panoramic view of the hot circumgalactic medium (CGM) of the Milky Way. Compared to the previous all-sky X-ray survey performed by ROSAT, the improved energy resolution of enabled us to map, for the first time, the sky within the narrow energy bands characteristic of soft X-ray emission lines. These lines provide essential information on the physical properties of the hot plasma. Here we present the eRASS1\ half sky maps in narrow energy bands corresponding to the most prominent soft X-ray lines and which allowed us to constrain the distribution of the hot plasma within and surrounding the Milky Way. We corrected the maps by removing the expected contribution associated with the cosmic X-ray background, the time-variable solar wind charge exchange, and the local hot bubble. We applied corrections to mitigate the effect of absorption, therefore highlighting the emission from the CGM of the Milky Way. We used the line ratio of the oxygen lines as a proxy to constrain the temperature of the warm-hot CGM, and we defined a pseudo-temperature $ T $ map. The map highlights how different regions are dominated by different thermal components. Toward the outer halo, the temperature distribution of the CGM on angular scales of 2--20 deg is consistent with being constant $ T T 4&lt;!PCT!&gt;$ with a marginal detection of $ T T = 2.7 &lt;!PCT!&gt; 0.2&lt;!PCT!&gt;$ (statistical) $ 0.6&lt;!PCT!&gt;$ (systematic) in the southern hemisphere. Instead significant variations of $ 12&lt;!PCT!&gt;$ are observed on scales of many tens of degrees when comparing the northern and southern hemispheres. The pseudo-temperature map shows significant variations across the borders of the bubbles, suggesting temperature variations, possibly linked to shocks, between the interior of the Galactic outflow and the unperturbed CGM. In particular, a shell characterized by a lower line ratio appears close to the edge of the bubbles.</description>
      <author>Xueying Zheng, G. Ponti, Nicola Locatelli, A. Merloni, Werner Becker, Johan Comparat, K. Dennerl, M. J. Freyberg, Chandreyee Maitra, M. Sasaki, A. W. Strong, M. C. H. Yeung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controls on Early Cretaceous South Atlantic Ocean circulation and carbon burial &#8211; a climate model&#8211;proxy synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/cp-20-1537-2024</link>
      <description>Sebastian Steinig, Wolf Dummann, Peter Hofmann, Martin Frank, Wonsun Park, Thomas Wagner, Sascha Fl&#246;gel, Climate of the past. 20(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400929548

                Abstract. Black shale sediments from the Barremian to Aptian South Atlantic document the intense and widespread burial of marine organic carbon during the initial stages of seafloor spreading between Africa and South America. The enhanced sequestration of atmospheric CO2 makes these young ocean basins potential drivers of the Early Cretaceous carbon cycle and climate perturbations. The opening of marine gateways between initially restricted basins and related circulation and ventilation changes are a commonly invoked explanation for the transient formation and disappearance of these regional carbon sinks. However, large uncertainties in palaeogeographic reconstructions limit the interpretation of available palaeoceanographic data and prevent any robust model-based quantifications of the proposed circulation and carbon burial changes. Here, we present a new approach to assess the principal controls on the Early Cretaceous South Atlantic and Southern Ocean circulation changes under full consideration of the uncertainties in available boundary conditions. Specifically, we use a large ensemble of 36 climate model experiments to simulate the Barremian to Albian progressive opening of the Falkland Plateau and Georgia Basin gateways with different configurations of the proto-Drake Passage, the Walvis Ridge, and atmospheric CO2 concentrations. The experiments are designed to complement available geochemical data across the regions and to test circulation scenarios derived from them. All simulations show increased evaporation and intermediate water formation at subtropical latitudes that drive a meridional overturning circulation whose vertical extent is determined by the sill depth of the Falkland Plateau. The densest water masses formed in the southern Angola Basin and potentially reached the deep Cape Basin as Walvis Ridge Overflow Water. Palaeogeographic uncertainties are as important as the lack of precise knowledge of atmospheric CO2 levels for the simulated temperature and salinity spread in large parts of the South Atlantic. Overall temperature uncertainties reach up to 15 &#176;C and increase significantly with water depth. The ensemble approach reveals temporal changes in the relative importance of geographic and radiative forcings for the simulated oceanographic conditions and, importantly, nonlinear interactions between them. The progressive northward opening of the highly restricted Angola Basin increased the sensitivity of local overturning and upper-ocean stratification to atmospheric CO2 concentrations due to large-scale changes in the hydrological cycle, while the chosen proto-Drake Passage depth is critical for the ocean dynamics and CO2 response in the southern South Atlantic. Finally, the simulated processes are integrated into a recent carbon burial framework to document the principal control of the regional gateway evolution on the progressive shift from the prevailing saline and oxygen-depleted subtropical water masses to the dominance of ventilated high-latitude deep waters.</description>
      <author>Sebastian Steinig, Wolf Dummann, Peter Hofmann, Martin Frank, Wonsun Park, Thomas Wagner, Sascha Fl&#246;gel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/cp-20-1537-2024</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
