<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 01:07:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of MoP/MoS2 Core-shell Structure Electrocatalyst for Boosting Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40242-024-4040-6</link>
      <description>Dan Meng, Shengnan Ran, Ling Gao, Yue Zhang, Xiaoguang San, Lei Zhang, Ruixiang Li, Quan Jin, Chemical research in Chinese universities/Chemical Research in Chinese Universities. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394786108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Meng, Shengnan Ran, Ling Gao, Yue Zhang, Xiaoguang San, Lei Zhang, Ruixiang Li, Quan Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40242-024-4040-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-step constructing advanced N-doped carbon@metal nitride as ultra-stable electrocatalysts via urea plasma under room temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109887</link>
      <description>Tao Tang, Chen Li, Sipu Li, Zhong Qiu, Tianqi Yang, Beirong Ye, San-Qiang Shi, Chunyang Wu, Feng Cao, Xinhui Xia, Minghua Chen, Xinqi Liang, Xinping He, Xin Liu, Yongqi Zhang, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394787344

                Highly active transition metal nitrides are desirable for electrocatalytic reactions, but their long-term stability is still unsatisfactory and thus limiting commercial applications. Herein, for the first time, we report a unique and universal room-temperature urea plasma method for controllable synthesis of N-doped carbon coated metal (Fe, Co, Ni, etc.) nitrides arrays electrocatalysts. The preformed metal oxides arrays can be successfully converted into metal nitrides arrays with preserved nanostructures and a thin layer of N-doped carbon (N-C) via one-step urea plasma. Typically, as a representative case, N-C@CoN nanowire arrays are illustrated and corresponding formation mechanism by plasma is proposed. Notably, the designed N-C@CoN catalysts deliver excellent electrocatalytic activity and long-term stability both in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR). For OER, a low overpotential (264 mV at 10 mA/cm2) and high stability (&gt;50 h at 20 mA/cm2) are acquired. For UOR, a current density of 100 mA/cm2 is achieved at only 1.39 V and maintain over 100 h. Theoretical calculations reveal that the synergetic coupling effect of CoN and N-C can significantly facilitate the charge-transfer process, optimize adsorbed intermediates binding strength and further greatly decrease the energy barrier. This strategy provides a novel method for fabrication of N-C@ metal nitrides as highly active and stable catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Tang, Chen Li, Sipu Li, Zhong Qiu, Tianqi Yang, Beirong Ye, San-Qiang Shi, Chunyang Wu, Feng Cao, Xinhui Xia, Minghua Chen, Xinqi Liang, Xinping He, Xin Liu, Yongqi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the adsorption of intermediates through modulating Mn d-band centers by the Mn-Ce heterojunction for high-performance lithium-oxygen batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234512</link>
      <description>Mengran Xie, Nan Wang, Shaoze Zhao, Zhongjun Li, Youcai Lu, Qingchao Liu, Journal of power sources. 605(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394790676

                Admitting that rare-earth (RE)-based transition metal oxides (TMO) are emerging as a promising catalyst for lithium-oxygen (Li-O2) batteries, the understanding of their electrocatalytic mechanism and active sites remains ambiguous. In this study, CeO2 nanoparticles modified MnOOH nanowires (CeO2@MnOOH NWs) is prepared by a simple solvothermal method as highly effective cathode catalysts for Li-O2 batteries. The incorporation of CeO2 nanoparticles into MnOOH facilitates a robust interaction between the 3d electronic state of MnOOH and the 4f electronic state of CeO2 at the Fermi level (Ef). The strong electron interaction at the heterogeneous interface between MnOOH and CeO2 promotes internal electron transfer. Compared to pristine MnOOH, the prepared CeO2@MnOOH NWs exhibits enhanced electrocatalytic activity and improved electrocatalytic stability. According to experimental analysis and density functional theory (DFT) results, it is demonstrated that there is a slight negative shift in the d-band center of the Mn site, resulting in faster electron transfer rates and higher conductivity. This acceleration of charge transfer optimizes the adsorption strength of the oxygen-containing intermediate (LiO2), thereby promoting the kinetics of the oxygen reduction/evolution reactions (ORR/OER) and reducting the reaction over-potential. As a result, the electrochemical performances of Li-O2 batteries are greatly enhanced.</description>
      <author>Mengran Xie, Nan Wang, Shaoze Zhao, Zhongjun Li, Youcai Lu, Qingchao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave assisted synthesis of cobalt-doped copper selenite nanorice as bifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118267</link>
      <description>Umer Rashid, Youqi Zhu, Chuanbao Cao, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. 962(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394795330

                In the research and development of noble-metal free catalysts, copper-based materials such as copper selenite have shown interest as electrocatalysts to drive the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in basic medium, however their Hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity is still unexplored. Therefore, we have performed the synthesis of cobalt doped copper selenite nanoparticles which can robustly and effectively do electrocatalysis for both the OER and HER in basic medium electrolyte. The novelty lies in the fact that microwave synthesis procedure utilizing oxidizing agent as a key precursor is entirely new, this particular material was never employed in water splitting and catalyst need very low amount of binder. The results revealed that cobalt doped copper selenite have a relatively lower starting potential and a higher current density due to the synergistic effects of a large active area, quick charge, mass transport, and a three-dimensional conducting path, having OER and HER overpotentials of 359 mV and 226 mV at 10 mA/cm2 current densities, respectively. We found a novel doped structure featuring porous surfaces and distinctive rice like morphology which facilitate an efficient electron transportation during the water splitting thereby illustrating an exceptional performance of this system along with rapid synthesis and lower costs.</description>
      <author>Umer Rashid, Youqi Zhu, Chuanbao Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined growth of Ultrathin, nanometer-sized FeOOH/CoP heterojunction nanosheet arrays as efficient self-supported electrode for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.084</link>
      <description>Yao Lu, Julong Li, Xiaoguang Bao, Lulu Zhang, Maosen Jing, Kaixin Wang, Qiaomei Luo, Lei Gou, Xiaoyong Fan, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394798802

                Self-supported electrodes, featuring abundant active species and rapid mass transfer, are promising for practical applications in water electrolysis. However, constructing efficient self-supported electrodes with a strong affinity between the catalytic components and the substrate is of great challenge. In this study, by combining the ideas of in-situ construction and space-confined growth, we designed a novel self-supported FeOOH/cobalt phosphide (CoP) heterojunctions grown on a carefully modified commercial Ni foam (NF) with three-dimensional (3D) hierarchically porous Ni skeleton (FeOOH/CoP/3D NF). The specific porous structure of 3D NF directs the confined growth of FeOOH/CoP catalyst into ultra-thin and small-sized nanosheet arrays with abundant edge active sites. The active FeOOH/CoP component is stably anchored on the rough pore wall of 3D NF support, leading to superior stability and improved conductivity. These structural advantages contributed to a highly facilitated oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and enhanced durability of the FeOOH/CoP/3D NF electrode. Herein, the FeOOH/CoP/3D NF electrode afforded a low overpotential of 234 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 (41 mV smaller than FeOOH/CoP grown on unmodified Ni foam) and high stability for over 90 h, which is among the top reported OER catalysts. Our study provides an effective idea and technique for the construction of active and robust self-supported electrodes for water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Yao Lu, Julong Li, Xiaoguang Bao, Lulu Zhang, Maosen Jing, Kaixin Wang, Qiaomei Luo, Lei Gou, Xiaoyong Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable synthesis of a hybrid mesoporous sheets-like Fe0.5NiS2@ P, N-doped carbon electrocatalyst for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.079</link>
      <description>Hassanien Gomaa, Cuihua An, Penggang Jiao, Weitai Wu, Hassan A.H. Alzahrani, Mohamed A. Shenashen, Qibo Deng, Ning Hu, Journal of colloid and interface science. 667(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394798882

                Owing to the high cost of precious metal catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the production of highly efficient and affordable electrocatalysts is important for generating pollution-free and renewable energy via electrochemical processes. A facile hydrothermal approach was employed to synthesize hybrid mesoporous iron-nickel bimetallic sulfides @ P, N-doped carbon for the OER. The prepared Fe0.5NiS2@C exhibited an overpotential (&#951;) of 250 mV at 10 mA/cm2. This exceeded the overpotentials recently reported for surface-modified P, N-doped carbon-based catalysts for the OER in a 1 M KOH medium. Moreover, the Fe0.5NiS2@C catalyst showed a notable Tafel slope of 90.5 mV/dec with long-dated stability even after 24 h at 10 mA/cm2. The superior OER performance of the Fe0.5NiS2@C catalysts may be due to their large surface area, sheet-like morphology with abundant active sites, fast transfer of mass and electrons, control of the electronic structure by co-treatment with heteroatoms (e.g., P and N), and the synergistic effect of bimetallic sulfides, making them favorable catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations showed that the Fe0.5NiS2@C catalyst exhibited strong H2O-adsorption energy. The enhanced OER activity of Fe0.5NiS2@C was attributed to its higher surface area, favorable H2O adsorption energy, improved electron transfer efficiency, and lower Gibbs free energy compared to those of the other proposed catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hassanien Gomaa, Cuihua An, Penggang Jiao, Weitai Wu, Hassan A.H. Alzahrani, Mohamed A. Shenashen, Qibo Deng, Ning Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in bifunctional catalysts for unitized regenerative fuel cells: exploring polaronic conduction and heterostructure designs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ad3e8b</link>
      <description>Uma Sharma, Pardeep K. Jha, P. C. Jha, Prabhakar Singh, Journal of physics. D, Applied physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394803094

                Abstract This study investigates the development and performance evaluation of a bifunctional catalyst tailored for unitized regenerative fuel cells (URFCs), capable of facilitating both oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in fuel cell and electrolyzer modes. The primary challenge addressed is the creation of electrocatalysts exhibiting high activity and corrosion resistance for oxygen reduction and water oxidation at the oxygen electrode. A novel catalyst structure based on La_{0.5}Sr_{0.5}Fe_{0.5}Ti_{0.5}O_{3}(LSFT),i.e., LSFT/ZnO/LSFT with a thickness of \sim2 &#956;m, is explored within an environmentally friendly medium. This catalyst demonstrates superior performance characteristics, including reduced overpotential in HER and enhanced stability during oxygen/hydrogen evolution processes in neutral medium. The study identifies the formation of interfacial polarons and polaronic charge modulation resulting from the incorporation of ZnO in LSFT, leading to multifunctional OER/HER behavior. Notably, the proposed interfacial small polaron mechanism offers valuable insights into complex interfacial phenomena and holds promise for applications in diverse heterostructures involving layered 2D materials and transition metal oxides. Moreover, the robust LSFT/ZnO/LSFT catalyst exhibits exceptional stability, maintaining for 168 hours of oxygen evolution at a constant potential of approximately 1.66 V for a current density of 1 A/cm&#178; in a neutral medium. These findings mark a significant advancement in URFC technology and present promising avenues for clean energy storage solutions.</description>
      <author>Uma Sharma, Pardeep K. Jha, P. C. Jha, Prabhakar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ad3e8b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe LDH/Mo-Ni3S2 heterogeneous electrocatalyst for alkaline efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104345</link>
      <description>Xiaoning Tong, Junli Wang, Yuantao Yang, Zhenwei Liu, Jing Wang, Can Zhang, Qingxiang Kong, Ruidong Xu, Linjing Yang, Surfaces and interfaces. 48(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394804992

                Currently, hydrogen production through water electrolysis stands out as one of the most promising methods. However, the efficiency of hydrogen production is limited by the anodic oxygen evolution reaction, which involves a four-electron transfer process. Therefore, the development of an efficient and durable anode catalyst is important to reduce energy consumption and increase the hydrogen production rate. Herein, the Mo-doped Ni3S2 nanopillar structures were successfully synthesized by hydrothermal process on nickel foam (NF). Subsequently, nanosheets of CoFe-layered double hydroxides (LDH) thin films were deposited to obtain the CoFe-LDH/Mo-Ni3S2/NF catalyst. Physical characterization results revealed polycrystalline properties of the CoFe LDH nanosheets, while a non-homogeneous interface was also formed with Mo-doped Ni3S2 nanopillars. The contact angle verified the excellent hydrophilicity, which allowed the rapid release of oxygen bubbles. In terms of electrocatalysis, the catalyst exhibited an overpotential of only 227 mV at 10 mA/cm2 and demonstrated remarkable current density retention after 100 h. The catalyst was also characterized by good retention of the current density at 10 mA/cm2. This work provided the strategy for designing efficient, inexpensive and durable catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaoning Tong, Junli Wang, Yuantao Yang, Zhenwei Liu, Jing Wang, Can Zhang, Qingxiang Kong, Ruidong Xu, Linjing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ba-leaching-initiated structural destabilization of perovskite Ruthenates during the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104341</link>
      <description>Seung Hyun Nam, Do Hyun Kim, Jegon Lee, Sangmoon Yoon, Jong&#8208;Sup Bae, Jin Young Oh, Seung Gyo Jeong, Jucheol Park, Jae-Yeol Hwang, Sang A Lee, Woo Seok Choi, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394806914

                The destabilization of a lattice structure during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the most essential aspects for designing and realizing highly efficient electrocatalysts. However, the underlying mechanism of structural evolution or degradation at the microscopic scale on the electrocatalyst surface during the OER has not been elucidated because of the sluggish yet dynamic character of the reaction. To address this issue, the direct observation of the unstable electrocatalytic activity is necessary. In this study, we demonstrate that the structural destabilization of epitaxial cubic perovskite BaRuO3 thin films during the OER originates from Ba leaching, Ru dissolution, and oxygen vacancy. A thin film geometry is adopted to selectively visualize the structural decomposition at the well-defined sample surface. The cubic BaRuO3 thin film initially exhibits high OER activity, which drastically decreases even during the first cyclic voltammetry cycle and is completely lost after the first cycle. The OER activity loss is closely related to the generation of structural defects on the surface, indicating the absence of the Ba and Ru atoms. This study proposes the mechanism underlying the OER activity that can be extended to elucidate the structural destabilization in various Ru- and Ir-based oxide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Seung Hyun Nam, Do Hyun Kim, Jegon Lee, Sangmoon Yoon, Jong&#8208;Sup Bae, Jin Young Oh, Seung Gyo Jeong, Jucheol Park, Jae-Yeol Hwang, Sang A Lee, Woo Seok Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A data-driven bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst with a record-breaking &#916;E = 0.57 V for ampere-hour-scale zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.03.017</link>
      <description>Jia&#8208;Ning Liu, Zhao Chang-xin, Juan Wang, Xiangdong Fang, Chen&#8208;Xi Bi, Bo&#8208;Quan Li, Qiang Zhang, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394807932

                Summary Refreshing the record of the electrocatalytic activity for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis is the first priority of developing next-generation rechargeable zinc-air batteries. A &#916;E indicator to evaluate the bifunctional electrocatalytic activity has stagnated with a record of &#916;E &gt; 0.60 V for decades. Herein, a bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst is developed to afford an ultrahigh bifunctional electrocatalytic activity of &#916;E = 0.57 V and realize high-performance rechargeable zinc-air batteries. Specifically, atomically dispersed Fe-N-C sites and NiFeCe layered double hydroxides are integrated to afford a composite FeNC@LDH electrocatalyst, following the guidance of the data-driven analysis. The FeNC@LDH electrocatalyst demonstrates a record-breaking electrocatalytic activity of &#916;E = 0.57 V, far exceeding the state-of-the-art level by ca. 60 mV. Practical ampere-hour-scale zinc-air batteries are constructed with a capacity of 6.4 Ah and cycle under 1.0 A and 1.0 Ah conditions. This work affords a record-breaking bifunctional electrocatalyst for ampere-hour-scale zinc-air batteries in future application scenarios.</description>
      <author>Jia&#8208;Ning Liu, Zhao Chang-xin, Juan Wang, Xiangdong Fang, Chen&#8208;Xi Bi, Bo&#8208;Quan Li, Qiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.03.017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semimetallic hydroxide materials for electrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2802-8</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Mohammed Ibrahim Jamesh, Qiang Gao, Bo Han, Ruimin Sun, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Chenggang Zhou, Zhao Cai, Science China. Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394809209

                Searching for catalyst materials with high intrinsic activity for water oxidation holds the key to numerous clean energy technologies. Hydroxide semiconductors are electrochemically active to drive oxygen evolution reaction (OER), but suffer from poor electronic conductivity, restricting their intrinsic electrocatalytic activity. Here, a semimetallic hydroxide material was designed as efficient OER catalyst with both improved electronic conductivity and intrinsic electrocatalytic activity. By cationic doping and anionic vacancy manipulation, the NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH) semiconductor was turned into semi-metallic with two orders of magnitude lower resistivity. Consequently, the semi-metallic LDH (SM LDH) array electrode exhibited an intrinsically improved OER activity with a low overpotential of 195 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a low Tafel slope of 40.9 mV dec&#8722;1 in alkaline medium, outperforming commercial RuO2 catalysts (316 mV, 99.6 mV dec&#8722;1) under the same test condition. In-depth Raman and first-principles calculations demonstrated that the enhanced OER intrinsic activity of SM LDH was associated with the high electronic conductivity, which promoted the formation and stabilization of high-valence metal sites in oxyhydroxide intermediates. These finding suggest semi-metallic hydroxides as an advanced electrode material with both fascinating electric and catalytic properties.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Mohammed Ibrahim Jamesh, Qiang Gao, Bo Han, Ruimin Sun, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Chenggang Zhou, Zhao Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-023-2802-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline metal phosphide-coated amorphous iron oxide-hydroxide (FeOOH) with oxygen vacancies as highly active and stable oxygen evolution catalyst in alkaline seawater at high current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.091</link>
      <description>Wei Yan, Zhuang Shi, Feng Hao, Jinshi Yu, Wenmiao Chen, Fuling Wang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394812135

                In this study, we employed a straightforward phosphorylation approach to achieve a dual objective: constructing c-a heterostructures consisting of crystalline Ni12P5 and amorphous FeOOH, while simultaneously enhancing oxygen vacancies. The resulting oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst, Ni12P5/FeOOH/NF, exhibited remarkable performance with current densities of 500 mA cm&#8722;2 in both 1 M KOH and 1 M KOH + seawater, requiring low overpotentials of only 288 and 365 mV, respectively. Furthermore, Ni12P5/FeOOH/NF exhibited only a slight increase in overpotential, with increments of 18 mV and 70 mV in 1 M KOH after 15 and 150 h, and 32 mV and 108 mV in 1 M KOH + seawater at 500 mA cm&#8722;2 after 15 and 150 h, respectively. This minimal change can be attributed to the stabilized c-a structure, the protective coating of Ni12P5, and superhydrophilic. Through in-situ Raman and ex-situ XPS analysis, we discovered that Ni12P5/FeOOH/NF can undergo a reconfiguration into an oxygen vacancy-rich (Fe/Ni)OOH phase during OER process. The elevated OER activity is mainly due to the contribution of the oxygen vacancy-rich (Fe/Ni)OOH phase from the reconfigure of the Ni12P5/FeOOH/NF. This finding emphasizes the critical role of oxygen vacancies in facilitating the production of OO species and overcoming the limitations associated with OOH formation, ultimately enhancing the kinetics of the OER.</description>
      <author>Wei Yan, Zhuang Shi, Feng Hao, Jinshi Yu, Wenmiao Chen, Fuling Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;100-x&lt;/sub&gt; for urea and oxygen evolution: a matter of compromise</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1139/cjc-2023-0130</link>
      <description>Noah Ruscica, Rylan Clark, J M B Stuart, Aaron Mason, Craig Bennett, Erwan Bertin, Canadian journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394812638

                The combination of aqueous electrolysis, either for hydrogen generation or CO 2 conversion, with wastewater treatment offers an elegant way to tackle issues associated with our energy transition and the need for clean drinking water. However, it requires an anode capable of doing both the oxidation of the targeted pollutant and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), as most pollutants are present in too low concentration to be practical for industrial electrolysis. In this study, we focussed on the oxidation of urea on Ni x Fe 100-x catalysts. These catalysts were prepared by pulsed laser ablation in liquid, a versatile and green technique to prepare electrocatalysts. Transmission electron microscopy of the nanoparticles indicates the production of monodisperse nanoparticles, with an average diameter increasing from 7.8 &#177; 2.8 to 19.7 &#177; 3.9 nm with a higher iron fraction. The composition could be controlled between pure Ni and NiFe bimetallic nanoparticles with up to 56 &#177; 3% of iron, by controlling the composition of the target. A brief optimisation of the electrode preparation (loading, catalyst-to-carbon ratio) yielded an optimum at about 30 &#181;g/cm 2 of catalyst with a catalyst-to-carbon ratio of 20:80. During the electrocatalytic tests, Ni was the best catalyst for urea oxidation, with a maximum peak current of 619 mA/mg. However, Ni 75 Fe 25 was the best OER catalyst, showing a peak current of 1150 mA/mg. The difference increased further during CA at 0.5 V, during which Ni 75 Fe 25 outperformed pure Ni by almost a factor of 3 after 30 min.</description>
      <author>Noah Ruscica, Rylan Clark, J M B Stuart, Aaron Mason, Craig Bennett, Erwan Bertin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1139/cjc-2023-0130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Photo in Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401578</link>
      <description>Zhixuan Feng, Chia-Tsen Dai, Peng Shi, Xuefei Lei, Xuanwen Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394816341

                Abstract Photo enhanced oxygen evolution reaction has recently emerged as an advanced strategy with great application prospects for highly efficient energy conversion and storage. In the course of photo enhanced oxygen evolution reactions, the other works focus has predominantly centered on catalysts while inadvertently overlooking the pivotal role of photo. Consequently, this manuscript embarks upon a comprehensive review of recent advancements in photo&#8208;driven, aiming to illuminate this critical dimension. A detailed introduction to the photothermal effect, photoelectronic effect, photon&#8208;induced surface plasmon resonance, photo and heterojunction, photo&#8208;induced reversible geometric conversion, photo&#8208;induced energy barrier reduction, photo&#8208;induced chemical effect, photo&#8208;charging, and the synthesis of laser/photo&#8208;assisted catalysts, offering prospects for the development of each case is provided. A detailed introduction to the photothermal effect, photoelectronic effect, photon&#8208;induced surface plasmon resonance, photo and heterojunction, photo&#8208;induced reversible geometric conversion, photo&#8208;induced energy barrier reduction, photo&#8208;induced chemical effect, photo&#8208;charging, and the synthesis of laser/photo&#8208;assisted catalysts is provided. At the same time, the overpotential and Tafel slope of some catalysts mentioned above at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 is collected, and calculated the lifting efficiency of light on them, offering prospects for the development of each case.</description>
      <author>Zhixuan Feng, Chia-Tsen Dai, Peng Shi, Xuefei Lei, Xuanwen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in Ir/Ru-based perovskite electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02623-x</link>
      <description>Ziyu Jiang, Chang Fan, Junyu Pan, Li Shao, Hao Wen, Erum Pervaiz, Dong Yan, Tongzhou Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Jihong Li, Yida Deng, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394819963

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyu Jiang, Chang Fan, Junyu Pan, Li Shao, Hao Wen, Erum Pervaiz, Dong Yan, Tongzhou Wang, Xuerong Zheng, Jihong Li, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02623-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Powered Hydrogen Production From Seawater Enabled by Trifunctional Exfoliated PtTe Nanosheet Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403099</link>
      <description>Zhipeng Yu, Gianluca D&#8217;Olimpio, Haoliang Huang, Chia&#8208;Nung Kuo, Chin Shan Lue, Giuseppe Nicotra, Fang Lin, Danil W. Boukhvalov, Antonio Politano, Lifeng Liu, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394822803

                Abstract Seawater electrolysis (SWE) is proposed to be a promising approach to green hydrogen (H 2 ) production but its large&#8208;scale deployment faces challenges because of the anodic competing chlorine evolution reaction (CER) and high energy consumption. To address these challenges, innovative hybrid SWE systems have recently emerged, able to mitigate the interference of CER and substantially reduce the electrical energy needed. Herein, the preparation of 2D layered PtTe nanosheets (e&#8208;PtTe NSs) using the liquid&#8208;phase exfoliation method is reported, which show outstanding electrocatalytic performance for the hydrogen evolution (HER), hydrazine oxidation (HzOR), and oxygen reduction reactions (ORR) in seawater. Using e&#8208;PtTe NSs as trifunctional catalysts, two hybrid SWE systems are demonstrated: 1) a hydrazine&#8208;assisted acid&#8208;alkaline dual&#8208;electrolyte seawater electrolyzer enabled by a bipolar membrane (BPM&#8208;OHzSWE), which can simultaneously produce H 2 and generate electricity through harvesting the electrochemical neutralization energy and leveraging the advantage of the HzOR over the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in terms of anodic potentials; 2) a hydrazine&#8208;assisted SWE system powered by a direct hydrazine fuel cell (DHzFC), which can realize self&#8208;powered H 2 production. These novel hybrid SWE systems show substantial promise for energy&#8208;saving and cost&#8208;effective production of H 2 from seawater.</description>
      <author>Zhipeng Yu, Gianluca D&#8217;Olimpio, Haoliang Huang, Chia&#8208;Nung Kuo, Chin Shan Lue, Giuseppe Nicotra, Fang Lin, Danil W. Boukhvalov, Antonio Politano, Lifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal synthesis of FeCoNi/V3O5 heterojunctions as highly efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136485</link>
      <description>Qiang Wan, Yue Zhang, Qianglong Qi, Hao Feng, Yang Feng, Fengning Bai, Chengxu Zhang, Jue Hu, Materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394823568

                To produce green hydrogen in a cost-effective and efficient manner, the research on low-cost, high-performance electrocatalysts is both attractive and challenging. In this study, a heterojunction electrocatalyst containing V3O5 and FeCoNi alloy nanoparticles was introduced. The adsorption and activation of the reactants at the FeCoNi/V3O5 heterointerface are significantly enhanced. The overall performance of the FeCoNi/V3O5 catalyst is excellent, with an OER activity reaching 265 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, nearly 65 mV lower compared to the commercial IrO2 catalyst. Furthermore, it exhibits outstanding durability, remaining stable for 50 h under a constant current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2. Theoretical calculations also revealed a synergistic effect between the FeCoNi alloy (referred to as FeCoNi) nanoparticles and V3O5, thereby enhancing the OER performance, consistent with the experimental findings.</description>
      <author>Qiang Wan, Yue Zhang, Qianglong Qi, Hao Feng, Yang Feng, Fengning Bai, Chengxu Zhang, Jue Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured NiMoO4 electrode materials for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.04.022</link>
      <description>Rajangam Vinodh, Shankara S. Kalanur, Sadesh Kumar Natarajan, Bruno G. Pollet, Journal of industrial and engineering chemistry/Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry - Korean Society of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394824054

                Bifunctional electrocatalysts derived from earth-abundant transition metals are a promising substitute for noble metals in general water electrolysis, but their low activity and short durability limit their application. Herein, a nickel molybdate nanoparticles decorated on nickel foam (NiMoO4/NF NPs) electrode was fabricated by a facile hydrothermal method at three different time intervals (6, 12, and 24 h) and verified for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The constructed electrodes exhibited high OER activity in 1.0 M KOH with overpotentials of 315 mV, 290 mV and 320 mV for NiMoO4-6 h, NiMoO4-12 h, and NiMoO4-24 h, respectively. In addition, the NiMoO4-12 h electrodes displayed remarkable durability with a negligible reduction of 1.28 % at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for 200 h. This research work delivers a new pathway to improve the electrocatalytic behaviour of the catalysts by synergistically moderating the inherent electrical conductivity, efficient surface moieties, and surface reaction.</description>
      <author>Rajangam Vinodh, Shankara S. Kalanur, Sadesh Kumar Natarajan, Bruno G. Pollet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.04.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorous and cations boost the electrocatalytic performances of Cu-based compounds for hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions and overall water-splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151322</link>
      <description>Qihao Wang, Yingxue Du, Yuecheng Gong, Weiping Xiao, Hongdong Li, Yunmei Du, Guangrui Xu, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394824331

                Developing durable, effective and inexpensive electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are crucial for the advancement of water splitting as a solution to the energy shortage. In this study, nanospheres stacked into nanochains are successfully prepared by oxidative corrosive engineering, solvothermal, and following calcination process (Co-Cu3P/CF). The unique nanochain structure facilitates growing the specific surface area, thereby exposing plenitude active sites. The introduced phosphorus (P) and Co ions can alter the electronic characteristics of metal phosphides, not only can accelerate the electron transport of the catalysts, but speed up the reaction kinetics. Thus, the prepared Co-Cu3P/CF exhibits low overpotentials, with 240/84 mV, in alkaline media for OER/HER to attain 10 mA cm&#8722;2. In alkaline freshwater/seawater, the self-assembled electrolyzer needs only 1.51/1.58 V to achieve 10 mA cm&#8722;2. This work provides an approach for the preparation of high-performing and economical electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Qihao Wang, Yingxue Du, Yuecheng Gong, Weiping Xiao, Hongdong Li, Yunmei Du, Guangrui Xu, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layered PbO2 electrode decorated with Ni-doped Mn5O8 peach-like microspheres for reinforced acidic oxygen evolution reaction in zinc electrowinning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127533</link>
      <description>Jinlong Wei, Xuanbing Wang, Junli Wang, Xiaoning Tong, Song Wu, Yuantao Yang, Qiong Wu, Buming Chen, Ruidong Xu, Linjing Yang, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394824332

                Developing anodic electrocatalysts with superior activity and durability suitable for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a challenge to overcome. Herein, a layered Pb-(0.76 wt%)Ag/&#945;-PbO2/&#946;-PbO2 electrode modified with Ni-doped Mn5O8 particles (PA/PbO2-NMO) is successfully synthesized by a coprecipitation coupling with anodic codeposition process. The physical characterization demonstrated that the surface of electrode is composed by &#946;-PbO2 and portion NMO that embedded in the deposit. In addition, it presents a layer structure, in which PA serving as support, &#945;-PbO2 as the mid layer enforcing the adherence, and &#946;-PbO2-NMO function as active layer. Benefiting from the above unique layered structure, the as-fabricated PA/PbO2-NMO electrode with a layered structure exhibits the outstanding acidic OER performance (583 mV, 139.04 mV dec&#8211;1) at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1.53 M H2SO4. Meanwhile, the responding accelerated corrosion life at 1.5 A cm&#8722;2 is up to 64 h, indicating its robust anticorrosion ability. As for the applied performance in zinc electrowinning simulation electrolyte (1.53 M H2SO4 + 0.31 M ZnSO4), the current efficiency of the PA/PbO2 electrode is promoted to 93.8 % after the modification with NMO. Moreover, the cell voltage and one-ton zinc energy consumption of the modified PA/PbO2 electrode are diminished by 14.32 %, 17.75 % compared with the industrial Pb-(0.76 wt%) Ag (PA) electrode. Therefore, this study offers a new horizon on the development of the anodic electrocatalyst for both strongly acidic watersplitting and non-ferrous metals electrowinning.</description>
      <author>Jinlong Wei, Xuanbing Wang, Junli Wang, Xiaoning Tong, Song Wu, Yuantao Yang, Qiong Wu, Buming Chen, Ruidong Xu, Linjing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking activity behavior of oxygen evolution reaction on perovskite oxides in alkaline solution via 3-dimensional electrochemical impedance spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118270</link>
      <description>Yuta Inoue, Yuto Miyahara, Kohei Miyazaki, Changhee Lee, Ryo Sakamoto, Takeshi Abe, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394824470

                Developing electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential for enhancing the efficiency of electrochemical water electrolysis. Among potential candidates, certain metal oxides, such as Ba0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3&#8722;&#948; (BSCF), undergo structural transformations at their surface during OER operation, and the in situ-formed active layer enhances their OER activities. However, it is challenging to quantitatively evaluate the time-variant electrochemically active surface area (ECSA) and inherent catalytic activity per surface area (area-specific activity) of the oxides. In this study, we utilize the 3-dimentional electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (3D EIS) technique to reveal the variations in the ECSA and area-specific activity of the perovskite oxides during OER operation in an alkaline solution. In BSCF, the diameter of instantaneous Nyquist plots decreases as the number of potential cycling in the OER potential range increases, contrasting with other perovskite oxides, such as La0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3&#8722;&#948; and LaCoO3. The fitting results of the Nyquist plots demonstrate that in BSCF, the ECSA significantly increases while the area-specific activity drops to less than half of its initial value during OER operation. Consequently, enhanced OER activity of BSCF mainly attributed to the increased ECSA rather than area-specific activity. This study demonstrates the utility of 3D EIS for tracking the ECSA and the area-specific activity of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuta Inoue, Yuto Miyahara, Kohei Miyazaki, Changhee Lee, Ryo Sakamoto, Takeshi Abe</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A short review on graphene derivatives towards photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202451601003</link>
      <description>Reem Abdullah Rashid Albalushi, Mohd Asmadi Mohammed Yussuf, E3S web of conferences. 516(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394826563

                Graphene oxide is vital in photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting, serving as an essential photoanode material. Its semiconducting nature allows for the generation of photocurrents, promoting water oxidation at the anode and contributing to hydrogen production efficiency. Additionally, graphene is a two-dimensional carbon allotrope that has quickly emerged as a highly promising material in PEC water splitting, potentially transforming renewable energy and sustainable hydrogen generation. Graphene improves PEC water-splitting efficiency by facilitating efficient charge transport, rapid electron transfer, and effective redox reactions at the electrode-electrolyte interface. It possesses high electrical conductivity, a large specific surface area, and excellent charge carrier mobility. Its unique band structure enables efficient light absorption across a broad spectrum, including visible light, resulting in better light-to-electricity conversion. Furthermore, the inherent catalytic activity of graphene speeds up the oxygen evolution process (OER), increasing water oxidation and aiding hydrogen gas production.</description>
      <author>Reem Abdullah Rashid Albalushi, Mohd Asmadi Mohammed Yussuf</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202451601003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Dft Investigation on Surface and Defect Modulation of the Co3o4 Catalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4794879</link>
      <description>Chenxu Huo, Xiufeng Lang, Guoxiong Song, Yujie Wang, Shihong Ren, Wanyi Liao, Hao Guo, Xueguang Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394827873

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Chenxu Huo, Xiufeng Lang, Guoxiong Song, Yujie Wang, Shihong Ren, Wanyi Liao, Hao Guo, Xueguang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4794879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoneedles like FeP engineered on Ni-Foam as an effective catalyst towards overall alkaline freshwater, urea, and seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131725</link>
      <description>Anjali Gupta, Cassia A. Allison, Rishabh Srivastava, Anuj Kumar, Mina Sim, Jeffery Horinek, Lin Wang, Felipe M. de Souza, Sanjay R. Mishra, Felio P&#233;rez, Ram K. Gupta, Tim Dawsey, Fuel. 369(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394835301

                The slow kinetics of electrochemical urea and water oxidation processes at electrode surfaces, which can be recognised as promising resources for pollution-free hydrogen energy production, motivate the scientific community to design and fabricate low-cost, high-efficiency electrocatalysts. Because the performance of electrocatalysts is dependent on their structural, morphological, and electronic properties, herein, the tuning of these properties of Fe3O4@Ni-Foam via phosphorylation and sulfurization, yielding iron phosphide (FeP@Ni-Foam) and iron sulphide (FeS@Ni-Foam), with nanoneedles (along with microstructures) and nanoflower-like morphologies, respectively, is investigated. Among all the prepared samples, FeP is found to be the most effective electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution process (OER), the urea oxidation reaction (UOR), and seawater electrolysis. The overpotentials observed for OER, UOR, and seawater splitting are significantly reduced when using FeP as compared to other materials, with values of 207 mV, 133 mV, and 287.1 mV, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA/cm2. The enhanced catalytic activity of FeP over FeS and Fe3O4 is attributed to morphological changes, improved electronic conductivity, and exceptional endurance. The theoretical studies reveal that FeP has a better density of states over the fermi level than FeS and Fe3O4, lowering the energy barriers for the OER and UOR processes and demonstrating significant catalytic activity towards these processes. This work demonstrates that phosphorylation and sulfurization treatments can alter morphologies and electrical characteristics, hence improving the catalytic activity of the materials.</description>
      <author>Anjali Gupta, Cassia A. Allison, Rishabh Srivastava, Anuj Kumar, Mina Sim, Jeffery Horinek, Lin Wang, Felipe M. de Souza, Sanjay R. Mishra, Felio P&#233;rez, Ram K. Gupta, Tim Dawsey</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchically Structured Graphene Aerogel Supported Nickel&#8211;Cobalt Oxide Nanowires as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081805</link>
      <description>Donglei Guo, Jiaqi Xu, Guilong Liu, Xu Yu, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394836247

                The rational design of a heterostructure electrocatalyst is an attractive strategy to produce hydrogen energy by electrochemical water splitting. Herein, we have constructed hierarchically structured architectures by immobilizing nickel&#8211;cobalt oxide nanowires on/beneath the surface of reduced graphene aerogels (NiCoO2/rGAs) through solvent&#8211;thermal and activation treatments. The morphological structure of NiCoO2/rGAs was characterized by microscopic analysis, and the porous structure not only accelerates the electrolyte ion diffusion but also prevents the agglomeration of NiCoO2 nanowires, which is favorable to expose the large surface area and active sites. As further confirmed by the spectroscopic analysis, the tuned surface chemical state can boost the catalytic active sites to show the improved oxygen evolution reaction performance in alkaline electrolytes. Due to the synergistic effect of morphology and composition effect, NiCoO2/rGAs show the overpotential of 258 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Meanwhile, the small values of the Tafel slope and charge transfer resistance imply that NiCoO2/rGAs own fast kinetic behavior during the OER test. The overlap of CV curves at the initial and 1001st cycles and almost no change in current density after the chronoamperometric (CA) test for 10 h confirm that NiCoO2/rGAs own exceptional catalytic stability in a 1 M KOH electrolyte. This work provides a promising way to fabricate the hierarchically structured nanomaterials as efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Donglei Guo, Jiaqi Xu, Guilong Liu, Xu Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Diffusion-Induced Amorphization of Pt Nanoparticles over Ru Oxide Boost Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01036</link>
      <description>Yanjun Hu, Xiao Han, Sixia Hu, Ge Yu, Tingting Chao, Geng Wu, Yunteng Qu, Cai Chen, Peigen Liu, Xiao Zheng, Qing Yang, Xun Hong, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394836769

                Phase transformation offers an alternative strategy for the synthesis of nanomaterials with unconventional phases, allowing us to further explore their unique properties and promising applications. Herein, we first observed the amorphization of Pt nanoparticles on the RuO2 surface by in situ scanning transmission electron microscopy. Density functional theory calculations demonstrate the low energy barrier and thermodynamic driving force for Pt atoms transferring from the Pt cluster to the RuO2 surface to form amorphous Pt. Remarkably, the as-synthesized amorphous Pt/RuO2 exhibits 14.2 times enhanced mass activity compared to commercial RuO2 catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Water electrolyzer with amorphous Pt/RuO2 achieves 1.0 A cm&#8211;2 at 1.70 V and remains stable at 200 mA cm&#8211;2 for over 80 h. The amorphous Pt layer not only optimized the *O binding but also enhanced the antioxidation ability of amorphous Pt/RuO2, thereby boosting the activity and stability for the OER.</description>
      <author>Yanjun Hu, Xiao Han, Sixia Hu, Ge Yu, Tingting Chao, Geng Wu, Yunteng Qu, Cai Chen, Peigen Liu, Xiao Zheng, Qing Yang, Xun Hong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of Commercial Stainless&#8208;Steel Mesh Size for Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400118</link>
      <description>Yuda Prima Hardiantoa, Mostafa M. Mohamed, Md. Abdul Aziz, Zain H. Yamani, Chemistry - an Asian journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394841074

                The study examines the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalytic efficiency of various stainless&#8208;steel mesh (SSM) sizes in electrolytic cells. Stainless steel is chosen due to its widespread availability and stability, making it an economically viable option. The primary objective of this investigation is to determine the optimal stainless&#8208;steel mesh size among those currently widely available on the market. The classification of stainless&#8208;steel mesh sizes as SS304 is confirmed by the minimal compositional variations observed across all mesh sizes through cyclic voltammetry (CV) and X&#8208;ray fluorescence (XRF) analyses. Remarkably, CV experiments carried out at different scan rates indicate that SSM 200 has the maximum specific electrochemical surface area (ECSA). As a result, SSM 200 demonstrates superior performance in terms of current density response and shows the lowest overpotential in the alkaline medium compared to other stainless&#8208;steel mesh sizes. Stability tests conducted under constant voltage further confirm the remarkable stability of SSM 200, making it an ideal anode for electrolytic cell applications. These findings emphasize the cost&#8208;effectiveness and high stability of SSM 200, presenting intriguing possibilities for future research and advancements in this field.</description>
      <author>Yuda Prima Hardiantoa, Mostafa M. Mohamed, Md. Abdul Aziz, Zain H. Yamani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Possibility of Hydrogen Peroxide Production by 2e&#8722; WOR with Non-Oxygen Evolution Catalysts and Its Application for Organic Dye Decomposition via a Sef-cycled Fenton System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112779</link>
      <description>Jun Xu, Yuqing Wang, Chaoran Dong, Xiaonan Yang, Kan Zhang, Jinyou Shen, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394848812

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Xu, Yuqing Wang, Chaoran Dong, Xiaonan Yang, Kan Zhang, Jinyou Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.112779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prussian blue analogue assisted construction of hierarchical CoS2@(Fe,Ni)S2 heterostructures for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133962</link>
      <description>Chenyu Song, Jui&#8208;Chen Yang, Chinnadurai Ayappan, S. Kannan, Haitang Yang, Ruimin Xing, Hongxun Yang, Shanhu Liu, Colloids and surfaces. A, Physicochemical and engineering aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394849349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenyu Song, Jui&#8208;Chen Yang, Chinnadurai Ayappan, S. Kannan, Haitang Yang, Ruimin Xing, Hongxun Yang, Shanhu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elemental Charge Engineering in Cobalt and Cobalt&#8211;Phosphide Interface for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution and Urea Oxidation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00694</link>
      <description>Xiang Ding, Jun Xiang, Yangyang Wan, Fuzhan Song, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394857746

                The development of cost-effective electrocatalysts with high performance for oxygen evolution and urea oxidation reaction (OER/UOR) is desirable but remains a great challenge. Here, we report a facile strategy for boron-doping cobalt and cobalt&#8211;phosphide interfacial electrocatalysts (B&#8211;Co/Co2P) for bifunctional OER/UOR. By virtue of B doping, the abundant exposed active sites as well as enhanced electrical conductivity can efficiently improve charge migration of the heterogeneous interfacial sites. Therefore, the obtained B&#8211;Co/Co2P electrocatalysts exhibit bifunctional OER/UOR activities with an outstanding overpotential of 284 and 107 mV at an industrial current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2, respectively. Such an excellent catalytic performance is attributed to the fact that the B dopant adjusts the electron distribution of interfacial catalytic sites and optimizes the adsorption/desorption of reaction intermediate species, as well as reduces the energy barriers of water oxidation. Furthermore, the setup two-electrode cell requires merely overpotentials of 280.7 and 56.9 mV to drive 10 mA cm&#8211;2 with robust stability in water splitting and urea electrolysis, respectively. Overall, this report provides a strategy to construct bifunctional OER/UOR catalysts with high efficiency for hydrogen generation.</description>
      <author>Xiang Ding, Jun Xiang, Yangyang Wan, Fuzhan Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward highly accessible Fe-N4 sites via rational design of metal chelated ionic liquids for ORR, OER and HER trifunctional electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151235</link>
      <description>Arunprasath Sathyaseelan, Vijayakumar Elumalai, M. Perumalsamy, Noor Ul Haq Liyakath Ali, Aparna Sajeev, Sang&#8208;Jae Kim, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394858474

                The development of efficient non-precious, atomically dispersed single-atom catalysts (SACs) is vital for advancing fuel cell and water electrolyzer technologies. Here, we rationally designed a metal-chelated ionic liquid (M-IL) as a cornerstone (single source) to synthesize highly efficient M-SAC electrocatalysts via a robust and straightforward approach for ORR, OER, and HER reactions. The effect of temperature, as well as various metals (Fe, Co, Cu, Ni), on the formation of the M-SAC catalyst, was meticulously investigated. Among the designed single-atom catalysts, IL-Fe-SAC-8 delivered superior methanol tolerance toward ORR with a higher half-wave potential (0.90 V vs. RHE) and lower overpotential values of &#8722;0.127 V and 1.511 V vs. RHE, achieving a benchmark current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 toward HER and OER reactions. Thanks to the optimal graphitization, abundant defects, enhanced surface area, and high atomic coordination (supported by HAADF &amp; XANES) of IL-Fe-SAC-8. Furthermore, the flexible DMFC assembled using IL-Fe-SAC-8 cathode delivered 2.5 times higher power density than the Pt/C-based cathode. When we tested a bifunctional IL-Fe-SAC-8||IL-Fe-SAC-8 electrolyzer, it achieved 1.58 V to deliver 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Moreover, for the real-time demonstration, we powered an H-type membrane water electrolyzer (separated by AEM) with a windmill and measured the hydrogen and oxygen produced concerning wind speeds. Furthermore, the produced hydrogen gas is used to power the lab-scale hydrogen fuel cell vehicle. This overall study demonstrates a new pathway to prepare unexplored atomically dispersed catalysts through a single source and template-free approach for next-generation energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Arunprasath Sathyaseelan, Vijayakumar Elumalai, M. Perumalsamy, Noor Ul Haq Liyakath Ali, Aparna Sajeev, Sang&#8208;Jae Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multicomponent nickel-molybdenum-tungsten-based nanorods for stable and efficient alkaline seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.092</link>
      <description>Qi Xiao, Lingxin Kong, Mengmeng Wang, Hui-Hao Li, Xinqi Liu, Ming Xue, Yi Fu, Ji-Sen Li, Qi Xiao, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394858637

                The electrolysis of seawater for hydrogen production holds promise as a sustainable technology for energy generation. Developing water-splitting catalysts with low overpotential and stable operation in seawater is essential. In this study, we employed a hydrothermal method to synthesize NiMoWOX microrods (NiMoWOX@NF). Subsequently, an annealing process yielded a composite N-doped carbon-coated Ni3N/MoO2/WO2 nanorods (NC@Ni3N/MoO2/WO2@NF), preserving the ultrahigh-specific surface area of the original structure. A two-electrode electrolytic cell was assembled using NC@Ni3N/MoO2/WO2@NF as the cathode and NiMoWOX@NF as the anode, demonstrating exceptional performance in seawater splitting. The cell operated at a voltage of 1.51 V with a current density of 100 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 in an alkaline seawater solution. Furthermore, the NC@Ni3N/MoO2/WO2@NF || NiMoWOX@NF electrolytic cell exhibited remarkable stability, running continuously for over 120 h at a current of 1100 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 without any observable delay. These experimental results are corroborated by density functional theory calculations. The NC@Ni3N/MoO2/WO2@NF || NiMoWOX@NF electrolyzer emerges as a promising option for industrial-scale hydrogen production through seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Qi Xiao, Lingxin Kong, Mengmeng Wang, Hui-Hao Li, Xinqi Liu, Ming Xue, Yi Fu, Ji-Sen Li, Qi Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Mn-Bi2O3 from Mn-doped Bi3O4Br Electro(pre)catalyst During Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00633j</link>
      <description>Avinava Kundu, Ashish Kumar Dhillon, Ruchi Singh, Sanmitra Barman, Soumik Siddhanta, Biswarup Chakraborty, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394861831

                A Mn-doped Bi3O4Br has been synthesized using a solvothermal route. The undoped Bi3O4Br and Mn-Bi3O4Br materials possess orthorhombic unit cells with two distinct Bi sites forming a layered atomic arrangement....</description>
      <author>Avinava Kundu, Ashish Kumar Dhillon, Ruchi Singh, Sanmitra Barman, Soumik Siddhanta, Biswarup Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00633j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core-Bishell Nife@Nc@Mos2 for Boosting Electrocatalytic Activity Toward Ultra-Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4795634</link>
      <description>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Chuanbin Li, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Wen Wen, Gang Li, Yanyan Liu, Weihua Hu, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Yongfeng Wang, Baojun Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394861881

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Chuanbin Li, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Wen Wen, Gang Li, Yanyan Liu, Weihua Hu, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Yongfeng Wang, Baojun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4795634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From scrap metal to highly efficient electrodes: harnessing the nanotextured surface of swarf for effective utilisation of Pt and Co for hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00711e</link>
      <description>Madasamy Thangamuthu, Egl&#234; Rejane Kohlrausch, Ming Li, Alistair Speidel, Adam T. Clare, Richard Plummer, Paul Geary, James W. Murray, Andrei N. Khlobystov, Jesum Alves Fernandes, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394861983

                Atomically deposited Pt and Co on nano-grooves result in active and stable electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution and oxygen evolution reactions.</description>
      <author>Madasamy Thangamuthu, Egl&#234; Rejane Kohlrausch, Ming Li, Alistair Speidel, Adam T. Clare, Richard Plummer, Paul Geary, James W. Murray, Andrei N. Khlobystov, Jesum Alves Fernandes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00711e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supporting high-entropy Co-Cr-Fe-Ni-Nb oxide electrocatalyst with nanoporous structure for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151233</link>
      <description>Yen-Hsing Lin, Wence Xu, Zhonghui Gao, Yanqin Liang, Hui Jiang, Zhaoyang Li, Shuilin Wu, Zhenduo Cui, Huaijun Sun, Huifang Zhang, Shengli Zhu, Chemical engineering journal. 489(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394865712

                Microscopic brittleness is a disadvantage of nanoporous metallic electrocatalysts. Design of nanoporous high-entropy alloys is a promising way to solve this problem due to the excellent intrinsic mechanical properties of high-entropy alloys. In this paper, the nanoporous high-entropy Co-Cr-Fe-Ni-Nb oxide electrocatalyst with self-supporting structure are prepared by melt-spinning and chemical dealloying. Due to the different cooling rates, the copper roller surface shows the disordered vermicular nanoporous structure, while the free surface shows the ordered dendritic nanoporous structure. The CoCrFeNiNb-1 sample with ordered nanoporous structure has lower overpotential (&#951;10 = 251 mV and &#951;100 = 304 mV) and smaller Tafel slope (42.7 mV dec&#8211;1) for catalyzing oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The nanoporous Co-Cr-Fe-Ni-Nb catalyst contains abundant active reactants with different valence states, such as metallic, oxides, hydroxides and oxyhydroxides which greatly improves the catalytic activity. Besides, the CoCrFeNiNb-1 sample with ordered nanoporous structure exhibits the good long-term durability.</description>
      <author>Yen-Hsing Lin, Wence Xu, Zhonghui Gao, Yanqin Liang, Hui Jiang, Zhaoyang Li, Shuilin Wu, Zhenduo Cui, Huaijun Sun, Huifang Zhang, Shengli Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing the Active Sites of Oxide Encapsulated Electrocatalysts with Controllable Oxygen Evolution Selectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00074a</link>
      <description>William D. H. Stinson, Robert Stinson, Jingjing Jin, Zejie Chen, Mingjie Xu, Fikret Aydin, Yinxian Wang, Mauro Andrade, Xiaoqing Pan, Tuan Anh Pham, Katherine Hurst, Tadashi Ogitsu, Shane Ardo, Daniel V. Esposito, EES catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394869719

                Electrocatalysts encapsulated by nanoscopic overlayers can control the rate of redox reactions at the outer surface of the overlayer or at the buried interface between the overlayer and the active...</description>
      <author>William D. H. Stinson, Robert Stinson, Jingjing Jin, Zejie Chen, Mingjie Xu, Fikret Aydin, Yinxian Wang, Mauro Andrade, Xiaoqing Pan, Tuan Anh Pham, Katherine Hurst, Tadashi Ogitsu, Shane Ardo, Daniel V. Esposito</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00074a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave sintering construct 3D NiFeAl micro/nano porous bulk electrode for effective oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.103</link>
      <description>Yang Yu, Xiaoyan Peng, J.L. Xu, Ge Gao, Ying Ma, Junming Luo, International journal of hydrogen energy. 67(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394871217

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Yu, Xiaoyan Peng, J.L. Xu, Ge Gao, Ying Ma, Junming Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid-Treated RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanostructures for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00742</link>
      <description>Xinhui Huang, Carmen Lee, Yongdan Li, J&#252; Xu, Daobin Liu, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394871496

                RuO2 is widely used as an acidic electrocatalyst to achieve high catalytic activity, but the severe leaching and scarcity of the Ru element restrict application on a large scale. Strategies such as designing nanostructures and adjusting metals' electronic properties to regulate the adsorption of reaction intermediates can be used for the design and preparation of catalysts. Herein, we designed an acid-treated RuO2/Co3O4 nanostructure electrocatalyst with low Ru content and an intimate heterogeneous interface to disrupt the trade-off relationship between stability and activity. The resulting acid-treated RuO2/Co3O4 displayed an overpotential of 152 mV in a 0.5 M H2SO4 electrolyte, greatly exceeding that of commercial RuO2 (221 mV). Despite continuous operation for 150 h, it still exhibited good stability with a degradation rate of 0.67 mV&#183;h&#8211;1. Multiple characterization analyses revealed that an electron transfer occurs from Ruoct to Cooct(III) sites through the mutual O atoms in acid-treated RuO2/Co3O4, which is further strengthened by the presence of oxygen vacancies. The oxygen vacancy and heterogeneous interface synergistically regulate electronic dispersion, optimize the adsorption of the oxygen intermediates (*OOH), and improve the reaction kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This work brings to light the significance of oxygen vacancies for modulating the electronic structure of RuO2 nanoparticles and enhancing stability on Co3O4 support, thus highlighting the use of nanostructure and interfacial engineering to achieve better acidic OER catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Xinhui Huang, Carmen Lee, Yongdan Li, J&#252; Xu, Daobin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00742</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directed electron transport induced surface reconstruction of 2D NiFe-LDH/Stanene heterojunction catalysts for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124073</link>
      <description>Ze Sheng Lu, Jingkun Wang, Pengfei Zhang, Wenhao Guo, Yongqing Shen, Peizhi Liu, Jianlong Ji, Hao Du, Min Zhao, Hao&#8208;Jie Liang, Junjie Guo, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394872099

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ze Sheng Lu, Jingkun Wang, Pengfei Zhang, Wenhao Guo, Yongqing Shen, Peizhi Liu, Jianlong Ji, Hao Du, Min Zhao, Hao&#8208;Jie Liang, Junjie Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Modulation Via Iron-Incorporated NiO to Boost Urea Oxidation/Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00893</link>
      <description>Guohua He, Xiong-Fei He, Hui-Ying Mu, Ran Su, Yue Zhou, Chao Meng, F. Li, Xuemin Chen, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394874347

                The urea-assisted water splitting not only enables a reduction in energy consumption during hydrogen production but also addresses the issue of environmental pollution caused by urea. Doping heterogeneous atoms in Ni-based electrocatalysts is considered an efficient means for regulating the electronic structure of Ni sites in catalytic processes. However, the current methodologies for synthesizing heteroatom-doped Ni-based electrocatalysts exhibit certain limitations, including intricate experimental procedures, prolonged reaction durations, and low product yield. Herein, Fe-doped NiO electrocatalysts were successfully synthesized using a rapid and facile solution combustion method, enabling the synthesis of 1.1107 g within a mere 5 min. The incorporation of iron atoms facilitates the modulation of the electronic environment around Ni atoms, generating a substantial decrease in the Gibbs free energy of intermediate species for the Fe-NiO catalyst. This modification promotes efficient cleavage of C-N bonds and consequently enhances the catalytic performance of UOR. Benefiting from the tunability of the electronic environment around the active sites and its efficient electron transfer, Fe-NiO electrocatalysts only needs 1.334 V to achieve 50 mA cm-2 during UOR. Moreover, Fe-NiO catalysts were integrated into a dual electrode urea electrolytic system, requiring only 1.43 V of cell voltage at 10 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Guohua He, Xiong-Fei He, Hui-Ying Mu, Ran Su, Yue Zhou, Chao Meng, F. Li, Xuemin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00893</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermally synthesized rGO based FeSe nanocomposite as electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112055</link>
      <description>Wajeeha Perveen, Haifa A. Alyousef, B. M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Khalid I. Hussein, A.M.A. Henaish, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394875382

                Highly productive catalysts are necessary in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to lower overpotential and enhance sluggish kinetics of the reaction. In this work, we present an effective OER electrocatalyst, i.e. composite of FeSe with reduced graphene oxide (FeSe/rGO) fabricated via hydrothermal method. Its main challenges include low electron conductivity and inadequate active site exposure. Meanwhile, the reduced graphene oxide (rGO) composite improves the conductivity, which raises OER activity and provides large electrochemical surface area. Different physical techniques were used to analyze the composite, according to BET surface area of FeSe/rGO was (201 cm3 g-1). To assess electrochemical characteristics of composite electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) cyclic voltammetry (CV), linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) and chronoamperometry was utilized. In comparison to benchmark of commercial RuO2, the FeSe/rGO catalyst exhibits a reduced overpotential (194 mV) and minimal Tafel slope (31 mV dec&#8722;1). FeSe/rGO exhibits exceptional stability and long-term durability to be used for OER. This work not only show low overpotential value of FeSe/rGO nanocomposite, but it also introduces a novel method for producing composite materials that are inexpensive and perform well and can be utilized in different future applications.</description>
      <author>Wajeeha Perveen, Haifa A. Alyousef, B. M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Khalid I. Hussein, A.M.A. Henaish</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Highly Porous and Sheet Like Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Carbon Nanocomposites: A Versatile Catalyst for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202304092</link>
      <description>Sathyanarayanan Shanmugapriya, Anand Kumar, Mohd Afzal, Ratiram Gomaji Chaudhary, Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Aniruddha Mondal, Sudip Mondal, ChemistrySelect. 9(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394877792

                Abstract Fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries are examples of renewable energy technologies that depend on having highly effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, a mesoporous nanostructure composed of Fe 3 O 4 &#8208;Carbon nanocomposites was synthesised using a simple and economically viable approach at a relatively low temperature. The observed catalytic activity of the prepared defected Fe 3 O 4 &#8208;Carbon nanocomposites mesoporous nanostructure was found to be remarkable. Additionally, the nanostructure exhibited a high tolerance to methanol and demonstrated durability towards the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. In the course of the experiment, it was observed that the catalyst exhibited noteworthy activity in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) when compared to the commercially available RuO 2 catalyst. This was evident through a more overpotential value of 325 mV at current density of 10 mA/cm 2 . The catalyst&#8216;s notable capacity for high oxygen reaction activity may potentially enhance the synergistic effect resulting from the combination of defect sites and the porous structure of Fe 3 O 4 &#8208;Carbon nanocomposites. The findings of this study indicate that the Fe 3 O 4 &#8208;Carbon nanocomposites nanostructures exhibit promising attributes as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in real&#8208;world scenarios.</description>
      <author>Sathyanarayanan Shanmugapriya, Anand Kumar, Mohd Afzal, Ratiram Gomaji Chaudhary, Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Aniruddha Mondal, Sudip Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202304092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the Synthesis Route and Co Coverage on Co / Ti3C2Tx Materials for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144269</link>
      <description>C. Kaplan, Ricardo Mogollon Restrepo, Thorsten Schultz, Ke Li, Valeria Nicolosi, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394882507

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C. Kaplan, Ricardo Mogollon Restrepo, Thorsten Schultz, Ke Li, Valeria Nicolosi, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Ru Sites on MOF-derived NC-ZnO for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00586d</link>
      <description>Sagar Varangane, Ragunath Madhu, Shahid Mehmood, Bhavya Jaksani, Vidha Bhasin, B. M. Abraham, Ammavasi Nagaraj, Chandra Shobha Vennapoosa, Venkata Subba Reddy Basireddy, Subrata Kundu, Ujjwal Pal, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394886482

                Developing acid-stable oxygen evolution/reduction reaction (OER/ORR) electrocatalysts is essential for high-performance water splitting. Still, the slow kinetics of the ORR and OER during the discharge and charge processes seriously impede...</description>
      <author>Sagar Varangane, Ragunath Madhu, Shahid Mehmood, Bhavya Jaksani, Vidha Bhasin, B. M. Abraham, Ammavasi Nagaraj, Chandra Shobha Vennapoosa, Venkata Subba Reddy Basireddy, Subrata Kundu, Ujjwal Pal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00586d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deactivation mechanism for water splitting: Recent advances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.528</link>
      <description>Yuqing Jia, Y. J. Li, Qiong Zhang, Sohail Yasin, Xinqian Zheng, Kai Ma, Hua Zhong, Jianfeng Shi, Chaohua Gu, Yuhai Dou, Shi Xue Dou, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394891351

                Abstract Hydrogen (H 2 ) has been regarded as a promising alternative to fossil&#8208;fuel energy. Green H 2 produced via water electrolysis (WE) powered by renewable energy could achieve a zero&#8208;carbon footprint. Considerable attention has been focused on developing highly active catalysts to facilitate the reaction kinetics and improve the energy efficiency of WE. However, the stability of the electrocatalysts hampers the commercial viability of WE. Few studies have elucidated the origin of catalyst degradation. In this review, we first discuss the WE mechanism, including anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Then, we provide strategies used to enhance the stability of electrocatalysts. After that, the deactivation mechanisms of the typical commercialized HER and OER catalysts, including Pt, Ni, RuO 2 , and IrO 2 , are summarized. Finally, the influence of fluctuating energy on catalyst degradation is highlighted and in situ characterization methodologies for understanding the dynamic deactivation processes are described.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Jia, Y. J. Li, Qiong Zhang, Sohail Yasin, Xinqian Zheng, Kai Ma, Hua Zhong, Jianfeng Shi, Chaohua Gu, Yuhai Dou, Shi Xue Dou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFeBP Micro Flowers (MFs) for Highly Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14080698</link>
      <description>Shusen Lin, Md Ahasan Habib, Mehedi Hasan Joni, Sumiya Akter Dristy, Rutuja Mandavkar, Jae&#8208;Hun Jeong, Young-uk Chung, Jihoon Lee, Nanomaterials. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394892213

                Hydrogen is one of the most promising green energy alternatives due to its high gravimetric energy density, zero-carbon emissions, and other advantages. In this work, a CoFeBP micro-flower (MF) electrocatalyst is fabricated as an advanced water-splitting electrocatalyst by a hydrothermal approach for hydrogen production with the highly efficient hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The fabrication process of the CoFeBP MF electrocatalyst is systematically optimized by thorough investigations on various hydrothermal synthesis and post-annealing parameters. The best optimized CoFeBP MF electrode demonstrates HER/OER overpotentials of 20 mV and 219 mV at 20 mA/cm2. The CoFeBP MFs also exhibit a low 2-electrode (2-E) cell voltage of 1.60 V at 50 mA/cm2, which is comparable to the benchmark electrodes of Pt/C and RuO2. The CoFeBP MFs demonstrate excellent 2-E stability of over 100 h operation under harsh industrial operational conditions at 60 &#176;C in 6 M KOH at a high current density of 1000 mA/cm2. The flower-like morphology can offer a largely increased electrochemical active surface area (ECSA), and systematic post-annealing can lead to improved crystallinity in CoFeBP MFs.</description>
      <author>Shusen Lin, Md Ahasan Habib, Mehedi Hasan Joni, Sumiya Akter Dristy, Rutuja Mandavkar, Jae&#8208;Hun Jeong, Young-uk Chung, Jihoon Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14080698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Sulfide Modified NiCu Nanoalloy with Excellent Oxygen Evolution Reaction Properties Prepared through Electrospinning and Heat Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11595-024-2886-6</link>
      <description>Tao Li, Ling Shuai, Shujie Zhong, Qiongyue Lou, Journal of Wuhan University of Technology. 39(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394893809

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Li, Ling Shuai, Shujie Zhong, Qiongyue Lou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11595-024-2886-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction on cobalt atoms embedded nitrogen doped graphene electrocatalysts: a density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00542b</link>
      <description>Meijing Liao, Bing Zhao, Guangsong Zhang, Junhao Peng, Yuexing Zhang, Bo Liu, Xinfang Wang, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394895860

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential to the development of renewable energy conversion and storage technologies. Eight N-doped graphenes containing variable numbers of embedded cobalt atoms (Coxy-NG, x = 1-4,...</description>
      <author>Meijing Liao, Bing Zhao, Guangsong Zhang, Junhao Peng, Yuexing Zhang, Bo Liu, Xinfang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00542b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Pot Synthesis of CoFe-Nanomesh for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05903</link>
      <description>Shashank Sharma, Amit Paul, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394904360

                Iron-doped cobalt-based nanomeshes have been synthesized in a one-pot methodology. 2-Methyl imidazole (2-HMIM) acted as an etchant, while high valent iron increased the acidity of the solution and helped to synthesize ultrathin (thickness 1.9&#8211;2.0 nm) two-dimensional (2D)-nanomeshes having small uniform mesopores (3.8&#8211;4.0 nm) on the basal plane with high surface area and high pore volume. 20% iron-doped nanomesh material (Co0.8Fe0.2(OH)x) revealed the best water oxidation reactivity, having an overpotential of 314 &#177; 3 mV, a mass activity of 413 &#177; 19 A/g, a turnover frequency (TOF) of 1.41 &#177; 0.04 s&#8211;1, and a TOFEIS of 4.15 &#177; 0.04 s&#8211;1. Electrochemical results suggested that the Co0.8Fe0.2(OH)x-nanomesh had a double-layer capacitance of 12.2 mF/cm2, corresponding to a roughness factor of 452, i.e., ion accessibility inside the nanomaterial was improved 452 times compared to the geometrical surface area of the electrode. This remarkable reactivity was due to (a) improved active sites for water oxidation at protruding edge sites and narrow mesopores on the basal planes of nanomeshes, (b) narrow mesopores on the basal planes ensured vertical ion penetration, vacant sites for water oxidation, and easy O2 release from the material, and (c) electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results suggested that nanomesh formation ensured fast charge propagation inside the nanomaterial during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and fast charge transfer at the electrode/electrolyte interface.</description>
      <author>Shashank Sharma, Amit Paul</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity of IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; from Quantum Mechanics and Experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14271</link>
      <description>Soonho Kwon, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger, Reshma R. Rao, Liang Qiao, William A. Goddard, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394907888

                The diversity of chemical environments present on unique crystallographic facets can drive dramatic differences in catalytic activity and the reaction mechanism. By coupling experimental investigations of five different IrO2 facets and theory, we characterize the detailed elemental steps of the surface redox processes and the rate-limiting processes for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The predicted complex evolution of surface adsorbates and the associated charge transfer as a function of applied potential matches well with the distinct redox features observed experimentally for the five facets. Our microkinetic model from grand canonical quantum mechanics (GC-QM) calculations demonstrates mechanistic differences between nucleophilic attack and O&#8211;O coupling across facets, providing the rates as a function of applied potential. These GC-QM calculations explain the higher OER activity observed on the (100), (001), and (110) facets and the lower activity observed for the (101) and (111) facets. This combined study with theory and experiment brings new insights into the structural features that either promote or hinder the OER activity of IrO2, which are expected to provide parallels in structural effects on other oxide surfaces.</description>
      <author>Soonho Kwon, Kelsey A. Stoerzinger, Reshma R. Rao, Liang Qiao, William A. Goddard, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interplay between Catalyst Corrosion and Homogeneous Reactive Oxygen Species in Electrochemical Ozone Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01317</link>
      <description>Rayan Alaufey, Lingyan Zhao, Andrew Lindsay, Tana Siboonruang, Qin Wu, John A. Keith, Ezra C. Wood, Maureen H. Tang, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394909286

                Electrochemical ozone production (EOP), a six-electron water oxidation reaction, offers promising avenues for creating value-added oxidants and disinfectants. However, progress in this field is slowed by a dearth of understanding of fundamental reaction mechanisms. In this work, we combine experimental electrochemistry, spectroscopic detection of reactive oxygen species (ROS), oxygen-anion chemical ionization mass spectrometry, and computational quantum chemistry calculations to determine a plausible reaction mechanism on nickel- and antimony-doped tin oxide (Ni/Sb&#8211;SnO2, NATO), one of the most selective EOP catalysts. Antimony doping is shown to increase the conductivity of the catalyst, leading to improved electrochemical performance. Spectroscopic analysis and electrochemical experiments combined with quantum chemistry predictions reveal that hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) is a critical reaction intermediate. We propose that leached Ni4+ cations catalyze hydrogen peroxide into solution phase hydroperoxyl radicals (&#8226;OOH); these radicals are subsequently oxidized to ozone. Isotopic product analysis shows that ozone is generated catalytically from water and corrosively from the catalyst oxide lattice without regeneration of lattice oxygens. Further quantum chemistry calculations and thermodynamic analysis suggest that the electrochemical corrosion of tin oxide itself might generate hydrogen peroxide, which is then catalyzed to ozone. The proposed pathways explain both the roles of dopants in NATO and its lack of stability. Our study interrogates the possibility that instability and electrochemical activity are intrinsically linked through the formation of ROS. In doing so, we provide the first mechanism for EOP that is consistent with computational and experimental results and highlight the central challenge of instability as a target for future research efforts.</description>
      <author>Rayan Alaufey, Lingyan Zhao, Andrew Lindsay, Tana Siboonruang, Qin Wu, John A. Keith, Ezra C. Wood, Maureen H. Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controling surface reconstruction of transition metal-hydroxide organic framework to enhance the stability of oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.04.223</link>
      <description>Lina Li, Tao Yang, Shuang Liu, Linlin Zhou, Kang Wang, Enhui Wang, Xiangtao Yu, Kuo&#8208;Chih Chou, Xinmei Hou, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394912622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lina Li, Tao Yang, Shuang Liu, Linlin Zhou, Kang Wang, Enhui Wang, Xiangtao Yu, Kuo&#8208;Chih Chou, Xinmei Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.04.223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium-based catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109906</link>
      <description>Jiawei Ge, Wang Xian, Heyuan Tian, Hao Wan, Wei Ma, Jiangying Qu, Junjie Ge, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394913003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Ge, Wang Xian, Heyuan Tian, Hao Wan, Wei Ma, Jiangying Qu, Junjie Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Biomimetic Catalyst with Mn&lt;sub&gt;4&#8208;x&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;CaO&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Structure for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401509</link>
      <description>Zhaoyi Xu, Zhibin Geng, Jianghao Wang, Qian Zhu, Zhiyu Shao, Ming Ya, Ying Yu, Guangshe Li, Shouhua Feng, Guangshe Li, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394917493

                Abstract In natural plants, Mn 4 CaO 5 cluster with metal&#8208;oxo &#8220;distorted chair&#8221;&#8208;like structure exhibits excellent oxygen evolution activity. However, the performance of biomimetic oxygen evolution catalysts based on the Mn 4 CaO 5 &#8208;like structure is far inferior to expectations. Herein, Ca and Ni are first doped together into birnessite and constructed a &#8220;distorted chair&#8221;&#8208;like structure unit Mn 4&#8208;x Ni x CaO 5 in a birnessite&#8208;like Ca&#8208;Mn(Ni)&#8208;O catalyst, the biomimetic Mn 4&#8208;x Ni x CaO 5 unit efficiently activates lattice oxygen and boosts the O&#9472;O coupling in oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which allows the catalyst to perform superior OER activity with an outstanding overpotential of 184 mV at 300 mA cm &#8722;2 . Besides, the birnessite&#8208;like Ca&#8208;Mn(Ni)&#8208;O catalyst is stabilized by coupling to NiMnO 3 nanoplate, thus forming a stable catalyst that can work for &gt;500 h without attenuation. This work optimizes biomimetic structures by introducing new elements, which provides new insight into developing efficient biomimetic materials.</description>
      <author>Zhaoyi Xu, Zhibin Geng, Jianghao Wang, Qian Zhu, Zhiyu Shao, Ming Ya, Ying Yu, Guangshe Li, Shouhua Feng, Guangshe Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Accumulation Induced by Electron Injection&#8208;Incomplete Discharge on NiFe LDH for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402397</link>
      <description>Rongrong Zhang, Yu Han, Qilong Wu, Min L&#252;, Guangsheng Liu, Zhangtao Guo, Yaowen Zhang, Jianrong Zeng, Xiaofeng Wu, Dongdong Zhang, Liyun Wu, Nan Song, Ping Yuan, Aijun Du, Keke Huang, Jun Chen, Xiangdong Yao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394918093

                Optimizing the local electronic structure of electrocatalysts can effectively lower the energy barrier of electrochemical reactions, thus enhancing the electrocatalytic activity. However, the intrinsic contribution of the electronic effect is still experimentally unclear. In this work, the electron injection-incomplete discharge approach to achieve the electron accumulation (EA) degree on the nickel-iron layered double hydroxide (NiFe LDH) is proposed, to reveal the intrinsic contribution of EA toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Such NiFe LDH with EA effect results in only 262 mV overpotential to reach 50 mA cm-2, which is 51 mV-lower compared with pristine NiFe LDH (313 mV), and reduced Tafel slope of 54.8 mV dec-1 than NiFe LDH (107.5 mV dec-1). Spectroscopy characterizations combined with theoretical calculations confirm that the EA near concomitant Vo can induce a narrower energy gap and lower thermodynamic barrier to enhance OER performance. This study clarifies the mechanism of the EA effect on OER activity, providing a direct electronic structure modulation guideline for effective electrocatalyst design.</description>
      <author>Rongrong Zhang, Yu Han, Qilong Wu, Min L&#252;, Guangsheng Liu, Zhangtao Guo, Yaowen Zhang, Jianrong Zeng, Xiaofeng Wu, Dongdong Zhang, Liyun Wu, Nan Song, Ping Yuan, Aijun Du, Keke Huang, Jun Chen, Xiangdong Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diamondoid Ni(II) Coordination Polymer as an Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions and Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400218</link>
      <description>Sanobar Naaz, Taposi Chatterjee, Subir Roy, Basudeb Dutta, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Masoom Raza Siddiqui, Malik Wahid, Seikh Mafiz Alam, Mohammad Hedayetullah Mir, Chemistry - an Asian journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394920446

                We have successfully synthesized a new Ni(II)-based coordination polymer (CP) [Ni2(cis-1,4-chdc)2(4,4'-bpy)3(H2O)2] (1); (cis-1,4- H2chdc = cis-1,4-cyclohexanedicarboxylic acid and 4,4'-bpy = 4,4'-bipyridine) employing slow diffusion method in a single pot technique. The connectivity of Ni(II) ions and bridging cis-1,4-chdc ligand gives rise to a three-dimensional (3D) framework with 2-fold interpenetrated diamondoid topology. Interestingly, the synthesized CP acts as efficient catalyst for electrocatalytic water splitting. The water oxidation activity of compound 1 exhibits Tafel slope equivalent to 361.48 mV.dec-1 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 353.53 mV.dec-1 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in an alkaline medium while almost similar values of Tafel slope for HER and OER equivalent to 287.33 mV.dec-1 and 289.93 mV.dec-1 respectively in acidic medium. Thus, the compound 1 has excellent efficacy in catalyzing HER and OER in acidic as well as alkaline medium, which is ascribed to its distinctive 3D architecture.</description>
      <author>Sanobar Naaz, Taposi Chatterjee, Subir Roy, Basudeb Dutta, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Masoom Raza Siddiqui, Malik Wahid, Seikh Mafiz Alam, Mohammad Hedayetullah Mir</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supporting nanosheet electrode for efficient oxygen evolution in a wide pH range: engineering electronic structure of Co3O4 by Fe doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05521-5</link>
      <description>Xinqi Cheng, Yanying Liu, Yunshan Shang, Ningning Han, Guangli He, Zhuang Xu, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394923385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinqi Cheng, Yanying Liu, Yunshan Shang, Ningning Han, Guangli He, Zhuang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05521-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antimony tin oxide supported iridium oxide nanocatalyst with bi-directional strains for oxygen evolution reaction in PEM electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118284</link>
      <description>Xinke Wu, Yi He, Lecheng Lei, Shaoyun Hao, Xingwang Zhang, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394926709

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinke Wu, Yi He, Lecheng Lei, Shaoyun Hao, Xingwang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supported monometallic FeS2/FeOOH-ZnO@NF with abundant oxygen vacancies as efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the OER and HER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174525</link>
      <description>Yuying Yang, Yanzhe Chen, Yaling Xiong, Yilun He, Qiannan Sun, Dequan Xu, Zhongai Hu, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394927057

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuying Yang, Yanzhe Chen, Yaling Xiong, Yilun He, Qiannan Sun, Dequan Xu, Zhongai Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal complexes of bipyridine-functionalized covalent organic frameworks as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02681-1</link>
      <description>Zhuangzhuang Wu, Tian Xia, Ying Liang, Yongpeng Li, Zhuyin Sui, Lijuan Feng, Daoxiong Wu, Xinlong Tian, Qi Chen, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394927346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuangzhuang Wu, Tian Xia, Ying Liang, Yongpeng Li, Zhuyin Sui, Lijuan Feng, Daoxiong Wu, Xinlong Tian, Qi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02681-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly defective NiFeV layered triple hydroxide with enhanced electrocatalytic activity and stability for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmats.2024.1388695</link>
      <description>Xiyuan Li, Lincheng Xu, Qianqian Wang, Ya Yan, Yue Feng, Fan Li, Frontiers in materials. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394928501

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the most important components of various electrochemical systems such as water splitting, metal air batteries, and carbon dioxide reduction. However, the four-electron process of OER suffers from intrinsically sluggish kinetics, which contributes to significant overpotential in the electrochemical system. Herein, highly defective NiFeV layered triple hydroxide (LTH) catalyst was efficiently prepared using a one-step hydrothermal method. The crystal structure, electronic structure, and surface composition of NiFeV LTH were characterized by X-ray diffraction and photoelectron spectroscopy. Moreover, NiFeV LTH demonstrated a superior OER catalytic performance with-low overpotential (158 mV @10 mA&#183;cm -2 ), related small Tafel slope (102.3 mV&#183;dec &#8722;1 ), and long-term stability at a high current density of 100 mA&#183;cm -2 . In situ Raman spectroscopy was applied to investigate the surface reconstruction during the OER process. It is revealed that Ni species were the most active sites at low overpotential, with the potential increasing subsequently Fe and V gradually participates in the catalytic reaction, the Fe and Ni species as OER catalytic active sites lead to the excellent OER catalytic activity of NiFeV LTH, and inhibited the further dissolution of high-valence NiOOH at high overpotential. The mechanism induced the outstanding activity and stability at high current densities in NiFeV LTH system. Dissolution of vanadium excited the active sites of NiFeV LTH synthesized by hydrothermal method which promoted both activity and stability, while the changes of surface species at different OER potentials were detected by in situ Raman spectroscopy.</description>
      <author>Xiyuan Li, Lincheng Xu, Qianqian Wang, Ya Yan, Yue Feng, Fan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmats.2024.1388695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pore Size-Regulated Vertically Aligned CoFe-LDH on a Carbon Support for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01018</link>
      <description>Parul Aggarwal, Palak Mehra, Amit Paul, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394931528

                Porous carbon-supported CoFe-layered double hydroxide (LDH)-based catalysts were synthesized and utilized as excellent oxygen evolution reaction catalysts in alkaline medium. High-resolution transmission electron microscopy images and N2-sorption experiments suggested vertical growth of LDH on the carbon support and a narrow mesoporous nature of the materials, respectively. We proposed that the surface oxygen functional groups of carbon materials provided the nucleation sites for the crystal growth of the LDH on the carbon support utilizing short-range electrostatic interactions, which led to vertical growth of LDH with a narrow mesoporous nature. Among the synthesized materials, CoFe-LDH/MMC showed a remarkable mass activity of 559.2 A g&#8211;1, a turnover frequency of 4.22 s&#8211;1, and a massive roughness factor value of 269. This excellent reactivity has been attributed to (a) the vertically aligned narrow mesoporous nature of the material that increased the electrolyte accessibility inside the material and thus improved active sites for catalysis, (b) the high electrical conductivity of the material that also enhanced accessibility, reduced resistance for charge transfer at the electrode/electrolyte interface, and reduced resistance for intermediate formation during water oxidation, and (c) the increased electron contribution to the 3d orbital of cobalt from carbon that weakened the Co&#8211;oxygen bond and thus further facilitated the formation of the O&#8211;O bond and O2 desorption during water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Parul Aggarwal, Palak Mehra, Amit Paul</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric-field-assisted proton coupling enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47568-y</link>
      <description>Xuelei Pan, Mengyu Yan, Qian Liu, Xunbiao Zhou, Xiaobin Liao, Congli Sun, Jiexin Zhu, Callum D. McAleese, Pierre Couture, Matthew K. Sharpe, Richard W. Smith, Nianhua Peng, Jonathan England, Shik Chi Edman Tsang, Yunlong Zhao, Liqiang Mai, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394933471

                Abstract The discovery of Mn-Ca complex in photosystem II stimulates research of manganese-based catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, conventional chemical strategies face challenges in regulating the four electron-proton processes of OER. Herein, we investigate alpha-manganese dioxide (&#945;-MnO 2 ) with typical Mn IV -O-Mn III -H x O motifs as a model for adjusting proton coupling. We reveal that pre-equilibrium proton-coupled redox transition provides an adjustable energy profile for OER, paving the way for in-situ enhancing proton coupling through a new &#8220;reagent&#8221;&#8212; external electric field. Based on the &#945;-MnO 2 single-nanowire device, gate voltage induces a 4-fold increase in OER current density at 1.7 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode. Moreover, the proof-of-principle external electric field-assisted flow cell for water splitting demonstrates a 34% increase in current density and a 44.7 mW/cm&#178; increase in net output power. These findings indicate an in-depth understanding of the role of proton-incorporated redox transition and develop practical approach for high-efficiency electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Xuelei Pan, Mengyu Yan, Qian Liu, Xunbiao Zhou, Xiaobin Liao, Congli Sun, Jiexin Zhu, Callum D. McAleese, Pierre Couture, Matthew K. Sharpe, Richard W. Smith, Nianhua Peng, Jonathan England, Shik Chi Edman Tsang, Yunlong Zhao, Liqiang Mai</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47568-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the High-Entropy Oxide Composition Space: Insights through Comparing Experimental with Theoretical Models for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05915</link>
      <description>Vladislav A. Mints, Katrine L. Svane, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394934324

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is key for the transition to a hydrogen-based energy economy. The observed activity of the OER catalysts arises from the combined effects of surface area, intrinsic activity, and stability. Therefore, alloys provide an effective platform to search for catalysts that balance these factors. In particular, high-entropy oxides provide a vast material composition space that could contain catalysts with optimal OER performance. In this work, the OER performance of the AuIrOsPdPtReRhRu composition space was modeled using an experimentally obtained dataset of 350 nanoparticles. This machine-learned model based on experimental data found the optimal catalyst to be a mixture of AuIrOsPdRu. However, as a "black-box model", it cannot explain the underlying chemistry. Therefore, density functional theory (DFT) calculations were performed to provide a complementary theoretical model with defined assumptions and, hence, a physical interpretation through comparison with the experimental model. The DFT calculations suggest that the majority of the activity originates from Ru and Ir active sites and that the addition of Pd improves the performance of these sites. However, the DFT calculation did not find the experimentally observed beneficial effects of Au and Os. Therefore, we hypothesize that the Os contributed to the performance of the tested catalysts by roughening the surface, whereas Au fulfilled the role of a structural support. Overall, it is demonstrated how machine learning can help accelerate catalyst discovery, and combining machine-learned models obtained from experimental data with models based on DFT calculations can provide important insights into the complex chemistry of OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Vladislav A. Mints, Katrine L. Svane, Jan Rossmeisl, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co3O4/Activated Carbon Nanocomposites as Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt03720g</link>
      <description>Fausthon F. da Silva, Lucian Barbu&#8208;Tudoran, Fausthon F. da Silva, Cristian Leo&#537;tean, Alandelon Lima, Anna&#237;res A. Louren&#231;o, Andr&#233; Luiz Menezes de Oliveira, Ovidiu Pan&#259;, Arpad Mihai Rostas, Vinicius Dias Silva, Daniel A. Macedo, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394937800

                The Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) is crucial in various processes, such as hydrogen production via water splitting. Several electrocatalysts, including metal oxides, have been evaluated to enhance the reaction efficiency....</description>
      <author>Fausthon F. da Silva, Lucian Barbu&#8208;Tudoran, Fausthon F. da Silva, Cristian Leo&#537;tean, Alandelon Lima, Anna&#237;res A. Louren&#231;o, Andr&#233; Luiz Menezes de Oliveira, Ovidiu Pan&#259;, Arpad Mihai Rostas, Vinicius Dias Silva, Daniel A. Macedo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt03720g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of supramolecular organic frameworks with reactive oxygen species enhancement properties for photocatalytic organic transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114153</link>
      <description>Xing Yang, Qianqian Wang, Shengsheng Yu, Kaijun Niu, G. Li, Hui Liu, Ling&#8208;Bao Xing, Molecular catalysis. 560(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394946116

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xing Yang, Qianqian Wang, Shengsheng Yu, Kaijun Niu, G. Li, Hui Liu, Ling&#8208;Bao Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Probing the Active Sites of Oxide Encapsulated Electrocatalysts with Controllable Oxygen Evolution Selectivity"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00074a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394960153

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00074a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and Oxygen Evolution Activity of the Composite Oxides of Ni and Co</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1994.3.3235</link>
      <description>Ping Cheng, Qiuzhi Shi, Jianming Zhang, Changchun Yang, Yingyong huaxue. 11(3)] 1994. https://openalex.org/W4394833728

                The composite oxide NiCo2O4 prepared by aikali dipping and thermodecomposition showed a higher oxygen evolution activity in alkaline solution,The influences of preparation conditions on the oxygen evolution activity of NiCo2O4 were studied.</description>
      <author>Ping Cheng, Qiuzhi Shi, Jianming Zhang, Changchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 1994 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1994.3.3235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Reconstruction Chemistry for Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400076</link>
      <description>Peiyu Ma, Chuanyi Jia, Z. D. Zhang, Jun Bao, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394808463

                Abstract Developing efficient and stable catalysts for energy conversion processes such as alkaline oxygen evolution reaction is one of the key measures to solve the energy shortage problems. During alkaline oxygen evolution, several electrocatalysts would undergo structural reconstruction from the pre&#8208;catalyst state to the real&#8208;catalyst state. The structural reconstruction may modify the quantity and characterizations of the active sites, thus affecting the configuration and adsorption strength of the reaction key intermediates, which directly influence the activity and stability of the electrocatalysts. Understanding the structural transformation chemistry is essential for the rational design of highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts. In this review, we have deeply discussed the role and regulation strategies of structural reconstruction. Then, on this basis, we described some characterization technologies to probe the structural reconstruction of catalysts during alkaline OER. Finally, we put forward some views on the future research direction of this vital field.</description>
      <author>Peiyu Ma, Chuanyi Jia, Z. D. Zhang, Jun Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur doped Co3O4 catalyst for efficient and stable oxygen evolution reaction at high current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112051</link>
      <description>Guijin Yang, Y. Li, Yujun Fu, Jinyun Li, Jingru Jiao, Weiwei Wang, Dongyang Fang, Chen Cheng, Zhengmei Zhang, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394842125

                The development of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts with excellent stability at high current density is key to achieving efficient hydrogen production, and spinel Co3O4 is a promising alternative material, yet its application to high current density remains challenging. Here, we employ doping engineering to apply Co3O4 modified by S to the OER. The doping of S optimizes the electronic environment of Co and generates richer oxygen defects, leading to excellent catalytic performance and cycling stability at high current density. The best performing S-Co3O4-45@NF catalyst that required 265 mV to achieve 10 mA/cm2. Furthermore, it exhibits outstanding cycling durability at 10, 200 and 1200 mA/cm2 as well as excellent mass transfer performance in multi-step current tests. The present work provides ideas for the development of low-cost and efficient transition metal-based electrocatalysts at high current density.</description>
      <author>Guijin Yang, Y. Li, Yujun Fu, Jinyun Li, Jingru Jiao, Weiwei Wang, Dongyang Fang, Chen Cheng, Zhengmei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Generations of Volcano Plots for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Beyond Proton-Coupled Electron Transfer Steps?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00048</link>
      <description>Kai S. Exner, Accounts of chemical research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394800474

                ConspectusDue to its importance for electrolyzers or metal-air batteries for energy conversion or storage, there is huge interest in the development of high-performance materials for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Theoretical investigations have aided the search for active material motifs through the construction of volcano plots for the kinetically sluggish OER, which involves the transfer of four proton-electron pairs to form a single oxygen molecule. The theory-driven volcano approach has gained unprecedented popularity in the catalysis and energy communities, largely due to its simplicity, as adsorption free energies can be used to approximate the electrocatalytic activity by heuristic descriptors.In the last two decades, the binding-energy-based volcano method has witnessed a renaissance with special concepts being developed to incorporate missing factors into the analysis. To this end, this Account summarizes and discusses the different generations of volcano plots for the example of the OER. While first-generation methods relied on the assessment of the thermodynamic information for the OER reaction intermediates by means of scaling relations, the second and third generations developed strategies to include overpotential and kinetic effects into the analysis of activity trends. Finally, the fourth generation of volcano approaches allowed the incorporation of various mechanistic pathways into the volcano methodology, thus paving the path toward data- and mechanistic-driven volcano plots in electrocatalysis.Although the concept of volcano plots has been significantly expanded in recent years, further research activities are discussed by challenging one of the main paradigms of the volcano concept. To date, the evaluation of activity trends relies on the assumption of proton-coupled electron transfer steps (CPET), even though there is experimental evidence of sequential proton-electron transfer (SPET) steps. While the computational assessment of SPET for solid-state electrodes is ambitious, it is strongly suggested to comprehend their importance in energy conversion and storage processes, including the OER. This can be achieved by knowledge transfer from homogeneous to heterogeneous electrocatalysis and by focusing on the material class of single-atom catalysts in which the active center is well defined. The derived concept of how to analyze the importance of SPET for mechanistic pathways in the OER over solid-state electrodes could further shape our understanding of the proton-electron transfer steps at electrified solid/liquid interfaces, which is crucial for further progress toward sustainable energy and climate neutrality.</description>
      <author>Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Oxygen Vacancy Defects in Heterogeneous NiO-CeO2&#8722;&#948; Hollow Multi-shelled Structure for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40242-024-4048-y</link>
      <description>Huan Wang, Guanzhong Gong, Guohua Sun, Jian Qi, Rong Yu, Dan Wang, Chemical research in Chinese universities/Chemical Research in Chinese Universities. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394821011

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Wang, Guanzhong Gong, Guohua Sun, Jian Qi, Rong Yu, Dan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40242-024-4048-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXene-induced electronic structure modulation of Fe-Al-LDH to boost the Fenton-like Reaction: Singlet oxygen evolution and electron-transfer mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.03.023</link>
      <description>Zhongzhu Yang, Zeyan Zhou, Xiaofei Tan, Guangming Zeng, Chang Zhang, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394849375

                Layered double hydroxide (LDH) based heterogonous peroxymonosulfate (PMS) activation degradation of pollutants has attracted extensive attention. The challenge is to selectively regulate the traditional free radical dominant degradation pathway into a nonradical degradation pathway. Herein, an interface architecture of Ti3C2Tx-MXene (MXene) loading on the Fe-Al LDH scaffold was developed, which showed excellent stability and robust resistance against harsh conditions. Significantly, the rate constant for tetracycline hydrochloride (TC) degradation in the MXene-LDH/PMS process was 0.421 min&#8722;1, which was ten times faster than the rate constant for pure Fe-Al LDH (0.042 min&#8722;1). Specifically, more reactive Fe with the closer d-band center to the Fermi level results in higher electron transfer efficiency. The occupations of Fe-3d orbitals in Mxene/Fe-Al LDH are pushed above the Fermi level to generate, which results in higher PMS adsorption and inhibition of the release of oxygen-containing active species intermediates, leading to the enhanced 1O2 generation. Additionally, the built-in electric field in the heterojunction was driven by the charge redistribution between MXene and Fe-Al LDH, resulting in a mediated-electron transfer mechanism, differentiating it from the Fe-Al LDH/PMS system. It was fascinating that MXene/Fe-Al LDH achieved satisfactory treatment efficiency in continuous column reactor and real landfill leachate.</description>
      <author>Zhongzhu Yang, Zeyan Zhou, Xiaofei Tan, Guangming Zeng, Chang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.03.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In-situ&lt;/i&gt; Analysis of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction on CuO Film in Alkaline Solution by Surface Interrogation Scanning Electrochemical Microscopy: Investigating Active Sites (Cu&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt;) and Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00628c</link>
      <description>Song Han, Jae Soo Yoo, Won Tae Choi, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394843023

                This study examines CuO film as a non-precious metal catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in an alkaline solution (pH 13) using surface interrogation scanning electrochemical microscopy (SI-SECM). We...</description>
      <author>Song Han, Jae Soo Yoo, Won Tae Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00628c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure and Texture Evolution in Cold&#8208;Rolled and Annealed Oxygen&#8208;Free Copper Sheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202404.1135.v1</link>
      <description>Jing Qin, Xun Li, Dongsheng Wang, Chen Zhou, Tao Hu, Jingwen Wang, Cijun Shuai, Yujun Hu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394922501

                The commercial oxygen-free copper sheets were cold-rolled with reduction rates ranging from 20% to 87% reduction rate and annealed at 400, 500 and 600 &#176;C. The microstructure and texture evolution during cold-rolling and annealing processes were studied using optical microscopy (OM), the scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and the electron back-scattered diffraction (EBSD). The results show that the deformation textures of {123} (S) , {112} (Copper) and {110} (Brass) were continuously enhanced with the increase of cold-rolling reduction. The orientations along the &#945;-oriented fiber converged towards Brass and the orientation density of &#946; fiber obviously increased when the rolling reduction exceeded 60%. The recrystallization texture was significantly affected by the cold-rolling reduction. After 60% cold-rolling reduction, Copper and S textures components gradually decreased and {011} recrystallization texture component formed with the increase of annealing temperature. After 87% cold-rolling reduction, a strong Cube texture formed and other textures were inhibited with the increase of annealing temperature. The strong Brass and S deformation texture was conducive to the formation of a strong Cube annealing texture. The density of annealing twin boundary decreased with the increase of annealing temperature, and more annealing twin boundaries formed in the oxygen-free copper sheets with the increase of cold rolling reduction.</description>
      <author>Jing Qin, Xun Li, Dongsheng Wang, Chen Zhou, Tao Hu, Jingwen Wang, Cijun Shuai, Yujun Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202404.1135.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Doping Enhances Zif-67 Based Hierarchical Carbon Bifunction Catalyst for Oxygen Reduction and Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4795294</link>
      <description>Kanjun Sun, Xiaofei Lei, Xuan Xie, Wenjuan Li, Wenbo Hou, Hui Peng, Guofu Ma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394803034

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Kanjun Sun, Xiaofei Lei, Xuan Xie, Wenjuan Li, Wenbo Hou, Hui Peng, Guofu Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4795294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protonated g-C3N4/oxygen-doped g-C3N4 S-scheme homojunction fabricated by electrostatic self-assembly for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution and tetracycline hydrochloride degradation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119153</link>
      <description>Cheng-Jie Zheng, R. Z. Zhang, Ke Xu, Jian Zhang, Kai Wang, Wei Chen, Guobo Huang, Hongfei Yin, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394928332

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng-Jie Zheng, R. Z. Zhang, Ke Xu, Jian Zhang, Kai Wang, Wei Chen, Guobo Huang, Hongfei Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecotoxicity of 2,4-Dichlorophenol to Microsorium pteropus by High Spatial Resolution Mapping of Stoma Oxygen Emission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w16081146</link>
      <description>Nanshan Zhong, Daoyong Zhang, Water. 16(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394932330

                The toxicity of emerging organic pollutants to photosystems of aquatic plants is still not well clarified. This study aimed to develop a novel ecotoxicological experimental protocol based on nanoscale electrochemical mapping of photosynthetic oxygen evolution of aquatic plants by scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM). The protocol was also checked by confocal laser scanning microscopy (CLSM), the traditional Clark oxygen electrode method, and the chlorophyll fluorescence technique. The typical persistent organic pollutant 2,4-dichlorophenol (2,4-DCP) in a water environment and the common aquatic Microsorium pteropus (M. pteropus) were chosen as the model organic pollutant and tested plant, respectively. It was found that the SECM method could discriminate the responses of stoma micromorphology and spatial pattens of photosynthetic oxygen evolution on single stoma well. The shape of stoma blurred with increasing 2,4-DCP concentration, which was in good agreement with the CLSM images. The dose&#8211;response curves and IC50 values obtained from the SECM data were verified by the data measured by the traditional Clark oxygen electrode method and chlorophyll fluorescence test. The IC50 value of single-stoma oxygen emission of plant leaves exposed for 24 h, which was derived from the SECM current data (32,535 &#956;g L&#8722;1), was close to those calculated from the maximum photosynthetic efficiency (Fv/Fm) measured by the chlorophyll fluorescence test (33,963 &#956;g L&#8722;1) and the Clark oxygen electrode method photosynthetic oxygen evolution rate (32,375 &#956;g L&#8722;1). The 72 h and 96 h 2,4-DCP exposure data further confirmed the reliability of the nanoscale stoma oxygen emission mapping methodology for ecotoxicological assessment. In this protocol, the procedures for how to collect effective electrochemical data and how to extract useful information from the single-stoma oxygen emission pattern were well established. This study showed that SECM is a feasible and reliable ecotoxicological tool for evaluation of toxicity of organic pollutants to higher plants with a unique nanoscale visualization advantage over the conventional methods.</description>
      <author>Nanshan Zhong, Daoyong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/w16081146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Oxidation of Organic Compounds and the Creation of Metal Oxide Nanocomposites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47392/irjaem.2024.0130</link>
      <description>S. S. Mokashi, Anil Kumar Sharma, A. S. Parlikar, Deleted Journal. 2(04)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394812768

                Electrochemical regeneration suffers from low regeneration efficiency due to side reactions like oxygen evolution, as well as oxidation of the adsorbent. Utilizing the solution cast method, we three alternative strategies for producing Cr2O3 nanoparticle-laden polyvinyl alcohol (PVA) solid polymer films. The peaks in the FTIR spectrum at molecular vibration and chemical bonding frequencies indicate that Cr2O3 is present in the PVA polymer structure.</description>
      <author>S. S. Mokashi, Anil Kumar Sharma, A. S. Parlikar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47392/irjaem.2024.0130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of amorphous catalysts in the field of electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.66</link>
      <description>Zhenyang Yu, Qi Sun, Lianwang Zhang, Yang Hui, Yuefang Chen, Jintang Guo, Mengmeng Zhang, Zhenyu Zhang, Yijiao Jiang, Microstructures. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394869918

                Amorphous materials feature unique structures and physicochemical properties, resulting in their synthesis and applications becoming a dynamic and fascinating new research direction. The high specific surface area, abundant active sites, and good electron transport properties endow amorphous materials with excellent electrocatalytic properties, thus appealing to increasing attention. Based on this, the summary of the current research status of amorphous catalysts in the field of electrocatalysis is urgent and important. In this review, the research progress of amorphous catalysts in electrocatalysis is systematically introduced, focusing on the classification, synthesis methods, modification strategies, characterizations, and electrocatalytic application (including hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, and nitrogen reduction reaction). Finally, this review proposes the prospects and challenges for the future development of high-active and high-selectivity amorphous electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhenyang Yu, Qi Sun, Lianwang Zhang, Yang Hui, Yuefang Chen, Jintang Guo, Mengmeng Zhang, Zhenyu Zhang, Yijiao Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.66</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Water Flipping and Electrostatic Fields at the Electrode:Electrolyte Interface from operando Nonlinear Optical Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2023-m9d1z-v3</link>
      <description>Raiden Speelman, Franz M. Geiger, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394926192

                While water's oxygen is the electron source in the industrially important oxygen evolution reaction, the strong absorber problem clouds our view of how the Stern layer water molecules orient themselves in response to applied potentials. Here, we report nonlinear optical measurements on nickel electrodes held at pH 13 indicating a disorder-to-order transition in the Stern layer water molecules prior to the onset of Faradaic current. A full water monolater (1.1 x 10^15 cm-2) aligns with oxygen atoms pointing towards the electrode at +0.8 V and the associated work is 80 kJ mol-1. Our experiments identify water flipping energetics as a target for understanding overpotentials, advance molecular electrochemistry, provide benchmarks for electrical double layer models, and serve as a diagnostic tool for understanding electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Raiden Speelman, Franz M. Geiger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2023-m9d1z-v3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining of Stable, Low-Cost Metal Oxides as Potential Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aichem.2024.100065</link>
      <description>Jing Xue, Hao Li, Artificial intelligence chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394859623

                Metal oxides (MOs) are a class of electrocatalysts which could be the low-cost alternatives to precious metals. However, many MOs suffer from poor stability under electrochemical operating conditions. The Materials Project stands out as one of the largest computational materials databases to date, where the bulk Pourbaix diagrams are essential in assessing the aqueous stability of potential electrocatalysts. Herein, we performed data mining from the Materials Project database to identify potentially stable MOs for industrially important electrocatalytic reactions including oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), chlorine evolution reaction (CER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR). We found that many MOs can be potentially stable under electrocatalytic conditions, especially in neutral and alkaline medium. Finally, we summarized those MOs that had been previously experimentally synthesized but haven't been explored as electrocatalysts. This comprehensive assessment effectively narrows down the exploration scope and facilitates the evaluation of material stability.</description>
      <author>Jing Xue, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aichem.2024.100065</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional flower-like N-doped tungsten carbide for enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112048</link>
      <description>Changchun He, Li Li, Ping Yin, Ting Lei, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. 191(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394834601

                It has been critical and challenging to develop non-precious transition-metal-based eletrocatalysts with low-cost and long-term durability for efficient water splitting. Herein, self-supported nitrogen-doped tungsten carbide on iron-nickel foam (N-WC@INF) with three-dimensional flower-like structure was prepared by a simple hydrothermal reaction followed by simultaneous nitridation and carbonization. The resulting N-WC@INF exhibits an overpotential of 103 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline media and a low Tafel slope of 47 mV dec&#8722;1, accompanied by a negligible loss of overpotential after 30 h consecutive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Additionally, N-WC@INF shows promising activity for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with an overpotential of 224 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a low Tafel slope of 22 mV dec&#8722;1.</description>
      <author>Changchun He, Li Li, Ping Yin, Ting Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Heterostructured NiS/NiSe2 and their application in electrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.101</link>
      <description>Y. Li, Haiyan Du, Yufang Su, Jinsheng Zhao, Konggang Qu, Xianxi Zhang, Yan Zhang, Yunyun Dong, Zhi Guo, International journal of hydrogen energy. 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394782710

                Development of non-precious metal electrocatalyst that can efficiently catalyze the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) simultaneously, is a great challenge. Herein, density functional theory (DFT) calculations are first conducted to explore the beneficial effect of NiSe2/NiS heterostructure on OER. Based on this, a series of nickel selenosulfides constructed by different amounts of NiS and NiSe2 are synthesized. Results indicate that Ni4&#8211;Se2&#8211;S2 with the NiS to NiSe2 ratio of 5.82/2.47 displays outstanding electrocatalytic activity for OER/HER, with overpotentials of 228 mV and 155 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. Moreover, a two-electrode electrolyzer using Ni4&#8211;Se2&#8211;S2 as the anode and cathode exhibits a lower voltage than RuO2||Pt/C. Moderate ratio of NiS to NiSe2 achieves a balance between conductivity and surface area, which endows Ni4&#8211;Se2&#8211;S2 the best catalytic performances. Our results pave a way for the optimization of heterostructured catalysts.</description>
      <author>Y. Li, Haiyan Du, Yufang Su, Jinsheng Zhao, Konggang Qu, Xianxi Zhang, Yan Zhang, Yunyun Dong, Zhi Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-Substituted Sr&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;FeMoO&lt;sub&gt;6&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; as an Electrode Material for Symmetrical and Reversible Solid-Oxide Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00509</link>
      <description>Yan&#8208;Ru Yang, Wenze Li, Siyuan Yang, Xuesong Shen, Zongying Han, Hao Yu, Meng Gao, Kunhua Wang, Zhibin Yang, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394874016

                This work develops a novel perovskite Sr2FeNi0.35Mo0.65O6-&#948; (SFN0.35M) simultaneously using as a fuel electrode and oxygen electrode in a reversible solid oxide cell (RSOC). SFN0.35M shows outstanding electrocatalytic activity for hydrogen oxidation, hydrogen evolution, oxygen reduction, and oxygen evolution. In situ exsolution and dissolution of Fe-Ni alloy nanoparticles in SFN0.35M is revealed. In a reducing atmosphere, SFN0.35M shows in situ exsolution of Fe-Ni alloy nanoparticles, and then the Fe-Ni alloy is reoxidized into SFN0.35M while converting into an oxidizing atmosphere. The polarization resistances of SFN0.35M electrode are 0.043 &#937; cm2 in 20% O2-N2 and 0.064 &#937; cm2 in H2 at 850 &#176;C. Moreover, symmetric fuel cells using the SFN0.35M electrode achieves a maximum power density of 0.501 W cm-2 at 850 &#176;C in H2 fuel, while the symmetric electrolysis cell has an electrolysis current density of 0.794 A cm-2 at 1.29 V in 90% H2O-10% H2 at 850 &#176;C. It is the first time we demonstrate that the cell voltage of symmetrical cell at 0.5 A cm-2 in the fuel cell mode and -0.5 A cm-2 in the electrolysis cell mode can be fully recovered in 10 electrode alternating cycles and therefore demonstrate the possibility that SFN0.35M can be used in a fully symmetric RSOC stack with electrode alternating functions.</description>
      <author>Yan&#8208;Ru Yang, Wenze Li, Siyuan Yang, Xuesong Shen, Zongying Han, Hao Yu, Meng Gao, Kunhua Wang, Zhibin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killing two birds with one stone: Enhancing the photoelectrochemical water splitting activity and stability of BiVO4 by Fe ions association</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109892</link>
      <description>Hailang Deng, Abebe Reda Woldu, Abdul Qayum, Zanling Huang, Zhu Wang, Xiang Peng, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394859473

                BiVO4 is a promising semiconducting photoanode for photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting due to its suitable bandgap. However, the dissolution of V5+ and sluggish reaction kinetics at the surface in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limit its applications. Herein, we report a convenient strategy to change the microenvironment by adding Fe(&#8546;) into the electrolyte. During the PEC process, Fe(&#8546;) ions not only improve the current density, but also show excellent stability of BiVO4. Consequently, the current increases by more than 1.7 times compared to that without Fe(III). Photoelectrochemical, morphological, and structural characterizations reveal that the FeOOH co-catalyst produced in situ on the BiVO4 photoanode by cyclical formation of the intermediates at the electrode/electrolyte interface during OER accelerates the OER kinetics and prevents photo-corrosion by suppressing the dissolution of V5+. The results reveal a new strategy for the multifunctional modification of photoanodes for efficient solar conversion.</description>
      <author>Hailang Deng, Abebe Reda Woldu, Abdul Qayum, Zanling Huang, Zhu Wang, Xiang Peng, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterointerface&#8208;Rich Ni3N/WO3 Hierarchical Nanoarrays for Efficient Glycerol Oxidation&#8208;Assisted Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400624</link>
      <description>Hongjing Wang, Wenfeng Zhan, Shaojian Jiang, Kai Deng, Ziqiang Wang, You Xu, Hongjie Yu, Liang Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394796728

                Glycerol oxidation&#8208;assisted water electrolysis has emerged as a cost&#8208;effective way of co&#8208;producing green hydrogen and HCOOH. Still, preparing highly selective and stable nickel&#8208;based metal electrocatalysts remains a challenge. Herein, heterostructure Ni3N/WO3 nanosheet arrays of bifunctional catalysts with large specific surface areas loaded on nickel foam (denoted as Ni3N/WO3/NF) were synthesized. This catalyst was for glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with excellent catalytic performance, a voltage saving of 267 mV compared to oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and a HER overpotential of 104 mV at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. The cell voltage in the assembled GOR // HER hybrid electrolysis system reaches 100 mA cm&#8208;2 at 1.50 V, 296 mV lower than the potential required for overall water splitting. This work demonstrates that replacing GOR with OER using a cost&#8208;effective and highly active Ni&#8208;based bifunctional electrocatalyst can make hybrid water electrolysis an energy&#8208;efficient, sustainable, and green strategy for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Hongjing Wang, Wenfeng Zhan, Shaojian Jiang, Kai Deng, Ziqiang Wang, You Xu, Hongjie Yu, Liang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing overall water splitting via phase-engineered amorphous/crystalline interface: A novel strategy to accelerate proton-coupled electron transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.085</link>
      <description>Hui Feng, Yue Han, Yutong Wang, Dong-Feng Chai, Jianxin Ran, Wenzhi Zhang, Zhuanfang Zhang, Guohua Dong, Meili Qi, Dongxuan Guo, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394798864

                Traditional phase engineering enhances conductivity or activity by fully converting electrocatalytic materials into either a crystalline or an amorphous state, but this approach often faces limitations. Thus, a practical solution entails balancing the dynamic attributes of both phases to maximize an electrocatalyst's functionality is urgently needed. Herein, in this work, Co/Co2C crystals have been assembled on the amorphous N, S co-doped porous carbon (NSPC) through hydrothermal and calcination processes. The stable biphase structure and amorphous/crystalline (A/C) interface enhance conductivity and intrinsic activity. Moreover, the adsorption ability of water molecules and intermediates is improved significantly attributed to the rich oxygen-containing groups, unsaturated bonds, and defect sites of NSPC, which accelerates proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) and overall water splitting. Consequently, A/C-Co/Co2C/NSPC (Co/Co2C/NSPC with amorphous/crystalline interface) exhibits outstanding behavior for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), requiring the overpotential of 240.0 mV and 70.0 mV to achieve 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Moreover, an electrolyzer assembled by A/C-Co/Co2C/NSPC-3 (anode) and A/C-Co/Co2C/NSPC-2 (cathode) demonstrates a low drive voltage of 1.54 V during overall water splitting process. Overall, this work has pioneered the coexistence of crystalline/amorphous phases in electrocatalysts and provided new insights into phase engineering.</description>
      <author>Hui Feng, Yue Han, Yutong Wang, Dong-Feng Chai, Jianxin Ran, Wenzhi Zhang, Zhuanfang Zhang, Guohua Dong, Meili Qi, Dongxuan Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte-free electrochemical oxygen generator for providing sterile and medical-grade oxygen in household applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.device.2024.100360</link>
      <description>Xuyan Zhao, Jia Zhao, Deming Liu, Fei Zhou, Peng Li, Yi Tan, Huang Zhou, Yu Zhang, Sen Lin, Yuen Wu, Device. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394843153

                Summary As COVID-19 coexists with humans, the need for home oxygen (O2) generators has grown, especially for those with heart and lung conditions. This study presents a prototype of an electrolyte-free proton-exchange membrane electrochemical oxygen generator (EOG) that uses pure water for safe, high-performance operation. The development of a novel oxygen evolution reaction catalyst, PtxIryRu1-x-yO2, and an efficient membrane electrode assembly has improved the EOG's performance, achieving a 1 L min&#8722;1 oxygen production rate and over 600 h of stability. Furthermore, the EOG demonstrates several distinct advantages for medical applications, including (1) directly producing sterile and medical-grade O2 (purity &gt;99.5%), (2) supporting nearly instantaneous O2 supply for emergency (startup time &lt;1 s), (3) supporting portable application due to its light weight (&lt;2 kg) and compact size (1 dm3), and (4) ensuring a quiet operating condition for patients (&lt;45 dB). The EOG, boasting unique application advantages, significantly outperforms commercial pressure swing adsorption devices, thereby showcasing its considerable potential for future applications.</description>
      <author>Xuyan Zhao, Jia Zhao, Deming Liu, Fei Zhou, Peng Li, Yi Tan, Huang Zhou, Yu Zhang, Sen Lin, Yuen Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.device.2024.100360</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PBA-Derived Ternary FeCoNi Alloy Supported on N-Doped Porous Carbon as a Bifunctional Catalyst for Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00776</link>
      <description>Lei Yu, Feng Zhang, Guang Li, Juan Yang, Ying Peng Xie, Hui Huang, Yongqiang Shen, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xianyou Wang, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394881613

                One of the challenges preventing rechargeable Zn-air batteries (ZABs) from being used in larger commercial applications is their slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Low-cost transition metal carbon-based materials are generally considered to be the most promising materials to replace precious metal catalysts to improve the OER and ORR performance. However, practical application of these materials is hampered by poor activity and stability. By optimization of the preparation technology and composition of the material, the catalytic activity and durability of the catalyst can be improved. Herein, through iterative coprecipitation and pyrolysis methods, FeCoNi alloy nanoparticles coated with graphitized carbon nanotubes (FeCoNi-N-CS) were constructed on activated carbon. The FeCoNi-N-CS exhibits impressive bifunctional electrocatalytic activity in alkaline media with a half-wave potential (E1/2) of 871 mV for the ORR, an overpotential of 334 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 (Ej=10) for the OER. Furthermore, when this catalyst is applied in ZAB, a greater specific capacity of 791 mAh gZn&#8211;1 and long-term cycling stability compared to commercialized Pt/C + RuO2 can be achieved.</description>
      <author>Lei Yu, Feng Zhang, Guang Li, Juan Yang, Ying Peng Xie, Hui Huang, Yongqiang Shen, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xianyou Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetal organic framework derived CoM@N-C composites as bifunctional oxygen catalysts for Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101576</link>
      <description>Hong-Rui Huang, Qianqian Liang, Jun Yan, Huajun Guo, Zhixing Wang, Guochun Yan, Xinhai Li, Wenjie Peng, Hui Duan, Jiexi Wang, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394859586

                Metal-loaded nitrogen-doped carbon (M@N-C) catalysts have shown promise as electrocatalysts for replacing noble metal catalysts in industrial processes. To study the influence on structural and performance caused by different bimetal doping, a family of bimetals CoM@N-C (M=Cu/Ni/Fe) composites with porous surface and abundant C defects were well-designed. After bimetallic doping, more defects are introduced into the carbon frameworks, and the Metal-N species are fixed. As such, efficient utilization of active sites and rapid mass transfer make the reaction kinetics process more favorable and stable. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that Cu/Ni doping optimizes the electronic environment of the Co-N, resulting in the balanced adsorption and dissociation of oxygen intermediates. While the synergy of FeCo activates the O=O, which promotes the sharp decrease in free energy of *OOH to *O, shifting the rate-determining step for ORR. This indicates the adsorption site transfer of CoFe0.05@N-C in oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions. The CoFe0.05@N-C catalyst exhibits superior bifunctional catalytic activity than that of Pt catalysts (E1/2=0.85V, Ej=10=1.65V). This work presents a simple strategy to fabricate well-defined bimetals doping in bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts and it is expected to inspire future work on the role of electronic structure modulation and interface engineering.</description>
      <author>Hong-Rui Huang, Qianqian Liang, Jun Yan, Huajun Guo, Zhixing Wang, Guochun Yan, Xinhai Li, Wenjie Peng, Hui Duan, Jiexi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degradation of tetracycline hydrochloride by electrocatalytic oxidation using NiO@Co3O4/Ti electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105242</link>
      <description>Ming Shi, Hong-Fu Wang, Pei&#8208;Qing Yuan, Xinru Xu, Jingyi Yang, Journal of water process engineering. 61(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394834660

                Tetracycline hydrochloride (TC-H) belongs to a class of broad-spectrum antibiotics and is difficult to remove from the environment, posing potential hazards to human health as well as the aquatic environment. In this paper, NiO@Co3O4/Ti, a dimensionally stable anode with NiO as the core and Co3O4 as the shell, was synthesized using a hydrothermal method. XRD, XPS, and SEM were conducted for characterization, revealing a constant charge transfer between Ni and Co, with mainly trivalent Co acting as the oxidant. The electrochemical characterization showed that the NiO@Co3O4/Ti electrode had a high oxygen evolution potential and low charge transfer resistance. Furthermore, 94.26 % of TC-H (100 mg/L) was degraded in 60 min under the optimal operating conditions (voltage of 10 V, 0.25 M NaCl, pH 7.88). According to radical quenching experiments, the active species O2&#8722; played an important role in the electrocatalytic oxidation process. In addition, the electrode maintained good stability after several degradation experiments.</description>
      <author>Ming Shi, Hong-Fu Wang, Pei&#8208;Qing Yuan, Xinru Xu, Jingyi Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boost alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction by intermetallic charge transfer in perovskite ruthenate encapsulated in ZIF-67 derived cobalt sulfide nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160128</link>
      <description>Chenhui Huang, Chuanhui Zhu, Jinjin Yang, Tong Han, Min Liang, Mei-Huan Zhao, Guangqin Li, Man-Rong Li, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394935929

                Constructing and manipulating heterostructure is an effective strategy to prepare electrocatalysts with excellent performance for water electrolysis. Herein, an efficient alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalysts, Co3S4-embedded in carbon-encapsulated BaRuO3 (BaRuO3@CS-0.1), was synthesized through the sacrificial template method of ZIF-67 encapsulated BaRuO3 precursors. By inheriting the exceptional merits of different ingredients, this heterostructure catalyst BaRuO3@CS-0.1 enables intermetallic charge transfer between Ru and Co with boosted HER kinetics, and thus displaying higher catalytic activity towards HER, as evidenced by the intensively theoretical calculations and experimental measurements. BaRuO3@CS-0.1 exhibits excellent HER performance, with the lowered overpotentials of 26 mV to achieve 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in comparison to the pristine BaRuO3 (51 mV), which is also superior to Pt/C catalyst at large current density. Moreover, this heterostructure also demonstrates comparable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activities with the representative electrocatalysts, delivering current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at a potential of 1.546 V for overall water splitting. These findings provide a rational route to optimize the performance of bulk electrocatalysts and endow them with richer electrochemical activity through this composite strategy.</description>
      <author>Chenhui Huang, Chuanhui Zhu, Jinjin Yang, Tong Han, Min Liang, Mei-Huan Zhao, Guangqin Li, Man-Rong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo-doped NiCoP nanoplates with amorphous/crystalline heterostructure for efficient alkaline overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100660</link>
      <description>Xiuwen Wang, Miao Yu Experiment, Chunmei Lv, Liyan Wang, Wei Kan, Guang Xu Experiment, Li Sun, Bing Zhao, FlatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394935971

                Developing highly active, low-cost, and robust transition metal-based phosphide for alkaline overall water splitting is of utmost important to promote the practical application from fundamental. Herein, two-dimensional (2D) Mo-doped NiCoP nanoplates with novel amorphous/crystalline heterostructure (Mo(0.05)-NiCoP) in situ grown on three-dimensional nickel foam (NF) has been successfully constructed through hydrothermal reaction followed by the phosphorization treatment. Benefited from the synergy of amorphous/crystalline heterointerface, Mo doping, and unique 2D structure, the optimized Mo(0.05)-NiCoP exhibits outstanding electrocatalytic activity for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), achieving low overpotential of 67 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for HER and 233 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for OER. Meanwhile, there are only a cell voltage of 1.569 V was required to drive 10 mA cm&#8722;2 when Mo(0.05)-NiCoP used as both anode and cathode for overall water splitting. Thus, this study provides a novel approach to construct efficient 2D bifunctional catalysts with amorphous/crystalline heterostructure and heterogeneous metal doping.</description>
      <author>Xiuwen Wang, Miao Yu Experiment, Chunmei Lv, Liyan Wang, Wei Kan, Guang Xu Experiment, Li Sun, Bing Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhibiting Photo&#8208;Oxidation and Enhancing Visible&#8208;Light&#8208;Driven Photocatalytic Water Oxidation over Covalent Organic Frameworks Through the Coordination of Cobalt with Bipyridine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401168</link>
      <description>Xinyu Li, Qing Yang, Yiqi Yuan, Yongguo Shama, H. Yanna Yan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394816521

                Abstract Photocatalytic water splitting using covalent organic frameworks (COFs) is a promising approach for harnessing solar energy. However, challenges such as slow kinetic dynamics in the photocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and COFs' self&#8208;oxidation hinder its progress. In this study, an enamine&#8208;based COF coordinated is introduced with cobalt dichloride, CoCl 2 (CoCl 2 &#8208;TpBPy). The coordination of cobalt ions with bipyridines in CoCl 2 &#8208;TpBPy enhances charge&#8208;carrier separation and migration, leading to effective photocatalytic OER. Under visible light irradiation, CoCl 2 &#8208;TpBPy achieves a notable OER rate of up to 1 mmol&#183;g &#8722;1 &#183;h &#8722;1 , surpassing the reported organic semiconductor analogs. Additionally, CoCl 2 &#8208;TpBPy shows minimal nitrogen evolution compared to TpBPy and ethanol&#8208;treated TpBPy (E&#8208;TpBPy), indicating cobalt plays a pivotal role in improving charge utilization and minimizing photo&#8208;oxidation. In situ X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) analyses revealed that Co(IV) species are key to the high OER efficiency. This work highlights Co(IV) species in the efficient OER and inhibiting photo&#8208;oxidation of CoCl 2 &#8208;TpBPy.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Li, Qing Yang, Yiqi Yuan, Yongguo Shama, H. Yanna Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Electrocatalytic Activity Regulation of R-P Perovskite La&lt;sub&gt;1.2&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;0.6&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;0.4&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4+&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; by Low-Temperature Fluorination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00553</link>
      <description>Xinyu Cao, Yulin Hao, Jianghui Zheng, Hao-Dong Wang, Lin Zhang, Yafang Zhao, Jiayi Liu, Ming Zhang, Zhongrong Shen, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394891615

                Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper (R-P) perovskite oxides have attracted much attention as highly active and stable bifunctional materials for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER)/oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in alkaline solutions due to the nonuse of precious metal elements. Herein, a triple (H+, O2&#8211;, and electron) conductive R-P perovskite oxide, La1.2Sr0.8Ni0.6Fe0.4O4+&#948;, was prepared, and the valence state of transition metal cations and highly oxidized oxygen (O&#8211;/O22&#8211;) in the structure was tuned by a low-temperature fluorine substitution treatment. The homogeneous distribution of the fluorine elements across the particles of the R-P perovskite oxide after its fluorination was confirmed by high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM) images. By regulation of the amount of highly oxidative state oxygen species and the valence state of transition metal cations in the R-P perovskite structure, the material exhibits a significant enhancement for both the OER and ORR electrocatalytic activities. The fluoridated La1.2Sr0.8Ni0.6Fe0.4O4+&#948;Fy (LSNF-OF) achieves a low OER overpotential of 308.1 mV in a 1 M KOH electrolyte at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2. This is superior to both commercial Co3O4 and the pristine sample without fluorination. The LSNF-OF electrode in an aqueous Zn-air battery (ZAB) exhibits a peak power density of 19.15 W g&#8211;1 at a current density of 24 mA g&#8211;1. The low-temperature trace fluorination can enhance the electrocatalytic efficiency of perovskite oxides. This technique can be applied to various types of metal oxides.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Cao, Yulin Hao, Jianghui Zheng, Hao-Dong Wang, Lin Zhang, Yafang Zhao, Jiayi Liu, Ming Zhang, Zhongrong Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ synthesis of encapsulated N-doped carbon metal oxide nanostructures for Zn-air battery applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119147</link>
      <description>Jhony Xavier Flores-Lasluisa, M. Garc&#237;a-Rodr&#237;guez, D. Cazorla&#8208;Amor&#243;s, Emilia Morall&#243;n, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394823553

                La, Mn and Co-based materials with diverse compositions encapsulated in N-doped carbon materials were synthesized by an in-situ sol-gel method. The as-prepared materials were physically activated with CO2 giving as a result composites with excellent performance for both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The composites were characterized by different physicochemical techniques revealing the importance of porosity created by CO2 activation. This crucial step increases the number of accessible active sites such as Co-Nx-C sites, Co/MnO heterointerfaces and graphitic N groups. Moreover, the formation of La2O2CO3 was detected to enhance electrical conductivity and electrochemical performance and it is active for ORR. Although the composite containing La, Mn and Co has less concentration of the highly active sites, its small particle size favour a better distribution of these sites. The Co-containing composites were tested as air-electrodes in a Zn-air battery and compared to commercial electrocatalysts. All composites showed a better operation in terms of higher cyclability and higher energy density which is a consequence of metal nanostructures encapsulation in N-doped porous carbon shells. Interestingly, the pure Co-based composite showed an outstanding performance related to the high concentration of the Co-Nx-C active sites that provide high activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Jhony Xavier Flores-Lasluisa, M. Garc&#237;a-Rodr&#237;guez, D. Cazorla&#8208;Amor&#243;s, Emilia Morall&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A universal strategy to synthesize amorphous/crystalline P, Mo dual-doped CoNiS nanostructures for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.02.082</link>
      <description>Xiaodong Yang, Hang Shen, Xiaoming Xiao, Yang Wei, Zhichao Li, Na Yang, Na Yang, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394847417

                In this work, P and Mo dual-doped CoNiS (PMo-CoNiS) nanosheet arrays were successfully constructed through a common solvothermal treatment. The precise doping of P and Mo species into the CoNiS can regulate the microstructures and meanwhile endow with PMo-CoNiS abundant amorphous/crystalline heterointerfaces, which can adjust the electronic structure, thus enhancing the intrinsic activity of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As a result, ultra-low overpotentials of merely 156 and 58 mV are required to deliver a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for OER and HER, respectively, and the electrocatalysts PMo-CoNiS also exhibit low Tafel slopes and maintain robust stability for 48 h in alkaline media at a high current density of 50 mA cm&#8722;2. In addition, in an assembled electrolyte cell for overall water splitting, a voltage as low as 1.48 V is sufficient to yield a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations further confirmed that the enhanced OER and HER result from the optimized OH* and H* adsorption energy of PMo-CoNiS due to P, Mo dual doping and generated interfacial effect. This work may offer an avenue for designing low-cost bifunctional catalysts with superior catalytic activity and provide a new application strategy for broader applications in various electrocatalytic fields.</description>
      <author>Xiaodong Yang, Hang Shen, Xiaoming Xiao, Yang Wei, Zhichao Li, Na Yang, Na Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.02.082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Volcano Trend in OER of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks with Asymmetric Configuration through Energy Band Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124089</link>
      <description>Jian Zhou, Zhichu Ren, Feng Qiao, Huiyu Gai, Siyao Qiu, Canhui Zhan, Xingkun Wang, Zongkun Chen, Heqing Jiang, Minghua Huang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394893489

                Local symmetry breaking of catalysts has emerged as an effective strategy for finely tuning oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, yet the fundamental comprehension regarding asymmetric structure-activity relationships remains limited. Here, we propose the energy band engineering to bridge the correlation between established asymmetric electronic structure and adsorption/desorption ability of reaction intermediates within metal-organic frameworks (MOFs). The deliberate synthesis of CoM-MOFs (M=Cu, Ni, and Fe) with distinct coordination microenvironments enables the customization of asymmetric Co-O-M electronic structure. A volcano-shaped relationship can be revealed between calculated OER overpotential and average d-band center (Ed) energy level for both active Co sites and substituted M. The CoFe-MOF, located close to the summit, showcases the balanced reaction intermediate behavior and thus for enhanced OER activity. This work presents a promising approach to thoroughly understand asymmetric electronic structure-activity relationships from the perspective of energy band engineering and further guide the discovery of high-efficiency MOF-based OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jian Zhou, Zhichu Ren, Feng Qiao, Huiyu Gai, Siyao Qiu, Canhui Zhan, Xingkun Wang, Zongkun Chen, Heqing Jiang, Minghua Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic role of dopant and graphene on BiVO4 photoanode for enhanced photoelectrochemical hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131329</link>
      <description>Mohaseen S. Tamboli, Santosh S. Patil, Dong Kyu Lee, C. S. Praveen, Asiya M. Tamboli, Uk Sim, Ki-Young Lee, Geun Ho Gu, Chinho Park, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394876478

                The development of an efficient and stable electrode remains an attractive challenge for photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting to generate cheaper and green hydrogen (H2). Herein, we have fabricated a novel multicomponent molybdenum (Mo) doped bismuth vanadate/graphene (Mo-doped BiVO4@graphene) photoanode by simple spin coating technique followed by an annealing process. Precise control over Mo and graphene doping concentration (GR3/BVO:Mo-0.5) was attained, enabling excellent photocurrent density (4-fold increase as compared to BVO) with an enhanced rate of H2 production. This is attributed to the synergistic effect between molybdenum and graphene enhancing charge carrier density and suppressing the recombination rate of photo-generated electrons and holes. Our DFT studies indicate a reduction in the band gap value after doping pure BVO with Mo. In addition, we observed that the potential determining step of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the electrochemical adsorption of hydroxyl radical (H2O(l) + * &#8594; HO* + H+(aq) + e-), which is reduced by &#8764;0.8 eV after doping with Mo. This study reports on the unique design of a Mo-doped BiVO4@graphene hybrid electrode, which can be used as a superior electrode for green hydrogen generation under sunlight.</description>
      <author>Mohaseen S. Tamboli, Santosh S. Patil, Dong Kyu Lee, C. S. Praveen, Asiya M. Tamboli, Uk Sim, Ki-Young Lee, Geun Ho Gu, Chinho Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling hole-transporting polyaniline layer with a cobalt phthalocyanine cocatalyst to boost photoelectrochemical water oxidation of bismuth vanadate photoanodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dyepig.2024.112150</link>
      <description>Aijian Wang, Xin Yang, Xiaoliang Shen, Xiaoyu Zhai, Yuqin Dou, Khalid Syed, Long Zhao, Weihua Zhu, Dyes and pigments. 226(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394794442

                Though bismuth vanadate (BiVO4) exhibits a promising potential as a semiconductor photoanode toward photoelectrochemical (PEC) water oxidation, its PEC performance is still limited by the poor charge carrier transport and sluggish oxygen evolution kinetics. Herein, the polyaniline (PANI) and cobalt coordinated-phthalocyanines (CoTcPc) were introduced onto the BiVO4 semiconductor substrate, constructing the integrated CoTcPc/nPANI/BiVO4 (n = 30, 60 and 90, n represents the deposition time for PANI with the unit of s) composite photoanodes. It is demonstrated that the PEC water oxidation activity of BiVO4 is significantly boosted by the incorporation of PANI and CoTcPc, stemming from the improved electron/hole transfer, enhanced charge separation efficiency, and accelerated carrier mobility and water oxidation kinetics. CoTcPc/60PANI/BiVO4 composite photoanode with the optimized compositions exhibits an enhanced photocurrent density of 4.03 mA/cm2 at 1.23 V vs. RHE under illumination, ranking among the best records reported recently. Furthermore, the roles of electrodeposition time to generate PANI are also distinguished through experimental studies. These results reveal the crucial role of engineering the hole transfer layer to optimize the semiconductor photoanodes toward efficient PEC water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Aijian Wang, Xin Yang, Xiaoliang Shen, Xiaoyu Zhai, Yuqin Dou, Khalid Syed, Long Zhao, Weihua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dyepig.2024.112150</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt corroles: Synthesis and applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215869</link>
      <description>Jyoti, Jiajia An, D. Y. Kim, David G. Churchill, Anil Kumar, Coordination chemistry reviews. 511(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394946656

                Cobalt corrole chemistry has become its own corpus of corrole literature in recent years, with findings involving synthesis, catalysis, sensing, electrocatalysis, etc reported with increasing frequency. Cobalt is abundant and biologically essential (e.g., cobalamin). Since Co metallocorroles are relatively straightforward to synthesize, this makes Co corroles already a practical and sustainable macrocycle class suitable for further research and "post functionalization." In addition, the metal is redox active and (therefore) vastly catalytically active. The versatility of redox active cobalt as a central atom in corroles helps achieve oxidation states ranging from Co1+ to Co5+; this has allowed researchers to synthesize, and therefore experimentally access, the chemistry of a large number of cobalt metallocorroles that have been substituted with various groups at the &#946;&#8211;, meso&#8211;, or axial&#8211; positions. From these published examples, a wide array of structural properties and characteristics continue to unfold; a review is now due to help focus the researchers concentrating on this area to enable for outstanding future investigations. Their stabilization into different oxidation states has also made Co corroles valuable and heavily pursued in electrocatalysis. These complexes are frequently used for oxygen and reduction reactions, hydrogen evolution reactions (HERs), and oxygen evolution reactions (OERs). Co&#8211;corroles have thus widespread usage beyond catalysis per se, including sensing of anions and various gas molecules and, in some cases, small molecule activation. When N2 and O2 are present, Co complexes may preferentially bind and detect CO. This current review helps (i) summarize the accomplishments to date in synthesis and characterization, (ii) consolidate all the key characteristics of cobalt corroles within a common area of access, and (iii) expand our understanding of how these "active" macrocycles might be used across different scientific and technological disciplines (see future work section).</description>
      <author>Jyoti, Jiajia An, D. Y. Kim, David G. Churchill, Anil Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First&#8208;Principles Investigations on Effects of B&#8208;Site Substitution (B&#9552;Mn, Fe, and Co) on La&#8208;Based Perovskite Oxides As Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Rechargeable Metal&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202301235</link>
      <description>Siriwimol Somdee, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Annop Ektarawong, Soorathep Kheawhom, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, Advanced theory and simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394890199

                Abstract The effects of B&#8208;site substitution (B&#9552;Mn, Fe, and Co) in La&#8208;based perovskite oxides (LPOs); LaMnO 3 , LaFeO 3 , LaCoO 3 , as bifunctional electrocatalysts during oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in metal&#8211;air batteries (MABs) under an alkaline electrolyte (pH = 13) are investigated using density functional theory (DFT). It is found that LaMnO 3 exhibits higher ORR activity than others with ORR overpotential ( &#951; ORR ) of 0.57 V, but its OER activity is poor with OER overpotential ( &#951; OER ) of 1.12 V. The &#951; ORR (0.59 V) and &#951; OER (1.13 V) of LaMn 0.75 Fe 0.25 O 3 closely resemble those of LaMnO 3 , suggesting that Fe substitution does not yield appreciable enhancements in activity. Fe substitution reduces the ORR and OER activity because the adsorption energies of intermediate species on Fe&#8208;substituted LPOs surfaces are too strong to obtain a potential determining step for ORR and OER. According to Sabatier's principle, the LaMn 0.25 Co 0.75 O 3 demonstrates superior OER activity compared to the other composition, while ORR activity approximates that of LaMnO 3 , evidenced by &#951; ORR of 0.65 V and &#951; OER of 0.53 V. The Co&#8208;terminated LaMn 0.25 Co 0.75 O 3 shows bifunctional activity higher than Mn/Co termination, indicating that Co is an active site for OER and Mn is a promoter for improved ORR activity.</description>
      <author>Siriwimol Somdee, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Annop Ektarawong, Soorathep Kheawhom, Bj&#246;rn Alling, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202301235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped CoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocages as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01449</link>
      <description>Bo Fang, Yue Li, Jiaqi Yang, Ting Lu, Xinjuan Liu, Xiaohong Chen, Likun Pan, Zhenjie Zhao, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394931309

                Currently, electrochemical water-splitting activity is limited by the slow intrinsic reaction kinetics and energy conversion efficiency, so designing highly efficient electrocatalysts that can facilitate electrochemical reactions remains necessary. Herein, the catalyst architecture consisting of Fe-doped CoS2 nanocages with nitrogen-doped carbon wrapping (CN/Fe-CoS2) was explored as an outstanding bifunctional electrocatalyst. Through density functional theory calculations, the introduction of Fe into CoS2 would modulate the density of states, making the reduced band gap and enhanced intrinsic charge transfer efficiency of CoS2. Simultaneously, the adsorption of intermediates during the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) processes is regulated, leading to an improvement in the intrinsic catalytic activity. The experimental results demonstrate that Fe doping significantly enhances the electron transfer, specific surface area, and electrochemical active area of CoS2, which facilitates the efficient utilization of charge and exposes additional active sites for electrochemical reactions. In addition, the nanocage architecture and nitrogen-doped carbon wrapping in CN/Fe-CoS2 act as a protective layer to prevent CoS2 aggregation, thereby exposing additional active sites and enhancing the interface with the electrolyte. By optimizing the amount of Fe, CN/Fe-CoS2 demonstrates a remarkably superior electrocatalytic performance and stability, as evidenced by the low overpotential (&#951;10) of 186 and 304 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH media for HER and OER, respectively. Overall, combining heteroatom doping and structure designing represents a promising approach to develop high-performance electrocatalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Bo Fang, Yue Li, Jiaqi Yang, Ting Lu, Xinjuan Liu, Xiaohong Chen, Likun Pan, Zhenjie Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-performance multidimensional-structured N-doped nickel modulated Mo2N/FeOxNy bifunctional electrocatalysts for efficient alkaline seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151348</link>
      <description>Yanxiang He, Yuwen Hu, Zhixiao Zhu, Jieqiong Li, Yongchao Huang, Shiguo Zhang, Muhammad&#8208;Sadeeq Balogun, Yexiang Tong, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394851592

                Realizing effective alkaline water/seawater electrolysis through efficient hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction (HER and OER) electrocatalysts is demanding but attracts significant task. Herein, a novel NNNF@Mo2N/FeOxNy electrocatalyst comprising of Mo2N/FeOxNy interfacial rod-shaped structure on nitrogen-doped nickel nanosheets modified nickel foam (NF) (denoted NNNF) with remarkable HER and OER catalytic performance is reported. The nanosheet-rod structure coupled with multidimensional interfacial boundaries enriches the optimized NNNF@Mo2N/FeOxNy catalyst with rich active sites. As a result, the as-prepared NNNF@Mo2N/FeOxNy catalyst demands low overpotentials of 22/130 mV and 28/142 mV to drive current densities of 10/100 mA cm&#8722;2 for the HER, 222/348 mV and 239/361 mV for the OER in 1 M alkaline freshwater/seawater electrolytes, respectively. The catalyst also reveals excellent HER and OER stability for 100 h at a constant high current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in both electrolytes. The catalyst also acts as bifunctional catalyst in overall water electrolytic devices requiring low overall voltages of 1.42/1.47 V@20 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline freshwater/seawater electrolytes, as well as considerable voltages of 1.50/1.81 V@100/500 mA cm&#8722;2 in 6 M KOH seawater electrolyte at 60 &#176;C for industrial conditions.</description>
      <author>Yanxiang He, Yuwen Hu, Zhixiao Zhu, Jieqiong Li, Yongchao Huang, Shiguo Zhang, Muhammad&#8208;Sadeeq Balogun, Yexiang Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metasurface-enhanced photochemical activity in visible light absorbing semiconductors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0199589</link>
      <description>Yamuna Paudel, Diego J. Chachayma-Farfan, Andrea Al&#249;, Matthew Y. Sfeir, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394813103

                Heterogeneous photocatalysis is an important research problem relevant to a variety of sustainable energy technologies. However, obtaining high photocatalytic efficiency from visible light absorbing semiconductors is challenging due to a combination of weak absorption, transport losses, and low activity. Aspects of this problem have been addressed by multilayer approaches, which provide a general scheme for engineering surface reactivity and stability independent of electronic considerations. However, an analogous broad framework for optimizing light-matter interactions has not yet been demonstrated. Here, we establish a photonic approach using semiconductor metasurfaces that is highly effective in enhancing the photocatalytic activity of GaAs, a high-performance semiconductor with a near-infrared bandgap. Our engineered pillar arrays with heights of &#8764;150 nm exhibit Mie resonances near 700 nm that result in near-unity absorption and exhibit a field profile that maximizes charge carrier generation near the solid-liquid interface, enabling short transport distances. Our hybrid metasurface photoanodes facilitate oxygen evolution and exhibit enhanced incident photon-to-current efficiencies that are &#8764;22&#215; larger than a corresponding thin film for resonant excitation and 3&#215; larger for white light illumination. Key to these improvements is the preferential generation of photogenerated carriers near the semiconductor interface that results from the field enhancement profile of magnetic dipolar-type modes.</description>
      <author>Yamuna Paudel, Diego J. Chachayma-Farfan, Andrea Al&#249;, Matthew Y. Sfeir</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0199589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined cobalt single&#8208;atom catalysts with strong electronic metal&#8208;support interactions based on a biomimetic self&#8208;assembly strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.554</link>
      <description>Bowen Guo, Zekun Wang, Lei Zheng, Guang Mo, Hongjun Zhou, Dan Luo, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394891223

                Abstract Designing high&#8208;performance and low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical for the conversion and storage of sustainable energy technologies. Inspired by the biomineralization process, we utilized the phosphorylation sites of collagen molecules to combine with cobalt&#8208;based mononuclear precursors at the molecular level and built a three&#8208;dimensional (3D) porous hierarchical material through a bottom&#8208;up biomimetic self&#8208;assembly strategy to obtain single&#8208;atom catalysts confined on carbonized biomimetic self&#8208;assembled carriers (Co SACs/cBSC) after subsequent high&#8208;temperature annealing. In this strategy, the biomolecule improved the anchoring efficiency of the metal precursor through precise functional groups; meanwhile, the binding&#8208;then&#8208;assembling strategy also effectively suppressed the nonspecific adsorption of metal ions, ultimately preventing atomic agglomeration and achieving strong electronic metal&#8208;support interactions (EMSIs). Experimental characterizations confirm that binding forms between cobalt metal and carbonized self&#8208;assembled substrate (Co&#8211;O 4 &#8211;P). Theoretical calculations disclose that the local environment changes significantly tailored the Co d&#8208;band center, and optimized the binding energy of oxygenated intermediates and the energy barrier of oxygen release. As a result, the obtained Co SACs/cBSC catalyst can achieve remarkable OER activity and 24 h durability in 1 M KOH ( &#951; 10 at 288 mV; Tafel slope of 44 mV dec &#8722;1 ), better than other transition metal&#8208;based catalysts and commercial IrO 2 . Overall, we presented a self&#8208;assembly strategy to prepare transition metal SACs with strong EMSIs, providing a new avenue for the preparation of efficient catalysts with fine atomic structures.</description>
      <author>Bowen Guo, Zekun Wang, Lei Zheng, Guang Mo, Hongjun Zhou, Dan Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Operation of Paired CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction/Glycerol Oxidation at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05952</link>
      <description>Attila Korm&#225;nyos, Adrienn Szirmai, Bal&#225;zs Endr&#337;di, Csaba Jan&#225;ky, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394786891

                Despite the considerable efforts made by the community, the high operation cell voltage of CO2 electrolyzers is still to be decreased to move toward commercialization. This is mostly due to the high energy need of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is the most often used anodic pair for CO2 reduction. In this study, OER was replaced by the electrocatalytic oxidation of glycerol using carbon-supported Pt nanoparticles as an anode catalyst. In parallel, the reduction of CO2 to CO was performed at the Ag cathode catalyst using a membraneless microfluidic flow electrolyzer cell. Several parameters were optimized, starting from the catalyst layer composition (ionomer quality and quantity), through operating conditions (glycerol concentration, applied electrolyte flow rate, etc.), to the applied electrochemical protocol. By identifying the optimal conditions, a 75&#8211;85% Faradaic efficiency (FE) toward glycerol oxidation products (oxalate, glycerate, tartronate, lactate, glycolate, and formate) was achieved at 200 mA cm&#8211;2 total current density while the cathodic CO formation proceeded with close to 100% FE. With static protocols (potentio- or galvanostatic), a rapid loss of glycerol oxidation activity was observed during the long-term measurements. The anode catalyst was reactivated by applying a dynamic potential step protocol. This allowed the periodic reduction, hence, refreshing of Pt, ensuring stable, continuous operation for 5 h.</description>
      <author>Attila Korm&#225;nyos, Adrienn Szirmai, Bal&#225;zs Endr&#337;di, Csaba Jan&#225;ky</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfurization-induced lattice disordering in high-entropy catalyst for promoted bifunctional electro-oxidation behavior</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151234</link>
      <description>Jing Chen, Kexin Wang, Zimeng Liu, Xin Sun, Xiaodong Zhang, Fengcai Lei, Xiuyan Wan, Junfeng Xie, Bo Tang, Chemical engineering journal. 489(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394835914

                The electro-oxidation reactions (EORs) are key half reactions to achieve efficient hydrogen production via direct or assisted water electrolysis, and the development of bifunctional EOR catalysts could further broaden the field of utilization and thus realize simultaneous hydrogen production and wastewater treatment. In this work, we proposed a mild sulfurization approach to fabricate a high-entropy septenary NiCrFeCoCuMnZn sulfide catalyst with unique sulfurization-induced lattice disordering. The disordered lattice and high-entropy feature of the pre-oxidation-favorable sulfide catalyst synergistically lead to enriched active sites and improved intrinsic activity towards promoted activity for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR). Dynamic analyses of the catalyst in EOR operation reveals that the enrichment of high-valence active species, increased surface roughness and the in-situ formed SO42- ions adsorbed on the surface of the activated catalyst could result in promoted catalytic kinetics, and thereby leading to significant enhancement of OER and HzOR activity without degradation during long-term catalysis. The exploration of the high-entropy lattice-disordered catalyst could promote the hydrogen production via direct and hydrazine-assisted water electrolysis, and the optimization strategies with synergy of phase engineering, lattice disordering and entropy modulation could guide the design of advanced catalysts for energy-related applications.</description>
      <author>Jing Chen, Kexin Wang, Zimeng Liu, Xin Sun, Xiaodong Zhang, Fengcai Lei, Xiuyan Wan, Junfeng Xie, Bo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial Impact of Spin State Evolution in OER/ORR Catalyzed by Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06122</link>
      <description>Mingyuan Yu, Ang Li, Erjun Kan, Caimao Zhan, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394925248

                The Fe-embedded N-doped graphene (Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C) is the most representative single atom catalyst (SAC) that has shown great potentiality in electrocatalysis, such as oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the active moiety of Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C is still elusive due to contradictory experimental results. Moreover, early simulations mainly focus on the thermodynamic potential of adsorbates, while the effect of spin multiplicity receives little attention. To explore the role of spin multiplicity in electrocatalysis, we employ the constant-potential density functional theory (DFT) to systematically study the structural evolution of the high-spin (HS) and intermediate-spin (IS) FeN4 site (marked by FeN4HS/IS) in OER and ORR processes. With the consideration of spin multiplicity, our simulation shows spontaneous oxidation from Fe(II)N4IS to Fe(III)N4HS at potential U = 0.4 V versus SHE. Further simulation indicates that the FeN4IS site undergoes a sequential adsorption of *OH and *OOH along with U increase, which leads to the spin state transition from IS to HS. According to the constant-potential free energy analysis, the FeN4HS*OOH is confirmed to be the practical active centers of OER, while the FeN4HS*OH and FeN4IS are assigned to the active center of ORR in low and high overpotentials. The predicted ORR activity of FeN4HS*OH agrees with the in situ X-ray absorption near-edge spectroscopy (XANES) and 57Fe M&#246;ssbauer spectroscopy measurement by Xiao et al. [Microporous Framework Induced Synthesis of Single-Atom Dispersed Fe-NC Acidic ORR Catalyst and its In Situ Reduced Fe-N4 Active Site Identification Revealed by X-Ray Absorption Spectroscopy. ACS Catal. 2018, 8, 2824&#8211;2832]. Based on the geometry and orbital analysis, the bond length of Fe&#8211;N and coordination number of Fe center are found to have a significant impact on the d orbital splitting energy and thus induce the turnover of HS/IS stability in the OER/ORR intermediates. Our study brings comprehensive insights into the evolution of coordination and spin state in Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C, which reveals the significance of spin multiplicity in electrocatalysis and benefits further theoretical design of SACs from the perspective of spin effects.</description>
      <author>Mingyuan Yu, Ang Li, Erjun Kan, Caimao Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication and characterizations of a novel Ce modified PbO2 electrode with Ti4O7-rGO as the middle layer for degradation of ceftazidime</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2024.117645</link>
      <description>Yue Ni, Yoon Mook Kang, Y. Liu, Fen&#173;wu Liu, Wen&#173;long Bi, Junmei Qin, Yuandong Wu, Zepeng Sun, Desalination. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394824373

                Developing stable and high-performance electrodes for effective removal of antibiotics from wastewater remains a significant challenge. Herein, a novel Ce-doped PbO2 electrode with Ti4O7-reduced graphene oxide as the middle layer (Ti/Ti4O7-rGO/Ce-PbO2) was fabricated through drop-coating and electrodeposition for the electrocatalytic degradation of ceftazidime (CAZ). The prepared Ti/Ti4O7-rGO/Ce-PbO2 electrode exhibited more active sites, higher oxygen evolution potential, and stronger ability for hydroxyl radical (&#8226;OH) generation. In the degradation experiments, approximately 100 % of CAZ (30 mg L&#8722;1) was degraded by the Ti/Ti4O7-rGO/Ce-PbO2 electrode at 40 mA cm&#8722;2 in 0.1 M Na2SO4 solution within 90 min. The quenching test and EPR analysis indicated that the &#8226;OH played a pivotal role in the degradation process. A possible degradation mechanism of CAZ, which involved bond breaking, decarboxylation, demethylation, oxidization, and ring-opening, was proposed. The Escherichia coli inhibition experiment showed that the toxicity of CAZ was substantially reduced after electrochemical oxidation. The Ti/Ti4O7-rGO/Ce-PbO2 electrode exhibited a constant degradation efficiency (&gt; 99 %) after 10 consecutive cycles, and its service life can reach 3000 min. Furthermore, CAZ maintained a high removal efficiency in swine wastewater. This study provides a new approach toward fabricating a Ce-PbO2 electrode with Ti4O7-rGO middle layer for the degradation of antibiotics in wastewater.</description>
      <author>Yue Ni, Yoon Mook Kang, Y. Liu, Fen&#173;wu Liu, Wen&#173;long Bi, Junmei Qin, Yuandong Wu, Zepeng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2024.117645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The synergistic cooperation of carbon quantum dots and Fe MOF for the greatly improved charge separation efficiency of MW:BVO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174421</link>
      <description>Lei Ding, Lin Wang, Shuai Chu, Wei Zhai, Jie Li, Xiaoru Li, Zhengbo Jiao, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394858345

                Bismuth vanadate (BiVO4) is a promising photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting material. However, its high carrier recombination rate, slow surface reaction kinetics, and narrow light absorption range have been major bottleneck problems. In this work, a novel composite material, MW:BVO@NH2-MIL-101(Fe) (Fe MOF)@CQDs, was successfully synthesized by simultaneous modification of the MW:BVO(BVO co-doped with Mo and W) surface with carbon quantum dots (CQDs) and Fe MOF nanoparticles. The introduction of Fe MOF and CQDs as co-catalysts significantly improved the photocurrent density of MW:BVO by nearly 5 times. CQDs, as a non-toxic and safe green material, exhibit excellent electron transfer ability and up-conversion luminescence characteristics, which help to suppress the recombination of photo-generated carriers and broaden the light absorption spectrum. The incorporation of CQDs resulted in a significant increase in the photocurrent density of MW:BVO@Fe MOF@CQDs up to 5.9 mA cm&#8722;2, while enhancing its light absorption ability. This enhancement can be attributed to two factors: firstly, the introduction of Ov defects due to the co-catalysis of CQDs and Fe MOF can greatly improve the OER reaction kinetics; secondly, the introduction of Fe MOF and CQDs can provide more active sites for oxygen evolution, and the synergistic effect of the dual co-catalysts promotes the separation of photogenerated carrier pairs, which may account for the significant improvement in the PEC performance of MW:BVO@Fe MOF@CQDs. Therefore, this work provides some interesting new insights for the construction of efficient photocatalytic anodes for PEC applications.</description>
      <author>Lei Ding, Lin Wang, Shuai Chu, Wei Zhai, Jie Li, Xiaoru Li, Zhengbo Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-Doped NiSe Nanosheets on Carbon Cloth for Electrochemical Water-Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01607</link>
      <description>Divya Rathore, Sujit Kumar Ghosh, Astha Gupta, Joydeep Chowdhury, Surojit Pande, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394841026

                Developing an affordable and efficient electrocatalyst for bifunctional activity is crucial for the advancement of water electrolysis technology. Doping with foreign atoms in electrocatalysts can tune the electronic properties, which further improves the water-splitting process. Herein, we have developed Ce-doped Ni0.85Se as a bifunctional electrocatalyst in an alkaline medium. The hydrothermal method was used to develop a two-dimensional (2D) nanosheet of the Ce-doped Ni0.85Se electrocatalyst. The as-developed pristine and doped electrocatalysts were characterized through various techniques. The optimized Ce0.1Ni0.85Se electrocatalyst represents &#8722;0.238 and 1.56 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode as an onset potential for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions, respectively, to generate 20 and 50 mA/cm2 current density. The Ce0.1Ni0.85Se electrocatalyst works as a suitable cell in an alkaline medium with 1.73 V to generate 10 mA/cm2 and 24 h stability. The introduction of Ce doping plays a pivotal role in tuning the electronic environment and facilitating a synergistic effect, ultimately improving the overall efficiency. Moreover, the active sites for water splitting were generated by expansion and distortion in the Ni0.85Se lattice. The enhanced specific surface area and porous 2D nanosheets of the doped sample are beneficial for water splitting. The theoretical results also prove that after doping with Ce, the catalyst has zero band gap, optimum Gibbs hydrogen adsorption energy, and an electronic state are the reasons for improved electrocatalytic performance. The actual active sites in the Ce-doped Ni0.85Se electrocatalyst were determined with density functional theory calculations. Therefore, this idea can generate a route for developing a doped electrocatalyst with efficient and stable activity.</description>
      <author>Divya Rathore, Sujit Kumar Ghosh, Astha Gupta, Joydeep Chowdhury, Surojit Pande</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Situ Nanoarchitectonics of Fe/Co LDH over Cobalt-Enriched N-Doped Carbon Cookies as Facile Oxygen Redox Electrocatalysts for High-Rate Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c19483</link>
      <description>Nadar Allwyn, Subramaniam Gokulnath, M. Sathish, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394798575

                The reality of long-term rechargeable and high-performance zinc&#8211;air batteries relies majorly on cost-effective and eminent bifunctional electrocatalysts, which can perform both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we demonstrate a new approach for the synthesis of in-situ-grown layered double hydroxide of iron and cobalt over a cobalt nanoparticle-enriched nitrogen-doped carbon frame (CoL 2:1) by a simple coprecipitation reaction with facile scale-up and explore its electrocatalytic ORR and OER activity for an electrically rechargeable zinc&#8211;air battery. Consequently, the developed composite displays excellent ORR and OER activity with an ORR half-wave potential of 0.84 V, a limiting current density of 5.85 mA/cm2, and an OER overpotential of 320 mV with exceptional stability. The outstanding bifunctionality index of the catalyst (&#916;E = 0.72 V) inspired us to utilize it as a cathode catalyst in an in-house developed prototype zinc&#8211;air battery. The battery could easily supply a specific capacity of 804 mAh/g with a maximum peak power density of 161 mW/cm2. The battery exhibits an attractive charge&#8211;discharge profile with a lesser voltage gap of 0.76 V at 10 mA/cm2 with durability for a period of 200 h and a voltage efficiency of 97%, which surpassed the corresponding Pt/C + RuO2-based zinc&#8211;air battery. Further, a maximum load of 50 mA/cm2 could easily be sustained during cycling, revealing its outstanding stability. A series-connected two CoL 2:1-based zinc&#8211;air batteries effortlessly enlighten a pinwheel fan and LED panel simultaneously, revealing its practicality. The high electrical conductivity and greater specific surface area of Co/N&#8211;C and its robust attachment with Fe/Co LDH preserves both active sites, thereby resulting in exceptional performance. Our method is capable of being flexible enough to create various bifunctional Co/N&#8211;C-based composite electrodes, opening up a feasible pathway to rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries with maximum energy density.</description>
      <author>Nadar Allwyn, Subramaniam Gokulnath, M. Sathish</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c19483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel mechanism of Fe4+/Ni3+ synergistic effect via exchange energy gain for boosting water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.100981</link>
      <description>Yalei Fan, Chenjia Zhang, Lunyong Zhang, Jing Zhou, Y.H. Li, Yu&#8208;Cheng Huang, Jun Ma, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Chao Jing, Yimin Mijiti, Z. Hu, Jianqiang Wang, Linjuan Zhang, Chem catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394893777

                Summary Synergistic effects are often used for interpreting the enhanced electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity of catalysts with two or more elements. However, the mechanism behind this synergy remains ambiguous. Here, we report an Fe-doped Ni2Mo3O8 (Ni2&#8722;xFexMo3O8, where x = 0.1, 0.3, 0.5, 0.7, and 1.0) series with high OER activity (only 196 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for x = 0.5) and high stability over 200 h at a high current density of 500 mA cm&#8722;2. Our in situ X-ray absorption spectroscopies indicated a valence-state transition from Fe2+/Ni2+ to Fe3+(Fe4+)/Ni3+ and a structural transition from corner-sharing Fe(Ni)&#8211;O&#8211;Fe(Ni) to an edge-sharing network. The highest catalytic activity of Ni1.5Fe0.5Mo3O8 among this series is interpreted as a gain in the exchange energy (ca. 1 eV) of the Fe4+/Ni3+ pair facilitated by intersite hopping owing to its highest Fe valence state. Our results reveal a previously unreported mechanism for the Ni-Fe synergistic effect that enhances OER activity.</description>
      <author>Yalei Fan, Chenjia Zhang, Lunyong Zhang, Jing Zhou, Y.H. Li, Yu&#8208;Cheng Huang, Jun Ma, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Chao Jing, Yimin Mijiti, Z. Hu, Jianqiang Wang, Linjuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.100981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of Ni Nanoclusters and Single Atom Site: Size Effect on the Performance of Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reaction and Rechargeable Zn&#8722;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202316824</link>
      <description>Kanghua Miao, Jundi Qin, Junzhong Yang, Xiongwu Kang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394911600

                Abstract The design of bifunctional electrocatalysts toward reduction reaction of carbon dioxide (ECO 2 RR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in aqueous rechargeable Zn&#9472;CO 2 batteries (ZABs) still poses a significant challenge. Herein, Ni clusters (Ni x ) of 0.5 and 0.8 nm in diameter coupled with single Ni site (Ni&#8722;N 4 &#8722;C), denoted as Ni&#8722;N 4 /Ni 5 and Ni&#8722;N 4 /Ni 8 , respectively, are synthesized and the size effect of Ni nanoclusters are studied. Ni&#8722;N 4 /Ni 5 exhibits an &#8776;100% Faradaic efficiency ( FE CO ) toward ECO 2 RR for CO from &#8722;0.4 to &#8722;0.8 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode, superior to that of Ni&#8722;N 4 &#8722;C ( FE CO = 55.0%) and Ni&#8722;N 4 /Ni 8 ( FE CO = 80.0%). The OER performance of Ni&#8722;N 4 /Ni 5 and Ni&#8722;N 4 /Ni 8 are superior or comparable to that of commercial RuO 2 but outperform that of Ni&#8722;N 4 &#8722;C. Theoretical calculation indicates that * COOH of ECO 2 RR intermediates bond synergistically with Ni x clusters and Ni&#8722;N 4 &#8722;C single atom site, promoting the activation of CO 2 and reducing the energy barrier of the potential determining step of ECO 2 RR. Such effect is strongly size&#8208;dependent and larger Ni x nanoclusters result in too strong binding of * COOH intermediates, impede the formation of * CO. As a bifunctional cathode electrocatalyst of rechargeable alkaline aqueous ZABs, Ni&#8722;N 4 /Ni 5 exhibits a peak power density of 11.7 mW cm &#8722;2 and cycling durability over 1200 cycles and 420 h.</description>
      <author>Kanghua Miao, Jundi Qin, Junzhong Yang, Xiongwu Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202316824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bi-functional air electrode developed from dual-MOFs strategy for high-performance zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00008k</link>
      <description>Yasir Arafat, Muhammad Rizwan Azhar, Yijun Zhong, Xiaomin Xu, Moses O. Tad&#233;, Zongping Shao, EES catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394910265

                Durable, high-performing and cost-effective bi-functional catalyst toward oxygen reduction/evolution reactions (ORR/OER) is key towards the practical application of Zn-air batteries (ZABs). Here we report a new concept of combining pristine...</description>
      <author>Yasir Arafat, Muhammad Rizwan Azhar, Yijun Zhong, Xiaomin Xu, Moses O. Tad&#233;, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00008k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the potential of Decade-Air exposed perovskite membranes through sustainable recycling approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151406</link>
      <description>Di Wu, Chao Shen, Weibin Zhou, Jinkun Tan, Yongqiang Niu, Zhengkun Liu, Guangru Zhang, Wanqin Jin, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394876120

                The stability of perovskite-based oxygen permeable membranes under long-term storage conditions, especially in the presence of water and carbon dioxide, presents a significant challenge. In this study, we examined the impact of extended storage (more than 10 years) on Nb2O5-doped SrCo0.8Fe0.2O3-&#948; (10Yr-SCFN) membranes. To unlock their industrial application potential, various approaches involving a combination of physical and chemical treatments to restore membrane properties in aged membranes are proposed and validated, while systematically investigating the evolution in chemical composition, microstructure, mechanical strength, and oxygen permeability. The 10Yr-SCFN membranes can be effectively restored through the secondary sintering method, wherein the membrane is first powdered and then calcinated in static air to maximize the removal of impurities. The mechanical strength and oxygen permeability reach levels of 30 MPa and 1.2 ml cm&#8722;2 min&#8722;1 (900 &#176;C), respectively, comparable to the performance of freshly prepared membranes. These findings shed some light on the potentiality of sustainable recycling of perovskite membranes and provide theoretical and technical support for the practical application and industrialization of oxygen permeable membranes.</description>
      <author>Di Wu, Chao Shen, Weibin Zhou, Jinkun Tan, Yongqiang Niu, Zhengkun Liu, Guangru Zhang, Wanqin Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the operating temperature on the degradation of solid oxide electrolysis cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234541</link>
      <description>Giuseppe Sassone, &#1254;zden &#199;elikbilek, Maxime Hubert, Katherine Develos-Bagarinao, Thomas David, Laure Gu&#233;taz, Isabelle Martin, Julie Villanova, Anass Benayad, L&#233;a Rorato, Julien Vulliet, Bertrand Morel, Aline L&#233;on, J&#233;r&#244;me Laurencin, Journal of power sources. 605(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394903662

                The present work aims to better understand the effect of operating temperature on the degradation of Solid Oxide Electrolysis Cells (SOECs). The studied SOECs consist of La0.6Sr0.4Co0.2Fe0.8O3-&#948;-Ce0.8Gd0.2O2-&#948; (LSCF-GDC) oxygen electrode, GDC diffusion barrier layer, Y0.16Zr0.84O1.92 (YSZ) electrolyte and Ni-YSZ hydrogen electrode. Durability tests are carried out at 750, 800 and 850 &#176;C for 2000 h at &#8722;1 A cm&#8722;2, using 10/90 vol% H2/H2O and dry air at the hydrogen and oxygen electrodes, respectively. The electrochemical impedance spectra measured before and after ageing reveal a strong evolution related to the hydrogen electrode, while the change in the oxygen electrode contribution remains negligible. A set of advanced characterization techniques are employed to study the cell degradation. For the hydrogen electrode, a large Ni depletion is observed after ageing, which increases with the operating temperature. The analysis of the oxygen electrode shows an elemental inter-diffusion between the LSCF-GDC/GDC/YSZ layers on the manufactured cells that seems to not evolve significantly upon operation. Moreover, the presence of SrZrO3 is not detected in the pristine cell and in the operated ones. Besides, only a limited LSCF decomposition is found in good agreement with the electrochemical characterizations. Hypotheses that could explain the good oxygen electrode stability are discussed.</description>
      <author>Giuseppe Sassone, &#1254;zden &#199;elikbilek, Maxime Hubert, Katherine Develos-Bagarinao, Thomas David, Laure Gu&#233;taz, Isabelle Martin, Julie Villanova, Anass Benayad, L&#233;a Rorato, Julien Vulliet, Bertrand Morel, Aline L&#233;on, J&#233;r&#244;me Laurencin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An environmental corrected descriptor based on &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;orbital spin states for atomically dispersed dual&#8208;metal catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18459</link>
      <description>Linkai Han, Xiaoqing Qiu, Zhonghua Xiang, AIChE journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394880123

                Abstract Atomically dispersed dual&#8208;metal sites catalysts, also named as dual&#8208;atom catalysts, have become a frontier, since they combine the merits of homogeneous and heterogeneous catalysts to satisfy the demands for critical catalytic reactions in green energy industrial equipment. However, the absence of further understanding for the evolution of catalyst structures in reaction environments results in a significant gap between the theoretical and experimental. Here, we provide a model to understand the evolution of the active configuration in acidic oxygen reduction and evolution reactions and propose an environmental corrected descriptor (&#916;&#958;) based on d &#8208;orbital spin states to reveal the activity control mechanism. Taking the acidic ORR as an example, &#916;&#958; correlated well with the overpotential ( R 2 = 0.96), which is determined by the number of electron occupancies in d z 2 orbital ( F dz 2 ). Accordingly, this work provides new insights into the design of green energy industrial catalysts in reaction environments.</description>
      <author>Linkai Han, Xiaoqing Qiu, Zhonghua Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18459</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bagasse derived N-doped graphitic carbon encapsulated cobalt nanoparticles as an efficient bifunctional catalyst for water splitting reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133959</link>
      <description>Rajathsing Kalusulingam, Krishnan Ravi, Selvam Mathi, &#1058;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1080;&#1093;&#1072;&#1081;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Kannan Srinivasan, Ankush V. Biradar, Tatiana N. Myasoedova, Colloids and surfaces. A, Physicochemical and engineering aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394857922

                The utilization of non-precious metal-based electrodes to unlock cost-effective and scalable processes for the production of clean energy is highly desirable. Herein, we reported a straightforward hydrothermal carbonization method for the synthesize of nitrogen-doped graphitic carbons integrated with cobalt (Co@NGC-600, Co@NGC-700, and Co@NGC-800) from sugarcane bagasse and their electrocatalytic applications in oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions. The graphitic nature of the Co integrated N-doped carbon materials was confirmed by Raman and XPS analysis. FESEM and HRTEM analysis confirms the dispersion of Co on N-doped carbon nanosheets. The Co@NGC-800 catalyst shows low overpotential and Tafel slope, requiring only 304 mV (84.1 mV dec-1) for oxygen electrode and 234 mV (118 mV dec-1) for HER at a current density of 10 mA cm-2. Moreover, Co@NGC-800 materials showed better activity than Co@NGC-700, Co Co@NGC-600, and Co@NC. The active Co@NGC-800 bifunctional electrocatalysts pair contributes to the fabrication of a water electrolyser with a 10 mA/cm2 current density at 1.68 V. The Co@NGC-800 // Co@NGC-800 electrocatalyst exhibits good stability over a period of 24 h. with negligible potential aberration during the process of water splitting. The electrocatalytic performance of the prepared catalyst in a 1.0 M KOH solution exhibits admirable bifunctional activity and remarkable stability. In fact, it outperforms cobalt-based and carbon-supported electrocatalysts, including highly valued commercial catalysts like IrO2 and Pt@C. The solar cell configuration, utilizing the energetic bifunctional Co@NGC-800 electrocatalyst, can continuously generate hydrogen and oxygen. The overall water-splitting process of Co@NGC-800 catalyst delivered at a cell voltage of 1.68 V, enabling sustained and efficient oxygen and hydrogen evolution at a large scale.</description>
      <author>Rajathsing Kalusulingam, Krishnan Ravi, Selvam Mathi, &#1058;. &#1057;. &#1052;&#1080;&#1093;&#1072;&#1081;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Kannan Srinivasan, Ankush V. Biradar, Tatiana N. Myasoedova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular structure characterization of coal with different coalification degrees: a combined study from FT-IR, Raman, 13C NMR spectroscopy and modelling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.138354</link>
      <description>Yuanji Li, Chao Dai, Sheng Meng, Ji Wu, Journal of molecular structure. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394808565

                While extensive research has been conducted on the evolution of coal's molecular structure during coalification, the heterogeneity and complexity of coal continue to impede the accurate and precise quantitative characterization of its structural evolution mechanism. In this study, the organic matter source, coal quality, carbon skeleton structure, and functional group occurrence of coal at different coalification stages have been determined using maceral identification, vitrinite reflectance, industrial quality, elemental analysis, and spectral analysis. Four molecular models have been created through computer-aided molecular design. The results indicate that the hydrogen atoms in the benzene ring structure reduce as coalification increases. The content of aliphatic compounds gradually decreases, while the length of aliphatic side chains first decreases (Ro,max&lt;1.81%) and then increases (Ro,max&gt;1.81%). Moreover, the chemical structure of coal tends to mature and stabilize, as the degree of coal crystallization increases, and the oxygen-containing groups gradually decrease. Therefore, aromatization increases with the condensation reaction dominating in the late stage of coalification. After intensive attempts to determine the chemical bond mode between aromatic carbon, aliphatic side chain, and oxygen functional group, the final molecular structure models are presented as C188H165O13N3 (F-1), C182H161O9N5 (J-1), C195H153O10N3 (T-1), and C193H129O7N3 (W-1). Furthermore, the mechanism of coalification is discussed based on the variation of the side chains and chemical bonds. According to the adsorption heat of functional groups, the methane adsorption capacity increases as the degree of coalification increases. The inflection point of methane adsorption capacity is at Ro,max&gt;1.80%. This study provides a theoretical framework to understand the molecular structure evolution of coals at varying degrees of metamorphism. Additionally, it proposes a reliable method for characterizing coal molecular structures with high accuracy.</description>
      <author>Yuanji Li, Chao Dai, Sheng Meng, Ji Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.138354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ablation mechanism of C/C&#8211;SiC composites in supersonic oxygen&#8208;enriched ablation environment for the internal flow field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14761</link>
      <description>Gao Yong, Jin&#8208;Jin Wang, Bailin Zha, Zhensheng Sun, Lingling Wang, Ruifeng Li, International journal of applied ceramic technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394882325

                Abstract This study investigates the ablation resistance of C/C&#8211;SiC composites using the ground simulation internal flow&#8208;field supersonic oxygen&#8208;rich ablation test technology. The microstructure evolution and ablation mechanism of the composites in a supersonic oxygen&#8208;rich environment were explored by examining the macroscopic and microscopic ablation morphologies of the composites before and after the test. The results demonstrate that C/C&#8211;SiC composites exhibit excellent ablation resistance, with mass and linear ablation rates of .46 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 g/s and .42 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 mm/s, respectively, after 120 s of ablation in a low gas temperature and high oxygen&#8208;rich ablation thermal environment. As the gas temperature increases, the mass and linear ablation rates of C/C&#8211;SiC composites gradually increase, even though the oxygen enrichment within the gas components decreases. When the gas temperature reaches 2178&#8211;2491 K, the mass and linear ablation rates increase to 1.31 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 g/s and .84 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 mm/s, respectively. Furthermore, at high temperatures above 2650 K, the mass and linear ablation rates of the composites exhibit a geometric multiple increase, reaching 4.73 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 g/s and 1.89 &#215; 10 &#8722;2 mm/s, respectively. These findings indicate that the ablation resistance of C/C&#8211;SiC composites in the supersonic oxygen&#8208;rich ablation environment is more sensitive to gas temperature than oxygen enrichment. The main factors contributing to the increased ablation rate of C/C&#8211;SiC composites in the supersonic oxygen&#8208;rich ablation process include the formation of a glass SiO 2 oxide film, transition to molten SiO 2 , erosion of molten SiO 2 , and high&#8208;temperature sublimation of the SiC matrix.</description>
      <author>Gao Yong, Jin&#8208;Jin Wang, Bailin Zha, Zhensheng Sun, Lingling Wang, Ruifeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miliary tuberculosis in an immunocompetent patient: Case report</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25176/rfmh.v24i1.5973</link>
      <description>Renzo S. Valle Farfan, Alejandro M. Pe&#241;a Villalobos, Walter J. Espinoza Hernandez, Steffano A. Valle Farfan, Revista de la Facultad de Medicina Humana. 24(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394893163

                Milar Tuberculosis (TB) is a presentation with a fatal outcome if it is not diagnosed or treated on time; although certain conditions are required to develop this presentation. In this In this article, the case of a 48-year-old man with no pathological history is studied, who started the disease with a time of six months with an initial diffuse gastrointestinal pain and later one month before admission presented progressive respiratory symptoms; he was admitted for emergencies where bilateral diffuse miliary compromise was evident in the chest computed tomography; upon admission, he was administered oxygen and support measures, an HIV test was obtained which was negative, and positive results were obtained in the sputum smear microscopy. His clinical evolution was stationary until the administration of antituberculosis therapy, observing slight clinical improvement, likewise, low doses of corticosteroids were administered after which a favorable evolution was demonstrated and he was discharged.</description>
      <author>Renzo S. Valle Farfan, Alejandro M. Pe&#241;a Villalobos, Walter J. Espinoza Hernandez, Steffano A. Valle Farfan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25176/rfmh.v24i1.5973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of the &lt;scp&gt;ECM&lt;/scp&gt;&#8211;receptor interaction for adaptive response to hypoxia based on integrated transcription and translation analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.17352</link>
      <description>Da Huo, Shilin Liu, Libin Zhang, Hongsheng Yang, Chunxi Jiang, Molecular ecology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394836284

                Abstract Low dissolved oxygen (LO) conditions represent a major environmental challenge to marine life, especially benthic animals. For these organisms, drastic declines in oxygen availability (hypoxic events) can trigger mass mortality events and thus, act as agents of selection influencing the evolution of adaptations. In sea cucumbers, one of the most successful groups of benthic invertebrates, the exposure to hypoxic conditions triggers adaptive adjustments in metabolic rates and behaviour. It is unclear, however, how these adaptive responses are regulated and the genetic mechanisms underpinning them. Here, we addressed this knowledge gap by assessing the genetic regulation (transcription and translation) of hypoxia exposure in the sea cucumber Apostichopus japonicus . Transcriptional and translational gene expression profiles under short&#8208; and long&#8208;term exposure to low oxygen conditions are tightly associated with extracellular matrix (ECM)&#8211;receptor interaction in which laminin and collagen likely have important functions. Finding revealed that genes with a high translational efficiency (TE) had a relatively short upstream open reading frame (uORF) and a high uORF normalized minimal free energy, suggesting that sea cucumbers may respond to hypoxic stress via altered TE. These results provide valuable insights into the regulatory mechanisms that confer adaptive capacity to holothurians to survive oxygen deficiency conditions and may also be used to inform the development of strategies for mitigating the harmful effects of hypoxia on other marine invertebrates facing similar challenges.</description>
      <author>Da Huo, Shilin Liu, Libin Zhang, Hongsheng Yang, Chunxi Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.17352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-mitosis dissection of acute and chronic DNA mutagenesis and repair</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41588-024-01712-y</link>
      <description>Paul Adrian Ginno, Helena Borgers, Christina Ernst, Anja Schneider, Mikaela Behm, Sarah J. Aitken, Martin S. Taylor, Duncan T. Odom, Nature genetics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394832260

                Abstract How chronic mutational processes and punctuated bursts of DNA damage drive evolution of the cancer genome is poorly understood. Here, we demonstrate a strategy to disentangle and quantify distinct mechanisms underlying genome evolution in single cells, during single mitoses and at single-strand resolution. To distinguish between chronic (reactive oxygen species (ROS)) and acute (ultraviolet light (UV)) mutagenesis, we microfluidically separate pairs of sister cells from the first mitosis following burst UV damage. Strikingly, UV mutations manifest as sister-specific events, revealing mirror-image mutation phasing genome-wide. In contrast, ROS mutagenesis in transcribed regions is reduced strand agnostically. Successive rounds of genome replication over persisting UV damage drives multiallelic variation at CC dinucleotides. Finally, we show that mutation phasing can be resolved to single strands across the entire genome of liver tumors from F1 mice. This strategy can be broadly used to distinguish the contributions of overlapping cancer relevant mutational processes.</description>
      <author>Paul Adrian Ginno, Helena Borgers, Christina Ernst, Anja Schneider, Mikaela Behm, Sarah J. Aitken, Martin S. Taylor, Duncan T. Odom</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41588-024-01712-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Galactic Chemical Evolution of Helium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.08765</link>
      <description>Miqaela K. Weller, David H. Weinberg, James W. Johnson, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394867239

                We examine the galactic chemical evolution (GCE) of $^4$He in one-zone and multi-zone models, with particular attention to theoretical predictions and empirical constraints on IMF-averaged yields. Published models of massive star winds and core collapse supernovae span a factor of 2 -- 3 in the IMF-averaged $^4$He yield, $y\mathrm{_{He}^{CC}}$. Published models of intermediate mass, asymptotic giant branch (AGB) stars show better agreement on the IMF-averaged yield, $y\mathrm{_{He}^{AGB}}$, and they predict that more than half of this yield comes from stars with $M=4-8 M_\odot$, making AGB $^4$He enrichment rapid compared to Fe enrichment from Type Ia supernovae. Although our GCE models include many potentially complicating effects, the short enrichment time delay and mild metallicity dependence of the predicted yields makes the results quite simple: across a wide range of metallicity and age, the non-primordial $^4$He mass fraction $\Delta Y = Y-Y_{\mathrm{P}}$ is proportional to the abundance of promptly produced $\alpha$-elements, like oxygen, with $\Delta Y/Z_{\mathrm{O}} \approx (y\mathrm{_{He}^{CC}}+y\mathrm{_{He}^{AGB}})/y\mathrm{_{O}^{CC}}$. Reproducing solar abundances with our fiducial choice of the oxygen yield $y\mathrm{_{O}^{CC}}=0.0071$ implies $y\mathrm{_{He}^{CC}}+y\mathrm{_{He}^{AGB}} \approx 0.022$, i.e., $0.022M_\odot$ of net $^4$He production per solar mass of star formation. Our GCE models with this yield normalization are consistent with most available observations, though the implied $y\mathrm{_{He}^{CC}}$ is low compared to most of the published massive star models. More precise measurements of $\Delta Y$ in stars and gas across a wide range of metallicity and [$\alpha$/Fe] ratio could test our models more stringently, either confirming the simple picture suggested by our calculations or revealing surprises in the evolution of the second most abundant element.</description>
      <author>Miqaela K. Weller, David H. Weinberg, James W. Johnson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.08765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical bond reorganization in intramolecular proton transfer revealed by ultrafast X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2321343121</link>
      <description>Yonghao Gu, Haiwang Yong, Bing Gu, Shaul Mukamel, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394933395

                Time-resolved X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (TR-XPS) is used in a simulation study to monitor the excited state intramolecular proton transfer between oxygen and nitrogen atoms in 2-(iminomethyl)phenol. Real-time monitoring of the chemical bond breaking and forming processes is obtained through the time evolution of excited-state chemical shifts. By employing individual atomic probes of the proton donor and acceptor atoms, we predict distinct signals with opposite chemical shifts of the donor and acceptor groups during proton transfer. Details of the ultrafast bond breaking and forming dynamics are revealed by extending the classical electron spectroscopy chemical analysis to real time. Through a comparison with simulated time-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy at the valence level, the distinct advantage of TR-XPS is demonstrated thanks to its atom specificity.</description>
      <author>Yonghao Gu, Haiwang Yong, Bing Gu, Shaul Mukamel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2321343121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONSERVATION AND VARIABILITY OF THE ANTIOXIDANT PROTECTION SYSTEM OF THE RETINAL PIGMENT EPITHELIA IN VERTEBRATES</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044452923030051</link>
      <description>Yu. V. Markitantova, &#1042;. &#1053;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1081;, &#381;urnal &#232;vol&#251;cionnoj biohimii i fiziologii. 59(3)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394923399

                In the course of evolution and adaptation to life conditions, organisms have developed the strategies that allow to use of the reactive oxygen species (ROS) in regulation of physiological processes and in maintenance of homeostasis. Retinal pigment epithelium (RPE) is one of the prime examples of tissues with a high level of metabolism and intracellular ROS, that have the more risk of damage after oxidative stress (OS), under the influence of exogenous or endogenous stress factors. Vertebrate RPE cells, despite the conservatism of the eye tissue structures and their main functions, respond differently to OS are due to the ta&#1093;on-species specificity of the components of signaling pathways that form the antioxidant defense system (AODS). Transcription factors, in particular, Nrf2 play a key role in AODS. AODS in RPE includes the several levels of regulation, interaction of which ensures the stability of morphofunctional state of the cells. Phylogenetic analysis of the key components of AODS in various vertebrates revealed not only conservation, but also variability in the protein domain organization. This may reflect the differences in functions, adaptability and regenerative potential. The identification of AODS mechanisms that ensure the morphofunctional stability of RPE cells is of fundamental importance and is aimed at finding tissue-specific targets for effective treatment of a spectrum of eye diseases.</description>
      <author>Yu. V. Markitantova, &#1042;. &#1053;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1081;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044452923030051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial results of our spectro-photometric monitoring of XZ Tau</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.09361</link>
      <description>Arpan Ghosh, Saurabh Sharma, Joe P. Ninan, D. K. Ojha, Aayushi Verma, Tarak Chand Sahu, Rakesh Pandey, Koshvendra Singh, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394866477

                We present here initial results of our spectro-photometric monitoring of XZ Tau. During our monitoring period, XZ Tau exhibited several episodes of brightness variations in timescales of months at optical wavelengths in contrast to the mid-infrared wavelengths. The color evolution of XZ Tau during this period suggest that the brightness variations are driven by changes in accretion from the disc. The mid-infrared light curve shows an overall decline in brightness by $\sim$ 0.5 and 0.7 magnitude respectively in WISE W1 (3.4 $\mu$m) and W2 (4.6 $\mu$m) bands. The emission profile of the hydrogen recombination lines along with that of Ca II IRT lines points towards magnetospheric accretion of XZ Tau. We have detected P Cygni profile in H$\beta$ indicating of outflowing winds from regions close to accretion. Forbidden transitions of oxygen are also detected, likely indicating of jets originating around the central pre-main sequence star.</description>
      <author>Arpan Ghosh, Saurabh Sharma, Joe P. Ninan, D. K. Ojha, Aayushi Verma, Tarak Chand Sahu, Rakesh Pandey, Koshvendra Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.09361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biosignatures from pre-oxygen photosynthesising life on TRAPPIST-1e</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.11611</link>
      <description>Jake K. Eager-Nash, Stuart J. Daines, Jill M. McDermott, Peter Andrews, Lucy A. Grain, J. M. Bishop, A. H. Rogers, J. Waldo Smith, Chadiga Khalek, Thomas J. Boxer, Mankin Mak, Robert J. Ridgway, Eric H&#233;brard, F. Hugo Lambert, Timothy M. Lenton, Nathan J. Mayne, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394948183

                In order to assess observational evidence for potential atmospheric biosignatures on exoplanets, it will be essential to test whether spectral fingerprints from multiple gases can be explained by abiotic or biotic-only processes. Here, we develop and apply a coupled 1D atmosphere-ocean-ecosystem model to understand how primitive biospheres, which exploit abiotic sources of H2, CO and O2, could influence the atmospheric composition of rocky terrestrial exoplanets. We apply this to the Earth at 3.8 Ga and to TRAPPIST-1e. We focus on metabolisms that evolved before the evolution of oxygenic photosynthesis, which consume H2 and CO and produce potentially detectable levels of CH4. O2-consuming metabolisms are also considered for TRAPPIST-1e, as abiotic O2 production is predicted on M-dwarf orbiting planets. We show that these biospheres can lead to high levels of surface O2 (approximately 1-5 %) as a result of \ch{CO} consumption, which could allow high O2 scenarios, by removing the main loss mechanisms of atomic oxygen. Increasing stratospheric temperatures, which increases atmospheric OH can reduce the likelihood of such a state forming. O2-consuming metabolisms could also lower O2 levels to around 10 ppm and support a productive biosphere at low reductant inputs. Using predicted transmission spectral features from CH4, CO, O2/O3 and CO2 across the hypothesis space for tectonic reductant input, we show that biotically-produced CH4 may only be detectable at high reductant inputs. CO is also likely to be a dominant feature in transmission spectra for planets orbiting M-dwarfs, which could reduce the confidence in any potential biosignature observations linked to these biospheres.</description>
      <author>Jake K. Eager-Nash, Stuart J. Daines, Jill M. McDermott, Peter Andrews, Lucy A. Grain, J. M. Bishop, A. H. Rogers, J. Waldo Smith, Chadiga Khalek, Thomas J. Boxer, Mankin Mak, Robert J. Ridgway, Eric H&#233;brard, F. Hugo Lambert, Timothy M. Lenton, Nathan J. Mayne</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.11611</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactive molecular dynamics study of soot formation during ethylene combustion catalyzed by alternating electric fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101627</link>
      <description>Pengyi Lv, Shengqiang Lin, Chengxu Qiu, Zhenjian Jia, Journal of the Energy Institute. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394858371

                The application of external electric fields (E-fields) is an effective method for controlling fuel combustion processes. Reactive molecular dynamics (ReaxFF MD) can effectively simulate the formation and intermediate evolution processes of soot during combustion. The combustion model of 750 ethylene and 450 oxygen is constructed. The E-field amplitude is selected to be 0.1 V/&#197;, and the alternating period is from 0.1 to 100. ps. The effects of E-field on the growth of soot under different alternating frequencies are simulated by comparing the conditions without E-field and applying unidirectional E-field. The results show that the addition of E-field reduces the molecular weight of the largest molecule in the system. The density of soot is reduced, S/V and H/C become larger, and the system is more dispersed. The E-field increases the activation energy of ethylene pyrolysis, makes the pyrolysis reaction path tilt to C2H4 C2H2 + H2, and delays the formation of the initial C6 ring. The E-field inhibits the growth of soot, and the effect of the E-field is more significant from high frequency to low frequency and then to unidirectional E-field.</description>
      <author>Pengyi Lv, Shengqiang Lin, Chengxu Qiu, Zhenjian Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lumbar Paravertebral Muscle Pain Management Using Kinesitherapy and Electrotherapeutic Modalities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare12080853</link>
      <description>S&#238;nziana C&#259;lina Sili&#351;teanu, Elisabeta Antonescu, Lavinia Duic&#259;, Maria Totan, Andrei Ionu&#355; Cucu, Andrei Ioan Costea, Healthcare. 12(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394932926

                Background: Low back pain is considered a public health problem internationally. Low back pain is a cause of disability that occurs in adolescents and causes negative effects in adults as well. The work environment and physical and psychosocial factors can influence the occurrence and evolution of low back pain. Methods: The purpose of this paper is to highlight the physiological and functional changes in young adults with painful conditions of the lumbar spine, after using exercise therapy. The study was of the longitudinal type and was carried out over a period 6 months in an outpatient setting. The rehabilitation treatment included electrotherapeutic modalities and kinesitherapy. Results: The results obtained when evaluating each parameter, for all moments, show statistically significant values in both groups. The results obtained regarding the relationship between the therapeutic modalities specific to rehabilitation medicine and low back pain are consistent with those reported in studies. Conclusions: Depending on the clinical-functional status of each patient, kinesitherapy can accelerate the heart rate and increase the blood pressure and oxygen saturation of the arterial blood, values that can later return to their initial levels, especially through training.</description>
      <author>S&#238;nziana C&#259;lina Sili&#351;teanu, Elisabeta Antonescu, Lavinia Duic&#259;, Maria Totan, Andrei Ionu&#355; Cucu, Andrei Ioan Costea</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare12080853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of electroless copper plating on microstructure, properties and interface of MWCNT-Cu / Ti composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174487</link>
      <description>Hao Fan, Di Ouyang, Xing Chen, Xia Chen, Lintao Liu, Jinchun Jiang, Li Ma, Manying Hu, Tingting Tu, Journal of alloys and compounds. 990(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394784885

                Electroless copper-plated multiwalled carbon nanotube-reinforced titanium matrix (MWCNT-Cu/Ti) composites were prepared by spark plasma sintering (SPS). The microstructure evolution, interface characteristics and properties of the composites, including strength and corrosion resistance, were investigated. The results showed that the surface impurities and structural defects of the MWCNTs were successfully removed, and the oxygen-containing functional groups such as-OH, and -COOH were introduced by acid functionalization. The structure of the electroless-plated Cu layer is that of crystalline Cu. The precipitation of TiC phases by the interface reaction of the MWCNT-Cu/Ti composites is prevented. The compressive strength of the MWCNT-Cu/Ti composites was 2303 MPa, which is approximately 2 times greater than that of pure Ti. The corrosion resistance decreased in the order MWCNT-Cu/Ti &gt; MWCNTs/Ti &gt; pure Ti. The orientations of [112&#773;0]&#945;-Ti//[11&#773;0]TiC, (1&#773;100)&#945;-Ti//(11&#773;1)TiC in the MWCNTs/Ti composites and Ti2Cu(2&#773;00)//Ti(1&#773;100), Ti2Cu (211) //Ti(1&#773;010) in the MWCNT-Cu/Ti composites are related.</description>
      <author>Hao Fan, Di Ouyang, Xing Chen, Xia Chen, Lintao Liu, Jinchun Jiang, Li Ma, Manying Hu, Tingting Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-separation transformation behaviors in NiO bearing Na2O-B2O3-SiO2 glass and melt through high-temperature Ni K-edge XAFS and time-resolved SAXS measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnoncrysol.2024.122975</link>
      <description>Kana Tomita, Takuya Kishi, Keiichi Osaka, Daiju Matsumura, Tetsuji Yano, Journal of non-crystalline solids. 634(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394903935

                High-temperature in-situ Ni-K edge XAFS and SAXS measurements were conducted on borosilicate glasses with low alkali content with/without phase separation tendency, which have been investigated to understand immiscibility into silica-rich phase and borate-rich one on the samples heat-treated at certain temperature followed by fast quenching. In this work, using in-situ analyzing techniques, in-situ time-domain evolution of phases along temperature and time was obtained to understand high-temperature behavior. Ni2+ ion probes phase separation behavior using its high selectivity favoring borate-rich phase and sensitivity to electron donating ability of surrounding oxygens. Taking advantage of these characters, local compositional change was tracked during phase separation under heat treatment. Time-resolved SAXS profiles revealed the speed of phase transformation in addition to changes of morphology at respective temperature. The phase-separation transformation mechanism via different phase separation scheme (homogeneous &#8594; spinodal &#8594; binodal &#8594;homogeneous) was clearly described, revealing effect of NiO clustering at higher temperature.</description>
      <author>Kana Tomita, Takuya Kishi, Keiichi Osaka, Daiju Matsumura, Tetsuji Yano</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnoncrysol.2024.122975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchored Cobalt Nanoparticles on Layered Perovskites for Rapid Peroxymonosulfate Activation in Antibiotic Degradation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202402935</link>
      <description>Yaobin Wang, Dong Li, Xinlei Ge, Jianguo Yu, Yunxia Zhao, Yunfei Bu, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394840549

                Abstract In the Fenton&#8208;like reaction, revealing the dynamic evolution of the active sites is crucial to achieve the activity improvement and stability of the catalyst. This study reports a perovskite oxide in which atomic (Co 0 ) in&#8208;situ embedded exsolution occurs during the high&#8208;temperature phase transition. This unique anchoring strategy significantly improves the Co 3+ /Co 2+ cycling efficiency at the interface and inhibits metal leaching during peroxymonosulfate (PMS) activation. The Co@L&#8208;PBMC catalyst exhibited superior PMS activation ability and could achieve 99% degradation of tetracycline within 5 min. The combination of experimental characterization and density functional theory (DFT) calculations elucidates that the electron&#8208;deficient oxygen vacancy accepts an electron from the Co 3d&#8208;orbital, resulting in a significant electron delocalization of the Co site, thereby facilitating the adsorption of the *HSO 5 /*OH intermediate onto the &#8220;metal&#8208;V O bridge&#8221; structure. This work provides insights into the PMS activation mechanism at the atomic level, which will guide the rational design of next&#8208;generation catalysts for environmental remediation. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Yaobin Wang, Dong Li, Xinlei Ge, Jianguo Yu, Yunxia Zhao, Yunfei Bu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202402935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical and experimental investigations of vanadium pentoxide&#8211;based electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00679-0</link>
      <description>Dima Abu Alhawa, Ahmed Badreldin, Abdellatif El-Ghenymy, Noor Hafizah Hassan, Wubulikasimu Yiming, Khaled Elsaid, Ahmed Abdel&#8208;Wahab, Emergent materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394813280

                Abstract A key approach towards better realization of intermittent renewable energy resources, namely, solar and wind, is green electrochemical hydrogen production from water electrolysis. In recent years, there have been increasing efforts aimed at developing noble metal-free electrocatalysts that are earth-abundant and electroactive towards hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline electrolytes, wherein an initial water dissociation step is followed by a two-electron transfer cathodic reaction. Although relatively earth-abundant, vanadium-based electrocatalysts have been sparsely reported due to subpar electroactivity and kinetics towards water electrolysis in general and alkaline electrolysis in specific. Herein, we investigate the fine-tuning of orthorhombic V 2 O 5 -based electrocatalysts as candidates for HER through a scalable two-step sol&#8211;gel calcination procedure. Briefly, surface-induced anionic oxygen deficiencies and cationic dopants are synergistically studied experimentally and theoretically. To that end, first-principle facet-dependent density function theory (DFT) calculations were conducted and revealed that the coupling of certain dopants on V 2 O 5 and co-induction of oxygen vacancies can enhance the catalytic HER performance by the creation of new electronic states near the Fermi level ( E F ), enhancing conductivity, and modulating surface binding of adsorbed protons, respectively. This was reflected experimentally through kinetically non-ideal alkaline electrochemical HER using Zn 0.4 V 1.6 O 5 whereby &#8722; 194 mV of overpotential was required to attain &#8722; 10 mA/cm 2 of current density, as opposed to pristine V 2 O 5 which required 32% higher overpotential requirement at the same conditions. The disclosed work can be extended to other intrinsically sluggish transition metal (TM)&#8211;based oxides via the presented systematic tuning of surface and bulk microenvironment modulation. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Dima Abu Alhawa, Ahmed Badreldin, Abdellatif El-Ghenymy, Noor Hafizah Hassan, Wubulikasimu Yiming, Khaled Elsaid, Ahmed Abdel&#8208;Wahab</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00679-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Petrogenesis of the Newly Discovered Neoproterozoic Adakitic Rock in Bure Area, Western Ethiopia Shield: Implication for the Pan-African Tectonic Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min14040408</link>
      <description>Junsheng Jiang, Wang Xiang, Peng Hu, Yulin Li, Fang Wu, Zeng Guo-ping, Xinran Guo, Zicheng Zhang, Yuhang Bai, Minerals. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394837348

                The Neoproterozoic Bure adakitic rock in the western Ethiopia shield is a newly discovered magmatic rock type. However, the physicochemical conditions during its formation, and its source characteristics are still not clear, restricting a full understanding of its petrogenesis and geodynamic evolution. In this study, in order to shed light on the physicochemical conditions during rock formation and provide further constraints on the petrogenesis of the Bure adakitic rock, we conduct electron microprobe analysis on K-feldspar, plagioclase, and biotite. Additionally, we investigate the trace elements and Hf isotopes of zircon, and the Sr-Nd isotopes of the whole rock. The results show that the K-feldspar is orthoclase (Or = 89.08~96.37), the plagioclase is oligoclase (Ab = 74.63~85.99), and the biotite is magnesio-biotite. Based on the biotite analysis results, we calculate that the pressure during rock formation was 1.75~2.81 kbar (average value of 2.09 kbar), representing a depth of approximately 6.39~10.2 km (average value of 7.60 km). The zircon thermometer yields a crystallization temperature of 659~814 &#176;C. Most of the (Ce/Ce*)D values in the zircons plotted above the Ni-NiO oxygen buffer pair, and the calculated magmatic oxygen fugacity (logfO2) values vary from &#8722;18.5 to &#8722;4.9, revealing a relatively high magma oxygen fugacity. The uniform contents of FeO, MgO, and K2O in the biotite suggest a crustal magma source for the Bure adakitic rock. The relatively low (87Sr/86Sr)i values of 0.70088 to 0.70275, positive &#949;Nd(t) values of 3.26 to 7.28, together with the positive &#949;Hf(t) values of 7.64~12.99, suggest that the magma was sourced from a Neoproterozoic juvenile crust, with no discernable involvement of a pre-Neoproterozoic continental crust, which is coeval with early magmatic stages in the Arabian Nubian Shield elsewhere. Additionally, the mean Nd model ages demonstrate an increasing trend from the northern parts (Egypt, Sudan, Afif terrane of Arabia, and Eritrea and northern Ethiopia; 0.87 Ga) to the central parts (Western Ethiopia shield; 1.03 Ga) and southern parts (Southern Ethiopia Shield, 1.13 Ga; Kenya, 1.2 Ga) of the East African Orogen, which indicate an increasing contribution of pre-Pan-African crust towards the southern part of the East African Orogen. Based on the negative correlation between MgO and Al2O3 in the biotite, together with the Lu/Hf-Y and Yb-Y results of the zircon, we infer that the Bure adakitic rock was formed in an arc&#8211;arc collision orogenic environment. Combining this inference with the whole rock geochemistry and U-Pb age of the Bure adakitic rock, we further propose that the rock is the product of thickened juvenile crust melting triggered by the Neoproterozoic Pan-African Orogeny.</description>
      <author>Junsheng Jiang, Wang Xiang, Peng Hu, Yulin Li, Fang Wu, Zeng Guo-ping, Xinran Guo, Zicheng Zhang, Yuhang Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min14040408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co and Co3O4 in the Hydrolysis of Boron-Containing Hydrides: H2O Activation on the Metal and Oxide Active Centers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17081794</link>
      <description>Vladislav R. Butenko, O.V. Komova, &#1042;.&#1048;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1084;&#1072;&#1075;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, Inna L. Lipatnikova, Anna M. Ozerova, N. A. Danilova, Vladimir A. Rogov, &#1043;. &#1042;. &#1054;&#1076;&#1077;&#1075;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1054;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1083;&#1072;&#1074;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Yu. A. Chesalov, O.V. Netskina, Materials. 17(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394817931

                This work focuses on the comparison of H2 evolution in the hydrolysis of boron-containing hydrides (NaBH4, NH3BH3, and (CH2NH2BH3)2) over the Co metal catalyst and the Co3O4-based catalysts. The Co3O4 catalysts were activated in the reaction medium, and a small amount of CuO was added to activate Co3O4 under the action of weaker reducers (NH3BH3, (CH2NH2BH3)2). The high activity of Co3O4 has been previously associated with its reduced states (nanosized CoBn). The performed DFT modeling shows that activating water on the metal-like surface requires overcoming a higher energy barrier compared to hydride activation. The novelty of this study lies in its focus on understanding the impact of the remaining cobalt oxide phase. The XRD, TPR H2, TEM, Raman, and ATR FTIR confirm the formation of oxygen vacancies in the Co3O4 structure in the reaction medium, which increases the amount of adsorbed water. The kinetic isotopic effect measurements in D2O, as well as DFT modeling, reveal differences in water activation between Co and Co3O4-based catalysts. It can be assumed that the oxide phase serves not only as a precursor and support for the reduced nanosized cobalt active component but also as a key catalyst component that improves water activation.</description>
      <author>Vladislav R. Butenko, O.V. Komova, &#1042;.&#1048;. &#1057;&#1080;&#1084;&#1072;&#1075;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;, Inna L. Lipatnikova, Anna M. Ozerova, N. A. Danilova, Vladimir A. Rogov, &#1043;. &#1042;. &#1054;&#1076;&#1077;&#1075;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1054;. &#1040;. &#1041;&#1091;&#1083;&#1072;&#1074;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Yu. A. Chesalov, O.V. Netskina</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17081794</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sunburst Arc with JWST: Detection of Wolf-Rayet stars injecting
  nitrogen into a low-metallicity, $z=2.37$ proto-globular cluster leaking
  ionizing photons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.08884</link>
      <description>T. Emil Rivera-Thorsen, J. Chisholm, Brian Welch, J. Keith Rigby, Taylor A. Hutchison, Michael Florian, Keren Sharon, Seungho Choe, H. Dahle, Matthew B. Bayliss, Gourav Khullar, Michael Gladders, Matthew Hayes, Angela Adamo, M. R. Owens, Ki Wook Kim, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394867466

                We report the detection of a population of Wolf-Rayet (WR) stars in the Sunburst Arc, a strongly gravitationally lensed galaxy at redshift $z=2.37$. As the brightest known lensed galaxy, the Sunburst Arc has become an important cosmic laboratory for studying star and cluster formation, Lyman $\alpha$ radiative transfer, and Lyman Continuum (LyC) escape. Here, we present the first results of JWST/NIRCam imaging and NIRSpec IFU observations of the Sunburst Arc, focusing on a stacked spectrum of the 12-fold imaged LyC-emitting (Sunburst LCE) cluster. In agreement with previous studies, we find that the cluster is massive and compact, with $M_{\text{dyn}} = (9\pm1) \times 10^{6} M_{\odot}$, Our age estimate of 4.2--4.5 Myr is much larger than the crossing time of $t_{\text{cross}} = 183 \pm 9 $ kyr, indicating that the cluster is dynamically evolved and consistent with being gravitationally bound. We find a significant nitrogen enhancement of the low ionization state ISM, with $\log(N/O) = -0.74 \pm 0.09$, which is $\approx 0.8$ dex above typical values for H II regions of similar metallicity in the local Universe. We find broad stellar emission complexes around He II$\lambda 4686$ and C IV$\lambda 5808$ with associated nitrogen emission -- this is the first time WR signatures have been directly observed at redshifts above $\sim 0.5$. The strength of the WR signatures cannot be reproduced by stellar population models that only include single-star evolution. While models with binary evolution better match the WR features, they still struggle to reproduce the nitrogen-enhanced WR features. JWST reveals the Sunburst LCE to be a highly ionized, proto-globular cluster with low oxygen abundance and extreme nitrogen enhancement that hosts a population of Wolf-Rayet stars, and possibly Very Massive stars (VMSs), which are rapidly enriching the surrounding medium.</description>
      <author>T. Emil Rivera-Thorsen, J. Chisholm, Brian Welch, J. Keith Rigby, Taylor A. Hutchison, Michael Florian, Keren Sharon, Seungho Choe, H. Dahle, Matthew B. Bayliss, Gourav Khullar, Michael Gladders, Matthew Hayes, Angela Adamo, M. R. Owens, Ki Wook Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.08884</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-in-one tandem catalysis for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction on Pt/CoV-LDHs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151237</link>
      <description>Xiaoxiao Li, Yu Yan, Yuan Yao, Yang Liu, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394858366

                Constructing a local acid-like microenvironment is an important and challenging issue for alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). In this work, we demonstrate a Three-in-one tandem catalysis strategy to achieve this goal. The ideal tandem catalyst should possess three separated active sites to drive three subsequent reaction steps, including water decomposition to construct a local acid-like microenvironment, H3O+ migration, and H2 production under alkaline conditions, respectively. Taking the Pt single atom anchored on CoV layered double hydroxides (Pt/CoV-LDHs) as a prototypical example, we have successfully constructed a local acid-like microenvironment and realized remarkable alkaline HER performances using theoretical prediction and experimental verification. In situ Raman spectroscopy observes the emergence of a key H3O+ intermediate. The further analysis reveals the mechanism of tandem catalysis that water molecule adsorbs on V site with the assistance of oxygen vacancy in CoV-LDHs; V and Co sites play synergistic role in dissociating water to construct a local acid-like microenvironment; Co sites transport H3O+ intermediate to Pt site for HER which undergoes Volmer-Tafel mechanism with fast kinetics. This work exhibits a rational on-demand design strategy of catalysis and may broaden the horizon of catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Xiaoxiao Li, Yu Yan, Yuan Yao, Yang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and kinetic analysis on the biomass syngas fueled chemical looping hydrogen generation process in fixed bed reactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131308</link>
      <description>Zixiang Gao, Di Wu, Fan Yin, Libin Sun, Dewang Zeng, Rui Xiao, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394787383

                Because of its simple structure and easy operation, the fixed bed reactor is widely used in the chemical looping process to assess the performance of oxygen carriers (OC) or to evaluate new chemical looping technologies. However, the systematic investigation of the redox behavior and temperature evolution during the chemical looping hydrogen generation (CLHG) process in the fixed bed reactor under different conditions, which is crucial for process optimization and reactor design, has received less attention. In the present work, the redox characteristics of the CLHG process with biomass syngas as the fuel in a fixed bed reactor were investigated and analyzed from a perspective of thermodynamics and kinetics. Results showed that high redox temperature (&gt;800 &#176;C) favors the fuel conversion due to the improved reaction kinetics and favorable thermodynamics. A space velocity in the range of 0.12-0.5 s-1 and superficial velocity of 0.008-0.075 m/s can provide enough reaction time meanwhile enhance the external diffusion of fuel gas, achieving high reduction degree of OC and further high H2 yield (3.4 mmol/g Fe2O3) and high H2 energy efficiency (45%). Moreover, a violent OC bed temperature rise (100 &#176;C) was observed in the air oxidization stage, which can be mitigated by diluting the Fe2O3 content and decreasing the air flow rate. Finally, the reaction front and flow front moving behavior were discussed in detail for a better understanding of the CLHG process.</description>
      <author>Zixiang Gao, Di Wu, Fan Yin, Libin Sun, Dewang Zeng, Rui Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Triple&#8208;Phase Interfaces around the Anode towards Practical Alkali Metal&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202400937</link>
      <description>Bingcheng Ge, Liang Hu, Xiaoliang Yu, Lixu Wang, Carlos Fernandez, Nianjun Yang, Qinghua Liang, Quan&#8208;Hong Yang, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394917123

                Abstract Alkali metal&#8211;air batteries (AMABs) promise ultrahigh gravimetric energy densities, while the inherent poor cycle stability hinders their practical application. To address this challenge, most previous efforts were devoted to advancing the air cathodes with high electrocatalytic activity. Recent studies have underlined the solid&#8211;liquid&#8211;gas triple&#8208;phase interface around the anode can play far more significant roles than previously acknowledged by the scientific community. Besides the bottlenecks of uncontrollable dendrite growth and gas evolution in conventional alkali metal batteries, the corrosive atmospheric gases, intermediate oxygen species, and redox mediators in AMABs cause more severe anode corrosion and structural collapse, posing greater challenges to the stabilization of the anode triple&#8208;phase interface. This work aims to provide a timely perspective on the anode interface engineering for durable AMABs. Taking the Li&#8211;air battery as a typical example, we have a critical review of the latest developed anode stabilization strategies, including formulating novel electrolytes to build protective interphases and alleviate corrosive attacks, fabricating advanced anodes to improve their anti&#8208;corrosion capability, and designing functional separator to shield the corrosive species. Finally, we highlight the remaining scientific and technical issues from the prospects of anode interface engineering, particularly materials system engineering, for the practical use of AMABs. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Bingcheng Ge, Liang Hu, Xiaoliang Yu, Lixu Wang, Carlos Fernandez, Nianjun Yang, Qinghua Liang, Quan&#8208;Hong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202400937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron irradiation effects and room-temperature annealing mechanisms for SiC MOSFETs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rinp.2024.107672</link>
      <description>Min He, Xuegong Yu, Yao Ma, Qingkui Yu, Shuang Cao, Wende Huang, Quan Xu, Sijie Zhang, Mingmin Huang, Yun Li, Zhimei Yang, Ming Gong, Results in physics. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394865891

                In this work, the electron irradiation effects and post-irradiation annealing (PIA) response on SiC MOSFETs were investigated and analyzed in terms of the evolution of oxide- and interface-trap charges after irradiation and PIA. It is found that the electron irradiation leads to the significant decrease of Ron, degraded blocking characteristics, and negative shift of capacitance characteristics, which can be ascribed to the promoted generation of positively charged oxide and interface traps by irradiation. Interestingly, these degraded electrical properties can be partly or completely recovered by room-temperature (RT) anneal, which is associated with the difference in the sensitivity to the oxide/interface charge variations in the channel, JFET, and termination region. Surprisingly, the positive charge in the oxide presents an incomplete recovery, which is suggested to result from the tunneling electrons from SiC and thus the subsequent electron capture by positively charged oxygen vacancy in the oxide. Whereas, the irradiation-induced interface-trap charges are fully eliminated even after RT anneal for 15 days. Deep-Level Transient Spectroscopy (DLTS) characterizations shows that the interface defects with the energy band from EC &#8722; 0.14 eV to EC &#8722; 0.7 eV are enhanced by irradiation and exhibits similar dependence on the filling pulse as the near-interface traps. However, the irradiation-induced interface state density (Dit) distributions show a recovery behavior after RT storage, which is suggested to be resulted from the change in the charge states of interface defects from the electron trapping.</description>
      <author>Min He, Xuegong Yu, Yao Ma, Qingkui Yu, Shuang Cao, Wende Huang, Quan Xu, Sijie Zhang, Mingmin Huang, Yun Li, Zhimei Yang, Ming Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rinp.2024.107672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding the landscape of anti-MoS2 monolayers: computational exploration of stability and multifaceted properties across the periodic table</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2861-2</link>
      <description>Fengyu Li, Yu Liu, Linke Yu, Xiaodong Liu, Peng Jin, Zhongfang Chen, Science China. Materials. 67(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394936891

                Inspired by the distinctive structural and electronic properties of two-dimensional (2D) transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs), we conducted comprehensive high-throughput first-principles computations to screen stable 2D chalcogenides X2T (X = transition metals Sc&#8211;Hg, totally 29 and main group elements Li&#8211;Ba, totally 37; T = S, Se, and Te) with anti-MoS2 configurations in both 1T and 2H phases. Among 396 evaluated candidates, the selected X2T monolayers (X = Sc, Fe, Y, Zr, Nb, Hf, Ta, IA elements Li&#8211;Fr, IIA elements Ca&#8211;Ra, N, In, Tl, and Te; T = S, Se, or Te) demonstrate outstanding thermodynamic, dynamic, mechanical properties, and thermal stabilities in 1T/1T&#8242; or 2H phases. These anti-MoS2 variants exhibit diverse characteristics, serving as nonmagnetic/magnetic metals or nonmagnetic/antiferromagnetic semiconductors, often surpassing MoS2 in Young's modulus and/or displaying negative Poisson's ratios. Transition-metal-based monolayers show susceptibility to O2 oxidization, and some show high N2 dissociation activity. Oxygen/nitrogen-terminations can quench TM magnetism and increase band-gaps over their pristine counterparts. Notably, the 2H-Fe2S monolayer maintains robust antiferromagnetism upon O-termination. Moreover, TM-based X2T sheets demonstrate promise as efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reactions. This study expands the diversity of 2D materials with new members and novel functional properties and broadens their potential applications.</description>
      <author>Fengyu Li, Yu Liu, Linke Yu, Xiaodong Liu, Peng Jin, Zhongfang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2861-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Operation of Chloralkaline Reversible Cells with Mixed Metal Oxide Electrodes Made Using Microwaves</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14080693</link>
      <description>Jamylle Yanka Cruz Ribeiro, G&#233;ssica de Oliveira Santiago Santos, Aline R. D&#243;ria, I&#241;aki Requena, Marcos R.V. Lanza, Giancarlo R. Salazar&#8208;Banda, Katlin I.B. Eguiluz, Justo Lobato, Manuel A. Rodrigo, Nanomaterials. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394877501

                This study focuses on the synthesis of mixed metal oxide anodes (MMOs) with the composition Ti/RuO2Sb2O4Ptx (where x = 0, 5, 10 mol) using hybrid microwave irradiation heating. The synthesized electrodes were characterized using scanning electron microscopy, X-ray energy-dispersive analysis, X-ray diffraction, cyclic voltammetry, and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. These electrodes were then evaluated in both bulk electrolytic and fuel cell tests within a reversible chloralkaline electrochemical cell. The configurations using the electrodes Ti/(RuO2)0.7-(Sb2O4)0.3 and Ti/(RuO2)66.5-(Sb2O4)28.5-Pt5 presented lower onset potential for oxygen and chlorine evolution reactions and reduced resistance to charge transfer compared to the Ti/(RuO2)63-(Sb2O4)27-Pt10 variant. These electrodes demonstrated notable performance in reversible electrochemical cells, achieving Coulombic efficiencies of up to 60% when operating in the electrolytic mode at current densities of 150 mA cm&#8722;2. They also reached maximum power densities of 1.2 mW cm&#8722;2 in the fuel cell. In both scenarios, the presence of platinum in the MMO coating positively influenced the process. Furthermore, a significant challenge encountered was crossover through the membranes, primarily associated with gaseous Cl2. This study advances our understanding of reversible electrochemical cells and presents possibilities for further exploration and refinement. It demonstrated that the synergy of innovative electrode synthesis strategies and electrochemical engineering can lead to promising and sustainable technologies for energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Jamylle Yanka Cruz Ribeiro, G&#233;ssica de Oliveira Santiago Santos, Aline R. D&#243;ria, I&#241;aki Requena, Marcos R.V. Lanza, Giancarlo R. Salazar&#8208;Banda, Katlin I.B. Eguiluz, Justo Lobato, Manuel A. Rodrigo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14080693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Model of Carbon Nitride as a Substrate to Support Single Metal Atom</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00975</link>
      <description>Pan Du, Shengwei Deng, Liang Chen, Ziqi Tian, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394933990

                Carbon nitrides are commonly employed as substrates to anchor single metal atoms. Numerous theoretical studies have previously characterized these single-atom systems using the pristine g-C3N4 structure, featuring a C6N7 motif. However, the relatively large pores in g-C3N4 may not effectively coordinate with metal cations, resulting in discordance with the coordination environment determined by experimental characterization. In this study, we introduce a novel model denoted as CN-N4, which preserves the essential g-C3N4 motif, while offering four nitrogen sites for metal binding. Compared with g-C3N4, the binding affinity between the metal and this new substrate model is significantly enhanced, similar to that of a commonly studied nitrogen-doped graphene model (N-gra). Additionally, we have assessed the catalytic performance in various reactions, including the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The CN-N4-supported system exhibits activity comparable to that of the corresponding N-gra-supported species. Fe- and Co-centered SACs can be promising catalysts for ORR, and relatively stable Cu-g-C3N4 is active to HER and CO2RR, consistent with reported experiments. In addition, V-CN-N4 and Rh-CN-N4 are predicted to be candidates to catalyze the HER and ORR, respectively. We suggest that the CN-N4 model aptly captures the local structure of carbon nitride-based materials with a high coordination number, providing an alternative foundation for investigating the reaction mechanisms of these single-atom catalysts.</description>
      <author>Pan Du, Shengwei Deng, Liang Chen, Ziqi Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ARE WE ASTRONAUTS BEFORE BIRTH? A MIRACLE OF INTRAUTERINE LIFE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47960/3029-3316.2024.1.1.48</link>
      <description>Milan Stanojevi&#263;, Asim Kurjak, No host. 1(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394921115

                Although a life in the womb is often described as a miracle of nature, it is still a mystery connected with many controversies even though science has the means to follow fetal intrauterine development virtually from the conception. Fetalassessmentisundertakentodetermineits&#8217; developmentandwell-beingusingdifferenttechniques.Assessment of fetal well-being can begin in early and late pregnancy, and during labor. An important ultrasound method for the evaluationofneurologicalwell-beingofthefetusisfour-dimensionalultrasound(4DUS)suitableforassessmentoffetal behavior. While assessing behavior using 4D US examiner is trying to understand how fetus is adapted in intrauterine environment by observation of different movements of the body, extremities and the head including facial expressions. From the evolutionary point of view temperature (either cold, hot or thermoneutral) and gravity (microgravity, or 1G Earth gravity) belong to controlling mechanisms of the origin and evolution of life on Earth. Intrauterine milieu with microgravityisimportantforoveralldevelopmentofhumanbeings.Inthisenvironmenteveryindividualisbeingprepared to be exposed to hostile extrauterine conditions characterized by cold and by Earth gravity (1G).Cold-induced activity and adaptation to cold can substitute 15 to 20% of the gravity and induce the activity of slow muscular fibers. After we were born or in other words while we landed from the universe and were exposed to cold, high oxygen concentrations and gravity, we stopped being astronauts and continued life as humans whose first year of development was marked by the tyranny of gravity.The aim of the paper is to speculate about the significance of intrauterine environment in terms of development and preparation of the fetus to be exposed to hostile extrauterine milieu.Keywords:BabyAstronautHypothesis,gravity,microgravity,fetalbehavior,four-dimensionalultrasound</description>
      <author>Milan Stanojevi&#263;, Asim Kurjak</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47960/3029-3316.2024.1.1.48</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracing rate and extent of human induced hypoxia during the last 200 years in the mesotrophic lake Tiefer See (NE Germany)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-835</link>
      <description>Ido Sirota, Rik Tjallingii, Sylvia Pinkerneil, Birgit Schroeder, M. R. Albert, Rebecca Kearney, Oliver Heiri, Silvia Breu, Achim Brauer, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394920040

                Abstract. The global spread of lake hypoxia, [O2] &lt; 2 mg/l, during the last two centuries has a severe impact on ecological systems and sedimentation processes. While the occurance of hypoxia was observed in many lakes, a detailed quantification of hypoxia spread remained largely unquantified. We track the evolution of hypoxia and its controls during the past 200 yrs in lake Tiefer See (TSK; NE Germany) using 17 gravity cores, recovered between 10 and 62 m water depth in combination with lake monitoring data. Lake hypoxia was associated by the onset of varve preservation in the TSK, and has been dated by varve counting to 1918&#177;1 at 62 m water depth and reached a lake-floor depth of 16 m at 1997&#177;1. This indicates oxygen concentration to fell below the threshold for varve preservation at the lakefloor (&gt;16 m). Sediment cores at 10&#8211;12 m depth do not contain varves indicating well oxygenation of the upper water column. Monitoring data show that the threshold for hypoxia at the depocenter is a period of five months of [O2] &lt; 5 mgl and two months of [O2] &lt; 2 mgl . Detailed TOC, &#948;13Corg and XRF core scanning analyses of the short cores indicate that the depletion in DO started several decades prior to the varve preservation. This proves a change in the depositional conditions in the lake following a transition phase of several decades during which varve preservation was not accomplished. Furthermore, varve preservation does occur at seasonal stratification and not necessarily requires permanent stratification.</description>
      <author>Ido Sirota, Rik Tjallingii, Sylvia Pinkerneil, Birgit Schroeder, M. R. Albert, Rebecca Kearney, Oliver Heiri, Silvia Breu, Achim Brauer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-835</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the Pyrolysis and Gas Generation Behavior of Silicomanganese Slag and Assessing its Foaming Abilities in Foam Glass Ceramic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142250</link>
      <description>Shichan Deng, Changrong Li, Xiaofeng Huang, Hongwei Guo, Wei Zhao, Bingji Yan, Peng Li, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394824603

                This paper proposes a novel route for the utilization of silicomanganese slag in the preparation of high-temperature foam ceramic materials, grounded in the unique characteristics of the slag. The phase evolution and gas generation mechanisms of silicomanganese slag was systematically investigated using thermogravimetric mass spectrometry (TG-MS), thermodynamic simulation, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and energy-dispersive spectroscopy (EDS). Foam glass ceramic with a density of 291&#177;8 kg/m3 and a compressive strength of 2.83&#177;0.07 MPa was prepared using silicomanganese slag as a foaming agent. This research indicated that manganese and sulfur in the silicomanganese slag are critical contributors to gas generation. Manganese in the slag oxidizes to dimanganese trioxide (Mn2O3) before reaching 1000&#176;C, and at temperatures between 1000-1200&#176;C, trivalent manganese (Mn3+) converts to divalent manganese (Mn2+) and enters the pyroxene crystal, releasing oxygen (O2). Sulfur in the slag, captured by divalent calcium (Ca2+), forms a more stable calcium sulfate (CaSO4) during heating and enriches the slag particle surface. As the temperature exceeds 1000&#176;C, Ca2+ gradually integrates into the pyroxene, prompting the release of sulfate decomposition products, forming sulfur dioxide (SO2) and O2. A small fraction of unreacted CaSO4 enters the glass phase, forming fibrous crystals that enhance the compressive strength of the foam glass-ceramic through fiber reinforcement. The outcomes of this work offer new insights into the high-value utilization of silicomanganese slag and enrich the understanding of gas generation mechanisms in Mn-based and S-based foaming agents.</description>
      <author>Shichan Deng, Changrong Li, Xiaofeng Huang, Hongwei Guo, Wei Zhao, Bingji Yan, Peng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A JWST Survey of the Supernova Remnant Cassiopeia A</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ad324b</link>
      <description>Dan Milisavljevic, Tea Temim, I. De Looze, Danielle Dickinson, J. Martin Laming, Robert A. Fesen, J. C. Raymond, Richard G. Arendt, Jacco Vink, Bettina Posselt, George G. Pavlov, O. Fox, Ethan Pinarski, B. M. Subrayan, J. Schmidt, William P. Blair, A. Rest, Daniel Patnaude, Bon&#8208;Chul Koo, Jeonghee Rho, S. Orlando, Hans-Thomas Janka, Moira Andrews, M. J. Barlow, Adam Burrows, Roger A. Chevalier, Geoffrey C. Clayton, Claes Fransson, Chris L. Fryer, Haley Louise Gomez, Florian Kirchschlager, Jae-Joon Lee, M. Matsuura, Maria Niculescu-Duvaz, Justin Pierel, Paul P. Plucinsky, F. D. Priestley, Aravind P. Ravi, Nina S. Sartorio, Franziska Schmidt, Melissa Shahbandeh, Patrick Slane, Nathan Smith, Niharika Sravan, Kathryn E. Weil, R. Wesson, J. C. Wheeler, &#152;The &#156;astrophysical journal. Letters. 965(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394858444

                Abstract We present initial results from a James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) survey of the youngest Galactic core-collapse supernova remnant, Cassiopeia A (Cas A), made up of NIRCam and MIRI imaging mosaics that map emission from the main shell, interior, and surrounding circumstellar/interstellar material (CSM/ISM). We also present four exploratory positions of MIRI Medium Resolution Spectrograph integral field unit spectroscopy that sample ejecta, CSM, and associated dust from representative shocked and unshocked regions. Surprising discoveries include (1) a weblike network of unshocked ejecta filaments resolved to &#8764;0.01 pc scales exhibiting an overall morphology consistent with turbulent mixing of cool, low-entropy matter from the progenitor&#8217;s oxygen layer with hot, high-entropy matter heated by neutrino interactions and radioactivity; (2) a thick sheet of dust-dominated emission from shocked CSM seen in projection toward the remnant&#8217;s interior pockmarked with small (&#8764;1&#8243;) round holes formed by &#8818;0.&#8243;1 knots of high-velocity ejecta that have pierced through the CSM and driven expanding tangential shocks; and (3) dozens of light echoes with angular sizes between &#8764;0.&#8243;1 and 1&#8242; reflecting previously unseen fine-scale structure in the ISM. NIRCam observations place new upper limits on infrared emission (&#8818;20 nJy at 3 &#956; m) from the neutron star in Cas A&#8217;s center and tightly constrain scenarios involving a possible fallback disk. These JWST survey data and initial findings help address unresolved questions about massive star explosions that have broad implications for the formation and evolution of stellar populations, the metal and dust enrichment of galaxies, and the origin of compact remnant objects.</description>
      <author>Dan Milisavljevic, Tea Temim, I. De Looze, Danielle Dickinson, J. Martin Laming, Robert A. Fesen, J. C. Raymond, Richard G. Arendt, Jacco Vink, Bettina Posselt, George G. Pavlov, O. Fox, Ethan Pinarski, B. M. Subrayan, J. Schmidt, William P. Blair, A. Rest, Daniel Patnaude, Bon&#8208;Chul Koo, Jeonghee Rho, S. Orlando, Hans-Thomas Janka, Moira Andrews, M. J. Barlow, Adam Burrows, Roger A. Chevalier, Geoffrey C. Clayton, Claes Fransson, Chris L. Fryer, Haley Louise Gomez, Florian Kirchschlager, Jae-Joon Lee, M. Matsuura, Maria Niculescu-Duvaz, Justin Pierel, Paul P. Plucinsky, F. D. Priestley, Aravind P. Ravi, Nina S. Sartorio, Franziska Schmidt, Melissa Shahbandeh, Patrick Slane, Nathan Smith, Niharika Sravan, Kathryn E. Weil, R. Wesson, J. C. Wheeler</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ad324b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Causes Influence Functional Aspects and Quality of Life in Patients with Nonfibrocystic Bronchiectasis?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/3446536</link>
      <description>&#193;dria Cristina da Silva, Jessica de Campos Medeiros, M&#244;nica Corso Pereira, Pulmonary medicine. 2024(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394803689

                Background. The denomination of noncystic fibrosis bronchiectasis (NCFB) includes several causes, and differences may be expected between the patient subgroups regarding age, comorbidities, and clinical and functional evolution. This study sought to identify the main causes of NCFB in a cohort of stable adult patients and to investigate whether such conditions would be different in their clinical, functional, and quality of life aspects. Methods. Between 2017 and 2019, all active patients with NCFB were prospectively evaluated searching for clinical data, past medical history, dyspnea severity grading, quality of life data, microbiological profile, and lung function (spirometry and six-minute walk test). Results. There was a female predominance; mean age was 54.7 years. Causes were identified in 82% of the patients, the most frequent being postinfections ( n=39 ), ciliary dyskinesia (CD) ( n=32 ), and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) ( n=29 ). COPD patients were older, more often smokers (or former smokers) and with more comorbidities; they also had worse lung function (spirometry and oxygenation) and showed worse performance in the six-minute walk test (6MWT) (walked distance and exercise-induced hypoxemia). Considering the degree of dyspnea, in the more symptomatic group, patients had higher scores in the three domains and total score in SGRQ, besides having more exacerbations and more patients in home oxygen therapy. Conclusions. Causes most identified were postinfections, CD, and COPD. Patients with COPD are older and have worse pulmonary function and more comorbidities. The most symptomatic patients are clinically and functionally more severe, besides having worse quality of life.</description>
      <author>&#193;dria Cristina da Silva, Jessica de Campos Medeiros, M&#244;nica Corso Pereira</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/3446536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal Alteration Processes of Xincheng Gold Deposit Jiaodong Peninsula, China: Constraints from Composition of Hydrothermal Rutile</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min14040417</link>
      <description>Zhenjun Liu, Liqiang Yang, Dong Xie, Wei Yang, Dapeng Li, Tao Feng, Jun Deng, Minerals. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394914778

                Delineating the process of hydrothermal alteration is crucial for effectively enhancing exploration strategies and better understanding the gold mineralization process. Rutile, with its capacity to accommodate a wide range of trace elements including high-field-strength elements and base metals, serves as a reliable fluid tracer in ore systems. As one of the most significant gold ore concentrations globally, Jiaodong boasts a gold reserve exceeding 5500 t. The Xincheng gold deposit is a world-class high-grade mine, boasting a proven gold reserve exceeding 200 t, and stands as one of the largest altered-type gold deposits in the vast gold province of the Jiaodong Peninsula, Eastern China. In this study, rutile (Rt1,2,3) was identified in the K-feldspar alteration, sericitization, and pyrite&#8211;sericite&#8211;quartz alteration stages of the Xincheng gold deposit in Jiaodong based on petrographic characteristics. Rt1 coexists with hydrothermal K-feldspar and quartz, while Rt2 coexists with minerals such as sericite, quartz, muscovite, and pyrite. Rt3 is widely distributed in hydrothermal veins and is primarily associated with minerals including quartz, pyrite, chalcopyrite, and sericite. Raman spectroscopy, EPMA, and LA-ICP-MS analysis were conducted to investigate the characteristics and evolution of altered hydrothermal fluids. This study indicates that the Zr vs. W and Nb/V vs. W diagrams suggest that Rt1 is of magmatic&#8211;hydrothermal origin, while Rt2 and Rt3 are of metamorphic&#8211;hydrothermal origin. Notably, the W content in Rt2 and Rt3 is significantly higher than in Rt1 (&lt;100 ppm), suggesting a close relationship between the W content in rutile and mineralization. The three types of rutile exhibit significantly different concentrations of trace elements such as W, V, Nb, Zr, Sn, and Fe, displaying distinct bright spots and elemental zoning characteristics in backscattered electron images and surface scans. These features arise from the isomorphic substitution of Ti4+. While Rt1 exhibits no significant element exchange with the hydrothermal fluids, Rt2 and Rt3 show a stronger substitution of W, Nb, V, and Fe, indicating a gradual enrichment of F and Cl in the fluids. This process activates and transports these elements into the fluids, leading to their continuous accumulation within the system. From Rt1 to Rt3, the increasing concentrations of Fe and W, along with the negative Eu anomaly, suggest a decrease in fluid temperature and oxygen fugacity during the alteration and mineralization process. The gradual increase in the contents of REEs and high-field-strength elements such as W, V, Nb, and Sn indicates that the hydrothermal fluids are enriched in F and Cl, exhibiting weak acidity. The nature of the fluids during hydrothermal alteration is closely related to the composition of rutile, making it a promising tool for studying hydrothermal alteration and related mineralization processes.</description>
      <author>Zhenjun Liu, Liqiang Yang, Dong Xie, Wei Yang, Dapeng Li, Tao Feng, Jun Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min14040417</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
