<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 01:22:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel-type calcium manganese oxide adorned on g-CN composite: A highly proficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111629</link>
      <description>Zarghuna Firdous, A. Alhadhrami, Khursheed Ahmad, Muhammad Arslan Aslam, Mohamed M. Ibrahim, Abdulraheem S. A. Almalki, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402955853

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zarghuna Firdous, A. Alhadhrami, Khursheed Ahmad, Muhammad Arslan Aslam, Mohamed M. Ibrahim, Abdulraheem S. A. Almalki, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Passivation of Mn2+&#8208;Doped CsPbX3(X=Cl,Br) Perovskite Nanocrystals as Electriccatalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400798</link>
      <description>Haiyun Zhou, Pingping Li, Tingting Zhong, Yang Teng, Siqi Li, Xiaofeng Luo, Sheng Wang, Min Yang, Guowei Deng, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402964302

                Mn:CsPbX3 (X= Cl, Br) nanosheets with excellent electrocatalytic properties are reported in this paper. Compared to conventional catalyst arrays, the band gap of Mn:CsPbBr3 nanocrystalline is easily tuned, the carrier diffusion distance is remote, the band edge position of the band structure is favorable for a wide range of electrocatalytic redox reactions, and the catalytic active site is maximally exposed. The Mn:CsPbBr3 exhibited preferable electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution (HER) performance in 1 mol/L KOH. The excess potential of the oxygen evolution reaction(OER) required to drive current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8208;2 is only 114.4 and 505.4 mV, with a Tafel slope of 43 mV dec&#8208;1. At a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2, the excess potential required for the HER is 158.6 mV and it exhibited excellent electrochemical stability. The Mn:CsPbBr3 nanocrystalline consists of two electrodes for the overall water splitting, requiring a voltage of only 1.45 V. Which in turn provides implications for the optimization of electrocatalysts in alkaline electrolytes with the aim of developing the next generation of 2D electrocatalysts for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Haiyun Zhou, Pingping Li, Tingting Zhong, Yang Teng, Siqi Li, Xiaofeng Luo, Sheng Wang, Min Yang, Guowei Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetal Metaphosphate/Molybdenum Oxide Heterostructure Nanowires for Boosting Overall Freshwater/Seawater Splitting at High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407892</link>
      <description>Pan Wang, Pan Wang, Tongwei Wu, Xuping Sun, Yanning Zhang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402967691

                Abstract Exploring excellent non&#8208;noble bifunctional electrocatalysts for freshwater/seawater splitting at high current densities has attracted extensive interest owing to strong anodic oxidation and severe chloride corrosion challenges. Herein, hierarchical bimetal Ni&#8208;Co metaphosphate/molybdenum oxide heterostructure nanowires (NiCoMoPO) are rationally designed and fabricated to efficiently boost oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline freshwater/seawater, where the favorable electronic structure from heterostructures, signified by X&#8208;ray absorption spectra, endows NiCoMoPO with the enhanced intrinsic activity, while its hierarchical nanowire structure and heterostructures provide abundant active sites. Additionally, the PO 3 &#8722; improves the chloride&#8208;corrosion resistance and efficiently facilitates the OER kinetics verified by theoretical and experimental studies. Therefore, NiCoMoPO drives 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 at low overpotentials of 467 and 442 mV for OER and HER in alkaline freshwater respectively, as well as a small cell voltage of 2.135 V for overall freshwater splitting with robust durability of 300 h. Impressively, due to the strong corrosion resistance, at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 of overall seawater splitting, NiCoMoPO maintains almost 2.096 V for 1200 h, indicating promising practical applications. This work sheds light on the rational design and fabrication of outstanding electrocatalysts at high current densities of seawater/freshwater splitting.</description>
      <author>Pan Wang, Pan Wang, Tongwei Wu, Xuping Sun, Yanning Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring of Zinc Oxide-based microstructures to efficiently promote piezocatalytic water oxidation and oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114312</link>
      <description>Paola Semeraro, Rosanna Pagano, Donato Valli, Michela Ottolini, Sudipto Pal, Johan Hofkens, Maarten B. J. Roeffaers, Gabriele Giancane, Salvatore Sortino, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402968254

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paola Semeraro, Rosanna Pagano, Donato Valli, Michela Ottolini, Sudipto Pal, Johan Hofkens, Maarten B. J. Roeffaers, Gabriele Giancane, Salvatore Sortino</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin B:NiCoOx-modified BiVO4 photoanode with abundant oxygen vacancies for photoelectrochemical glycerol conversion coupled with hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156324</link>
      <description>Zihu Kang, Yue Zheng, Haotong Li, Yujie Shen, Wanru Zhang, Meilan Huang, Xia Tao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402970418

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihu Kang, Yue Zheng, Haotong Li, Yujie Shen, Wanru Zhang, Meilan Huang, Xia Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3d-Orbital Overlap Modulated D-Band Center of High-Entropy Oxyhydroxide for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972232</link>
      <description>Shaobing Tang, Shuang Wei, Yujun Wu, Zhichao Jia, Zhengyu Bai, Lin Yang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402970947

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaobing Tang, Shuang Wei, Yujun Wu, Zhichao Jia, Zhengyu Bai, Lin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-Etched Silver Electrodes Loaded with Iron/Cobalt Catalysts for Enhanced Plasmon-Induced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972231</link>
      <description>Jian Wu, Zehua Dong, Yiming Niu, Xuguang Chen, Yuchuan Cheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402970948

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Wu, Zehua Dong, Yiming Niu, Xuguang Chen, Yuchuan Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First principles study of V2CT2-based MXenes materials in oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118686</link>
      <description>Wang Zhang, Shanmin Gao, Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Zhongzhou Dong, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402973557

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wang Zhang, Shanmin Gao, Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Zhongzhou Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel N-Doped Biomass Carbon Spheres Loaded with In-Situ Grown Feco Layered Double Hydroxide for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972166</link>
      <description>Chong Cai, Ningzhao Shang, Danhua Sun, Li Wang, Yufan Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402974013

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chong Cai, Ningzhao Shang, Danhua Sun, Li Wang, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction via a Surface Reconstruction-Induced Lattice Oxygen Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03594</link>
      <description>Subin Choi, Sejun Kim, Sunghoon Han, Jian Wang, Juwon Kim, Bonho Koo, Alexander A. Ryabin, Sebastian Kunze, Hyejeong Hyun, Jeongwoo Han, Shu-Chih Haw, Keun Hwa Chae, Chang Hyuck Choi, Hyungjun Kim, Jongwoo Lim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402976597

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subin Choi, Sejun Kim, Sunghoon Han, Jian Wang, Juwon Kim, Bonho Koo, Alexander A. Ryabin, Sebastian Kunze, Hyejeong Hyun, Jeongwoo Han, Shu-Chih Haw, Keun Hwa Chae, Chang Hyuck Choi, Hyungjun Kim, Jongwoo Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-Doped Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C/Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C Nanosheets as an Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalyst under Alkaline and Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04024</link>
      <description>Luyan Wang, Xili Liu, Keke Su, Wenfeng Liu, Fuquan Niu, Xiangnan Li, Hongyun Yue, Hongyu Dong, Shuting Yang, Yanhong Yin, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402977655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luyan Wang, Xili Liu, Keke Su, Wenfeng Liu, Fuquan Niu, Xiangnan Li, Hongyun Yue, Hongyu Dong, Shuting Yang, Yanhong Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual electric field effects boost bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156285</link>
      <description>Yi Yang, Jiugang Hu, Lili He, Yue Peng, Kejian Ding, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Xiaobo Ji, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402979721

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Yang, Jiugang Hu, Lili He, Yue Peng, Kejian Ding, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Xiaobo Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial modulation of catalysis mechanism via charge-asymmetric for enhanced electrocatalytic performance toward hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129934</link>
      <description>Bin Wang, Tianmin Zhang, Wang Gui, Xiyue Han, Xingqun Zheng, Guangtao Mao, Qingmei Wang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402979999

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Wang, Tianmin Zhang, Wang Gui, Xiyue Han, Xingqun Zheng, Guangtao Mao, Qingmei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129934</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure&#8211;Activity Relationships in Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408139</link>
      <description>Jingqi Guan, Jingru Sun, Siyu Chen, Siying Zhang, Luoluo Qi, Anaer Husile, Jingqi Guan, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402994393

                Abstract Oxygen electrocatalysis, as the pivotal circle of many green energy technologies, sets off a worldwide research boom in full swing, while its large kinetic obstacles require remarkable catalysts to break through. Here, based on summarizing reaction mechanisms and in situ characterizations, the structure&#8211;activity relationships of oxygen electrocatalysts are emphatically overviewed, including the influence of geometric morphology and chemical structures on the electrocatalytic performances. Subsequently, experimental/theoretical research is combined with device applications to comprehensively summarize the cutting&#8208;edge oxygen electrocatalysts according to various material categories. Finally, future challenges are forecasted from the perspective of catalyst development and device applications, favoring researchers to promote the industrialization of oxygen electrocatalysis at an early date.</description>
      <author>Jingqi Guan, Jingru Sun, Siyu Chen, Siying Zhang, Luoluo Qi, Anaer Husile, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of H2O2 in Near-Neutral Zn-air Batteries Enables Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3k21g-v2</link>
      <description>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402996465

                Rechargeable Zn-air batteries with near-neutral electrolytes hold promise as cheap, safe and sustainable devices, but they suffer from slow charge kinetics and remain poorly studied. Here we reveal a charge storage mechanism of near-neutral Zn-air batteries that is mediated by H2O2 formation upon cell discharge and its oxidation upon charge. The manifestation of this mechanism strongly depends on the electrolyte composition and positive electrode material, being pronounced when ZnSO4 solutions and carbon nanotubes are employed. Oxidation of dissolved H2O2 is facile, enabling oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at low potentials (~1.5 V vs. Zn2+/Zn) which, in contrast to conventional four-electron OER, does not induce corrosion of carbon electrodes. Facilitation of the H2O2-mediated pathway might therefore be helpful for developing high-performance near-neutral Zn-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3k21g-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn&#9472;O Covalency as a Lever for Na&#8314; Intercalation Kinetics: The Role of Oxygen Edge&#8208;Sharing Co Octahedral Sites in MnO&#8322;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407690</link>
      <description>Yuanming Liu, Weijie Fu, Shuyun Yao, Shiyu Wang, Yingjie Ji, Jingxian Li, Lanlan Shi, Sheng Wang, Feike Zhang, Jing Wang, Renhuai Liu, Jiangzhou Xie, Zhiyu Yang, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402999596

                Abstract The strategic enhancement of manganese&#8211;oxygen (Mn&#9472;O) covalency is a promising approach to improve the intercalation kinetics of sodium ions (Na&#8314;) in manganese dioxide (MnO 2 ). In this study, an augmenting Mn&#9472;O covalency in MnO 2 by strategically incorporating cobalt at oxygen edge&#8208;sharing Co octahedral sites is focused on. Both experimental results and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal an increased electron polarization from oxygen to manganese, surpassing that directed toward cobalt, thereby facilitating enhanced electron transfer and strengthening covalency. The synthesized Co&#8211;MnO 2 material exhibits outstanding electrochemical performance, demonstrating a superior specific capacitance of 388 F g &#8722;1 at 1 A g &#8722;1 and maintaining 97.21% capacity retention after 12000 cycles. Additionally, an asymmetric supercapacitor constructed using Co&#8211;MnO 2 achieved a high energy density of 35 Wh kg &#8722;1 at a power density of 1000 W kg &#8722;1 , underscoring the efficacy of this material in practical applications. This work highlights the critical role of transition metal&#8211;oxygen interactions in optimizing electrode materials and introduces a robust approach to enhance the functional properties of manganese oxides, thereby advancing high&#8208;performance energy storage technologies.</description>
      <author>Yuanming Liu, Weijie Fu, Shuyun Yao, Shiyu Wang, Yingjie Ji, Jingxian Li, Lanlan Shi, Sheng Wang, Feike Zhang, Jing Wang, Renhuai Liu, Jiangzhou Xie, Zhiyu Yang, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing oxygen evolution promoting hole defect states at BiVO4 surface for enhanced photoelectrochemical activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.09.009</link>
      <description>Fatima Chmali, Basanth S. Kalanoor, Shankara S. Kalanur, Bruno G. Pollet, Nano Materials Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403000453

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fatima Chmali, Basanth S. Kalanoor, Shankara S. Kalanur, Bruno G. Pollet</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.09.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological Synthesis of 2D High&#8208;Entropy Multimetallic (Oxy)hydroxide for Enhanced Lattice Oxygen Oxidation Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409530</link>
      <description>Sijia Liu, Baorui Jia, Sheng Wang, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Fengmei Fan, Yunpu Qin, Jianfang Liu, Yirui Jiang, Bin Sun, Hong Zhao, Hao Li, Wenxiang Zhou, Haoyang Wu, Deyin Zhang, Xuanhui Qu, Mingli Qin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403002748

                Abstract Owing to sluggish reaction kinetics and high potential, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts face a trade&#8208;off between activity and stability. Herein, an innovative topological strategy is presented for preparing 2D multimetallic (oxy)hydroxide, including ternary CoFeZn, quaternary CoFeMnZn, and high&#8208;entropy CoFeMnCuZn. The key to the synthesis lies in using Ca&#8208;rich brownmillerite oxide as a precursor, which possesses inherent structural flexibility enabling tailored elemental adjustments and topologically transforms from a point&#8208;shared structure of metal&#8208;oxygen octahedrons into an edge&#8208;shared structure under alkaline conditions. The presence of Zn in the catalysts causes a shift in the center of the O2p band toward the Fermi level, resulting in more Co 4+ species, which drive holes into oxygen ligands to promote intramolecular oxygen coupling. The triggered lattice oxidation mechanism is identified by detecting peroxo&#8208;like (O 2 2&#8722; ) negative species using tetramethylammonium chemical probe, along with 18 O isotope labeling experiments. As a result, the catalyst demonstrates an overpotential of 267 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , ranking it among the top&#8208;performing non&#8208;Ni&#8208;based catalysts. Importantly, the catalysts also show high Fe&#8208;leaching resistance during OER compared to conventional NiFe and CoFe hydroxides/(oxy)hydroxides. The assembled zinc&#8208;air battery enables stable operation for over 225 h at a low charging voltage of 1.93 V.</description>
      <author>Sijia Liu, Baorui Jia, Sheng Wang, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Fengmei Fan, Yunpu Qin, Jianfang Liu, Yirui Jiang, Bin Sun, Hong Zhao, Hao Li, Wenxiang Zhou, Haoyang Wu, Deyin Zhang, Xuanhui Qu, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;B Electronic Effects in Layered Double Hydroxides for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407564</link>
      <description>Yuke Bai, Zhaojun Liu, Xiaoxiao Wang, Zhixue Zhang, Kai Liu, Chuanbo Gao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403005540

                Abstract NiFe layered double hydroxides (LDHs) are state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, yet they still face significant overpotentials. Here, quantitative boron (B) doping is introduced in NiFe LDHs (ranging from 0% to 20.3%) to effectively tailor the Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;B electronic interactions for enhanced OER performance. The co&#8208;hydrolysis synthesis approach synchronizes the hydrolysis rates of Ni and Fe precursors with the formation rate of B&#9472;O&#9472;M (M: Ni, Fe) bonds, ensuring precise B doping into the NiFe LDHs. It is demonstrated that B, as an electron&#8208;deficient element, acts as an &#8220;electron sink&#8221; at doping levels from 0% to 13.5%, facilitating the transition of Ni 2+ to the active Ni 3+&#948; , thereby accelerating OER kinetics. However, excessive B doping (13.5&#8211;20.3%) effectively generates oxygen vacancies in the LDHs, which increases electron density at Ni 2+ sites and hinders their transition to Ni 3+&#948; , thereby reducing OER activity. Optimal OER performance is achieved at a B doping level of 13.5%, with an overpotential of only 208 mV to reach a current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 , placing it among the most effective OER catalysts to date. This Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;B electronic engineering opens new avenues for developing highly efficient anode catalysts for water&#8208;splitting hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Yuke Bai, Zhaojun Liu, Xiaoxiao Wang, Zhixue Zhang, Kai Liu, Chuanbo Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of SnS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@SnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure for Photo&#8208;Assisted Electrocatalysis of Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407659</link>
      <description>J. Wang, Ze Wang, Jie He, L.F. Han, Xin Li, Keyi Han, Tianen Chen, Qianyu Zhou, Lizhong Yang, Dongye Zhao, Yuanhao Wang, Shifeng Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403005567

                Abstract Photo&#8208;assisted electrocatalysis has arisen as a promising approach for hydrogen generation by incorporating photocatalysts into electrocatalysts. 2D SnS 2 is a photocatalyst that absorbs visible light. However, the rapid recombination of photo&#8208;generated electron&#8208;hole pairs significantly reduces the overall photocatalytic efficiency of SnS 2 , limiting its practical application. Thus, this study prepares an in situ heterojunction SnS 2 @SnO 2 using a one&#8208;step hydrothermal method. The degradation efficiency of methyl orange (MO) using SnS 2 @SnO 2 is measured, achieving a degradation rate of 92.75% within 1 h, which is 1.9 times higher than that of pure SnS 2 . Additionally, FeNiS/SnS 2 @SnO 2 is synthesized and exhibited significant improvements in the photo&#8208;assisted oxygen evolution reaction (OER). It achieves an overpotential of 260 mV and a Tafel slope of 65.1 mV dec &#8722;1 at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , showing reductions of 11.8% and 31.8%, respectively, compared to FeNiS alone. These enhancements highlight the strong photo&#8208;response capability of SnS 2 @SnO 2 . Under the internal electric field of SnS 2 @SnO 2 , the photogenerated electrons in the conduction band of SnS 2 quickly move toward SnO 2 , facilitating efficient photocatalytic reactions. FeNiS, with a lower Fermi energy level (E F ), facilitates electron transfer from SnS 2 @SnO 2 and enhances OER performance by efficiently participating in the reaction. This study paves a new path for 2D photocatalyst materials.</description>
      <author>J. Wang, Ze Wang, Jie He, L.F. Han, Xin Li, Keyi Han, Tianen Chen, Qianyu Zhou, Lizhong Yang, Dongye Zhao, Yuanhao Wang, Shifeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene oxide supported-stabilized oxygen defective CoCr2O4 for boosted bifunctional electrocatalytic oxygen evolution and urea oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133313</link>
      <description>Jiahui Liao, Changcun Tang, Yiting Sun, Xilin Wang, Yanhe Xiao, Baochang Cheng, Shuijin Lei, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403008776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahui Liao, Changcun Tang, Yiting Sun, Xilin Wang, Yanhe Xiao, Baochang Cheng, Shuijin Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triggered factors and structure-activity relationship in the dynamic reconstruction processing of MOF for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216235</link>
      <description>Qianglong Qi, Chengxu Zhang, Jue Hu, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 522(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403009849

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianglong Qi, Chengxu Zhang, Jue Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An impedance spectroscopy study to unravel the effect of water on proton and oxygen transport in PEM fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145172</link>
      <description>Tatyana V. Reshetenko, Ying Sun, Thomas Kadyk, Michael Eikerling, Andrei Kulikovsky, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403014868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tatyana V. Reshetenko, Ying Sun, Thomas Kadyk, Michael Eikerling, Andrei Kulikovsky</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ingenious regulation and activation of sites in the 2H-MoS2 basal planes by oxygen incorporation for enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen evolution of CdS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156367</link>
      <description>Guixin Zeng, Honghai Miao, Jiangbo Wu, Baibiao Huang, Jianjian Yi, Xiurong Zhu, Haotian Qi, Zaiyong Jiang, Zhao Mo, Jinyuan Liu, Baibiao Huang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403015120

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guixin Zeng, Honghai Miao, Jiangbo Wu, Baibiao Huang, Jianjian Yi, Xiurong Zhu, Haotian Qi, Zaiyong Jiang, Zhao Mo, Jinyuan Liu, Baibiao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403017663

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403017949

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403018525

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoparticles of CoFeZn Supported on N-Doped Carbon as Bifunctional Catalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04291</link>
      <description>Huijuan Zhang, Bo Chen, Xiaoxiong Feng, Miaomiao Yu, Jun Luo, Yuhua Xue, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403021164

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huijuan Zhang, Bo Chen, Xiaoxiong Feng, Miaomiao Yu, Jun Luo, Yuhua Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Morphology Engineering and Electron Modulation on a Molybdenum-Ruthenium Oxide Electrocatalyst for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4973072</link>
      <description>Lin Zhang, Wenyuan Gao, Ziyao Liu, Wei Wang, Chen Yang, Wei&#8208;Guang Zhang, Yibing Li, Jie Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403037203

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lin Zhang, Wenyuan Gao, Ziyao Liu, Wei Wang, Chen Yang, Wei&#8208;Guang Zhang, Yibing Li, Jie Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4973072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Engineering of Dopant and Support of Ru Oxide Catalyst Enables Ultrahigh Performance for Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408714</link>
      <description>Felix Ofori Boakye, Karim Harrath, Dantong Zhang, Ya You, Wenbin Zhang, Sheng Wang, Yong Qiu, Jiexin Zhu, Juncai Long, Jianqiu Zhu, Ghulam Yasin, Kwadwo Asare Owusu, Mohammad Tabish, Linjuan Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaofeng Shi, Mingrui He, Bin Wu, Liqiang Mai, Wei Zhao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403042989

                Abstract Active and robust electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are of crucial importance for efficient proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEM&#8208;WE). Ruthenium (Ru) oxide has attracted considerable attention due to its high activity. However, the unsatisfying stability of Ru oxide in acidic OER environments hinders the application. Here, Ce&#8208;doped RuO 2 nanoparticles are designed and supported on Co&#9472;N&#9472;C material (Ce@RuO 2 /CoNC) for acidic OER. It is demonstrated that Ce@RuO 2 /CoNC delivers a super low overpotential of 150 mV and an excellent stability of 1000 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , outperforming most previously reported Ru&#8208;based catalysts. The mass activity is estimated as 2365.5 Ag Ru &#8722;1 at 1.5 V (vs RHE), representing &#8776;2&#215; advance compared to the best prior study. Furthermore, applied in a single&#8208;cell PEM&#8208;WE device, it can steadily operate for 1000 h at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 . The studies show that Ce&#8208;doping and Co&#9472;N&#9472;C support synergistically enhance the activity and stability of Ru oxide by optimizing the free energies of OER intermediates and suppressing the dissolution of Ru.</description>
      <author>Felix Ofori Boakye, Karim Harrath, Dantong Zhang, Ya You, Wenbin Zhang, Sheng Wang, Yong Qiu, Jiexin Zhu, Juncai Long, Jianqiu Zhu, Ghulam Yasin, Kwadwo Asare Owusu, Mohammad Tabish, Linjuan Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Xiaofeng Shi, Mingrui He, Bin Wu, Liqiang Mai, Wei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Enhanced Active Oxygen Formation by Incorporating Chromium into Nickel Hydroxide Nanosheets for Improved Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02441</link>
      <description>Seunghwa Lee, Gyeong Hee Ryu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403051890

                Nickel-based oxyhydroxides have emerged as promising catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) among Earth-abundant metals. While the incorporation of foreign elements is recognized to enhance catalytic activity, the origin of this enhancement is still debated. We synthesize and examine Ni hydroxide nanosheets, both with and without Cr doping, to elucidate the underlying enhancements. Operando UV-vis and Raman spectroscopy are employed to unravel the behavior of the catalysts. The Cr doping facilitates the oxidation of Ni, resulting in the generation of active oxygen species. The enriched active oxygen species improves OER performance through a lattice oxygen-mediated pathway in Fe-free KOH, and further contribute to the creation and increased activity of FeO</description>
      <author>Seunghwa Lee, Gyeong Hee Ryu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends and industrial prospects of NiFe-layered double hydroxide for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156219</link>
      <description>Sarmad Iqbal, Johan Ehlers, P. Rosaiah, Kaili Zhang, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403054145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarmad Iqbal, Johan Ehlers, P. Rosaiah, Kaili Zhang, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birnessite Enhanced Cr(Iii) Oxidation During Subsurface Geochemical Processes: Role of Mn(Iii)-Induced Nonphotochemical Reactive Oxygen Species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4974662</link>
      <description>Yuting Zhou, Changdong Ke, Yanping Deng, Yanjun Jiang, Meiling Yin, Kai Chen, Yukui Zhang, Guining Lu, Zhi Dang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403062566

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuting Zhou, Changdong Ke, Yanping Deng, Yanjun Jiang, Meiling Yin, Kai Chen, Yukui Zhang, Guining Lu, Zhi Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4974662</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Underlying Mechanism of the Fourth Entity in Medium-Entropy NiCoFeMP toward Boosting Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10131</link>
      <description>Xue&#8208;Zhi Song, Xiaobing Wang, Tao Zhang, Jihong Dong, Yulan Meng, De-Kun Liu, Yu&#8208;Xin Luan, Changguang Yao, Zhenquan Tan, Xiaofeng Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403066519

                High-/medium-entropy materials have been explored as promising electrocatalysts for water splitting due to their unique physical and chemical properties. Unfortunately, state-of-the-art materials face the dilemma of explaining the enhancement mechanism, which is now limited to theoretical models or an unclear cocktail effect. Herein, a medium-entropy NiCoFeMnP with an advanced hierarchical particle-nanosheet-tumbleweed nanostructure has been synthesized via simple precursor preparation and subsequent phosphorization. Evaluated as the electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the medium-entropy NiCoFeMnP displays a lower overpotential of 272 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Xue&#8208;Zhi Song, Xiaobing Wang, Tao Zhang, Jihong Dong, Yulan Meng, De-Kun Liu, Yu&#8208;Xin Luan, Changguang Yao, Zhenquan Tan, Xiaofeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing lattice oxygens in a high-entropy perovskite oxide for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01204f</link>
      <description>Sujan Sen, Tapas Kumar Mandal, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403073277

                Development of highly active and stable electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the main challenge in water electrolysis for green hydrogen production. Although Ru-based electrocatalysts have been in use...</description>
      <author>Sujan Sen, Tapas Kumar Mandal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01204f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of high&#8208;entropy oxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401663</link>
      <description>Qian Zhang, Xuexue Wang, Xiaomeng Lv, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403073360

                High&#8208;entropy oxides (HEOs), similar to high&#8208;entropy materials (HEMs), have "four&#8208;core effects", i.e., high&#8208;entropy effect, delayed diffusion effect, lattice distortion effect and cocktail effect, which have attracted more and more attention in the scientific field of renewable energy technology due to their unique structural characteristics, variable chemical composition and corresponding functional properties. HEOs have become potential candidates for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is a key half reaction for electrolytic CO2, nitrogen reduction, and water electrolysis. However, the precise synthesis of HEOs with a wide range of components and structures is challenging, not to mention their active and stable operation for OER. In this paper, we review the recent advancements in the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution facilitated by HEOs in water electrolysis. We analyze these developments from the perspectives of activity and stability in acid and alkaline conditions, respectively. Furthermore, we summarize the design from the aspect of element composition, structure, morphology, and catalyst&#8208;support interactions, along with related reaction mechanism of HEOs. Additionally, we discuss the current challenges faced by HEOs in the field of OER and suggest potential directions for the future development of HEOs beyond water electrolysis application.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhang, Xuexue Wang, Xiaomeng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten based nanostructured hybrid electrocatalysts in neutral medium for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.394</link>
      <description>L. Sophia Jacquline, E. Elangovan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 89(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403073379

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. Sophia Jacquline, E. Elangovan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Ni&#8208;MOF Derived Nickel Sulfides as Efficient Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction Through Optimizing the Sulfur Sources Selection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403487</link>
      <description>Fang Wu, Yuhong Jiao, Jinlong Ge, F. Chen, Zhong Wu, Yujun Zhu, Lin Qiu, ChemistrySelect. 9(37)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082193

                Abstract Developing low&#8208;cost and exceedingly efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is vital for application of hydrogen production from water splitting. Herein, three different nickel sulfides on nickel foam were fabricated via a simple sulfuring the as&#8208;formed Ni&#8208;MOF with different sulfide as the sulfur source. The effect of sulfur source on OER performance, morphology and structure of the as&#8208;prepared product are well discussed. The optimized Ni&#8208;MOF/NF&#8208;SS deliver overpotentials of 253 and 330 mV to reach current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 with a small Tafel slope of 70.9 mVdec &#8722;1 , and stability of over 50 h. This work provides insights into the relationship between the OER activity and the structures of nickel sulfides, but also affords a new route to fabricate nickel sulfides&#8208;based electrocatalysts for OER.</description>
      <author>Fang Wu, Yuhong Jiao, Jinlong Ge, F. Chen, Zhong Wu, Yujun Zhu, Lin Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible PET/Carbon/NiFe&#8208;LDH Electrode for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Water&#8208;Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400571</link>
      <description>Carlos A. Vel&#225;squez, Juan Jos&#233; Pati&#241;o-L&#243;pez, Kevin Ballestas, Juan Felipe Montoya, Daniel Ram&#237;rez, Franklin Jaramillo, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082423

                Abstract The development of low&#8208;cost, readily scalable catalytic systems for green hydrogen production is crucial for diverse research and industrial applications. This work demonstrates the facile coupling of carbon/NiFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide (LDH) onto flexible polyethylene terephthalate (PET) substrates deposited by blade coating and spray coating techniques. These low&#8208;temperature solution processes enable high&#8208;throughput electrode fabrication. The resulting carbon electrode exhibits sheet resistance of 25 &#937; sq &#8722;1 , comparable to other state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art works, and displays excellent adhesion to the substrate and catalyst layer, thereby ensuring system stability. Remarkably, the developed electrode exhibits high catalytic activity for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), achieving an overpotential of 215.9 and 267.4 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722; 2 in rigid and flexible substrates respectively, and maintaining its performance even at 10 mA cm &#8722; 2 for 24 h. This work highlights the potential of this methodology for producing readily transportable, flexible electrocatalytic systems with exceptional performance and minimal surface treatment of the substrate. Additionally, the use of low&#8208;cost, readily recyclable PET plastic aligns with the principles of circular economy, promoting the integration of this platform into both research and industrial environments.</description>
      <author>Carlos A. Vel&#225;squez, Juan Jos&#233; Pati&#241;o-L&#243;pez, Kevin Ballestas, Juan Felipe Montoya, Daniel Ram&#237;rez, Franklin Jaramillo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Plasma&#8208;Engineering of Oxygen Vacancies on NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanowires with Enhanced Bifunctional Electrocatalytic Performance for Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Battery&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404107</link>
      <description>He Li, Jihao Wang, Tim Tjardts, Igor Barg, Haoyi Qiu, Martin M&#252;ller, Jan Krahmer, Sadegh Askari, Salih Veziro&#287;lu, Cenk Aktas, Lorenz Kienle, Jan Benedikt, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082535

                No abstract</description>
      <author>He Li, Jihao Wang, Tim Tjardts, Igor Barg, Haoyi Qiu, Martin M&#252;ller, Jan Krahmer, Sadegh Askari, Salih Veziro&#287;lu, Cenk Aktas, Lorenz Kienle, Jan Benedikt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen defects-engineered build Zn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7-y&lt;/sub&gt; as anode materials for Lithium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03177f</link>
      <description>Qingrong Kong, Ning Zhang, Yanjun Cai, Zhi Su, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403082703

                Zn 2 P 2 O 7-y (referred to as ZPO) is expected to be an ideal anode material for lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) due to its low cost, good chemical and thermal stability, and environmental friendliness....</description>
      <author>Qingrong Kong, Ning Zhang, Yanjun Cai, Zhi Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03177f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Metal-Doped IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Rotating Disk Electrode and Membrane Electrode Assembly Configurations for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04447</link>
      <description>Yichen Zhao, Xin Cai, Shengchu Liu, Rui Lin, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403089008

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yichen Zhao, Xin Cai, Shengchu Liu, Rui Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling active sites in FeOOH nanorods@NiOOH nanosheets heterojunction for superior OER and HER electrocatalysis in water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.219</link>
      <description>Huai Sun, Sayyar Ali Shah, Gabriel Engonga Obiang Nsang, Rani Sayyar, Barkat Ullah, Noor Ullah, Naseem Ahmad Khan, Aihua Yuan, Abd. Rashid bin Mohd Yusoff, Habib Ullah, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403097925

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huai Sun, Sayyar Ali Shah, Gabriel Engonga Obiang Nsang, Rani Sayyar, Barkat Ullah, Noor Ullah, Naseem Ahmad Khan, Aihua Yuan, Abd. Rashid bin Mohd Yusoff, Habib Ullah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal Synthesis of Tungsten Oxide Photo/electrocatalysts: Precursor-Driven Morphological Tailoring and Electrochemical Performance for Hydrogen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction Reaction Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4836798/v1</link>
      <description>Rahul Sarma, Biraj Kumar Kakati, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403098663

                Abstract This research examines the effective use of two specific precursor i.e Hydrochloric acid and Oxalic acid used in the synthesis of Tungsten oxide (WO3). Catalytic reactions including Oxygen Reduction Reaction (ORR) and Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) was investigated with the synthesised material. The morphological as well as electrochemical characteristics were studied using Field Emission Scanning Electron Microscope (FESEM), X-ray Diffraction (XRD), Energy-Dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), UV spectroscopy along with electrochemical analysis. It is being found that the WO3 synthesised with oxalic acid (WO3-ox) demonstrated in superior HER catalysis, whereas the other variant (WO3 with HCl (WO3-h)) showed better ORR performance. An optical bandgap of 2.638 eV was obtained for WO3-ox. Moreover, electrochemical analysis revealed an ORR peak at 0.52 V for WO3-h, in acidic media of electrolyte. As a result of which the two electrocatalyst were utilised in two different applications. WO3-ox was used for Methylene Blue (MB) degradation under the UV light and WO3-h was incorporated as a cathode catalyst for electricity generation and wastewater treatment in Microbial Fuel Cell (MFC). A degradation efficiency of 83.9% was attained in a span of 3 hours. On the other hand, MFC showed superior electrical power density of 209.72 mW/m2 with catalyst as compared to bare carbon cloth electrode (139.78 mW/m2). The chemical oxygen demand (COD) removal efficiency, which acts as a measure of wastewater treatment was 1.47 folds higher with the MFC having the catalyst. Thus, by tailored modulation of synthesised material with different precursor can lead to optimization of its features for various applications like degradation of methylene blue and microbial fuel cell.</description>
      <author>Rahul Sarma, Biraj Kumar Kakati</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4836798/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Situ Decoration of Nico-Thiophene Based Metal-Organic Framework on Nickel Foam as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4975510</link>
      <description>Muhammad Salman, Xiaoping Shen, Hanli Qin, Yuming Zou, Zhenyuan Ji, Hu Zhou, Hongbo Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, S. Premlatha, Aihua Yuan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403101361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Salman, Xiaoping Shen, Hanli Qin, Yuming Zou, Zhenyuan Ji, Hu Zhou, Hongbo Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, S. Premlatha, Aihua Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4975510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Chlorine-Doped Nickel Diselenide Ultrathin Nanosheets through Steric Effects: An Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Urea Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03510</link>
      <description>Xiaofeng Lin, Shuli Tang, Min Yang, Zhiqiang Zhang, Qitong Huang, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403101390

                Exploration of electrocatalysts suitable for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is essential for electrocatalytic hydrogen production. In this work, a ligand substitution strategy is used to synthesize ultrathin-nanosheet electrocatalysts of Cl-doped NiSe</description>
      <author>Xiaofeng Lin, Shuli Tang, Min Yang, Zhiqiang Zhang, Qitong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Reconstructing NiFe Oxalate Toward Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408754</link>
      <description>Zhen Zhang, Xiaoyu Ren, Wenyuan Dai, Hang Zhang, Zhen Sun, Ye Zhuang, Ying Hou, Peizhi Liu, Bingshe Xu, Lihua Qian, Ting Liao, Haixia Zhang, Junjie Guo, Ziqi Sun, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403103759

                Abstract Surface reconstruction plays an essential role in electrochemical catalysis. The structures, compositions, and functionalities of the real catalytic species and sites generated by reconstruction, however, are yet to be clearly understood, for the metastable or transit state of most reconstructed structures. Herein, a series of NiFe oxalates (Ni x Fe 1&#8208; x C 2 O 4 , x = 1, 0.9, 0.7, 0.6, 0.5, and 0) are synthesized for overall water splitting electrocatalysis. Whilst Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x C 2 O 4 shows great hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity, the in situ reconstructed Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x OOH exhibits outstanding oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. As identified by the in situ Raman spectroscopy and quasi&#8208;in situ X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) techniques, reconstructions from Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x C 2 O 4 into defective Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x OOH and finally amorphous Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x OOH active species (R&#8208;Ni x Fe 1&#8208;x OOH) are confirmed upon cyclic voltammetry processes. Specifically, the fully reconstructed R&#8208;Ni 0.6 Fe 0.4 OOH demonstrates the best OER activity (179 mV to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), originating from its abundant real active sites and optimal d&#8208;band center. Benefiting from the reconstruction, an alkaline electrolyzer composed of a Ni 0.6 Fe 0.4 C 2 O 4 cathode and an in situ reconstructed R&#8208;Ni 0.6 Fe 0.4 OOH anode achieves a superb overall water splitting performance (1.52 V@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ). This work provides an in&#8208;depth structure&#8208;property relationship understanding on the reconstruction of catalysts and offers a new pathway to designing novel catalyst.</description>
      <author>Zhen Zhang, Xiaoyu Ren, Wenyuan Dai, Hang Zhang, Zhen Sun, Ye Zhuang, Ying Hou, Peizhi Liu, Bingshe Xu, Lihua Qian, Ting Liao, Haixia Zhang, Junjie Guo, Ziqi Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Band alignment of CoO(100)&#8211;water and CoO(111)&#8211;water interfaces accelerated by machine learning potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0224137</link>
      <description>Jinyuan Hu, Yong&#8208;Bin Zhuang, Jun Cheng, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403103930

                Cobalt monoxide (CoO) nanomaterials have drawn attention for their remarkable photocatalytic water splitting without an externally applied potential or co-catalyst. The success of overall water splitting is due to the appropriate band edge positions of the catalyst, which span the redox potentials of water splitting. Typically, CoO nanomaterials possess complex morphologies, which consist of multiple active surfaces. As a result, the precise roles of the surfaces in the overall water-splitting process remain to be elucidated. In this work, we have undertaken a thorough investigation into the band alignments at the CoO(100)&#8211;water and CoO(111)&#8211;water interfaces using ab initio molecular dynamics and machine learning accelerated molecular dynamics simulations. The results of band alignment reveal that CoO(100) supports both the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction, whereas CoO(111) only facilitates the HER. Moreover, the variance in band positions between CoO(100) and CoO(111) results in an intrinsic potential difference, facilitating the migration of electrons toward CoO(100), while holes accumulate on CoO(111). The separation of photoexcited carriers effectively promotes water splitting in CoO.</description>
      <author>Jinyuan Hu, Yong&#8208;Bin Zhuang, Jun Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0224137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Oxygen Evolution: Challenges, Strategies, and Advances Toward Industrial&#8208;Scale Deployment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410618</link>
      <description>Yansong Zhou, Zhitong Wang, Minghui Cui, Haiyan Wu, Ying Liu, Qiongrong Ou, Xinlong Tian, Shuyu Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403108901

                Abstract Developing high&#8208;efficiency alkaline water splitting technology holds great promise in potentially revolutionizing the traditional petrochemical industry to a more sustainable hydrogen economy. Importantly, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) accompanied at the anode is considered as a critical bottleneck in terms of both complicated mechanism and sluggish kinetics, requiring rational design of OER electrocatalysts to elucidate the structure&#8208;performance relationship and reduce the applied overpotential. As a benchmarked non&#8208;precious metal candidate, NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts have gained enormous attention due to low&#8208;cost, earth&#8208;abundance, and remarkable intrinsic OER activity, which are expected to be implemented in industrial alkaline water splitting. In this contribution, a comprehensive overview of NiFe&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts is provided, starting with fundamental mechanisms, evaluation metrics, and synthetic protocols. Subsequently, basic principles with corresponding regulatory strategies are summarized following the sequence of substrate&#8208;catalyst&#8208;electrolyte design of efficient and robust NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts toward industrial&#8208;scale deployment. Perspectives on remaining challenges and instructive opportunities in this booming field are finally discussed.</description>
      <author>Yansong Zhou, Zhitong Wang, Minghui Cui, Haiyan Wu, Ying Liu, Qiongrong Ou, Xinlong Tian, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution over Fe1/NiSe2 single-atom electrocatalyst: The role of thermal-electrical cascade and surface reconstruing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114596</link>
      <description>Ju Wang, Yu&#8208;Sheng Liu, Zhaoxu Wang, Jia Wang, Wenyou Zhu, Wenchang Zhuang, Lin Tian, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403115431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ju Wang, Yu&#8208;Sheng Liu, Zhaoxu Wang, Jia Wang, Wenyou Zhu, Wenchang Zhuang, Lin Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe/FeCo-based metal-organic framework nanosheet/ nanoparticle directly grown on nickel foam as a stable electrode for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.003</link>
      <description>Jiangyan Dang, Uzma sattar, Wenjuan Xu, Xiaoying Zhang, Wenliang Li, Jingping Zhang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 89(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403119174

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiangyan Dang, Uzma sattar, Wenjuan Xu, Xiaoying Zhang, Wenliang Li, Jingping Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanadate-Mediated Mismatch Configuration over the Reconstructed Nickel&#8211;Iron Electrocatalyst for Boosting Alkaline Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03670</link>
      <description>Ruopeng Li, Youzheng Wu, Peixia Yang, Yaqiang Li, Fan Meng, Yuhao Fan, Dan Wang, Penghui Ren, Hao Xu, Xuesong Peng, Weirun Zhu, Hui Wang, Jiang Qin, Jinqiu Zhang, Maozhong An, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403130365

                During the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), catalyst candidates that can fully trigger self-reconstruction to derive active species with favorable configurations are expected to overcome the sluggish reaction kinetics. Herein, we innovatively propose the introduction of heterogeneous vanadate dopants into nickel-iron alloy precatalysts, where the crystal mismatch structure induces local electron delocalization in the hexagonal close packed alloy phase, thereby facilitating adequate electrochemical reconstruction to form (oxy)hydroxides as the real catalytic species. Simultaneously, the participation of vanadate in the reconstruction also triggers mismatch in the derived (oxy)hydroxides, reinforcing the metal-oxygen covalence, so that lattice oxygen activation is kinetically favorable and facilitates the OER via the lattice oxygen pathway. Optimized reconstructed catalyst r-NiFeVO</description>
      <author>Ruopeng Li, Youzheng Wu, Peixia Yang, Yaqiang Li, Fan Meng, Yuhao Fan, Dan Wang, Penghui Ren, Hao Xu, Xuesong Peng, Weirun Zhu, Hui Wang, Jiang Qin, Jinqiu Zhang, Maozhong An</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Engineering in Hollow Layered Hydroxide Arrays to Boost 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural Electrooxidation by Suppressing Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c01085</link>
      <description>Xin Yu, Hongchuan Fu, Liyu Chen, Yongfei Ji, Yingwei Li, Kui Shen, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403138626

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Yu, Hongchuan Fu, Liyu Chen, Yongfei Ji, Yingwei Li, Kui Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c01085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface reconstruction on spinel oxides for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32657/10356/180152</link>
      <description>Songzhu Luo, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4403110354

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Songzhu Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32657/10356/180152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Oxygen Evolution Mechanism of Transition Metal-Anchored Holey Graphyne</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4974142</link>
      <description>K. Simmy Joseph, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Shweta D. Dabhi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403074221

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Simmy Joseph, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Shweta D. Dabhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4974142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Diatomic Active Sites for Elucidating Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance Trends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413749</link>
      <description>Nanfeng Xu, Yuxiang Jin, Qiunan Liu, Meng Yu, Zibo Wang, Xiaogang Wang, Wei Tu, Zhirong Zhang, Zhigang Geng, Kazu Suenaga, Fangyi Cheng, Erhong Song, Zhangquan Peng, Junyuan Xu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140470

                Diatomic catalysts, especially those with heteronuclear active sites, have recently attracted significant attention for their advantages over single&#8208;atom catalysts in reactions with relatively high energy barrier, e.g. oxygen evolution reaction. Rational design and synthesis of heteronuclear diatomic catalysts are of immense significance but have so far been plagued by the lack of a definitive correlation between structure and catalytic properties. Here, we report macrocyclic precursor constrained strategy to fabricate series of transition metal (MT, Ni, Co, Fe, Mn, or Cu)&#8208;noble (MN, Ir or Ru) centers in carbon material. One notable performance trend is observed in the order of Cu&#8208;MN &lt; Mn&#8208;MN &lt; Fe&#8208;MN &lt; MN &lt; Co&#8208;MN &lt; Ni&#8208;MN. However, the pathway has been not altered, still following the traditional adsorption reaction mechanism. The effect of the MT atoms on the performances could possibly originate from the distinct adsorption/desorption behaviors of key intermediates (i.e. *OH, *O and/or *OOH), strongly implying that &#916;G*OOH&#8208;&#916;G*OH could be used as the performance descriptor. We believe that our work provides useful strategy for synthesis of diatomic active sites with sole coordination configuration and varied composition, and in&#8208;depth insight to their catalytic mechanism, which could be used for further optimization of diatomic catalysts towards oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Nanfeng Xu, Yuxiang Jin, Qiunan Liu, Meng Yu, Zibo Wang, Xiaogang Wang, Wei Tu, Zhirong Zhang, Zhigang Geng, Kazu Suenaga, Fangyi Cheng, Erhong Song, Zhangquan Peng, Junyuan Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly dispersed Ir nanoparticles on Ti3C2Tx MXene nanosheets for efficient oxygen evolution in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.009</link>
      <description>Meihong Fan, Lijia Liu, Yue Li, Fengmei Gu, Xingquan He, Hui Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403097736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meihong Fan, Lijia Liu, Yue Li, Fengmei Gu, Xingquan He, Hui Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Measurement of Gross Oxygen Evolution and Underlying Photosynthetic Redox Reactions: A Case Study Using Cyanobacteria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.10.03.616403</link>
      <description>Oded Liran, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403143045

                In phytoplankton, the intricate balance between respiration and photosynthesis is co-regulated to ensure efficient energy management and adaptation to varying environmental conditions. In cyanobacteria, both processes occur on the same membrane, sharing electron transport carriers within the same cellular compartment. By studying the interaction between photosynthesis and respiration, we can better understand how cyanobacteria balance their energetic budget for survival. In this study, we present an integrated approach that combines tracking gas exchange between cyanobacteria and their environment with analysing the redox kinetics of the underlying photosynthetic electron transport chain. This combined system allows for real-time, simultaneous acquisition of respiration and photosynthesis data. For example, it enabled us to show that the electron transport rate generated by photosystem II, translated to in-vivo oxygen concentration, equals the actual concentration of oxygen produced by water splitting plus the amount of oxygen respired. We further demonstrate that our system can accurately assess light respiration in wild-type strains of cyanobacteria, which amounts to 1/10 of their photosynthetic activity under optimal growth conditions. This level of accuracy was previously achievable only with specific cyanobacteria mutants. We envision applying this system in monitoring programs to elaborate on the role of photosynthetic light reactions within the broader context of primary productivity and to understand its dynamics in response to fluctuations in external environmental conditions.</description>
      <author>Oded Liran</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.10.03.616403</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational phosphorization of ferrocene-based metal organic framework for enhanced oxygen evolution and urea oxidation performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161392</link>
      <description>Liwen Wang, Si&#8208;Fu Tang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403085347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liwen Wang, Si&#8208;Fu Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring the Structural Changes in Iridium Nanoparticles during Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis with &lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; X-ray Total Scattering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08149</link>
      <description>Rebecca Pittkowski, Stefanie Punke, Andy S. Anker, Aline Bornet, Nicolas P. L. Magnard, Nicolas Schlegel, Laura G. Graversen, Jonathan Quinson, Alexandra Dworzak, Mehtap Oezaslan, Jacob J. K. Kirkensgaard, Marta Mirolo, Jakub Drnec, Matthias Arenz, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402996198

                Understanding the structure of nanoparticles under (electro)catalytic operating conditions is crucial for uncovering structure-property relationships. By combining</description>
      <author>Rebecca Pittkowski, Stefanie Punke, Andy S. Anker, Aline Bornet, Nicolas P. L. Magnard, Nicolas Schlegel, Laura G. Graversen, Jonathan Quinson, Alexandra Dworzak, Mehtap Oezaslan, Jacob J. K. Kirkensgaard, Marta Mirolo, Jakub Drnec, Matthias Arenz, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g</link>
      <description>Shujin Li, Shinichi Hata, Zhengying Wu, Yukou Du, Wei Xiao, Shudi Yu, Jie Li, Tianpeng Liu, Yukihide Shiraishi, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402986707

                Heteroatom doped metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have been widely used in OER catalysis. However, the effects of doping methods on these materials are still rarely reported. Herein, the structure and activity...</description>
      <author>Shujin Li, Shinichi Hata, Zhengying Wu, Yukou Du, Wei Xiao, Shudi Yu, Jie Li, Tianpeng Liu, Yukihide Shiraishi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic&#8208;Level Observation of Potential&#8208;Dependent Variations at the Surface of an Oxide Catalyst during Oxygen Evolution Reaction (Adv. Mater. 38/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202470301</link>
      <description>Chang Hyun Park, Hyungdoh Lee, Jin&#8208;Seok Choi, Tae Gyu Yun, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung, Advanced Materials. 36(38)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403100352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang Hyun Park, Hyungdoh Lee, Jin&#8208;Seok Choi, Tae Gyu Yun, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202470301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403017676

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403018667

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen&#8208;doped Porous Ultrathin Graphitic Carbon Nitride Nanosheets for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution and Rhodamine B Degradation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400474</link>
      <description>Tao Liu, Yan Zeng, Tao Ma, Feng Liang, ChemPlusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403113526

                Graphite phase carbon nitride (g-C3N4) is a highly promising metal-free photocatalyst. However, its applicability is restricted by low activity, due to weak quantum efficiency and small specific surface area. Exfoliating bulk crystals into porous thin-layer nanosheets and introducing element doping have been shown to improve photocatalytic efficiency, but these methods are often complex, time-consuming, and costly processes. In this study, we successfully synthesized porous oxygen-doped g-C3N4 (OCN) nanosheets utilizing a straightforward method. Our findings show that OCN have much higher light absorption and visible-light photocatalytic activity than bulk g-C3N4 (BCN) and nonporous g-C3N4 (CN). The OCN photocatalyst has a remarkable hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) rate of 8.02 mmol&#183;g-1 h-1, which is 8 times greater than BCN. Additionally, the OCN shows a high degradation rate of 97.3% for Rhodamine B (RhB). This enhanced photocatalytic activity is ascribed to the narrow band gap and superior electron transfer capacity. Our findings suggest a potential technique for generating efficient g-C3N4 photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Liu, Yan Zeng, Tao Ma, Feng Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a high-performance bifunctional MnO2-based electrocatalyst towards applications on rechargeable Zinc-Air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05182c</link>
      <description>Xianghui Yi, Yijian Song, Deliang He, Weijie Li, Anqiang Pan, Cheng Han, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403035433

                Slow oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the liquid-solid-gas interface of the air cathode have always been a big obstacle for different renewable energy devices, especially...</description>
      <author>Xianghui Yi, Yijian Song, Deliang He, Weijie Li, Anqiang Pan, Cheng Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05182c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of nanostructured 2D (photo-)electrocatalysts for biomass valorization coupled with H2 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01034e</link>
      <description>Bahareh Feizi Mohazzab, Korosh Torabi, Dandan Gao, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403075899

                Electrocatalytic water splitting driven by renewable energy is a promising strategy for sustainable hydrogen production. However, the slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics severely limit the rate of the hydrogen...</description>
      <author>Bahareh Feizi Mohazzab, Korosh Torabi, Dandan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01034e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Molybdenum Telluride as an Efficient Trifunctional Electrocatalyst for Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100684</link>
      <description>R.K. Kar, Amideddin Nouralishahi, Harish Singh, Manashi Nath, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403072426

                A mixed-metal ternary chalcogenide, cobalt molybdenum telluride (CMT), has been identified as an efficient tri-functional electrocatalyst for seawater splitting, leading to enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The CMT was synthesized by a single step hydrothermal technique. Detailed electrochemical studies of the CMT-modified electrodes showed that CMT has a promising performance for OER in the simulated seawater solutions, exhibiting a small overpotential of 385 mV at 20 mA cm&#8722;2, and superior catalyst durability for prolonged period of continuous oxygen evolution. Interestingly, while gas chromatography analysis confirmed the evolution of oxygen in an anodic chamber, it showed that there was no chlorine evolution from these electrodes in alkaline seawater, highlighting the novelty of this catalyst. CMT also displayed remarkable ORR activity in simulated seawater as indicated by its four-electron reduction pathway forming water as the dominant product. One of the primary challenges of seawater splitting is chlorine evolution from the oxidation of dissolved chloride salts. The CMT catalyst successfully and significantly lowers the water oxidation potential, thereby separating the chloride and water oxidation potentials by a larger margin. These results suggest that CMT can function as a highly active tri-functional electrocatalyst with significant stability, making it suitable for clean energy generation and environmental applications using seawater.</description>
      <author>R.K. Kar, Amideddin Nouralishahi, Harish Singh, Manashi Nath</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different FeS Concentrations for Encapsulating ZIF-67 Nanomaterials toward the Enhanced Oxidation Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02517</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Guo&#8208;Ping Yang, Yao&#8208;Yu Wang, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403012113

                Due to the slow kinetic nature of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the development of electrocatalysts with high efficiency, stability, and economy for oxygen production using metal-organic framework (MOF) materials is still a challenging research topic. In this work, we chose the different concentrations of FeS adsorption to encapsulate metal cobalt-based ZIF-67 MOF for preparing a series of electrocatalysts (ZIF</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Guo&#8208;Ping Yang, Yao&#8208;Yu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partial oxidation of Rh/Ru nanoparticles within carbon nanofibers for high-efficiency hydrazine oxidation-assisted hydrogen generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.227</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Xu, Mengxiao Zhong, Yan Su, Xiaojie Chen, Weimo Li, Meijiao Xu, Ce Wang, Xiaofeng Lu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402956047

                Hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR), an alternative to oxygen evolution reaction, effectively mitigates hydrazine pollution while achieving energy-efficient hydrogen production. Herein, partially oxidized Ru/Rh nanoparticles embedded in carbon nanofibers (CNFs) are fabricated as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and HzOR. The presence of multiple components including metallic Ru and Rh and their oxides provides numerous electrochemically active sites and superior charge transfer properties, thus improving the electrocatalytic performance. Additionally, the confinement of the active components within CNFs further enhances structural stability. Consequently, the optimized electrocatalyst exhibits ultralow overpotentials of 16 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Xu, Mengxiao Zhong, Yan Su, Xiaojie Chen, Weimo Li, Meijiao Xu, Ce Wang, Xiaofeng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Battery with High Energy Efficiency Enabled by a Hydrogen Peroxide Bifunctional Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403817</link>
      <description>Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Jonathan Tzadikov, Angus Pedersen, Hui Luo, Gabriel Mark, Itamar Liberman, Alexander Upcher, Michael Volokh, Idan Hod, S. Barzilai, Malachi Noked, Menny Shalom, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403099590

                Abstract Rechargeable alkaline zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZAB) hold great promise as a viable, sustainable, and safe alternative energy storage system to the lithium&#8208;ion battery. However, the practical realization of ZABs is limited by their intrinsically low energy trip efficiency, stemming from a large charge and discharge potential gap. This overpotential is attributed to the four&#8208;electron oxygen evolution and reduction reactions and their sluggish kinetics. Here, a new concept based on two&#8208;electron generation and consumption of hydrogen peroxide at the air electrode is introduced. The O 2 /peroxide chemistry, facilitated by a newly developed Ni&#8208;based bifunctional electrocatalyst, enables fast peroxide generation/consumption, exceptional energy efficiency, high durability, and high capacity. Hence, this new design offers substantial progress toward the commercialization of high energy density metal&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Jonathan Tzadikov, Angus Pedersen, Hui Luo, Gabriel Mark, Itamar Liberman, Alexander Upcher, Michael Volokh, Idan Hod, S. Barzilai, Malachi Noked, Menny Shalom</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D MXenes: Synthesis, Properties, and Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405576</link>
      <description>Sunil Kumar, Syed Muhammad Zain Mehdi, Yongho Seo, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403002354

                Abstract The fascinating properties and versatile nature of 2D MXenes have generated significant interest in the scientific community. This has led to extensive research on expanding these materials into 1D and 0D forms. This review investigates the synthesis, properties, and applications of 1D MXenes, elucidating their potential across various fields. 1D MXenes, including nanowires, nanoribbons, nanorods, and nanotubes, inherit the remarkable properties of their 2D counterparts while also exhibiting unique anisotropic characteristics that enhance their performance in various applications. The review explores various methods for synthesizing 1D MXenes and examines their structural, electronic, and optical properties. The transition from 2D to 1D results in MXenes that offer superior properties, which are advantageous for various next&#8208;generation systems. The increased aspect ratio and surface area of 1D MXenes broaden their usage in energy storage, photothermal therapy, oxygen evolution reactions (OER), hydrogen evolution reactions (HER), oxygen reduction reactions (ORR), microwave absorption, filtration membranes, gas sensors, metal detection, etc. The review also addresses the challenges associated with 1D MXenes, such as limited synthesis methods, scalable production, size customization, preservation of structural integrity, and stability. Furthermore, potential opportunities and future directions in the field of 1D MXenes have also been proposed.</description>
      <author>Sunil Kumar, Syed Muhammad Zain Mehdi, Yongho Seo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen&#8208;Reaction Electrocatalysis and Corrosion Resistance of CoCrFeNi Thin Films by Tuned Microstructure and Surface Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400296</link>
      <description>Clara Linder, Robert Boyd, Grzegorz Greczy&#324;ski, Mikhail Vagin, Daniel Lundin, Karin T&#246;rne, Per Eklund, Emma M. Bj&#246;rk, Small Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402961289

                Oxygen electrocatalysts play a key role in renewable and fossil&#8208;free energy production. Bifunctional catalysts active for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) allow use of the same material system for both energy production (ORR) and fuel generation (OER). However, optimizing the performance of bifunctional catalysts requires in depth understanding of the catalyst structure, its surface chemistry in terms of active sites and the underlying catalytic mechanism. Here, the catalytic performance of CoCrFeNi thin films is investigated, synthesized using high&#8208;power impulse magnetron sputtering, as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts. The film crystal structure and morphology, and thereby the catalytic performance, can be tuned by the ion acceleration (bias) to the substrate. To further enhance the catalytic activity, anodization is used to electrochemically modify the films, forming a thicker oxide layer enriched in Co and Ni cations which significantly improves the ORR performance. Anodization improves the catalyst stability during OER, with an OER potential of 1.45 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for more than 24 h. While the corrosion resistance is high both before and after anodization, in terms of catalytic activity the anodized films outperformed the as&#8208;deposited ones. This makes anodized films excellent electrocatalyst candidates in corrosive alkaline environments such as fuel cells and electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Clara Linder, Robert Boyd, Grzegorz Greczy&#324;ski, Mikhail Vagin, Daniel Lundin, Karin T&#246;rne, Per Eklund, Emma M. Bj&#246;rk</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induction heating boosts water splitting on iron-coated nickel foam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ad816d</link>
      <description>Tinghua Li, Shuai Kang, Shoubo Li, Wendi Yang, Wei&#8208;Hua Lei, Wenqiang Lu, Zhiqiang Li, Zhu Donglai, Xia Zhang, Peng Lei, Journal of Physics D Applied Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403013961

                Abstract Alkaline water electrolysis at high temperatures can rival acidic proton-exchange membranes.&amp;#xD;However, they suffer from increased energy consumption, reduced lifespan of materials and heightened safety risks. Magnetic hyperthermia is a method of localizing intense heating in the presence of an external high-frequency alternating magnetic field. In this study, we developed a custom electromagnetic induction device capable of generating a small magnetic field of about 2 &#181;T. High-permeability nickel foam is used as electrodes. Results show that the iron coated nickel foam decreases the overpotential of the hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction by ~150 mV and 60 mV, respectively, at 20 mAcm&#8722;2 when subjected to magnetic heating in a high-frequency alternating magnetic field. The overall water splitting current of Ni foam/Fe increases 540% under intermittent induction. The enhanced stability of Ni foam/Fe is attributed to the high binding energy of metal-O on the surface. The density function theory calculations further indicates that the lattice expansion of the metal electrode under induction heating optimizes the adsorption and desorption of H*, thereby enhancing the HER performance.&amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Tinghua Li, Shuai Kang, Shoubo Li, Wendi Yang, Wei&#8208;Hua Lei, Wenqiang Lu, Zhiqiang Li, Zhu Donglai, Xia Zhang, Peng Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ad816d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;B/Mo&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanorods Encapsulated by a Boron&#8208;Rich Amorphous Layer for Universal pH Water Splitting at the Ampere Level</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402866</link>
      <description>Madiha Rafiq, Karim Harrath, Minyan Feng, Jia Li, Abebe Reda Woldu, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Fushen Lu, Xiangdong Yao, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403158348

                Abstract Heterostructured interfaces are crucial to electrocatalysts for water splitting. Herein, coral&#8208;like multiheterostructured Ni x B/Mo 0.8 B 3 (NMB) nanorods encapsulated by a boron&#8208;rich amorphous layer are prepared for water splitting. Density&#8208;functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that the NMB interface adjusts the d &#8208;band center and electronic structure of the molybdenum sites. Owing to the strong electronic coupling between Ni, Mo, and B at the heterojunction, large number of exposed catalytic active sites, as well as the special hydrophilic characteristics endowed by the surrounding amorphous layer, the NMB catalyst exhibits remarkable universal&#8208;pH hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity with low overpotentials ( &#951; ) of 15, 26, and 83 mV to deliver 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in basic, acid, and neutral media, respectively, and outstanding oxygen evolution reaction (OER) characteristics in the basic medium with &#951; 10 and &#951; 500 of 170 and 420 mV, respectively. The unique self&#8208;supporting 3D hierarchical interconnected structure facilitates mass transport thus leading to high mechanical stability for 450 and 200 h in HER and OER at &#8776;1000 mA cm &#8722;2 . More importantly, the NMB exhibits excellent performance toward overall&#8208;water electrolysis as a bifunctional catalyst with ultralow cell voltages of 1.45/1.56/1.85 V @ 10/100/1000 mA cm &#8722;2 , demonstrating the large potential in industrial water splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Madiha Rafiq, Karim Harrath, Minyan Feng, Jia Li, Abebe Reda Woldu, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Fushen Lu, Xiangdong Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402866</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Hydrogen Production via Seawater Electrolysis: Current Status and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100691</link>
      <description>Yi Xin Zhang, Yukui Zhang, Zhichuan Li, Ende Yu, H. J. Ye, Zihang Li, Margot Pellegrino, Daojin Zhou, Cheng Wang, Qihao Sha, Yun Kuang, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403136707

                Seawater electrolysis represents a promising green energy technology with significant potential for efficient energy conversion. This study provides an in-depth examination of the key scientific challenges inherent in the seawater-electrolysis process and their potential solutions. Initially, it analyzes the potential issues of precipitation and aggregation at the cathode during hydrogen evolution, proposing strategies such as self-cleaning cathodes and precipitate removal to ensure cathode stability in seawater electrolysis. Subsequently, it addresses the corrosion challenges faced by anode catalysts in seawater, introducing several anti-corrosion strategies to enhance anode stability, including substrate treatments such as sulfidation, phosphidation, selenidation, and LDH (layered double hydroxide) anion intercalation. Additionally, this study explores the role of regulating the electrode surface microenvironment and forming unique coordination environments for active atoms to enhance seawater electrolysis performance. Regulating the surface microenvironment provides a novel approach to mitigating seawater corrosion. Contrary to the traditional understanding that chloride ions accelerate anode corrosion, certain catalysts benefit from the unique coordination environment of chloride ions on the catalyst surface, potentially enhancing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Lastly, this study presents the latest advancements in the industrialization of seawater electrolysis, including the in situ electrolysis of undiluted seawater and the implementation of three-chamber dual anion membranes coupled with circulating electrolyte systems. The prospects of seawater electrolysis are also explored.</description>
      <author>Yi Xin Zhang, Yukui Zhang, Zhichuan Li, Ende Yu, H. J. Ye, Zihang Li, Margot Pellegrino, Daojin Zhou, Cheng Wang, Qihao Sha, Yun Kuang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Amorphous/Crystalline Nanoflower Heterostructures for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401472</link>
      <description>Rong Cao, Chang Liu, Bowen Zhang, Jun Liang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402962724

                Efficient water electrolysis for green hydrogen production relies on the development of robust oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, particularly for acidic environments. This study introduces amorphous/crystalline Mn&#8208;Ru binary oxides nanoflowers (a/c&#8208;Mn0.9Ru0.1O2) as a promising acidic OER catalyst, synthesized via a two&#8208;step phase engineering approach. The optimized a/c&#8208; Mn0.9Ru0.1O2&#8208;200 composition exhibits exceptional OER activity, requiring a low overpotential of 168 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and demonstrating remarkable stability over 28 hours. This significantly outperforms commercial RuO2 catalysts, which require an overpotential of 320 mV at 10 mA/cm2 and exhibit a stability of only 0.5 h under identical conditions. X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis results reveals the formation of Mn&#8208;O&#8208;Ru linkages and an optimized d&#8208;band electronic structure, attributed to strong electronic coupling at the amorphous/crystalline interface. This unique architecture promotes optimal adsorption/desorption of OER intermediates, leading to enhanced catalytic performance. This study offers a novel strategy for the rational design and production of efficient acidic OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Rong Cao, Chang Liu, Bowen Zhang, Jun Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Multifunctionality in a Colloidal Self&#8208;Repairing Catalyst for Alkaline Water Electrolysis to Achieve High Activity and Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400196</link>
      <description>Yoshiyuki Kuroda, Daiji Mizukoshi, Vinay Yadav, Tatsuya Taniguchi, Yuta Sasaki, Yoshinori Nishiki, Zaenal Awaludin, Akihiro Kato, Shigenori Mitsushima, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403061879

                Self&#8208;repairing catalysts are useful for achieving alkaline water electrolyzers with long lifetimes under intermittent operation. However, rational methodologies for designing self&#8208;repairing catalysts have not yet been established. Herein, hybrid cobalt hydroxide nanosheets (Co&#8208;ns), with a high deposition (repairing) rate, and &#946;&#8208;FeOOH nanorods (Fe&#8208;nr), with high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) ability, are electrostatically self&#8208;assembled into composite catalysts. This strategy is developed to integrate multifunctionality in self&#8208;repairing catalysts. Positively charged Co&#8208;ns and negatively charged Fe&#8208;nr form uniform composites when dispersed in an electrolyte. These composites are electrochemically deposited on a nickel electrode by electrolysis at 800 mA cm &#8722;2 . Co&#8208;ns form a conductive mesoporous assembly of CoOOH nanosheets as a support. Fe&#8208;nr are then distributed on the CoOOH nanosheets as active sites for the OER. Because of the high deposition rate of Co&#8208;ns, the amount of Fe&#8208;nr deposited increases 22 times compared to when Fe&#8208;nr is deposited alone, and the OER current density increases 14 times compared to that of Co&#8208;ns alone. The composite self&#8208;repair catalyst shows the highest activity and durability under an accelerated durability test (ADT), and its degradation rate decreases from 84 &#956;V cycle &#8722;1 (Fe&#8208;nr only) to 60 &#956;V cycle &#8722;1 (composite catalyst) under ADT conditions without repair.</description>
      <author>Yoshiyuki Kuroda, Daiji Mizukoshi, Vinay Yadav, Tatsuya Taniguchi, Yuta Sasaki, Yoshinori Nishiki, Zaenal Awaludin, Akihiro Kato, Shigenori Mitsushima</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Hydrogen, an Alternative Renewable Energy Source: Based on Solar-Energy-Driven Water-Splitting Technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31674/book.2024ecc.12</link>
      <description>Amit Kumar Dutta, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403139835

                The need for zero-emission, eco-friendly hydrogen fuel has increased enormously over the years due to adverse impacts on the environment caused by conventional fuels such as natural gas, coal, oil, fossil fuels, bio-mass etc. This chapter reports the safest and most efficient route for hydrogen-fuel production based on solar-energy-driven watersplitting technology over a heterogeneous photo-catalyst. Several challenges have been made for the extension of photo-catalyst, based on nano-sized semiconducting materials such as binary and ternary metal chalcogenides nano-materials, CuS, CdS, Fe3O4, CuInO2, CuInS2, CuGaS2 and their composites with hetero-nanostructure. When the nano-structures have the ability to absorb solar-light-energy (having a narrow band gap energy &lt; 3.6 eV), i.e., to utilise the most of the solar-spectrum, the photo-catalytic performances have increased much more. The catalytic performances of the semiconductors have also been improved for enhanced hydrogen production using nano-engineering technology, i.e., different modifications to the nano-catalyst surface and electronic energy structure, so that they can act as an efficient photo-catalyst for solar-energy driven water electrolysis to produce enhanced large-scale hydrogen-fuel. The possible mechanism of the photo-chemical processes has also been explored through the formation of free electron-hole pair (e- /h+) on suitable heterogeneous catalyst&#8217;s surface and controlling the kinetics of hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. How the proposed nano-catalyst materials have been designed to optimize solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency, improve the rate of hydrogen production and commercialized for the sake of society has been deliberated.</description>
      <author>Amit Kumar Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31674/book.2024ecc.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the combined electrocoagulation (EC) and electrochemical oxidation (EO) for treating the petroleum wastewater from crude oil storage tank bottoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5009089/v1</link>
      <description>Mona Galedari, Mohsen Mehdipour Ghazi, Maryam Hosseini Aliabadiba, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403039762

                Abstract This study investigated the treatment of petroleum-contaminated water from the crude oil storage tank by employing sequential coupling electrocoagulation and electrochemical oxidation using Fe and Ti/Sb-SnO2 electrodes as the sacrificial and oxidation anodes respectively. Although the Ti/Sb-SnO2 electrode is commonly used, its short lifetime disadvantages have limited its performance in industrial applications. A long-standing (highly stable) Ti/Sb-SnO2 electrode with high electro-oxidation capability was fabricated by applying an electrodeposited-annealed Sb-SnO2 interlayer between the Ti substrate and the Top Sb-SnO2 coating. Physical characterization results, including Field Emission Scanning Electron Microscopy (FESEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and Energy Dispersive Spectroscopy (EDS), revealed the presence of SnO2 and Sb in the anode composition. The surface appeared flat with a uniform spherical shape, averaging about 13&#8211;22 nm in size. The 2 V oxygen evolution overpotential and the accelerated lifetimes of 11 hours demonstrated that using the electro-deposited interlayer improved the electrocatalytic performance and stability of the electrode for electro-oxidation applications. The highest COD removal of the mentioned wastewater was optimized using the RSM methodology for EC and EO, respectively. The integrated EC-EO process achieved a maximum COD reduction efficiency of 96.5% at a current density of 20 mA/cm2, with electrodes placed 2.5 cm apart in a neutral pH environment for 120 minutes.</description>
      <author>Mona Galedari, Mohsen Mehdipour Ghazi, Maryam Hosseini Aliabadiba</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5009089/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetron technology for manufacturing electrodes of electrolysers with a proton-exchange membrane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0424857024030071</link>
      <description>&#1057;. &#1048;. &#1053;&#1077;&#1092;&#1077;&#1076;&#1082;&#1080;&#1085;, A. V. Ryabukhin, V. E. Eletskikh, &#1056;. &#1043;. &#1041;&#1086;&#1083;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;, V. D. Mikhnevich, &#1052;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1083;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1069;&#1083;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1103;. 60(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403121643

                The results of the development and study of catalysts for the anode of water decomposition electrolyzers with a proton exchange membrane are presented. To deposit catalytic layers on a titanium carrier, the magnetron method of sputtering composite targets in a vacuum was used. Iridium and ruthenium were used as the main catalyst, and molybdenum, chromium, and titanium were used as functional additives. The electrochemical and structural characteristics of catalytic coatings have been studied. Using voltammetry methods, cyclic current-voltage and anodic characteristics of catalytic compositions were obtained, including at different temperatures of subsequent heat treatment in air, as well as at different measurement temperatures. The Tafel slopes of the current-voltage characteristics of the composite anodes, as well as the currents at a potential of 1.55 V (RHE), were determined. It has been shown that the minimum slopes were obtained for the Ir&#8211;Ru&#8211;Mo&#8211;Ti catalytic composition (b = 40&#8211;63 mV/dec), and the maximum currents for the Ir&#8211;Mo&#8211;Cr catalytic composition (i = 100&#8211;110 mA/cm2 at E = 1.55 V (RHE)). It has been shown that the magnitude of CV adsorption currents in the anodic potential region correlates with the coefficient b of the Tafel equation E&#8211;lgi and determines the number of catalytic centers for the deprotonization stage of the oxygen evolution reaction. However, the activity of the catalyst in the OER is determined not only by the number of such centers, but mainly by the functional features of the catalyst itself, i.e., the composition of the catalyst and the conditions for its preparation (including the temperature of subsequent heat treatment of the catalyst in air). Catalytic compositions based on iridium with additions of molybdenum and chromium have higher activity in OER. Structural studies have shown that during magnetron sputtering of composite targets, even with small catalyst loadings, dispersed structures are formed, which on real porous titanium anodes should form on the front surface with a higher catalyst content.</description>
      <author>&#1057;. &#1048;. &#1053;&#1077;&#1092;&#1077;&#1076;&#1082;&#1080;&#1085;, A. V. Ryabukhin, V. E. Eletskikh, &#1056;. &#1043;. &#1041;&#1086;&#1083;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;, V. D. Mikhnevich, &#1052;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1083;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0424857024030071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing roof-harvested rainwater storage: Impact of dissolved oxygen regime on self-purification and quality dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.176574</link>
      <description>Zan Gao, Qionghua Zhang, Shiyi Gao, Mawuli Dzakpasu, Xiaochang C. Wang, The Science of The Total Environment. 954(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403097785

                Roof-harvested rainwater presents a promising, unconventional, and sustainable water resource for both potable and non-potable uses. However, there is a significant gap in understanding the quality evolution of stored rainwater under varying dissolved oxygen conditions and its suitability for various applications. This study investigated the evolution of rainwater quality under three distinct storage conditions: aerated, open, and sealed. Additionally, the microbial community and metabolic functions were analyzed to systematically evaluate the self-purification performance over long-term storage durations. The results indicate that aerated storage enhances microbial carbon metabolism, leading to a degradation rate of 54.4 %. Sealed and open storage conditions exhibited primary organic matter degradation during the early and late stages, respectively. Roof-rainwater harvesting (RRWH) systems showed limited denitrification activity across all three dissolved oxygen conditions. The maximum accumulation of NO</description>
      <author>Zan Gao, Qionghua Zhang, Shiyi Gao, Mawuli Dzakpasu, Xiaochang C. Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.176574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of the MELTS program to the fractional crystallization of low-alumina alkaline magma on Jeju Volcanic Island, Korea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s40562-024-00360-8</link>
      <description>Huy L&#234;, Cheolwoo Chang, Sung-Hyo Yun, Geoscience Letters. 11(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403148993

                Abstract Jeju Volcanic Island is the largest island in South Korea and is considered a continental shelf intraplate volcanic island. In this study, MELTS, a powerful program for modeling magmatic evolution processes, was applied to simulate the fractional crystallization process of the low-alumina alkaline volcanic rock suite on Jeju Island. MELTS modeling was conducted at many isobaric pressures ranging from 2.0 GPa to 0.1 GPa, different oxygen fugacities (fO 2 ) from FMQ-3 to FMQ + 3, and different H 2 O contents. The results demonstrate that the most suitable fractionation model for the Jeju low-alumina alkaline magma involves a pressure of 0.2 GPa to 0.1 GPa and an oxygen fugacity close to the FMQ buffer. Additionally, an H 2 O content of 0.5 wt.% is the most consistent with the evolution trend and mineral composition of the natural rock suite on Jeju Island. Although MELTS possesses several limitations in terms of the stability of calibration, such as spinel overestimation and a lack of experiments on hydrous minerals (which should be improved), MELTS performs well in terms of temperature and pressure prediction and in terms of the assessment of other factors of the fractional crystallization process on Jeju Island. Consequently, to evaluate a magmatic process in a particular region, MELTS should be combined with other analyses and not relied upon independently.</description>
      <author>Huy L&#234;, Cheolwoo Chang, Sung-Hyo Yun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s40562-024-00360-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An in-silico study of conventional and FLASH radiotherapy iso-effectiveness: potential impact of radiolytic oxygen depletion on tumor growth curves and tumor control probability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6560/ad8291</link>
      <description>Isabel Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Crespo, F. G&#243;mez, &#211;scar L&#243;pez Pouso, Juan Pardo&#8208;Montero, Physics in Medicine and Biology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403086787

                Abstract &amp;#xD;Objective: This work aims to investigate the iso-effectiveness of conventional and FLASH radiotherapy on tumors through in-silico mathematical models. We focused on the role of radiolytic oxygen depletion (ROD), which has been argued as a possible factor to explain the FLASH effect.&amp;#xD;&amp;#xD;Approach: We used a spatiotemporal reaction-diffusion model, including ROD, to simulate tumor oxygenation and response. From those oxygen distributions we obtained surviving fractions (SFs) using the linear-quadratic (LQ) model with the oxygen enhancement ratios (OER). We then employed the calculated SFs to describe the evolution of preclinical tumor volumes through a mathematical model of tumor response, and we also extrapolated those results to calculate tumor control probabilities (TCPs) using the Poisson-LQ approach.&amp;#xD;&amp;#xD;Main results: Our study suggests that the ROD effect may cause differences in SF between FLASH and conventional radiotherapy, especially in low &#945;/&#946; and poorly oxygenated cells. However, a statistical analysis showed that these changes in SF generally do not result in significant differences in the evolution of preclinical tumor growth curves when the sample size is small, because such differences in SF may not be noticeable in the heterogeneity of the population of animals}. Nonetheless, when extrapolating this effect to TCP curves, we observed important differences between both techniques (TCP is lower in FLASH radiotherapy). When analyzing the response of tumors with heterogeneous oxygenations, differences in TCP are more important for well oxygenated tumors. This apparent contradiction with the results obtained for homogeneously oxygenated cells is explained by the complex interplay between the heterogeneity of tumor oxygenation, the OER effect, and the ROD effect.&amp;#xD;&amp;#xD;Significance: This study supports the experimentally observed iso-effectiveness of FLASH and conventional radiotherapy when analyzing the volume evolution of preclinical tumors (that are far from control). However, this study also hints that tumor growth curves may be less sensitive to small variations in SF than tumor control probability: ROD may lead to increased SF in FLASH radiotherapy, which while not large enough to cause significant differences in tumor growth curves, could lead to important differences in clinical TCPs. Nonetheless, it cannot be discarded that other effects not modeled in this work, like radiation-induced immune effects, can contribute to tumor control and maintain the iso-effectiveness of FLASH radiotherapy. The study of tumor growth curves may not be the ideal experiment to test the iso-effectiveness of FLASH, and experiments reporting TCP or D50 may be preferred.</description>
      <author>Isabel Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Crespo, F. G&#243;mez, &#211;scar L&#243;pez Pouso, Juan Pardo&#8208;Montero</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6560/ad8291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Local Grain Boundary Chemistry and Correlating it with Local Mass Transport in Mixed&#8208;Conducting Perovskite Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404702</link>
      <description>Zijie Sha, James O. Douglas, Llu&#237;s Yedra, Ieuan D. Seymour, S&#242;nia Estrad&#233;, F. Peir&#243;, Stephen J. Skinner, John A. Kilner, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403158504

                Abstract Grain boundary (GB) mass transport, and chemistry exert a pronounced influence on both the performance and stability of electrodes for solid oxide electrochemical cells. Lanthanum strontium cobalt ferrite (LSCF6428) is applied as a model mixed ionic and electronic conducting (MIEC) perovskite oxide. The cation&#8208;vacancy distribution at the GBs is studied at both single and multi&#8208;grain scales using high&#8208;resolution characterization techniques and computational approaches. The accumulation of oxygen vacancies () in the GB region, rather than necessarily at the GB core, results in an enhancement of the oxygen diffusivity by 3 &#8211; 4 orders of magnitude along the GBs ( D gb ). At 350 &#176;C, the oxygen tracer diffusion coefficient ( D *) is measured as 2.5 &#215; 10 &#8722;14 cm 2 s &#8722;1 . The D gb is determined to be 2.8 &#215; 10 &#8722;10 cm 2 s &#8722;1 assuming a crystallographic GB width (&#948; crystal ) of 1 nm, and 2.5 &#215; 10 &#8722;11 cm 2 s &#8722;1 using a chemically measured &#948; chem of 11.10 nm by atom probe tomography (APT). The origin of the concomitant changes in the cation composition is also investigate. In addition to the host cations, strong Na segregation is detected at all the GBs examined. Despite the low (ppm) level of this impurity, its presence can affect the space charge potential (&#934; 0 ). This, in turn, will influence the evolution of GB chemistry.</description>
      <author>Zijie Sha, James O. Douglas, Llu&#237;s Yedra, Ieuan D. Seymour, S&#242;nia Estrad&#233;, F. Peir&#243;, Stephen J. Skinner, John A. Kilner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404702</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracing rate and extent of human-induced hypoxia during the last 200 years in the mesotrophic lake, Tiefer See (NE Germany)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-4317-2024</link>
      <description>Ido Sirota, Rik Tjallingii, Sylvia Pinkerneil, Birgit Schroeder, M. R. Albert, Rebecca Kearney, Oliver Heiri, Silvia Breu, Achim Brauer, Biogeosciences. 21(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403066822

                Abstract. The global spread of lake hypoxia, [O2] &lt; 2 mg L&#8722;1, during the last 2 centuries has had a severe impact on ecological systems and sedimentation processes. While the occurrence of hypoxia was observed in many lakes, a detailed quantification of hypoxia spread at centennial timescales remained largely unquantified. We track the evolution of hypoxia and its controls during the past 200 years in a lake, Tiefer See (TSK; NE Germany), using 17 gravity cores recovered from between 10 and 62 m water depth in combination with lake monitoring data. Lake hypoxia was associated with the onset of varve preservation in the TSK and has been dated by varve counting to 1918 &#177; 1 at 62 m water depth and reached a lake floor depth of 16 m in 1997 &#177; 1. This indicates that oxygen concentration fell below the threshold for varve preservation at the lake floor (&gt; 16 m). Sediment cores at 10&#8211;12 m depth do not contain varves indicating good oxygenation of the upper-water column. Monitoring data show that the threshold for hypoxia, and the intensity and duration of hypoxia which are sufficient for varve preservation, is a period of 5 months of [O2] &lt; 5 mg L&#8722;1 and 2 months of [O2] &lt; 2 mg L&#8722;1. Detailed total organic carbon (TOC), &#948;13Corg, and X-ray fluorescence (XRF) core scanning analyses of the short cores indicate that the decline in dissolved oxygen (DO) started several decades prior to the varve preservation. This proves a change in the depositional conditions in the lake, following a transition phase of several decades during which varves were not preserved. Furthermore, varve preservation does occur at seasonal stratification and does not necessarily require permanent stratification.</description>
      <author>Ido Sirota, Rik Tjallingii, Sylvia Pinkerneil, Birgit Schroeder, M. R. Albert, Rebecca Kearney, Oliver Heiri, Silvia Breu, Achim Brauer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-4317-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phenanthridine&#8208;based Covalent Organic Frameworks for Boosting Overall Solar H2O2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417115</link>
      <description>Jieyu Yue, Jing&#8208;Xian Luo, Zi&#8208;Xian Pan, Qing Xu, Peng Yang, Bo Tang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403140481

                Solar&#8208;driven H2O2 production via the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and water oxidation reaction (WOR) dual channels is green and sustainable, but severely restricted by the sluggish reaction kinetics. Constructing intriguing photocatalysts with effective active centers is a shortcut to breaking the kinetic bottleneck with great significance. Herein, we synthesize two novel neutral phenanthridine&#8208;based covalent organic frameworks (PD&#8208;COF1 and PD&#8208;COF2) for photosynthesizing H2O2. Compared to the no phenanthridine counterpart (AN&#8208;COF), the H2O2 photosynthetic activities of PD&#8208;COF1 and PD&#8208;COF2 are markedly boosted. In air and pure water without sacrificial agents, under Xe lamp and natural sunlight, the H2O2 photogeneration rate of PD&#8208;COF2 is 6103 and 3646 &#956;mol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1, respectively. Further experimental and theoretical inspections demonstrate that introducing phenanthridine units into COFs smoothly modulates the charge carrier dynamics and thermodynamically favors the generation of crucial OOH* and OH* intermediates in the ORR and WOR paths, respectively. Additionally, this is the first time the neutral phenanthridine moiety serves as the photooxidation unit for 2e&#8208; WOR towards H2O2 photoproduction. The current work sheds light on exploring novel catalytic centers for high&#8208;performance H2O2 evolution.</description>
      <author>Jieyu Yue, Jing&#8208;Xian Luo, Zi&#8208;Xian Pan, Qing Xu, Peng Yang, Bo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical composition of planetary hosts: C, N, and &#945;-element abundances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451889</link>
      <description>Anubhav Sharma, E. Stonkut&#233;, A. Drazdauskas, R. Minkevi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, &#352;. Mikolaitis, G. Tautvaisien&#279;, T. Narbuntas, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403058828

                Accurate atmospheric parameters and chemical composition of planet hosts play a major role in characterising exoplanets and understanding their formation and evolution. Our objective is to uniformly determine atmospheric parameters and chemical abundances of carbon (C), nitrogen (N), oxygen(O), and the alpha -elements, magnesium (Mg) and silicon (Si), along with C/O, N/O and Mg/Si abundance ratios for planet-hosting stars. In this analysis, we aim to investigate the potential links between stellar chemistry and the presence of planets. e tai Observatory telescope. The determination of stellar parameters was based on a standard analysis using equivalent widths and one-dimensional, plane-parallel model atmospheres calculated under the assumption of local thermodynamical equilibrium. The differential synthetic spectrum method was used to uniformly determine the carbon C(C2), nitrogen N(CN), oxygen O I magnesium Mg I, and silicon Si I elemental abundances as well as the C/O, N/O, and Mg/Si ratios. We analysed elemental abundances and ratios in dwarf and giant stars, finding that C/Fe O/Fe and Mg/Fe are lower in metal-rich dwarf hosts; whereas N/Fe is close to the Solar ratio. Giants show smaller scatter in C/Fe and O/Fe and lower than the Solar average C/Fe and C/O ratios. The (C+N+O) abundances increase with Fe/H in giant stars, with a minimal scatter. We also noted an overabundance of Mg and Si in planet-hosting stars, particularly at lower metallicities, and a lower Mg/Si ratio in stars with planets. In giants hosting high-mass planets, nitrogen shows a moderate positive relationship with planet mass. C/O and N/O ratios show moderate negative and positive slopes in giant stars, respectively. The Mg/Si ratio shows a negative correlation with planet mass across the entire stellar sample.</description>
      <author>Anubhav Sharma, E. Stonkut&#233;, A. Drazdauskas, R. Minkevi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, &#352;. Mikolaitis, G. Tautvaisien&#279;, T. Narbuntas</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctional Nanostructured Carbon and Inorganic Nanoparticles Based Nanocomposites for Electrochemical Energy Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.114238</link>
      <description>Mohammed Rafi Shaik, Mufsir Kuniyil, Mujeeb Khan, Mohammad Rafe Hatshan, Muhammad Tahir, Syed Farooq Adil, Mujeeb Khan, IntechOpen eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402994702

                Electrochemical energy conversion and storage technologies play a crucial role in ensuring a sustainable energy future. In these regards, nanostructured carbon-based materials (NCMs) are very critical in the development of novel energy technologies and devices. NCMs include CNTs, graphene, fullerene, and ordered mesoporous carbon materials, which exist in different morphologies. NCMs offer great opportunities for effective modifications through surface functionalization, doping with heteroatoms, and fabrication of composites with organic or inorganic species. Particularly, the composites of NCMs with inorganic materials such as metallic NPs, metal oxide NPs, and their other derivatives (MNPs) have gained considerable recognition in electrochemical energy applications. These materials demonstrate distinct properties, including excellent thermal and electrical conductivity, large surface area, and chemical stability. Herein, we have highlighted some of the trends and outlooks in this exciting area, including fundamentals of these substances according to material science perspective. Besides, the latest research and development of multifunctional MNPs@NCMs composites for electrochemical energy applications have also been illustrated. Particularly, the utilization of these composites from the perspective of different electrochemical energy applications has been summarized, such as energy conversion processes like hydrogen evolution reactions (HER), oxygen reduction reactions (ORR), and energy storage devices like batteries and supercapacitors.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Rafi Shaik, Mufsir Kuniyil, Mujeeb Khan, Mohammad Rafe Hatshan, Muhammad Tahir, Syed Farooq Adil, Mujeeb Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.114238</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of inventions in the development of national industrial culture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15276/ict.01.2024.43</link>
      <description>Oleksii M. Kozachenko, Sofiia R. Honcharuk, Aleksandra Rusek, No host. 1(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403149071

                The work is dedicated to highlighting the influence of prominent inventors on the development of culture and the traditions of invention, which play a key role in shaping national identity and industrial culture. The article analyzes how innovations and technological achievements of individuals contribute to the formation of national pride, raising awareness, and strengthening the international image of a nation. Special attention is given to inventions that have become symbols of national progress and reflect unique cultural traits embedded in the collective consciousness of the people. The study emphasizes the importance of invention as an integral part of national culture and its significance in building a society focused on innovation and development. In particular, the research highlights the most important moments in the life and scientific activity of a prominent Polish inventor closely connected with Odesa. It traces the evolution of creative ideas and the diversity of interests of Stefan Drzewiecki, whose multifaceted and extraordinary creative interests are reflected in innovations that were groundbreaking in the mechanical engineering of that time. Special attention is given to inventions in the field of submarine construction, particularly the creation of the first military submarine prototype. The structural features of the submarine stimulated further research, which, in turn, led to new inventions. These included the development of an autonomous power system using batteries, an oxygen storage and supply system, and equipment for submarine maneuvering. Many of the proposed solutions were revolutionary for their time and significantly advanced global shipbuilding.</description>
      <author>Oleksii M. Kozachenko, Sofiia R. Honcharuk, Aleksandra Rusek</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15276/ict.01.2024.43</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sociality shapes mitochondrial adaptations supporting hypoxia tolerance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.30.615914</link>
      <description>Alice Rossi, Max Ruwolt, Paraskevi Kakouri, Tetiana Kosten, S&#233;verine Kunz, Dmytro Puchkov, Jane Reznick, Damir Omerba&#353;i&#263;, Daniel Mendez-Aranda, Georgia Carai, Guido Mastrobuoni, Daniel W. Hart, Michela Carraro, Ludovica Tommasin, Nigel C. Bennett, Val&#233;rie B&#233;gay, Katja Faelber, Oliver Daumke, Paolo Bernardi, Thomas J. Park, Stefan Kempa, Fan Liu, Gary R. Lewin, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403058436

                Oxygen deprivation or hypoxia is poorly dealt with by most terrestrial species and often leads to permanent tissue damage and death. One prominent exception is the naked mole-rat (Heterocephalus glaber) which is remarkably adapted to withstand prolonged periods (~18 mins) of severe hypoxia, a trait likely driven by its crowded underground lifestyle. Other African mole-rat species are less social or entirely solitary like the Cape mole-rat (Georychus capensis). Here, we asked whether cellular and molecular adaptations to hypoxia map to social traits. We discovered that at the cellular level naked mole-rat fibroblasts survive &gt;30 hours in 1% oxygen, while fibroblasts from terrestrial or non-social mole-rat species (human, mouse and Cape mole-rat) die rapidly under hypoxic conditions. We further show that naked mole-rat mitochondria have evolved morphological, functional and proteomic adaptations crucial for hypoxia resistance, remaining unaffected after long periods of severe hypoxia. We identify the mitochondrial protein Optic Atrophy 1 (OPA1) as a key player in naked mole-rat hypoxia resilience. Naked mole-rat mitochondria not only express more protective forms of OPA1, but also harbor a structurally unique isoform that likely protects cells from hypoxic damage. We show that evolutionary changes including the functionalization of a unique Opa1 exon support mitochondrial mediated cellular protection. Indeed, knockdown of OPA1 in naked mole-rat cells is sufficient to render them equally susceptible to hypoxia as human cells or cells from non-social African species. Our study demonstrates how molecular evolution drives unique adaptations that enable cells to achieve unprecedented resistance to hypoxic damage. We also show that molecular changes at the level of mitochondria are crucial in conferring hypoxia resistance. Our results thus chart a novel molecular path to understand how robust cellular hypoxia resistance can be achieved. Such knowledge may eventually inspire novel strategies to circumvent the consequences of hypoxic-damage in humans.</description>
      <author>Alice Rossi, Max Ruwolt, Paraskevi Kakouri, Tetiana Kosten, S&#233;verine Kunz, Dmytro Puchkov, Jane Reznick, Damir Omerba&#353;i&#263;, Daniel Mendez-Aranda, Georgia Carai, Guido Mastrobuoni, Daniel W. Hart, Michela Carraro, Ludovica Tommasin, Nigel C. Bennett, Val&#233;rie B&#233;gay, Katja Faelber, Oliver Daumke, Paolo Bernardi, Thomas J. Park, Stefan Kempa, Fan Liu, Gary R. Lewin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.30.615914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrophenoxylation of alkynes by gold catalysts: a mini review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-024-06152-3</link>
      <description>Miguel Ramos, Miquel Sol&#224;, Albert Poater, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 30(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402975044

                Abstract Context The field of chemistry has significantly evolved, with catalysis playing a crucial role in transforming chemical processes. From Valerius&#8217; use of sulfuric acid in the sixteenth century to modern advancements, catalysis has driven innovations across various industries. The introduction of gold as a catalyst marked a pivotal shift, expanding its applications beyond ornamentation to homogeneous catalysis. Gold&#8217;s unique properties, such as its electrophilic nature and flexibility, have enabled its use in synthesizing complex molecules, including those in nanomedicine and sustainable chemical processes. The development of gold-based complexes, particularly in hydroalkoxylation and hydroamination reactions, showcases their efficiency in forming carbon&#8211;oxygen bonds under mild conditions. Recent studies on dual gold catalysis and heterobimetallic complexes further highlight gold&#8217;s versatility in achieving high turnover rates and selectivity. This evolution underscores the potential of gold catalysis in advancing environmentally sustainable methodologies and enhancing the scope of modern synthetic chemistry. The debate about the nature of monogold and dual-gold catalysis is open. Methods DFT calculations have played a key role in promoting the activation of alkynes, in particular the hydrophenoxylation of alkynes by metal-based catalysts. They not only help identify the most efficient and selective catalysts but also aid in screening for those capable of performing a dual metal catalytic mechanism. The most commonly used functionals are BP86 and B3LYP, with the SVP and 6-31G(d) basis sets employed for geometry optimizations, and M06 with TZVP or 6-311G(d,p) basis sets used for single-point energy calculations in a solvent. Grimme dispersion correction has been explicitly added either in the solvent single point energy calculations or in the gas phase geometry optimizations or in both. To point out that M06 implicitly includes part of this dispersion scheme.</description>
      <author>Miguel Ramos, Miquel Sol&#224;, Albert Poater</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-024-06152-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially&#8211;resolved gas-phase metallicity in Seyfert galaxies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2263</link>
      <description>Mark Armah, Rog&#233;rio Riffel, L G Dahmer-Hahn, R. Davies, O. L. Dors, D. Kakkad, Rogemar A. Riffel, A. Rodr&#237;guez-Ardila, Daniel Ruschel-Dutra, Thaisa Storchi&#8208;Bergmann, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403086798

                Abstract We explore the relations between the gas-phase metallicity radial profiles (few hundred inner parsec) and multiple galaxy properties for 15 Seyfert galaxies from the AGNIFS (Active Galactic Nuclei Integral Field Spectroscopy) sample using optical Integral Field Unit (IFU) observations from Gemini Multi-Object Spectrographs (GMOS) and Multi Unit Spectroscopic Explorer (MUSE) processed archival data. The data were selected at z &#8818; 0.013 within black hole mass range [6 &amp;lt; log (MBH/M&#8857;) &amp;lt; 9] with moderate 14&#8211;150 keV X-ray luminosities $\left[42\, \lesssim \, \log L_X (\rm erg\, s^{-1})\, \lesssim \, 44\right]$. We estimated the gas-phase metallicity using the strong-line methods and found mean values for the oxygen dependent (Z &#8764; 0.75 Z&#8857;) and nitrogen dependent (Z &#8764; 1.14 Z&#8857;) calibrations. These estimates show excellent agreement with &#916;Z &#8776; 0.19 dex and &#916;Z &#8776; 0.18 dex between the mean values from the two strong-line calibrations for GMOS and MUSE respectively, consistent with the order of metallicity uncertainty via the strong-line methods. We contend that our findings align with a scenario wherein local Seyferts have undergone seamless gas accretion histories, resulting in positive metallicity profile over an extended period of time, thereby providing insights into galaxy evolution and the chemical enrichment or depletion of the universe. Additionally, we argue that metal-poor gas inflow from the local interstellar medium (ISM) and accreted through the circumgalactic medium (CGM) onto the galaxy systems regulates the star formation processes by diluting their central metallicity and inverting their metallicity gradients, producing a more prominent anti-correlation between gas-phase metallicity and Eddington ratio.</description>
      <author>Mark Armah, Rog&#233;rio Riffel, L G Dahmer-Hahn, R. Davies, O. L. Dors, D. Kakkad, Rogemar A. Riffel, A. Rodr&#237;guez-Ardila, Daniel Ruschel-Dutra, Thaisa Storchi&#8208;Bergmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNCOVERing the Faint-End of the z=7 [OIII] Luminosity Function with
  JWST's F410M Medium Bandpass Filter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.19023</link>
      <description>Isak Wold, Sangeeta Malhotra, James E. Rhoads, John R. Weaver, Bingjie Wang, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402963648

                Strong emission from doubly ionized oxygen is a beacon for some of the most intensely star forming galaxies known. JWST enables the search for this beacon in the early universe with unprecedented sensitivity. In this work, we extend the study of faint [OIII]$_{5008}$ selected galaxies by an order of magnitude in line luminosity. We use publicly available UNCOVER DR1 JWST/NIRCam and HST imaging data of the cluster lensing field, Abell 2744, to identify strong (rest-frame EW$&gt;500$\AA) [OIII]$_{5008}$ emitters at $z\sim7$ based on excess F410M flux. We find $N=68$ $z\sim7$ [OIII] candidates, with a subset of $N=33$ that have deep HST coverage required to rule-out lower redshift interlopers (13.68 arcmin$^2$ with F814W $5\sigma$ depth $&gt;28$ AB). Such strong emission lines can lead to very red colors that could be misinterpreted as evidence for old, massive stellar populations, but are shown to be due to emission lines where we have spectra. Using this deep HST sample and completeness simulations, which calculate the effective survey volume of the UNCOVER lensing field as a function of [OIII] luminosity, we derive a new [OIII] luminosity function (LF) extending to $41.09&lt;\rm{log}_{10}(L/\rm{erg\,s}^{-1})&lt;42.35$ which is an order of magnitude deeper than previous $z\sim6$ [OIII] LFs based on JWST slitless spectroscopy. This LF is well fit by a power law with a faint-end slope of $\alpha=-2.07^{+0.22}_{-0.23}$. There is little or no evolution between this LF and published [OIII] LFs at redshifts $3\lesssim z\lesssim7$, and no evidence of a turnover at faint luminosities. The sizes of these extreme [OIII] emitters are broadly similar to their low redshift counterparts, the green peas. The luminosity function of [OIII] emitters matches that of Lyman-$\alpha$ at the bright end, suggesting that many of them should be Lyman-$\alpha$ emitters.</description>
      <author>Isak Wold, Sangeeta Malhotra, James E. Rhoads, John R. Weaver, Bingjie Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.19023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cathodoluminescence textures and trace elements in quartz: Constraints on Ag mineralization in adularia&#8211;sericite epithermal systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2138/am-2024-9415</link>
      <description>Shen Gao, Xinyu Zou, Albert H. Hofstra, Liangliang Huang, Haijun Yang, Kezhang Qin, Erin E. Marsh, Kaixuan Hui, Jing Xu, Li Wang, Zhenzhen Li, Junxing Zhao, Ri Han, Guangming Li, American Mineralogist. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403123277

                Abstract Quartz chemistry is important for revealing fluid sources and evolution in hydrothermal deposits, but such information is lacking for many epithermal systems and deposit types. To investigate quartz chemistry in this system further, we collected representative samples of quartz from adularia-sericite epithermal Ag deposits in China and determined their chemical compositions. In adularia-sericite epithermal Ag-bearing systems, magmatic quartz from porphyry intrusions and host subvolcanic rocks is SEM-CL spectral peaks at 360 and 415 nm and exhibits homogenous CL or weak zonal textures (alternating growth zones within individual quartz crystal). Trace elements in magmatic quartz have the lowest Sb concentrations (median = 0.1 ppm; n = 80). Hydrothermal quartz can be classified into type I and type II by CL false color and CL spectral peaks. Hydrothermal type I quartz has spectral peaks at 360 and 415 nm, exhibits zonal or sector textures, and is associated with base metal sulfides and minor Ag mineralization. Such hydrothermal type I quartz has low Sb concentrations (median = 4.5 ppm; n = 839), contains liquid-rich fluid inclusions and formed by cooling. The cooling trend is indicated by a positive correlation between the concentrations of Sb and Al, as well as between Li and Al. Hydrothermal type I quartz has an Fe center by electron spin resonance, whereas other centers are missing or weak at room temperature. In general, hydrothermal type II quartz mantles type I quartz. Hydrothermal type II quartz has a very high intensity peak (by several orders of magnitude) at 580 nm, zonal textures, and is associated with abundant Ag mineralization. Hydrothermal type II quartz has the highest Sb concentrations (median = 71 ppm; n = 185), which remain constant as Al decreases on an Sb vs. Al plot. This quartz has colloform, bladed or zonal textures and contains coexisting liquid- and vapor-rich fluid inclusions, indicative of boiling. Additionally, this quartz has a significantly higher E'1 center intensity, suggesting a high concentration of oxygen vacancies associated with rapid crystallization. The mineral paragenesis, analytical results, and geochemical models show that in these Ag-bearing epithermal systems hydrothermal type I quartz associated with base metal sulfides precipitated during cooling whereas subsequent growth zoned hydrothermal type II quartz with high Sb concentrations and Ag-minerals precipitated during boiling. These results suggest that the CL texture and spectra, trace elements, and electron spin resonance data of quartz could identify veins with potential for Ag mineralization in epithermal systems.</description>
      <author>Shen Gao, Xinyu Zou, Albert H. Hofstra, Liangliang Huang, Haijun Yang, Kezhang Qin, Erin E. Marsh, Kaixuan Hui, Jing Xu, Li Wang, Zhenzhen Li, Junxing Zhao, Ri Han, Guangming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2138/am-2024-9415</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
