<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 01:41:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting effect of ultrasonication on the oxygen evolution reaction during zinc electrowinning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ultsonch.2024.107183</link>
      <description>Guihong Han, Zhen Chen, N. Cui, Shuzhen Yang, Yanfang Huang, Bingbing Liu, Hu Sun, Ultrasonics Sonochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404878669

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guihong Han, Zhen Chen, N. Cui, Shuzhen Yang, Yanfang Huang, Bingbing Liu, Hu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ultsonch.2024.107183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCoCe/NF Nanosheet Clusters for Alkaline Electrolyzed Water Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.111173</link>
      <description>Zandong Zhang, Wenfei Wang, Zhezhi Chen, Zuobo Yang, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404878997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zandong Zhang, Wenfei Wang, Zhezhi Chen, Zuobo Yang, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.111173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881031

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881065

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881073

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881227

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881288

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881341

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881591

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881598

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrosion-Engineered Room-Temperature Deposition of NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/NiS/Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; at Nickel Foam: An Efficient Strategy and Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01627</link>
      <description>Marilia B. Dalla Benetta, Eithne Dempsey, Carmel B. Breslin, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404882261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marilia B. Dalla Benetta, Eithne Dempsey, Carmel B. Breslin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping Ti into RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Accelerate Bridged&#8208;Oxygen&#8208;Assisted Deprotonation for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411709</link>
      <description>Wei Hu, Bolong Huang, Mingzi Sun, Jing Du, Yong Hai, Wen Yin, Xiaomei Wang, Wensheng Gao, Zhao Chun-Yang, Yinghong Yue, Zelong Li, Can Li, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404883582

                Abstract The development of efficient and durable electrocatalysts for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential for advancing renewable hydrogen energy technology. However, the slow deprotonation kinetics of oxo&#8208;intermediates, involving the four proton&#8208;coupled electron steps, hinder the acidic OER progress. Herein, a RuTiO x solid solution electrocatalyst is investigated, which features bridged oxygen (O bri ) sites that act as proton acceptors, accelerating the deprotonation of oxo&#8208;intermediates. Electrochemical tests, infrared spectroscopy, and density functional theory results reveal that the moderate proton adsorption energy on O bri sites facilitates fast deprotonation kinetics through the adsorbate evolution mechanism. This process effectively prevents the over&#8208;oxidation and deactivation of Ru sites caused by the lattice oxygen mechanism. Consequently, RuTiO x shows a low overpotential of 198 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 geo and performance exceeding 1400 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 geo with negligible deactivation. These insights into the OER mechanism and the structure&#8208;function relationship are crucial for the advancement of catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Wei Hu, Bolong Huang, Mingzi Sun, Jing Du, Yong Hai, Wen Yin, Xiaomei Wang, Wensheng Gao, Zhao Chun-Yang, Yinghong Yue, Zelong Li, Can Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/response1</link>
      <description>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404890679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Study on the Electrocatalytic Performance of Defected Monolayer Vanadium Diselenide for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122669</link>
      <description>Rabia Hassan, Rehan Hassan, Fei Ma, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404893517

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rabia Hassan, Rehan Hassan, Fei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermally Synthesized NiO-SnO2 Nanocomposite as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) and Urea Oxidation Reaction (UOR)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177865</link>
      <description>Bodicherla Naresh, T.V.M. Sreekanth, C. N Suma, K. Sunil Kumar, Kisoo Yoo, Jonghoon Kim, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404902482

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bodicherla Naresh, T.V.M. Sreekanth, C. N Suma, K. Sunil Kumar, Kisoo Yoo, Jonghoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Oxygen Vacancy Distribution in Perovskites via A-Site Cation Engineering for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07345b</link>
      <description>Zhaoen Su, Jingpin Wu, Tao Song, Lele Duan, Peili Zhang, Licheng Sun, Ke Fan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404909946

                Oxygen-deficient perovskite oxides hold great potential as highly efficient catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), but regulating and in-depth understanding oxygen vacancies (Vo) effectively remains challenging. This study reports the...</description>
      <author>Zhaoen Su, Jingpin Wu, Tao Song, Lele Duan, Peili Zhang, Licheng Sun, Ke Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07345b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Step Synthesis of TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/FeO(OH) Nano-Heterostructures as Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05410</link>
      <description>Hailin Liu, Li Wang, Mengmeng Wang, Zihao Li, Quanmin Dai, Shuo Sun, Xuyang Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Wei Lai, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404912346

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hailin Liu, Li Wang, Mengmeng Wang, Zihao Li, Quanmin Dai, Shuo Sun, Xuyang Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Wei Lai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of RuO2/Ni-Co3O4 Heterostructures for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.246</link>
      <description>Bilal Zaman, Dongxu Jiao, Jinchang Fan, Dewen Wang, Huafeng Fan, Ming Gong, Shan Xu, Yanhua Liu, Muhammad Faizan, Xiaoqiang Cui, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 682(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404893565

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bilal Zaman, Dongxu Jiao, Jinchang Fan, Dewen Wang, Huafeng Fan, Ming Gong, Shan Xu, Yanhua Liu, Muhammad Faizan, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Ruthenium&#8208;Cobalt Active Pair with Moderate Spacing for Enhanced Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409173</link>
      <description>Xiaoxia Chen, Meihuan Liu, C.Y. Ni, Yiwen Chen, Tianyu Liu, Shiyu Li, Hui Su, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404900015

                Abstract Ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;based catalysts have emerged as promising alternatives to Iridium (Ir) catalysts in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis cells due to their lower price and excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. However, their stability is compromised by generation of unstable high&#8208;valence Ru sites and oxygen vacancy in a lattice oxygen&#8208;mediated (LOM) pathway. Here, a low&#8208;load Ru site on a Barium (Ba)&#8208;doped Co 3 O 4 (RuBa x Co 3&#8211;x O 4 ) catalyst is developed with abundant Ruthenium&#9472;Cobalt (Ru&#9472;Co) pairs for enhanced acidic OER activity. The incorporation of Ba can efficiently modulate the lattice of Co 3 O 4 , creating Ru&#9472;Co active pairs with optimized spacing through compression stress. In situ characterizations exhibit contractive Ru&#9472;Co pairs that promote the rapid and direct coupling of * O&#9472;O * radicals, bypassing the sluggish * OOH species and avoiding the oxygen vacancies, which can trigger the oxide path mechanism (OPM) for an efficient and stable OER process. As a result, the designed catalyst delivers a low overpotential of 219 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and also demonstrates excellent stability, maintaining performance over 50 h of continuous operation at a larger current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . These findings highlight the potential of the RuBa x Co 3&#8208;x O 4 catalysts for durable and efficient OER applications.</description>
      <author>Xiaoxia Chen, Meihuan Liu, C.Y. Ni, Yiwen Chen, Tianyu Liu, Shiyu Li, Hui Su</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing reconstruction achieves ultrastable water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2407350121</link>
      <description>Yu Lin, Danji Huang, Qunlei Wen, Ruoou Yang, Bowen Chen, Yi Shen, Youwen Liu, Jiakun Fang, Huiqiao Li, Tianyou Zhai, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 121(50)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404913196

                The dissolution of active atoms under operating potential will lead to a decline in their oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, thus preventing the current highly active catalysts from being practically applicable in industrial water electrolysis. Here, we propose a sequential leaching strategy to utilize the dynamic restructuring and enhance the chemical bond strength for highly active and stable OER. Modeling on nickel-iron sulfides (NiFe-S), we introduced and utilized foreign Mo dopant preleaching as the sacrificial agent to alleviate the oxidation corrosion of partial M&#9472;S bonds. Operando spectroscopic reveal that foreign Mo dopant leach from the matrix and then adsorb on the surface of NiFe O(S)OH as molybdate at lower OER potential. The crystal occupation hamiltonian population analysis uncovers that the charge transfer from molybdate into NiFe O(S)OH will enhance bond energy of M&#9472;S, thus preventing further S and Fe/Ni leaching. By manipulating ion leaching, the resulting active phase achieves an ultralow overpotential of 250 mV at 400 mA cm &#8722;2 and high stability of more than 3,700 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . An industrial water electrolysis equipment using our catalysts delivered ultralow energy consumption of 4.30 kWh m &#8722;3 H2 and record stability over 250 h (2,300 h lifetime by epitaxial method with 10% attenuation) under a high working current of 8,000 mA. The hydrogen production cost of US$2.46/kg H2 aligns with the green hydrogen cost target set by the European Commission for the coming decade.</description>
      <author>Yu Lin, Danji Huang, Qunlei Wen, Ruoou Yang, Bowen Chen, Yi Shen, Youwen Liu, Jiakun Fang, Huiqiao Li, Tianyou Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2407350121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur doping and heterostructure on NiSe@Co(OH)2 with facilitated surface reconstruction and interfacial electron regulation to boost oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133978</link>
      <description>Fei Nie, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Xiaodan Chong, Xiaoping Dai, Yikai Yang, Jinsheng Zhao, Fuel. 384(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404917759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Nie, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Xiaodan Chong, Xiaoping Dai, Yikai Yang, Jinsheng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy-Activated Surface Reconstruction of Perovskite Nanofibers for Efficient Lattice Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16293</link>
      <description>Lin&#8208;Bo Liu, Yufeng Tang, Lei Zhu, Mulin Yu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Wei Xiao, Subiao Liu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404925461

                Inducing the surface reconstruction of perovskites to promote the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has garnered increasing attention due to the enhanced catalytic activities caused by the self-reconstructed electroactive species. However, the high reconstruction potential, limited electrolyte penetration, and accessibility to the perovskite surface greatly hindered the formation of self-reconstructed electroactive species. Herein, trace Ce-doped La0.95Ce0.05Ni0.8Fe0.2O3&#8722;&#948; nanofibers (LCNF-NFs) were synthesized via electrospinning and postcalcination to boost surface reconstruction. The upshift of the O 2p band center induced by the rich oxygen vacancies lowered the reconstruction potential, and the specific one-dimensional nanostructure effectively enabled enhanced electrolyte accessibility and permeation to the LCNF-NFs. These collectively caused massive in situ generation of self-reconstructed electroactive Ni/FeO(OH) species on the surface. As a result, the surface-reconstructed LCNF-NFs exhibited accelerated lattice kinetics with a comparatively lower Tafel slope of 50.12 mV dec&#8211;1, together with an overpotential of only 342.3 mV to afford a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 0.1 M KOH, which is superior to that of pristine LaNi0.8Fe0.2O3&#8722;&#948; nanoparticles (NPs) and the same stoichiometric La0.95Ce0.05Ni0.8Fe0.2O3&#8722;&#948; NPs, commercial IrO2, and most of the state-of-the-art OER electrocatalysts. This study provided deep insights into the surface reconstruction behaviors induced by oxygen defects and an intellectual approach for constructing electroactive species in situ on perovskites for various energy storage and conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Lin&#8208;Bo Liu, Yufeng Tang, Lei Zhu, Mulin Yu, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Wei Xiao, Subiao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degradation of LaTiO2N (100) and BiVO4 (001) surfaces as photocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction: a DFT-MD-based study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsusfall.2024.179</link>
      <description>Deqi Tang, Fabrizio Creazzo, Ziwei Chai, Sandra Luber, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404925611

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deqi Tang, Fabrizio Creazzo, Ziwei Chai, Sandra Luber</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsusfall.2024.179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and solvation of key intermediates of the oxygen evolution reaction on rutile oxide surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsusfall.2024.220</link>
      <description>Livia Giordano, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404925723

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Livia Giordano</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsusfall.2024.220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of chirality and magnetic fields in the electrocatalysis of the spin-restricted oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsusfall.2024.149</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404926041

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsusfall.2024.149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin enhanced oxygen evolution reaction: effects of chirality and magnetic fields.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsusfall.2024.236</link>
      <description>Priscila Vensaus, Yunchang Liang, Nicolas Zigon, Jean&#8208;Philippe Ansermet, Galo J. A. A. Soler&#8208;Illia, Narcis Avarvari, &#8234;Magal&#237; Lingenfelder, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404926075

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Priscila Vensaus, Yunchang Liang, Nicolas Zigon, Jean&#8208;Philippe Ansermet, Galo J. A. A. Soler&#8208;Illia, Narcis Avarvari, &#8234;Magal&#237; Lingenfelder</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsusfall.2024.236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn-doped NiCo LDH nanosheets with rich oxygen vacancies for high-performance supercapacitors and efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114848</link>
      <description>Zan Xu, Tao Zhou, Yanfei Ha, Xuanye Chen, Xiaoyu Zhu, Junwen Tao, Yongsheng Liu, Journal of Energy Storage. 106(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404928887

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zan Xu, Tao Zhou, Yanfei Ha, Xuanye Chen, Xiaoyu Zhu, Junwen Tao, Yongsheng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recovery of cathode materials from inprocess rejected electrode scrape of lithium-ion batteries for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00986445.2024.2435906</link>
      <description>T. Gokulasaravanan, Nafis Ahmed, P. Balaji Bhargav, Gautham Kumar G., Mathew K. Farncis, Lankipalli Rekha, C. A. Niranjan, Chemical Engineering Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404933897

                In this study, we present an experimental approach for recycling cathode electrode of spent lithium-ion battery (LIB), repurposing the recovered cathode material as an oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalyst. The process involves an initial pretreatment at 450 &#176;C to remove the binder (PVDF), followed by calcination at 500 &#176;C for further purification. Comprehensive characterization of the structural and morphological properties was conducted using XRD, FESEM, EDS, and XPS. The refined materials, coated on carbon cloth, were evaluated for OER performance. The results indicated promising catalytic activity, with the LT2 sample displaying an overpotential of 528 mV, a Tafel slope of 103.6 mV/dec, and an electrochemical surface area (ECSA) of 25.5 mF/cm2. The improved performance is attributed to the effective removal of the binder and enhanced surface area from the calcination process. This method demonstrates a viable pathway for the sustainable recycling of LIBs, providing efficient electrocatalysts for OER applications.</description>
      <author>T. Gokulasaravanan, Nafis Ahmed, P. Balaji Bhargav, Gautham Kumar G., Mathew K. Farncis, Lankipalli Rekha, C. A. Niranjan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00986445.2024.2435906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Progress of Rare Earth Based Low-temperature Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/s1004-0277.20240048</link>
      <description>Yu Sun, Qi-jing ZHANG, Konggang Qu, Chinese Rare Earths. 45(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404943953

                Hydrogen energy is a strategic emerging industry and the key development direction of the future industry, and is one of the important directions of China's new quality productive forces. Hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions are important electrochemical processes in the preparation and utilization of hydrogen energy, low-cost, highly efficient, environmentally friendly and stable electrocatalysts are the key to economically drive the aforesaid electrochemical reactions. RE elements have unique electronic structures and low electronegativity, which can serve as active sites for electrocatalytic reactions, more importantly, they can act as additives to regulate the electronic properties of active sites, significantly affecting the reaction energy barrier and adsorption energy of reactants, thereby achieving the improvement of electrocatalytic performance. This article mainly introduces the research progress of RE-based low-temperature electrocatalysts in hydrogen energy related electrocatalytic reactions, and also summarizes the mechanisms of the above three reactions as well as the synthesis methods of RE-based catalysts. Therefore, this review has certain guiding significance for the comprehensive utilization of RE elements and further exploration and research of RE-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yu Sun, Qi-jing ZHANG, Konggang Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/s1004-0277.20240048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional nanoflower-like transition metal sulfide heterostructures (Co9S8/Co1-xS /WS2) as efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145467</link>
      <description>Binbin Fan, Anders Lei, Yongjin Zou, Miao Liu, Lianhua Zhao, Biyao Jin, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404944117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Binbin Fan, Anders Lei, Yongjin Zou, Miao Liu, Lianhua Zhao, Biyao Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of &#948;-FeOOH/NiMn2S4 heterointerface for efficient alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133980</link>
      <description>Ziqi Zhao, Fuxi Bao, Jiawen Wang, Zongli Gu, Yanbing Huang, Chaocao Cao, Y.F. Yuan, Changhong Sun, Guo Wen, Fuel. 384(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404944209

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziqi Zhao, Fuxi Bao, Jiawen Wang, Zongli Gu, Yanbing Huang, Chaocao Cao, Y.F. Yuan, Changhong Sun, Guo Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing cation defects through selective etching tetrahedral sites in Co3O4 for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00823e</link>
      <description>Xiaotian Wu, Qian Zhu, Yingge Cong, Zhibin Geng, Keke Huang, Mei Han, Zhiyu Shao, Materials Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404944383

                Herein, Zn was introduced to regulate the tetrahedral coordination of Co3O4 and then leached out using the method of alkaline impregnation. Experimental characterizations indicated that the generation of tetrahedral defects...</description>
      <author>Xiaotian Wu, Qian Zhu, Yingge Cong, Zhibin Geng, Keke Huang, Mei Han, Zhiyu Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00823e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Soluble Lead Flow Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad9a04</link>
      <description>Miji E. Joy, Vivekanand Vivekanand, Richard Wills, Manoj Neergat, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404957726

                Abstract Kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on PbO2 deposited glassy carbon disk electrode in methane sulfonic acid (MSA) is analyzed with cyclic voltammetry and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy, for soluble lead flow battery applications. The effect of concentration of active species (Pb2+), and the electrolyte (MSA) on the OER at the deposited PbO2 layer is investigated. The apparent activation energy of the OER on PbO2, deposited at various overpotential, is obtained from the Arrhenius and Eyring analysis. The apparent activation energy follows a special trend that it increases with overpotential, reaches a maximum and decreases thereafter. This is consistent with the PbO2 specifically deposited from low concentration of MSA (&lt;1M), where the gel layer composed of hydrated PbO(OH)2 is also found. It is observed that low MSA concentration is preferred for limiting the OER at the positive electrode.</description>
      <author>Miji E. Joy, Vivekanand Vivekanand, Richard Wills, Manoj Neergat</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad9a04</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanosheet arrays derived from ZIF-67 grown on three-dimensional frameworks for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02635g</link>
      <description>Jiangyan Dang, Jingjing Qiu, Xiaoying Zhang, Jingping Zhang, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404957777

                Hydrogen energy has become one of the most promising substitutes for conventional fuels because of its high calorific value and green and renewable advantages. Among various hydrogen production strategies, the...</description>
      <author>Jiangyan Dang, Jingjing Qiu, Xiaoying Zhang, Jingping Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02635g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supported Porous Carbon Monoliths for Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution in Alkaline Freshwater and Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03427</link>
      <description>Bei Li, Changshui Wang, Shuijian He, Zhenlu Liu, Chunmei Zhang, Zhiqiang Sun, Haoqi Yang, Shaoju Jian, Qian Zhang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404959860

                Developing efficient catalysts for seawater electrolysis hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is crucial for producing green hydrogen. Carbonized wood (CW), a porous carbon monolith, is a promising self-supporting electrocatalytic electrode owing to its environmentally friendly, sustainable, and hierarchically porous properties. However, the impact of different tree species on the hydrogen evolution performance remains unclear. In this study, various types of CWs, including carbonized poplar (PoCW), carbonized balsa (BaCW), carbonized fir (FiCW), and carbonized pine (PiCW), have been selected to investigate their electrocatalytic performance in hydrogen evolution. Among these, the PoCW exhibits superior electrocatalytic HER performance compared to the other CWs, attributed to its electrochemically active surface area, resistance, and the content of oxygen-containing functional groups. PoCW demonstrates a low overpotential of 284 mV and 356 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in alkaline freshwater and seawater, respectively. Moreover, PoCW shows long-term durability for 100 h in both alkaline freshwater and seawater. This work guides the selection of wood-based carbon monoliths and demonstrates that metal-free, CW-based self-supporting electrodes hold great potential for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution in both freshwater and seawater.</description>
      <author>Bei Li, Changshui Wang, Shuijian He, Zhenlu Liu, Chunmei Zhang, Zhiqiang Sun, Haoqi Yang, Shaoju Jian, Qian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing porous electrocatalysts to minimize overpotential for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05348f</link>
      <description>Takahiro Ami, Kouki Oka, Hitoshi Kasai, Tatsuo Kimura, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404962640

                The development of electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the most critical issues for improving the efficiency of electrochemical water-splitting, which can produce green hydrogen energy without...</description>
      <author>Takahiro Ami, Kouki Oka, Hitoshi Kasai, Tatsuo Kimura</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05348f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Interactive Ir Atoms into Titanium Oxide Lattice for Proton Exchange Membrane Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407386</link>
      <description>Li Yang, Guoxiang Zhao, Shouwei Zuo, Linrui Wen, Qiao Liu, Chen Zou, Yuanfu Ren, Yoji Kobayashi, Hua Bing Tao, Deyan Luan, Kuo-Wei Huang, Luigi Cavallo, Huabin Zhang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404978001

                Abstract Iridium (Ir)&#8208;based oxide is the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art electrocatalyst for acidic water oxidation, yet it is restricted to a few Ir&#8208;O octahedral packing modes with limited structural flexibility. Herein, the geometric structure diversification of Ir is achieved by integrating spatially correlated Ir atoms into the surface lattice of TiO 2 and its booting effect on oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is investigated. Notably, the resultant i &#8208;Ir/TiO 2 catalyst exhibits much higher electrocatalytic activity, with an overpotential of 240 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and excellent stability of 315 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in acidic electrolyte. Both experimental and theoretical findings reveal that flexible Ir&#9472;O&#9472;Ir coordination with varied geometric structure plays a crucial role in enhancing OER activity, which optimize the intermediate adsorption by adjusting the d &#8208;band center of active Ir sites. Operando characterizations demonstrate that the interactive Ir&#9472;O&#9472;Ir units can suppress over&#8208;oxidation of Ir, effectively widening the stable region of Ir species during the catalytic process. The proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, equipped with i &#8208;Ir/TiO 2 as an anode, gives a low driving voltage of 1.63 V at 2 A cm &#8722;2 and maintains stable performance for over 440 h. This work presents a general strategy to eliminate the inherent geometric limitations of IrO x species, thereby inspiring further development of advanced catalyst designs.</description>
      <author>Li Yang, Guoxiang Zhao, Shouwei Zuo, Linrui Wen, Qiao Liu, Chen Zou, Yuanfu Ren, Yoji Kobayashi, Hua Bing Tao, Deyan Luan, Kuo-Wei Huang, Luigi Cavallo, Huabin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Origin of Surface Reconstruction via Oxygen Termination and Improved Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07462a</link>
      <description>Kishan H. Mali, Rushikesh Pokar, Alpa Dashora, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404978607

                The details of the catalyst surface including description of active sites and presence of surface termination groups and their distribution are the root behind the overall catalytic activity. Surface reconstruction...</description>
      <author>Kishan H. Mali, Rushikesh Pokar, Alpa Dashora</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07462a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cef3-Accelerated Surface Reconstruction of Moo&#8322; Nanosheets into 3d Coral-Like Cef&#8323;/Moo&#8322; Composites Enhances the Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5043302</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Xianglin Qiu, Chenglin Liu, Tianshuo Zhang, Shanshan Gao, Xiaoming Song, Fushan Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404984793

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Xianglin Qiu, Chenglin Liu, Tianshuo Zhang, Shanshan Gao, Xiaoming Song, Fushan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5043302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional TiO2 nanobelt array with disordered surface and oxygen vacancies for boosted photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03722g</link>
      <description>Ming Meng, Hucheng Zhou, Weifeng Liu, Jing Yang, Honglei Yuan, Zhixing Gan, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404985039

                The exploitation of the photoelectrode materials with high-efficiency utilization of solar light, outstanding separation property of photogenerated charges and a large surface area is extremely meaningful yet significantly challenging. Herein,...</description>
      <author>Ming Meng, Hucheng Zhou, Weifeng Liu, Jing Yang, Honglei Yuan, Zhixing Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03722g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Porous Y&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;MnO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/Carbon Heterostructures with Abundant Oxygen Vacancies for High-Efficiency and Ultrastable Zinc-Ion Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18461</link>
      <description>Yibo Zhang, Zhihua Li, Bo Zhao, Ziteng Guo, Qianqian Shi, Kang Xie, Sheng Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404992203

                Manganese oxides have been considered as the most competitive cathode materials for aqueous zinc-ion batteries (ZIBs) on account of their inherent safety, high operating voltage, environmental friendliness, and cost-effectiveness. Unfortunately, the manganese dissolution, inherently poor electronic conductivity, and the sluggish reaction kinetics of commercial manganese-based oxides severely hinder their practical applications. To address the above issues, we creatively developed hierarchical porous Y</description>
      <author>Yibo Zhang, Zhihua Li, Bo Zhao, Ziteng Guo, Qianqian Shi, Kang Xie, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of &#945;-FeOOH in KOH Electrolytes on the Activity of NiO Electrodes in Alkaline Water Electrolysis for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120870</link>
      <description>Tae Hyun Kim, Jae-Hee Jeon, Jieun Kim, Kyoung-Soo Kang, Jaekyung Yoon, Chu-Sik Park, Kwangjin Jung, Taeyang Han, Hyojin Lee, Hyunku Joo, Hyunjoon Lee, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404994505

                Iron cation impurities reportedly enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity of Ni-based catalysts, and the enhancement of OER activity by Fe cations has been extensively studied. Meanwhile, Fe salts, such as iron hydroxide and iron oxyhydroxide, in the electrolyte improve the OER performance, but the distinct roles of Fe cations and Fe salts have not been fully clarified or differentiated. In this study, NiO electrodes were synthesized, and their OER performance was evaluated in KOH electrolytes containing goethite (&#945;-FeOOH). Unlike Fe cations, which enhance the performance via incorporation into the NiO structure, &#945;-FeOOH boosts OER activity by adsorbing onto the electrode surface. Surface analysis revealed trace amounts of &#945;-FeOOH on the NiO surface, indicating that physical contact alone enables &#945;-FeOOH to adsorb onto NiO. Moreover, interactions between &#945;-FeOOH and NiO were observed, suggesting their potential role in OER activity enhancement. These findings suggest that Fe salts in the electrolyte influence OER performance and should be considered in the development of OER electrodes.</description>
      <author>Tae Hyun Kim, Jae-Hee Jeon, Jieun Kim, Kyoung-Soo Kang, Jaekyung Yoon, Chu-Sik Park, Kwangjin Jung, Taeyang Han, Hyojin Lee, Hyunku Joo, Hyunjoon Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cnts Entangled Nise2 with S Doping and Se Vacancy for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5043962</link>
      <description>Xuemei Han, Qian Han, Yunfan Zhao, Jianfeng Ji, Zhichao Cao, Ping Zhu, Xinsheng Zhao, Sa Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404997849

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuemei Han, Qian Han, Yunfan Zhao, Jianfeng Ji, Zhichao Cao, Ping Zhu, Xinsheng Zhao, Sa Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5043962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of H2O2 in Near&#8208;Neutral Zn&#8208;air Batteries Enables Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418792</link>
      <description>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405000839

                Rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) with near&#8208;neutral electrolytes hold promise as cheap, safe and sustainable devices, but they suffer from slow charge kinetics and remain poorly studied. Here we reveal a charge storage mechanism of near&#8208;neutral Zn&#8208;air batteries that is mediated by formation of dissolved hydrogen peroxide upon cell discharge and its oxidation upon charge. This H2O2&#8208;mediated pathway facilitates oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at ~1.5 V vs. Zn2+/Zn, reducing charge overpotentials by ~0.2&#8211;0.5 V and mitigating carbon corrosion &#8212; a common issue in ZABs. The manifestation of this mechanism strongly depends on the electrolyte composition and positive electrode material, contributing up to ~60% of the capacity with ZnSO4 solutions and carbon nanotubes. Enhancing the H2O2&#8208;mediated pathway offers a route to higher energy efficiency and durability in near&#8208;neutral ZABs, advancing practical, sustainable energy storage.</description>
      <author>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of H2O2 in Near&#8208;Neutral Zn&#8208;air Batteries Enables Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418792</link>
      <description>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405000859

                Rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) with near&#8208;neutral electrolytes hold promise as cheap, safe and sustainable devices, but they suffer from slow charge kinetics and remain poorly studied. Here we reveal a charge storage mechanism of near&#8208;neutral Zn&#8208;air batteries that is mediated by formation of dissolved hydrogen peroxide upon cell discharge and its oxidation upon charge. This H2O2&#8208;mediated pathway facilitates oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at ~1.5 V vs. Zn2+/Zn, reducing charge overpotentials by ~0.2&#8211;0.5 V and mitigating carbon corrosion &#8212; a common issue in ZABs. The manifestation of this mechanism strongly depends on the electrolyte composition and positive electrode material, contributing up to ~60% of the capacity with ZnSO4 solutions and carbon nanotubes. Enhancing the H2O2&#8208;mediated pathway offers a route to higher energy efficiency and durability in near&#8208;neutral ZABs, advancing practical, sustainable energy storage.</description>
      <author>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Ratio of Metallic and Single-Atom Co in CoNC via Annealing Temperature Modulation for Enhanced Bifunctional Oxygen Evolution Reaction/Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235721</link>
      <description>H. Y. Cheng, Haojie Sun, Meizhen Dai, Yucai Li, Jian Wang, Shiwei Song, Dong Zhang, Depeng Zhao, Molecules. 29(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405002320

                Developing low-cost, efficient alternatives to catalysts for bifunctional oxygen electrode catalysis in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical for advancing the practical applications of alkaline fuel cells. In this study, Co particles and single atoms co-loaded on nitrogen-doped carbon (CoNC) were synthesized via pyrolysis of a C3N4 and cobalt nitrate mixture at varying temperatures (900, 950, and 1000 &#176;C). The pyrolysis temperature and precursor ratios were found to significantly influence the ORR/OER performance of the resulting catalysts. The optimized CoNC-950 catalyst demonstrated exceptional ORR (E1/2 = 0.85 V) and OER (Ej10 = 320 mV) activities, surpassing commercial Pt/C + RuO2-based devices when used in a rechargeable zinc&#8211;air battery. This work presents an effective strategy for designing high-performance non-precious metal bifunctional electrocatalysts for alkaline environments.</description>
      <author>H. Y. Cheng, Haojie Sun, Meizhen Dai, Yucai Li, Jian Wang, Shiwei Song, Dong Zhang, Depeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29235721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis, Structure, Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) and Visible - light Assisted Organic Reaction Studies on A2M2TeB2O10 (A = Ba, Pb; M = Mg, Zn, Co, Ni, Cu, Fe)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02706j</link>
      <description>Srinivasan Natarajan, Indrani. G. Shanmugapriya, Shreenibasa Sa, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405003413

                Compounds with the general formula A2M2TeB2O10 (A = Ba, Pb; M = Mg, Zn, Co, Ni, Cu, Fe) have been prepared by solid state techniques and characterised. The structure has...</description>
      <author>Srinivasan Natarajan, Indrani. G. Shanmugapriya, Shreenibasa Sa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02706j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic properties of ultrathin FeSe2/Ni0&#183;85Se heterostructure hollow nanobelts for oxygen evolution in alkaline water and simulated seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.479</link>
      <description>Wenyue Jiang, Bingxin Zhao, Ziting Li, Peng Zhou, Xiaoshuang Chen, Jinping Wang, Rui Yang, Chunling Zuo, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 97(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405003420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenyue Jiang, Bingxin Zhao, Ziting Li, Peng Zhou, Xiaoshuang Chen, Jinping Wang, Rui Yang, Chunling Zuo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus-oxygen bonded CoZn catalysts for efficiently boosting oxygen evolution activity of BiVO4 photoanodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.435</link>
      <description>Xiaojiao Shao, Xiao Jia, Hualin Wu, Houyu Fu, Faqi Zhan, Y. Zhang, Fucheng Yu, Z Bian, Xiang Cheng, Chenchen Feng, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 97(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405003524

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojiao Shao, Xiao Jia, Hualin Wu, Houyu Fu, Faqi Zhan, Y. Zhang, Fucheng Yu, Z Bian, Xiang Cheng, Chenchen Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0D-3D-1D nanoarchitectured CQDs modified NiFe layered double hydroxides supported with MWCNTs: Enhanced electrocatalytic performance for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.474</link>
      <description>Kannankuzhiyil Surjith, Dinesh Harsha, Ramakrishnan Vishnuraj, Murali Rangarajan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 97(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405003525

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kannankuzhiyil Surjith, Dinesh Harsha, Ramakrishnan Vishnuraj, Murali Rangarajan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.474</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Ru&#8208;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Single Atoms Regulate the Charge Redistribution at Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/FeSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Interface for Improved Overall Water Splitting in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402558</link>
      <description>Linke Guo, Tianpeng Liu, Zhang Le, Mengyao Ma, Peng Gao, Dong Cao, Daojian Cheng, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405004863

                Abstract Developing low&#8208;cost, highly active, and stable bifunctional catalysts is of great significance for electrochemical water splitting. Herein, novel Ru&#8208;O 3 Se 4 single atoms doped Ni 3 Se 2 /FeSe 2 interface catalyst is fabricated by a two&#8208;step method for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Notably, Ru&#8208;Ni 3 Se 2 /FeSe 2 nanosheets exhibit excellent HER (43 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and OER (283 mV@100 mA cm &#8722;2 ) activities in alkaline solution. In particular, the mass activity of Ru&#8208;Ni 3 Se 2 /FeSe 2 catalyst is 3593.61 mA mg Ru &#8722;1 at 200 mV for HER and 7073.80 mA mg Ru &#8722;1 at 400 mV for OER, which is 25.91 and 367.28 times of commercial Pt/C and RuO 2 , respectively. In situ spectroscopy techniques confirm Ru&#8208;O 3 Se 4 single atoms facilitate the adsorption of intermediates H * and OOH * during HER and OER processes, respectively. Further density functional theory calculations reveal introducing Ru&#8208;O 3 Se 4 single atoms causes the transfer of electrons from Ru to Ni and Fe atoms, leading to a redistribution of charge at the Ni 3 Se 2 /FeSe 2 interface, thus reducing the energy barriers of rate&#8208;determining step to &#8722;0.37 and 1.92 eV for HER and OER, respectively. This work emphasizes the significant role of single atoms at the interface for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Linke Guo, Tianpeng Liu, Zhang Le, Mengyao Ma, Peng Gao, Dong Cao, Daojian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402558</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combined In Situ X&#8208;Ray Spectroscopic and Theoretical Study on Trimetal Synergistic Enhancement of Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404599</link>
      <description>Yalei Fan, Xubin Ye, Jing Zhou, Dabiao Lu, Chang&#8208;Yang Kuo, Yucheng Huang, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Youwen Long, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Zhiwei Hu, Linjuan Zhang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405005074

                Abstract Electrochemical water&#8208;splitting is vital in energy storage and conversion applications. However, the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) hinders the electrochemical water&#8208;splitting. Therefore, developing efficient catalysts and understanding the OER mechanism are highly desirable. This study successfully synthesized a new quadruple perovskite oxide CaCu 3 Co 2 Ru 2 O 12 (CCCRO) catalyst exhibiting high OER activity with overpotential 198 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , a Tafel slope of 37 mV dec &#8722;1 , and long&#8208;term operational stability with a current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for &gt;500 h. The in situ X&#8208;ray absorption near&#8208;edge structure (XANES) indicated that a part of high&#8208;spin (HS) Co 3+ ions and low&#8208;spin (LS) Ru 5+ ions transitioned to the tetravalent Co (IV) and hexavalent Ru (VI) valence states under OER. However, the Cu 2+ valence state remained unchanged. Furthermore, the density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the lattice&#8208;oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) rather than conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) is responsible for high OER activity in Ru (VI)&#8208;O&#8208;Co (IV) network, and that the Cu(A&#8217;)/Co(B)/Ru(B&#8217;) three sites synergistically facilitate the OER activity for CCCRO.</description>
      <author>Yalei Fan, Xubin Ye, Jing Zhou, Dabiao Lu, Chang&#8208;Yang Kuo, Yucheng Huang, Ting&#8208;Shan Chan, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Youwen Long, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Zhiwei Hu, Linjuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bias&#8208;Free Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation Coupled with Electrochemical Oxygen Reduction Reaction via Fe&#8208;Based Electrodes with Long&#8208;Term Operation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418670</link>
      <description>Haojie Chen, Zehua Gao, Nhat Truong Nguyen, Zilong Li, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405005219

                Abstract Photoelectrochemistry (PEC) is a green and sustainable approach in the synthesis of H 2 O 2 , depending on the semiconductor to initiate two&#8208;electron water oxidation into hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ). However, the photoanodes generally have sluggish charge transfer and a limited number of active sites, which limit the yield and faradaic efficiency (FE) for the production of H 2 O 2 . Herein, Ti&#8208;doped Fe 2 O 3 photoanode with the modification of ZnO passivation layer (ZnO/Ti&#8208;Fe 2 O 3 ) for PEC H 2 O 2 production is developed. The optimized photoanode has shown a high FE and selectivity for two&#8208;electron water oxidation, achieving a yield approaching 0.56 &#181;mol min &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V RHE and an average FE over 80% in the potential range from 1.0 to 1.6 V RHE . Impressively, an unassisted PEC system is designed to generate H 2 O 2 at the ZnO/Ti&#8208;Fe 2 O 3 photoanode while performing an oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at the Fe(Co)&#8208;NC cathode. The integrated system enables the average PEC H 2 O 2 production rate of 0.275 &#181;mol min &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 without applying any additional bias. Moreover, an unassisted PEC cell obtains a long&#8208;term stability of 100 h. This work demonstrates new possibilities in designing efficient and stable PEC assemblies using low&#8208;cost earth&#8208;abundant materials for light&#8208;driven catalysis.</description>
      <author>Haojie Chen, Zehua Gao, Nhat Truong Nguyen, Zilong Li, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418670</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation in Spin State of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Decorated Fe Single Atom Enables a Superior Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Battery Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414801</link>
      <description>Yuhua Xie, Yu&#8208;Mei Feng, Shiao Zhu, Yingjie Yu, Haifeng Bao, Qingting Liu, Fang Luo, Zehui Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405005543

                Abstract High&#8208;performance bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is the keystone for the industrialization of rechargeable zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB). In this work, the modulation in the spin state of Fe single atom on nitrogen doped carbon (Fe 1 &#8208;NC) is devised by Co 3 O 4 (Co 3 O 4 @Fe 1 &#8208;NC), and a mediate spin state is recorded. Besides, the d band center of Fe is downshifted associated with the increment in e g filling revealing the weakened interaction with OH * moiety, resulting in a boosted ORR performance. The ORR kinetic current density of Co 3 O 4 @Fe 1 &#8208;NC is 2.0&#8208; and 5.6 times higher than Fe 1 &#8208;NC and commercial Pt/C, respectively. Moreover, high spin state is found for Co in Co 3 O 4 @Fe 1 &#8208;NC contributing to the accelerated surface reconstruction of Co 3 O 4 witnessed by operando Raman and electrochemical impedance spectroscopies. A robust OER activity with overpotential of 352 mV at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 is achieved, decreased by 18 and 60 mV by comparison with Co 3 O 4 @NC and IrO 2 . The operando Raman reveals a balanced adsorption of OH * species and its deprotonation leading to robust stability. The ZAB performance of Co 3 O 4 @Fe 1 &#8208;NC is 193.2 mW cm &#8722;2 and maintains for 200 h. Furthermore, the all&#8208;solid&#8208;state ZAB shows a promising battery performance of 163.1 mW cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Yuhua Xie, Yu&#8208;Mei Feng, Shiao Zhu, Yingjie Yu, Haifeng Bao, Qingting Liu, Fang Luo, Zehui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Hybrid Electrocatalysts; Materials Description and Mechanistic Aspects Toward Hydrogen Production, Oxygen Evolution&#8208;Reduction, and CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400166</link>
      <description>Aneela Tahira, Mohsen Padervand, Elmuez A. Dawi, Umair Aftab, Shahnaz Ghasemi, Brigitte Vigolo, Matteo Tonezzer, Samina Bidmeshkipour, Masoud Baghernejad, Abdelkader Labidi, &#201;ric Lichtfouse, Chuanyi Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405006035

                Abstract Controlling the adverse effects of global warming on human communities requires reducing carbon dioxide emissions and developing clean energy resources. Fossil fuel overuse damages the environment and raises sustainability concerns. As a resource&#8208;rich element, cobalt oxide hybrids have attracted considerable attention as low&#8208;priced and eco&#8208;friendly electrocatalysts. Alkaline solutions disperse Co 3 O 4 easily despite its highly stable nature, which arises from the reverse spinel structures of Co. Metal oxides, nickel foam, polymeric frameworks, and carbon nanotubes have been successfully served to combine with the Co 3 O 4 constructions for improving the electrocatalytic performance. To date, no comprehensive study has systematically investigated the relation between the cobalt oxide hybrid's physicochemical&#8208;electronic aspects and its catalytic features. This review mainly focuses on material design, fabrication, morphology, structural characteristics, and electroactivity, considering the critical factors towards practical applications. The economic impacts of the constructions and their expected contribution to large&#8208;scale utilizations are also demonstrated. Moreover, this research discusses the synergistic effects of crucial electrochemical parameters on sustainable energy production over the Co 3 O 4 &#8208;based hybrids. Finally, some beneficial conclusive suggestions are made based on emerging factors for real&#8208;world application. Future research in the field aiming at developing sustainable and clean energy production technologies can effectively benefit from the findings of this report.</description>
      <author>Aneela Tahira, Mohsen Padervand, Elmuez A. Dawi, Umair Aftab, Shahnaz Ghasemi, Brigitte Vigolo, Matteo Tonezzer, Samina Bidmeshkipour, Masoud Baghernejad, Abdelkader Labidi, &#201;ric Lichtfouse, Chuanyi Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable fabrication of FeSnO3/gCN (FSO/gCN) nanohybrid: Effective electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction in basic medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111840</link>
      <description>Rida Zahra, Soumaya Gouadria, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Gul N. Khan, Abhinav Kumar, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405010013

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rida Zahra, Soumaya Gouadria, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Gul N. Khan, Abhinav Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nixby-Coxsy, Nixby and Coxsy Electrocatalysts as Potential Anode Electrodes for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5044448</link>
      <description>Eda Akg&#252;l, Ayb&#252;ke Leba Akman, Osman Cem Alt&#305;nc&#305;, M&#252;sl&#252;m Demir, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405015412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eda Akg&#252;l, Ayb&#252;ke Leba Akman, Osman Cem Alt&#305;nc&#305;, M&#252;sl&#252;m Demir</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5044448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-optimizing Cobalt Tungsten Oxide Electrocatalysts toward Enhanced Oxygen Evolution in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vkd9h</link>
      <description>Christean Nickel, David Leander Troglauer, Zsolt Dallos, Dhouha Abid, Kevin Sowa, Magdalena Ola Cichocka, Ute Kolb, Boris Mashtakov, S.H. Han, Lijie Ci, Deping Li, Xiaohang Lin, Minghao Hua, Rongji Liu, Dandan Gao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405020407

                Self-optimizing mixed metal oxides are a novel class of electrocatalysts for the advanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, we report the self-assembled cobalt and tungsten oxide nanostructures on the lab-synthesized copper oxide substrate via a one-step deposition approach. The resulting composite demonstrates remarkable self-optimization, achieving significantly reduced overpotentials and enhanced current densities. Mechanistic investigations reveal the origins of the boosted OER performance, highlighting substantial enhancements in OER kinetics, the electrocatalytically active surface area, surface wettability, and electrical conductivity. Interfacial restructuring of the electrocatalyst under operating conditions indicates the in situ formation of oxidized cobalt species as true active sites. Complementary density functional theory (DFT) analysis demonstrates the formation of *OOH as the rate-determining step of OER, and elucidates the self-activation mechanism originating from the adaptation of adsorbed oxygen intermediates binding site from tungsten to cobalt. Our study provides a fundamental understanding of the self-optimization mechanism and advances the knowledge-driven design of efficient water-splitting electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Christean Nickel, David Leander Troglauer, Zsolt Dallos, Dhouha Abid, Kevin Sowa, Magdalena Ola Cichocka, Ute Kolb, Boris Mashtakov, S.H. Han, Lijie Ci, Deping Li, Xiaohang Lin, Minghao Hua, Rongji Liu, Dandan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vkd9h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Borate Mediator Species Enables Industrial COProduction with Improved Overall Energy Efficiency by Sustainable Molten Salt CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202406457</link>
      <description>Xinyu Li, Bowen Deng, Kaifa Du, Wenmiao Li, Di Chen, Xin Qu, Fangzhao Pang, Xiaodan Zhang, Hao Zha, Huayi Yin, Dihua Wang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405021778

                Abstract The electrochemical conversion of CO 2 into CO represents a promising strategy for mitigating excessive global greenhouse gas emissions. Nevertheless, achieving industrial&#8208;scale electrochemical CO 2 &#8208;to&#8208;CO conversion with enhanced selectivity and reduced energy consumption presents significant challenges. In this study, a borate&#8208;enhanced molten salt process for CO 2 capture and electrochemical transformation is employed, achieving over 98% selectivity for CO and over 55% energy efficiency without the necessity for complex and costly electrocatalysts. Cathodic CO 2 electro&#8208;reduction (CO 2 ER) with the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at an overall current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 using non&#8208;nanostructured transition&#8208;metal plate electrodes at 650 &#176;C is coupled. By regulating the electrolyte's oxo&#8208;basicity with earth&#8208;abundant borax (Na 2 B 4 O 7 ), a borate&#8208;enhanced electrolyte is established that accelerates the overall electrochemical reaction efficiently. This system involved a series of well&#8208;designed target borate species (BO 3 3&#8722; , BO 2 &#8722; , and B 4 O 7 2&#8722; ) that acted as mediators shuttling between the cathode and anode, favoring CO as the primary cathodic product. Manipulating the atmosphere above the anode facilitated a spontaneous transformation of borates, further enhancing OER performance with long&#8208;term operational stability over a cumulative period of 50 h, while also reducing overall energy consumption. This work presents a cost&#8208;effective strategy for the industrial&#8208;scale production of CO derived from CO 2 , contributing to a lower carbon footprint by establishing a sustainable borate&#8208;mediated closed loop.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Li, Bowen Deng, Kaifa Du, Wenmiao Li, Di Chen, Xin Qu, Fangzhao Pang, Xiaodan Zhang, Hao Zha, Huayi Yin, Dihua Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202406457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling activity-stability paradox of reconstructed NiIrOx electrocatalysts by bridged W-O moiety</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54987-4</link>
      <description>Muhammad Imran Abdullah, Fang Yu-sheng, Xiaobing Wu, Meiqi Hu, Jing Shao, Youkun Tao, Haijiang Wang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405022664

                One challenge remaining in the development of Ir-based electrocatalyst is the activity-stability paradox during acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), especially for the surface reconstructed IrOx catalyst with high efficiency. To address this, a phase selective Ir-based electrocatalyst is constructed by forming bridged W-O moiety in NiIrOx electrocatalyst. Through an electrochemical dealloying process, an nano-porous structure with surface-hydroxylated rutile NiWIrOx electrocatalyst is engineered via Ni as a sacrificial element. Despite low Ir content, NiWIrOx demonstrates a minimal overpotential of 180 mV for the OER at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2. It maintains a stable 300 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 current density during an approximately 300 h OER at 1.8 VRHE and shows a stability number of 3.9 &#215; 105 noxygen &#183; nIr&#8722;1. The resulting W &#8211; O&#8211;Ir bridging motif proves pivotal for enhancing the efficacy of OER catalysis by facilitating deprotonation of OER intermediates and promoting a thermodynamically favorable dual-site adsorbent evolution mechanism. Besides, the phase selective insertion of W-O in NiIrOx enabling charge balance through the W-O-Ir bridging motif, effectively counteracting lattice oxygen loss by regulating Ir-O co-valency. One challenge remaining in the electrocatalysts for acidic water electrolysis is the activity-stability paradox. Here, the authors report a facile approach to tackle the challenge by introducing a bridged W-O moiety in NiIrOx electrocatalyst, enhancing the efficacy and stability simultaneously.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Imran Abdullah, Fang Yu-sheng, Xiaobing Wu, Meiqi Hu, Jing Shao, Youkun Tao, Haijiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54987-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the oxygen evolution performance by introducing Pd-Cu alloy supported rod-like hollow titanium dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118844</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Mingying Zhao, Lei E, Dan Zhao, Chengyi Wang, Zhifeng Liu, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405024150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Mingying Zhao, Lei E, Dan Zhao, Chengyi Wang, Zhifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy stabilization and metal-oxygen covalency optimization strategies for enhanced oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.046</link>
      <description>Jinzhou Li, Biyun Wang, Jiancheng Wang, Yanan Dai, Xuewei Lv, Jie Dang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405030569

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinzhou Li, Biyun Wang, Jiancheng Wang, Yanan Dai, Xuewei Lv, Jie Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt oxide/Cerium oxide/Carbon Heterostructure Nanoflowers Derived from CoCe-ZIF-67 as Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.12.069</link>
      <description>Wei Ma, Meng Zhang, Zengyan Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Rongfeng Chen, Ming-Yu Qin, Lin Zhu, Yaming Wang, Xiaoxiao Huang, Feng Ming, Peigang He, Dechang Jia, Yu Zhou, Xiaoming Duan, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405035176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Ma, Meng Zhang, Zengyan Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Rongfeng Chen, Ming-Yu Qin, Lin Zhu, Yaming Wang, Xiaoxiao Huang, Feng Ming, Peigang He, Dechang Jia, Yu Zhou, Xiaoming Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.12.069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birnessite enhanced Cr(III) oxidation during subsurface geochemical processes: role of Mn(III)-induced nonphotochemical reactive oxygen species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2024.125436</link>
      <description>Yuting Zhou, Chuling Guo, Yanping Deng, Yanjun Jiang, Meiling Yin, Kai Chen, Siyu Zhang, Guining Lu, Zhi Dang, Environmental Pollution. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405035487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuting Zhou, Chuling Guo, Yanping Deng, Yanjun Jiang, Meiling Yin, Kai Chen, Siyu Zhang, Guining Lu, Zhi Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2024.125436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phytochemical-enhanced NiO nanostructures for superior oxygen evolution and asymmetric supercapacitor applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2632-959x/ad9ac0</link>
      <description>Asma Hayat, Elmuez A. Dawi, Aneela Tahira, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Imran Ali Halepoto, Gulzar Ali, Ihsan Ali Mahar, Irum Naz, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Abdul Ghaffar Solangi, Umair Aftab, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Ayman Nafady, Brigitte Vigolo, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, Nano Express. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405047254

                Abstract The development of new energy conversion and storage technologies has contributed to the widespread use of renewable energy. However, new methodologies for electrochemical energy storage systems remain to be developed. This study presents a facile, low-cost, scalable, and environmentally friendly method for the synthesis of nickel oxide (NiO) nanostructures by hydrothermal methods using lotus root extract. The different volumes of lotus root extract were tested on NiO nanostructures (sample 1, sample 2) using 1 mL and 2 mL amounts of the extract, respectively. Therefore, phytochemicals from lotus extract have influenced the surface morphology, crystal quality, optical band gap, electrical conductivity, and surface active sites of NiO nanostructures. Sample 2 of the NiO nanostructures was found to be highly active for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and showed an overpotential of 380 mV at 10 mA cm-2 and a durability of 30 hours at 10 mA cm-2. Furthermore, sample 2 of NiO has shown specific capacitance of 1503.84 F/g at 2 A/g as well as cycling stability over a period of forty thousand GCD cycles. The percentage specific capacitance retention were highly improved up to 100.6%. An asymmetric energy storage device has been constructed using NiO sample 2 as the anode electrode material, demonstrating excellent capacitance of about 700 F/g at 5 A/g. For the asymmetric supercapacitor device, a power density of 20000 W/kg and an energy density of 245 Wh/kg were obtained. In a study of cycling stability for 40000 GCD cycles, it was observed that the asymmetric device retained 96.86% of its specific capacitance. A significant contribution was made to the electrochemical performance of sample 2 of NiO by phytochemicals derived from lotus extract.</description>
      <author>Asma Hayat, Elmuez A. Dawi, Aneela Tahira, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Imran Ali Halepoto, Gulzar Ali, Ihsan Ali Mahar, Irum Naz, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Abdul Ghaffar Solangi, Umair Aftab, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Ayman Nafady, Brigitte Vigolo, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2632-959x/ad9ac0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-5 nm amorphous iridium oxide nanosheets with synergistic multi-element doping for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158213</link>
      <description>J. FENG, Shouxin Zhang, Zhen Yang, Kunyan Qian, Xin Wang, Wanqing Song, Panzhe Qiao, Jia Ding, Wenbin Hu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405048905

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J. FENG, Shouxin Zhang, Zhen Yang, Kunyan Qian, Xin Wang, Wanqing Song, Panzhe Qiao, Jia Ding, Wenbin Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials for Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3373-0669-8.ch001</link>
      <description>Fid&#226; Baragh, Abderrahim Najah Elidrissi, Houssam Amiry, Rachid Amrousse, Advances in chemical and materials engineering book series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405066380

                Achieving global decarbonization goals by 2050 hinges on green hydrogen production via water electrolysis. With increasing demand for hydrogen in renewable energy, industrial sectors, and transportation, the importance of this technology continues to grow. This chapter delves into hydrogen production fundamentals and recent advancements in water electrolysis, emphasizing its pivotal role in generating green hydrogen. Key mechanisms of water splitting, such as electrocatalysis, photocatalysis, and photoelectrolysis, are explored. Special focus is given to advanced electrocatalysts, including both noble metals and cost-effective alternatives, that enhance the hydrogen evolution and oxygen evolution reactions. Innovative photocatalytic materials, including transition metal chalcogenides and phosphides, are highlighted for their efficiency gains through heteroatom doping and cocatalyst integration. Storage solutions and hydrogen's industrial applications in sectors like energy, chemicals, and transportation are also examined, presenting a roadmap for future development.</description>
      <author>Fid&#226; Baragh, Abderrahim Najah Elidrissi, Houssam Amiry, Rachid Amrousse</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4018/979-8-3373-0669-8.ch001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conformational Flexibility of D1-Glu189: A Crucial Determinant in Substrate Water Selection, Positioning, and Stabilization within the Oxygen-Evolving Complex of Photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c09981</link>
      <description>Hiroshi Isobe, Takayoshi Suzuki, Michihiro Suga, Jian&#8208;Ren Shen, K. Yamaguchi, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405072122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hiroshi Isobe, Takayoshi Suzuki, Michihiro Suga, Jian&#8208;Ren Shen, K. Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c09981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vertically Aligned Ultrathin CoNi-LDH@NiS@MXCF Core&#8211;Shell Heterostructure for Flexible Supercapacitor Electrodes and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04103</link>
      <description>Deyang Zhang, Di Wang, Binhe Feng, Jinbing Cheng, Hailong Yan, Jin Chang, Paul K. Chu, Yongsong Luo, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405084007

                A multilayer core-shell heterostructure with CoNi-LDH as the core and NiS nanosheets as the shell is deposited on MXene-coated carbon nanofibers by electrospinning and electrochemical deposition. This unique structure not only combines highly conductive and hydrophilic one-dimensional carbon nanofibers but also exposes abundant two-dimensional reactive sites and multiple ion diffusion channels to maximize material utilization, enhance electron transfer kinetics, accelerate Faraday reaction, high capacitance and strong stability. The CNNS@MXCF electrode exhibits outstanding electrochemical characteristics, including a capacity of 1441.8 F g</description>
      <author>Deyang Zhang, Di Wang, Binhe Feng, Jinbing Cheng, Hailong Yan, Jin Chang, Paul K. Chu, Yongsong Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal-stimulated spin disordering accelerates water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee04597a</link>
      <description>Fakang Xie, Yu Du, Mengfei Lu, Shicheng Yan, Zhigang Zou, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405084239

                The sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) greatly limits the efficiency of water splitting. The high OER overpotentials would originate from the high electron transfer barriers in the...</description>
      <author>Fakang Xie, Yu Du, Mengfei Lu, Shicheng Yan, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee04597a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrPdCuFeNiCoMo Based Core&#8208;Shell Icosahedron Nanocrystals and Nanocages for Efficient and RobustAcidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419956</link>
      <description>Mairui Long, Siyuan Lai, Kanghua Miao, W. J. Fan, Xiongwu Kang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405088323

                Facets engineering of high entropy alloy (HEA) nanocrystals might be achieved via shape&#8208;controlled synthesis, which is promising but remains challenging in designing Ir&#8208;based catalysts towards efficient and robust oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic medium. Herein, icosahedra nanocrystals featured with PdCu core and IrPdCuFeNiCoMo shell were prepared by wet&#8208;chemical reduction in one&#8208;pot, ascribing to the initial formation PdCu core and subsequent deposition and diffusion of IrPdCuFeNiCoMo HEA shell. Sequential selective chemical etching of PdCu core results in IrPdCuFeNiCoMo HEA nanocages, delivering an overpotential of 235 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, 51.0 mV dec&#8722;1, and 1624 A gIr&#8722;1 at 1.50 V in a conventional three electrode cell. In a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer, it delivers a low cell voltage of 1.65 and 1.77 V at a current density of 1.0 and 2.0 A cm&#8722;2, respectively, and maintains stable over 900 h at 500 mA cm&#8722;2. Theoretical calculations attribute the enhanced intrinsic activity to the broad distribution of the binding energy for OER intermediates on IrPdCuFeNiCoMo HEA, which breaks the linear scaling relationship and accelerates the OER process.</description>
      <author>Mairui Long, Siyuan Lai, Kanghua Miao, W. J. Fan, Xiongwu Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrPdCuFeNiCoMo Based Core&#8208;Shell Icosahedron Nanocrystals and Nanocages for Efficient and RobustAcidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419956</link>
      <description>Mairui Long, Siyuan Lai, Kanghua Miao, W. J. Fan, Xiongwu Kang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405088324

                Facets engineering of high entropy alloy (HEA) nanocrystals might be achieved via shape&#8208;controlled synthesis, which is promising but remains challenging in designing Ir&#8208;based catalysts towards efficient and robust oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic medium. Herein, icosahedra nanocrystals featured with PdCu core and IrPdCuFeNiCoMo shell were prepared by wet&#8208;chemical reduction in one&#8208;pot, ascribing to the initial formation PdCu core and subsequent deposition and diffusion of IrPdCuFeNiCoMo HEA shell. Sequential selective chemical etching of PdCu core results in IrPdCuFeNiCoMo HEA nanocages, delivering an overpotential of 235 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, 51.0 mV dec&#8722;1, and 1624 A gIr&#8722;1 at 1.50 V in a conventional three electrode cell. In a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer, it delivers a low cell voltage of 1.65 and 1.77 V at a current density of 1.0 and 2.0 A cm&#8722;2, respectively, and maintains stable over 900 h at 500 mA cm&#8722;2. Theoretical calculations attribute the enhanced intrinsic activity to the broad distribution of the binding energy for OER intermediates on IrPdCuFeNiCoMo HEA, which breaks the linear scaling relationship and accelerates the OER process.</description>
      <author>Mairui Long, Siyuan Lai, Kanghua Miao, W. J. Fan, Xiongwu Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419956</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-Boosted Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution via a 2D/2D Heterostructure Constructed by Integrating Reduced Graphene Oxide on NiFe-LDH Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101619</link>
      <description>Qian Liu, Jinyi Wang, Yuxia Zhang, Wa Gao, Cui Li, Jingxiang Low, Haiming Zhang, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405095582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Liu, Jinyi Wang, Yuxia Zhang, Wa Gao, Cui Li, Jingxiang Low, Haiming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascading Water Activation and Interfacial Lattice Oxygen over Nanocluster CuOx&#8208;modified MnO2 for Electrocatalytic Propylene Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420780</link>
      <description>Ming Cheng, Jintong Lan, Xiaoxian Sun, Yinglin Wang, Ailijiang Tuerdi, Falong Jia, Yanbing Guo, Xiao Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405096696

                Direct electrooxidation of propylene using water&#8208;oxidation intermediates represents a promising route for propylene glycol production. Unfortunately, this economic and environmentally friendly process suffers from low yield and poor Faradaic efficiency resulting from the mismatched oxidative capacity of reactive oxygen species and pronounced side reactions. Herein, we developed an earth&#8208;abundant metal&#8208;based nanocluster CuOx&#8208;modified MnO2 catalyst for the efficient electrooxidation of propylene into propylene glycol, achieving a remarkable production rate of 63.0 g/m2/h and 95% Faradaic efficiency at 1.3 V vs. Ag/AgCl. Mechanistic studies revealed that the oxygen vacancy&#8208;mediated water activation on CuOx&#8208;MnO2 in synergy with the activated interfacial lattice oxygen drove the propylene oxidation to a novel *OOH pathway rather than the traditional *OH route. Additionally, the interfacial interactions intensified the propylene adsorption and polarization for its activation. This work offers new insights into the mechanism of electrocatalytic propylene oxidation and presents great opportunities for the synthesis of commercial chemicals based on earth&#8208;abundant metal catalysts and renewable electricity&#8208;driven route.</description>
      <author>Ming Cheng, Jintong Lan, Xiaoxian Sun, Yinglin Wang, Ailijiang Tuerdi, Falong Jia, Yanbing Guo, Xiao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420780</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Cr&#8722;O&#8722;Ti structure towards boosted vinyl chloride destruction: Oxygen species evolution and reaction mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124914</link>
      <description>Xu Han, Jing Wang, Mingjiao Tian, Yaruo Zhao, Dong Guo, Zeyu Jiang, Yanfei Jian, Yadi Wang, Fan Dang, Chunli Ai, Jialei Wan, Reem Albilali, Chi He, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405097401

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu Han, Jing Wang, Mingjiao Tian, Yaruo Zhao, Dong Guo, Zeyu Jiang, Yanfei Jian, Yadi Wang, Fan Dang, Chunli Ai, Jialei Wan, Reem Albilali, Chi He</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of donor doping on in situ synthesized Co(M)-NiSe2&#8211;VSe2 for battery-type supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158368</link>
      <description>Qadeer Akbar Sial, Gourab Mohapatra, Rana Basit Ali, Muhammad Waqas Khan, Muhammad Waqas, Ashish Kumar, Hyungtak Seo, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405098404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qadeer Akbar Sial, Gourab Mohapatra, Rana Basit Ali, Muhammad Waqas Khan, Muhammad Waqas, Ashish Kumar, Hyungtak Seo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling electrocatalyst reaction mechanisms in water electrolysis: &lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; Raman spectra</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232980</link>
      <description>Chao Huang, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Ping Qin, Qingdong Ruan, Dorsa Dehghan&#8208;Baniani, Xiang Peng, Babak Mehrjou, Paul K. Chu, Applied Physics Reviews. 11(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405103486

                Electrocatalysis is crucial for sustainable energy solutions, focusing on energy harvesting, storage, and pollution control. Despite the development of various electrocatalysts, understanding the dynamic processes in electrochemical reactions is still limited, hindering effective catalyst design. In situ Raman spectra have emerged as a critical tool, providing molecular-level insights into surface processes under operational conditions and discussing their development, advantages, and configurations. This review emphasizes new findings at the catalyst&#8211;electrolyte interface, especially interface water molecule state, during the hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction in recent years. Finally, the challenges and future directions for in situ Raman techniques in electrocatalysis are discussed, emphasizing their importance in advancing understanding and guiding novel catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Chao Huang, Wei&#8208;Xue Li, Ping Qin, Qingdong Ruan, Dorsa Dehghan&#8208;Baniani, Xiang Peng, Babak Mehrjou, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning on Highly Dispersed Iridium on Antimony-Doped Tin Oxide with Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interaction for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02363</link>
      <description>Inayat Ali Khan, P. Morgen, Raghunandan Sharma, Shuang Ma Andersen, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405104921

                In the present study, we used a simple and efficient microwave-assisted NaBH4 reduction method to generate unsupported and antimony-doped tin oxide (ATO)-supported metallic iridium nanoparticles (Ir-NPs). The effects of pretreatment on the support and iridium precursor oxidation state in two different salts (IrCl3&#183;nH2O and (NH4)2IrCl6) were investigated to produce efficient and stable electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic electrolysis. Electrocatalysts with an Ir loading of 40 wt % supported on pristine ATO and acid-treated ATO were synthesized, and the performance was compared with the unsupported, synthesized, and commercial electrocatalysts. The Ir-NPs loaded on the support surface with 98% reaction yield and narrow size distribution, while without the support, somewhat agglomerated Ir-NPs were generated. A strong metal&#8211;support electron interaction at the junction of the Ir support, promoting the electrocatalyst stability and activity, was achieved for the supported electrocatalysts obtained from both precursors. The best electrocatalyst has demonstrated an excellent OER activity of 597 A gIr&#8211;1 compared to that of 305 A gIr&#8211;1 for a commercial IrO2 benchmark and a high potentiodynamic accelerated stress test stability (OER activity retention: 76% compared to 31% for commercial IrO2). The superior electrochemical performance can be attributed to the prereaction strong adsorption of the iridium precursor on the support surface, resulting in postreaction highly dispersed small NPs over the support surface generating strong metal&#8211;support interaction at the junction of Ir-ATO.AT.</description>
      <author>Inayat Ali Khan, P. Morgen, Raghunandan Sharma, Shuang Ma Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of High-Entropy LDH Nanostructures to Promote Alkaline Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54026/aroic/1017</link>
      <description>Yang Li, No host. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404923921

                The development of highly active transition metal-based catalysts is a key challenge for improving the efficiency of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER). In this study, a high-entropy layered double hydroxide (HE-LDH) composed of five metals was successfully designed and synthesized using a hydrothermal method. Electrochemical performance tests comparing different metal combinations in high-entropy LDHs revealed that NiCoCuFeAl LDH exhibited an overpotential of only 389 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178;. Moreover, it demonstrated a smaller Tafel slope of 124.4 mV dec&#8315;&#185;. This superior catalytic performance is attributed to the synergistic interactions among the five metals, which optimize the electronic environment. This study offers a promising strategy for designing efficient electrocatalysts with enhanced OER performance.</description>
      <author>Yang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54026/aroic/1017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zirconium Fluoride-Supported High-Entropy Fluoride: A Catalyst for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-4f99b</link>
      <description>Christian Heinekamp, Arkendu Roy, Stephanos Karafiludis, Sourabh Kumar, Ana Guilherme Buzanich, Tomasz M. Stawski, Aist&#279; Mili&#363;t&#279;, Marcus von der Au, Mike Ahrens, Thomas Braun, Franziska Emmerling, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405081667

                Extended hydrogen initiatives promote the urgency of research on water splitting technologies and therein oxygen evolution reaction catalysts being developed. A route to access a ZrF4 supported high-entropy fluoride catalyst using a facile sol-gel route is presented. The high-entropy character of the catalyst was confirmed by scanning transmission electron microscopy and energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (STEM-EDX) as well as inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS). Additional investigations on the local structure were performed using extended X-ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy (EXAFS) and pair distribution function (PDF) analysis. The catalyst shows significant potential for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media with a current density of 100 mA cm-2 at approximately 1.60 V, thus outperforming benchmark materials such as IrO2, despite a significant reduction in electrochemical mass loading. A potential mechanism is suggested based on free energy calculation using DFT calulations.</description>
      <author>Christian Heinekamp, Arkendu Roy, Stephanos Karafiludis, Sourabh Kumar, Ana Guilherme Buzanich, Tomasz M. Stawski, Aist&#279; Mili&#363;t&#279;, Marcus von der Au, Mike Ahrens, Thomas Braun, Franziska Emmerling</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-4f99b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction mechanism on platinum dioxide surfaces based on density functional theory calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115020</link>
      <description>Xiru Cao, Zhibin Tan, Ji Chen, Changwei Pan, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404958222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiru Cao, Zhibin Tan, Ji Chen, Changwei Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.115020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Mixed Silver&#8211;Bismuth Oxides: A Robust Oxygen Evolution Catalyst Operating at Low pH and Elevated Temperatures&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07007</link>
      <description>Darcy Simondson, Manjunath Chatti, James L. Gardiner, Brittany Kerr, Dijon A. Hoogeveen, Pavel V. Cherepanov, Inga Kuschnerus, Tam D. Nguyen, Bernt Johannessen, Shery L. Y. Chang, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Rosalie K. Hocking, Alexandr N. Simonov, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404991001

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Darcy Simondson, Manjunath Chatti, James L. Gardiner, Brittany Kerr, Dijon A. Hoogeveen, Pavel V. Cherepanov, Inga Kuschnerus, Tam D. Nguyen, Bernt Johannessen, Shery L. Y. Chang, Douglas R. MacFarlane, Rosalie K. Hocking, Alexandr N. Simonov</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Catalytic Selectivity of Electron/Proton Dual&#8208;Conductive Sulfonated Polyaniline Micropore Encased IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst by Screening Effect for Oxygen Evolution of Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202412862</link>
      <description>Yuhan Shen, Shengqiu Zhao, Fanglin Wu, Hao Zhang, Liyan Zhu, Mingjuan Wu, Tian Tian, Haolin Tang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404995914

                Abstract Acidic seawater electrolysis offers significant advantages in high efficiency and sustainable hydrogen production. However, in situ electrolysis of acidic seawater remains a challenge. Herein, a stable and efficient catalyst (SPTTPAB/IrO 2 ) is developed by coating iridium oxide (IrO 2 ) with a microporous conjugated organic framework functionalized with sulfonate groups (&#8208;SO 3 H) to tackle these challenges. The SPTTPAB/IrO 2 presents a &#8208;SO 3 H concentration of 5.62 &#215; 10 &#8722;4 mol g &#8722;1 and micropore below 2 nm numbering 1.026 &#215; 10 16 g &#8722;1 . Molecular dynamics simulations demonstrate that the conjugated organic framework blocked 98.62% of Cl &#8722; in seawater from reaching the catalyst. This structure combines electron conductivity from the organic framework and proton conductivity from &#8208;SO 3 H, weakens the Cl &#8722; adsorption, and suppresses metal&#8208;chlorine coupling, thus enhancing the catalytic activity and selectivity. As a result, the overpotential for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is only 283 mV@10 mA cm &#8722;2 , with a Tafel slope of 16.33 mV dec &#8722;1 , which reduces 13.8% and 37.8% compared to commercial IrO 2 , respectively. Impressively, SPTTPAB/IrO 2 exhibits outstanding seawater electrolysis performance, with a 35.3% improvement over IrO 2 to 69 mA cm &#8722;2 @1.9 V, while the degradation rate (0.018 mA h &#8722;1 ) is only 24.6% of IrO 2 . This study offers an innovative solution for designing high&#8208;performance seawater electrolysis electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuhan Shen, Shengqiu Zhao, Fanglin Wu, Hao Zhang, Liyan Zhu, Mingjuan Wu, Tian Tian, Haolin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202412862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Intramuscular Fatty Acid Composition During Lamb Meat Storage in High Oxygen or Vacuum Packs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3920/9789086865796_160</link>
      <description>I. &#193;lvarez, J. de la Fuente, M.T. D&#305;&#769;az, Sara &#193;lvarez, C. P&#233;rez, S. Lauzurica, V. Ca&#241;eque, No host. None(None)] 2006. https://openalex.org/W4405039328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>I. &#193;lvarez, J. de la Fuente, M.T. D&#305;&#769;az, Sara &#193;lvarez, C. P&#233;rez, S. Lauzurica, V. Ca&#241;eque</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3920/9789086865796_160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Vitamin E Supplementation on Evolution of Meat Fatty Acid Composition During Storage in High Oxygen Packs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3920/9789086865796_028</link>
      <description>I. &#193;lvarez, V. Ca&#241;eque, J. de la Fuente, S. &#193;lvarez, C. P&#233;rez, S. Lauzurica, M.T. Silva, M.T. D&#305;&#769;az, No host. None(None)] 2006. https://openalex.org/W4405037494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>I. &#193;lvarez, V. Ca&#241;eque, J. de la Fuente, S. &#193;lvarez, C. P&#233;rez, S. Lauzurica, M.T. Silva, M.T. D&#305;&#769;az</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3920/9789086865796_028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Short-Term Annealing on the Thermal Stability and Microstructural Evolution of Oxygen-Free Copper Processed by High-Pressure Torsion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17235886</link>
      <description>Meshal Y. Alawadhi, Abdulkareem S. Aloraier, Ayman M. Alaskari, Abdullah A. Alazemi, Yi Huang, Materials. 17(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404960210

                This study explores the impact of short-term annealing on the thermal stability and mechanical properties of oxygen-free copper subjected to high-pressure torsion (HPT). Copper samples were deformed through HPT with varying numbers of turns at room temperature and subsequently subjected to short-term annealing at temperatures of 398 K and 423 K. Microstructural analysis revealed that annealing led to grain growth and a reduction in dislocation density, with samples processed with fewer HPT turns exhibiting more significant grain coarsening. The microhardness measurements indicated a reduction in hardness after annealing, particularly at the edges of the discs, suggesting recrystallization. Samples processed with 10 HPT turns demonstrated higher thermal stability and less grain growth compared to 1/2-turn samples. The findings suggest that post-HPT short-term annealing can be used to tailor the balance between strength and ductility in oxygen-free copper, enhancing its suitability for industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Meshal Y. Alawadhi, Abdulkareem S. Aloraier, Ayman M. Alaskari, Abdullah A. Alazemi, Yi Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17235886</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Performance of Oxygen Vacancies-Rich Moo2/Comoo4 Heterojunction Via Regulating the Electron Distribution of Mo-O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5042309</link>
      <description>Junxia Guo, Yangfan Pan, Hanming Zhang, Peng Wang, Jinfeng Sun, Jianli Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404969954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junxia Guo, Yangfan Pan, Hanming Zhang, Peng Wang, Jinfeng Sun, Jianli Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5042309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of spent Zn C dry battery powder-based composites into high-performance supercapacitor electrode materials: Tuning various metal valence state ratios to construct oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114844</link>
      <description>Pei Gao, Chenguang Zhang, Xiaodong Zhang, Shuhao Li, Xiaolan Zhao, Boxiong Shen, Journal of Energy Storage. 106(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405098850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pei Gao, Chenguang Zhang, Xiaodong Zhang, Shuhao Li, Xiaolan Zhao, Boxiong Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114844</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental Material: Fluid evolution and connections between porphyry-type and skarn-type ore in an intracontinental porphyry-skarn Cu-Au system: Evidence from apatite textures, composition, and oxygen isotopes at Dongguashan Cu-Au (Mo) deposit, eastern China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1130/gsab.s.27957036.v1</link>
      <description>Xin Xiao, et al., No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404945132

                &lt;p&gt;Tables S1&#8211;S4 and Supplemental Text S1.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Xin Xiao, et al.</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1130/gsab.s.27957036.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental Material: Fluid evolution and connections between porphyry-type and skarn-type ore in an intracontinental porphyry-skarn Cu-Au system: Evidence from apatite textures, composition, and oxygen isotopes at Dongguashan Cu-Au(-Mo) deposit, eastern China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1130/gsab.s.27957036.v2</link>
      <description>Xin Xiao, et al., No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404957765

                &lt;p&gt;Tables S1&#8211;S4 and Supplemental Text S1.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Xin Xiao, et al.</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1130/gsab.s.27957036.v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental Material: Fluid evolution and connections between porphyry-type and skarn-type ore in an intracontinental porphyry-skarn Cu-Au system: Evidence from apatite textures, composition, and oxygen isotopes at Dongguashan Cu-Au(-Mo) deposit, eastern China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1130/gsab.s.27957036</link>
      <description>Xin Xiao, et al., No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404957790

                &lt;p&gt;Tables S1&#8211;S4 and Supplemental Text S1.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Xin Xiao, et al.</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1130/gsab.s.27957036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative multi-interface engineering and dynamic iron exchange boost robust bifunctional water electrolysis at 2 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee04619f</link>
      <description>Dongyang Li, Yong Zhang, Weiqiang Xie, Qian Zhou, Yu Fang, Ying Qi, Ziyi Lian, Long Zhang, Hui Wang, Dongsheng Tang, Haiqing Zhou, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405036940

                Due to the incompatibility and inconsistence of the active species for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions, nearly all the intermetallic catalysts present superb catalytic activity for one half reaction at...</description>
      <author>Dongyang Li, Yong Zhang, Weiqiang Xie, Qian Zhou, Yu Fang, Ying Qi, Ziyi Lian, Long Zhang, Hui Wang, Dongsheng Tang, Haiqing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee04619f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zinc-Alcohol-Air Batteries with Ultra-Narrow Cyclic Voltage Windows</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee04691a</link>
      <description>Zilong Li, Shunlian Ning, Yanshuo Jin, Nan Wang, Shuhui Sun, Hui Meng, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405018041

                Optimization of the charging reaction for zinc-air batteries remains a significant challenge. Here, we report a series of zinc-alcohol-air batteries that replace the oxygen evolution reaction with more thermodynamically favorable...</description>
      <author>Zilong Li, Shunlian Ning, Yanshuo Jin, Nan Wang, Shuhui Sun, Hui Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee04691a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light-induced charge transfer from fullerene to zeolitic imidazolate framework enhance the alkaline electrocatalytic hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04236k</link>
      <description>Jun Zhang, Mengting Gao, Ying Wang, Ying Wei, Yirong Qi, Lei Zhu, Li Xu, Qunzhi Ma, Jianfeng Huang, Yongqiang Feng, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404978408

                In the process of water electrolysis, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) suffers from the high energy barrier, which has become a key factor restricting the large-scale commercial application of renewable energy...</description>
      <author>Jun Zhang, Mengting Gao, Ying Wang, Ying Wei, Yirong Qi, Lei Zhu, Li Xu, Qunzhi Ma, Jianfeng Huang, Yongqiang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04236k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; Ion-Induced Phase and Morphology Tailoring in Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;CuMoSe Nanorod Catalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04302</link>
      <description>Yanfei Ha, Tao Zhou, Zan Xu, Xiaoyu Zhu, Xuanye Chen, Zihao Wang, Yongsheng Liu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404945779

                Copper molybdenum-based selenides (CuMoSe) as promising hydrogen evolution catalysts have been widely applied in the electrocatalytic splitting of water, while their limited active sites and relatively poor oxygen evolution activity restrict their further application as effective bifunctional electrocatalysts. Here, we report a simple hydrothermal method to fabricate rodlike NiCuMoSe arrays on nickel foam (Nix&#8211;CuMoSe/NF), the morphology of which is determined by Ni2+ ions because Ni2+ can promote the growth of the rodlike structure. Furthermore, the phase transformation from CuSe to CuSe2 is triggered by adjusting the Ni2+ ion content of the growth solution. Due to the morphology control and phase component modulation, the prepared Ni2.5&#8211;CuMoSe/NF possesses effective catalytic activities of the hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction (HER/OER) with overpotentials of 89/183 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1 M KOH, and the cell (composed of Ni2.5&#8211;CuMoSe/NF as both the cathode and anode) can provide a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 at a low cell voltage of 1.50 V with a stability of 110 h. This work will advance the development of transition metal electrocatalysts for effective overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yanfei Ha, Tao Zhou, Zan Xu, Xiaoyu Zhu, Xuanye Chen, Zihao Wang, Yongsheng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current&#8208;Dependent Product Distribution and Reaction Mechanisms of Glycerol Electrooxidation on Nickel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400534</link>
      <description>Erica Ng, Camilo A. Mesa, E. Mas-Marz&#225;, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405009834

                Abstract The Glycerol Electrooxidation Reaction (GEOR) is a promising alternative to oxygen evolution in electrochemical processes like hydrogen production and CO 2 reduction. Although GEOR has attracted increasing attention, its oxidation kinetics in alkaline media are not well understood. In this study, electrochemical characterization and kinetic analysis were conducted using nickel foil as the electrocatalyst. Four galvanostatic conditions (1, 3, 5, and 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) were evaluated to study product distribution. Increasing the current density from 3 to 5 mA cm &#8722;2 led to a fivefold decrease in formate production, indicating a shift in GEOR selectivity within the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) region. At 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , formate remained as major product, followed by glycolate and glycerate, while tartronate and oxalate production were significantly inhibited, reducing the total Faradaic Efficiency (FE) by half relative to 5 mA cm &#8722;2 . Rate constants showed increased kinetics for glycerate, glycolate, oxalate, and tartronate as current increased, surpassing formate production at 5 mA cm &#8722;2 . Spectroelectrochemical measurements revealed the reaction order for GEOR (&#945; GEOR ~1) and OER (&#945; OER ~3), showing that GEOR proceeds via a more efficient oxidative pathway, requiring interaction with just one NiOOH species, while OER involves three highly oxidized Ni&#8208;species.</description>
      <author>Erica Ng, Camilo A. Mesa, E. Mas-Marz&#225;, Sixto Gim&#233;nez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Better Electrocatalysts via Ion Exchange for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417880</link>
      <description>Yu Li, Gao Chen, Liangshuang Fei, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404937747

                Abstract Green hydrogen, produced through electrocatalytic water splitting, stands as a promising clean energy source for future large&#8208;scale applications. Significant efforts have been dedicated to advancing high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction. Ion exchange, a widely adopted technology, facilitates the chemical transformation of materials by substituting the cations or anions in original electrocatalysts with guest ions. By finely tuning the atomic structure of electrocatalysts, ion exchange enables leveraging strengths and compensating for weaknesses. This review begins with an exploration of the fundamentals of water splitting and ion exchange reactions, stating the regulatory impact of ion exchange on performance. Special emphasis is placed on distinguishing the structural characteristics of different electrocatalysts in the context of ion exchange. The review also underscores the significance of reaction conditions for ion exchange, revealing their dynamic effects. Finally, the review proposes perspectives aimed at inspiring further research efforts to design novel electrocatalysts beyond applying in water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yu Li, Gao Chen, Liangshuang Fei, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417880</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Proton&#8208;Mediated Synthesis of a High&#8208;Entropy Borate Library</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414067</link>
      <description>Da Liu, Peifang Guo, Qiangqiang Wang, Xingyu Ding, Yufei He, Jin Zhou, Dalin Sun, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404900244

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy compounds (HECs) provide extensive possibilities for exploring distinctive properties and potential applications. However, most HECs reported so far are synthesized by an arduous high&#8208;temperature treatment and special equipment, which is clearly not scalable for practical application. Here a scalable room&#8208;temperature solution synthetic strategy is reported for a library of high&#8208;entropy borates with arbitrary metal component numbers from 5 to 12 up to 3302 kinds in total and more than a hundred grams per operation within one minute. In conjunction with theoretical and in situ investigations, it is uncovered that the highly local concentration of protons at ethanol/aqueous interface is favorable to the creation of a stable thermodynamic microenvironment and a desirable kinetic miscibility reservoir, thus enabling a formation of single&#8208;phase borates. With the FeCoNiMoCu high&#8208;entropy borate, it is further shows that it functions as a highly active catalyst for catalytic oxygen evolution reaction. The work opens up opportunities for the scalable synthesis of HECs for energy storage and conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Da Liu, Peifang Guo, Qiangqiang Wang, Xingyu Ding, Yufei He, Jin Zhou, Dalin Sun, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab&#8208;on&#8208;Fiber Operando Deciphering of a MOF Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411510</link>
      <description>Tiansheng Huang, Li&#8208;Peng Sun, Xiangping Li, Bai&#8208;Ou Guan, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405083950

                Abstract Despite the great success in deploying metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) as efficient electrocatalysts, the low adoption of operando methods hinders the understanding of underlying mechanism. By leveraging the subtle refractive index evolution, including both the real and the imaginary parts, an entirely new concept of a lab&#8208;on&#8208;fiber operando method and its feasibility for &#8220;pristine&#8208;immersion&#8208;operando&#8208;post analysis&#8221; of electrocatalyts are demonstrated. Concurrent collection of absorption spectra and surface plasmon resonance is achieved by engineering fiber&#8208;optic waveguides to simultaneously induce guided light attenuation and plasmonic coupling. In situ&#8208;formed Co hydroxide and oxide reactive intermediates in zeolitic imidazolate framework&#8208;67 (ZIF&#8208;67) electrocatalyst are optically identified, which shows its underlying self&#8208;reconstruction conversions at different stages during electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions, and address the gap in knowledge concerning whether ZIF&#8208;67 is a precatalyst for real catalyst production. This illuminating operando method offers intriguing opportunities to collect all the observables in a single fiber, provides an exciting potential of a new class of device with long&#8208;sought integration and miniaturization capability, and is expected to enable the electrocatalysis community to conquer challenges with conducting multimodal operando experiments outside the laboratory.</description>
      <author>Tiansheng Huang, Li&#8208;Peng Sun, Xiangping Li, Bai&#8208;Ou Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline&#8208;Amorphous Interface&#8208;Triggered Electron Redistribution on Copper(II) Sulfide@Metal (Ni, Co, and Fe) Oxyhydroxides for Ultra&#8208;Efficient Overall Water/Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403657</link>
      <description>Peng Gu, Yidong Song, Yihe Fan, Xin Meng, Lei Zhu, Guofeng Wang, Zhouguanwei Li, Heyuan Sun, Ziyu Zhao, Jinlong Zou, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404900237

                Abstract Rearranging the electronic orbitals of metal sites through interface engineering is the breakthrough for achieving high efficiencies in hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) on bimetallic catalysts. Here, via a multistep liquid&#8208;phase synthesis strategy, the crystalline&#8208;amorphous (c&#8208;a) interface is built by coating amorphous oxyhydroxide layer on the surface of crystallized copper(II) sulfide (CuS@MOOH, M = iron (Fe), cobalt (Co) and nickel (Ni)) with an internal cavity. For HER, c&#8208;a interface facilitates the electron filling of the 3d orbitals of Cu, thereby enhancing the coordination between Cu sites (Cu 2+ /Cu + ) and *H and reducing the energy barrier for *H adsorption. For OER, c&#8208;a interface triggers electronic rearrangement in the 3d orbitals of M sites, prompting electron transition from the t2g orbitals to the eg orbitals to achieve a half&#8208;filled state, optimizing the oxygen&#8208;intermediates adsorption on M sites (M 3+ /M 4+ ). Among CuS@MOOH, the as&#8208;marked CuS@CoOOH&#8208;6 exhibits the best activities with ultra&#8208;low overpotentials of 62 mV (HER) and 136 mV (OER). Only 1.52 V is sufficient to power the electrolyzer with CuS@CoOOH&#8208;6&#8208;based cathode/anode, maintaining a ultra&#8208;stable efficiency (96.9 %) over 72 h. Notably, CuS@CoOOH&#8208;6 also exhibits impressive activity/durability for natural seawater electrolysis. This study enhances understanding of the properties and electronic structure of the c&#8208;a interface for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Peng Gu, Yidong Song, Yihe Fan, Xin Meng, Lei Zhu, Guofeng Wang, Zhouguanwei Li, Heyuan Sun, Ziyu Zhao, Jinlong Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ELECTROCHEMICAL DEPOSITION OF NANOCRYSTALLINE NICKEL&#8211;CERIUM DIOXIDE COMPOSITE FROM A DEEP EUTECTIC SOLVENT TO FABRICATE ELECTROCATALYSTS FOR HYDROGEN ENERGY</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37827/ntsh.chem.2024.75.161</link>
      <description>V. S. Protsenko, O.D. Sukhatskyi, T.E. Butyrina, Proceedings of the Shevchenko Scientific Society Series &#1057;hemical sciences. 2024(75)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404892819

                This study reports the patterns of electroplating a composite coating containing phases of nanocrystalline metallic nickel and cerium dioxide from an electrolyte based on a new generation of ionic liquids, deep eutectic solvents (DESs). Currently, the use of DESs is an extremely promising direction for the electrochemical deposition of electrocatalytic coatings for electrochemical energy, particularly for "green" hydrogen energy. The electrolyte for deposition contained a liquid eutectic mixture of choline chloride and urea (the so-called "reline", a typical representative of DESs), in which nickel (II) chloride (0.1 mol/dm&#179;) and cerium (III) chloride (0.2&#8211;0.4 mol/dm3) were dissolved. According to the results of energy-dispersive X-ray analysis and XRD investigations, the composite coating contains approximately 12&#8211;16 at.% cerium, presumably in the form of cerium dioxide. A reaction scheme for the formation of the composite nanocoating, which includes a combination of chemical and electrochemical stages, is proposed. It was found that the incorporation of cerium oxide leads to a significant increase in electrocatalytic activity (compared to nickel coating) in the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction and anodic oxygen evolution and urea oxidation reactions. It is hypothesized that the observed enhancement in electrocatalytic effect is due to the formation of additional active catalytic sites on the surface containing cerium in different oxidation states (e.g., Ce(+4)/Ce(+3)), which can act as electron carriers in both cathodic and anodic reactions. A significant advantage of this composite is its bifunctionality as an electrocatalyst, meaning it can be used for both cathodic and anodic processes. The obtained results can be used in the development of new high-efficiency processes for the electrochemical synthesis of "green" hydrogen.</description>
      <author>V. S. Protsenko, O.D. Sukhatskyi, T.E. Butyrina</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37827/ntsh.chem.2024.75.161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Aluminum Doping Effects of In&#8208;Situ Transmogrified Dual&#8208;LDH Heterostructure and Its Fermi&#8208;Level Alignment to Water Splitting Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403889</link>
      <description>Nandapriya Manivelan, JunJi Piao, Jaekook Kim, Seunghwa Lee, Youngji Kim, Vaiyapuri Soundharrajan, Min&#8208;Kyu Son, Amir Humayun, Masoud Darvish Ganji, Hyunseok Ko, Kandasamy Prabakar, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405006357

                Abstract The layered double hydroxide (LDH) captivates the starlight of electrochemical water&#8208;splitting applications due to its stacked layers and larger surface area. A novel approach is reported to integrate CoFe&#8208;LDH/NiAl&#8208;LDH heterostructure through a single&#8208;step in situ transmogrification, harnessing the benefits of LDH. The in situ Raman spectroscopy reveals that aluminum (Al) doping promotes the formation of high&#8208;valent Co III/IV &#8208;O active species concentration in LDH, whereas without Al dopants, the catalyst predominantly exhibit Ni II/III &#8208;O species and underperform the catalytic activity. The projected density of states is very close to the Fermi level positions in Al&#8208;doped samples which significantly enhance the electron transfer processes. The Mott&#8211;Schottky studies confirm that both Al40 CoFe30 and Al60 CoFe20 catalysts are p&#8208;type semiconductors, exhibiting a distinct redox behaviors under applied bias. At positive bias, Al60 CoFe20 undergoes downward band bending (accumulation), and align the Fermi&#8208;level near the water oxidation potential, which promotes the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The negative bias causes upward band bending (deep depletion) in the Al40 CoFe30, and shifts the Fermi&#8208;level near the water reduction potential, and hence facilitates hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Overall, this study highlights the importance of manipulating Fermi&#8208;level alignment in LDH catalysts through strategic metal doping to achieve targeted water&#8208;splitting reactions.</description>
      <author>Nandapriya Manivelan, JunJi Piao, Jaekook Kim, Seunghwa Lee, Youngji Kim, Vaiyapuri Soundharrajan, Min&#8208;Kyu Son, Amir Humayun, Masoud Darvish Ganji, Hyunseok Ko, Kandasamy Prabakar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Calcination Temperature on the Transformation of Spent NCM811 into Efficient TMO Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5464212/v1</link>
      <description>Haeseong Jang, Hyeeun Kim, Seongkwan Kim, Minho Kim, Chihyun Hwang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404923105

                Abstract The expansion of electric vehicles has increased spent lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) containing valuable transition metals. Recycling these materials reduces economic costs and addresses resource shortages. Additionally, transition metal-based catalysts derived from spent LIBs can replace expensive noble metal catalysts. This study examines the catalytic performance of spent LiNi0.8Co0.1Mn0.1O2 (NCM811) materials, enhanced by adjusting mixed valence states and defect structures. Increasing calcination temperature transformed the layered structure into spinel and rock salt phases, inducing mixed valence states. Consequently, the optimized NCM catalysts exhibited improved catalytic activity in both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The ORR onset potential increased by 0.07 V, while the OER overpotential decreased by about 26.9%. In a zinc-air battery, the optimized catalyst demonstrated a discharge capacity of 792.1 mAh g&#8315;&#185; and stable performance over 100 cycles. Operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) confirmed Mn as the main active site, with Ni and Co enhancing Mn's activity as electron donors and acceptors. These findings suggest that calcination-induced structural changes and mixed valence states enhance Mn site reactivity, improving catalytic performance. Overall, this study highlights the feasibility of repurposing spent LIB cathode materials into efficient electrocatalysts, thereby improving the economic viability and sustainability of catalyst development.</description>
      <author>Haeseong Jang, Hyeeun Kim, Seongkwan Kim, Minho Kim, Chihyun Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5464212/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Knowledge-Based Molecular Single-Source Precursor Approach to Nickel Chalcogenide Precatalysts for Electrocatalytic Water, Alcohol, and Aldehyde Oxidations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c08058</link>
      <description>Basundhara Dasgupta, Shenglai Yao, Indranil Mondal, Stefan Mebs, Johannes Schmidt, Konstantin Laun, Ingo Zebger, Holger Dau, Matthias Drie&#223;, Prashanth W. Menezes, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404946539

                The development and comprehensive understanding of nickel chalcogenides are critical since they constitute a class of efficient electro(pre)catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and value-added organic oxidations. This study introduces a knowledge-based facile approach to analogous NiE (E = S, Se, Te) phases, originating from molecular &#946;-diketiminato [Ni2E2] complexes and their application for OER and organic oxidations. The recorded activity trends for both target reactions follow the order NiSe &gt; NiS &gt; NiTe. Notably, NiSe displayed efficient performance for both OER and the selective oxidation of benzyl alcohol and 5-hydroxymethylfurfural, exhibiting stability in OER for 11 days under industrially pertinent conditions. Comprehensive analysis, including quasi in situ X-ray absorption and Raman spectroscopy, in combination with several ex situ techniques, revealed a material reconstruction process under alkaline OER conditions, involving chalcogen leaching. While NiS and NiSe experienced full chalcogen leaching and reconstruction into NiIII/IV oxyhydroxide active phases with intercalated potassium ions, the transformation of NiTe is incomplete. This study highlights the structure&#8211;activity relationship of a whole series of analogous nickel chalcogenides, directly linking material activity to the availability of active sites for catalysis. Such findings hold great promise for the development of efficient electrocatalysts for a wide range of applications, impacting various industrial processes and sustainable energy solutions.</description>
      <author>Basundhara Dasgupta, Shenglai Yao, Indranil Mondal, Stefan Mebs, Johannes Schmidt, Konstantin Laun, Ingo Zebger, Holger Dau, Matthias Drie&#223;, Prashanth W. Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c08058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis degradation of biochemical tail water from coking wastewater using particle electrode with persulphate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/09593330.2024.2433729</link>
      <description>Haoran Lu, Xinyu You, Tong Yang, Zheng Zhu, Xu Han, Wenyan Liang, Environmental Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404906477

                Due to the intricate composition and recalcitrant nature of coking wastewater, the biochemical effluent often fails to meet standards. This study explored the preparation of particle electrodes, utilizing activated carbon powder (PAC) loading single-element Fe, Co, and Ni, as well as dual-element Ni&#8211;Fe and Co&#8211;Fe as catalyst. The particle electrode system was integrated with persulphate (PS) activation to enhance its performance. The effects of potassium persulphate (KPS) dosages, currents, and Ni:Fe ratios were investigated. The results showed that bimetallic particle electrodes outperformed their monometallic particle electrodes. Among the five electrode materials, Ni&#8211;Fe/PAC achieved the best degradation efficiency of 84.4% and the lowest energy consumption of 19.73 kW&#183;h&#183;kg&#8722;1 COD. When the initial concentrations of TOC and COD were set at 300 and 280 mg L&#8722;1, the Ni&#8211;Fe/PAC with 5 mmol L&#8722;1 KPS achieved removal efficiencies of 61.7 and 84.4%, respectively. The metals on Ni/PAC and Co/PAC existed in the zero-valent state, while Fe on Fe/PAC was present as Fe2O3. Co&#8211;Fe/PAC exhibited the formation of CoFe2O4 oxides. Ni&#8211;Fe/PAC possessed the lowest hydrogen evolution reaction potential (&#8722;0.28 V), and the highest oxygen evolution potential (2.4 V), and reached an electrochemical active surface area (ECSA) of 236.3 cm2. Cyclic voltammetry (CV) curves indicated that the direct redox reactions and indirect oxidation of pollutants occurred concurrently. Both &#8226;OH and &#8901;SO4&#8722; radicals played crucial roles during the degradation processes. The degradation efficiency of organic matter was as follows: benzene compounds (88.4%) &gt;heterocyclic compounds (75.3%) &gt;polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (53.9%).</description>
      <author>Haoran Lu, Xinyu You, Tong Yang, Zheng Zhu, Xu Han, Wenyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/09593330.2024.2433729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Electron Transfer Direction&#8208;Tuned Urea Electrooxidation Over Multi&#8208;Interface Nickel Sulfide Heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408908</link>
      <description>Xingyu Guo, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhengrong Xu, Liu Deng, Aiguo Kong, Lei Zhu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405084764

                Abstract Hydrogen can be produced by electrolyzing urea aqueous solution under smaller overpotentials, owing to the lower thermodynamic potential of urea oxidation reaction (UOR) at anode than oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The efficient and selective electrocatalysts for UOR are crucial to achieve this. Herein, two NiS&#8208;based NiS/Ni 3 S 2 and NiS/NiS 2 heterojunctions with Ni cores embedding in nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes (NiS/Ni 3 S 2 &#8208; and NiS/NiS 2 &#8208;Ni@NCNT) are demonstrated as efficient UOR electrocatalysts. The electrocatalytic UOR performance over heterojunctions is efficiently tuned by altering the electron transfer direction on their interfaces. NiS/Ni 3 S 2 &#8208;Ni@NCNT with interface electrons transferring from Ni 3 S 2 to NiS, delivers a 10 mA cm &#8722;2 UOR current density in 1.0 m KOH with 0.5 m urea at 1.37 V, superior to NiS/NiS 2 &#8208;Ni@NCNT with the electron transfer direction from NiS to NiS 2 . Experimental and theoretical calculation results reveal that NiS/Ni 3 S 2 Mott&#8211;Schottky heterojunctions facilitate the rapid in situ formation of NiOOH active species by removing electrons of Ni 3 S 2 , and also accelerate the adsorption and conversion of urea molecules and key intermediates of * CON 2 at its interfaces. This work demonstrates an interface electron transfer direction tuning strategy on heterojunctions for harvesting high&#8208;performance UOR electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xingyu Guo, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhengrong Xu, Liu Deng, Aiguo Kong, Lei Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Highly Porous Low Iridium Anode Catalysts Via Dealloying for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409386</link>
      <description>Jiashun Liang, Cehuang Fu, Sooyeon Hwang, Chaochao Dun, Liuxuan Luo, Zulipiya Shadike, Shuiyun Shen, J. Zhang, Hui Xu, Gang Wu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405083952

                Abstract Iridium (Ir) is the most active and durable anode catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). However, their large&#8208;scale applications are hindered by high costs and scarcity of Ir. Lowering Ir loadings below 1.0 mgcm &#8722;2 causes significantly reduced PEMWE performance and durability. Therefore, developing efficient low Ir&#8208;based catalysts is critical to widely commercializing PEMWEs. Herein, an approach is presented for designing porous Ir metal aerogel (MA) catalysts via chemically dealloying IrCu alloys. The unique hierarchical pore structures and multiple channels of the Ir MA catalyst significantly increase electrochemical surface area (ECSA) and enhance OER activity compared to conventional Ir black catalysts, providing an effective solution to design low&#8208;Ir catalysts with improved Ir utilization and enhanced stability. An optimized membrane electrode assembly (MEA) with an Ir loading of 0.5 mg Ir cm &#8722;2 generated 2.0 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.79 V, higher than the Ir black at a loading of 2.0 mg Ir cm &#8722;2 (1.63 A cm &#8722;2 ). The low&#8208;Ir MEA demonstrated an acceptable decay rate of &#8776;40 &#181;V h &#8722;1 during durability tests at 0.5 (&gt;1200 h) and 2.0 A cm &#8722;2 (400 h), outperforming the commercial Ir&#8208;based MEA (175 &#181;V h &#8722;1 at 2.0 mg Ir cm &#8722;2 ).</description>
      <author>Jiashun Liang, Cehuang Fu, Sooyeon Hwang, Chaochao Dun, Liuxuan Luo, Zulipiya Shadike, Shuiyun Shen, J. Zhang, Hui Xu, Gang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonradiative Charge Recombination Dynamics in Fully Hydroxylated Hematite Surface: A Time-Domain Ab Initio Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05933</link>
      <description>Yi Liu, Bipeng Wang, Hua Wang, Qiang Wang, Peixian Su, Zhaohui Zhou, Oleg V. Prezhdo, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404941862

                Hematite (&#945;-Fe2O3) is a typical semiconducting transition metal oxide that exhibits attractive properties for photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting and other applications. However, it has been widely reported that charge recombination in &#945;-Fe2O3 photoanodes is a serious problem, hindering further improvement in the efficiency of PEC water splitting. We used ab initio nonadiabatic molecular dynamics (NAMD) to investigate the charge recombination in bulk and surface phases of &#945;-Fe2O3. The NAMD simulations employ the decoherence-induced surface hopping (DISH) method implemented within time-dependent density functional theory. We test and demonstrate the need to incorporate both the phase-consistency correction and the all-electron calculation of the NA coupling, the latter needed for transition metals with d-shell electrons. The NAMD simulations show that the time scale of intrinsic charge recombination in bulk &#945;-Fe2O3 can reach microseconds, in accordance with the existence of long-lived photogenerated charge carriers observed in transient absorption measurements on &#945;-Fe2O3 electrodes. However, the hydroxylated iron-termination of the &#945;-Fe2O3(0001) surface, one of the most stable &#945;-Fe2O3 surfaces in aqueous solution, exhibits a much faster charge recombination, about 1 order of magnitude faster compared to bulk &#945;-Fe2O3. The key factor for the fast charge recombination in the surface can mainly be assigned to the strong fluctuations in the NAC and the energy gap between the conduction band minimum (CBM) and valence band maximum (VBM) and the quantum anti-Zeno effect. This work extends the charge recombination dynamics from bulk phase to aqueous interfacial phase of &#945;-Fe2O3, approaching the PEC reaction conditions, and thus assists in understanding of the charge dynamics underlying the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the Fe2O3&#8211;water interface and design of new efficient Fe2O3-based photoanode materials.</description>
      <author>Yi Liu, Bipeng Wang, Hua Wang, Qiang Wang, Peixian Su, Zhaohui Zhou, Oleg V. Prezhdo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Internal Radial Gradient of Chemical Abundances in
  Spiral Galaxies from CALIFA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.15327</link>
      <description>Ant&#243;nio Cardoso, O. Cavichia, M. Moll&#225;, L. S&#225;nchez-Menguiano, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404986271

                The study of chemical evolution is of paramount importance for understanding the galaxies evolution. Models and observations propose an inside-out mechanism in the formation of spiral galaxy disks implying a negative radial gradient of elemental abundances when represented in logarithmic scale. However, observed chemical abundance gradients, in some instances, deviate from a single linear negative straight line, revealing inner drops or outer flattenings, particularly in more massive galaxies. This study analyzes oxygen abundance gradients in spiral galaxies based on observations from the Calar Alto Legacy Integral Field Area (CALIFA) survey. Our focus is specifically on examining oxygen abundance gradient profiles, as obtained with data from HII regions, with a special emphasis on the inner radial gradient. We employ an automated fitting procedure to establish correlations between the physical properties of galaxies and bulges and the presence of these inner drops, seeking for potential explanations for these gradient variations. We find that the different criteria used in the literature to distinguish HII regions from other ionization sources in the galaxy, such as Active Galactic Nuclei, significantly impact the results, potentially altering abundance gradient profiles and uncovering galaxies with distinct inner drops. Additionally, we analyze the abundance radial gradients to investigate the impact of diffuse ionized gas (DIG) decontamination on oxygen abundances over the featuring inner drops. We observe that DIG, concentrated mainly in the central regions of galaxies, can modify oxygen abundance gradient profiles if left unaddressed.</description>
      <author>Ant&#243;nio Cardoso, O. Cavichia, M. Moll&#225;, L. S&#225;nchez-Menguiano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.15327</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Measurement of the Water Abundance in the Atmosphere of the Hot
  Jupiter WASP-43b with High-resolution Cross-correlation Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.17923</link>
      <description>Dare Bartelt, Megan Mansfield, Michael Line, Vivien Parmentier, Luis Welbanks, Elspeth K. H. Lee, Jorge Abril S&#225;nchez, Arjun B. Savel, Peter Smith, Emily Rauscher, Joost P. Wardenier, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404990240

                Measuring the abundances of carbon- and oxygen-bearing molecules has been a primary focus in studying the atmospheres of hot Jupiters, as doing so can help constrain the carbon-to-oxygen (C/O) ratio. The C/O ratio can help reveal the evolution and formation pathways of hot Jupiters and provide a strong understanding of the atmospheric composition. In the last decade, high-resolution spectral analyses have become increasingly useful in measuring precise abundances of several carbon- and oxygen-bearing molecules. This allows for a more precise constraint of the C/O ratio. We present four transits of the hot Jupiter WASP-43b observed between 1.45 $-$ 2.45 $\mu$m with the high-resolution Immersion GRating InfraRed Spectrometer (IGRINS) on the Gemini-S telescope. We detected H$_2$O at a signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) of 3.51. We tested for the presence of CH$_4$, CO, and CO$_2$, but we did not detect these carbon-bearing species. We ran a retrieval for all four molecules and obtained a water abundance of $\log_{10}(\text{H}_2\text{O}) = -2.24^{+0.57}_{-0.48}$. We obtained an upper limit on the C/O ratio of C/O $&lt;$ 0.95. These findings are consistent with previous observations from the Hubble Space Telescope and the James Webb Space Telescope.</description>
      <author>Dare Bartelt, Megan Mansfield, Michael Line, Vivien Parmentier, Luis Welbanks, Elspeth K. H. Lee, Jorge Abril S&#225;nchez, Arjun B. Savel, Peter Smith, Emily Rauscher, Joost P. Wardenier</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.17923</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas dynamics around a Jupiter mass planet: II. Chemical evolution of
  circumplanetary material</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.17408</link>
      <description>A. Cridland, Elena Lega, M. Benisty, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404988717

                In an ongoing effort to understand planet formation the link between the chemistry of the protoplanetary disk and the properties of resulting planets have long been a subject of interest. These connections have generally been made between mature planets and young protoplanetary disks through the carbon-to-oxygen (C/O) ratio. In a rare number of systems, young protoplanets have been found within their natal protoplanetary disks. These systems offer a unique opportunity to directly study the delivery of gas from the protoplanetary disk to the planet. In this work we post-process 3D numerical simulations of an embedded Jupiter-massed planet in its protoplanetary disk to explore the chemical evolution of gas as it flows from the disk to the planet. The relevant dust to this chemical evolution is assumed to be small, co-moving grains with a reduced dust-to-gas ratio indicative of the upper atmosphere of a protoplanetary disk. We find that as the gas enters deep into the planet's gravitational well, it warms significantly (up to $\sim 800$ K), releasing all of the volatile content from the ice phase. This change in phase can influence our understanding of the delivery of volatile species to the atmospheres of giant planets. The primary carbon, oxygen, and sulfur carrying ices: CO$_2$, H$_2$O, and H$_2$S are released into the gas phase and along with the warm gas temperatures near the embedded planets lead to the production of unique species like CS, SO, and SO$_2$ compared to the protoplanetary disk. We compute the column densities of SO, SO$_2$, CS, and H$_2$CS in our model and find that their values are consistent with previous observational studies.</description>
      <author>A. Cridland, Elena Lega, M. Benisty</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.17408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving massive stars to core collapse with GENEC: Extension of equation of state, opacities, and effective nuclear network</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451816</link>
      <description>Adam Griffiths, M. &#193;. Aloy, Rapha&#235;l Hirschi, Moritz Reichert, M. Obergaulinger, Emily E. Whitehead, S&#233;bastien Martinet, Luca Sciarini, Sylvia Ekstr&#246;m, G. Meynet, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405055206

                Stars with initial mass above roughly 8 $M_ odot $ will evolve to form a core made of iron group elements, at which point no further exothermic nuclear reactions between charged nuclei may prevent the core collapse. Electron capture, neutrino losses, and the photo-disintegration of heavy nuclei trigger the collapse of these stars. Models at the brink of core collapse are produced using stellar evolution codes, and these pre-collapse models may be used in the study of the subsequent dynamical evolution (including their explosion as supernovae and the formation of compact remnants such as neutron stars or black holes). We upgraded the physical ingredients employed by the GENeva stellar Evolution Code, GENEC, so that it covers the regime of high-temperatures and high-densities required to produce the progenitors of core-collapse. Our ultimate goal is producing pre-supernova models with GENEC, not only right before collapse, but also during the late phases (silicon and oxygen burning). We have improved GENEC in three directions: equation of state, the nuclear reaction network, and the radiative and conductive opacities adapted for the computation of the advanced phases of evolution. We produce a small grid of pre-supernova models of stars with zero age main sequence masses of $15M_ odot $, $20M_ odot $, and $25M_ odot $ at solar and less than half solar metallicities. The results are compared with analogous models produced with the MESA code. The global properties of our new models, particularly of their inner cores, are comparable to models computed with MESA and pre-existing progenitors in the literature. Between codes the exact shell structure varies, and impacts explosion predictions. Using GENEC with state-of-the-art physics, we have produced massive stellar progenitors prior to collapse. These progenitors are suitable for follow-up studies, including the dynamical collapse and supernova phases. Larger grids of supernova progenitors are now feasible, with the potential for further dynamical evolution.</description>
      <author>Adam Griffiths, M. &#193;. Aloy, Rapha&#235;l Hirschi, Moritz Reichert, M. Obergaulinger, Emily E. Whitehead, S&#233;bastien Martinet, Luca Sciarini, Sylvia Ekstr&#246;m, G. Meynet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Ion-Exchange Processes in the Synthesis of ZnS&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;@ZnO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;1&#8211;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructures from Controlled Sulfidation of ZnO Nanocrystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01892</link>
      <description>Ekaterina Bellan, Martin Jakoobi, Vincent Colli&#232;re, Yannick Coppel, Julien Tr&#233;bosc, Olivier Lafon, Pierre Lecante, Paul Fleurat&#8208;Lessard, C&#233;line Dupont, Jean&#8208;Cyrille Hierso, Pierre Fau, Katia Fajerwerg, Lauriane Pautrot&#8208;d'Alen&#231;on, Thierry Le Mercier, Myrtil L. Kahn, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404942834

                Semiconducting heterostructures are considered promising candidates for meeting specific environmental challenges, such as greener or decarbonated production of energy. However, optimizing the performance of these hybrid systems largely depends on the fine understanding of the mechanisms by which they are formed in relation to their mode of preparation. We report herein the synthesis of nanosized semiconducting heterostructures of ZnS@ZnO shell-core nature; this is from well-controlled preformed ZnO nanoparticles (NPs) modified via anion exchange process using (TMS)2S. The formation of these ZnS@ZnO heterostructures has been investigated in depth, shedding light specifically on the sulfidation mechanism and its dynamics. Our study reveals the dynamic evolution of the nanomaterial in the sulfidation process, evidencing that it is both driven by the initial presence of oxygen vacancies&#9472;acting as gateways for sulfur atoms&#9472;and also by the action in the medium of (TMS)2S, which as a sulfurizing agent behaves also as an oxygen atom extractor. The structural modification of the preformed monocrystalline ZnO nanomaterial into a polycrystalline ZnS hollow nanostructure occurs via amorphization&#8211;crystallization steps, which clearly depends on the amount of (TMS)2S in the reaction. This morphological transition to a hollow structure has been followed by multinuclear NMR spectroscopy (1H, 13C, 17O), and notably oxygen atoms at the interfaces of ZnS@ZnO heterostructures have been identified and quantified. Consistently, our study clearly establishes the link between the preparation mode of the ZnS@ZnO heterostructures and the modification of their optical band gaps as a function of their composition. The variation in optical properties, and the bowing of the band gap, depends on the sulfidation level, and this mode of sulfidation is clarified step-by-step by a DFT computational approach of surface and interface processes that is fully supported by the experimental characterization (XRD, WAXS, EDX line-analysis, HRTEM, STEM-HAADF) of these materials.</description>
      <author>Ekaterina Bellan, Martin Jakoobi, Vincent Colli&#232;re, Yannick Coppel, Julien Tr&#233;bosc, Olivier Lafon, Pierre Lecante, Paul Fleurat&#8208;Lessard, C&#233;line Dupont, Jean&#8208;Cyrille Hierso, Pierre Fau, Katia Fajerwerg, Lauriane Pautrot&#8208;d'Alen&#231;on, Thierry Le Mercier, Myrtil L. Kahn</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition to Metallic and Superconducting States Induced by Thermal or Electrical Deoxidation of the Dislocation Network in the Surface Region of SrTiO3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14231944</link>
      <description>K. Szot, Christian Rodenb&#252;cher, K. Rogacki, Gustav Bihlmayer, W. Speier, Krystian Roleder, F. Krok, H. Keller, Arndt Simon, A. Bussmann&#8208;Holder, Nanomaterials. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405003098

                The question as to why deoxidized SrTiO3&#8722;&#948; becomes metallic and superconducting at extremely low levels of oxygen vacancy concentration has been a mystery for many decades. Here, we show that the real amount of effused oxygen during thermal reduction, which is needed to induce superconducting properties, is in the range of only 1014/cm3 and thus even lower than the critical carrier concentrations assumed previously (1017&#8211;1019/cm3). By performing detailed investigations of the optical and electrical properties down to the nanoscale, we reveal that filaments are forming during reduction along a network of dislocations in the surface layer. Hence, a reduced epi-polished SrTiO3&#8722;&#948; crystal has to be regarded as a nano-composite consisting of a perfect dielectric matrix with negligible carrier density, which is short-circuited by metallic filaments with a local carrier density in the range of 1020/cm3. We present that electro-degradation leads to a more pronounced evolution of filamentary bundles and thus can generate a superconducting state with higher TC than thermal reduction. These findings indicate that traditional homogeneous models of superconductivity in self-doped SrTiO3&#8722;&#948; need to be revised, and we propose an alternative explanation taking into account the coexistence of metallic dislocation cores with polar insulating regions allowing for polaronic coupling.</description>
      <author>K. Szot, Christian Rodenb&#252;cher, K. Rogacki, Gustav Bihlmayer, W. Speier, Krystian Roleder, F. Krok, H. Keller, Arndt Simon, A. Bussmann&#8208;Holder</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14231944</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilevel Resistive Switching Dynamics by Controlling Phase and Self&#8208;Assembled Nanochannels in HfO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409798</link>
      <description>Tanmayee Parida, Minh Anh Luong, Santanu Das, A. Claverie, A. Kanjilal, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405083706

                Abstract A resistive switching device with precise control over the formation of conductive filaments (CF) holds immense potential for high&#8208;density memory arrays and atomic&#8208;scale in&#8208;memory computing architectures. While ion migration and electrochemical switching mechanisms are well understood, controlling the evolution of CF remains challenging for practical resistive random&#8208;access memory (RRAM) deployment. This study introduces a systematic approach to modulate oxygen vacancies (OV) in HfO 2 films of Ag/HfO 2 /Pt&#8208;based RRAM devices by controlling the substrate temperature. At 300 &#176;C, the HfO 2 film exhibits a dominant monoclinic phase with maximum OV concentration, which plays a key role in achieving optimal multilevel resistive switching behavior. Self&#8208;assembled nanochannels in the HfO 2 films guide CF evolution, and the diffusion of Ag at inside these films suggests a synergistic interplay between OV and Ag&#8314; ion migration for reseting the voltage&#8208;controlled resistive states. This approach addresses the endurance/retention trade&#8208;off with an impressive R on /R off ratio of &#8776;8000 while demonstrating growth temperature&#8208;driven OV modulation as a tool for multi&#8208;bit data storage. These findings provide a blueprint for developing high&#8208;performance oxide&#8208;based RRAM devices and offer valuable insights into multilevel resistive switching mechanisms, paving the way for future low&#8208;power, high&#8208;density memory technologies.</description>
      <author>Tanmayee Parida, Minh Anh Luong, Santanu Das, A. Claverie, A. Kanjilal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magma ocean evolution at arbitrary redox state</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.19137</link>
      <description>Harrison Nicholls, Tim Lichtenberg, Dan J. Bower, Raymond T. Pierrehumbert, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405030047

                Interactions between magma oceans and overlying atmospheres on young rocky planets leads to an evolving feedback of outgassing, greenhouse forcing, and mantle melt fraction. Previous studies have predominantly focused on the solidification of oxidized Earth-similar planets, but the diversity in mean density and irradiation observed in the low-mass exoplanet census motivate exploration of strongly varying geochemical scenarios. We aim to explore how variable redox properties alter the duration of magma ocean solidification, the equilibrium thermodynamic state, melt fraction of the mantle, and atmospheric composition. We develop a 1D coupled interior-atmosphere model that can simulate the time-evolution of lava planets. This is applied across a grid of fixed redox states, orbital separations, hydrogen endowments, and C/H ratios around a Sun-like star. The composition of these atmospheres is highly variable before and during solidification. The evolutionary path of an Earth-like planet at 1 AU ranges between permanent magma ocean states and solidification within 1 Myr. Recently solidified planets typically host H2O- or H2-dominated atmospheres in the absence of escape. Orbital separation is the primary factor determining magma ocean evolution, followed by the total hydrogen endowment, mantle oxygen fugacity, and finally the planet's C/H ratio. Collisional absorption by H2 induces a greenhouse effect which can prevent or stall magma ocean solidification. Through this effect, as well as the outgassing of other volatiles, geochemical properties exert significant control over the fate of magma oceans on rocky planets.</description>
      <author>Harrison Nicholls, Tim Lichtenberg, Dan J. Bower, Raymond T. Pierrehumbert</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.19137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A gravitational wave detectable candidate Type Ia supernova progenitor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.19916</link>
      <description>Emma Chickles, Kevin B. Burdge, Joheen Chakraborty, V. S. Dhillon, Paul A. Draghis, Scott A. Hughes, James Munday, S. Rappaport, J. Tonry, Evan B. Bauer, Alex Brown, N. Castro, Deepto Chakrabarty, M. Dyer, Kareem El-Badry, Anna Frebel, G&#225;bor F&#369;r&#233;sz, James A. Garbutt, Matthew Green, Aaron Householder, Dan Jarvis, Erin Kara, Mark Kennedy, P. Kerry, S. P. Littlefair, J. McCormac, Geoffrey Mo, Mason Ng, S. G. Parsons, Ingrid Pelisoli, Eleanor Pike, Thomas A. Prince, G. Ricker, Jan van Roestel, D. I. Sahman, Ken J. Shen, Robert A. Simcoe, Pier-Emmanuel Tremblay, Andrew Vanderburg, Tin Long Sunny Wong, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405033082

                Type Ia supernovae, critical for studying cosmic expansion, arise from thermonuclear explosions of white dwarfs, but their precise progenitor pathways remain unclear. Growing evidence supports the ``double-degenerate'' scenario, where two white dwarfs interact. The absence of other companion types capable of explaining the observed Ia rate, along with observations of hyper-velocity white dwarfs interpreted as surviving companions of such systems provide compelling evidence in favor of this scenario. Upcoming millihertz gravitational wave observatories like the Laser Interferometer Space Antenna (LISA) are expected to detect thousands of double-degenerate systems, though the most compact known candidate Ia progenitors produce only marginally detectable gravitational wave signals. Here, we report observations of ATLAS J1138-5139, a binary white dwarf system with an orbital period of 28 minutes. Our analysis reveals a 1 solar mass carbon-oxygen white dwarf accreting from a helium-core white dwarf. Given its mass, the accreting carbon-oxygen white dwarf is poised to trigger a typical-luminosity Type Ia supernova within a few million years, or to evolve into a stably mass-transferring AM CVn system. ATLAS J1138-5139 provides a rare opportunity to calibrate binary evolution models by directly comparing observed orbital parameters and mass transfer rates closer to merger than any previously identified candidate Type Ia progenitor. Its compact orbit ensures detectability by LISA, demonstrating the potential of millihertz gravitational wave observatories to reveal a population of Type Ia progenitors on a Galactic scale, paving the way for multi-messenger studies offering insights into the origins of these cosmologically significant explosions.</description>
      <author>Emma Chickles, Kevin B. Burdge, Joheen Chakraborty, V. S. Dhillon, Paul A. Draghis, Scott A. Hughes, James Munday, S. Rappaport, J. Tonry, Evan B. Bauer, Alex Brown, N. Castro, Deepto Chakrabarty, M. Dyer, Kareem El-Badry, Anna Frebel, G&#225;bor F&#369;r&#233;sz, James A. Garbutt, Matthew Green, Aaron Householder, Dan Jarvis, Erin Kara, Mark Kennedy, P. Kerry, S. P. Littlefair, J. McCormac, Geoffrey Mo, Mason Ng, S. G. Parsons, Ingrid Pelisoli, Eleanor Pike, Thomas A. Prince, G. Ricker, Jan van Roestel, D. I. Sahman, Ken J. Shen, Robert A. Simcoe, Pier-Emmanuel Tremblay, Andrew Vanderburg, Tin Long Sunny Wong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.19916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of hypoxia and its dynamic evolution in glioblastoma via qBOLD MRI: a comparative study with metformin treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s41747-024-00533-2</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Jie Chen, Yinwei Ying, Xinxin Zhao, Nan Mei, Xuanxuan Li, Yuqi Zhu, Jin Cui, Pu&#8208;Yeh Wu, Yiping Lu, Bo Yin, European Radiology Experimental. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404931252

                Abstract Background To investigate the accuracy of quantitative blood oxygen level-dependent (qBOLD) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) in identifying hypoxia within glioblastoma and explore dynamic changes in oxygenation status of glioblastoma with and without metformin administration. Methods Three healthy and seven C6-bearing rats underwent 7-T qBOLD MRI. Oxygen extraction fraction (OEF) and cerebral metabolism rate of O 2 (CMRO 2 ) were calculated from qBOLD data. Tumor tissues were stained using hypoxia-inducible factor-1 $$\alpha$$  &#945;  (HIF-1 $$\alpha$$  &#945;  ) and pimonidazole. The correlation between the hypoxia markers and corresponding qBOLD-based parameters was analyzed. Six C6-bearing rats were divided into metformin-treated and control groups for a longitudinal study of qBOLD imaging changes, with scans conducted on the 12th, 15th, and 18th day post-tumor implantation. Results In healthy rats, gray matter showed higher values than white matter in T2, T2*, cerebral blood volume (CBV), and cerebral blood flow (CBF), whereas OEF was lower. Glioblastoma tissues exhibited elevated T2, T2*, CBV, and CBF but decreased OEF and CMRO 2 relative to normal-appearing white matter. No significant correlation was found between staining scores from HIF-1 $$\alpha$$  &#945;  and pimonidazole. T2* and T2 values were negatively correlated with pimonidazole scores in tumor regions. As the tumor progressed, OEF values increased with intra-tissue variations, whereas CMRO 2 decreased. Metformin delayed the reduction of T2 and T2* values, with significant differences in OEF and CMRO 2 values compared to controls on day 18. Conclusion T2* and T2 values were significantly associated with the hypoxia status in glioma. Metformin could potentially mitigate the progression of hypoxia in glioblastoma, which can be tracked by qBOLD parameters. Relevance statement This study demonstrates the potential of qBOLD parameters in assessing glioma dynamic oxygen metabolism and the efficacy of metformin as an anti-hypoxic agent, providing insights into improving glioblastoma treatment strategies. Key Points The study investigated qBOLD imaging&#8217;s accuracy in identifying hypoxia status within glioblastoma. qBOLD effectively assesses hypoxia and its dynamic evolution in glioblastoma. qBOLD parameters assist in identifying a suitable patient demographic for metformin treatment. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Jie Chen, Yinwei Ying, Xinxin Zhao, Nan Mei, Xuanxuan Li, Yuqi Zhu, Jin Cui, Pu&#8208;Yeh Wu, Yiping Lu, Bo Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s41747-024-00533-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signatures of the Shock Interaction as an Additional Power Source in the
  Nebular Spectra of SN 2023ixf</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.03509</link>
      <description>Amit Kumar, Raya Dastidar, J. R. Maund, Adam J. Singleton, Ning-Chen Sun, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405090768

                Red supergiants may lose significant mass through steady winds and episodic eruptions in the final 100-1000 years before the core collapses, shaping their circumstellar environment. Interaction between supernova (SN) ejecta and distant circumstellar material (CSM) can generate shocks, which can energize the ejecta and serve as a key power source during the nebular phase of the SN. In the present work, we investigate the nebular spectrum of SN 2023ixf, observed one year post-explosion (at +363 d) with the recently commissioned WEAVE instrument on the 4.2m William Herschel Telescope. This marks the first supernova spectrum captured with WEAVE. In this spectrum, H$\alpha$ exhibits a peculiar evolution, flanked by blueward and redward broad components centred at $\sim\pm 5650\,\mathrm{km\,s^{-1}}$ from the rest velocity of H$\alpha$, which are seen for only a few SNe to date. These features indicate energy deposition from shocks generated by the interaction of ejecta with a CSM expelled nearly 350 $-$ 640 years pre-explosion. Comparisons of the +363 d spectrum with model spectra from the literature, that include varying shock powers, suggest a shock power of at least $\sim 5 \times 10 ^{40}\,\mathrm{erg\,s^{-1}}$ at this epoch. Additionally, analysis of the [O I] doublet, along with other prominent emission lines, provides evidence for clumpiness, dust formation, and asymmetry within the ejecta and/or the surrounding CSM. These emission lines also helped to constrain the oxygen mass ($\approx0.19^{\scriptscriptstyle +0.08}_{\scriptscriptstyle -0.04} M_\odot$), He-core mass ($&lt;3 M_\odot$) and the zero-age main sequence mass ($\lesssim 12 M_\odot$) of the progenitor of SN 2023ixf. The comparison with other Type II SNe highlights SN 2023ixf's unique shock interaction signatures and evidence of dust formation, setting it apart in terms of evolution and dynamics.</description>
      <author>Amit Kumar, Raya Dastidar, J. R. Maund, Adam J. Singleton, Ning-Chen Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.03509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Parameter Study of 1D Atmospheric Models of Pulsating AGB Stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/galaxies12060081</link>
      <description>Henry A. Prager, L. A. Willson, Joyce Ann Guzik, M. J. Creech&#8208;Eakman, Qian Wang, Galaxies. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404993573

                Using the atmospheric pulsation code written by George Bowen, we have performed a parameter study examining the effects of modifying various parameters of models of oxygen-rich AGB atmospheres pulsating in the fundamental and first-overtone modes. For each pulsation mode, we have examined the effects of adjusting the dust condensation temperature, dust condensation temperature range, pulsation amplitude, dust opacity, and metallicity. Our model grids are generated with the constraint that their luminosities are chosen to span the range of observed mass loss rates at a chosen mass. The dust condensation temperature, pulsation amplitude, and dust opacity have strong effects on the ultimate location and shape of the final model grids in the mass luminosity plane. The mass loss rate evolution of the fundamental and first-overtone mode models show a significant difference in behavior. While the fundamental mode models exhibit the typically assumed power&#8211;law relation with mass and luminosity, the first-overtone mode models show significant non-power law behavior at observed mass loss rates. Effectively, models in the first-overtone mode require somewhat higher luminosities to reach the same mass loss rates seen in fundamental mode models of the same mass, consistent with observed AGB stars.</description>
      <author>Henry A. Prager, L. A. Willson, Joyce Ann Guzik, M. J. Creech&#8208;Eakman, Qian Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/galaxies12060081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: The potential of nanocellulose composites for sustainable food packaging applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pc.29321</link>
      <description>Abd El Salam Nasra, Yasmeen A. Hasanien, Soma A. El Mogy, Polymer Composites. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404968351

                Abstract This work addresses the innovative use of nanocellulose (NC) as an environmentally friendly and sustainable substitute for conventional food packaging made of polymers. The review delves into the synthesis approaches of NC/polymer&#8208;mixed composites. The characterization of these composites is discussed, highlighting their mechanical properties, biodegradability, and characteristics of a barrier toward oxygen, moisture, and oil resistance. The review further explores the development of active packaging, which utilizes NC's capacity to preserve and release active ingredients like antioxidants and antimicrobials to lengthen the amount of time that food supplies can be stored. The evolution of intelligent and smart packaging is also explored, showcasing how NC&#8208;based packaging can incorporate indicators for freshness, temperature, pH, and spoilage, offering customers and retailers knowledge accessibility in real time. The opportunities and problems facing NC in food packaging are discussed, and the need for more study and advancement is highlighted to reach its full potential. For those interested in sustainable food packaging solutions, researchers, business professionals, and policymakers will find this thorough review to be highly insightful. Highlights It covers examples of polymer composites filled with NC. Mention the preparation methods and characterization of NC&#8208;based composites. Highlight the promising areas of NC /polymer composite applications in smart food packaging Concludes the challenges and prospects of NC composite in food packaging.</description>
      <author>Abd El Salam Nasra, Yasmeen A. Hasanien, Soma A. El Mogy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pc.29321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of orbital ordering in cooperative Jahn-Teller models: Machine-learning enabled large-scale simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.123602</link>
      <description>Sagar Ghosh, Sheng Zhang, Cheng Chen, Gia-Wei Chern, Physical Review Materials. 8(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404920510

                We present a scalable machine-learning (ML) force-field model for the adiabatic dynamics of cooperative Jahn-Teller (JT) systems. Large-scale dynamical simulations of the JT model also shed light on the orbital ordering dynamics in colossal magnetoresistance manganites. The JT effect in these materials describes the distortion of local oxygen octahedra driven by a coupling to the orbital degrees of freedom of ${e}_{g}$ electrons. An effective electron-mediated interaction between the local JT modes leads to a structural transition and the emergence of long-range orbital order at low temperatures. Assuming the principle of locality, a deep-learning neural-network model is developed to accurately and efficiently predict the electron-induced forces that drive the dynamical evolution of JT phonons. A group-theoretical method is utilized to develop a descriptor that incorporates the combined orbital and lattice symmetry into the ML model. Large-scale Langevin dynamics simulations, enabled by the ML force-field models, are performed to investigate the coarsening dynamics of the composite JT distortion and orbital order after a thermal quench. The late-stage coarsening of orbital domains exhibits pronounced freezing behaviors, which are likely related to the unusual morphology of the domain structures. Our paper highlights a promising avenue for multiscale dynamical modeling of correlated electron systems.</description>
      <author>Sagar Ghosh, Sheng Zhang, Cheng Chen, Gia-Wei Chern</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.123602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History and Habitability of the LP 890-9 Planetary System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.02743</link>
      <description>Rory Barnes, Laura N. R. Amaral, Jessica Birky, L. Carone, Peter Driscoll, Joseph R. Livesey, David Graham, Juliette Becker, Kaiming Cui, Martin Schlecker, Rodolfo Garc&#237;a-Sierra, Megan T. Gialluca, Arthur D. Adams, Md Redyan Ahmed, Paul Bonney, Wynter Broussard, Charu Chawla, M. Damasso, W. C. Danchi, Russell Deitrick, Elsa Ducrot, Emeline F. Fromont, Brandt A. L. Gaches, Sakshi Gupta, Michelle L. Hill, James A G Jackman, Estelle Janin, Mikolaj Karawacki, Matheus Daniel Koren, Roberto La Greca, Michaela Leung, Arturo Miranda-Rosete, Michael Kent A. Olohoy, Cecelia Ngo, D Paul, Chandan Sahu, Debajyoti Basu Sarkar, Mohammad Afzal Shadab, Edward W. Schwieterman, Melissa Sedler, Katie Texeira, Allona Vazan, Karen N. Delgado Vega, R. Vijayakumar, Jonathan T. Wojack, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405076795

                We present numerous aspects of the evolution of the LP 890-9 (SPECULOOS-2/TOI-4306) planetary system, focusing on the likelihood that planet c can support life. We find that the host star reaches the main sequence in 1 Gyr and that planet c lies close to the inner boundary of the habitable zone. We find the magma ocean stage can last up to 50 Myr, remove 8 Earth-oceans of water, and leave up to 2000 bars of oxygen in the atmosphere. However, if the planet forms with a hydrogen envelope as small as 0.1 Earth-masses, no water will be lost during the star's pre-main sequence phase from thermal escape processes. We find that the planets are unlikely to be in a 3:1 mean motion resonance and that both planets tidally circularize within 0.5 Gyr when tidal dissipation is held constant. However, if tidal dissipation is a function of mantle temperature and rheology, then we find that planet c's orbit may require more than 7 Gyr to circularize, during which time tidal heating may reach hundreds of terawatts. We thus conclude that the habitability of planet c depends most strongly on the initial volatile content and internal properties, but no data yet preclude the viability of an active biosphere on the planet.</description>
      <author>Rory Barnes, Laura N. R. Amaral, Jessica Birky, L. Carone, Peter Driscoll, Joseph R. Livesey, David Graham, Juliette Becker, Kaiming Cui, Martin Schlecker, Rodolfo Garc&#237;a-Sierra, Megan T. Gialluca, Arthur D. Adams, Md Redyan Ahmed, Paul Bonney, Wynter Broussard, Charu Chawla, M. Damasso, W. C. Danchi, Russell Deitrick, Elsa Ducrot, Emeline F. Fromont, Brandt A. L. Gaches, Sakshi Gupta, Michelle L. Hill, James A G Jackman, Estelle Janin, Mikolaj Karawacki, Matheus Daniel Koren, Roberto La Greca, Michaela Leung, Arturo Miranda-Rosete, Michael Kent A. Olohoy, Cecelia Ngo, D Paul, Chandan Sahu, Debajyoti Basu Sarkar, Mohammad Afzal Shadab, Edward W. Schwieterman, Melissa Sedler, Katie Texeira, Allona Vazan, Karen N. Delgado Vega, R. Vijayakumar, Jonathan T. Wojack</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.02743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms for the Production and Suppression of Hydrogen Peroxide at the Hydrogen Electrode in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells and Water Electrolyzers: Theoretical Considerations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120890</link>
      <description>Donald A. Tryk, Guoyu Shi, Katsuyoshi Kakinuma, Makoto Uchida, Akihiro Iiyama, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404993532

                Hydrogen peroxide is inevitably produced at the hydrogen electrode in both the proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) and the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) when platinum-based catalysts are used. This peroxide attacks and degrades the membrane, seriously limiting its lifetime. Here we review some of our previous efforts to suppress peroxide production using PtFe as a hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst and PtCo as a hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR) catalyst. The mechanisms, which involve the chemical reaction of adsorbed hydrogen with oxygen, are examined using density functional theory. The onset of excess peroxide production at 0.1 V above the reversible potential has not been adequately explained thus far, and therefore a new mechanism is proposed here. This involves a unique reaction site including hydrogen adsorbed at (110) step edges adjacent to (111) terraces on the Pt surface, as well as on Pt alloys and other metals such as Rh and Ir. This mechanism helps explain the recent finding of the Wadayama group that Ir single crystal surfaces such as Ir(111) and Ir(110) produce little peroxide during the HOR. It also points the way toward the design of new catalysts for the hydrogen electrode that suppress peroxide production while retaining high HOR and HER activity.</description>
      <author>Donald A. Tryk, Guoyu Shi, Katsuyoshi Kakinuma, Makoto Uchida, Akihiro Iiyama</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observing Mixed Chemical Reactions at the Positive Electrode in the High-Performance Self-Powered Electrochemical Humidity Sensor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c10432</link>
      <description>Mingxiang Zhang, Zaihua Duan, Zhen Yuan, Yadong Jiang, Huiling Tai, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404967415

                Electrochemical humidity (ECH) sensors that integrate power generation and humidity sensing have attracted great research attention in recent years. However, the design of high-performance ECH sensors faces many challenges. Namely, the working mechanism of the ECH sensors is still controversial, and related self-powered applications have not been well implemented. To overcome these limitations, this study constructs an ECH sensor with high power-generation and humidity-sensing performance using the KCl/carbon black/halloysite nanotubes (KCl/CB/HNTs) as a humidity-sensing electrolyte. The proposed ECH sensor has a wide humidity-sensing response of 10.9%-91.5% relative humidity (RH), and a single ECH sensor can output 1.46 V with a maximum power of 133.2 &#956;W at 91.5% RH. Particularly, the unprecedented mixed chemical reactions at the positive electrode, including the hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen reduction reaction, are analyzed using multiple characterization and testing techniques. The analysis results provide solid experimental evidence for the current controversial working mechanism of ECH sensors. Due to the advantage of high-power generation, the proposed ECH sensor can be used for self-powered humidity detection. This study provides a valuable reference for improving the power generation of ECH sensors and solid evidence for clarifying their working mechanism, which could be beneficial for guiding the future development of ECH sensors.</description>
      <author>Mingxiang Zhang, Zaihua Duan, Zhen Yuan, Yadong Jiang, Huiling Tai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c10432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genome-Wide Identification, Classification, Expression Analysis, and Screening of Drought and Heat Resistance-Related Candidates of the Rboh Gene Family in Wheat</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13233377</link>
      <description>Miyuan Cao, Yue Zhang, Xiaoxiao Zou, Huangping Yin, Yan Yin, Zeqi Li, Wenjun Xiao, Shucan Liu, Yongliang Li, Xinhong Guo, Plants. 13(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404913539

                Plant respiratory burst oxidase homologs (Rbohs) are key enzymes that produce reactive oxygen species (ROS), which serve as signaling molecules regulating plant growth and stress responses. In this study, 39 TaRboh genes (TaRboh01&#8211;TaRboh39) were identified. These genes were distributed unevenly among the wheat genome&#8217;s fourteen chromosomes, with the exception of homoeologous group 2 and 7 and chromosomes 4A, as well as one unidentified linkage group (Un). TaRbohs were classified into ten distinct clades, each sharing similar motif compositions and gene structures. The promoter regions of TaRbohs contained cis-elements related to hormones, growth and development, and stresses. Furthermore, five TaRboh genes (TaRboh26, TaRboh27, TaRboh31, TaRboh32, and TaRboh34) exhibited strong evolutionary conservation. Additionally, a Ka/Ks analysis confirmed that purifying selection was the predominant force driving the evolution of these genes. Expression profiling and qPCR results further indicated differential expression patterns of TaRboh genes between heat and drought stresses. TaRboh11, TaRboh20, TaRboh22, TaRboh24, TaRboh29, and TaRboh34 were significantly upregulated under multiple stress conditions, whereas TaRboh30 was only elevated in response to drought stress. Collectively, our findings provide a systematic analysis of the wheat Rboh gene family and establish a theoretical framework for our future research on the role of Rboh genes in response to heat and drought stress.</description>
      <author>Miyuan Cao, Yue Zhang, Xiaoxiao Zou, Huangping Yin, Yan Yin, Zeqi Li, Wenjun Xiao, Shucan Liu, Yongliang Li, Xinhong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13233377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deepening the understanding of wreck ecology: a comparative study of marine sediment microbiomes across 10 Maltese wreck sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1480265</link>
      <description>Emma Bolton, Nadine Greenhalgh, Emily Kunselman, Jonathon C.O. Mifsud, Neem Patel, Maja Sausmekat, Phoebe Oldach, Timmy Gambin, Frontiers in Marine Science. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405055577

                The anthropogenic influences of historical shipwrecks on the marine environment remain largely uncharacterized, particularly for wrecks located at depths of ~50 meters and lost over 80 years ago. Below 50 meters, the marine environment transitions from the euphotic to the mesophotic zone, where reduced light, significant changes in oxygen levels, and increased pressure may alter microbial communities and metabolic pathways. Understanding these shifts can provide insights into the adaptation and evolution of microorganisms. Sediment samples were collected by a team of divers from nine wreck sites off the coast of Malta, varying in depth from 5 to 100 meters. All sampling was conducted with the consent and authorization of the Government of Malta for the collection of marine genetic resources. Chemical analyses and metabarcoding techniques were employed to assess how shipwrecks influence microbial diversity and community composition in the surrounding sediments. Alpha ( &#945; ) diversity of microbial communities was higher in sediments adjacent to the shipwrecks compared to those collected over 100 meters away from any wreck site. Across all nine wreck sites, sediment size emerged as the most significant driver of microbial diversity, followed by frame type and the presence of oil leaks. This study demonstrates that shipwrecks, varying in depth, frame type, and country of origin, significantly influence the microbial ecosystems and sediment chemistry of their surrounding environment. The findings suggest that shipwrecks act as focal points for ecological and chemical changes, contributing to the dynamic interactions between historical artifacts and marine ecosystems.</description>
      <author>Emma Bolton, Nadine Greenhalgh, Emily Kunselman, Jonathon C.O. Mifsud, Neem Patel, Maja Sausmekat, Phoebe Oldach, Timmy Gambin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1480265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Translating laboratory success into the large-scale implementation of photocatalytic overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fsci.2024.1507745</link>
      <description>Markus Antonietti, Christian Mark Pelicano, Frontiers in Science. 2(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404970591

                As global energy consumption continues to rise, mitigating anthropogenic climate change demands the search for carbon-neutral energy sources to cut down on our reliance on fossil fuels. Sunlight-driven water splitting using particulate photocatalysts represents a promising and sustainable approach for the large-scale production of green H2. In their Frontiers in Science Lead Article, Hisatomi and colleagues [1] provide comprehensive yet succinct insights that lay a crucial foundation for the development of future H2 generation systems through particulate photocatalysis. They focus on key aspects such as photocatalyst stability, efficient H2 recovery, the safe design of reactor systems, and advancement in technologies for the separate production of H2 and O2 from H2O. The authors have developed heterogeneous photocatalysts capable of efficiently splitting H2O into H2 and O2 in the near-UV region, highlighting the ideal structure and properties of cocatalyst/photocatalyst hybrid systems for overall water splitting (OWS) [2]. Photocatalyst materials have also been identified to split H2O with longer wavelengths of visible light, but their apparent quantum yield (AQY) values remain low, mainly due to difficulties in fine-tuning their material properties [3]. New techniques have been introduced to harness visible light for Z-scheme OWS by combining distinct photocatalysts. In addition, efforts are underway to develop reactors for large-scale applications and routes to extract pure H2 from oxyhydrogen mixture saturated with H2O vapor [4]. The authors finally emphasized the importance of creating standardized methods for measuring solar-to-hydrogen (STH) efficiency, stressing that leading researchers in photocatalysis should drive this initiative, given its current low technology readiness level. The notable progress highlighted largely stems from over four decades of research in the field of OWS, with much of this work spearheaded by the authors themselves. At this pivotal juncture, where there is an unprecedented demand for scalable solar fuel production technologies, the influence of their research is anticipated to extend far beyond the scope of solar-driven catalysis and engineering, impacting a broad spectrum of industries. This viewpoint endeavors to spark a critical discussion on the challenges associated with translating laboratory success into largescale implementation of photocatalytic OWS.Current maximum STH efficiencies for photocatalytic OWS systems are close to 1%, attained under laboratory conditions with constrained testing durations and remain considerably distant from real-world settings. In 2021, Domen et al. conducted a large-scale experiment (on a 100 m 2 scale) by immobilizing Al doped SrTiO3 photocatalysts on panels and generating 600 L of H2 on a sunny day using a commercial separation membrane, reaching an optimal STH efficiency of 0.76%. This work highlights both the potential for safely generating H2 on a large scale and the significant challenges facing its actual application [4]. While the reported system can continuously produce H2, the current efficiency levels are still insufficient to make this technology viable for large-scale H2 production at this stage. Thus, realizing higher solar-toenergy conversion efficiencies remain the primary focus to make practical implementation of photocatalytic OWS feasible. In the search for suitable photocatalysts, an absorption limit over 600 nm coupled with an AQY value exceeding 60% are the necessary benchmarks for reaching the goal of 10% STH efficiency [5]. Conversely, band gap (Eg) reduction diminishes the ability of photocatalysts to facilitate redox reactions. Hence, it is crucial to strike a balance between lowering the Eg to extend light absorption and increasing it to generate stronger driving potential to promote H2O splitting. Metal (oxy)nitrides and oxysulfides have been shown to be effective for photocatalytic OWS under light with wavelengths up to 600 nm. However, these photocatalysts generally display low efficiencies and limited chemical stability. Recent progress on metal-free carbon nitride photocatalysts for H2O splitting presents a promising alternative to these inorganic semiconductors [6,7].Enhancing solar energy conversion efficiency typically involves hybridizing photocatalysts with cocatalysts. These cocatalyst materials assist in carrier separation and transport while providing active sites and speeding up water-splitting reactions [8]. However, most photocatalysts for OWS rely on rare or expensive materials, such as platinum-group metals and other toxic inorganic components, as cocatalysts. This dependence on scarce resources limits scalability and increases costs, raising sustainability issues. For instance, Rh@CrOx (or Rh-Cr mixed oxide) and Ru/Ir-based oxides serve as cocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in these systems. Another concern is that the CrOx shell could potentially leach Cr 6+ ions during prolonged photo-irradiation, leading to not only catalyst deactivation but also environmental harm and health risks [9]. Although these rare and hazardous materials are used in minimal amounts, their inclusion still presents economic and environmental challenges. Given the limited production capacities of noble metals, widespread adoption of photocatalytic OWS technology could cause substantial market price increases due to rising demand and expectations. As highlighted in the lead article, precious cocatalyst materials can be recycled using standard metal recovery processes once the photocatalyst's lifecycle is complete. Nonetheless, there is a pressing need to develop cost-effective, earthabundant cocatalysts that offer performance similar to noble metals to eliminate the need for additional recycling steps. If using noble metals is necessary, one possible solution is to alloy at least one platinum-group metal with another or with a more widely available metal.Bimetallic systems can alter their electronic structure, resulting in a catalytic performance that surpasses that of their individual parent metals [10].Author 1 et al. Short title/running header 6 Similar to the previous concerns with cocatalysts, although immobilizing photocatalysts on substrates or sheets has demonstrated scalability and effectiveness in advancing OWS, attention must also be directed toward the disposal problems related to future water-splitting systems. Although the scalability and efficiency of photocatalysts are well established, it is of equal importance to probe how to address their environmental impact. Again, the key question is that can photocatalysts and other essential components in these systems be restored or regenerated? More specifically, the photocatalysts should endure multiple operational cycles with only minor losses in efficiency. Developing recycling protocols that do not involve dismantling the entire system can be an excellent solution to minimize operating and maintenance costs. Materials approaching the end of their service life must be disposed of correctly to mitigate environmental and health risks.Lastly, one of the biggest challenges in the practical implementation of photocatalytic OWS systems is integrating them with existing energy infrastructures, especially when it comes to safely storing and transporting generated H2 to avoid contamination and operational risks.Hisatomi et al. emphasized that after H2 is separated and recovered, it can be used in various catalytic reactions to create other value-added chemicals and fuels. This approach is more practical for safe handling and transportation compared to managing H2 as the final product [1]. In this context, governments will play a crucial role in setting safety and environmental standards for the secure production, storage, and potential transport of surplus H2. Investments in key infrastructures by governments will further accelerate the adoption of photocatalytic OWS. Strong political commitment is crucial for implementing regulations and policies, such as setting H2 production standards and providing tax incentives, to make green H2 more competitive-similar to the approach taken with other emerging technologies. For example, Germany's National Hydrogen Strategy envisions a comprehensive H2 infrastructure by 2030. This involves plans to build over 1,800 kilometers of new and repurposed pipelines dedicated In summary, although significant progress has been made in photocatalytic OWS technology, challenges remain, particularly in achieving higher STH efficiencies and addressing both economic and environmental sustainability concerns. The development of cost-effective, earthabundant photocatalysts and cocatalysts, alongside standardized methods for efficiency measurement, will be crucial for the future scalability of these systems. Furthermore, the environmental impact of the future water-splitting systems must be thoroughly investigated in order to ensure their sustainability, minimize potential ecological risks, and create efficient recycling and disposal protocols that comply with environmental safety regulations. With continued research, political support, and partnerships between industries, the shift from laboratory breakthroughs to scalable photocatalytic H2 production systems holds promise for contributing to global decarbonization efforts.</description>
      <author>Markus Antonietti, Christian Mark Pelicano</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fsci.2024.1507745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation on Crystallization of CaO&#8208;Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;BaO Slag Using Differential Scanning Calorimeter and In Situ High&#8208;Temperature Raman Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400697</link>
      <description>Yong Lin, Francis Gyakwaa, Tommi Kokkonen, Riku Mattila, Baijun Yan, Timo Fabritius, Qifeng Shu, steel research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404891934

                CaO&#8208;Al 2 O 3 &#8208;B 2 O 3 &#8208;based slag is among the most promising &#8220;nonreactive&#8221; mold fluxes for continuous casting of high&#8208;aluminum steel. However, CaO&#8208;Al 2 O 3 &#8208;B 2 O 3 &#8208;based slag system exhibits a stronger crystallization ability compared to traditional mold fluxes. Herein, calcium oxide in CaO&#8208;Al 2 O 3 &#8208;10%B 2 O 3 slag is partially replaced by the same mass of barium oxide (5 and 10 mass%) to adjust the crystallization ability. The crystallization of glassy slags is then investigated using a differential scanning calorimeter and their crystallization kinetics are analyzed using the Matusita&#8211;Sakka model. The structural evolution of glassy slags from room temperature to 1200 &#176;C is also investigated using in situ Raman spectroscopy. The kinetic analysis shows that the crystallization process of CaO&#8208;Al 2 O 3 &#8208;B 2 O 3 &#8208;BaO glassy slags follows the surface crystallization mechanism. The predominant crystalline products are calcium monoaluminate (CaAl 2 O 4 ) and calcium borate (Ca 3 (BO 3 ) 2 ). The partial replacement of calcium oxide by barium oxide inhibits the growth of CaAl 2 O 4 in the slag by increasing the activation energy of crystal growth. The high&#8208;temperature Raman spectroscopy study shows that the band between 700 and 900 cm &#8722;1 gets weaker relative to the band between 450 and 650 cm &#8722;1 at high temperatures. This indicates the strengthening of bending vibration of Al&#8208;O&#8208;Al, which is consistent with the precipitation of CaAl 2 O 4 with full oxygen bridging.</description>
      <author>Yong Lin, Francis Gyakwaa, Tommi Kokkonen, Riku Mattila, Baijun Yan, Timo Fabritius, Qifeng Shu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400697</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two mixed-valent cerium oxo clusters: synthesis, structure, and self-assembly</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1507834</link>
      <description>Yuan Gao, Yang Zhang, Zhe Han, Chunhui Wang, Lei Zhang, Jieshan Qiu, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404897473

                Studies on cerium oxo clusters (CeOCs) are not only significant for understanding the redox and hydrolysis behaviors of Ce(III/IV) ions but also crucial for the rational synthesis of novel clusters and nanoceria with specific Ce(III)/Ce(IV) ratios. Here, two sets of reactions were conducted using cerium nitrate and H 2 O 2 -oxidized cerium nitrate, resulting in the formation of two distinct mixed-valent CeOCs [Ce III 4 Ce IV 10 O 14 (OH) 2 (PhCO 2 ) 22 (DMF) 6 ] (Ce 14 ) and [Ce III 2 Ce IV 22 O 28 (OH) 8 (PhCO 2 ) 30 (DMF) 4 ] (Ce 24C ). These two clusters exhibit different structures and Ce(III)/Ce(IV) ratios, demonstrating the critical role of cerium oxidation states and the occurrence of redox reactions in cluster formation. Ce 14 is the first tetradecanuclear CeOC with a novel structure, whereas Ce 24C differed in its Ce(III)/Ce(IV) ratio, protonation levels of O atoms, and ligands from previously reported 24-nuclear CeOCs. Furthermore, various techniques were employed to investigate the formation process of these two clusters. X-ray photoelectron spectra (XPS) revealed that the white precipitates formed during the preparation of Ce 14 contain Ce(III) ions, while the reddish-brown precipitates formed during the preparation of Ce 24C contain a mixture of Ce(III) and Ce(IV) ions. These two precipitations were individually dissolved in N,N-Dimethylformamide (DMF). The evolution of solution color and ultraviolet-visible (UV-Vis) spectra over time revealed the gradual oxidation of partial Ce(III) ions by oxygen in the solution of the white precipitation. As Ce(IV) ions increased in this solution, time-resolved small angle X-ray scattering (SAXS) data demonstrated the self-assembly of the Ce 14 clusters after 4 days. In contrast, SAXS data and UV-Vis spectra revealed the rapid assembly of Ce 24C clusters within 2 h due to the initial coexistence of Ce(IV) and Ce(III) ions in the DMF solution of the reddish-brown precipitation. The continued reduction of partial Ce(IV) ions in this solution does not affect Ce 24C clusters&#8217; formation and stability. Our studies expand the family of CeOCs and enhance our understanding of the effects of cerium&#8217;s oxidation states on cluster formation.</description>
      <author>Yuan Gao, Yang Zhang, Zhe Han, Chunhui Wang, Lei Zhang, Jieshan Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1507834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pill-Induced Esophagitis Mimicking Esophageal Neoplasia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14309/crj.0000000000001564</link>
      <description>K Ferdinande, David J. Tate, Triana Lobat&#243;n, Liesbeth Ferdinande, Anne Hoorens, Pieter Hindryckx, ACG Case Reports Journal. 11(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404998656

                CASE REPORT An 80-year-old man with a history of ischemic heart disease presented with hematemesis, retrosternal chest pain, dysphagia, and weight loss. His medication included tramadol hydrochloride, which was recently added for lower back pain, and various cardiovascular drugs. He did not have a history of gastrointestinal disease nor did he smoke or drink alcohol. On examination, his blood pressure was 165/103 mm Hg, heart rate 110 beats per minute, and oxygen saturation 97%. Laboratory tests revealed a low hemoglobin level and elevated C-reactive protein and lactate. Imaging showed an esophageal mass with severe narrowing and suspected malignancy (Figure 1).Figure 1.: Contrast-enhanced computed tomography. Panel (A) Coronal, Panel (B) Axial. Contrast-enhanced computed tomography showing an eccentric esophageal tumor on the left at carina level with severe narrowing of the lumen (white arrows).The patient underwent an endoscopy, revealing a large, necrotic lesion highly suspicious for a tumoral mass (Figure 2, panel A-C). However, a second endoscopy the next day showed multiple deep ulcerations, suggesting severe pill-induced esophagitis rather than a neoplasm (Figure 2). Biopsies confirmed ulcerative esophagitis with polarizable foreign material, consisting with the diagnosis of pill-induced esophagitis, but no malignancy (Figure 3). The esophagitis was suspected to be attributed to tramadol, which can impair esophageal motility and prolong medication transit time.1Figure 2.: Panel (A), (B), and (C) (from proximal to distal): first esophagogastroduodenoscopy with documentation of a bulky and necrotic tumoral lesion starting midesophageal over a length of 15 cm distally, obliterating the entire lumen. Panel (C) showing large blood clot formation more distally in the esophagus. Panel (D), (E), and (F): second esophagogastroduodenoscopy with documentation of multiple very deep ulcerations (black arrow) with the impression of fistula (white arrow). Adherent to the ulcerations, large clot formation could be seen. Panel (G), (H), and (I): third esophagogastroduodenoscopy with documentation of ongoing positive evolution of the esophagus with the presence of large superficial ulcerations (black arrow). Panel (J), (K), and (L): fourth esophagogastroduodenoscopy at 1 month after the initial presentation with documentation of healing of the previously documented extensive ulcerations. Presence of some superficial mucosal tears (black arrow).Treatment involved proton-pomp inhibitors and discontinuing tramadol, with follow-up endoscopies showing progressive healing. This case underscores the importance to consider pill-induced esophagitis in patients with odynophagia, dysphagia, retrosternal chest pain, or hematemesis and to rule out malignancy. Pill-induced esophagitis has an excellent prognosis after conservative treatment.2,3Figure 3.: Top&#8212;Hematoxylin and eosin stain (&#215;40). Squamous epithelium with spongiosis (dilated intercellular spaces) and neutrophilic infiltration and attached an inflammatory exudate with foreign material. Below: Higher magnification (&#215;200) of the area indicated by a rectangle in the upper figure; Left&#8212;Hematoxylin and eosin stain: Gray-pink stained foreign material embedded in fibrinopurulent exudate. Right: The foreign material is birefringent in polarized light.DISCLOSURES Author contributions: Writing manuscript and literature research: K. Ferdinande. Supervision case and writing manuscript: D. Tate and T. Lobaton. Pathology expert: L. Ferdinande and A. Hoorens. Supervision writing manuscript, GI-expert, article guarantor: P. Hindryckx. Financial disclosure: None to report. Informed consent was obtained for this case report.</description>
      <author>K Ferdinande, David J. Tate, Triana Lobat&#243;n, Liesbeth Ferdinande, Anne Hoorens, Pieter Hindryckx</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14309/crj.0000000000001564</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
