<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 01:12:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Using Carbon-encapsulated Co-Fe-Al Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175969</link>
      <description>Jaeeun Jeon, Kyu-bong Jang, Sunghwan Yeo, Kyoung Ryeol Park, Hayun Jeon, HyukSu Han, Heechae Choi, Sungwook Mhin, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401502642

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jaeeun Jeon, Kyu-bong Jang, Sunghwan Yeo, Kyoung Ryeol Park, Hayun Jeon, HyukSu Han, Heechae Choi, Sungwook Mhin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ constructed NiCoZnS composite on nickel foam with hierarchical structures as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175983</link>
      <description>A. Sai Kumar, K. Naga Sathya Sai, K. Prasad, Ammar M. Tighezza, Durga Prasad Pabba, Jong Su Kim, Sang Woo Joo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401503165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Sai Kumar, K. Naga Sathya Sai, K. Prasad, Ammar M. Tighezza, Durga Prasad Pabba, Jong Su Kim, Sang Woo Joo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aspartic acid/ thiourea &#8722; derived N and S &#8722; doped porous carbon as a metal-free electrocatalyst for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112972</link>
      <description>Elham Soltani, Mohammad Bagher Gholivand, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401503321

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elham Soltani, Mohammad Bagher Gholivand</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mos2@Mwcnts Core&#8211;Shell Heterostructure for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4923458</link>
      <description>Huy Du Nguyen, Kyu Yeon Jang, Hye Bin Jung, MinJoong Kim, Changsoo Lee, Young&#8208;Woo Lee, Kyu&#8208;Nam Jung, Seung Woo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Hana Yoon, Younghyun Cho, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401507352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huy Du Nguyen, Kyu Yeon Jang, Hye Bin Jung, MinJoong Kim, Changsoo Lee, Young&#8208;Woo Lee, Kyu&#8208;Nam Jung, Seung Woo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Hana Yoon, Younghyun Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4923458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Ruthenium-Based Oxides with Rich Grain Boundaries for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01333</link>
      <description>Youcai Che, Xiuxiu Zhang, Shuowen Bo, Qizheng An, Jing Zhang, Baojie Li, Chenyu Yang, Wanlin Zhou, Weiren Cheng, Qinghua Liu, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401512678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youcai Che, Xiuxiu Zhang, Shuowen Bo, Qizheng An, Jing Zhang, Baojie Li, Chenyu Yang, Wanlin Zhou, Weiren Cheng, Qinghua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxyanion Engineering on RuO2 for Efficient Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413653</link>
      <description>Ying Duan, Li Wang, W. Zheng, Xiaolong Zhang, Xiaoran Wang, Guojin Feng, Ziyou Yu, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401513172

                In proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE), the anode oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts rely heavily on the expensive and scarce iridium&#8208;based materials. Ruthenium dioxide (RuO2) with lower price and higher OER activity, has been explored for the similar task, but has been restricted by the poor stability. Herein, we developed an anion modification strategy to improve the OER performance of RuO2 in acidic media. The designed multicomponent catalyst based on sulfate anchored on RuO2/MoO3 displays a low overpotential of 190 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and stably operates for 500 hours with a very low degradation rate of 20 &#956;V h&#8208;1. When assembled in a PEMWE cell, this catalyst as an anode shows an excellent stability at 500 mA cm&#8208;2 for 150 h. Experimental and theoretical results revealed that MoO3 could stabilize sulfate anion on RuO2 surface to suppress its leaching during OER. Such MoO3&#8208;anchored sulfate not only reduces the formation energy of *OOH intermediate on RuO2, but also impedes both the surface Ru and lattice oxygen loss, thereby achieving the high OER activity and exceptional durability.</description>
      <author>Ying Duan, Li Wang, W. Zheng, Xiaolong Zhang, Xiaoran Wang, Guojin Feng, Ziyou Yu, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413653</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally activated growth of ternary oxyhydroxides on perovskites for efficient water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02744b</link>
      <description>Chao Wu, Zhou Xiao, Jiagang Wu, Junhua Li, Anqi Zou, Jiliang Zhu, Xiaopeng Wang, Chao Wu, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401518227

                This study showcased the thermally activated growth of an amorphous FeCoW oxyhydroxide on triple perovskite pre-catalysts, exhibiting greatly enhanced oxygen evolution reaction activities.</description>
      <author>Chao Wu, Zhou Xiao, Jiagang Wu, Junhua Li, Anqi Zou, Jiliang Zhu, Xiaopeng Wang, Chao Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02744b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycling Spent Ternary Cathodes to Oxygen Evolution Catalysts for Pure Water Anion-Exchange Membrane Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c07340</link>
      <description>Liyue Zhang, Qiucheng Xu, Shuting Wen, Hao-Xuan Zhang, Ling Chen, Hao Jiang, Chunzhong Li, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401520130

                Recycling spent lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) to efficient water-splitting electrocatalysts is a promising and sustainable technology route for green hydrogen production by renewables. In this work, a fluorinated ternary metal oxide (F-TMO) derived from spent LIBs was successfully converted to a robust water oxidation catalyst for pure water electrolysis by utilizing an anion-exchange membrane. The optimized catalyst delivered a high current density of 3.0 A cm</description>
      <author>Liyue Zhang, Qiucheng Xu, Shuting Wen, Hao-Xuan Zhang, Ling Chen, Hao Jiang, Chunzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c07340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reactions Using Advanced Heterostructures for Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Battery Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c02289</link>
      <description>Dongliang Qiu, Huihui Wang, Wei Wang, Jun Huang, Zhen Meng, Dayong Fan, Chris Bowen, Huidan Lu, Yongping Liu, Sundaram Chandrasekaran, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401520523

                In order to facilitate electrochemical oxygen reactions in electrically rechargeable zinc-air batteries (ZABs), there is a need to develop innovative approaches for efficient oxygen electrocatalysts. Due to their reliability, high energy density, material abundance, and ecofriendliness, rechargeable ZABs hold promise as next-generation energy storage and conversion devices. However, the large-scale application of ZABs is currently hindered by the slow kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the development of heterostructure-based electrocatalysts has the potential to surpass the limitations imposed by the intrinsic properties of a single material. This Account begins with an explanation of the configurations of ZABs and the fundamentals of the oxygen electrochemistry of the air electrode. Then, we summarize recent progress with respect to the variety of heterostructures that exploit bifunctional electrocatalytic reactions and overview their impact on ZAB performance. The range of heterointerfacial engineering strategies for improving the ORR/OER and ZAB performance includes tailoring the surface chemistry, dimensionality of catalysts, interfacial charge transfer, mass and charge transport, and morphology. We highlight the multicomponent design approaches that take these features into account to create advanced highly active bifunctional catalysts. Finally, we discuss the challenges and future perspectives on this important topic that aim to enhance the bifunctional activity and performance of zinc-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Dongliang Qiu, Huihui Wang, Wei Wang, Jun Huang, Zhen Meng, Dayong Fan, Chris Bowen, Huidan Lu, Yongping Liu, Sundaram Chandrasekaran</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c02289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Porous Li&#8211;Al Alloy Anode toward High&#8208;Performance Sulfide&#8208;Based All&#8208;Solid&#8208;State Lithium Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407128</link>
      <description>Jinhui Zhu, Jiayao Luo, Jingyan Li, Senhe Huang, H.Z. Geng, Zhenying Chen, Linan Jia, Yongzhu Fu, Xi Zhang, Xiaodong Zhuang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401524484

                Abstract Compared to lithium (Li) anode, the alloy/Li&#8208;alloy anodes show more compatible with sulfide solid electrolytes (SSEs), and are promising candidates for practical SSE&#8208;based all&#8208;solid&#8208;state Li batteries (ASSLBs). In this work, a porous Li&#8211;Al alloy (LiAl&#8208;p) anode is crafted using a straightforward mechanical pressing method. Various characterizations confirm the porous nature of such anode, as well as rich oxygen species on its surface. To the best knowledge, such LiAl&#8208;p anode demonstrates the best room temperature cell performance in comparison with reported Li and alloy/Li&#8208;alloy anodes in SSE&#8208;based ASSLBs. For example, the LiAl&#8208;p symmetric cells deliver a record critical current density of 6.0 mA cm &#8722;2 and an ultralong cycling of 5000 h; the LiAl&#8208;p|LiNi 0.8 Co 0.1 Mn 0.1 O 2 full cells achieve a high areal capacity of 11.9 mAh cm &#8722;2 and excellent durability of 1800 cycles. Further in situ and ex situ experiments reveal that the porous structure can accommodate volume changes of LiAl&#8208;p and ensure its integrity during cycling; and moreover, a robust Li inorganics&#8208;rich solid electrolyte interphase can be formed originated from the reaction between SSE and surface oxygen species of LiAl&#8208;p. This study offers inspiration for designing high&#8208;performance alloy anodes by focusing on designing special architecture to alleviate volume change and constructing stable interphase.</description>
      <author>Jinhui Zhu, Jiayao Luo, Jingyan Li, Senhe Huang, H.Z. Geng, Zhenying Chen, Linan Jia, Yongzhu Fu, Xi Zhang, Xiaodong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(La0.8Sr0.2)0.95Mn0.5Fe0.5O3 perovskite as an efficient bi&#8208;functional electrocatalyst for oxygen&#8208;involved reaction and Zn&#8208;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401113</link>
      <description>Hong&#8208;En Wang, Xinjun Bao, Shichang Xia, Jiwei Hou, Guangjun He, Bin He, Zejie Zhang, Zejie Zhang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401525534

                The perovskite&#8208;type oxide (La0.8Sr0.2)0.95Mn0.5Fe0.5O3, synthesized using lanthanum resources recovered from polishing powder waste and manganese resources obtained from zinc anode mud, was prepared via a facile polymer&#8208;assisted combustion method, and further applied in zinc&#8208;air batteries. The crystal phase and microstructure features of the obtained nanoparticles were characterized usingn (XRD), (SEM), (TEM), (XPS), and nitrogen adsorption&#8208;desorption measurements. The results showed that the obtained (La0.8Sr0.2)0.95Mn0.5Fe0.5O3 nanoparticles, with nanoscale size, possess a high specific surface area and a suitable Mn3+/Mn4+ molar ratio, which will benefit both the(ORR) and the (OER). As expected, the thus&#8208;fabricated (La0.8Sr0.2)0.95Mn0.5Fe0.5O3 electrode exhibits a high current density of 71.2 and 85.2 mA cm&#8208;2 at &#8208;0.2 V and 0.6 V vs. Hg/HgO, respectively, which is superior to that of the commercial Pt/C catalyst (58 and 31 mA cm&#8208;2, respectively). Subsequently, this compound oxide can be an air electrode in a rechargeable zinc&#8208;air battery. The assembled battery, using (La0.8Sr0.2)0.95Mn0.5Fe0.5O3 as the cathode, exhibits a discharge voltage of 1.05~1.16 V and a charge voltage of 2.03~2.13 V under 15 mA cm&#8208;2 for 150 h. The excellent electrochemical results presented in this study highlight the potential of (La0.8Sr0.2)0.95Mn0.5Fe0.5O3 as a highly efficient and commercially viable bifunctional electrocatalyst for applications in rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Hong&#8208;En Wang, Xinjun Bao, Shichang Xia, Jiwei Hou, Guangjun He, Bin He, Zejie Zhang, Zejie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable selenium nickel-iron electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline and natural seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.097</link>
      <description>Jue Wang, Zhi Li, Libei Feng, Dachun Lu, Fang Wei, Qinfang Zhang, Daniel Hedman, Shengfu Tong, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401528343

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jue Wang, Zhi Li, Libei Feng, Dachun Lu, Fang Wei, Qinfang Zhang, Daniel Hedman, Shengfu Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaMn-doped cobalt spinel catalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution performance in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.162</link>
      <description>Zili Zheng, Junqi Li, Taotao Zhang, G. D. Wang, Kun Jiang, Xiaoying Hou, Chuan Shi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401533984

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zili Zheng, Junqi Li, Taotao Zhang, G. D. Wang, Kun Jiang, Xiaoying Hou, Chuan Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.162</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeNi-LDH Nanoflakes on Co-Encapsulated CNT Networks for Stable and Efficient Ampere-Level Current Density Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124506</link>
      <description>Xian Wang, Ze Qin, Jinjie Qian, Liyu Chen, Kui Shen, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401537411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xian Wang, Ze Qin, Jinjie Qian, Liyu Chen, Kui Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial and Vacancy Engineering on 3D-Interlocked Anode Catalyst Layer for Achieving Ultralow Voltage in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03668</link>
      <description>Lei Wan, Dongcheng Lin, Jing Liu, Ziang Xu, Qin Xu, Yihan Zhen, Maobin Pang, B. X. Wang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401538396

                Developing a high-efficiency and stable anode catalyst layer (CL) is crucial for promoting the practical applications of anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolyzers. Herein, a hierarchical nanosheet array composed of oxygen vacancy-enriched CoCrO</description>
      <author>Lei Wan, Dongcheng Lin, Jing Liu, Ziang Xu, Qin Xu, Yihan Zhen, Maobin Pang, B. X. Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c03668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the activity origin of electrochemical oxygen evolution on heteroatom&#8208;decorated carbon matrix</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411218</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Cailing Chen, Guoxiang Zhang, Huawei Huang, Yuanfu Ren, Shouwei Zuo, Zhi&#8208;Peng Wu, Lirong Zheng, Zhiping Lai, Jian Zhang, Magnus Rueping, Yu Han, Huabin Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401539457

                Chemical modification via functional dopants in carbon materials holds great promise for elevating catalytic activity and stability. To gain comprehensive insights into the pivotal mechanisms and establish structure&#8208;performance relationships, especially concerning the roles of dopants, remains a pressing need. Herein, we employ computational simulations to unravel the catalytic function of heteroatoms in the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), focusing on a physical model of high&#8208;electronegative F and N co&#8208;doped carbon matrix. Theoretical and experimental findings elucidate that the enhanced activity originates from the F and pyridinic&#8208;N (Py&#8208;N) species that achieve carbon activation. This activated carbon significantly lowers the conversion energy barrier from O* to OOH*, shifts the potential&#8208;limiting step from OOH* formation to O* generation, and ultimately optimizes the energy barrier of the potential&#8208;limiting step. This wok elucidates that the critical role of heteroatoms in catalyzing the reaction and unlocks the potential of carbon materials for acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Cailing Chen, Guoxiang Zhang, Huawei Huang, Yuanfu Ren, Shouwei Zuo, Zhi&#8208;Peng Wu, Lirong Zheng, Zhiping Lai, Jian Zhang, Magnus Rueping, Yu Han, Huabin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the activity origin of electrochemical oxygen evolution on heteroatom&#8208;decorated carbon matrix</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411218</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Cailing Chen, Guoxiang Zhang, Huawei Huang, Yuanfu Ren, Shouwei Zuo, Zhi&#8208;Peng Wu, Lirong Zheng, Zhiping Lai, Jian Zhang, Magnus Rueping, Yu Han, Huabin Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401539627

                Chemical modification via functional dopants in carbon materials holds great promise for elevating catalytic activity and stability. To gain comprehensive insights into the pivotal mechanisms and establish structure&#8208;performance relationships, especially concerning the roles of dopants, remains a pressing need. Herein, we employ computational simulations to unravel the catalytic function of heteroatoms in the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), focusing on a physical model of high&#8208;electronegative F and N co&#8208;doped carbon matrix. Theoretical and experimental findings elucidate that the enhanced activity originates from the F and pyridinic&#8208;N (Py&#8208;N) species that achieve carbon activation. This activated carbon significantly lowers the conversion energy barrier from O* to OOH*, shifts the potential&#8208;limiting step from OOH* formation to O* generation, and ultimately optimizes the energy barrier of the potential&#8208;limiting step. This wok elucidates that the critical role of heteroatoms in catalyzing the reaction and unlocks the potential of carbon materials for acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Cailing Chen, Guoxiang Zhang, Huawei Huang, Yuanfu Ren, Shouwei Zuo, Zhi&#8208;Peng Wu, Lirong Zheng, Zhiping Lai, Jian Zhang, Magnus Rueping, Yu Han, Huabin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel one-dimensional Co-phenylmercaptotetrazole MOF templated fabrication of N, S co-doped Co9S8@NSC porous nanotubes for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2975-1</link>
      <description>Peixue Fu, Ruize Yin, Shitan Yan, Yong Qian, Qin Cheng, Hanni Yang, Siyang Li, Weiwei Xiong, Junhao Zhang, Aihua Yuan, Ting Bian, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401543812

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peixue Fu, Ruize Yin, Shitan Yan, Yong Qian, Qin Cheng, Hanni Yang, Siyang Li, Weiwei Xiong, Junhao Zhang, Aihua Yuan, Ting Bian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2975-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-oxidation properties and phase composition evolution of the MoSi2-HfO2 duplex bond coat in air and steam/oxygen atmosphere at 1450 &#176;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2024.131235</link>
      <description>Kexue Peng, Guifang Han, Jingde Zhang, Long Wang, Weibin Zhang, Weili Wang, Jingde Zhang, Surface and Coatings Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401546916

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kexue Peng, Guifang Han, Jingde Zhang, Long Wang, Weibin Zhang, Weili Wang, Jingde Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2024.131235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study on the Electrocatalytic Activity of Transition Metal&#8208;Doped Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Microflowers for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400137</link>
      <description>Sergio Battiato, Mario Urso, Anna Lucia Pellegrino, A. Terrasi, S. Mirabella, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401547202

                Abstract Green hydrogen production by water splitting holds great potential as a clean and renewable source of energy for sustainable energy solutions. However, the efficiency of this process is hampered by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Overcoming these kinetic hurdles requires the development of highly efficient electrocatalysts. This study explores the effect of transition metal doping on the electrocatalytic properties of Ni(OH) 2 microflowers towards alkaline OER. Transition metal&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 microflowers, with highly porous structures due to interconnected nanosheets, are synthesized by a facile, cheap, and scalable chemical bath deposition (CBD), and combined with graphene paper (GP) substrates to fabricate electrodes. Through a systematic exploration of the relationship between the transition metal dopant element type (Mn, Fe, Co, Zn) or concentration and the consequent electrochemical properties, Co&#8208;doping demonstrates improvement in the overpotential at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 (329 mV), Tafel slope (45 mV dec &#8722;1 ), and other key performance indicators of Ni(OH) 2 microflowers for OER. These results are attributed to the high number of active sites and their enhanced electrocatalytic activity benefiting from the presence of the transition metal dopant. The proposed strategy paves the way for the development of cost&#8208;effective and highly efficient electrocatalysts for water splitting technologies.</description>
      <author>Sergio Battiato, Mario Urso, Anna Lucia Pellegrino, A. Terrasi, S. Mirabella</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru Doped Ir Nanowires for High&#8208;Efficient and Durable Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411062</link>
      <description>Bingqian Pang, Suyang Feng, Yueshan Xu, Hui Chen, Jing Wang, Yuliang Yuan, Xiaoxin Zou, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401547396

                Abstract Long&#8208;term operation of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) poses significant challenges due to the high potential and strong acidic environment associated with the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), leading to severe catalyst degradation. Here, ultrafine iridium&#8211;ruthenium nanowires (IrRu NWs) are developed through a facile process, which exhibits excellent activity and stability for acidic OER. The IrRu NWs achieve an overpotential of 243 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is significantly lower than that of commercial IrO 2 and pure Ir nanowires. Importantly, the IrRu NWs demonstrate 17.6% higher current density at 2 V in real PEMWE device than that of the commercial IrO 2 and Pt/C catalysts at the anode and cathode, respectively. The PEMWE device with the IrRu NWs catalyst layers can be stably operated at 1.0 and 1.5 A cm &#8722;2 for more than 500 h with a degradation rate of only 28 &#181;V h &#8722;1 , which makes the IrRu NWs a promising catalyst toward PEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Bingqian Pang, Suyang Feng, Yueshan Xu, Hui Chen, Jing Wang, Yuliang Yuan, Xiaoxin Zou, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction performance misjudgment caused by the self-oxidation process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/nre.2024.9120136</link>
      <description>Siyi Yang, Jianbin Luo, Yinghui Xu, Mingjie Wu, Yingkui Yang, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401549983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siyi Yang, Jianbin Luo, Yinghui Xu, Mingjie Wu, Yingkui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/nre.2024.9120136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando multi-edge XAS to unlock the effect of Co in Li- and Mn-rich NMC Li-ion cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4844249/v1</link>
      <description>Laura Simonelli, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Shehab E. Ali, Andrea Sorrentino, Matthias Kuenzel, Dominic Bresser, Hyeongseon Choi, Stefano Passerini, Dino Tonti, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401556825

                Abstract Thanks to their high voltage and delivered capacity, Li-rich transition metal (TM) oxide positive electrode (cathode) materials are among the most promising for next-generation lithium-ion-batteries, where Co-free Li-rich cathodes join reduced costs with competitive performance. However, their cycle-life remains limited, and the individual role of TMs is still not fully understood. The investigation of the TM chemical species&#8217; evolution along the first charge for Li1.2Mn0.56Ni0.16Co0.08O2 and Li1.2Mn0.6Ni0.2O2 has been accessed by means of operando multi edge XAS. The charge compensation mechanism has been studied and the effect induced by removing Co has been revealed. The absence of Co results in an accelerated and completed Ni oxidation along the first stage of charge and an inhibited formation of the undesired spinel phase and oxygen release at the end of the high voltage plateau. Interestingly, the oxygen release in the Co-containing material involves mainly the oxygen close to the Mn site and occurs while local structural interlayer re-arrangements are taking place.</description>
      <author>Laura Simonelli, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Shehab E. Ali, Andrea Sorrentino, Matthias Kuenzel, Dominic Bresser, Hyeongseon Choi, Stefano Passerini, Dino Tonti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4844249/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Component Synergistic Effect of Co9S8/FeBOx Composite system for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175959</link>
      <description>Chong Wang, Lianfang Ge, Yunxiao Hu, Huanlu Tu, Jia Li, Jian Xu, Hongwei Tian, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401558854

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chong Wang, Lianfang Ge, Yunxiao Hu, Huanlu Tu, Jia Li, Jian Xu, Hongwei Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175959</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Dynamic Surface Reconstruction of Electrocatalysts in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31635/renewables.024.202400064</link>
      <description>Liuqing Wang, Qinglei Meng, Meiling Xiao, Haibo Liu, Wei Wang, Di Yang, Renewables. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401566132

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liuqing Wang, Qinglei Meng, Meiling Xiao, Haibo Liu, Wei Wang, Di Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31635/renewables.024.202400064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quench-induced the formation of enriched oxygen vacancies on the surface of Co3O4 for boosting electrochemical sensing of glucose</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176004</link>
      <description>Ziyin Yang, Yaqi Kong, Chengcheng Qi, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401567354

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyin Yang, Yaqi Kong, Chengcheng Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Oxygen Vacancies-Enriched Triple Perovskite Oxide Electrocatalyst for Efficient and Stable Oxygen Evolution in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01536c</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Wu, Tixuan Xia, Lu Yang, Feifan Guo, Wei Jiang, Jihui Lang, Yunchao Ma, Jingdong Feng, Guangbo Che, Chunbo Liu, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401576633

                The development of anodic electrocatalysts toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in harsh acidic environments face significant challenges of low efficiency, instability and high cost. Ru-based oxides exhibit remarkable initial activity...</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Wu, Tixuan Xia, Lu Yang, Feifan Guo, Wei Jiang, Jihui Lang, Yunchao Ma, Jingdong Feng, Guangbo Che, Chunbo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01536c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pd/CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Interface with Abundant Oxygen Vacancies for Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution/Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03414</link>
      <description>Tianlong Zheng, Shiyuan Chen, Jiaqi Qin, Fei Yang, Jinhua Shi, Yongfeng Hu, Yujiang Song, Xiaobo Shi, Meng Gu, Miao Wang, Qinggang He, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401578726

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianlong Zheng, Shiyuan Chen, Jiaqi Qin, Fei Yang, Jinhua Shi, Yongfeng Hu, Yujiang Song, Xiaobo Shi, Meng Gu, Miao Wang, Qinggang He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Hydrogen Evolution on Pulsed Laser-Crafted Pt-Infused Oxygen-Deficient Black TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in Real-Time Using Raman Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04174</link>
      <description>Juhyeon Park, Binaya Kumar Sahu, Cheol Joo Moon, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Ahreum Min, S.H. Yun, Myong Yong Choi, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401579368

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juhyeon Park, Binaya Kumar Sahu, Cheol Joo Moon, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Ahreum Min, S.H. Yun, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extraordinary Hydrogen Evolution and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity From PPy@FeCo-LDH/NF Bifunctional Electrocatalyst in Alkaline Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6a91</link>
      <description>Boxuan Zhang, Jinxing Cui, Jia Li, Changlong Yang, Weiwei Dong, Jia Li, Yuanyuan Ma, Nan Zheng, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. 171(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401581329

                Alkaline water electrolysis is a promising technique for the production of hydrogen and oxygen. Nevertheless, the development of low-cost, high-activity metal-based electrocatalysts that can effectively catalyze the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a significant challenge. Herein, we polymerized Polypyrrole (PPy) with FeCo layered double metal hydroxide grown in situ on nickel foam (NF) (FeCo-LDH/NF) by electrochemical polymerization to acquire composite material PPy@FeCo-LDH/NF. As a promising electrocatalyst with dual functionality for the HER and OER, the HER overpotential of PPy@FeCo-LDH/NF was 153 mV, and the OER overpotential was 245 mV at a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 . It was because that PPy increased the number of active adsorption sites, which in turn regulated the ion transfer rate between the electrolyte and the prepared catalyst. At the same time, after 24 h of stability testing, the HER and OER capacitance retention rates were 96.7% and 97.1%, respectively.</description>
      <author>Boxuan Zhang, Jinxing Cui, Jia Li, Changlong Yang, Weiwei Dong, Jia Li, Yuanyuan Ma, Nan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6a91</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Interface Active Site of Mofs ( Zif-67) Sulfide by Rgo to Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4925528</link>
      <description>Hongjuan Hao, Huayan Pu, Dingze Lu, Xiao Zhou, Bo Zhang, Xin Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401583292

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongjuan Hao, Huayan Pu, Dingze Lu, Xiao Zhou, Bo Zhang, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4925528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A universal Strategy of Constructing Cr-NiFe MOF/CMC Aerogel Composite Catalysts for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01385a</link>
      <description>Xin&#8208;Yao Yu, Xiaohui Guo, Jiangcheng Zhang, Yuxin Jia, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Haoyu Yao, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401594383

                Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs)-based aerogel composite display extensive applications in such as catalysis, chemical, separation and biology aspects due to their high specific surface area, tailored structure and component features. The...</description>
      <author>Xin&#8208;Yao Yu, Xiaohui Guo, Jiangcheng Zhang, Yuxin Jia, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Haoyu Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01385a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoNi-phosphides with iron incorporation effectively boost hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.208</link>
      <description>Yafei Kuang, Shuang Zhao, Shang Gao, Na Song, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401598466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yafei Kuang, Shuang Zhao, Shang Gao, Na Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;SrZrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Cube-Decorated PbS Nanoflowers as Robust Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05127</link>
      <description>F. F. Alharbi, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Faheem Ashiq, Riaz Hussain, Salma Aman, Muhammad Najam&#8208;ul&#8208;Haq, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, T.A. Taha, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401609897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>F. F. Alharbi, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Faheem Ashiq, Riaz Hussain, Salma Aman, Muhammad Najam&#8208;ul&#8208;Haq, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, T.A. Taha</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron-doped diamond composites for durable oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.106</link>
      <description>Yalun Ku, Kuikui Zhang, Ying Guo, Shulong Chang, Yang Yu, Guang&#8208;Song Zheng, Han Gao, Dongsheng Song, John Xun Yang, Shaobo Cheng, Dong Lin, Chongxin Shan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401610695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yalun Ku, Kuikui Zhang, Ying Guo, Shulong Chang, Yang Yu, Guang&#8208;Song Zheng, Han Gao, Dongsheng Song, John Xun Yang, Shaobo Cheng, Dong Lin, Chongxin Shan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Active Site Local Proton Transfer in Porous Organic Polymers for Boosted Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414104</link>
      <description>Qian Zhao, Qingxin Zhang, Yuhan Xu, Aili Han, Hua He, Haoquan Zheng, Zhang Wei, Haitao Lei, Ulf&#8208;Peter Apfel, Rui Cao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401613779

                Improving proton transfer is vital for electrocatalysis with porous materials. Although several strategies are reported to assist proton transfer in channels, few studies are dedicated to improving proton transfer at the local environments of active sites in porous materials. Herein, we report on new Co&#8208;corrole&#8208;based porous organic polymers (POPs) with improved proton transfer for electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). By tuning the pore sizes and installing proton relays at Co corrole sites, we designed and synthesized POP&#8208;2&#8208;OH with improved proton transfer both in channels and at local Co active sites. This POP shows remarkable activity for both electrocatalytic ORR with E1/2 = 0.91 V vs RHE and OER with h10 = 255 mV. Therefore, this work is significant to present a strategy to improve active site local proton transfer in porous materials and highlight the key role of such structural functionalization in boosting oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhao, Qingxin Zhang, Yuhan Xu, Aili Han, Hua He, Haoquan Zheng, Zhang Wei, Haitao Lei, Ulf&#8208;Peter Apfel, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-capable spinel cobalt oxide nanoparticles for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution and water contaminant removal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-34682-z</link>
      <description>Siddhi S. Dakave, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, C.M. Kanamadi, Environmental Science and Pollution Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401616409

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Siddhi S. Dakave, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, C.M. Kanamadi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-34682-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Synthesis of Carbon Quantum Dots for Enhancing Photocatalytic Activity: Hydrogen/Oxygen Evolution and Dye Photodegradation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114996</link>
      <description>Cl&#225;udio C&#233;sar Weber Backes, Felipe Bado dos Reis, Guilherme B. Strapasson, Marcelo Assis, &#201;lson Longo, Daniel E. Weibel, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401630173

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cl&#225;udio C&#233;sar Weber Backes, Felipe Bado dos Reis, Guilherme B. Strapasson, Marcelo Assis, &#201;lson Longo, Daniel E. Weibel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation Mechanism and Hydrothermal Synthesis of Highly Active Ir&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ru&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04607</link>
      <description>Andreas Dueholm Bertelsen, Magnus Kl&#248;ve, Bo B. Iversen, Martin Bondesgaard, Rasmus S. Christensen, Ann&#8208;Christin Dippel, Qinyu Li, Richard D. Tilley, Mads R. V. J&#248;rgensen, Bo B. Iversen, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401631546

                Iridium dioxide (IrO</description>
      <author>Andreas Dueholm Bertelsen, Magnus Kl&#248;ve, Bo B. Iversen, Martin Bondesgaard, Rasmus S. Christensen, Ann&#8208;Christin Dippel, Qinyu Li, Richard D. Tilley, Mads R. V. J&#248;rgensen, Bo B. Iversen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TM-doping Modulated p-d Orbital Coupling to Enhance the Oxygen Evolution Performance ofNi3S2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00503a</link>
      <description>Qiuhong Li, Minghao Zhang, Rui Wang, Jing Pan, Huailiang Fu, Nanoscale Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401644755

                The design of an ideal catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is very important for electrocatalytic water-splitting. The Ni3S2 (101) facet is considered to be a suitable electrocatalyst owing...</description>
      <author>Qiuhong Li, Minghao Zhang, Rui Wang, Jing Pan, Huailiang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00503a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Structure Amorphization and Electronic Structure Reconstruction of FeCoNiCrMo&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; High&#8208;Entropy Alloy Nanoparticles for Highly Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405596</link>
      <description>Xian Zhou, He Zhu, Shu Fu, Si Lan, Horst Hahn, Jianrong Zeng, Tao Feng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401652842

                Abstract The complexity of the multielement interaction in high&#8208;entropy alloys (HEAs) may provide more active sites to adapt different catalytic reaction steps in oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Investigating the correlation between structure and performance of HEAs electrocatalysts is both essential and challenging. In this work, FeCoNiCrMo x HEA nanoparticles are successfully fabricated utilizing a unique nanofabrication method called inert gas condensation. With the increase of high&#8208;valence metal component Mo, the atomic structure amorphization and electronic structure reconstruction are unveiled. According to the X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy valence spectra, the d&#8208;band center of FeCoNiCrMo x is ascending, and thus enhancing the adsorption energy. Synchrotron pair distribution function analysis reflects the degree of structural disorder and reveals a robust correlation with the intrinsic OER activities of the electrocatalysts. FeCoNiCrMo 1.0 high&#8208;entropy metallic glass nanoparticles exhibit an outstanding OER performance with an ultralow overpotential of 294.5 mV at a high current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work brings fundamental and practical insights into the modulation mechanism of metal components of HEAs catalysts for developing OER.</description>
      <author>Xian Zhou, He Zhu, Shu Fu, Si Lan, Horst Hahn, Jianrong Zeng, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecting Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;NiSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Triple&#8208;Interface Heterostructure on MXene Nanosheets for Boosting Water Splitting by Electronic Modulation and Interface Effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403596</link>
      <description>Yan Liang, Yonghang Chen, Jinbo Xie, Hao Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401652872

                Abstract Strategically engineering electrocatalysts with optimized interfacial electronic architectures and accelerated reaction dynamics is pivotal for augmenting hydrogen generation via alkaline water electrolysis on an industrial scale. Herein, a novel triple&#8208;interface heterostructure Ni 3 Se 4 &#8208;NiSe 2 &#8208;Co 3 O 4 nanoarrays are designed anchored on Ti 3 C 2 T x MXene (Ni 3 Se 4 &#8208;NiSe 2 &#8208;Co 3 O 4 /MXene) with significant work function difference (&#916;&#934;) as bifunctional electrocatalysts for water electrolysis. Theoretical calculations combined with experiments uncover the pivotal role of the interface&#8208;induced electric field in steering charge redistribution, which in turn modulates the adsorption and desorption kinetics of reaction intermediates. Furthermore, the synergistic interaction between Ni 3 Se 4 &#8208;NiSe 2 &#8208;Co 3 O 4 and Ti 3 C 2 T x MXene nanosheets endows the hybrids with a large electrochemical surface area, abundantly active sites, and high conductivity. Thus, Ni 3 Se 4 &#8208;NiSe 2 &#8208;Co 3 O 4 /MXene manifests exceptional catalytic prowess for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In addition, the Ni 3 Se 4 &#8208;NiSe 2 &#8208;Co 3 O 4 /MXene electrocatalyst in the water electrolyzer delivers excellent performance and maintains commendable stability beyond 100 h of electrocatalytic operation.</description>
      <author>Yan Liang, Yonghang Chen, Jinbo Xie, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Electronic Structure of Cobalt&#8208;Vanadium Bimetal Catalysts for High&#8208;Stable Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408634</link>
      <description>Zhijian Liang, Di Shen, Wei Yao, Fanfei Sun, Ying Xie, Lei Wang, Honggang Fu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401653113

                Abstract Modulating the electronic structure of catalysts to effectively couple the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential for developing high&#8208;efficiency anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE). Herein, a coral&#8208;like nanoarray composed of nanosheets through the synergistic layering effect of cobalt and the 1D guiding of vanadium is synthesized, which promotes extensive contact between the active sites and electrolyte. The HER and OER activities can be enhanced by modulating the electronic structure through nitridation and phosphorization, respectively, enhancing the strength of metal&#8208;H bond to optimize hydrogen adsorption and facilitating the proton transfer to improve the transformation of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates. Resultantly, the AEMWE achieves a current density of 500 mA cm &#8211;2 at 1.76 V for 1000 h in 1.0 M KOH at 70 &#176;C. The energy consumption is 4.21 kWh Nm &#8211;3 with the producing hydrogen cost of $0.93 per kg H 2 . Operando synchrotron radiation and Bode phase angle analyses reveal that during the high&#8208;energy consumed OER, the dissolution of vanadium species transforms distorted Co&#8722;O octahedral into regular octahedral structures, accompanied by a shortening of the Co&#8722;Co bond length. This structural evolution facilitates the formation of oxygen intermediates, thus accelerating the reaction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Zhijian Liang, Di Shen, Wei Yao, Fanfei Sun, Ying Xie, Lei Wang, Honggang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium Single&#8208;Atom Modulated Protonated Iridium Oxide for Acidic Water Oxidation in Proton Exchange Membrane Electrolysers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407394</link>
      <description>Jialin Tang, Xinyan Liu, Xiaoxia Xiong, Qingqian Zeng, Yuan Ji, Chunxiao Liu, Jiawei Li, Hongliang Zeng, Yizhou Dai, Xinyan Zhang, Chengbo Li, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Chuan Xia, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401653631

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolysers promise to usher in a new era of clean energy, but they remain a formidable obstacle in designing active and durable electrocatalysts for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, a protonated iridium oxide embedded with single&#8208;atom dispersed ruthenium atoms (H 3.8 Ir 1&#8722; x Ru x O 4 ) that demonstrates exceptional activity and stability in acidic water oxidation is introduced. The single Ru dopants favorably induce localized oxygen vacancies in the Ir&#9472;O lattice, synergistically strengthening the adsorption of OOH* intermediates and enhancing the intrinsic OER activity. In addition, the preferential oxidation of Ru and the electronegativity of the oxygen vacancies significantly stabilize the Ir&#9472;O active sites, improving the OER stability. Consequently, the H 3.8 Ir 1&#9472; x Ru x O 4 catalyst shows an overpotential of 255 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and displays exceptional catalytic endurance in acidic electrolytes, surpassing 1100 h, representing a remarkable one&#8208;order&#8208;of&#8208;magnitude increase in stability compared to that of pristine H 3.8 IrO 4 . A proton exchange membrane electrolyser utilizing the H 3.8 Ir 1&#8722; x Ru x O 4 catalyst as an anode exhibits stable performance for more than 1280 h under a high current density of 2 A cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Jialin Tang, Xinyan Liu, Xiaoxia Xiong, Qingqian Zeng, Yuan Ji, Chunxiao Liu, Jiawei Li, Hongliang Zeng, Yizhou Dai, Xinyan Zhang, Chengbo Li, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Qiu Jiang, Tingting Zheng, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating electron structure of active sites in high-entropy metal sulfide nanoparticles with greatly improved electrocatalytic performance for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.221</link>
      <description>Jinhui Tong, Jiayao Fang, Shaobo Yang, Fang Nian, Lumei Pu, Zijun Ma, Jinhui Tong, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 84(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401658409

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinhui Tong, Jiayao Fang, Shaobo Yang, Fang Nian, Lumei Pu, Zijun Ma, Jinhui Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin Engineering of Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C by Axial Ligand Modulation for Enhanced Bifunctional Oxygen Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409794</link>
      <description>Jingyuan Qiao, Chengjie Lu, Lingqiao Kong, Jing Zhang, Qipu Lin, Haibin Huang, Caifang Li, Wei He, Min Zhou, ZhengMing Sun, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401658644

                Abstract Iron&#8208;based single&#8208;atom catalysts (Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C) exhibit excellent oxygen reduction activity but struggle with bifunctional performance due to their poor oxygen evolution activity. Although the Fe spin state is found to be closely associated with enhanced bifunctional activity, controllably regulating the Fe spin state remains a challenge. Here, the controllable regulation of Fe spin state is directly achieved through competitive coordination between chlorine and pyridine nitrogen in the axial direction of Fe&#9472;N 4 . The spin state of Fe is regulated from high spin to intermediate spin by the modulation of axial ligands from weak&#8208;field ligand chlorine to strong&#8208;field ligand pyridinic nitrogen, which leads to the enhanced bifunctional activity of N&#9472;FeN 4 with a small potential gap (&#916; E = 0.68 V). Theoretical calculations indicate that the spin state turning is accompanied by an enhanced binding strength between Fe sites and *OH leading to a significant decrease in the OER barrier. Moreover, N&#9472;FeN 4 exhibits sufficient durability for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) (over 50 h), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) (over 200 h), and the assembled zinc&#8211;air battery (over 1000 h). Here a novel approach is proposed for designing efficient catalysts based on spin state and profound insights into Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C spin state for bifunctional oxygen catalysis.</description>
      <author>Jingyuan Qiao, Chengjie Lu, Lingqiao Kong, Jing Zhang, Qipu Lin, Haibin Huang, Caifang Li, Wei He, Min Zhou, ZhengMing Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409794</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambipolar Nature Accelerates Dual&#8208;Functionality on Ni/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N@NC for Simultaneous Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution in Electrochemical Water Splitting System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400059</link>
      <description>Gnanaprakasam Janani, Subramani Surendran, Dae Jun Moon, P. S. Ramesh, Joon Young Kim, Yoongu Lim, Krishnan Veeramani, Shivraj Mahadik, Sebastian Cyril Jesudass, Jinuk Choi, Il Kim, Philipp Jung, Heechae Choi, Gibum Kwon, Kyoungsuk Jin, Jung Kyu Kim, Yong Il Park, Jaeyeong Heo, Kootak Hong, Young Soo Kang, Uk Sim, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401658698

                Abstract Metal nitrides with extraordinary electrochemical characteristics established widespread applications in energy devices. Inspired by the recent research on promising heterostructured catalysts, the preparation of a nitride&#8208;based heterostructure via a facile approach involving a one&#8208;step nitridation process is revisited. An innovative Ni/Ni 3 N is decorated on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (NC) and evaluated for its dual&#8208;functionality as a catalyst in the electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (EHER) and the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (EOER). In contrast to Ni@NC and pristine NC, Ni/Ni 3 N@NC with the well&#8208;constructed NC significantly enhanced its catalytic performance toward EHER and EOER in a water electrolyzer. The water electrolyzer consists of Ni/Ni 3 N@NC as both the anode and cathode achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a remarkably low voltage of 1.52 V. The designed catalyst takes full advantage of its heterostructure and ambipolar behavior leading to the presence of active sites for EOER and EHER, as confirmed by in&#8208;situ Raman analysis. These results provide important guidance on designing an efficient and cost&#8208;effective heterostructured dual&#8208;functional catalyst as well as revealing the mechanism at the interface between the surface of an ambipolar catalyst and electrolyte.</description>
      <author>Gnanaprakasam Janani, Subramani Surendran, Dae Jun Moon, P. S. Ramesh, Joon Young Kim, Yoongu Lim, Krishnan Veeramani, Shivraj Mahadik, Sebastian Cyril Jesudass, Jinuk Choi, Il Kim, Philipp Jung, Heechae Choi, Gibum Kwon, Kyoungsuk Jin, Jung Kyu Kim, Yong Il Park, Jaeyeong Heo, Kootak Hong, Young Soo Kang, Uk Sim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a medium-entropy and A-site deficient perovskite oxide for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.211</link>
      <description>Wenying Yang, Shimin Lai, Kaitao Li, Siyu Pan, Feifei Dong, Zhan Lin, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 84(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401671895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenying Yang, Shimin Lai, Kaitao Li, Siyu Pan, Feifei Dong, Zhan Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical study of iridum oxide materials for the oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE)</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4401596562</link>
      <description>Silvia Dur&#225;n, Marine Elmaalouf, Mateusz Odziomek, Marco Faustini, Marion Giraud, C&#233;dric Boissi&#232;re, Jennifer P&#233;ron, C&#233;dric Tard, No host. None(None)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4401596562

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silvia Dur&#225;n, Marine Elmaalouf, Mateusz Odziomek, Marco Faustini, Marion Giraud, C&#233;dric Boissi&#232;re, Jennifer P&#233;ron, C&#233;dric Tard</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4401596562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noble metal free high entropy alloys with amorphous based heterostructure for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01290a</link>
      <description>Jia Yao, Yinan Zhu, Ting Dai, Tao L&#252;, Yin&#8217;an Zhu, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401649958

                Designing cost-effective catalysts with high activity and stability for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is important in the scaling-up of water electrolysis process for hydrogen production. Herein, (FeNiCuCoZn)90-xVxP10 (x=10,15, and 20,...</description>
      <author>Jia Yao, Yinan Zhu, Ting Dai, Tao L&#252;, Yin&#8217;an Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01290a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gd Active Sites Modulating the Intermediate Adsorption and Activation in Exfoliated Gadolinium Telluride for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00415</link>
      <description>Roshan Nazir, Partha Kumbhakar, Sakshi Agarwal, Arko Parui, Soumyabrata Roy, Pulickel M. Ajayan, Abhishek K. Singh, Sudhanshu Sharma, Chandra Sekhar Tiwary, ACS Applied Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401613370

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Roshan Nazir, Partha Kumbhakar, Sakshi Agarwal, Arko Parui, Soumyabrata Roy, Pulickel M. Ajayan, Abhishek K. Singh, Sudhanshu Sharma, Chandra Sekhar Tiwary</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the Structure and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in Metal Organic Frameworks via Symmetrical Control on the Functional Groups of Ligands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00641k</link>
      <description>Zhi Li, Jia Li, Jie Lei, Chengjie Yin, Xiaohui Wu, Jin&#8208;Song Hu, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401522120

                The crystal structure and electrocatalytic performance of Ni-based MOFs were controlled by the symmetrical engineering of Br functional groups on the terephthalic acid ligand. The asymmetric coordination between the metal...</description>
      <author>Zhi Li, Jia Li, Jie Lei, Chengjie Yin, Xiaohui Wu, Jin&#8208;Song Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00641k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective oxygen evolution of NCF@CoNiO2 with one-dimensional core-shell structure synthesized by induced effect of polymer nanofibers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.192</link>
      <description>Ning Song, Wenjie Chen, Jia Jia, Hansong Cheng, Hongjun Dong, Yun Wang, Chunmei Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401598671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Song, Wenjie Chen, Jia Jia, Hansong Cheng, Hongjun Dong, Yun Wang, Chunmei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of iron-doped nickel cobalt phosphide nanoparticles via solvothermal phosphidization and their application in oxygen evolution in alkaline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.038</link>
      <description>Xuan Liu, Zhiping Hu, Pengfei Xing, Jiquan Guo, Yichuang Xing, Shuling Liu, Chao Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 677(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4401528096

                Multi-metallic phosphides offer the possibility to combine the strategies of surface reconstruction, electronic interaction and mechanistic pathway tuning to achieve high electrocatalytic oxygen evolution activity. Here, iron-doped nickel cobalt phosphide nanoparticles (Fe</description>
      <author>Xuan Liu, Zhiping Hu, Pengfei Xing, Jiquan Guo, Yichuang Xing, Shuling Liu, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Properties of Ni&lt;sub&gt;1+&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;A&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;N (A = Mo, W): The Effect of Mo and W in the Oxygen Evolution and Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/nano.202400051</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Antonio Coca Clemente, Isabel Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, P. Oc&#243;n, M. Retuerto, Sergio Rojas, Nano Select. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401638572

                ABSTRACT Ni, Fe&#8208;based nitrides have been widely studied for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, displaying electrocatalytic activities similar to Pt and other noble metal electrocatalysts. The incorporation of small amounts of Mo or W on these Ni, Fe&#8208;based nitrides is expected to have a significant effect on the electrocatalytic performance of these materials, especially for the HER activity. In this work, transition metal nitrides (TMNs) with the empirical formula Ni 1+ x Fe 3&#8722; x &#8722; y A y N (A = Mo, W), were obtained in two steps: synthesis of the transition metal oxide precursors by an easy, one&#8208;pot sol&#8211;gel polymerization method followed by nitridation under ammonia atmosphere to obtain the final TMNs. Their HER and OER catalytic performances in alkaline electrolyte (0.1 M KOH solution) were studied and it was observed that the incorporation of small quantities of Mo or W in these Ni, Fe&#8208;based nitrides (Ni 1+ x Fe 3&#8722; x &#8722; y A y N, where y = 0.1) results in improved HER and OER activities, especially in the TMN that contains W (i.e., Ni 1+ x Fe 2.9&#8722; x W 0.1 N), where the overpotentials were 348 mV for OER and 269 mV for HER. These values are lower than those obtained for Ni 1+ x Fe 3&#8722; x N, which are 395 mV for OER and 368 mV for HER.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Antonio Coca Clemente, Isabel Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, P. Oc&#243;n, M. Retuerto, Sergio Rojas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/nano.202400051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution and Competitive Struggles of Lactiplantibacillus plantarum under Different Oxygen Contents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25168861</link>
      <description>Sojeong Heo, Eun Jin Jung, Mi&#8208;Kyung Park, Moon&#8208;Hee Sung, Do&#8208;Won Jeong, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 25(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401583853

                Lactiplantibacillus (Lb.) plantarum is known as a benign bacterium found in various habitats, including the intestines of animals and fermented foods. Since animal intestines lack oxygen, while fermented foods provide a limited or more oxygen environment, this study aimed to investigate whether there were genetic differences in the growth of Lb. plantarum under aerobic vs. anaerobic conditions. Genomic analysis of Lb. plantarum obtained from five sources&#8212;animals, dairy products, fermented meat, fermented vegetables, and humans&#8212;was conducted. The analysis included not only an examination of oxygen-utilizing genes but also a comparative pan-genomic analysis to investigate evolutionary relationships between genomes. The ancestral gene analysis of the evolutionary pathway classified Lb. plantarum into groups A and B, with group A further subdivided into A1 and A2. It was confirmed that group A1 does not possess the narGHIJ operon, which is necessary for energy production under limited oxygen conditions. Additionally, it was found that group A1 has experienced more gene acquisition and loss compared to groups A2 and B. Despite an initial assumption that there would be genetic distinctions based on the origin (aerobic or anaerobic conditions), it was observed that such differentiation could not be attributed to the origin. However, the evolutionary process indicated that the loss of genes related to nitrate metabolism was essential in anaerobic or limited oxygen conditions, contrary to the initial hypothesis.</description>
      <author>Sojeong Heo, Eun Jin Jung, Mi&#8208;Kyung Park, Moon&#8208;Hee Sung, Do&#8208;Won Jeong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25168861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of progressive evolution of oxygen extraction fraction in the brain during acute stroke by using quantitative susceptibility mapping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58530/2023/2111</link>
      <description>Xiaodong Zhang, Yuguang Meng, Chunxia Li, Proceedings on CD-ROM - International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine. Scientific Meeting and Exhibition/Proceedings of the International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, Scientific Meeting and Exhibition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401572051

                Oxygen extraction fraction (OEF) has been suggested to be an effective measure to assess the oxygen metabolism and viability of tissue at risk. The preliminary results in a monkey model of stroke demonstrated progressive OEF reduction in both grey matter and white matter after pMCAO, in agreement with the neuron loss and fiber denegation as indicated by diffusion MRI indices following stroke. The findings suggest QSM derived OEF could provide additional information about the oxygen metabolism of the tissue and may be used to assess the ischemia-induced damage of the brain during acute stroke.</description>
      <author>Xiaodong Zhang, Yuguang Meng, Chunxia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58530/2023/2111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Work Function Induced Local Charge Regulation towards Activating Octamolybdate Cluster-based Solid for Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02645d</link>
      <description>Harshita Bagdwal, Parul Sood, Anisa Dhillon, Ashi Singh, Monika Singh, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401551338

                The advancement of highly robust and efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions (OER) under acidic conditions is imperative for the sustainable production of green hydrogen. In accomplishing sustainable and sturdy...</description>
      <author>Harshita Bagdwal, Parul Sood, Anisa Dhillon, Ashi Singh, Monika Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02645d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition regulation of Ni-BDC MOF architecture to enhance electrocatalytic urea oxidation in alkaline solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00550c</link>
      <description>Xiaoyue Fu, Bo Pu, Pan Li, R. Ming, Qian Lv, Xiaobo Chen, Lihong Tian, Materials Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401667246

                Urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is a promising substitution of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on anode for highly efficient H2 production. However, the sluggish kinetics and high oxidation potential of...</description>
      <author>Xiaoyue Fu, Bo Pu, Pan Li, R. Ming, Qian Lv, Xiaobo Chen, Lihong Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00550c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace F-doped Co3O4 nanoneedles for enhanced acidic water oxidation activity via promoting OH coverage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc01895h</link>
      <description>Genyan Hao, Tao Zhao, Qiang Fang, Yunzhen Jia, Dandan Li, Dazhong Zhong, Jinping Li, Qiang Zhao, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401596526

                Exploring earth-abundant and efficient electrocatalysts to replace Ir and Ru for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential to reduce the cost of clean hydrogen production. Here, we show that...</description>
      <author>Genyan Hao, Tao Zhao, Qiang Fang, Yunzhen Jia, Dandan Li, Dazhong Zhong, Jinping Li, Qiang Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc01895h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation via crafting Co-O-W bridge bonds on Amorphous core/shell NiCo-ZIF@POM catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01319k</link>
      <description>Tianhao Yu, Peng Gao, Hong Du, Ling Dong, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401626798

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) requires the development of a strong and efficient electrocatalyst due to its slow mechanism and high overpotential. Hence, we assembled POM and NiCo-ZIF-67 to obtain...</description>
      <author>Tianhao Yu, Peng Gao, Hong Du, Ling Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01319k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolation and Crystallographic Characterization of an Octavalent Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Diamond Core</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07335</link>
      <description>Joseph E. Schneider, Shilin Zeng, Sophie W. Anferov, Alexander S. Filatov, John S. Anderson, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401602947

                High-valent cobalt oxides play a pivotal role in alternative energy technology as catalysts for water splitting and as cathodes in lithium-ion batteries. Despite this importance, the properties governing the stability of high-valent cobalt oxides and specifically possible oxygen evolution pathways are not clear. One root of this limited understanding is the scarcity of high-valent Co(IV)-containing model complexes; there are no reports of stable, well-defined complexes with multiple Co(IV) centers. Here, an oxidatively robust fluorinated ligand scaffold enables the isolation and crystallographic characterization of a Co(IV)</description>
      <author>Joseph E. Schneider, Shilin Zeng, Sophie W. Anferov, Alexander S. Filatov, John S. Anderson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;organic framework materials as bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/batt.202400402</link>
      <description>Fangqing Liu, Xiaoyi Lu, Chenglong Shi, Zhipeng Sun, Batteries &amp; Supercaps. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401615399

                Rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries offer the advantages of environmental friendliness, safety, low prices and high energy density, and are highly valued. However, the major challenge faced by rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries nowadays is the low energy efficiency due to the slow reaction kinetics of electrocatalyst at the air cathode. Bifunctional catalysts are key to the development of Zn&#8208;air batteries by improving their overall performance and long&#8208;term cycling stability. Metal&#8208;organic framework (MOF) materials have shown great benefits as oxygen electrocatalysts in promoting oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This paper reviews the recent advances of three kinds of MOF materials as bifunctional catalysts for rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries. Additionally, this paper also discusses the synthetic design strategy of MOF composite derivatives, and concludes by suggesting the application of MOF materials in the field of rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Fangqing Liu, Xiaoyi Lu, Chenglong Shi, Zhipeng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/batt.202400402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A High&#8208;Entropy Oxyhydroxide with a Graded Metal Network Structure for Efficient and Robust Alkaline Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202406008</link>
      <description>Chenxu Zhang, Di Yin, Yuxuan Zhang, Yuxiang Sun, Xinbing Zhao, Wugang Liao, Johnny C. Ho, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401550930

                Designing high-entropy oxyhydroxides (HEOs) electrocatalysts with controlled nanostructures is vital for efficient and stable water-splitting electrocatalysts. Herein, a novel HEOs material (FeCoNiWCuOOH@Cu) containing five non-noble metal elements derived by electrodeposition on a 3D double-continuous porous Cu support is created. This support, prepared via the liquid metal dealloying method, offers a high specific surface area and rapid mass/charge transfer channels. The resulting high-entropy FeCoNiWCuOOH nanosheets provide a dense distribution of active sites. The heterostructure between Cu skeletons and FeCoNiWCuOOH nanosheets enhances mass transfer, electronic structure coupling, and overall structural stability, leading to excellent activities in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and water splitting reaction. At 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Chenxu Zhang, Di Yin, Yuxuan Zhang, Yuxiang Sun, Xinbing Zhao, Wugang Liao, Johnny C. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202406008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Active Site Local Proton Transfer in Porous Organic Polymers for Boosted Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414104</link>
      <description>Qian Zhao, Qingxin Zhang, Yuhan Xu, Aili Han, Hua He, Haoquan Zheng, Zhang Wei, Haitao Lei, Ulf&#8208;Peter Apfel, Rui Cao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401614118

                Improving proton transfer is vital for electrocatalysis with porous materials. Although several strategies are reported to assist proton transfer in channels, few studies are dedicated to improving proton transfer at the local environments of active sites in porous materials. Herein, we report on new Co&#8208;corrole&#8208;based porous organic polymers (POPs) with improved proton transfer for electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). By tuning the pore sizes and installing proton relays at Co corrole sites, we designed and synthesized POP&#8208;2&#8208;OH with improved proton transfer both in channels and at local Co active sites. This POP shows remarkable activity for both electrocatalytic ORR with E1/2 = 0.91 V vs RHE and OER with h10 = 255 mV. Therefore, this work is significant to present a strategy to improve active site local proton transfer in porous materials and highlight the key role of such structural functionalization in boosting oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Qian Zhao, Qingxin Zhang, Yuhan Xu, Aili Han, Hua He, Haoquan Zheng, Zhang Wei, Haitao Lei, Ulf&#8208;Peter Apfel, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N,F co&#8208;doped carbon derived from spent bleaching earth waste as oxygen electrocatalyst support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400160</link>
      <description>Behzad Aghabarari, Esmat Ebadati, Jes&#250;s Cebollada, David Fern&#225;ndez-Inchusta, M.V. Mart&#305;&#769;nez-Huerta, ChemPlusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401642010

                Affordable nitrogen and fluorine co&#8208;doped carbon nanostructure was prepared from the hazardous industrial waste of edible oil refinery, spent bleaching earth (SBE), and used as raw material for obtaining high&#8208;performance non&#8208;noble metal bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts. Waste SBE contains 35 per cent residue non&#8208;saturated oil as a carbon source and the assistance of montmorillonite (MMT) as the template. This study converts waste SBE into a fluorine&#8208;doped carbon nanostructure through a pyrolysis process followed by removing the aluminosilicate layers of the MMT by HF etching. Furthermore, the impregnation of the support with Co and Fe nitrates readily gives rise to N, F co&#8208;doped carbon (NFC) electrocatalysts, as confirmed by XPS analysis. Electrochemical results evidenced that the Co&#8208;NFC catalyst proved to be a valuable bifunctional competitor for oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media, showing activity in both reactions and superior stability compared with the Fe&#8208;NFC catalyst in accelerated tests. This work offers a straightforward, economical and eco&#8208;friendly strategy for designing N, F co&#8208;doped carbon&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen reactions in electrochemical devices.</description>
      <author>Behzad Aghabarari, Esmat Ebadati, Jes&#250;s Cebollada, David Fern&#225;ndez-Inchusta, M.V. Mart&#305;&#769;nez-Huerta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400160</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphitic carbon nitride functionalized with NiO nanoaggregates: An X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0003732</link>
      <description>Enrico Scattolin, Mattia Benedet, Davide Barreca, G. Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Chiara Maccato, Surface Science Spectra. 31(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401577297

                The design and synthesis of low-cost oxygen evolution reaction (OER) photoelectrocatalysts endowed with high activity and durability is of utmost importance for sustainable energy generation via solar-assisted water splitting. In this regard, and in the framework of our recent activities, we have focused on the electrophoretic deposition of graphitic carbon nitride (gCN) specimens containing dispersed NiO nanoaggregates on carbon cloth substrates. In the present study, the attention is devoted to the x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy characterization of a representative gCN&#8211;NiO specimen. In particular, we provide an analysis of C 1s, N 1s, O 1s, and Ni 2p regions, discussing in detail the main spectral features. The obtained results, that provide evidence for a direct electronic interplay between the single material components, may serve as a useful comparison for additional research on analogous materials for energy and environmental applications.</description>
      <author>Enrico Scattolin, Mattia Benedet, Davide Barreca, G. Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Chiara Maccato</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0003732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel&#8208;Type Metal Oxides with Tailored Amorphous/Crystalline Heterointerfaces for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410439</link>
      <description>Mengying Wang, Feng Xia, Shan Li, Yuxing Ma, Yuxin Peng, Shujiao Yang, Haibo Liu, Haitao Lei, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, Zhang Wei, Rui Cao, Haoquan Zheng, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401652766

                Abstract Metal oxides with spinel structure have garnered increasing attention as promising alternatives to noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts. However, these electrocatalysts often fail to simultaneously exhibit high activity and stability for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), limiting their applications in electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, crystalline/amorphous heterogeneous interfaces are successfully introduced into spinel NiCo 2 O 4 nanosheets, which are grown in situ on carbon cloth (CC), denoted as NiCo 2 O 4 &#8208;B&#8208;CC. The amorphous/crystalline heterostructures combine the advantages of both phases in electrocatalysts. The amorphous phase of the spinel NiCo 2 O 4 nanosheets modulates the electron density, provides abundant oxygen single vacancies as active sites, and enhances the corrosion resistance, while the crystalline phase improves conductivity. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations are performed to investigate the influence of surface oxygen single vacancy (SV O ) on the activity of the OER and HER processes. The NiCo&#8322;O&#8324;&#8208;B&#8208;CC exhibits overpotentials of only 26 mV for HER and 215 mV for OER at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . It exhibits excellent electrocatalytic performance for water splitting, achieving a current density of 400 mA cm &#8722;2 at an applied voltage of 2.0 V. The construction of crystalline/amorphous heterogeneous interfaces in electrocatalysts provides novel approach for enhancing the electrocatalytic performance of metal oxides in water splitting.</description>
      <author>Mengying Wang, Feng Xia, Shan Li, Yuxing Ma, Yuxin Peng, Shujiao Yang, Haibo Liu, Haitao Lei, Jing&#8208;Shuang Dang, Zhang Wei, Rui Cao, Haoquan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxyanion Engineering on RuO2 for Efficient Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413653</link>
      <description>Ying Duan, Li Wang, W. Zheng, Xiaolong Zhang, Xiaoran Wang, Guojin Feng, Ziyou Yu, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401513399

                In proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE), the anode oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts rely heavily on the expensive and scarce iridium&#8208;based materials. Ruthenium dioxide (RuO2) with lower price and higher OER activity, has been explored for the similar task, but has been restricted by the poor stability. Herein, we developed an anion modification strategy to improve the OER performance of RuO2 in acidic media. The designed multicomponent catalyst based on sulfate anchored on RuO2/MoO3 displays a low overpotential of 190 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and stably operates for 500 hours with a very low degradation rate of 20 &#956;V h&#8208;1. When assembled in a PEMWE cell, this catalyst as an anode shows an excellent stability at 500 mA cm&#8208;2 for 150 h. Experimental and theoretical results revealed that MoO3 could stabilize sulfate anion on RuO2 surface to suppress its leaching during OER. Such MoO3&#8208;anchored sulfate not only reduces the formation energy of *OOH intermediate on RuO2, but also impedes both the surface Ru and lattice oxygen loss, thereby achieving the high OER activity and exceptional durability.</description>
      <author>Ying Duan, Li Wang, W. Zheng, Xiaolong Zhang, Xiaoran Wang, Guojin Feng, Ziyou Yu, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413653</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Construction of Honeycomb-like Carbon Network-Encapsulated MoSe2 Nanocrystals as Bifunctional Catalysts for Highly Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163877</link>
      <description>Changjie Ou, Zhongkai Huang, Xiaoping Yan, Xiangzhong Kong, Xi Chen, Shi Li, Lihua Wang, Zhongmin Wan, Molecules. 29(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401647067

                The scalable fabrication of cost-efficient bifunctional catalysts with enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance plays a significant role in overall water splitting in hydrogen production fields. MoSe2 is considered to be one of the most promising candidates because of its low cost and high catalytic activity. Herein, hierarchical nitrogen-doped carbon networks were constructed to enhance the catalytic activity of the MoSe2-based materials by scalable free-drying combined with an in situ selenization strategy. The rationally designed carbonaceous network-encapsulated MoSe2 composite (MoSe2/NC) endows a continuous honeycomb-like structure. When utilized as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for both HER and OER, the MoSe2/NC electrode exhibits excellent electrochemical performance. Significantly, the MoSe2/NC&#8214;MoSe2/NC cells require a mere 1.5 V to reach a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for overall water splitting in 1 M KOH. Ex situ characterizations and electrochemical kinetic analysis reveal that the superior catalytic performance of the MoSe2/NC composite is mainly attributed to fast electron and ion transportation and good structural stability, which is derived from the abundant active sites and excellent structural flexibility of the honeycomb-like carbon network. This work offers a promising pathway to the scalable fabrication of advanced non-noble bifunctional electrodes for highly efficient hydrogen evolution.</description>
      <author>Changjie Ou, Zhongkai Huang, Xiaoping Yan, Xiangzhong Kong, Xi Chen, Shi Li, Lihua Wang, Zhongmin Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163877</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bubble&#8208;Guidance Breaking Gas Shield for Highly Efficient Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405493</link>
      <description>Yuliang Li, Jia Li, Li L&#252;, Jianjing Gao, Li Wang, Wentao Zou, Honghao Li, Qian Zhang, Yan Li, Xiaofang Zhang, Dongliang Tian, Jia Li, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401554082

                Overall water splitting is a promising technology for sustainable hydrogen production, but the primary challenge is removing bubbles from the electrode surface quickly to increase hydrogen production. Inspired by the directional fluid transport properties of natural biological surfaces like Nepenthes peristome and Morpho butterfly's wings, here a strategy is demonstrated to achieve highly efficient overall water splitting by a bubble-guidance electrode, that is, an anisotropic groove-micro/nanostructured porous electrode (GMPE). Gradient groove micro/nanostructures on the GMPE serve as high-speed bubble transmission channels and exhibit superior bubble-guidance capabilities. The synergistic effect of the asymmetric Laplace pressure generated between microscale porous structure and groove patterns and the buoyancy along the groove patterns pushes the produced bubbles directionally to spread, transport, and detach from the electrode surface in time. Moreover, the low adhesive nanosheet arrays are beneficial to reduce bubble size and increase bubble release frequency, which cooperatively improve mass transfer with the microscale structure. Notably, GMPE outperforms planar-micro/nanostructured porous electrode (PMPE) in hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions, with GMPE||GMPE showing better water splitting performance than commercially available RuO</description>
      <author>Yuliang Li, Jia Li, Li L&#252;, Jianjing Gao, Li Wang, Wentao Zou, Honghao Li, Qian Zhang, Yan Li, Xiaofang Zhang, Dongliang Tian, Jia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional MnCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Se&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nano&#8208;cubes directly grown on nickel foam for effective water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20059</link>
      <description>Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Karam Jabbour, Nigarish Bano, Muhammad Yousaf Ur Rehman, Razan A. Alshgari, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401523731

                Abstract Green and sustainable energy alternatives to replace fossil fuels are a topic of research in scientific community, thus yielding pursuit of advancing renewable energy systems with hydrogen emerging as a suitable and viable alternative. Efficient and non&#8208;precious metal catalysts are crucial for large&#8208;scale electrochemical water splitting yielding clean H 2 . Here, a novel two&#8208;step hydrothermal synthesis approach to fabricate manganese&#8211;cobalt selenide nano&#8208;cubes grown directly on nickel foam (NF) (MnCo 2 Se 4 /NF) is adopted. Leveraging its hierarchically structured architecture, augmented active sites, and electrochemically active surface area, MnCo 2 Se 4 /NF material demonstrates exceptional electrocatalytic performance for both water oxidation and reduction. With an overpotential of 233 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and 187 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction at a current density of 10 mA/cm 2 , MnCo 2 Se 4 /NF also exhibits a Tafel slope of 44 mV/dec for sluggish OER process. Notably, this nanocrystalline catalyst displays enhanced catalytic activity under alkaline conditions, accelerates water dissociation, and maintains good stability over 50 h. Outperforming state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art RuO 2 , particularly in two&#8208;electrode assemblies with an overpotential of 218 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 , this work offers a promising pathway for designing and manufacturing of innovative bifunctional electrocatalysts for efficient water splitting processes, thereby contributing to broader goal of sustainable energy production.</description>
      <author>Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Karam Jabbour, Nigarish Bano, Muhammad Yousaf Ur Rehman, Razan A. Alshgari, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N,S&#8208;doped Zeolite&#8208;Templated Carbon Like Substrate Supported NixFeySz Nanoparticles as an Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Rechargeable Zinc Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400555</link>
      <description>Lola Loupias, Roald Boul&#233;, Nora Benbakoura, Steven Comp&#232;re, Julie Rousseau, Laetitia Mazi&#232;re, F. Pailloux, Vincent Mauchamp, J. Pacaud, St&#233;phane C&#233;l&#233;rier, Karine Servat, T&#234;ko W. Napporn, Cl&#225;udia Morais, Alexander Sachse, Aur&#233;lien Habrioux, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401541788

                A still unexplored class of heterostructured bifunctional catalysts for oxygen evolution (OER) and reduction (ORR) reactions is investigated: Ni&#8208;Fe sulfides deposited onto a N,S&#8208;co&#8208;doped zeolite&#8208;templated carbon (ZTC) substrate achieved upon the impregnation of a ZTC with thiourea and Ni and Fe precursors (Ni/Fe atomic ratio of 1). By heat&#8208;treating the impregnated ZTC substrate at 700 &#176;C under N2 atmosphere the efficient bifunctional catalyst is generated. A difference of only 0.76 V is measured between the potential required to drive an OER current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and the ORR half&#8208;wave potential. Using electrochemical measurements and physico&#8208;chemical characterizations, it is evidenced that OER activity results from the presence of a sulfide containing both Fe and Ni whereas the ORR activity originates from the N,S&#8208;doped ZTC substrate. The selectivity of the ORR process is improved through the presence of sulfide phases. Compared to more conventional carbon substrate such as N,S&#8208;co&#8208;doped reduced graphene oxide, high specific surface area ZTC favors high ORR performances. The functional ZTC material was further successfully implemented as bifunctional air electrode in a coin&#8208;type Zn&#8208;air battery.</description>
      <author>Lola Loupias, Roald Boul&#233;, Nora Benbakoura, Steven Comp&#232;re, Julie Rousseau, Laetitia Mazi&#232;re, F. Pailloux, Vincent Mauchamp, J. Pacaud, St&#233;phane C&#233;l&#233;rier, Karine Servat, T&#234;ko W. Napporn, Cl&#225;udia Morais, Alexander Sachse, Aur&#233;lien Habrioux</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pH Dependence of Noble Metals Dissolution: Gold</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400373</link>
      <description>Kevin Stojanovski, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Matej Zlatar, Christian G&#246;llner, Serhiy Cherevko, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401519351

                Abstract The electrochemical applications of gold span the entire pH spectrum. Recently, gold dissolution in acidic and alkaline media has been studied, but less attention has been given to electrolytes at intermediate pH values. To address this gap, this work uses on&#8208;line electrochemical dissolution inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP&#8208;MS) to examine gold dissolution across a pH range of 1 to 12.7 using phosphate buffer solutions. All experimental parameters, except pH, are kept constant, enabling a clear investigation of pH effects on anodic (gold oxidation) and cathodic (gold oxide reduction) dissolution processes. Results show that dissolution amounts are lowest at neutral pH values between 3 and 7, varying with the applied potential and exposure time. Anodic and cathodic dissolution dominate in acidic and alkaline electrolytes, respectively. Depending on the highest applied potentials and time exposure, the main dissolution mechanism shifts at pH=5, 7, and 9. The pH dependence of Au dissolution is proposed to be linked to the nature of gold oxides formed, the kinetics of oxide formation/reduction, gold ion redeposition, and the influence of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on dissolution. These results provide fundamental insights into gold dissolution under neutral pH conditions.</description>
      <author>Kevin Stojanovski, Valent&#237;n Briega&#8208;Martos, Matej Zlatar, Christian G&#246;llner, Serhiy Cherevko</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phenotypic divergence associated with genomic changes suggest local adaptation in obligate asexuals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.08.15.608098</link>
      <description>Athina Karapli-Petritsopoulou, Jasmin Josephine Heckelmann, N. John Anderson, S&#246;ren Franzenburg, Dagmar Frisch, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401662274

                Local adaptation is a key evolutionary process that generates global biodiversity and is promoted by environmental heterogeneity. Most of the existing knowledge on adaptive capacity is focused on sexual organisms, while the adaptation potential of asexually reproducing eukaryotes as well as their vulnerability to environmental change remains unclear. Cyclical parthenogens of the keystone freshwater grazer Daphnia are known to be locally adapted with genetic differentiation related to environmental conditions even between neighbouring ponds. Similar patterns have been found in obligate parthenogenetic congeners, however studies on their local adaptation potential are rare. Here, we use respiration rate and whole genome sequencing to test the local adaptation of Arctic asexual polyploid Daphnia from lakes with contrasting oxygen environments. The genomic data revealed the presence of two genetic clusters which differed significantly in respiration rates, suggesting molecular evolution as an adaptive mechanism. Functional enrichment pointed to differences in metabolic processes between the two genetic clusters. Our results, combining phenotypic and whole genome sequencing data, suggest that these clones are locally adapted to low oxygen concentrations and provide support for local adaptation by evolution in an obligate parthenogen.</description>
      <author>Athina Karapli-Petritsopoulou, Jasmin Josephine Heckelmann, N. John Anderson, S&#246;ren Franzenburg, Dagmar Frisch</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.08.15.608098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selection for Photocatalytic Function through Darwinian Evolution of Synthetic Self-Replicators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x4fdr-v2</link>
      <description>Kai Liu, Omer Markovitch, Chris van Ewijk, Yari Katar Knelissen, Armin Kiani, Marcel Eleveld, Wouter H. Roos, Jan B. F. N. Engberts, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401552716

                The onset of Darwinian evolution represents a key step in the transition of chemical systems into living ones. Here, we show the emergence of Darwinian evolution in two systems of self-replicating molecules, where natural selection favors replicator mutants best capable of catalyzing the production of the precursors required for their own replication. Such selection for protometabolic activity was observed in a system where trimer and hexamer replicators compete for common resources, as well as in a system of different hexamer replicator mutants. An out-of-equilibrium replication-destruction regime was implemented in a flow reactor, where replication from continuously supplied dithiol building blocks needs to keep up with &#8220;destruction&#8221; by outflow. Selection occurred based on the ability of the mutants to activate a cofactor that photocatalytically produces singlet oxygen which, in turn, enhances the rate by which dithiol building blocks are converted into disulfide-based replicator precursors. Selection was based on a functional trait (catalytic activity) opening up Darwinian evolution as a tool for catalyst development. This work functionally integrates self-replication with protometabolism and Darwinian evolution and marks a further advance in the de-novo synthesis of life.</description>
      <author>Kai Liu, Omer Markovitch, Chris van Ewijk, Yari Katar Knelissen, Armin Kiani, Marcel Eleveld, Wouter H. Roos, Jan B. F. N. Engberts</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x4fdr-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition-Regulated Photocatalytic Activity of ZnIn2S4@CdS Hybrids for Efficient Dye Degradation and H2O2 Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163857</link>
      <description>Nikolaos Karamoschos, Andreas Katsamitros, Labrini Sygellou, Konstantinos S. Andrikopoulos, Dimitrios Tasis, Molecules. 29(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401618409

                Heterostructures of visible light-absorbing semiconductors were prepared through the growth of ZnIn2S4 crystallites in the presence of CdS nanostructures. A variety of hybrid compositions was synthesized. Both reference samples and heterostructured materials were characterized in detail, regarding their morphology, crystalline character, chemical speciation, as well as vibrational properties. The abovementioned physicochemical characterization suggested the absence of doping phenomena, such as the integration of either zinc or indium ions into the CdS lattice. At specific compositions, the growth of the amorphous ZnIn2S4 component was observed through both XRD and Raman analysis. The development of heterojunctions was found to be composition-dependent, as indicated by the simultaneous recording of the Raman profiles of both semiconductors. The optical band gaps of the hybrids range at values between the corresponding band gaps of reference semiconductors. The photocatalytic activity was assessed in both organic dye degradation and hydrogen peroxide evolution. It was observed that the hybrids demonstrating efficient photocatalytic activity in dye degradation were rather poor photocatalysts for hydrogen peroxide evolution. Specifically, the hybrids enriched in the CdS component were shown to act efficiently for hydrogen peroxide evolution, whereas ZnIn2S4-enriched hybrids demonstrated high potential to photodegrade an azo-type organic dye. Furthermore, scavenging experiments suggested the involvement of singlet oxygen in the mechanistic path for dye degradation.</description>
      <author>Nikolaos Karamoschos, Andreas Katsamitros, Labrini Sygellou, Konstantinos S. Andrikopoulos, Dimitrios Tasis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Respiratory Worsening at the End of a Hospital Stay for Severe Covid19 Pneumonia Revealing Pulmonary Tuberculosis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33425/2690-5191.1120</link>
      <description>Touab Rida, Ayoub Bouayda, Rabii Andaloussi Mohamed, Chakib Chwikh, Khalil Mounir, Abdelhamid Eljaafari, Hicham Balkhi, Medicine and Clinical Science. 6(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401584462

                The coexistence of a viral and tuberculous respiratory infection increases mortality and the transition to a severe form in both directions. We report an observation for a 55-year-old woman with untreated diffuse interstitial pnuemopathy, investigated by immunological and infectious tests, and found negative for pulmonary tuberculosis. Bronchial biopsies revealed non-specific inflammation, responsible for chronic dyspnea. Having presented ten days previously with myalgias, fatigue, dry cough and fever, with worsening of basic dyspnoea, without digestive or neurological manifestations, she was referred to the emergency department, where physical examination showed SpO2 at 80% on room air, reduced to 92% under 15 L/mn delivered via a high-concentration mask, polypnoea at 40 cycles per minute with bilateral diffuse crackling rales on auscultation, scattering just the anterior quadrants. The initial evolution was favorable, with clinical improvement in oxygen saturation to 94% on two liters per minute of oxygen delivered by nasal cannula, with respiratory rate at 23 cycles per minute with modest effort tolerance. On day 18 of hospitalization, she presented with a febrile peak of 38.3&#176;C, polypnoea at 33 cycles per minute, increased oxygen requirements with a flow rate of 6l/m by face mask to reach an oxygen saturation of 92%, tachycardia at 130 beats per minute, and was therefore readmitted to intensive care with high-flow nasal oxygen therapy and antibiotic therapy with imipenem and amikacin. Multiplex PCR showing no germ, and a PCR test for pulmonary tuberculosis on a sputum sample which was positive, prompting the introduction of antibacillary treatment based on a fixed quadric-association of rifampicin, isoniaside, pyrazinaamide and ethombutol. Non-specific antibiotic therapy was discontinued after improvement of the inflammatory syndrome, and antibacillary treatment is still ongoing. Conclusion: Through this observation we discuss the difficulties in terms of diagnosis, management and outcome of a coinfection by SARS-COV 19 and mycobacterium tuberculosis.</description>
      <author>Touab Rida, Ayoub Bouayda, Rabii Andaloussi Mohamed, Chakib Chwikh, Khalil Mounir, Abdelhamid Eljaafari, Hicham Balkhi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33425/2690-5191.1120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of ultrasonic flight time based on SHADE algorithm and extended kalman filtering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2815/1/012039</link>
      <description>Peng Mao, Jinglin Xiong, Xisheng Li, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2815(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401521484

                Abstract Traditional methods of using ultrasound to measure oxygen concentration have the issue of inaccuracy and susceptibility to noise interference when measuring the time of flight (TOF) of ultrasonic echo signals. A proposed algorithm for ultrasonic parameter estimation, utilizing an asymmetric Gaussian model, aims to enhance the precision and reliability of TOF estimation, aiming to reduce the influence of noise interference. The algorithm combines an improved Self-Adaptive Differential Evolution (SHADE) algorithm based on successful historical records with an Extended Kalman Filter (EKF). The improved SHADE algorithm controls the degree of mutation strategy greediness during the mutation operation based on the number of iterations, thereby enhancing the algorithm&#8217;s iteration speed. Then, the obtained solution is used as the initial value for the EKF to estimate the model parameters, thus addressing the issue of EKF&#8217;s dependency on accurate initial values to obtain precise outputs. Through simulation and experimental measurements of ultrasonic oxygen concentration, several commonly used parameter estimation algorithms are compared with the proposed SHADE-EKF algorithm. Results demonstrate that the SHADE-EKF algorithm exhibits superior performance in estimating the TOF of ultrasonic waves.</description>
      <author>Peng Mao, Jinglin Xiong, Xisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2815/1/012039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Stable In Situ Self&#8208;Assembled Air Electrodes for Reversible Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409598</link>
      <description>Yixuan Huang, Fan He, Kang Xu, Hui Gao, Xirui Zhang, Yangsen Xu, Zhiwei Du, Feng Zhu, Wenjie Gong, Cuiying Jian, Yu Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401654927

                Abstract Reversible protonic ceramic electrochemical cells (R&#8208;PCECs) have garnered significant attention owing to their proficiency in efficiently converting and storing energy. The performance of R&#8208;PCECs is largely limited by the activity and durability of oxygen reduction/evolution reactions in air electrodes. Herein, an Nb and Y doped cobalt&#8208;based double perovskite of PrBaCo 1.8 Nb 0.1 Y 0.1 O 5+&#948; (denoted as PBCNY) is reported. The perovskite is however in situ assembled into a deficient&#8208;PrBa 1&#8722;x Co 1.8 Nb 0.1&#8722;x Y 0.1&#8722;x O 5+&#948; parental phase and a Ba 2 YNbO 6 secondary phase during operation, accordingly demonstrating a low area&#8208;specific resistance of 0.24 &#8486; cm 2 at 600 &#176;C. The high activity is attributed to the enhancement in oxygen vacancy concentration, oxygen surface exchange, and bulk diffusion coefficient, confirmed by X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and electrical conductivity relaxation. At 700 &#176;C, when the PBCNY cathode is applied as air electrodes for R&#8208;PCECs, a peak power density of 1.99 W cm &#8722;2 and a current density of &#8722;5.20 A cm &#8722;2 (at 1.3 V) are achieved in fuel cell (FC) mode, and electrolysis (EL) mode with appropriate Faradaic efficiencies. Furthermore, R&#8208;PCECs with PBCNY air electrodes display promising operational stability in FC mode (over 100 h), EL mode (over 200 h), and reversible cyclic testing (29 cycles for 120 h).</description>
      <author>Yixuan Huang, Fan He, Kang Xu, Hui Gao, Xirui Zhang, Yangsen Xu, Zhiwei Du, Feng Zhu, Wenjie Gong, Cuiying Jian, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RNA or DNA? Revisiting the Chemical Nature of the Cenancestral Genome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00239-024-10194-9</link>
      <description>Wolfgang Cottom-Salas, Arturo Becerra, Antonio Lazcano, Journal of Molecular Evolution. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401618239

                Abstract One of the central issues in the understanding of early cellular evolution is the characterisation of the cenancestor. This includes the description of the chemical nature of its genome. The disagreements on this question comprise several proposals, including the possibility that AlkB-mediated methylation repair of alkylated RNA molecules may be interpreted as evidence of a cenancestral RNA genome. We present here an evolutionary analysis of the cupin-like protein superfamily based on tertiary structure-based phylogenies that includes the oxygen-dependent AlkB and its homologs. Our results suggest that the repair of methylated RNA molecules is the outcome of the enzyme substrate ambiguity, and doesn&#180;t necessarily indicates that the last common ancestor was endowed with an RNA genome.</description>
      <author>Wolfgang Cottom-Salas, Arturo Becerra, Antonio Lazcano</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00239-024-10194-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In&#8208;Situ Dynamic Carburization of Mo Oxide with Unprecedented High CO Formation Rate in Reverse Water&#8208;Gas Shift Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411761</link>
      <description>Xiangze Du, Rongtan Li, Xin Hui, Yamei Fan, Haibo Liu, Xiaohui Feng, Jianyang Wang, Cui Dong, Chao Wang, Jia Li, Qiang Fu, Xinhe Bao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401619972

                In&#8208;situ construction of active structure under reaction conditions is highly desired but still remains challenging in many important catalytic processes. Herein, we observe structural evolution of molybdenum oxide (MoOx) into highly active molybdenum carbide (MoCx) during reverse water&#8208;gas shift (RWGS) reaction. Surface oxygen atoms in various Mo&#8208;based catalysts are removed in H2&#8208;containing atmospheres and then carbon atoms can accumulate on surface to form MoCx phase with the RWGS reaction going on, both of which are enhanced by the presence of intercalated H species or Pt&#8208;dopants in MoOx. The structural evolution from MoOx to MoCx is accompanied by enhanced CO2 conversion, which is positively correlated with the surface C/Mo ratio but negatively with the surface O/Mo ratio. As a result, an unprecedented CO formation rate of 7544.6 mmol&#183;gcatal&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1 at 600 &#176;C has been achieved over in&#8208;situ carbonized H&#8208;intercalated MoO3 catalyst, which is even higher than those from noble metal catalysts. During 100 h stability test only a minimal deactivation rate of 2.3% is observed.</description>
      <author>Xiangze Du, Rongtan Li, Xin Hui, Yamei Fan, Haibo Liu, Xiaohui Feng, Jianyang Wang, Cui Dong, Chao Wang, Jia Li, Qiang Fu, Xinhe Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In&#8208;Situ Dynamic Carburization of Mo Oxide with Unprecedented High CO Formation Rate in Reverse Water&#8208;Gas Shift Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411761</link>
      <description>Xiangze Du, Rongtan Li, Xin Hui, Yamei Fan, Haibo Liu, Xiaohui Feng, Jianyang Wang, Cui Dong, Chao Wang, Jia Li, Qiang Fu, Xinhe Bao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401620688

                In&#8208;situ construction of active structure under reaction conditions is highly desired but still remains challenging in many important catalytic processes. Herein, we observe structural evolution of molybdenum oxide (MoOx) into highly active molybdenum carbide (MoCx) during reverse water&#8208;gas shift (RWGS) reaction. Surface oxygen atoms in various Mo&#8208;based catalysts are removed in H2&#8208;containing atmospheres and then carbon atoms can accumulate on surface to form MoCx phase with the RWGS reaction going on, both of which are enhanced by the presence of intercalated H species or Pt&#8208;dopants in MoOx. The structural evolution from MoOx to MoCx is accompanied by enhanced CO2 conversion, which is positively correlated with the surface C/Mo ratio but negatively with the surface O/Mo ratio. As a result, an unprecedented CO formation rate of 7544.6 mmol&#183;gcatal&#8208;1&#183;h&#8208;1 at 600 &#176;C has been achieved over in&#8208;situ carbonized H&#8208;intercalated MoO3 catalyst, which is even higher than those from noble metal catalysts. During 100 h stability test only a minimal deactivation rate of 2.3% is observed.</description>
      <author>Xiangze Du, Rongtan Li, Xin Hui, Yamei Fan, Haibo Liu, Xiaohui Feng, Jianyang Wang, Cui Dong, Chao Wang, Jia Li, Qiang Fu, Xinhe Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of electrolyte concentration on bubble evolution and mass transfer characteristics in photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.73.20240533</link>
      <description>Wang Meng-Sha, Qiang Xu, Nie Teng-Fei, Xinyi Luo, Guo Liejin, Acta Physica Sinica. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401591463

                In the photoelectrochemical water splitting reaction system, the bubble will cover the reaction area on the photoelectrode surface, affecting the reaction impedance and gas-liquid mass transfer. A laser irradiation system was built and coupled with an electrochemical workstation and high-speed microscopic imaging system. The evolution behavior and mass transfer characteristics of single O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; bubble on the TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; photoelectrode were studied at different electrolyte concentrations (Na&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;SO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;, 0.1-2.0 mol/L). With the increase of electrolyte concentration from 0.1 mol/L to 2.0 mol/L, the solution resistance and bubble additional resistance decrease, and the overpotential in the stable growth stage of bubble decreases from 0.113 V to -0.089 V. The bubble will cause the fluctuation of overpotential in the nucleation, growth and detachment stages, which is consistent with the impedance change caused by the change of dissolved oxygen concentration in the liquid phase. By analyzing the correlation between gas evolution efficiency and bubble coverage, it is found that the increase of electrolyte concentration would lead to the simultaneous decrease of bubble coverage and gas evolution efficiency. By calculating the Sherwood dimensionless number, the results show that the total convective mass transfer coefficient increases with the electrolyte concentration. Single-phase natural convection plays a dominant role in the process of gas product transfer, and its mass transfer coefficient is one order of magnitude larger than that of bubble-induced convection. In summary, by adjusting the electrolyte concentration, the bubble on the gas evolution photoelectrode surface can be effectively removed and the mass transfer of the system can be optimized, which is of great significance for improving the efficiency of photoelectrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Wang Meng-Sha, Qiang Xu, Nie Teng-Fei, Xinyi Luo, Guo Liejin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.73.20240533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction and Progress of Small Molecule&#8208;Based Coupled Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402429</link>
      <description>Yanxi Qin, Yingyong Wang, Guojun Jin, Xili Tong, Nianjun Yang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401548817

                Abstract Coupled electrolyzer is a desirable way to realize efficient energy conversion from electricity to chemical energy. Using coupled electrolyzers highly valuable chemicals (e.g., H 2 , CH x COO &#8722; , nitrile, S, NH 3 , CO) can be obtained at low voltages, environmental pollutants can be alleviated, and wastewater (e.g., ammonia, urea, hydrazine) can be recycled. They are even helpful to realize the goal of carbon peaking and carbon neutrality. Compared to traditional chemical methods, small molecule&#8208;based coupled electrolyzers are more cost&#8208;efficient. This review summarizes state&#8208;of&#8208;art of coupled electrolyzers, mainly the replacement of oxygen reduction reaction with oxidation reactions of small molecules and their further coupling with cathodic reduction reactions such as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), N 2 reduction reaction (NRR), and other reduction reactions of matching small molecules. In terms of oxidation reactions of small molecules, two types of reactions are covered: sacrificial agent oxidation reaction (SAOR) and electrochemical synthesis reaction (ESR). After detailing the design principle of coupled electrolyzers and several oxidation reactions of small molecules, construction, characterization, and performance of coupled electrolyzers are systematically overviewed along with discussion and outline of current challenges and prospects of this appealing strategy.</description>
      <author>Yanxi Qin, Yingyong Wang, Guojun Jin, Xili Tong, Nianjun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Performance of Mn&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; Electrodes for Hydrogen Evolution Using Natural Bischofite Salt from Atacama Desert. A Novel Application for Solar Saline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.0640.v1</link>
      <description>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Edward Fuentealba, Susana Leiva-Guajardo, Luis C&#225;ceres, Carlos Portillo, Felipe D. Sep&#250;lveda, Iv&#225;n Brito, J.A. Cobos-Murcia, Omar F. Rojas-Moreno, Victor Jimenez-Arevalo, Eduardo Schott, &#193;lvaro Soliz, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401586377

                Solar saline water splitting is a promising approach for sustainable hydrogen production, harnessing abundant solar energy and the availability of brine resources, especially in the Atacama Desert. Bischofite (MgCl2&amp;middot;6H2O), a naturally occurring salt, has garnered significant attention due to its wide range of industrial applications and the challenges associated with efficient hydrogen production in arid or hyper arid locations. This work discloses the electrochemical performance of Mn2O3 electrodes using a superposition model based on mixed potential theory and evaluates the superficial performance of this electrode in contact with a 0.5 M nature Bischofite salt solution focusing on hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), that occurs during saline water splitting. The application of the non-linear superposition model provides valuable electrochemical kinetic parameters that complement the understanding of Mn2O3, this being one of the novelties of the manuscript.</description>
      <author>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Edward Fuentealba, Susana Leiva-Guajardo, Luis C&#225;ceres, Carlos Portillo, Felipe D. Sep&#250;lveda, Iv&#225;n Brito, J.A. Cobos-Murcia, Omar F. Rojas-Moreno, Victor Jimenez-Arevalo, Eduardo Schott, &#193;lvaro Soliz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.0640.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Sustainable h&#8208;BN Encapsulated MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrogen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402272</link>
      <description>Jungmoon Lim, Su Jin Heo, Min J. Jung, Tae&#8208;Hun Kim, Junsung Byeon, Hong Ju Park, Jae Eun Jang, John Hong, Janghyuk Moon, Sangyeon Pak, SeungNam Cha, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401655147

                Abstract Despite the importance of the stability of the 2D catalysts in harsh electrolyte solutions, most studies have focused on improving the catalytic performance of molybdenum disulfide (MoS 2 ) catalysts rather than the sustainability of hydrogen evolution. In previous studies, the vulnerability of MoS 2 crystals is reported that the moisture and oxygen molecules can cause the oxidation of MoS 2 crystals, accelerating the degradation of crystal structure. Therefore, optimization of catalytic stability is crucial for approaching practical applications in 2D catalysts. Here, it is proposed that monolayered MoS 2 catalysts passivated with an atomically thin hexagonal boron nitride (h&#8208;BN) layer can effectively sustain hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and demonstrate the ultra&#8208;high current density (500 mA cm&#8315; 2 over 11 h) and super stable (64 h at 150 mA cm&#8315; 2 ) catalytic performance. It is further confirmed with density functional theory (DFT) calculations that the atomically thin h&#8208;BN layer effectively prevents direct adsorption of water/acid molecules while allowing the protons to be adsorbed/penetrated. The selective penetration of protons and prevention of crystal structure degradation lead to maintained catalytic activity and maximized catalytic stability in the h&#8208;BN covered MoS 2 catalysts. These findings propose a promising opportunity for approaching the practical application of 2D MoS 2 catalysts having long&#8208;term stability at high&#8208;current operation.</description>
      <author>Jungmoon Lim, Su Jin Heo, Min J. Jung, Tae&#8208;Hun Kim, Junsung Byeon, Hong Ju Park, Jae Eun Jang, John Hong, Janghyuk Moon, Sangyeon Pak, SeungNam Cha</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; crystallization in enhancing the luminescence of Dy&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt;&#8208;Sm&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; co&#8208;doped glass ceramics for cool white light application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bio.4862</link>
      <description>M. Monisha, M. Saravanan, Nirmal Mazumder, M.I. Sayyed, Mona M. Rashad, Sudha D. Kamath, Luminescence. 39(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401523262

                Abstract The present work investigates the structural and luminescence behaviour of Dy 3+ &#8208;Sm 3+ co&#8208;doped glass ceramics obtained through heat treatment of precursor glasses. The growth of SiO 2 polycrystalline particles and evolution of these crystallites in the glass domain are witnessed via XRD and FESEM study. The presence of network vibrational bands, hydroxyl groups and the increased quantity of bridging oxygens (BOs) in glass ceramics are analysed through FTIR spectroscopy study. The absorption study (UV&#8211;Visible&#8211;NIR) showed the possible electronic transitions of Dy 3+ and Sm 3+ ions. The red shift in the absorption band edges and the lower bandgap values are obtained as a result of improved heat treatment in glass ceramics. Emission studies show the enhanced luminescence intensity of glass ceramics under 350 and 402 nm excitations. Decay measurement of glass ceramics showed the improved lifetimes of Dy 3+ and Sm 3+ ions to have appeared in microseconds (&#215;10 &#8722;6 s). The colour characteristics of glass ceramics analysed using CIE colour chromaticity diagram and correlated colour temperature (CCT) values suggest the neutral to cool white light emissions. Therefore, prepared glass ceramics with SiO 2 polycrystalline phase are considered to be suitable materials in cool white LEDs applications.</description>
      <author>M. Monisha, M. Saravanan, Nirmal Mazumder, M.I. Sayyed, Mona M. Rashad, Sudha D. Kamath</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bio.4862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the Interaction of Perovskite-Like Surfaces (LaMnO3 and LaCoO3) with Ar, H2, CO, and O2 through NAP-XPS Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04778-9</link>
      <description>Juan Tapia, Jaime Gallego, Oscar Gamba, Juan F. Espinal, Catalysis Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401657799

                Abstract Perovskite-like oxides present huge chemical variability and a wide range of applications as catalysts for oxidation reactions. The interaction of several small gas molecules with the surface of LaCoO 3 and LaMnO 3 perovskite-like oxides was studied by Near Ambient Pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (NAP-XPS) and CO Temperature Programmed Desorption (CO-TPD). Surface chemical changes such as the O surf /O lattice and cation B oxidation state ratios were analyzed as a function of temperature (400 K, 450 K, 500 K, 550 K, and 650 K) under different gas atmospheres like Ar, CO, H 2 , and O 2 . It was found that there was a partial surface reduction when H 2 and CO were used in the reaction, and therefore, the cation B oxidation state (Mn 4+ /Mn 3+ and Co 3+ /Co 2+ ) ratio decreased. Under the CO stream, carbonate species were formed, presenting a C1s signal between 284.5 eV and 287 eV. The CO 2 evolution during the reaction at temperatures greater than 500 K was associated with CO activation over or near to surface oxygen species. A Mars-van Krevelen mechanism was proposed for the process, finding significant differences between LaCoO 3 and LaMnO 3 perovskite-like solid catalysts behavior. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Juan Tapia, Jaime Gallego, Oscar Gamba, Juan F. Espinal</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10562-024-04778-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization and Degradation of Perovskite Mini-Modules</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12080219</link>
      <description>R. Ebner, Ankit Mittal, G. &#218;jv&#225;ri, Maria Hadjipanayi, Vasiliki Paraskeva, George E. Georghiou, Afshin Hadipour, Ar&#225;nzazu Aguirre, Tom Aernouts, Inorganics. 12(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401610662

                Organic&#8211;inorganic hybrid metal halide perovskites are poised to revolutionize the next generation of photovoltaics with their exceptional optoelectronic properties and compatibility with low-cost and large-scale fabrication methods. Since perovskite tends to degrade over short time intervals due to various parameters (oxygen, humidity, light, and temperature), advanced characterization methods are needed to understand their degradation mechanisms. In this context, investigation of the electrical and optoelectronic properties of several perovskite mini-modules was performed by means of photo- and electroluminescence imaging as well as Dark Lock-In Thermography methods. Current&#8211;voltage curves at periodic time intervals and External Quantum Efficiency measurements were implemented alongside other measurements to reveal correlations between the electrical and radiative properties of the solar cells. The different imaging techniques used in this study reveal the changes in radiative emission processes and how those are correlated with performance. Alongside the indoor optoelectronic characterization of perovskite reference samples, the outdoor monitoring of two perovskite modules of the same structure for 23 weeks is reported. Significant performance degradation is presented outdoors from the first week of testing for both samples under test. The evolution of the major electrical characteristics of the mini-modules and the diurnal changes were studied in detail. Finally, dark storage recovery studies after outdoor exposure were implemented to investigate changes in the major electrical parameters.</description>
      <author>R. Ebner, Ankit Mittal, G. &#218;jv&#225;ri, Maria Hadjipanayi, Vasiliki Paraskeva, George E. Georghiou, Afshin Hadipour, Ar&#225;nzazu Aguirre, Tom Aernouts</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12080219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of improving the mechanical and barrier properties of poly(lactide)/poly(butylene adipate&#8208;&lt;i&gt;co&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;terephthalate) blends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/app.56120</link>
      <description>Yongjian Xie, Chenxi Wang, Shanglin Gao, Zhen Li, Sheng Cheng, Hao&#8208;Yan Yin, Yiyang Zhou, Yunsheng Ding, Journal of Applied Polymer Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401618921

                Abstract Poly(lactide)/poly(butylene adipate&#8208; co &#8208;terephthalate) (PLA/PBAT) blends containing different amounts of polyethylene wax (PEW) were fabricated via melt&#8208;blending, and the effects of PEW on the interfacial morphological evolution and properties of the PLA/PBAT blends were investigated. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) micrographs show that the compatibility between PLA and PBAT is obviously improved by addition of low contents of PEW. Differential scanning calorimeter (DSC) results indicate that PEW can simultaneously enhance the crystallization ability of PLA and PBAT. Rheological behavior of the blends indicates that PEW has a significant plasticizing effect and can promote the mobility of polymer chains in the blends. More importantly, it is revealed that PEW can effectively improve the mechanical and barrier properties of the blends. Even with a PEW content of only 1 wt%, the elongation at break and notched impact strength of the blend reach 344.1% and 12.55 kJ/m 2 , respectively, which are 54% and 140% higher than the blend without PEW. Meanwhile, the water vapor transmission rate (WVTR) and oxygen transmission rate (OTR) of the films containing 1 wt% PEW are decreased from 87.34 to 67.40 g m &#8722;2 &#183;24 h &#8722;1 and from 118.26 to 80.94 cm 3 m &#8722;2 &#183;24 h &#8722;1 , respectively, which are 22.8% and 31.5% lower than those of the PLA/PBAT film.</description>
      <author>Yongjian Xie, Chenxi Wang, Shanglin Gao, Zhen Li, Sheng Cheng, Hao&#8208;Yan Yin, Yiyang Zhou, Yunsheng Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/app.56120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast-Neutron Radiolysis of Sub- and Supercritical Water at 300&#8211;600 &#176;C and 25 MPa: A Monte Carlo Track Chemistry Simulation Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14167024</link>
      <description>Md Shakhawat Hossen Bhuiyan, Jintana Meesungnoen, Abida Sultana, Jean&#8208;Paul Jay&#8208;Gerin, Applied Sciences. 14(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401536067

                (1) Background: Supercritical water-cooled reactors (SCWRs) and their smaller modular variants (SMRs) are part of the &#8216;Generation IV International Forum&#8217; (GIF) on advanced nuclear energy systems. These reactors operate beyond the critical point of water (tc = 373.95 &#176;C and Pc = 22.06 MPa), which introduces specific technical challenges that need to be addressed. The primary concerns involve the effects of intense radiation fields&#8212;including fast neutrons, recoil protons/oxygen ions, and &#947; rays&#8212;on the chemistry of the coolant fluid and the integrity of construction materials. (2) Methods: This study employs Monte Carlo simulations of radiation track chemistry to investigate the yields of radiolytic species in SCWRs/SMRs exposed to 2 MeV neutrons. In our calculations, only the contributions from the first three recoil protons with initial energies of 1.264, 0.465, and 0.171 MeV were considered. Our analysis was conducted at both subcritical (300 and 350 &#176;C) and supercritical temperatures (400&#8211;600 &#176;C), maintaining a constant pressure of 25 MPa. (3) Results: Our simulations provide insights into the radiolytic formation of chemical species such as e&#8722;aq, H&#9679;, H2, &#9679;OH, and H2O2 from ~1 ps to 1 ms. Compared to data from radiation with low linear energy transfer (LET), the G(e&#8722;aq) and G(&#9679;OH) values obtained for fast neutrons show a similar temporal dependence but with smaller amplitude&#8212;a result demonstrating the high LET nature of fast neutrons. A notable outcome of our simulations is the marked increase in G(&#9679;OH) and G(H2), coupled with a corresponding reduction in G(H&#9679;), observed during the homogeneous chemical stage of radiolysis. This evolution is attributed to the oxidation of water by the H&#9679; atom according to the reaction H&#9679; + H2O &#8594; &#9679;OH + H2. This reaction acts as a significant source of H2, potentially reducing the need to add extra hydrogen to the reactor&#8217;s coolant water to suppress the net radiolytic production of oxidizing species. Unlike in subcritical water, our simulations also indicate that G(H2O2) remains very low in low-density SCW throughout the interval from ~1 ps to 1 ms, suggesting that H2O2 is less likely to contribute to oxidative stress under these conditions. (4) Conclusions: The results of this study could significantly impact water-chemistry management in the proposed SCWRs and SCW-SMRs, which is crucial for assessing and mitigating the corrosion risks to reactor materials, especially for long-term operation.</description>
      <author>Md Shakhawat Hossen Bhuiyan, Jintana Meesungnoen, Abida Sultana, Jean&#8208;Paul Jay&#8208;Gerin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14167024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Large to Giant Porphyry Mo Deposits: Constraints From Whole-Rock and In Situ Mineral Geochemistry of Causative Magmatic Rocks in the Tongbai-Hong&#8217;an-Dabie Orogens, Central China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5382/econgeo.5081</link>
      <description>Wen-Tian Li, Shao&#8208;Yong Jiang, Deliang Liu, Meizhen Yang, Pan&#8208;Pan Niu, Economic Geology. 119(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401634464

                Abstract The Tongbai-Hong&#8217;an-Dabie orogenic belt (THD) contains over 3 million tonnes (Mt) of metal Mo. At least 10 porphyry Mo deposits developed in small to giant scales, forming a significant Mo mineralized belt in China. Ore genetic models of these porphyry Mo deposits have been widely discussed; however, key factors responsible for forming the large to giant porphyry Mo deposits still remain unclear. In this study, we investigated samples from three small deposits (Wangwan, Mushan, and Bao&#8217;anzhai) and two large to giant deposits (Tangjiaping and Shapinggou) in the THD. Comprehensive characterization of whole-rock compositions and in situ geochemical analysis of apatite, plagioclase, and biotite from these deposits were conducted to provide potential distinguishable indicators for evaluating the prospectivity of a given magmatic suite in continental collisional settings. The data show that the productive granites from the large to giant Tangjiaping and Shapinggou deposits are characterized by higher Nd-Hf-O isotopes than those in the small ones, as well as magma temperatures of 832&#176; and 860&#176;C. It is also noteworthy that a significant number of mafic igneous rocks were intruded in the THD, such as in the Tangjiaping deposit, coeval with the formation of the Mo deposits. Apatite within the contemporary mafic enclaves of the Lingshan granitic pluton is anticipated to demonstrate the key geochemical characteristics of these mafic rocks, with the apatite displaying high SO3 contents ranging from 0.45 to 0.91 wt %.These observations suggest that the formation of large to giant porphyry Mo deposits could be linked to the replenishment of the hotter mafic magma in the deep magma chamber in extensional tectonic settings, which might provide sufficient heat and sulfur in parent fertile magmas. The reverse zoning and complex core-to-rim variations in the plagioclase crystals from mafic enclaves provide further evidence for magma mixing processes in the deep magma chamber in the THD from the regional perspective. Magma oxygen fugacity in the Tangjiaping and Shapinggou deposits derived from biotite chemistry is comparable to that in the small ones, implying minimal controls on the large to giant Mo mineralization. The application of plagioclase-based hygrometer reveals that fertile magmas from Tangjiaping and Shapinggou are less hydrous with H2O contents of 3~4 wt %. However, estimates of absolute sulfur and fluorine contents in these mineralization-related melts from apatite SO3 and F contents using available partitioning models suggest that they are indeed significantly richer in S and F, with contents of 45 to 301 and 2,100 to 2,852 ppm, respectively. Moreover, these magmas are also characterized by lower magma viscosity with log &#414; values of 6.0 to 6.4 Pa s, as calculated from whole-rock and apatite compositions. In contrast to primary fertile chlorine-rich fluids responsible for porphyry Cu deposits, the primary ore-forming fluids in the Tangjiaping and Shapinggou in equilibrium with biotite are enriched in fluorine with intercept values (IV[F]) of 0.75 to 1.23. Also, log(fHCl/fHF) and log(fH2O/fHF) values derived from biotite and XF/XCl, XCl/XOH ratios and SO3 contents in apatite record that hydrous volatile exsolution from melts occurred earlier during the magmatic-hydrothermal evolution in the Tangjiaping and Shapinggou deposits. In detail, our modeling illustrates that primary fluids initially developed at high temperatures exceeding 765&#176;C. Meanwhile, S and Cl were extracted from the melts into primary ore fluids, leading to a reduction in their concentrations within the melts, decreasing from 0.03 to 0.005 wt % for S and from 0.030 to 0.005 wt % for Cl. This process accounts for the generation of high-temperature, low-Cl, and S-rich ore-forming fluids.</description>
      <author>Wen-Tian Li, Shao&#8208;Yong Jiang, Deliang Liu, Meizhen Yang, Pan&#8208;Pan Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5382/econgeo.5081</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
