<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:42:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic Specific Activity Enhancement for Bifunctional Electrocatalytic Activity toward Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions via Structural Modification of Nickel Organophosphonates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c03960</link>
      <description>Poojita, Tanmay Rom, Rathindranath Biswas, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Avijit Kumar Paul, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391677825

                A comprehensive knowledge of the structure&#8211;activity relationship of the framework material is decisive to develop efficient multifunctional electrocatalysts. In this regard, two different metal organophosphonate compounds, [Ni(Hhedp)2]&#183;4H2O (I) and [Ni3(H3hedp)2(C4H4N2)3]&#183;6H2O (II) have been isolated through one-pot hydrothermal strategy by using H4hedp (1-hydroxyethane 1,1-diphosphonic acid) and N-donor auxiliary ligand (pyrazine; C4H4N2). The structures of synthesized materials have been established through single-crystal X-ray diffraction studies, which confirm that compound I formed a one-dimensional molecular chain structure, while compound II exhibited a three-dimensional extended structure. Further, the crystalline materials have participated as efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution and hydrogen evolution reactions (OER and HER) as compared to the state-of-the-art electrocatalyst RuO2. The electrocatalytic OER and HER performances show that compound II displayed better electrocatalytic performances toward OER (&#951;10 = 305 mV) and HER (&#951;10 = 230 mV) in alkaline (1 M KOH) and acidic (0.5 M H2SO4) media, respectively. Substantially, the specific activity has been assessed in order to measure the inherent electrocatalytic activity of the title electrocatalyst, which displays an enrichment of fourfold higher activity of compound II (0.64 mA/cm2) than compound I (0.16 mA/cm2) for the OER experiments. Remarkably, inclusion of an auxiliary pyrazine ligand into the metal organophosphonate structure (compound II) not only offers higher dimensionality along with significant enhancement of the overall bifunctional electrocatalytic performances but also improves the long-term stability, which is noteworthy for the family of hybrid framework materials.</description>
      <author>Poojita, Tanmay Rom, Rathindranath Biswas, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Avijit Kumar Paul</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c03960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fast&#8208;Charging Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries with Stable Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis of Mo&#8208;Induced Nanodefective Mo&#9472;Co/N&#9472;C Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314622</link>
      <description>Y. Zhang, Xiaoli Ma, Zhendong Cheng, Jingwen Wang, Guobin Wen, Lin Yang, Zhengyu Bai, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391680217

                Abstract Fast&#8208;charging technology plays a pivotal role in propelling the commercialization of zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). While the lifetime of ZABs under fast&#8208;charging is severely shortened by the abundant O 2 bubbles and the deactivation of the cathode catalysts. Herein, a defective Mo&#9472;Co / N&#9472;C electrocatalyst is presented with Co nanoparticles and molybdenum&#8208;oxo subnano clusters by pyrolyzing the Lindqvist polyoxometalate incorporated ZIF&#8208;67 precursor. The crystalline defects are exacerbated by doping the polyoxometalate into the pores of ZIF&#8208;67. Furthermore, the accessibility of the pore defects is increased by Mo&#8208;leaching during the pre&#8208;activation. These accessible pore defects effectively prevent the exfoliation of catalysts from the support under the attack of O 2 bubbles, and improve the electrolyte penetration. Besides, the pore defects offer numerous active sites for the electrocatalytic reactions, resulting in an active and stable Mo&#9472;Co / N&#9472;C catalyst. Hence, such a Mo&#9472;Co / N&#9472;C electrocatalyst achieves a long lifetime of 1538 h at 5 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a long lifetime of 641 h under a fast charge of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 in the homemade ZAB. The unique components and operational mechanisms propel scientists to portray splendid blueprints for durable fast&#8208;charging ZABs for potential industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Y. Zhang, Xiaoli Ma, Zhendong Cheng, Jingwen Wang, Guobin Wen, Lin Yang, Zhengyu Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202314622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Based Metal Organic Framework-Derived FeNiP/N-Doped Carbon Heterogeneous Core&#8211;Shell Structures for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c04512</link>
      <description>Yijia Cao, Yunfang Yan, Yan Wen, Mengya Cao, Yanrong Liu, Haijiao Xie, Wen Gu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391684595

                It is of great significance to explore high activity, low overpotential, and outstanding durability electrocatalysts without precious metals for oxygen evolution reaction to reduce the energy consumption in the electrolysis of water to product hydrogen. Metal organic frameworks (MOFs) with periodic structure and uniform pore distribution have been widely used as precursors for the synthesis of transition metal electrocatalysts. Herein, we first synthesized nanoscale Fe-soc-MOFs with relatively high specific surface area and in situ converted it into nickel&#8211;iron double layer hydroxide/MOF (FeNi LDH/MOF) by Ni2+ etching. Finally, a nickel&#8211;iron phosphide/nitrogen-doped carbon cubic nanocage (FeNiP/NC) was obtained by calcination and phosphating. FeNiP/NC with its unique core&#8211;shell structure has an overpotential of only 240 mV at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and can be continuously electrolyzed for 45 h. High catalytic activity of FeNiP/NC is mainly attributed to the action of Fe and Ni bimetals and the synergistic effect between FeNiP and N-doped porous carbon, which was confirmed by the calculation of density functional theory (i.e., Gibbs free energy). After a long period of electrolysis, FeNiP was converted to MOOH (M = Fe and Ni) and became the new active site. This study provides a feasible optimization strategy for the development of high-efficiency three-dimensional electrode materials without precious metals.</description>
      <author>Yijia Cao, Yunfang Yan, Yan Wen, Mengya Cao, Yanrong Liu, Haijiao Xie, Wen Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c04512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-doped nickel oxide supported on carbon black for highly active oxygen reduction/evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108335</link>
      <description>Junkai Zhang, Xiangqun Zhuge, Tong Liu, Kun Luo, Jiayin Lyu, Yurong Ren, Yibing Li, Xing Li, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391685515

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junkai Zhang, Xiangqun Zhuge, Tong Liu, Kun Luo, Jiayin Lyu, Yurong Ren, Yibing Li, Xing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing DMC Production from CO2: Tuning Oxygen Vacancies and In Situ Water Removal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17040839</link>
      <description>K Wang, Shiguang Li, Miao Yu, Xinhua Liu, Energies. 17(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391693710

                The direct synthesis of dimethyl carbonate (DMC) from methanol and CO2 presents an attractive route to turn abundant CO2 into value-added chemicals. However, insufficient DMC yields arise due to the inert nature of CO2 and the limitations of reaction equilibrium. Oxygen vacancies are known to facilitate CO2 activation and improve catalytic performance. In this work, we have demonstrated that tuning oxygen vacancies in catalysts and implementing in situ water removal can enable highly efficient DMC production from CO2. CexZryO2 nanorods with abundant oxygen vacancies were synthesized via a hydrothermal method. In liquid-phase DMC synthesis, the Ce10Zr1O2 nanorods exhibited a 1.7- and 1.4-times higher DMC yield compared to CeO2 nanoparticles and undoped CeO2 nanorods, respectively. Zr doping yielded a CeZr solid solution with increased oxygen vacancies, promoting CO2 adsorption and activation. In addition, adding 2-cyanopyridine as an organic dehydrating agent achieved an outstanding 87% methanol conversion and &gt;99% DMC selectivity by shifting the reaction equilibrium to the desired product. Moreover, mixing CeO2 nanoparticles with hydrophobic fumed SiO2 in gas-phase DMC synthesis led to a doubling of DMC yield. This significant increase was attributed to the faster diffusion of water molecules away from the catalyst surface, facilitated by the hydrophobic SiO2. This study illustrates an effective dual strategy of enhancing oxygen vacancies and implementing in situ water removal to boost DMC production from CO2. The strategy can also be applied to other reactions impacted by water accumulation.</description>
      <author>K Wang, Shiguang Li, Miao Yu, Xinhua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17040839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the potential of NiO@V2CTx MXene-derived electrocatalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.322</link>
      <description>Usman Naeem, Syedah Afsheen Zahra, Irfan Ali, Hu Li, Asif Mahmood, Syed Rizwan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391716775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Usman Naeem, Syedah Afsheen Zahra, Irfan Ali, Hu Li, Asif Mahmood, Syed Rizwan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.322</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Synergistic Redox Activity of SrCoS/PANI for Hybrid Energy Storage and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1402-4896/ad28a4</link>
      <description>Haseeb ul Hassan, Muhammad Waqas Iqbal, Sameer Akbar, Amir Muhammad Afzal, Ehtisham Umar, S. Noor Mohammad, Asma A. Alothman, Niaz Ahmad, Ehsan Elahi, Physica Scripta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391740608

                Abstract Supercapacitors (SCs) and secondary batteries (SBs) are commonly utilized for energy storage, although each has some limitations: low energy density (Ed) and power density (Pd), respectively. To address these issues, a hybrid supercapacitor is a new emerging technique known as supercapattery, which combines both of these devices to optimum the Ed and Pd in a single setting. The hydrothermal method was adopted to synthesize a cost-effective, eco-friendly, and non-toxic SrCoS/PANI, a composite material for optimum results of supercapattery. Crystallinity and morphology study of synthesized nanocomposites strontium cobalt sulfide with Polyaniline (SrCoS/PANI) were examined using SEM and XRD techniques. Initially, the performance was tested using a three-electrode setup of nanocomposites (SrCoS/PANI) in 1 M KOH electrolyte. The effectiveness of a SrCoS/PANI-activated carbon two-electrode supercapattery was examined through cyclic CV, GCD, and EIS techniques. In the two electrodes setup, the device performs admirably with an astonishing specific capacity of 139.4 C/g, a high Ed of 29.56 Wh/kg, and a high Pd of 800 W/kg at 1.0 A/g. The cyclic stability was tested by putting the device through 5000 charging and discharging cycles, which maintained 91.65 % of its Specific capacity (Qs). A hybrid nanocomposite (SrCoS/PANI) device was accomplished, with exceptional electrochemical capabilities at a low price making them a fascinating active material with potential applications in supercapattery technology. The electrocatalytic performance of the synthesized nanostructure (NSs) was studied comprehensively with regard to an oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Haseeb ul Hassan, Muhammad Waqas Iqbal, Sameer Akbar, Amir Muhammad Afzal, Ehtisham Umar, S. Noor Mohammad, Asma A. Alothman, Niaz Ahmad, Ehsan Elahi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1402-4896/ad28a4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cathodized Stainless Steel Mesh for Binder-Free NiFe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;4&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;/NiFe Layer Double Hydroxides Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4028/p-1bmxjg</link>
      <description>Natthapon Sripallawit, Soorathep Kheawhom, Engineering Innovations. 9(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391748095

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an essential reaction commonly applied in various energy storage and conversion technologies. One of the common issues of OER lies in its low kinetic activity. Therefore, developing durable, low-cost, and high-performance OER catalysts is critical. Recently, many attempts have used stainless steel mesh (SSM) as the substrate for OER electrodes because SSM is abundant, cheap, and durable. Nickel/iron-based materials, i.e., NiFe 2 O 4 /NiFe layer double hydroxides (LDHs), are regarded as one of the most excellent OER catalysts in alkaline electrolytes, making them attractive low-cost materials for OER catalysts. However, synthesizing NiFe 2 O 4 /NiFe LDHs directly on the surface of SSM is challenging. Modifying the SSM surface through cathodization has proved to enhance the adhesion and OER activity. Moreover, the cathodization technique is facile and cost-effective. In this work, the surface of SSM is modified by cathodization treatment. Subsequently, NiFe 2 O 4 /NiFe LDHs are deposited onto the surface of treated SSM via a low-temperature one-step chemical bath deposition technique. This synthesis is a binder-free method; the resulted electrodes show excellent OER performance without the binder effects. The as-prepared electrodes have a small Tafel slope of 125.4 mV/dec (1 M KOH) and high durability (10 mA/cm2 for 50 hours).</description>
      <author>Natthapon Sripallawit, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4028/p-1bmxjg</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchically Designed Co&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;@N-Doped Graphitic Carbon as an Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution in Anion-Exchange-Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04077</link>
      <description>S.J. Park, Jong Han Jun, Minjeong Park, Jaehoon Jeong, Jae-Young Jo, Sohee Jeon, Juchan Yang, Sung Mook Choi, Wook Jo, Ji-Hoon Lee, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391748270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S.J. Park, Jong Han Jun, Minjeong Park, Jaehoon Jeong, Jae-Young Jo, Sohee Jeon, Juchan Yang, Sung Mook Choi, Wook Jo, Ji-Hoon Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Tracking the Interactions between CoO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; and CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; during Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303529</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Natasha Hales, Adam H. Clark, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391754627

                Abstract CeO 2 greatly enhances the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity of CoO x , though the enhancement mechanism beyond this synergy is yet to be understood. Here, operando hard X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (hXAS) is applied to monitor the Co K edge and Ce L 3 edge in CoO x /CeO 2 to shed light on the evolution of the Co and Ce oxidation states during OER. In addition, ex situ soft XAS (sXAS) characterizations provide information on the irreversible surface&#8208;specific transformations of the Co L 3 edge as well as of the O K edge. Combining the operando and ex situ spectroscopic characterizations with comprehensive electrochemical analyses, it is confirmed that CeO 2 is not the active center for the OER. However, coupling CeO 2 with CoO x introduces significant modifications in the Co and O species at the CoO x surface and alters the flat band potential (E fb ), leading to more favorable Co oxidation state transformations during OER and possibly modifying the preferential reaction pathway. This work establishes the connections between electronic structures, Co oxidation state and the OER reaction mechanism for CoO x /CeO 2 composites electrodes.</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Natasha Hales, Adam H. Clark, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au Micro&#8208; and Nanoelectrodes as Local Voltammetric pH Sensors During Oxygen Evolution at Electrocatalyst&#8208;Modified Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202300283</link>
      <description>Lejing Li, Ndrina Limani, Rajini P. Antony, Stefan Dieckh&#246;fer, Carla Santana Santos, Wolfgang Schuhmann, Small science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391757154

                The scarcity of state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts has led to intensive research on alternative viable electrocatalytic materials. While activity and cost are the main factors to be sought after, the catalyst stability under harsh acidic conditions is equally crucial. Considering that OER is a proton&#8208;coupled electron&#8208;transfer reaction that involves local acidification of the reaction environment by liberation of H + , the catalyst stability can be largely compromised in such conditions. Consequently, probing the pH value near the catalyst surface under operation leads to a deeper understanding of this process. The applicability of bare Au microelectrodes and nanoelectrodes as sensitive local pH probes during OER is shown in this work by using scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM). Two case studies are presented, including the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art OER catalyst (IrO 2 ) in acidic media and a ZnGa 2 O 4 catalyst in alkaline buffered solution, demonstrating the suitability of the Au probe to accurately determine the local pH value in a wide pH range.</description>
      <author>Lejing Li, Ndrina Limani, Rajini P. Antony, Stefan Dieckh&#246;fer, Carla Santana Santos, Wolfgang Schuhmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202300283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental evidences of the direct influence of external magnetic fields on the mechanism of the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0179761</link>
      <description>Camilo A. Mesa, Felipe A. Garc&#233;s&#8208;Pineda, Miguel Garc&#237;a&#8208;Tecedor, Jiahao Yu, Bahareh Khezri, Sergi Plana-Ruiz, Bruno L&#243;pez, R. Iturbe, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s, APL Energy. 2(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391766798

                The use of magnetic fields as external stimuli to improve the kinetics of electrochemical reactions is attracting substantial attention, given their potential to reduce energy losses. Despite recent reports showing a positive effect on catalytic performance upon applying a magnetic field to a working electrode, there are still many uncertainties and a lack of experimental evidence correlating the presence of the magnetic field to the electrocatalytic performance. Here, we present a combination of electrochemical and spectroscopic tools that demonstrate how the presence of an external magnetic field alters the reaction mechanism of the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), accelerating the overall performance of a Ni4FeOx electrode. Complementary experimental evidence has been gathered supporting the participation of this microscopic magnetic field effect. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) points to a speed-up of the intrinsic reaction kinetics, independent of other indirect effects. In the same direction, the spectro-electrochemical fingerprint of the intermediate species that appear during the electrocatalytic cycle, as detected under operando conditions, indicates a change in the order of the reaction as a function of hole accumulation. All these experimental data confirm the direct influence of an external magnetic field on the reaction mechanism at the origin of the magnetically enhanced electrocatalytic OER.</description>
      <author>Camilo A. Mesa, Felipe A. Garc&#233;s&#8208;Pineda, Miguel Garc&#237;a&#8208;Tecedor, Jiahao Yu, Bahareh Khezri, Sergi Plana-Ruiz, Bruno L&#243;pez, R. Iturbe, N&#250;ria L&#243;pez, Sixto Gim&#233;nez, Jos&#233; Ram&#243;n Gal&#225;n&#8208;Mascar&#243;s</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0179761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Limitations of Chronopotentiometry Test Protocols for Stability Study on Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysts and Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07103</link>
      <description>Inayat Ali Khan, Per Morgen, Raghunandan Sharma, Shuang Ma Andersen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391766804

                The stability studies, using a rotating disk electrode under a constant current, are commonly used for the development of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalyst, where rise in potential with time is reported to be due to the electrocatalyst degradation. Here, we present a careful examination on the use of this technique on commercial IrO2 electrocatalysts in acidic media for a duration of 9 h. We observed that a sudden rise in the electrode potential after &#8764;6 h is rather due to the glassy carbon surface-edge corrosion and detachment between carbon&#8211;catalyst interfaces. Indeed, the layer detachment generates an insulating gap between the electrode and carbon layer, resulting in an increase in the cell potential. On this regard, we examine and recommend a potentiodynamic stability test as a reliable and practical method for fast material screening and for the development of OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Inayat Ali Khan, Per Morgen, Raghunandan Sharma, Shuang Ma Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interplay between Defects and Short-Range Disorder Manipulating the Oxygen Evolution Reaction on a Layered Double Hydroxide Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c02885</link>
      <description>Zixian Li, Jiangrong Yang, Rui Gao, Simin Xu, Xianggui Kong, Xiao Hua, Pu Zhao, Haigang Hao, Dermot O&#8217;Hare, Yufei Zhao, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391773871

                Improving the efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for advancing sustainable and environmentally friendly hydrogen energy. Layered double hydroxides (LDHs) have emerged as promising electrocatalysts for the OER. However, a thorough understanding of the impact of structural disorder and defects on the catalytic activity of LDHs remains limited. In this work, a series of NiAl-LDH models are systematically constructed, and their OER performance is rigorously screened through theoretical density functional theory. The acquired results unequivocally reveal that the energy increase induced by structural disorder is effectively counteracted at the defect surface, indicating the coexistence of defects and disorder. Notably, it is ascertained that the simultaneous presence of defects and disorder synergistically augments the catalytic activity of LDHs in the context of the OER. These theoretical findings offer valuable insights into the design of highly efficient OER catalysts while also shedding light on the efficacy of LDH electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zixian Li, Jiangrong Yang, Rui Gao, Simin Xu, Xianggui Kong, Xiao Hua, Pu Zhao, Haigang Hao, Dermot O&#8217;Hare, Yufei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c02885</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCoNi molybdenum-based oxides for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.104</link>
      <description>Weiliu Fan, Chaofan Liu, Hairong Wang, Jiang Wu, Sheng Chen, Weijie Fang, C. D. Wu, Yong Quan, Daolei Wang, Yongfeng Qi, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391774742

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiliu Fan, Chaofan Liu, Hairong Wang, Jiang Wu, Sheng Chen, Weijie Fang, C. D. Wu, Yong Quan, Daolei Wang, Yongfeng Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tri-metallic fluoride nanoplates immobilized on reduced graphene architectures as efficient oxygen evolution reaction catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118108</link>
      <description>Yanhui Lu, Chengang Pei, Han Xu, Yong Li, Ho Seok Park, Jung Kyu Kim, Xu Yu, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391774927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanhui Lu, Chengang Pei, Han Xu, Yong Li, Ho Seok Park, Jung Kyu Kim, Xu Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metals Based Dual Single&#8208;atom Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis: Stunning Advances and Future Prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301392</link>
      <description>Saira Ajmal, Yang Zhao, Ghulam Yasin, Felix Ofori Boakye, Mohammad Tabish, Mohammed Mujahid Alam, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Wei Zhao, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391778585

                Abstract During the past few years, single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted considerable attention in electrolysis due to their outstanding catalytic performance and efficient atomic utilization. SACs exhibit a simple structure, high catalytic activity, consistent scaling relationships for single sites, and low metal content but their practical applications are still limited. Dual single&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs), which feature excellent selectivity, high atomic utilization efficiency, and remarkable stability, are emerging as new frontiers in heterogeneous electrocatalysis. They increase catalytic activity by promoting synergistic effects between metal&#8208;active sites. In this paper, we present a comprehensive overview of the latest developments in dual&#8208;atom catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In addition, we explore the differences between homonuclear and heteronuclear configurations, the emergence of single/dual&#8208;site metal catalysts, and the methods currently used for their synthesis. Lastly, this review discusses several perspectives for advancing the development of dual&#8208;atom catalysts for OER and ORR electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Saira Ajmal, Yang Zhao, Ghulam Yasin, Felix Ofori Boakye, Mohammad Tabish, Mohammed Mujahid Alam, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Wei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured Co3O4@NiFe-LDH Heterojunction Catalysts for Improving Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173837</link>
      <description>Zhehao Liu, Hefeng Yuan, Zihao Wan, Zhanhong Ma, Xiaoyang Deng, Xiaoguang Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391787360

                Constructing nano-heterojunction catalysts is a highly efficient method for enhancing the thermodynamics and kinetics towards oxygen evolution reaction. In the present study, NiFe-LDH nanoparticles in-situ grown on Co3O4 nanowires bring about abundant heterogeneous interfaces, which productively increase specific surface area and tune electron density distribution. The as-obtained composite comprises rich unsaturated Co sites on Co3O4 and hybrid crystalline/amorphous NiFe-LDH phase, both of which expedite the flow of charge and expose large amounts of active sites. The Co-Ni-Fe electron transport channels are established at the core-shell heterojunction with the transmission of electrons from Co3O4 to NiFe-LDH. The resultant optimal Co3O4@NiFe-LDH/NF-100 catalyst displayed attractive OER activity with low overpotential of 270 mV at 50 mA cm&#8722;2, along with excellent durability in alkaline media. This typical core-shell heterojunction promotes H2O dissociation and strengthens the adsorption of intermediates, thereby enhancing oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Zhehao Liu, Hefeng Yuan, Zihao Wan, Zhanhong Ma, Xiaoyang Deng, Xiaoguang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photosynthetic live microorganism-incorporated hydrogels promote diabetic wound healing via self-powering and oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149545</link>
      <description>Yan Wu, Meiyun Li, Ruiying He, Lan Xiao, Sen Liu, Kaiyuan Chen, Huifen Qiang, kim eun ji, Luxin Li, Yunfei Yin, Xianglin Yuan, Meng Li, Jie Gao, Yulin Li, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391788147

                Electrical stimulation and oxygen are vital for promoting cell proliferation, migration, and differentiation to repair damaged tissues in chronic wound healing in patients with diabetes. The effective oxygen production by Chlorella has garnered attention in the medical field, but the potential of extracellular electron production in skin repair has not been explored. Inspired by this, we developed CHPS hydrogels, a composite of polyacrylamide and sodium alginate, with Chlorella loaded in a semi-interpenetrating network. This network is formed by crosslinking acrylamide initiated by free radicals, with alginate chains dispersed within the network. When applied to wounds, CHPS hydrogels effectively protect damaged tissue, provide mechanical support to Chlorella against external forces, and create an optimal artificial microenvironment to promote the proliferation of Chlorella. Our study demonstrated that CHPS hydrogels exhibit remarkable fracture elongation and adhesion properties and continuously produce oxygen and bioelectrical currents through photosynthesis. Furthermore, the sustained release of dissolved oxygen and bioelectricity by CHPS hydrogels significantly enhances cell proliferation, migration, and angiogenesis, leading to improved wound healing in diabetic mice. These findings provide compelling evidence for further exploration of CHPS hydrogels as a cost-effective, simple, and accessible strategy for enhancing the clinical treatment of chronic wounds in diabetic patients.</description>
      <author>Yan Wu, Meiyun Li, Ruiying He, Lan Xiao, Sen Liu, Kaiyuan Chen, Huifen Qiang, kim eun ji, Luxin Li, Yunfei Yin, Xianglin Yuan, Meng Li, Jie Gao, Yulin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-Mn Pair-Site Triggers Key Oxygen Intermediate for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4725247</link>
      <description>Faming Gao, Y. Wang, Kuo Wei, Yanli Song, Adekunle Adedapo Obisanya, Heen Li, Jing Wang, Hongguan Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391790841

                Herein, variable valence states Mn was adopted to regulate Ru-NC, which serves as a model to reduce the localization of Ru 4d structure and stimulate facile charge transfer, achieving accelerated surface reconstruction to generate Ru&#8210;O active ingredient with high active to acidic water oxidation. Doping Mn not only accelerate surface reconstruction, but also improves durability by eliminating Ru peroxidation due to Mn-buffered charge compensation. The enhancement of OER activity results from the Mn and O induced Ru spin states to change from intermediate spin to low spin, thereby weakening the interaction with *O intermediates, and promoting *OH adsorption&#65292;which benefits the initial step of OER.</description>
      <author>Faming Gao, Y. Wang, Kuo Wei, Yanli Song, Adekunle Adedapo Obisanya, Heen Li, Jing Wang, Hongguan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4725247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directed Electron Transport Induced Surface Reconstruction of 2d Nife-Ldh/Stanene Heterojunction Catalysts for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4725244</link>
      <description>Ze Sheng Lu, Jingkun Wang, Pengfei Zhang, Wenhao Guo, Yongqing Shen, Peizhi Liu, Jianlong Ji, Min Zhao, Hao&#8208;Jie Liang, Junjie Guo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391790924

                As promising non-noble candidates for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), NiFe-based layered double hydroxides (NiFe-LDH) has been proven to transform into its high-oxidation-state Ni/Fe oxyhydroxide, which act as the primary active sites. However, advancing the emergence of high-oxidation-state Ni/Fe oxyhydroxide during OER process currently remains a challenge. Herein, a novel 2D NiFe-LDH/stanene p-n junction catalyst is achieved by inserting stanene between NiFe LDH and Ni foam. Time-dependent Raman spectra and density functional theory calculations (DFT) confirm that stanene not only benefits for the construction of built-in electric field, but also serves as an electron absorber to induce a directed electron transport from Ni, Fe to Sn, which thus facilitates the surface reconstruction to form the catalytically active NiOOH. Consequently, an ultralow OER overpotential (230 mV) at 100 mA cm-2 is achieved, corresponding to a considerable decrease of 22.3 % and 42.1 % compared with the individual NiFe-LDH and stanene, respectively.</description>
      <author>Ze Sheng Lu, Jingkun Wang, Pengfei Zhang, Wenhao Guo, Yongqing Shen, Peizhi Liu, Jianlong Ji, Min Zhao, Hao&#8208;Jie Liang, Junjie Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4725244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inlaying CoP/Ni2P/Fe2P triple heterostructure in MOF-derived carbon nanobox for robust oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131181</link>
      <description>Cuiqing Zhang, Zhiyuan Xing, Peng Yi, Hao Zhang, Lei Zhang, Zhang&#8208;Hui Lu, Fuel. 365(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391795662

                Water electrolysis is a promising strategy for hydrogen production but the major hindrance lies in the inherently sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, a potential OER catalyst with hollow nanostructure is designed and fabricated, which is composed of highly dispersed mixed metal phosphide (CoP/Ni2P/Fe2P) nanoparticles encapsulated in the mesoporous carbon nanoboxes (denoted as CoNiFeP@C NBs). Beneficial from abundant CoP/Ni2P/Fe2P interfaces in these nanoparticles, the electronic structure would be optimized and thus decrease the catalytic energy barrier. Furthermore, the porous hollow carbon layer can not only promote electron and mass transport but also expose more active sites and prevent aggregation of active CoNiFeP units. Owing to the structural and compositional advantages including the suitable electronic structure, promoted charge and mass transfer capability, and massive electrochemical catalytic active sites, the optimized CoNiFeP@C NBs exhibit excellent electrocatalytic performance towards OER. Typically, an overpotential of 260 mV is achieved for CoNiFeP@C NBs at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 with a low Tafel slope of 65.5 mV dec&#8722;1, which is among the top values of the reported Co-based OER electrocatalysts and even outperform commercial RuO2. Impressive stability is also realized in alkaline electrolyte due to the protective carbon layer. This work paves the way for developing advanced OER catalyst towards high catalytic capability and remarkable stability.</description>
      <author>Cuiqing Zhang, Zhiyuan Xing, Peng Yi, Hao Zhang, Lei Zhang, Zhang&#8208;Hui Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing binder for enhanced oxygen evolution and supercapacitance in a PCN-224 functionalized V2CTx composite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.110923</link>
      <description>Ehtisham Umar, Haseebul Hassan, Muhammad Waqas Iqbal, Afaf Alqorashi, Badriah S. Almutairi, Hussein Alrobei, Journal of Energy Storage. 84(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391795749

                The synthesis of nanoscale porous coordination network (PCN-224 MOF) is intricate due to the difficulty in spatially influencing typical soluble metal salt chemicals, leading to the formation of bulk MOFs. This study presents the novel utilization of V2CTx as a metal precursor for the preparation of PCN-224 MOF nanostructures, with the ability to modulate the resulting nanostructure by adjusting the reaction temperature. The growth of PCN-224 provides the surface atoms with strong electronegative in V2CTx MXene and the availability of abundant accessible active sites for ligands. This study introduces a novel methodology for fabricating a composite material by integrating V2CTx MXene and PCN-224 MOF. The PCN-224/V2CTx supercapattery have 185.5C/g specific capacity (Qs) at 2 A/g and an electrode with 82 Wh/kg and 840 W/kg energy density (Ed) and power density (Pd). The electrode exhibited a coulombic efficiency and capacitive retention of 96 % and 82 % after undergoing 15,000 cycles. It has outstanding cyclic stability, maintaining 94 % of charge time and 97 % discharge time after 15,000 cycles. This study suggests using duplicate cell electrodes of PCN-224/V2CTx supercapattery in daily-use portable devices and oxygen evaluation reaction (OER) investigation. This is the first study to examine PCN-224/V2CTx electrochemical behavior and propose high-energy, high-rate electrochemical devices use it as an electrode.</description>
      <author>Ehtisham Umar, Haseebul Hassan, Muhammad Waqas Iqbal, Afaf Alqorashi, Badriah S. Almutairi, Hussein Alrobei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.110923</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doubly-Enhanced Strategy to Construct a Highly Efficient Carbon-Based Bifunctional Catalyst to Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions for Rechargeable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4726915</link>
      <description>Tongwen Xu, Jie Zhang, Xiong Zhang, Jingqi Sha, Shijin Zhang, Yang Mei, Lei Ying, Rong Jin, Haifeng Chen, Lingtao Sun, Yujun Si, Chaozhong Guo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391804875

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tongwen Xu, Jie Zhang, Xiong Zhang, Jingqi Sha, Shijin Zhang, Yang Mei, Lei Ying, Rong Jin, Haifeng Chen, Lingtao Sun, Yujun Si, Chaozhong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4726915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supported Nifes2/Nife-Ldh Nanoflowers for High-Efficiency Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4726604</link>
      <description>Luyao Wang, Lin Liu, Hongxu Zhang, Jian Yu, Lijia Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391809531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luyao Wang, Lin Liu, Hongxu Zhang, Jian Yu, Lijia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4726604</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved oxygen evolution reaction for high-current PEM water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100897</link>
      <description>Guoyu Zhong, Shurui Xu, Baizeng Fang, Chem Catalysis. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391849833

                Ru-based electrocatalysts have been extensively studied for the oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis, and the interactions between Ru atoms and their supports play a crucial role. In a recent issue of Nature Communications, Lv and co-workers reported that the enhanced metal-support interaction significantly improved the stability.</description>
      <author>Guoyu Zhong, Shurui Xu, Baizeng Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Theoretical Study on the Enhanced Oxygen evolution Performance of NiN4-graphene by Ni Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ad297c</link>
      <description>Runchuan Shi, Shihao Feng, Zhaoming Fu, Zongxian Yang, Xilin Zhang, Journal of Physics D: Applied Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391824445

                Abstract Isolated metal-coordinated nitrogen embedded carbon (M-N-C) materials are potential alternatives to noble catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and the activity of metal centers can be further modulated by adjusting the coordination environment. Recently, experimental studies have shown that the aggregation of metal atoms into small clusters or particles is inevitable during the high temperature pyrolysis, while the influences of metal clusters on the OER activity of single metal atoms in M-N-C are unclear. Herein, taking Ni-based single atom as examples, the interaction characters of NiN4 doped graphene (NiN4-graphene) with different Ni clusters were studied. The modulation effects of Ni clusters to the NiN4-graphene were systematically investigated from the geometric configurations, electronic structures, and the OER activity of the Ni single atom. It was found that the OER&amp;#xD;performance of NiN4-graphene can be remarkably improved through the addition of Ni clusters, and the lowest overpotential of 0.43 V is achieved on NiN4-graphene with the modification of Ni13 cluster, which is smaller than that of 0.69 V on NiN4-graphene. Electronic properties calculations showed that the charge transfer from Ni clusters to NiN4-graphene will alter the density of states of Ni single atom near the Fermi level, which promotes the charge transfer from NiN4-graphene to oxygen containing products and optimizes the adsorption strength of oxygen intermediate to close to the ideal adsorption free energy of 2.46 eV by enhancing the hybridization interaction between the O-p orbitals and the Ni-dxz, Ni-dyz orbitals, and finally leading to an enhanced OER activity. The current findings highlight the important role of metal clusters on improving the catalytic performance of M-N-C materials, which benefits for the rational design of M-N-C catalysts with high catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Runchuan Shi, Shihao Feng, Zhaoming Fu, Zongxian Yang, Xilin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ad297c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lowering the kinetic barrier via enhancing electrophilicity of surface oxygen to boost acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2024.01.025</link>
      <description>Ning Han, Xuan Zhang, Chengkai Zhang, Shihui Feng, Wei Zhang, Wei Guo, Runtian Zheng, Renji Zheng, Pengyun Liu, Yunwei Li, Jan Fransaer, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391825290

                The acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential for many renewable energy conversion and storage technologies. However, the high energy required to break the strong covalent O-H bond of H2O in acidic media results in sluggish OER kinetics. Here, we report the critical role of iron in a new family of iron-containing yttrium ruthenate (Y2-xFexRu2O7-&#948;) electrocatalysts in highly increasing the electrophilicity of surface oxygen, leading to a significant reduction of the kinetics barrier by 33%, thus an exceptional OER mass activity of 1,021 A &#183; g Ru &#8722; 1 up to 12.4 and 7.7 times that of Y2Ru2O7-&#948; and RuO2, respectively. Introducing iron reduces the Mulliken atomic charge on the O sites in the generated Ru-O-Fe structure, thereby facilitating the acid-base nucleophilic assault from H2O and reducing the free energy on the rate-determining step of OER. This work provides an effective strategy to reduce the kinetics barrier to achieve highly efficient and economic OER in acidic conditions.</description>
      <author>Ning Han, Xuan Zhang, Chengkai Zhang, Shihui Feng, Wei Zhang, Wei Guo, Runtian Zheng, Renji Zheng, Pengyun Liu, Yunwei Li, Jan Fransaer, Bao&#8208;Lian Su</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matt.2024.01.025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of an ultra-thin electrode for the oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.120159</link>
      <description>Zhenye Kang, Gaoqiang Yang, Jinjun Mo, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391849959

                Noble metal electrocatalysts are highly preferred for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in a proton exchange membrane water electrolysis cell (PEMWE) due to their exceptional catalytic activity and stability. This study proposes a novel thin electrode (NTE) design to enhance the performance of noble metal electrocatalysts for the OER in PEMWE. The NTE utilizes a thin porous transport layer for the direct deposition of Iridium (Ir). Unlike conventional gas diffusion electrodes with deep porous structures that underutilize the catalyst due to limited triple-phase boundary conditions, the flat NTEs with straight-through pores overcome this restriction. The paper compares two deposition methods, electroplating and sputter coating. The in-situ electrochemical properties of NTEs with varying Ir loadings (0.06&#8211;1.01 mg cm&#8722;2) are investigated. The electroplated NTE demonstrates excellent mass activity, achieving 5.05 A mg&#8722;1 at 1.6 V and 80 &#176;C. The NTE exhibits a simple fabrication process and low cost while significantly improving catalyst mass activity. Additionally, the NTE reduces electrode thickness from hundreds of micrometers to only 25 &#956;m. This concept holds great promise for the future advancement of compact and high-efficiency PEMWE electrodes, resulting in reduced cost, volume, and mass of both the electrode itself and the overall system.</description>
      <author>Zhenye Kang, Gaoqiang Yang, Jinjun Mo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.120159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt decorated S-doped carbon electrocatalyst assembly for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100717</link>
      <description>Selvam Mathi, Venkatachalam Ashok, Abdullah Alodhayb, Saravanan Pandiaraj, Nagaraj P. Shetti, Materials Today Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391819159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Selvam Mathi, Venkatachalam Ashok, Abdullah Alodhayb, Saravanan Pandiaraj, Nagaraj P. Shetti</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Electron Interaction at the Amorphous/Crystalline Interface Enables Advanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07189</link>
      <description>Xingheng Zhang, Xingwen Lin, Shoufu Cao, Xiao Chen, Qi Hou, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Fang Dai, Xiaoqing Lu, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391815529

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingheng Zhang, Xingwen Lin, Shoufu Cao, Xiao Chen, Qi Hou, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Fang Dai, Xiaoqing Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D Ruthenium&#8211;Chromium Oxide with Rich Grain Boundaries Boosts Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311172</link>
      <description>Xuhao Zhao, Zijian Li, Haeseong Jang, Xiaoqian Wei, Liu Wang, Min Kim, Jaephil Cho, Xien Liu, Qing Qin, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391818792

                Abstract Ruthenium oxide is currently considered as the promising alternative to Ir&#8208;based catalysts employed for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers but still faces the bottlenecks of limited durability and slow kinetics. Herein, a 2D amorphous/crystalline heterophase ac&#8208;Cr 0.53 Ru 0.47 O 2&#8208;&#948; substitutional solid solution with pervasive grain boundaries (GBs) is developed to accelerate the kinetics of acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and extend the long&#8208;term stability simultaneously. The ac&#8208;Cr 0.53 Ru 0.47 O 2&#8208;&#948; shows a super stability with a slow degradation rate and a remarkable mass activity of 455 A g Ru &#8722;1 at 1.6 V vs RHE, which is &#8776;3.6&#8208; and 5.9&#8208;fold higher than those of synthesized RuO 2 and commercial RuO 2 , respectively. The strong interaction of Cr&#8211;O&#8211;Ru local units in synergy with the specific 2D structural characteristics of ac&#8208;Cr 0.53 Ru 0.47 O 2&#8208;&#948; dominates its enhanced stability. Meanwhile, high&#8208;density GBs and the shortened Ru&#8208;O bonds tailored by amorphous/crystalline structure and Cr&#8211;O&#8211;Ru interaction regulate the adsorption and desorption rates of oxygen intermediates, thus accelerating the overall acidic OER kinetics.</description>
      <author>Xuhao Zhao, Zijian Li, Haeseong Jang, Xiaoqian Wei, Liu Wang, Min Kim, Jaephil Cho, Xien Liu, Qing Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-cost conversion of Mo industrial waste powder into MoO 3 nanobelts catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3873315/v1</link>
      <description>Felice Ursino, Giacometta Mineo, Antonino Scandurra, Angelo Forestan, Carlos G. Alb&#224;, R. Reitano, A. Terrasi, S. Mirabella, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391844551

                Abstract Efficient catalysts for electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) drag a lot of interest in the materials science community since they represent a limiting step in the hydrogen production kinetics during water electrolysis. One of the main goals is developing efficient and sustainable OER catalysts, to replace the currently used platinum group materials (PGMs). Here, we report a low-cost process to produce efficient OER catalysts MoO 3 nanobelts from Mo-based powder obtained by industrial waste. Hydrothermal synthesis was conducted at specific pH values using a solution of Mo-based powder and hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ), leading to different MoO x nanostructures. Morphological, structural and optical characterizations were performed by using Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM), Raman Spectroscopy, X-Ray Diffraction (XRD) and Rutherford Backscattering Spectroscopy (RBS), UV-Vis spectrophotometry. OER performances were evaluated with Linear Sweep Voltammetry (LSV), Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy (EIS) and Mott-Schottky analysis. Under proper pH condition we obtained MoO 3 nanobelts (50&#8211;200 nm wide, 10 &#181;m long) showing the best OER performances at 10 mA cm &#8722; 2 with overpotential of 324 mV and Tafel Slope of 45 mV dec &#8722; 1 . The effect of hydrogen peroxide addiction was investigated and a sustainable solution for industrial waste treatment is proposed.</description>
      <author>Felice Ursino, Giacometta Mineo, Antonino Scandurra, Angelo Forestan, Carlos G. Alb&#224;, R. Reitano, A. Terrasi, S. Mirabella</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3873315/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiMoSe/Ti3C2Tx MXene @ CC as a highly operative bifunctional electrocatalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions in an alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.100</link>
      <description>Mohammad Saquib, Nitish Srivastava, Pratham Arora, Amit C. Bhosale, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 59(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391830822

                Low-cost and highly efficient cathode and anode materials are required for proton exchange membrane and alkaline water electrolyzers. The present work demonstrates the development of a bifunctional cathode and anode material for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) in an alkaline environment. The bimetallic Ni&#8211;Mo selenide is fabricated over the MXene (Ti3C2Tx) grown over the activated carbon fibers by an inexpensive, simple one-step and eco-friendly approach. The electrocatalyst NiMoSe/Ti3C2Tx@CC is developed via a hydrothermal method wherein NiMoSe is observed to grow highly dense nanoporous structure as confirmed by various characterization techniques. Highest activity for HER is observed using NiMoSe/Ti3C2Tx@CC with only overpotential of 203 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 with low Tafel slope (45 mV dec&#8722;1). The catalyst is also proven to support OER activity with requirement of 320 mV as overpotential at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, thus better than commercial IrO2 (&#951;10 = 380 mV). The Tafel slope obtained by NiMoSe/Ti3C2Tx@CC for OER is found to be minimum (189 mV dec&#8722;1) along with a very low charge transfer resistance (3.04 &#937;) and high electrochemical surface area (0.0378 mF cm&#8722;2). The NiMoSe/Ti3C2Tx@CC is found to be highly stable for HER/OER with 1000 LSV cycles.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Saquib, Nitish Srivastava, Pratham Arora, Amit C. Bhosale</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptor for C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;N-Supported Single-Cluster Catalysts in Bifunctional Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03573</link>
      <description>Jing Pan, Min Li, Ivo A. W. Filot, Hui Wang, Emiel J. M. Hensen, Long Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391840068

                Developing highly active cluster catalysts for the bifunctional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is significant for future renewable energy technology. Here, we employ first-principles calculations combined with a genetic algorithm to explore the activity trends of transition metal clusters supported on C2N. Our results indicate that the supported clusters, as bifunctional catalysts for the OER and the ORR, may outperform single-atom catalysts. In particular, the C2N-supported Ag6 cluster exhibits outstanding bifunctional activity with low overpotentials. Mechanistic analysis indicates that the activity of the cluster is related to the number of atoms in the active site as well as the interaction between the intermediate and the cluster. Accordingly, we identify a descriptor that links the intrinsic properties of the clusters with the activity of both the OER and the ORR. This work provides guidelines and strategies for the rational design of highly efficient bifunctional cluster catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jing Pan, Min Li, Ivo A. W. Filot, Hui Wang, Emiel J. M. Hensen, Long Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of ferroelectric polarization on oxygen evolution reaction: a theoretical study of MIrSn2S6 (M = Bi, Mn, and Sb)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00152d</link>
      <description>Haoyun Bai, Weng Fai Ip, Weixu Feng, Hui Pan, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391819463

                The ferroelectric polarization plays important roles in catalytic reactions, but the mechanism is still under debate. In this work, 2D ferroelectric MIrSn2S6 is systematically investigated for revealing the effects of...</description>
      <author>Haoyun Bai, Weng Fai Ip, Weixu Feng, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00152d</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
