<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 01:19:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of bifunctional oxygen evolution reaction and oxygen reduction reaction catalyst CoO-TiO2@NG by high gravity-hydrothermal method for rechargeable Zn air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235675</link>
      <description>Qihui Ding, Qi Zhang, Binbin Li, Ding Cai, Wei Wu, Journal of Power Sources. 625(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403752987

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qihui Ding, Qi Zhang, Binbin Li, Ding Cai, Wei Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study of Highly Active Bifunctional Double-Atom Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02759</link>
      <description>Wei Zhang, Xueqi Cheng, Xiongyi Liang, Keke Mao, Xiao Cheng Zeng, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757553

                Dual-atom catalysts (DACs) can be very effective for catalyzing both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we present theoretical evidence of a new class of highly active DACs, namely, the double-atom embedded in nitrogen-doped graphene sheet 2M-N-C (M = Mn, Fe) on the basis of density functional theory calculations. Importantly, we find that the double active sites of 2M-N-C DACs entail an unconventional catalytic reaction pathway for ORR and OER. We also show that the local coordination environment of the active sites can significantly affect the stability and oxygen catalytic activity of 2M-N-C DACs. In particular, MnFe-N-C DAC not only exhibits good stability but also possesses outstanding bifunctional ORR/OER catalytic activity with the potential difference (&#916;</description>
      <author>Wei Zhang, Xueqi Cheng, Xiongyi Liang, Keke Mao, Xiao Cheng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Lattice Oxygen Regeneration of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide Enhances Oxygen Evolution Catalysis Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413250</link>
      <description>Fengyu Wu, Fenyang Tian, Menggang Li, Shuo Geng, Longyu Qiu, Lin He, Lulu Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Yongsheng Yu, Weiwei Yang, Yanglong Hou, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403764296

                The lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) endows NiFe layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH) with superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, yet the frequent evolution and sluggish regeneration of lattice oxygen intensify the dissolution of active species. Herein, we overcome this challenge by constructing the NiFe hydroxide/Ni4Mo alloy (NiFe&#8208;LDH/Ni4Mo) heterojunction electrocatalyst, featuring the Ni4Mo alloy as the oxygen pump to provide oxygenous intermediates and electrons for NiFe&#8208;LDH. The released lattice oxygen can be timely offset by the oxygenous species during the LOM process, balancing the regeneration of lattice oxygen and assuring the enhancement of the durability. In consequence, the durability of NiFe&#8208;LDH is significantly enhanced after the modification of Ni4Mo with an impressively durability for over 60 h, much longer than that of NiFe&#8208;LDH counterpart with only 10 h. In&#8208;situ spectra and first&#8208;principle simulations reveal that the adsorption of OH&#8722; is significantly strengthened owing to the introduction of Ni4Mo, ensuring the rapid regeneration of lattice oxygen. Moreover, NiFe&#8208;LDH/Ni4Mo&#8208;based anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) presents an impressive durability for over 150 h at 100 mA cm&#8722;2. The oxygen pump strategy opens opportunities to balance the evolution and regeneration of lattice oxygen, enhancing the durability of efficient OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Fengyu Wu, Fenyang Tian, Menggang Li, Shuo Geng, Longyu Qiu, Lin He, Lulu Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Yongsheng Yu, Weiwei Yang, Yanglong Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Lattice Oxygen Regeneration of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide Enhances Oxygen Evolution Catalysis Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413250</link>
      <description>Fengyu Wu, Fenyang Tian, Menggang Li, Shuo Geng, Longyu Qiu, Lin He, Lulu Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Yongsheng Yu, Weiwei Yang, Yanglong Hou, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403766152

                The lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) endows NiFe layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH) with superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, yet the frequent evolution and sluggish regeneration of lattice oxygen intensify the dissolution of active species. Herein, we overcome this challenge by constructing the NiFe hydroxide/Ni4Mo alloy (NiFe&#8208;LDH/Ni4Mo) heterojunction electrocatalyst, featuring the Ni4Mo alloy as the oxygen pump to provide oxygenous intermediates and electrons for NiFe&#8208;LDH. The released lattice oxygen can be timely offset by the oxygenous species during the LOM process, balancing the regeneration of lattice oxygen and assuring the enhancement of the durability. In consequence, the durability of NiFe&#8208;LDH is significantly enhanced after the modification of Ni4Mo with an impressively durability for over 60 h, much longer than that of NiFe&#8208;LDH counterpart with only 10 h. In&#8208;situ spectra and first&#8208;principle simulations reveal that the adsorption of OH&#8722; is significantly strengthened owing to the introduction of Ni4Mo, ensuring the rapid regeneration of lattice oxygen. Moreover, NiFe&#8208;LDH/Ni4Mo&#8208;based anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) presents an impressive durability for over 150 h at 100 mA cm&#8722;2. The oxygen pump strategy opens opportunities to balance the evolution and regeneration of lattice oxygen, enhancing the durability of efficient OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Fengyu Wu, Fenyang Tian, Menggang Li, Shuo Geng, Longyu Qiu, Lin He, Lulu Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Yongsheng Yu, Weiwei Yang, Yanglong Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt oxide/cerium oxide heterogeneous interfaces as advanced durable and bifunctional electrocatalysts for robust industrially relevant overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05895j</link>
      <description>Akbar I. Inamdar, Amol S. Salunke, Jun Ho Seok, Harish S. Chavan, Nabeen K. Shrestha, Sang Uck Lee, Sangeun Cho, Hyunsik Im, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403771846

                Non-precious mixed-phase Co oxide and Ce oxide heterostructured electrodes are investigated as bifunctional electrocatalysts for both oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions in an alkaline medium. They are capable to operate at industrial relevant current density.</description>
      <author>Akbar I. Inamdar, Amol S. Salunke, Jun Ho Seok, Harish S. Chavan, Nabeen K. Shrestha, Sang Uck Lee, Sangeun Cho, Hyunsik Im</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05895j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Probing Coupled with Density Functional Theory Calculation to Reveal the Influence of Fe Doping on Fe&#8208;NiOOH Electrode for High Current Density of Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202304260</link>
      <description>Feng Li, Shiyuan Xu, Xueru Zhao, Wei Ma, Zhulin Niu, Xing Zhong, Jing Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776213

                Abstract Fe&#8208;doped NiOOH electrocatalysts have attracted wide interest for the exceptional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, but the precise role of Fe doping on the improved intrinsic activity remains unclear. Herein, the molecular probe technique combined with density functional theory calculation is used to reveal the influence of the Fe atom on the rate&#8208;determining step of the OER reaction, where the pre&#8208;catalyst of hierarchical self&#8208;supporting NiFe layered double hydroxide [LDH] nanosheets equipped on nickel foam (NiFe LDH/NF) is generated via a facile and industrially well&#8208;matched one&#8208;pot corrosion method. The physical characterization results reveal the reconstruction of NiFe LDH into Fe&#8208;doped NiOOH for promoted OER, which has a lower OH* adsorption energy with fast subsequent steps that help in obtaining an improved charge injection efficiency compared to NiOOH. In addition, more exposed electroactive species and facile delivery of mass/electron inside the catalytic procedure actually have a high&#8208;quality contribution to the outstanding catalytic activity. Therefore, the NiFe LDH 36 /NF electrocatalyst provides high catalytic activities of 241 and 320 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 toward the OER and overall water&#8208;splitting in 1 m KOH. This work provides a promising avenue for the rational design of durable self&#8208;supporting electrodes toward large&#8208;scale water splitting.</description>
      <author>Feng Li, Shiyuan Xu, Xueru Zhao, Wei Ma, Zhulin Niu, Xing Zhong, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202304260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Ultrastable Seawater Electrolysis at Industrial Current Density with Strong Metal&#8208;Support Interaction and Dual Cl&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt;&#8208;Repelling Layers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408982</link>
      <description>Dong Liu, Xiaotian Wei, Jianxi Lu, Xin Wang, Lei Zhu, Yaohai Cai, Yingwei Qi, Lei Wang, Haoqiang Ai, Zhen&#8208;Bo Wang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776351

                Abstract Direct seawater electrolysis is emerging as a promising renewable energy technology for large&#8208;scale hydrogen generation. The development of Os&#8208;Ni 4 Mo/MoO 2 micropillar arrays with strong metal&#8208;support interaction (MSI) as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for seawater electrolysis is reported. The micropillar structure enhances electron and mass transfer, extending catalytic reaction steps and improving seawater electrolysis efficiency. Theoretical and experimental studies demonstrate that the strong MSI between Os and Ni 4 Mo/MoO 2 optimizes the surface electronic structure of the catalyst, reducing the reaction barrier and thereby improving catalytic activity. Importantly, for the first time, a dual Cl &#8722; repelling layer is constructed by electrostatic force to safeguard active sites against Cl &#8722; attack during seawater oxidation. This includes a strong Os&#9472;Cl adsorption and an in situ&#8208;formed MoO 4 2&#8722; layer. As a result, the Os&#8208;Ni 4 Mo/MoO 2 catalyst exhibits an ultralow overpotential of 113 and 336 mV to reach 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for HER and OER in natural seawater from the South China Sea (without purification, with 1 m KOH added). Notably, it demonstrates superior stability, degrading only 0.37 &#181;V h &#8722;1 after 2500 h of seawater oxidation, significantly surpassing the technical target of 1.0 &#181;V h &#8722;1 set by the United States Department of Energy.</description>
      <author>Dong Liu, Xiaotian Wei, Jianxi Lu, Xin Wang, Lei Zhu, Yaohai Cai, Yingwei Qi, Lei Wang, Haoqiang Ai, Zhen&#8208;Bo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408982</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a Z-scheme heterojunction of oxygen-deficient WO3-x and g-C3N4 for superior photocatalytic evolution of H2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105346</link>
      <description>Fengyun Su, Mengzhen Tian, Hailong Cao, Zhishuai Wang, Qiang Zhao, Haiquan Xie, Yezhen Zhang, Xiaoli Jin, Xin Li, Zhengdao Li, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengyun Su, Mengzhen Tian, Hailong Cao, Zhishuai Wang, Qiang Zhao, Haiquan Xie, Yezhen Zhang, Xiaoli Jin, Xin Li, Zhengdao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Back Cover: Rationalizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction over IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Essential Role of Hydronium Cation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418265</link>
      <description>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Jingguang G. Chen, Ping Liu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403777461

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Jingguang G. Chen, Ping Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Back Cover: Rationalizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction over IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Essential Role of Hydronium Cation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418265</link>
      <description>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Jingguang G. Chen, Ping Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403777477

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Jingguang G. Chen, Ping Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long&#8208;Term Selective Photoelectrochemical Glycerol Oxidation via Oxygen Vacancy Modulated Tungsten Oxide with Self&#8208;Healing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409082</link>
      <description>Yoonsung Jung, Seung&#8208;Hwan Kim, Seung&#8208;Kyu Kim, Yejoon Kim, Jun Beom Hwang, Dong&#8208;Yu Kim, Sanghan Lee, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403778140

                Abstract The photoelectrochemical selective oxidation of biowaste glycerol into the high value&#8208;added material, along with hydrogen production, holds significant promise for advancing renewable and sustainable energy technologies. Here, the surface oxygen state of tungsten oxide is modified to selectively oxidize glycerol into glyceraldehyde, a high&#8208;value&#8208;added material, and the selectivity is maintained over a prolonged period using the photo&#8208;stimulated self&#8208;recovery capability. The surface&#8208;coordinated photoelectrode exhibits high charge transfer efficiency to glycerol and favorable glycerol adsorption capacity, enabling the selective conversion of glycerol. At 1.2 V RHE in a 2 m glycerol electrolyte adjusted to pH 2, the tungsten oxide photoelectrode achieves a photocurrent density of 2.58 mA cm &#8722;2 and a production rate of 378.8 mmol m &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 with selectivity of 86.1%. The high selectivity is preserved for 18 h by utilizing the self&#8208;healing capability of tungsten oxide to restore initial states modified by photoelectrochemical oxidation. This work sheds light on the design of highly efficient metal oxide photoelectrodes for selective biomass oxidation over extended periods.</description>
      <author>Yoonsung Jung, Seung&#8208;Hwan Kim, Seung&#8208;Kyu Kim, Yejoon Kim, Jun Beom Hwang, Dong&#8208;Yu Kim, Sanghan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo Bimetallic ZIF Derivatives decorated with CoFe&#8208;LDH to Promote Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401556</link>
      <description>Feng Zhang, Lei Yu, Guang Li, Yangchen Xie, Jiaxin Guo, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xianyou Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779574

                Reasonably screening the targeted oxygen reduction reaction (ORR)/oxygen evolution reaction (OER) constituents and constructing high&#8208;efficiency and stabilized ORR/OER bifunctional electrocatalysts are pivotal for the advancement of rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). Here, CoFe layered double hydroxide (CoFe&#8208;LDH) nanosheets are deposited on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphite&#8208;carbon polyhedra with FeCo alloy nanoparticles (FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP). Due to the synergic effect between FeCo&#8208;NGCP, CoFe&#8208;LDH and FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP, the electrocatalyst with the abundant and accessible active sites can provide good charge/mass transfer, and thus shows wonderful ORR and OER bifunctional electrocatalytic performance. In ORR tests, FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP catalyst displays larger half&#8208;wave potential (E1/2, 0.89 V vs. 0.85 V), higher limiting current density (JL, 5.91 mA/cm2 vs. 5.14 mA/cm2) and better stability than commercial Pt/C. As for OER, FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP possesses a smaller overpotential (&#951;) of 299.6 mV at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and more durable stability than commercial RuO2 (330.6 mV). Furthermore, in ZAB tests, the cycling stability of ZAB&#8208;FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP (over 470 h) outperforms the ZAB&#8208;Pt/C+RuO2 (92 h) with commercial electrocatalyst (Pt/C+RuO2). Therefore, the FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP catalyst offers a new perspective to construct ZABs bifunctional catalysts and their commercial application in ZABs.</description>
      <author>Feng Zhang, Lei Yu, Guang Li, Yangchen Xie, Jiaxin Guo, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xianyou Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A&#8208;site Regulated (PrBa)xCo1.5Fe0.5O6&#8208;&#948; Double Perovskite Oxides: Highly Active and Durable Electrocatalysts for the Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401236</link>
      <description>Changjing Fu, Shibo Ma, Huizhu Xu, Weiling Zhao, Xuedong Xie, Tiantian Cang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779917

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) represents a significant bottleneck in many energy technologies such as electrochemical water splitting, metal&#8208;oxygen (O) batteries, and solid oxide fuel cells (SOFCs), because of the complexity of the reaction process. Double perovskite oxides (ABO3), recognized for their compositional flexibility, have emerged as excellent OER activity and stability. This study investigates the catalytic potential of B&#8208;site ordered double ABO3 with (PrBa)xCo1.5Fe0.5O6&#8208;&#948; (PBCF&#8208;x, x=0.9&#8208;1.1) in alkaline media. The results reveal that PBCF&#8208;0.9, characterized by an A&#8208;site deficient composition, exhibits exceptional OER activity. It demonstrates a low Tafel slope of 76.12 mV&#8901;dec&#8208;1 and a low overpotential (&#951;) of 270 mV at 10 mA&#8901;cm&#8208;2. Notably, the intrinsic OER activity of PBCF&#8208;0.9 is 25% higher than that of the stoichiometric PBCF&#8208;1.0. Additionally, PBCF&#8208;0.9 exhibits remarkable durability, as evidenced by its stable performance during a 6&#8208;hour chronopotentiometry (CP) test and minimal microstructural changes. These results underscore the effectiveness of A&#8208;site deficiency in optimizing the structure of double ABO3 for improved OER performance. This approach presents a promising strategy for designing highly efficient, stable, and inexpensive catalysts for energy&#8208;related applications.</description>
      <author>Changjing Fu, Shibo Ma, Huizhu Xu, Weiling Zhao, Xuedong Xie, Tiantian Cang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homologous Metal-Organic Complexes Reconstructed Oxy-Hydroxide Heterostructures as Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5000343</link>
      <description>Yuting Chen, Haikuo Lan, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Kang Liu, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Yuchen Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403783175

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuting Chen, Haikuo Lan, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Kang Liu, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Yuchen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5000343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-Etched Silver Electrodes Loaded with Iron/Cobalt Catalysts for Enhanced Plasmon-Induced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5000473</link>
      <description>Jian Wu, Zhichen dong, Yimin Niu, Xuguang Chen, Yuchuan Cheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403784494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Wu, Zhichen dong, Yimin Niu, Xuguang Chen, Yuchuan Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5000473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Non&#8208;Noble Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Focus on Transition and Rare&#8208;Earth Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400151</link>
      <description>Jala Bib Khan, Yuan&#8208;Chang Liang, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403792218

                Abstract The demand for renewable energy sources has become more urgent due to climate change and environmental pollution. The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role in green energy sources. This article primarily explores the potential of using non&#8208;noble metals, such as transition and rare earth metals, to enhance the efficiency of the OER process. Due to their cost&#8208;effectiveness and unique electronic structure, these non&#8208;noble metals could be a game&#8208;changer in the field. &#8242;Doping,&#8242; which is the process of adding a small amount of impurity to a material to alter its properties, and &#8242;synergistic effects,&#8242; which refer to the combined effect of two or more elements that is greater than the sum of their individual effects, are two key concepts in this field. Transition and rare earth metals can reduce the overpotential, a measure of the excess potential required to drive a reaction, thus enhancing the OER process by engineering the electronic and surface molecular structure. This article summarizes the roles of various non&#8208;noble metals in the OER process and highlights opportunities for researchers to propose innovative ways to optimize the OER process.</description>
      <author>Jala Bib Khan, Yuan&#8208;Chang Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nanomaterials for efficient oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions in water splitting: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24294/can.v7i2.8543</link>
      <description>Razu Shahazi, Amirul Islam Saddam, Md. Rakibul Islam, Md. Kawsar Mahamud, Mohammed M. Rahman, M. M. Alam, Characterization and Application of Nanomaterials. 7(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403802804

                Water splitting has gained significant attention as a means to produce clean and sustainable hydrogen fuel through the electrochemical or photoelectrochemical decomposition of water. Efficient and cost-effective water splitting requires the development of highly active and stable catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Carbon nanomaterials, including carbon nanotubes, graphene, and carbon nanofibers, etc., have emerged as promising candidates for catalyzing these reactions due to their unique properties, such as high surface area, excellent electrical conductivity, and chemical stability. This review article provides an overview of recent advancements in the utilization of carbon nanomaterials as catalysts or catalyst supports for the OER and HER in water splitting. It discusses various strategies employed to enhance the catalytic activity and stability of carbon nanomaterials, such as surface functionalization, hybridization with other active materials, and optimization of nanostructure and morphology. The influence of carbon nanomaterial properties, such as defect density, doping, and surface chemistry, on electrochemical performance is also explored. Furthermore, the article highlights the challenges and opportunities in the field, including scalability, long-term stability, and integration of carbon nanomaterials into practical water splitting devices. Overall, carbon nanomaterials show great potential for advancing the field of water splitting and enabling the realization of efficient and sustainable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Razu Shahazi, Amirul Islam Saddam, Md. Rakibul Islam, Md. Kawsar Mahamud, Mohammed M. Rahman, M. M. Alam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24294/can.v7i2.8543</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of Perovskite Pr0.5Ba0.5Mn0.8Co0.1Ru0.1O2.5+&#948;/CoRu Nanoparticles with Co&#8211;N&#8211;C Composite Enabling Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403445</link>
      <description>Jialu Wei, Jing Wang, Jing Wang, Yuezhen Mao, Chunwen Sun, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403805667

                Bifunctional catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are essential components of rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries. In this study, we synthesized a Pr0.5Ba0.5Mn0.8Co0.1Ru0.1O2.5+&#948; (PBMCRO) perovskite composite with in situ exsolved CoRu nanoparticles and Co&#8211;N&#8211;C, functioning as an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for zinc&#8208;air batteries. The in situ exsolution of CoRu nanoparticles from the perovskite oxide was facilitated by the reducing action of 2&#8208;methylimidazole (2&#8208;MIM). Concurrently, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C was used to decorate PBMCRO, forming a novel bifunctional composite electrode of Co&#8211;N&#8211;C&#8211;PBMCRO. The incorporation of CoRu nanoparticles introduces a significant number of electrochemically active oxygen vacancies in the perovskite matrix, enhancing ORR and OER performance. Additionally, the Co&#8211;N&#8211;C synergistically improves electrochemical activity while preserving the structural stability of the perovskite oxide. The prepared Co&#8211;N&#8211;C&#8211;PBMCRO catalyst demonstrates significantly enhanced bifunctional performance compared to the undecorated pristine perovskite Pr0.5Ba0.5MnO3&#8211;&#948; (PBMO). The zinc&#8208;air battery with Co&#8211;N&#8211;C&#8211;PBMCRO catalyst achieve a peak power density of approximately 90 mW/cm2 and exhibit remarkable cycling stability for 788 h. This study presents a novel and effective strategy to enhance the catalytic performance of perovskite&#8208;based air electrodes for rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Jialu Wei, Jing Wang, Jing Wang, Yuezhen Mao, Chunwen Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination tuning of FeNi&#8208;HMT Framework derived effective hybrid catalysts for water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401580</link>
      <description>Yunmeng Wang, Luhong Fu, Jiawei Wu, Fulin Yang, Ligang Feng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403805670

                FeNi&#8208;based hybrid materials are promising oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts for water electrolysis in hydrogen generation. In this work, the coordination tuning of FeNi&#8208;HMT frameworks was achieved by simply changing the Fe/Ni ratios using hexamethylenetetramine (HMT) as an organic ligand, and the derived hybrid FeNi catalysts with varied compositions were probed for OER. Incorporating varying amounts of Fe3+ by adjusting the Ni/Fe ratio results in different metal&#8208;organic framework (MOF) structures, and higher Fe feed leads to the formation of amorphous structures due to the coordination structure destruction from the weaker coordination capacity of Fe3+ compared to Ni2+ combining with the tertiary amine ligand. Among them, the FeNi&#8208;HMT (with the Fe/Ni molar ratio of 1/1) derived catalyst, consisting of Fe0.36Ni0.64 alloy/Ni0.4Fe2.6O4 spinel oxide heterostructures supported by graphitized carbon matrix, exhibits the highest OER performance. The unique structure facilitates significant electron transfer at the alloy/spinel interface due to the large work function difference between each phase. This strong electronic effect downshifts the d&#8208;band center of the catalyst and optimizes the binding energies to the crucial oxygenated intermediates, thereby promoting the OER kinetics. This work highlights the importance of the coordination tuning of FeNi&#8208;HMT frameworks for highly efficient catalyst development.</description>
      <author>Yunmeng Wang, Luhong Fu, Jiawei Wu, Fulin Yang, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Screening of Bifunctional Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reaction at the Subnanometer Regime</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02787f</link>
      <description>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403808225

                The development of low-cost, stable, and highly efficient electrocatalysts for the bifunctional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for advancing future renewable technologies. In this...</description>
      <author>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02787f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achievements and Challenges in Surfactants&#8208;Assisted Synthesis of MOFs&#8208;Derived Transition Metal&#8211;Nitrogen&#8211;Carbon as a Highly Efficient Electrocatalyst for ORR, OER, and HER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408227</link>
      <description>Ru&#8208;Ji Li, Wen&#8208;Jun Niu, Wei&#8208;Wei Zhao, Bing&#8208;Xin Yu, Chen&#8208;Yu Cai, Liyang Xu, Fu&#8208;Ming Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403808262

                Abstract Metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) are excellent precursors for preparing transition metal and nitrogen co&#8208;doped carbon catalysts, which have been widely utilized in the field of electrocatalysis since their initial development. However, the original MOFs derived catalysts have been greatly limited in their development and application due to their disadvantages such as metal atom aggregation, structural collapse, and narrow pore channels. Recently, surfactants&#8208;assisted MOFs derived catalysts have attracted much attention from researchers due to their advantages such as hierarchical porous structure, increased specific surface area, and many exposed active sites. This review mainly focuses on the synthesis methods of surfactants&#8208;assisted MOFs derived catalysts and comprehensively introduces the action of surfactants in MOFs derived materials and the structure&#8208;activity relationship between the catalysts and the oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, and hydrogen evolution reaction performance. Apparently, the aims of this review not only introduce the status of surfactants&#8208;assisted MOFs derived catalysts in the field of electrocatalysis but also contribute to the rational design and synthesis of MOFs derived catalysts for fuel cells, metal&#8211;air cells, and electrolysis of water toward hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Ru&#8208;Ji Li, Wen&#8208;Jun Niu, Wei&#8208;Wei Zhao, Bing&#8208;Xin Yu, Chen&#8208;Yu Cai, Liyang Xu, Fu&#8208;Ming Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seawater alkalization via an energy-efficient electrochemical process for CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2410841121</link>
      <description>Xun Guan, Ge Zhang, Jinlei Li, Sang Cheol Kim, Guangxia Feng, Yuqi Li, Tony Cui, Adam Brest, Yi Cui, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 121(45)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403824379

                Electrochemical pH-swing strategies offer a promising avenue for cost-effective and energy-efficient carbon dioxide (CO 2 ) capture, surpassing the traditional thermally activated processes and humidity-sensitive techniques. The concept of elevating seawater&#8217;s alkalinity for scalable CO 2 capture without introducing additional chemical as reactant is particularly intriguing due to its minimal environmental impact. However, current commercial plants like chlor-alkali process or water electrolysis demand high thermodynamic voltages of 2.2 V and 1.23 V, respectively, for the production of sodium hydroxide (NaOH) from seawater. These high voltages are attributed to the asymmetric electrochemical reactions, where two completely different reactions take place at the anode and cathode. Here, we developed a symmetric electrochemical system for seawater alkalization based on a highly reversible and identical reaction taking place at the anode and cathode. We utilize hydrogen evolution reaction at the cathode, where the generated hydrogen is looped to the anode for hydrogen oxidation reaction. Theoretical calculations indicate an impressively low energy requirement ranging from 0.07 to 0.53 kWh/kg NaOH for established pH differences of 1.7 to 13.4. Experimentally, we achieved the alkalization with an energy consumption of 0.63 kWh/kg NaOH, which is only 38% of the theoretical energy requirements of the chlor-alkali process (1.64 kWh/kg NaOH). Further tests demonstrated the system&#8217;s potential of enduring high current densities (~20 mA/cm 2 ) and operating stability over an extended period (&gt;110 h), showing its potential for future applications. Notably, the CO 2 adsorption tests performed with alkalized seawater exhibited remarkably improved CO 2 capture dictated by the production of hydroxide compared to the pristine seawater.</description>
      <author>Xun Guan, Ge Zhang, Jinlei Li, Sang Cheol Kim, Guangxia Feng, Yuqi Li, Tony Cui, Adam Brest, Yi Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2410841121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discrimination between OH&#8722; and H2O oxidation for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101157</link>
      <description>Mengjun Xiao, Qianbao Wu, Hongfei Liu, Xia Zheng, Lei Li, Yan Wang, Chunhua Cui, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403825173

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengjun Xiao, Qianbao Wu, Hongfei Liu, Xia Zheng, Lei Li, Yan Wang, Chunhua Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Ultrahigh&#8208;Loading Ir Single Atoms on Reconstructed Mn&#9472;NiOOH for Enhanced Catalytic Performance in Urea&#8208;Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406786</link>
      <description>Quynh Phuong Ngo, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Byoung&#8208;Suhk Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403825820

                Abstract Investigating advanced electrocatalysts is crucial for improving the efficacy of water splitting to generate environmentally friendly fuel. The discovery of highly effective electrocatalysts, capable of driving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR) in urea&#8208;alkaline environments, is pivotal for advancing large&#8208;scale hydrogen production. This study aims to introduce a new method that involves creating nanosheets of high&#8208;loading iridium single atoms embedded in a manganese&#8208;containing nickel oxyhydroxide matrix (Ir@Mn&#9472;NiOOH). These nanostructures are derived from self&#8208;supported hydrate pre&#8208;catalyst nanosheets grown on nickel foam and then activated through electrochemical etching pretreatment. The Ir@Mn&#9472;NiOOH nanoarchitecture displays outstanding electrocatalytic activity, having a low overpotential of just 258 mV and a potential of 1.319 V (at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) for OER and UOR, respectively. Such extraordinary catalytic characteristics of Ir@Mn&#9472;NiOOH is mainly owing to the strong synthetic electronic interaction between Ir single atoms and Mn&#9472;NiOOH, which can change its electronic characteristics and boost electrochemical catalytic sites. This research presents a new way to produce exceptionally efficient catalysts by adding a synergistic effect to complex multi&#8208;electron processes.</description>
      <author>Quynh Phuong Ngo, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Byoung&#8208;Suhk Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-current decoupled hydrogen and oxygen evolution via nickel&#8211;cobalt based redox mediators and bifunctional catalyst of 3D printing substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.148</link>
      <description>Weide Shao, Guiwei Li, Aodu Zheng, Wenzheng Wu, Biao Lu, Jianing Zhang, Shuguang Chen, Chunling Zhang, Feifei Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403828604

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weide Shao, Guiwei Li, Aodu Zheng, Wenzheng Wu, Biao Lu, Jianing Zhang, Shuguang Chen, Chunling Zhang, Feifei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Ru doping induced interface and defects engineering in 2D square micro-mesoporous CoNiRuOx nanosieves for advanced oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.159</link>
      <description>Wendong Zhang, Xinye Liu, Haonan Zheng, Shan Zhang, Fei Gao, Shaojun Zheng, Yangping Zhang, Xiyue Zhang, Aihua Yuan, Xiangjun Zheng, Yukou Du, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403828751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wendong Zhang, Xinye Liu, Haonan Zheng, Shan Zhang, Fei Gao, Shaojun Zheng, Yangping Zhang, Xiyue Zhang, Aihua Yuan, Xiangjun Zheng, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Step Scalable Synthesis of 3D Self-Supported Superaerophobic Ce-Coupled Ni3S2/NiS@NF Nanobud Catalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110752</link>
      <description>Mengjie Lu, Run Cheng, Sheng Wang, Dandan Liang, Meng Qin, Bili Wang, Rui Song, Duo Chen, Catalysts. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403835596

                The elaborate design of inexpensive, high-performance electrocatalysts from earth-abundant elements toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical in various (electro)chemical processes. Herein, a novel binder-free catalyst of Ce-coupled Ni3S2/NiS supported on Ni foam (Ce-Ni3S2/NiS@NF) is successfully synthesized via a facile one-step hydrothermal method that enables practical feasibility with a significant enhancement of OER activity through anchoring Ce dopants on an Ni3S2/NiS nanobud host. Ce species coupling can modulate electronic structure, which reduces the reaction energy barrier and optimizes OER catalytic activity. More profoundly, the superhydrophilic and superaerophobic properties of the Ce-Ni3S2/NiS@NF electrode further promote mass transfer. As a result, the Ce-Ni3S2/NiS@NF electrode exhibits excellent OER activity with a low overpotential of 236 and 350 mV to achieve current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively, and long-term durability for 24 h in alkaline medium. These results could supply valuable guidelines for the design of other OER catalysts and beyond.</description>
      <author>Mengjie Lu, Run Cheng, Sheng Wang, Dandan Liang, Meng Qin, Bili Wang, Rui Song, Duo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Imidazole-Modified Covalent Organic Frameworks as Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29215076</link>
      <description>Meng Xia, Xinxin Yu, Zhuangzhuang Wu, Yuzhen Zhao, Lijuan Feng, Qi Chen, Molecules. 29(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403837043

                Since the product contains no carbon-based substances and can be driven by non-carbon-based electricity, electrocatalytic water splitting is considered to be among the most effective strategies for alleviating the energy crisis and environmental pollution. This process helps lower greenhouse gas emissions while also supporting the shift toward renewable energy sources. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) involves a more complex multi-electron transfer process, which is the principal limiting factor in overall water splitting. Extensive research has demonstrated that the controlled design of effective electrocatalysts can address this limitation. In this study, a previously unreported covalent organic framework material (COF-IM) was synthesized via a post-synthetic modification strategy. Notably, COF-IM contains imidazole nitrogen metal active sites. Transition metal-coordinated COF-IM@Co can function as a highly effective electrocatalyst, exhibiting a lower overpotential (403.8 mV@10 mA cm&#8722;2) in alkaline electrolytes, thereby highlighting its potential for practical applications in energy conversion technologies. This study offers new perspectives on the design and synthesis of COFs, while also making substantial contributions to the advancement and application of OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Meng Xia, Xinxin Yu, Zhuangzhuang Wu, Yuzhen Zhao, Lijuan Feng, Qi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29215076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Co bimetallic MOF-derived carbon directly application as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113394</link>
      <description>Jingchuan Guo, Yan Gao, Xuankai Cao, Xing Rong, Shidan Chi, Guolan Fan, Lei Zhang, Guohong Tian, Xudong Zhao, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403837219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingchuan Guo, Yan Gao, Xuankai Cao, Xing Rong, Shidan Chi, Guolan Fan, Lei Zhang, Guohong Tian, Xudong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron phosphides nanoparticles strongly coupled to N-doped carbon for high-efficiency oxygen reduction and evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161629</link>
      <description>Qingsong Luo, Pengfei Zheng, Lina Han, Yidan Fu, Xiaoyuan Zeng, Jing Feng, Yudong Sui, Peng Dong, Yingjie Zhang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403838689

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingsong Luo, Pengfei Zheng, Lina Han, Yidan Fu, Xiaoyuan Zeng, Jing Feng, Yudong Sui, Peng Dong, Yingjie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel synthesis of CuHCF/B-rGO composites for oxygen evolution reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-75605-9</link>
      <description>S. Swathi, R. Yuvakkumar, L. Kungumadevi, G. Ravi, Dhayalan Velauthapillai, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403841704

                In this work, we have focused on the preparation of copper hexacyanoferrate/boron doped rGO composites (abbreviated as CuHCF/B-rGO) by employing simple co-precipitation technique subsequently processed with ultrasonication method. The XRD spectra confirmed the existence of the cubic structure of copper hexacyanoferrate with high crystalline peaks. The prepared nanocomposite morphology was evaluated by scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and confirmed CuHCF nanoparticles formation with flake-like and wrinkled sheets. Pure CuHCF nanostructures revealed good OER action at 430 mV to obtain 10 mA/cm2. The obtained CuHCF product OER activity can be further upgraded by incorporating the electrically conductive boron doped reduced graphene oxide matrix into CuHCF nanostructures, for the reason that the overpotential of the CuHCF/B-rGO was reduced to 380 mV to attain 10 mA/cm2 with 88 mV/dec Tafel slope value. The doping of heteroatom considerably improves charge-transfer resistance of metal hexacyanoferrate, giving a small resistance value of 2.97 &#937;, which was lower than that of CuHCF (5.57 &#937;) and CuHCF/rGO (4.31 &#937;). Furthermore, the catalytic activity of the CuHCF/B-rGO was stable at prolonged hours with a small decay of 12.5%. Therefore, this work offers new approach to stimulate the catalytic performance of metal hexcyanoferrate by highly conductive carbon-based materials for water splitting performance.</description>
      <author>S. Swathi, R. Yuvakkumar, L. Kungumadevi, G. Ravi, Dhayalan Velauthapillai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-75605-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to: Synergistic enhancement of electrochemical performance in reversible solid oxide cells via deficiency-induced oxygen vacancy and nanoparticle generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03034-8</link>
      <description>Meng-Yun Zhang, Yunfeng Tian, Lu Zou, Jian Pu, Bo Chi, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403841728

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meng-Yun Zhang, Yunfeng Tian, Lu Zou, Jian Pu, Bo Chi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03034-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Bath Deposition of NiFe Alloy Anode for Efficient Alkaline Water Electrolyzer Integration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407374</link>
      <description>Jingwen Wu, Zhibo Ren, Xindi Xu, Dong Hyeon Mok, Weiqi Guo, Ke Ye, Peng Shen, Weiyi Zhang, Baoxin Ni, Shusheng Wan, Guoliang Yu, Wenbin Cai, Seoin Back, Jinyi Wang, Kun Jiang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403847133

                Abstract Green hydrogen production from water splitting is a feasible way for intermittent renewable energy storage and utilization, where the exploration and scale&#8208;up preparation of high&#8208;performance anodic oxygen evolution electrocatalysts are critical prerequisites for its industrial&#8208;level applications. Herein, a chemical bath deposition of FeNi 3 intermetallic alloys onto Ni mesh support is performed, which delivers a current density of 0.62 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.72 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode for alkaline water oxidation in 1 m KOH and an excellent electrolysis stability at 0.2 A cm &#8722;2 for over 300 h. Moreover, via 3D computational fluid dynamics simulation and flow field optimization, a homogeneous deposition of &#8776;5400 cm 2 NiFe anode is demonstrated within 4 min using the developed flow bath reactor. Once integrating the as&#8208;prepared NiFe anodes into alkaline electrolyzer stack, the voltage variation between each unit cell is below 40 mV at a total operation current of 71 A, or ca. current density of 0.2 A cm &#8722;2 , confirming the uniformity of this batch synthesis protocol and its great potential for industrial alkaline water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Jingwen Wu, Zhibo Ren, Xindi Xu, Dong Hyeon Mok, Weiqi Guo, Ke Ye, Peng Shen, Weiyi Zhang, Baoxin Ni, Shusheng Wan, Guoliang Yu, Wenbin Cai, Seoin Back, Jinyi Wang, Kun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ transcribed local coordinations from CoP nanorods pre-catalyst for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110414</link>
      <description>Yuhao Zhang, Xiuxiu Zhang, Jing Zhang, Chenyu Yang, Baojie Li, Jianglong Guo, Jingjing Jiang, Wanlin Zhou, Donghai Wu, Dongwei Ma, Shiqiang Wei, Qinghua Liu, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403854052

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhao Zhang, Xiuxiu Zhang, Jing Zhang, Chenyu Yang, Baojie Li, Jianglong Guo, Jingjing Jiang, Wanlin Zhou, Donghai Wu, Dongwei Ma, Shiqiang Wei, Qinghua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wet-Chemical Synthesis of Co3Mo3C-Based Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/chemle/upae197</link>
      <description>Ikki Yanagimoto, Masashi Wada, Satoko Takase, Youichi Shimizu, Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403859804

                Abstract In recent years, efforts have been made to adapt secondary metal-air batteries for practical rechargeable applications through the development of bifunctional catalysts, which are highly active in both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Molybdenum carbides, known for their high chemical durability and electrical conductivity, are being investigated as electrode materials for hydrogen evolution reactions in water electrolysis. In this study we found a new wet-chemical synthesis of cobalt-molybdenum-based carbides. Especially, the synthesized Mn-doped Co&#8323;(Mo&#8320;.&#8329;Mn&#8320;.&#8321;)&#8323;C catalyst gave a remarkable activity for both OER and ORR, showing significant potential for the advancement of metal-air batteries as secondary batteries.</description>
      <author>Ikki Yanagimoto, Masashi Wada, Satoko Takase, Youichi Shimizu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/chemle/upae197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of perovskite oxygen vacancies for oxygen electrocatalysis at different temperatures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53578-7</link>
      <description>Zhiheng Li, Xin Mao, Desheng Feng, Mengran Li, Xiaoyong Xu, Yadan Luo, Linzhou Zhuang, Rijia Lin, Tianjiu Zhu, Fengli Liang, Zi Huang, Dong Liu, Zifeng Yan, Aijun Du, Zongping Shao, Zhonghua Zhu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403875968

                Efficient catalysts are imperative to accelerate the slow oxygen reaction kinetics for the development of emerging electrochemical energy systems ranging from room-temperature alkaline water electrolysis to high-temperature ceramic fuel cells. In this work, we reveal the role of cationic inductive interactions in predetermining the oxygen vacancy concentrations of 235 cobalt-based and 200 iron-based perovskite catalysts at different temperatures, and this trend can be well predicted from machine learning techniques based on the cationic lattice environment, requiring no heavy computational and experimental inputs. Our results further show that the catalytic activity of the perovskites is strongly correlated with their oxygen vacancy concentration and operating temperatures. We then provide a machine learning-guided route for developing oxygen electrocatalysts suitable for operation at different temperatures with time efficiency and good prediction accuracy. Catalyst screening is an important process but it's usually time-consuming and labor intensive. Here the authors report the prediction of oxygen vacancy for perovskites using machine learning techniques to develop suitable oxygen electrocatalysts for solid oxide fuel cells at reduced temperatures.</description>
      <author>Zhiheng Li, Xin Mao, Desheng Feng, Mengran Li, Xiaoyong Xu, Yadan Luo, Linzhou Zhuang, Rijia Lin, Tianjiu Zhu, Fengli Liang, Zi Huang, Dong Liu, Zifeng Yan, Aijun Du, Zongping Shao, Zhonghua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53578-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of Catalytic Electrodes Containing Iron&#8208;Cobalt&#8208;Nickel Composite Components for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400500</link>
      <description>Ming Du, Xiao Lv, Zhiyong Cao, Wei Wang, Jun Qu, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403877321

                Transition metal&#8208;based electrocatalytic materials for hydrogen production through water splitting offer advantages in terms of price and availability compared to noble metal&#8208;based catalysts, among which, Fe&#8208;, Co&#8208;, and Ni&#8208;based compounds are the most typical and widely studied materials. Utilizing the synergistic effects between composite components in compounds containing multiple metal elements is an important way to improve the catalytic performance of catalysts, so developing ternary or multiple active center catalysts containing Fe, Co, and Ni is a promising direction. In this mini&#8208;review, we provide an summary of the latest achievements of water splitting catalyst materials simultaneously containing Fe, Co, and Ni elements. It was summarized according to several groups including compounds of boron&#8208;/carbon&#8208;/nitrogen&#8208;/phosphorus&#8208;/oxygen&#8208;group elements, metal&#8208;organic framework&#8208;based compounds, and compounds in situ grown from alloy matrix. Also challenges that need to be addressed are presented at the end of the article.</description>
      <author>Ming Du, Xiao Lv, Zhiyong Cao, Wei Wang, Jun Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of Flower&#8208;like Co 2 P/WO 3&#8208;x /Carbon Cloth Catalysts with Oxygen Vacancies for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402907</link>
      <description>Hui Guo, Lu Pan, Huimin Jiang, Mengyou Gao, Hong Wang, Aslam Khan, Nasir A. Siddiqu, Jianjian Lin, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403877764

                The Constructing an efficient and low&#8208;cost oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalyst is critical for improving the performance of electrolysis in alkaline water. In this study, a self&#8208;supported electrocatalyst of flower&#8208;like cobalt phosphide and tungsten oxide (Co2P/WO3&#8208;x/CC) was prepared on carbon cloth (CC) surface by hydrothermal reaction with solution immersion etching and phosphorization annealing under H2/Ar atmosphere. This strategy can generate oxygen vacancies (OV), improving the speed of charge transfer between cobalt phosphide (Co2P) and tungsten oxide (WO3&#8208;x) components. The catalyst greatly increases the electrochemical active surface area, which is beneficial for efficient oxygen evolution. Electrochemical testing studies show that in 1.0 M KOH solution, Co2P&#8208;WO3&#8208;x/CC catalyst exhibits good OER activity, with a low overpotential of 254 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2, a small Tafel slope of 58.32 mV dec&#8208;1. The synergistic effect of oxygen vacancies and Co2P with WO3&#8208;x can regulate electronic structures, expose more active sites, and cooperatively enhancing the OER activity. This study provides a workable strategy for preparing efficient non&#8208;noble metal OER electrocatalysts on engineered interfaces and OV.</description>
      <author>Hui Guo, Lu Pan, Huimin Jiang, Mengyou Gao, Hong Wang, Aslam Khan, Nasir A. Siddiqu, Jianjian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Octahedral Co&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt;&#8208;O&#8208;Co&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; in Mixed Cobalt Spinel Promotes Active and Stable Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404007</link>
      <description>Daojin Zhou, Jiaqi Yu, Jialun Tang, Xiaoyan Li, Pengfei Ou, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403879129

                Abstract Cobalt (Co)&#8208;based oxides show promising activity as precious metal&#8208;free catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis, but the dissolution of Co has limited the durability of Co 3 O 4 at industrially relevant current densities. This work demonstrates that cation in an octahedral coordination environment accounts for the oxygen evolution activity. Using a mixed inverse&#8208;normal phase spinel Co x Ga (3&#8208; x ) O 4 as a proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept example, the designed Co 2+ &#8208;O&#8208;Co 3+ motifs in octahedral sites trigger oxygen evolution through a kinetically favorable radical coupling pathway. Furthermore, lattice oxygen exchange, a leading factor in catalyst structural degradation for normal Co 3 O 4 , is suppressed, as evidenced by isotopic labeling experiments and theoretical calculations. With the optimized catalyst, Co 1.8 Ga 1.2 O 4 , an overpotential of 310 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 is reported, with stable operation at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 for 200 h in a three&#8208;electrode setup, and a proton exchange membrane electrolyzer operating at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 for 450 h.</description>
      <author>Daojin Zhou, Jiaqi Yu, Jialun Tang, Xiaoyan Li, Pengfei Ou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the evolution of high-entropy oxide OER electrocatalyst with anion regulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.295</link>
      <description>Dan Wang, Yihang Yu, Huan He, Zenghui Li, Xiaojing Wen, Yanguo Liu, Xiwei Qi, Zhiyuan Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403880232

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Wang, Yihang Yu, Huan He, Zenghui Li, Xiaojing Wen, Yanguo Liu, Xiwei Qi, Zhiyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Al and Zn on Oxygen Evolution Reaction of (FeCoNiMnCu)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3.2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202404023</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Junhua You, Yao Zhao, Baolin Yi, Ren Ying&#8208;lei, ChemistrySelect. 9(41)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403881523

                Abstract Because of its low cost and abundant sources, hydrogen serves as a clean energy alternative capable of successfully substituting fossil fuels. A highly efficient method for generating hydrogen energy currently is by the electrolysis of water. The oxygen&#8208;extraction reaction (OER), a component of water electrolysis, requires a complex chemical pathway that involves multiproton and multielectron interactions. To enhance reaction efficiency in the OER process, catalysts are crucial; thus, the search for high&#8208;performance, cost&#8208;effective catalysts is underway. This experimental study involved the enhancement of the five&#8208;membered high&#8208;entropy oxide (FeCoNiMnCu) 3 O 3.2 by incorporating a sixth group element (Zn, Al). The organization, morphology, and OER properties were analyzed following the preparation utilizing a mechanical ball milling process. A series of rock salt&#8208;type hexagonal high entropy oxides with differing ball milling durations were synthesized to investigate the influence of the production method on the surface shape and catalytic properties of high entropy oxides. The results indicated that the single&#8208;phase rock salt structure of (FeCoNiMnCuAl) 3 O 3.5 , a high&#8208;entropy oxide, exhibited significantly altered diffraction peaks, hence improving OER performance. Optimization of the preparation technique revealed that a 72&#8208;h ball milling duration resulted in an overpotential of merely 293 mV and an electrochemically active surface area approximately double that of the other milling durations.</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Junhua You, Yao Zhao, Baolin Yi, Ren Ying&#8208;lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202404023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bioinspired Water Oxidation Catalyst that is ~1/10th as Active as the Photosystem II Oxygen Evolving Center at pH 7: A Study of Activity and Stability Factors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02336f</link>
      <description>Danijel Boskovic, Richard Terrett, Matthew Longhurst, Sabeel M. Basheer, Alireza Ariafard, Pawe&#322; Wagner, Ron J. Pace, Rob Stranger, Gerhard F. Swiegers, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403881595

                The activity and stability of a heterogeneous water oxidation catalyst inspired by the Photosystem II &#8211; Oxygen Evolving Center (PSII-OEC) is reported. Ca-doped birnessite MnOx supported on a liquid crystalline...</description>
      <author>Danijel Boskovic, Richard Terrett, Matthew Longhurst, Sabeel M. Basheer, Alireza Ariafard, Pawe&#322; Wagner, Ron J. Pace, Rob Stranger, Gerhard F. Swiegers</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02336f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced asymmetric supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction performance by sugarcane molasses-generated Co3O4 nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.253</link>
      <description>Asma Hayat, Aneela Tahira, Gulzar Ali, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Ihsan Ali Mahar, Elmuez A. Dawi, Matteo Tonezzer, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885386

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asma Hayat, Aneela Tahira, Gulzar Ali, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Ihsan Ali Mahar, Elmuez A. Dawi, Matteo Tonezzer, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling New Insights into Photocatalytic Enhancement of p-n BiVO4-OV/NiMoO4 Heterojunctions through Oxygen Defect Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hazadv.2024.100515</link>
      <description>Bavani Thirugnanam, Mani Preeyanghaa, S. Munusamy, Journal of Hazardous Materials Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403896436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bavani Thirugnanam, Mani Preeyanghaa, S. Munusamy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hazadv.2024.100515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating surface reconstruction and lattice oxygen mechanism of nickel (oxy)hydroxide by defect engineering for industrial electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156977</link>
      <description>Xiangling Wang, Zhimin Li, Yu Tang, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Guo Chen, Jinsong Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403897159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangling Wang, Zhimin Li, Yu Tang, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Guo Chen, Jinsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Nickel-Based Perovskite Oxides for the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01471</link>
      <description>Juliana B. Falqueto, Natasha Hales, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403900758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juliana B. Falqueto, Natasha Hales, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical heterostructure regulated by nickel-iron oxyhydroxides on carbon-incorporated cobalt oxide nanorod arrays for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.355</link>
      <description>Jing Li, Yuanqiang Wang, Zhili Xue, Ting Wang, Haozhen Zhu, Yichuan Rui, Chengjie Wang, Dezhi Pan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403902652

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Li, Yuanqiang Wang, Zhili Xue, Ting Wang, Haozhen Zhu, Yichuan Rui, Chengjie Wang, Dezhi Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A fluffy sphere-like NiCoCu-carbonate hydroxide based electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction in pH neutral electrolyte solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04511d</link>
      <description>Li Yu, Xiaocai Ma, Qin Liang, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403904488

                Highly efficient, serviceable, and cost-efficient electrode materials for electrochemical water oxidation to evolve O2 is an important factor in renewable chemical fuels, including water splitting and reusable metal&#8722;air battery. Herein,...</description>
      <author>Li Yu, Xiaocai Ma, Qin Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04511d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lanthanum-based nanomaterials for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.10.008</link>
      <description>Miao He, Ping Wang, Jiasai Yao, Y. Li, Senyao Meng, Zhenxing Li, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403904817

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miao He, Ping Wang, Jiasai Yao, Y. Li, Senyao Meng, Zhenxing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.10.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-efficiency Photocatalytic Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Properties by Z-scheme Electron Transfer in BiVO4/C3N5 Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124766</link>
      <description>Wuyou Wang, Biqing Li, Jia Shi, Kai Zhu, Yeru Zhang, Xuexin Liu, Claudia Li, Feiyang Hu, Xinguo Xi, Sibudjing Kawi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403905019

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wuyou Wang, Biqing Li, Jia Shi, Kai Zhu, Yeru Zhang, Xuexin Liu, Claudia Li, Feiyang Hu, Xinguo Xi, Sibudjing Kawi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant-induced electronic state modulation of ruthenium oxide for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157107</link>
      <description>Lu Lu, Zijing Xu, Shuaichong Wei, Songan Zhao, Xiaohang Du, Yanji Wang, Lanlan Wu, Guihua Liu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403905255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Lu, Zijing Xu, Shuaichong Wei, Songan Zhao, Xiaohang Du, Yanji Wang, Lanlan Wu, Guihua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe2O4 nanoparticle embedded carbon nanofibers: A promising non-noble metal catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.353</link>
      <description>Trupti Kamble, S.R. Shingte, Vijay D. Chavan, Deok&#8208;kee Kim, S.H. Mujawar, Tukaram D. Dongale, P.B. Patil, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403906342

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Trupti Kamble, S.R. Shingte, Vijay D. Chavan, Deok&#8208;kee Kim, S.H. Mujawar, Tukaram D. Dongale, P.B. Patil</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V-doped transition metal selenides derived from NiFe Prussian blue analogues for efficient oxygen evolution reaction and urea oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.267</link>
      <description>Youwei Cheng, Lian Zhu, Yaqiong Gong, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403906511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youwei Cheng, Lian Zhu, Yaqiong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress of Ir/Ru-based catalysts for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction in acidic environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.277</link>
      <description>Jiayang Li, Chunmei Tang, Yangdong Zhou, Ruijiang Hong, Fang Meng, Lixin Xing, Sheng Wang, Ling Meng, Siyu Ye, Lei Du, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403906548

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayang Li, Chunmei Tang, Yangdong Zhou, Ruijiang Hong, Fang Meng, Lixin Xing, Sheng Wang, Ling Meng, Siyu Ye, Lei Du</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A binary mixture of ionic liquids as a sustainable electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.126385</link>
      <description>Bidyutjyoti Dutta, Madhabi Konwar, Lakhyajyoti Borthakur, Diganta Sarma, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403910583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bidyutjyoti Dutta, Madhabi Konwar, Lakhyajyoti Borthakur, Diganta Sarma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.126385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and synthesis of a 3D urchin-like Ni/WC@NSCNT electrocatalyst for enhanced bifunctional performance in oxygen evolution and reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177221</link>
      <description>Eunsu Jang, Subin Lee, Jangwoo Cho, Ji Hoon Kim, Jooheon Kim, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1010(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403912631

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eunsu Jang, Subin Lee, Jangwoo Cho, Ji Hoon Kim, Jooheon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Co/CoTe heterostructure internal hairy fibers towards high-efficiency oxygen electrocatalysis for flexible Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.183</link>
      <description>Jin Wang, Bing Li, Tiantian Tang, Caiyun Li, Hongrui Yang, Hanwen He, Xiaoqing Lin, Yang Song, Sen Zhang, Chao Deng, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915344

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jin Wang, Bing Li, Tiantian Tang, Caiyun Li, Hongrui Yang, Hanwen He, Xiaoqing Lin, Yang Song, Sen Zhang, Chao Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Density Atomic Level Defect Engineering of 2D Fe&#8208;Based Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks Boosts Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202405936</link>
      <description>Xin Zhao, Shixun Wang, Yanhui Cao, Yun Li, Arsenii S. Portniagin, Bing Tang, Qi Liu, Peter Kas&#225;k, Tianshuo Zhao, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Andrey L. Rogach, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403917276

                Abstract Electrocatalysts based on metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) attracted significant attention for water splitting, while the transition between MOFs and metal oxyhydroxide poses a great challenge in identifying authentic active sites and long&#8208;term stability. Herein, we employ on&#8208;purpose defect engineering to create high&#8208;density atomic level defects on two&#8208;dimensional Fe&#8208;MOFs. The coordination number of Fe changes from 6 to 4.46, and over 28% of unsaturated Fe sites are formed in the optimized Fe&#8208;MOF. In situ characterizations of the most optimized Fe&#8208;MOF 0.3 electrocatalyst during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process using Fourier transform infrared and Raman spectroscopy have revealed that some Fe unsaturated sites become oxidized with a concomitant dissociation of water molecules, causing generation of the crucial *OH intermediates and Fe oxyhydroxide. Moreover, the presence of Fe oxyhydroxide is compatible with the Volmer and Heyrovsky steps during the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) process, which lower its energy barrier and accelerate the kinetics. As a result, the optimized Fe&#8208;MOF electrodes delivered remarkable OER (259 mV at 10 mA cm -2 ) and HER (36 mV at 10 mA cm -2 ) performance. Our study offers comprehensive understanding of the effect of phase transformation on the electrocatalytic process of MOF&#8208;based materials.</description>
      <author>Xin Zhao, Shixun Wang, Yanhui Cao, Yun Li, Arsenii S. Portniagin, Bing Tang, Qi Liu, Peter Kas&#225;k, Tianshuo Zhao, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Andrey L. Rogach</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202405936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand engineering enhances (photo) electrocatalytic activity and stability of zeolitic imidazolate frameworks via in-situ surface reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53385-0</link>
      <description>Zheao Huang, Zhouzhou Wang, Hannah Rabl, Shaghayegh Naghdi, Qiancheng Zhou, Sabine Schwarz, Do&#287;ukan Hazar Apayd&#305;n, Ying Yu, Dominik Eder, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403918762

                Abstract The current limitations in utilizing metal-organic frameworks for (photo)electrochemical applications stem from their diminished electrochemical stability. In our study, we illustrate a method to bolster the activity and stability of (photo)electrocatalytically active metal-organic frameworks through ligand engineering. We synthesize four distinct mixed-ligand versions of zeolitic imidazolate framework-67, and conduct a comprehensive investigation into the structural evolution and self-reconstruction during electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions. In contrast to the conventional single-ligand ZIF, where the framework undergoes a complete transformation into CoOOH via a stepwise oxidation, the ligand-engineered zeolitic imidazolate frameworks manage to preserve the fundamental framework structure by in-situ forming a protective cobalt (oxy)hydroxide layer on the surface. This surface reconstruction facilitates both conductivity and catalytic activity by one order of magnitude and considerably enhances the (photo)electrochemical stability. This work highlights the vital role of ligand engineering for designing advanced and stable metal-organic frameworks for photo- and electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Zheao Huang, Zhouzhou Wang, Hannah Rabl, Shaghayegh Naghdi, Qiancheng Zhou, Sabine Schwarz, Do&#287;ukan Hazar Apayd&#305;n, Ying Yu, Dominik Eder</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53385-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo-MOF-74/Mn-MOF-74 Nanocomposite as a electrocatalyst for improved oxygen evolution reaction catalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133516</link>
      <description>Lan Xiao, Jian Wen, Guanghui Wu, Pinghua Chen, Mengxue Wang, Hualin Jiang, Xinming Zhou, Jianan Yan, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403931276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lan Xiao, Jian Wen, Guanghui Wu, Pinghua Chen, Mengxue Wang, Hualin Jiang, Xinming Zhou, Jianan Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous network of boron-doped IrO2 nanoneedles with enhanced mass activity for acidic oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01358a</link>
      <description>Fei Hu, P. Huang, Feng Xu, Changjian Zhou, Xinjuan Zeng, Congcong Liu, Guangjin Wang, Xiaowei Yang, Huawen Hu, Materials Horizons. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403931327

                While the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is essential for realizing practical hydrogen production, the trade-off among activity, stability, and cost of state-of-the-art iridium (Ir)-based oxygen evolution reaction (OER)...</description>
      <author>Fei Hu, P. Huang, Feng Xu, Changjian Zhou, Xinjuan Zeng, Congcong Liu, Guangjin Wang, Xiaowei Yang, Huawen Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01358a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of Co doping for Fe metal on boosting hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133558</link>
      <description>Xuxin Song, Chunyan Fan, Tang Yao, Yangyang Ren, Zehao Zang, Lanlan Li, Xiaofei Yu, Zunming Lu, Xiaojing Yang, Xinghua Zhang, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403917411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuxin Song, Chunyan Fan, Tang Yao, Yangyang Ren, Zehao Zang, Lanlan Li, Xiaofei Yu, Zunming Lu, Xiaojing Yang, Xinghua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133558</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and Activity of Organometallic Phthalocyanine Sheets for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999676</link>
      <description>Walter Orellana, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Walter Orellana</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing electronic structure modulation strategies toward the development of low&#8208;cost oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elt2.65</link>
      <description>Zhen Zhang, Shaobo Han, Li Cheng, Chao Cai, Meng Gu, Electron. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779894

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reactions (OER) are critical to electrochemical synthesis reactions, including hydrogen production and organic hydrogenation. However, the high cost of existing OER catalysts (primarily Ir/Ru and its derived oxides) limits their practical application for electrochemical synthesis. To develop a low&#8208;cost, high&#8208;efficiency alternative, we need a deeper understanding of both the mechanisms that drive OER and the relationship between the catalyst's electronic structure and active sites. Here, we summarized recent developments of catalysts, especially focusing on the electronic structure modulation strategies and their subsequent activity enhancement. Most importantly, we pointed out the study directions for further work.</description>
      <author>Zhen Zhang, Shaobo Han, Li Cheng, Chao Cai, Meng Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elt2.65</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Covalent Coupling of Carbon Nitrides and Dyes for Selective and Sensitive Electrochemiluminescent Detection of Local H+ in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l831h</link>
      <description>Yu Wang, Zhou Sijia, Yunying Zhen, Yongji Wang, Y.H. Hou, Kaiqing Wu, Chaofeng Huang, Songqin Liu, Yanfei Shen, Ran Chen, Yuanjian Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776137

                An accurate understanding of the mechanism of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for the design of efficient catalysts and the development of hydrogen energy. Despite significant advancements in microscopic pH detection studies through the use of mainstream strategies, such as scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM), rotating ring-disc electrode (RRDE), and spectroscopic techniques, selective and sensitive detection of the change of proton (H+) concentration near the vicinity of the electrode during OER with high temporal resolution remains elusive. In this study, we pioneered the creation of an efficient hybrid electrochemiluminescence-based (ECL-based) pH sensor that enables the detection of H+ in the vicinity of the electrodes during OER. A new class of luminophore based on ECL resonance energy transfer (ECL-RET) was theoretically predicted and further synthesized by grafting fluorescent dyes onto carbon nitride nanosheets (CN) through non-covalent interaction. We present that one of the newly synthesized emitters, CN-FITC, is capable of detecting proton with fast response time, where the ECL intensity of CN-FITC is regulated by proton concentration. By coating this emitter onto an electrode positioned near OER catalysts, proton generation near the vicinity of the catalysts could be qualitatively detected, providing details of the reaction mechanism of OER and unveiling the catalyst degrading pathway caused by proton accumulation. Additionally, the average proton generation rate on the catalyst was extracted from the local pH measurement, leading to a quantitative descriptor of the OER reaction rate. Owing to the high designability of the dye, this study opens up a new strategy for the detection of more reaction intermediates.</description>
      <author>Yu Wang, Zhou Sijia, Yunying Zhen, Yongji Wang, Y.H. Hou, Kaiqing Wu, Chaofeng Huang, Songqin Liu, Yanfei Shen, Ran Chen, Yuanjian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l831h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-MOF-based catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction: Microenvironment regulated by organic ligands, metals and carbonization synergistically</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120888</link>
      <description>Chenchen Ding, Weiwei Zhong, Yuqi Cao, Tingting Ma, Huimin Ye, Zheng Fang, Yirong Feng, Shuangfei Zhao, Jiming Yang, Yuguang Li, L. Shen, Wei He, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403936537

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenchen Ding, Weiwei Zhong, Yuqi Cao, Tingting Ma, Huimin Ye, Zheng Fang, Yirong Feng, Shuangfei Zhao, Jiming Yang, Yuguang Li, L. Shen, Wei He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of high vacuum tribological performance of lead-doped hydrogenated diamond-like carbon coatings after atomic oxygen and ultraviolet irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2024.110356</link>
      <description>Jiadong Shi, Guozheng Ma, Guolu Li, Zhen Li, Haichao Zhao, Cuihong Han, Haidou Wang, Tribology International. 202(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403860172

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiadong Shi, Guozheng Ma, Guolu Li, Zhen Li, Haichao Zhao, Cuihong Han, Haidou Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2024.110356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave&#8208;assisted control of Pt&#63743;Ni nanoalloy clusters on the nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene oxide for energy conversion with oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12499</link>
      <description>Seung Geun Jo, Gil&#8208;Ryeong Park, Jemin Kim, D. Ahn, Rahul Ramkumar, Sun&#8208;I Kim, Duck Hyun Lee, Jung Woo Lee, EcoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403822209

                Abstract Research on the production and utilization of hydrogen energy is essential to overcome the environmental issues caused by fossil fuels. Herein, we anchor Pt&#63743;Ni nanoalloy clusters (Pt&#8208;Ni NACs) on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene oxide (NrGO) by a facile microwave&#8208;assisted synthesis and analyze the variations of catalyst properties based on the Pt&#63743;Ni composition and the presence of nitrogen. Ni inclusion in the Pt matrix can induce lattice strain and change the electronic structure, while the doped nitrogen into the graphene can enhance electron transfer and improve the durability of the catalyst through strong chemical bonding with the alloy clusters. TEM analysis discovers that the NACs are uniformly decorated in a few&#8208;nanometer&#8208;size on the graphene surface, and the formation of the Pt&#63743;Ni NACs and structural changes according to composition are confirmed through XRD and XPS. In addition, the structural changes due to N&#8208;doping and its bonding with the NACs are observed through Raman spectroscopy and XPS. Electrochemical measurements reveal that Pt 2.6 Ni NACs/NrGO exhibits the highest ORR onset potential (0.893 V) and the lowest HER overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 (22 mV) among other catalysts, and those activities are almost unchanged under long&#8208;term durability tests. From these results, Pt 2.6 Ni NACs/NrGO is utilized in a zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB) system, demonstrating better battery performance than commercial Pt and Ir&#8208;based catalysts. Moreover, it is applied to hydrogen collection, showing linear trend in hydrogen production over time, confirming the catalyst's availability in hydrogen production and utilization. image</description>
      <author>Seung Geun Jo, Gil&#8208;Ryeong Park, Jemin Kim, D. Ahn, Rahul Ramkumar, Sun&#8208;I Kim, Duck Hyun Lee, Jung Woo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Carrier Dynamics of BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanode via Dual Incorporation of Au and Co(OH)&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Cooperative Modification for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416091</link>
      <description>Xinchao Chen, Xiang Li, Youming Peng, Hao Yang, Yexiang Tong, Muhammad&#8208;Sadeeq Balogun, Yongchao Huang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403886209

                Abstract Photoelectrochemical solar to hydrogen production is a promising way to achieve carbon neutrality, but severe charge recombination in photoanodes limits the conversion efficiency. Herein, Au nanoparticles and Co(OH) x co&#8208;sensitized bismuth vanadate (BiVO 4 ) to construct AuCo(OH) x /BiVO 4 photoanode for significantly enhancing the performance of photoelectrochemical water splitting. This process significantly improves the bulk charge carrier separation efficiency, the surface kinetics of water oxidation, and the electron density of BiVO 4 photoanode through Au surface plasmon resonance (SPR) and Co(OH) x oxygen evolution catalysts effect. Additionally, the enhancement of the *O and the *OOH generation accelerate the oxygen evolution reaction kinetics. Consequently, the constructed AuCo(OH) x /BiVO 4 photoanode demonstrates an excellent photocurrent of 6.2 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode and a stable continuous output within 42 h. This work contributes to developing high&#8208;efficiency and high&#8208;stability photoanodes for solar H 2 production through SPR effect and oxygen evolution catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xinchao Chen, Xiang Li, Youming Peng, Hao Yang, Yexiang Tong, Muhammad&#8208;Sadeeq Balogun, Yongchao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Electrochemical Catalytic Mechanism of Atomically Dispersed Metal on h-BCN Monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02845g</link>
      <description>Na Zhou, Yan&#8208;Ning Wang, Jiao Wang, Panchao Zhao, Hang Zhang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403808314

                Exploiting efficient and inexpensive electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is of great significance for the rapid development of renewable energy technologies. The embedding of...</description>
      <author>Na Zhou, Yan&#8208;Ning Wang, Jiao Wang, Panchao Zhao, Hang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02845g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Electrode Catalysis in N-Doped Graphene: Role of Nitrogen Coordination and Solvation Effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03645j</link>
      <description>Jun-Xian Liu, Yun Wang, Yuantong Gu, Liangzhi Kou, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403808317

                The efficiency of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in energy conversion devices is often hindered by sluggish kinetics and high overpotential. The role of different nitrogen...</description>
      <author>Jun-Xian Liu, Yun Wang, Yuantong Gu, Liangzhi Kou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03645j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superior electrocatalytic performance of nitrogen-doped carbon-embeded Ni/NiO/NiB nanocrystals for urea oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03424d</link>
      <description>Xiaofei Zhao, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403764167

                Electrocatalytic urea oxidation reaction (UOR) can serve as an alternative to the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water splitting. Therefore, to improve the kinetics of UOR, it is of...</description>
      <author>Xiaofei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03424d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Synthesis of Al and V Co-doped TiO2 NTAs Interlayer Enhanced PbO2 Composite for Efficient Zinc Electrowinning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03085k</link>
      <description>Shengyou Su, Junli Wang, Ruidong Xu, Xuanbing Wang, Linjing Yang, Tianyang Liu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403854544

                The high overpotential of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the strong corrosion of the anode are the main problems currently facing the zinc hydrometallurgical process. This study achieved the...</description>
      <author>Shengyou Su, Junli Wang, Ruidong Xu, Xuanbing Wang, Linjing Yang, Tianyang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03085k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical investigation on the OER and ORR activity of graphene-based TM-N3 and TM-N2X (X=B, C, O, P) single atom catalysts by density functional theory calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03779k</link>
      <description>Jiaxiang Wu, Erjun Kan, Cheng Zhan, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403772462

                Single-atom catalysts (SAC) have shown promising activity in electrocatalysis, such as CO2 reduction (CO2RR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Transition metal-embedded N-doped graphene (M-N-C) with TM-N4...</description>
      <author>Jiaxiang Wu, Erjun Kan, Cheng Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03779k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering high-valence nickel sites in Ni3S2/Ni3Se2 architectures enabling urea-assisted hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc04318a</link>
      <description>AI Tao-tao, Miaomiao Bai, Weiwei Bao, Jie Han, Xue-Ling Wei, Xiangyu Zou, Jungang Hou, Lizhai Zhang, Zhifeng Deng, Yuxin Zhang, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403753780

                A more thermodynamically favorable organic oxidation reaction should be used instead of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to avoid high power consumption. Implementing this technology requires the development of stable, highly...</description>
      <author>AI Tao-tao, Miaomiao Bai, Weiwei Bao, Jie Han, Xue-Ling Wei, Xiangyu Zou, Jungang Hou, Lizhai Zhang, Zhifeng Deng, Yuxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc04318a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 min synthesis of phase-pure nanocrystalline high-entropy sulphides for efficient water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-n5r4n</link>
      <description>Judith Zander, Roland Marschall, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403774326

                The development of noble-metal free electrocatalysts with low production cost is of utmost importance for sustainable water electrolysis. Herein, we present a fast, flexible synthesis pathway for the preparation of a variety of different medium- and high-entropy spinel sulphides of various compositions, using a non-aqueous microwave-assisted synthesis without any H2S. Nanoparticulate high-entropy sulphides containing up to 8 different metal cations can be obtained after an extremely short synthesis time of only 1 min and comparatively low temperatures of 200-230 &#176;C. We further demonstrate the high activity of the obtained sulphides for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Judith Zander, Roland Marschall</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-n5r4n</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assigning surface hole polaron configurations of titanium oxide materials to excited state optical absorptions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-66jf9</link>
      <description>Christopher Boyd, Shay McBride, Michael Paolino, Moritz Lang, Geoffroy Hautier, Tanja Cuk, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403871936

                For water splitting, a comprehensive understanding of the underlying reaction intermediates and pathways is crucial for optimizing existing materials or discovering novel ones. Among the most well-known active photoanodes for the oxygen evolution half-reaction are various TiO2-based materials. A hole polaron, which consists of a metal-oxide distortion around trapped holes, has been suggested as a local reactive oxygen configuration for the oxidative reaction. While first principal calculations identify new electronic states in the middle of the band gap due to hole-polarons and the influence of hole-polaron dynamics on transport, an assignment of hole-polaron configurations to a measured spectrum has been challenging due to broad optical transitions in the visible regime. Here, we compare the excited state absorption (ESA) for two titanium oxide materials with a similar electronic structure, but different titanium-oxide crystal structure and find that the maximum in the broad spec-trum shifts from 3.1 eV in rutile TiO2 (100) to 2.2 eV in perovskite SrTiO3. A principal component analysis isolates the ESA generated at ultra-fast timescales (&lt; 1 ps) in the pump-probe spectroscopy. Density functional theory (DFT) and time-dependent DFT (TD-DFT) calculations predict the energies of the mid-gap states for stable hole-polarons and the corresponding spectra from the valence band, respectively. When compared to the experimental spectra, we can rationalize the shift in the ESA by the transition optical dipole, considering both the edge and deeper states in the valence band, being bright for certain configurations of hole polarons in rutile TiO2 (100) (terminal O&#8226;-) and STO (lateral Ti2O&#8226;-). The spectral assignment of the ESA in two transition metal oxides materials via their distinctive crystal structures paves the way for the assignment of hole-polaron configurations and their dynamics in other transition metal oxides for oxygen evolution catalysis and more-generally, photo-driven processes.</description>
      <author>Christopher Boyd, Shay McBride, Michael Paolino, Moritz Lang, Geoffroy Hautier, Tanja Cuk</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-66jf9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air-condition process for Constructing MeAl-LDHs/rGO (Me = Co, Ni, Fe) hybrids toward efficient oxygene evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.146</link>
      <description>Dongdong Zhang, Binyuan Tang, Kai Wang, Lin Wang, Kai Tang, Shanliang Chen, Xiaoqiang Zhan, Hongli Yang, Weiyou Yang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403918636

                Transition-metal-based layered double hydroxides (LDHs) are emerging as one of the most promising candidates with superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. However, their fabrication under mild conditions remains a significant challenge. Here, we propose a low-cost, high-production-rate strategy for controlled preparation of AlOOH/reduced graphene oxide (rGO) with strong adsorption capacity for transition metal cations, and then in-situ conversion to CoAl-LDH/rGO, NiAl-LDH/rGO and FeAl-LDH/rGO under ambient conditions. Based on Density Functional Theory calculations, it is witnessed that the rational electronic coordination between Co and Al enables the charge absorption by surrounding oxygen atoms, thereby playing a critical role in reducing the adsorption free energy and overpotential of OER intermediates toward efficient OER. Consequently, the resultant CoAl-LDH/rGO hybrids exhibit an overpotential of just 368 mV at the current density of 100 mA/cm</description>
      <author>Dongdong Zhang, Binyuan Tang, Kai Wang, Lin Wang, Kai Tang, Shanliang Chen, Xiaoqiang Zhan, Hongli Yang, Weiyou Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Phosphide Nanobundles for Efficient Electrochemical Hydrogen Evolution Reaction in Acidic and Basic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09660</link>
      <description>Shubham Sharma, Nishan Khatri, Sharad Puri, Menuka Adhikari, Phadindra Wagle, David N. McIlroy, A. Kaan Kalkan, Yolanda Vasquez, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403861450

                Earth-abundant transition metal phosphide (TMP) nanomaterials have gained significant attention as potential replacements for Pt-based electrocatalysts in green energy applications, such as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and overall water splitting. In particular, FeP nanostructures exhibit superior electrical conductivity and high stability. Moreover, their diverse composition and unique crystal structures position FeP nanomaterials as emerging candidates for HER electrocatalysts. However, the synthesis or fabrication method employed for FeP nanostructures can significantly affect their overall electrocatalytic properties. For example, the solution synthesis of pure-phase FeP nanostructures remains challenging due to the formation of multiple binary phases and undesirable agglomeration. In this work, we use a simple approach to synthesizing FeP nanobundles by reacting &#946;-FeOOH (iron oxyhydroxide) with trioctylphosphine (TOP). FeP nanobundles were evaluated as HER electrocatalysts in both acidic and basic conditions, demonstrating good HER activity with overpotential values of 170 and 338 mV at a current density of -10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Shubham Sharma, Nishan Khatri, Sharad Puri, Menuka Adhikari, Phadindra Wagle, David N. McIlroy, A. Kaan Kalkan, Yolanda Vasquez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threefold Impact on Reaction Coordinate Mapping of Zirconium Based Tri&#8208;Chalcogenide Pseudo&#8208;Monolayers as Emerging Ultrathin Catalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400816</link>
      <description>Ponnappa Kechanda Prasanna, Sudip Chakraborty, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403782112

                Abstract The continuous quest of finding optimum catalysts for photo&#8208;electrocatalytic (PEC) water splitting has been revolving around 2D ultrathin materials because of the fact of exploiting both the surface area. In this work, a threefold impact is envisaged route to enhance the activity both in terms of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in the emerging Zirconium Tri&#8208;sulfides (ZrS 3 ) based pseudo&#8208;monolayers. Due to the unique and distinct electronic properties of the tri&#8208;chalcogenide systems as compared to the di&#8208;chalcogenide counterpart of Zirconium, one could afford to explore the implications of not only single&#8208;atom functionalization and vacancy defect, but also the external strain to expedite the bifunctional catalytic activity in this promising material. Rigorous electronic structure calculations have been performed for the mentioned threefold effect on not only the band&#8208;edge alignment, but going beyond to it by further constructing the reaction coordinate mapping corresponding to HER and OER mechanism. The repercussion of external strain in addition to the single atom functionalization and vacancy defect on the adsorption free energies of the prime intermediates of HER and OER reaction has been further correlated with the work function variation in this pseudo&#8208;monolayer system.</description>
      <author>Ponnappa Kechanda Prasanna, Sudip Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Electrolyte Solvation Structure for High&#8208;Voltage and Low&#8208;Temperature Magnesium&#8208;ion Supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/batt.202400620</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Tan, Chi Fang, Zhongqi Liang, Zhengjie Xu, Jiaxin Zheng, Xianqi Xu, Yufeng Jin, Guoshen Yang, Hang Zhou, Batteries &amp; Supercaps. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403921239

                Aqueous electrolytes supercapacitors have great potential in energy storage devices due to their high&#8208;power density and safety. However, due to the water hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the electrochemical stabilization window of aqueous electrolytes needs to be widened. Moreover, the application of aqueous electrolyte at low temperature is often limited by the freezing point of water. In this paper, we modulate the solvation structure of aqueous magnesium&#8208;ion supercapacitors by using sulfolane as a co&#8208;solvent. The modulated low salt concentration hybrid electrolyte extends the electrochemical stability window of the electrolyte to 2.9V and enhances the stability of the electrolyte at extreme temperatures, as well as provides safe and non&#8208;flammable properties. Based on the hybrid electrolyte, the water&#8208;organic hybrid magnesium&#8208;ion supercapacitors (HMSCs) are able to operate within an enlarged voltage range of 0 &#8211; 2.2 V at a low temperature of &#8208;30&#176;C. The HMSC shows a specific capacitance of up to 58 F/g at room temperature and retains a specific capacitance of 39 F/g at a current density of 15 A/g. Furthermore, it has an outstanding cycling performance at &#8208;30 &#176;C, maintaining a specific capacitance of more than 92% after 20,000 cycles.</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Tan, Chi Fang, Zhongqi Liang, Zhengjie Xu, Jiaxin Zheng, Xianqi Xu, Yufeng Jin, Guoshen Yang, Hang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/batt.202400620</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited NiB Films as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts in Alkaline Water Electrolizer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad8bf6</link>
      <description>Josue R. Lopez-Montelongo, Victor M. Becerril, Jorge V&#225;zquez-Arenas, Ren&#233; H. Lara, No&#233; Arjona, Jos&#233; de Jes&#250;s P&#233;rez Bueno, Jes&#250;s Adri&#225;n D&#237;az&#8208;Real, Ra&#250;l Ortega, Alia M&#233;ndez&#8211;Albores, G. Trejo, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403822442

                Abstract Sustainable electrochemical energy generation requires cost-effective, noble-metal-free electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen production in electrolyzers. This study used electrodeposition to create crystalline NiB films with different boron (B) contents&#8212;Ni-B(1.17 wt.%), Ni-B(1.06 wt.%), Ni-B(0.94 wt.%), and Ni-B(0.89 wt.%)&#8212;on FTO substrates. These films were tested as bifunctional electrocatalyst electrodes for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. The NiB films' composition and morphology were analyzed using SEM, AFM, XRD, GD-OES, and XPS. Linear sweep voltammetry assessed their electrocatalytic performance. Higher B content in the films promoted the formation of electroactive NiOOH, enhancing the OER. The Ni-B(1.17 wt.%) electrode required an overpotential of 380 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; for OER, while the Ni-B(1.06 wt.%) electrode required 146 mV for the same current density for HER. An alkaline water electrolyzer using Ni-B(1.17 wt.%) as the anode and Ni-B(1.06 wt.%) as the cathode achieved a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; at 1.71 V for overall water splitting. The system showed stability over 12 hours of testing. The results indicate that NiB films on FTO substrates are promising, low-cost bifunctional electrocatalysts for alkaline water electrolysis, offering an alternative to noble-metal-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Josue R. Lopez-Montelongo, Victor M. Becerril, Jorge V&#225;zquez-Arenas, Ren&#233; H. Lara, No&#233; Arjona, Jos&#233; de Jes&#250;s P&#233;rez Bueno, Jes&#250;s Adri&#225;n D&#237;az&#8208;Real, Ra&#250;l Ortega, Alia M&#233;ndez&#8211;Albores, G. Trejo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad8bf6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three rate-determining protein roles in photosynthetic O2-evolution addressed by time-resolved experiments on genetically modified photosystems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5291688/v1</link>
      <description>Holger Dau, Sarah M. M&#228;usle, Ricardo Assun&#231;&#227;o, Gianluca Parisse, Cristina De Santis, Leonardo Guidoni, Daniele Narzi, Philipp S. Simon, Richard J. Debus, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403900396

                Abstract Light-driven water splitting by plants, algae and cyanobacteria is pivotal for global bioenergetics and biomass formation. A manganese cluster bound to the photosystem-II proteins catalyzes the complex reaction at high rate, but the rate-determining factors are insufficiently understood. Here we traced the oxygen-evolution transition by time-resolved polarography and infrared spectroscopy for cyanobacterial photosystems genetically modified at two strategic sites, complemented by computational chemistry. We conclude three rate-determining functions of the protein environment of the metal cluster: acceleration of proton-coupled electron transfer, acceleration of substrate-water insertion after O2-formation, and balancing of rate-determining enthalpic and entropic contributions. Whereas in general the substrate-water insertion step may be unresolvable in time-resolved experiments, here it likely became traceable because of deceleration by genetic modification. Our results may stimulate new time-resolved experiments on substrate-water insertion in photosynthesis, clarification of enthalpy-entropy compensation in enzyme catalysis, and knowledge-guided development of inorganic catalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Holger Dau, Sarah M. M&#228;usle, Ricardo Assun&#231;&#227;o, Gianluca Parisse, Cristina De Santis, Leonardo Guidoni, Daniele Narzi, Philipp S. Simon, Richard J. Debus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5291688/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Transformed CoOOH@Co3S4 Heterostructured Catalyst for Highly Efficient Catalytic OER Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14211732</link>
      <description>Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Vijaya Gopalan Sree, Abhishek Meena, Akbar I. Inamdar, Hyunsik Im, Sangeun Cho, Nanomaterials. 14(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403865812

                The deprived electrochemical kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst is the prime bottleneck and remains the major obstacle in the water electrolysis processes. Herein, a facile hydrothermal technique was implemented to form a freestanding polyhedron-like Co3O4 on the microporous architecture of Ni foam, its reaction kinetics enhanced through sulfide counterpart transformation in the presence of Na2S, and their catalytic OER performances comparatively investigated in 1 M KOH medium. The formed Co3S4 catalyst shows outstanding catalytic OER activity at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 by achieving a relatively low overpotential of 292 mV compared to the pure Co3O4 catalyst and the commercial IrO2 catalyst. This enhancement results from the improved active centers and conductivity, which boost the intrinsic reaction kinetics. Further, the optimized Co3S4 catalyst exhibits admirable prolonged durability up to 72 h at varied current rates with insignificant selectivity decay. The energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX) and Raman spectra measured after the prolonged OER stability test reveal a partial transformation of the active catalyst into an oxyhydroxide phase (i.e., CoOOH@Co3S4), which acts as an active catalyst phase during the electrolysis process.</description>
      <author>Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Vijaya Gopalan Sree, Abhishek Meena, Akbar I. Inamdar, Hyunsik Im, Sangeun Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14211732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Corrosion&#8208;Resistant and Multi&#8208;Scenario MoNiP Electrode for Efficient Industrial&#8208;Scale Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403009</link>
      <description>Weiju Hao, Xunwei Ma, Lincai Wang, Y. P. Guo, Qingyuan Bi, Jinchen Fan, Hexing Li, Guisheng Li, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885883

                Abstract The construction of efficient and durable multifunctional electrodes for industrial&#8208;scale hydrogen production presents a main challenge. Herein, molybdenum&#8208;modulated phosphorus&#8208;based catalytic electrodes (Mo&#8208;NiP@NF) are prepared via mild electroless plating. Heteroatoms doping or heterostructures construction can reconfigure the intrinsic electronic structure of the pre&#8208;catalyst and optimizes the key intermediates adsorption. Moreover, the (hypo/meta&#8208;)phosphite anions (PO x &#948;&#8722; ) and molybdate ions (MoO x &#948;&#8722; ) on the electrode surface of Mo&#8208;NiP@NF afford resistance to chloride (Cl &#8722; ) corrosion. Mo&#8208;NiP@NF exhibits ultralow overpotentials of 278/550 and 282/590 mV at 1 A cm &#8722;2 during the hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction (HER/OER) in alkaline simulated and real seawater, respectively, whereas catalytic overall seawater splitting (OWS) reach 1 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.96 and 1.97 V cell . Remarkably, Mo&#8208;NiP@NF maintains stable operation for 1500 h in OWS. The scalability of Mo&#8208;NiP@NF allowing the assembly of proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer powered by photovoltaic energy, simulating a portable hydrogen&#8208;oxygen respirator provides an oxygen/hydrogen flows of 160/320 mL min &#8722;1 . Expanding further, the trace ruthenium&#8208;loaded Mo&#8208;NiP@NF catalyst sodium borohydride (NaBH 4 ) hydrolysis achieving a hydrogen generation rate (HGR) of 11049.2 mL min &#8722;1 g &#8722;1 . This work provides strategic innovations and optimization solutions for the economical and mild construction of multi&#8208;scenario durable green energy conversion materials at industrial&#8208;scale application.</description>
      <author>Weiju Hao, Xunwei Ma, Lincai Wang, Y. P. Guo, Qingyuan Bi, Jinchen Fan, Hexing Li, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Iron Oxide Electrocatalysis for Efficient Overall Water Splitting: A Study of Tailored Synthesis for Advanced Energy Generation and Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/est2.70062</link>
      <description>N. Maley, Pratik Patel, Felipe M. de Souza, Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta, Energy Storage. 6(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403755619

                ABSTRACT Water splitting, a critical milestone in the development of renewable energy, allows the production of pure hydrogen and oxygen. Iron oxide (Fe 2 O 3 ), a fundamental component in electrochemical water splitting for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), offers potential because of its accessibility, low cost, and environmental safety. Herein, to analyze the impact of the methodology on its properties, Fe 2 O 3 was produced in three different ways: freeze&#8208;drying (aerogel) (Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;AG), hydrothermal (Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;HT), and microwave (Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;MW). The Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;AG outperformed Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;HT and Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;MW in most properties which showed improved current and overall water&#8208;splitting efficiency. The resulting materials demonstrated good electrocatalytic performance for both HER and OER in alkaline media, with overpotentials for HER of 204, 235, and 255 mV and overpotentials for OER of 222, 288, and 292 mV for the Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;AG, Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;HT, and Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;MW samples, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA/cm 2 . The freeze&#8208;drying synthesis process has significant potential as a feasible method for the manufacture of Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;based electrocatalysts for water&#8208;splitting applications. This study provides important insights into the influence of electrocatalytic and energy storage properties of Fe 2 O 3 based on the use of different methodologies, that is, hydrothermal, microwave&#8208;assisted, and freeze&#8208;drying. Through that, a more assertive analysis can be made concerning changes in morphology, conductivity, exposure of active area, and electrochemical stability which are crucial for the overall performance, hence providing valuable information and considerations for possible large&#8208;scale applications for energy generation and energy storage.</description>
      <author>N. Maley, Pratik Patel, Felipe M. de Souza, Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/est2.70062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Water Confinement and Dual Electrolyte&#8211;Electrode Interfaces by Zwitterionic Oligomer for High&#8208;Voltage Aqueous Lithium&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416566</link>
      <description>Yinyan Deng, Chunxian Xing, Chuan Li, Yangbo Zhou, Zhiping Peng, Linfeng Fei, Chunyi Zhi, Tao Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403792624

                Abstract Aqueous lithium&#8208;ion batteries (ALIBs) have attracted significant interest due to their inherent advantage on safety. However, water itself has a narrow electrochemical stability window (ESW), limiting the energy density of ALIBs. Here, a low&#8208;molecular&#8208;weight zwitterionic oligomer, oligo(propylsulfonate dimethylammonium propylmethacrylamide) (OPDP), as an effective water binding agent for high&#8208;voltage ALIBs is demonstrated. The OPDP can effectively confine water molecules while reducing water activity. The OPDP&#8208;based electrolyte, with an ultra&#8208;high water weight percentage of 25.4%, possesses an outstanding ESW of up to 3.26 V and an ionic conductivity as high as 3.18 mS cm &#8722;1 . Furthermore, the aqueous Mo 6 S 8 //LiMn 2 O 4 full cell with OPDP&#8208;based electrolyte achieves a 99.7% capacity retention after 200 cycles at 0.5C with a high Coulombic efficiency (CE) of 98.7% and a specific energy of 88&#8211;101 Wh kg &#8722;1 . Also, it achieves an 89% capacity retention after 2000 cycles at 10C with a high CE of 99.9%. These postmortem characterizations suggest that robust organic&#8211;inorganic hybrid cathode/anode&#8208;electrolyte interfaces have been constructed during the cycling through the heteroatoms of N, S, and O in the zwitterionic oligomer, leading to the inhibited hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions and high performance of the full cell. This work provides a promising strategy for developing low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;voltage aqueous batteries.</description>
      <author>Yinyan Deng, Chunxian Xing, Chuan Li, Yangbo Zhou, Zhiping Peng, Linfeng Fei, Chunyi Zhi, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Metal&#8208;Support Interactions in Heterogeneous Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407167</link>
      <description>Zhiqian Hou, Chenghao Cui, Yanan Yang, Zhikun Huang, Yu Zhuang, Ye Zeng, Xi Gong, Tao Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403791868

                Molecular oxygen redox electrocatalysis involves oxygen reduction and evolution as core reactions in various energy conversion and environmental technology fields. Strong metal-support interactions (SMSIs) based nanomaterials are regarded as desirable and state-of-the-art heterogeneous electrocatalysts due to their exceptional physicochemical properties. Over the past decades, considerable advancements in theory and experiment have been achieved in related studies, especially in modulating the electronic structure and geometrical configuration of SMSIs to enable activity, selectivity, and stability. In this focuses on the concept of SMSI, explore their various manifestations and mechanisms of action, and summarizes recent advances in SMSIs for efficient energy conversion in oxygen redox electrocatalysis applications. Additionally, the correlation between the physicochemical properties of different metals and supports is systematically elucidated, and the potential mechanisms of the structure-activity relationships between SMSIs and catalytic performance are outlined through theoretical models. Finally, the obstacles confronting this burgeoning field are comprehensively concluded, targeted recommendations and coping strategies are proposed, and future research perspectives are outlined.</description>
      <author>Zhiqian Hou, Chenghao Cui, Yanan Yang, Zhikun Huang, Yu Zhuang, Ye Zeng, Xi Gong, Tao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-energy nuclear scattering of neutrinos</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.00673</link>
      <description>Anh Dung Le, Heikki M&#228;ntyssari, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403820746

                We study the energy dependence of the total and diffractive neutrino-nucleon and neutrino-nucleus cross sections at very high energies. The calculation employs the QCD dipole model and the small-$x$ nonlinear Balitsky-Kovchegov evolution. We show the sensitivity of the nuclear effect quantification on the nuclear setup, and predict up to $\sim 10\%$ nuclear suppression in the inclusive neutrino-oxygen scattering stemming from the nonlinear evolution. Diffractive contribution to the total scattering is small, which is only few percentage. The $\left|q\bar{q}g\right&gt;$ componnent of the $W^{\pm}$ boson is found to contribute significantly to the diffractive process, which reaches up to $\sim 40\%$ of the diffractive cross section.</description>
      <author>Anh Dung Le, Heikki M&#228;ntyssari</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.00673</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen&#8208;Bonded Amorphous Transition Metal Dichalcogenides with pH&#8208;Responsive Reactive Oxygen Biocatalysis for Combined Antibacterial and Anti&#8208;inflammatory Therapies in Diabetic Wound Healing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407046</link>
      <description>Lingyi Huang, Tiantian Li, Wei Geng, Xiaodong Xie, Peiqi Wang, Yuting Deng, Yang Gao, Ding Bai, Tian Tang, Chong Cheng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403878626

                Abstract Diabetic wound healing is a formidable challenge, often complicated by biofilms, immune dysregulation, and hindered vascularization within the wound environments. The intricate interplay of these microenvironmental factors has been a significant oversight in the evolution of therapeutic strategies. Herein, the design of an efficient and versatile oxygen&#8208;bonded amorphous transition metal dichalcogenide biocatalyst (aRuS&#8208;O r ) with pH&#8208;responsive reactive oxygen biocatalysis for combined antibacterial and anti&#8208;inflammatory therapies in promoting diabetic wound healing is reported. Leveraging the incorporation of Ru&#9472;O bonds, aRuS&#8208;O r exhibits optimized adsorption/desorption behavior of oxygen intermediates, thereby enhancing both the reactive oxygen species (ROS) generation activity in acidic conditions and ROS scavenging performance in neutral environments. Remarkably, aRuS&#8208;O r demonstrates exceptional bactericidal potency within infected milieus through biocatalytic ROS generation. Beyond its antimicrobial capability, post&#8208;eradication, aRuS&#8208;O r serves a dual role in mitigating oxidative stress in inflammatory wounds, providing robust cellular protection and fostering an M2&#8208;phenotype polarization of macrophages, which is pivotal for accelerating the wound repair process. The findings underscore the multifaceted efficacy of aRuS&#8208;O r , which harmoniously integrates high antibacterial action with anti&#8208;inflammatory and pro&#8208;angiogenic properties. This triad of functionalities positions aRuS&#8208;O r as a promising candidate for the comprehensive management of complex diabetic ulcers, addressing the unmet needs in the current therapeutics.</description>
      <author>Lingyi Huang, Tiantian Li, Wei Geng, Xiaodong Xie, Peiqi Wang, Yuting Deng, Yang Gao, Ding Bai, Tian Tang, Chong Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating The Efficiency Of Reused Powder For Sustainable Production Of Austenitic Stainless Steel 316L By LPBF Additive Manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59499/ep246281053</link>
      <description>Mohammadreza Jandaghi, Johan Moverare, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403840181

                The sustainability of Laser Powder Bed Fusion (L-PBF) in metallic component production hinges on effective powder reusing, given the significant unsolidified feedstock residue. This study evaluates the influence of powder reuse on phase evolutions using thermodynamic simulations via Thermo-Calc software. Both virgin and five-time reused powders of austenitic steel 316L (SS316L) were examined alongside printed parts. Results indicate unavoidable Rhodonite (MnSiO3) inclusions due to its high oxidation affinity. Rapid solidification produces ferritic single crystal particles from hot spatters. Sieving inefficiencies allow smaller oxide particles to persist, increasing oxide fractions in printed parts. Scheil diagrams show that while minor oxygen does not impact solidification, increased dissolved oxygen promotes Spinel (MnCr2O4) formation and inclusion clustering, serving as potential nucleation sites for ferrite. Tensile sample analysis reveals that, despite the pinning effect of fine oxide particles, increased inclusion size in reused samples compromises tensile strength.</description>
      <author>Mohammadreza Jandaghi, Johan Moverare</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59499/ep246281053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tectonic Evolution and Sedimentary Responses of Palaeocene&#8211;Eocene Tethys Himalayan Foreland Basin in Southern Tibet</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/gj.5082</link>
      <description>Songtao Yan, Ailing Ding, Lidong Zhu, Li Wang, Hu Li, Xuejian Dai, Yangchun Wei, Hao Huang, Qingsong Wu, Geological Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403808042

                ABSTRACT The tectonic evolution of the Palaeocene&#8211;Eocene Tethys Himalayan foreland basin plays a crucial role in reshaping the collisional orogenic process of the Yarlung&#8211;Tsangpo oceanic basin. However, studies examining the sedimentary response during the tectonic evolution of the foreland basin are lacking. In this study, through a detailed field investigation and analysis of Palaeocene&#8211;Eocene strata in the Tingri area, we clarified the evolution of the Tethys Himalayan tectonic regions and its sedimentary response. Carbon and oxygen isotopes, geochemistry and detrital zircon U&#8211;Pb dating demonstrated that the lower Palaeocene Jidula Formation and upper Palaeocene&#8211;lower Eocene Zongpu Formation were deposited in a coastal&#8211;shallow marine environment, with the detritus sourced from the northern Indian passive margin. The upper Eocene Pengqu Formation was deposited in a deltaic environment, with its detritus sourced from the Gangdese arc and the Yarlung&#8211;Tsangpo suture zone at the active continental margin. Combined with the nearshore subaqueous fan branch channel of the Jidula Formation and the slump deformation of the Zongpu Formation, the Palaeocene&#8211;Early Eocene southern Tethys Himalaya in the Tingri area was located in the forebulge of the peripheral foreland basin. The marine&#8211;continental interactive delta of the Pengqu Formation and its provenance from the Gangdese magmatic arc indicate that the Tingri area was situated in the foredeep of the peripheral foreland basin during the Late Eocene. The study provides valuable insights into the collisional orogenic processes between the Indian and Eurasian plates.</description>
      <author>Songtao Yan, Ailing Ding, Lidong Zhu, Li Wang, Hu Li, Xuejian Dai, Yangchun Wei, Hao Huang, Qingsong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/gj.5082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution During Bottle Ageing of Wines Macerated with Toasted Vine-Shoots and Micro-Oxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biom14111372</link>
      <description>Cristina Cebri&#225;n&#8208;Taranc&#243;n, Rosario S&#225;nchez&#8208;G&#243;mez, Ana M. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Gil, Mar&#237;a del &#193;lamo Sanza, Ignacio Nevares, M. Rosario Salinas, Biomolecules. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403875386

                The effects of SEGs (&#8220;Shoot from vines&#8212;Enological&#8212;Granule&#8221;) on winemaking within the same variety are well established. However, the interaction of different SEG varieties combined with micro-oxygenation (MOX) and its subsequent evolution in the bottle has not been investigated to date. In this work, Tempranillo wines were treated with two doses of SEGs from Tempranillo and Cabernet Sauvignon (12 and 24 g/L) and subjected to two fixed MOX doses (LOTR, 6.24 mg/L&#183;month, and HOTR, 11.91 mg/L&#183;month). After that, the wines were bottled, and their chemical composition and sensory profile were analysed after 3 and 6 months. Although no clear trend directly associated with the use of MOX was observed, in terms of chemical composition, wines showed an evolution in their chemical profile over time, with compounds such as vanillin increasing as more oxygen was added. Regarding their sensorial profile, the wines were more rounded after 6 months that in bottling, where SEGs or toasted descriptors, studied at the taste phase, were slightly more intense with the low SEG dose and HOTR combination.</description>
      <author>Cristina Cebri&#225;n&#8208;Taranc&#243;n, Rosario S&#225;nchez&#8208;G&#243;mez, Ana M. Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Gil, Mar&#237;a del &#193;lamo Sanza, Ignacio Nevares, M. Rosario Salinas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biom14111372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Imperfections of Perovskite Oxide Catalysts in the Aspect of Defect Equilibria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400386</link>
      <description>Maria Christy, Seunggun Choi, Jiseok Kwon, Jin-Woo Jeong, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song, Small Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403780594

                ABX 3 (X = O) perovskite oxides are an uprising class of alternative electrocatalysts in eminent technologies like electrocatalysis, photocatalysis, thermocatalysis, and energy storage. The perquisites of perovskite oxide catalysts encompass ordered atomic structure, structural/compositional extensibility, flexible electronic structure, lucrativeness, and so on. The ingenuity to precisely control and tune the inherent properties by reconstructing their crystal structure is particularly advantageous in electrocatalysis reactions like oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER). Incorporating multidimensional imperfections in the presumably perfect crystal structure of the perovskite catalysts is garnering booming attention among researchers. This concept can expertly influence the electronic structure and boost the reaction kinetics during electrocatalysis. Defects or imperfections are achieved by substituting A&#8208; and/or B&#8208;sites with heteroatoms or by oxygen vacancies. Defect engineering points to a promising new direction in the development of perovskite oxide catalysts. This work surveys the recent progress in defect engineering and how it plays a vital role in their design, and application in electrocatalysis, mainly ORR/OER. The architecture, dimensionality, and the types of perovskite oxides based on their cations, crystal structures, and stoichiometries are surveyed for a comprehensive understanding. This review aims to provide an extensive outlook on oxide perovskite catalysts concerning structural defects.</description>
      <author>Maria Christy, Seunggun Choi, Jiseok Kwon, Jin-Woo Jeong, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive theoretical study of the effects of facet, oxygen vacancies, and surface strain on iron and cobalt impurities in different surfaces of anatase TiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74423-3</link>
      <description>Danil W. Boukhvalov, V. Yu. Osipov, Anna Baldycheva, Benjamin T. Hogan, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403914609

                Abstract We report the results of systematic ab initio modelling of various configurations of iron and cobalt impurities embedded in the (110), (101), and (100) surfaces of anatase TiO 2 , with and without oxygen vacancies. The simulation results demonstrate that incorporation into interstitial voids at the surface level is significantly more favourable than other configurations for both iron and cobalt. The calculations also demonstrate the crucial effect of the facet as well as the lesser effects of other factors, such as vacancies and strain on the energetics of defect incorporation, magnetic moment, bandgap, and catalytic performance. It is further shown that there is no tendency towards the segregation or clustering of impurities on the surface. The calculated free energies of the hydrogen evolution reaction in acidic media predict that iron impurities embedded in the (101) surface of anatase TiO 2 can be a competitive catalyst for this reaction.</description>
      <author>Danil W. Boukhvalov, V. Yu. Osipov, Anna Baldycheva, Benjamin T. Hogan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74423-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field Evolution for Crystallization-driven Dynamos in C/O White Dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad7a6a</link>
      <description>Matias Castro-Tapia, Shuang&#8208;Nan Zhang, A. Cumming, The Astrophysical Journal. 975(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776482

                Abstract We investigate the evolution of magnetic fields generated by the crystallization-driven dynamo in carbon&#8211;oxygen white dwarfs (WDs) with masses &#8818;1.05 M &#8857; . We use scalings for the dynamo to demonstrate that the initial magnetic field strength ( B 0 ) has an upper limit that depends on the initial convection zone size ( R out,0 ) and the WD mass. We solve the induction equation to follow the magnetic field evolution after the dynamo phase ends. We show that the predicted surface magnetic field strength ( B surf ) differs from B 0 by at least a factor of &#8764;0.3. This reduction depends on R out,0 , where values smaller than half of the star radius give B surf &#8818; 0.01 B 0 . We implement electrical conductivities that account for the solid phase effect on the ohmic diffusion. We observe that the conductivity increases as the solid core grows, freezing in the magnetic field at a certain point of the evolution and slowing its outward transport. We study the effect of turbulent magnetic diffusivity induced by the convection and find that for a small R out,0 , B surf is stronger than the nonturbulent diffusion cases because of the more rapid transport, but still orders of magnitude smaller than B 0 . Given these limitations, the crystallization-driven dynamo theory could explain only magnetic C/O WDs with field strengths less than a few megagauss for the mass range 0.45&#8211;1.05 M &#8857; . Our results also suggest that a buried fossil field must be at least 100 times stronger than observed surface fields if crystallization-driven convection is responsible for its transport to the surface.</description>
      <author>Matias Castro-Tapia, Shuang&#8208;Nan Zhang, A. Cumming</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad7a6a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promiscuous and unbiased recombination underlies the sequence-discrete species of the SAR11 lineage in the deep ocean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.10.30.621061</link>
      <description>Jianshu Zhao, Maria Pachiadaki, Roth E. Conrad, Janet K. Hatt, Laura A. Bristow, Luis M. Rodr&#237;guez-R, Ramon Rossell&#243;&#8208;M&#243;ra, Frank J. Stewart, Konstantinos T. Konstantinidis, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885946

                Surveys of microbial communities (metagenomics) or isolate genomes have revealed sequence-discrete species. That is, members of the same species usually show &gt;95% Average Nucleotide Identity (ANI) of shared genes among themselves vs. &lt;83% ANI to members of other species while genome pairs showing between 83-95% ANI are comparatively rare. In these surveys, aquatic bacteria of the ubiquitous SAR11 clade (Class Alphaproteobacteria), which play a major role in carbon cycling, are an outlier and often do not exhibit discrete species boundaries, suggesting the potential for alternate modes of genetic differentiation. To explore evolution in SAR11, we analyzed high-quality, single-cell amplified genomes (SAGs) and companion metagenomes from an oxygen minimum zone (OMZ) in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Ocean, where the SAR11 make up ~20% of the total microbial community. Our results show that SAR11 do form several sequence-discrete species, but their ANI range of discreteness is shifted to lower identities between 86-91%, with intra-species ANI ranging between 91-100%. Measuring recent gene exchange among these genomes based on a newly developed methodology revealed higher frequency of homologous recombination within compared to between species that affects sequence evolution at least twice as much as diversifying point mutation across the genome. Recombination in SAR-11 appears to be more promiscuous compared to other prokaryotic species and has facilitated the spreading of adaptive mutations within the species, further promoting the high intra-species diversity observed. These results implicate rampant, genome-wide homologous recombination as the mechanism that underlies the evolution of SAR11 into discrete species.</description>
      <author>Jianshu Zhao, Maria Pachiadaki, Roth E. Conrad, Janet K. Hatt, Laura A. Bristow, Luis M. Rodr&#237;guez-R, Ramon Rossell&#243;&#8208;M&#243;ra, Frank J. Stewart, Konstantinos T. Konstantinidis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.10.30.621061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for Type Ib/c origin of the supernova remnant G292.0+1.8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.17542</link>
      <description>Takuto Narita, Hiroyuki Uchida, Jacco Vink, Satoru Katsuda, Hideyuki Umeda, Takashi Yoshida, Toshiki Sato, Kai Matsunaga, Takeshi Go Tsuru, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403795841

                Circumstellar material (CSM) produced by mass loss from massive stars ($\gtrsim10 M_{\odot}$) through strong stellar winds or binary stripping provides rich information for understanding progenitors of core-collapse supernova remnants. In this paper we present a grating spectroscopy of a Galactic SNR G292.0+1.8, which is claimed to be a Type Ib/c remnant in a binary system according to recent studies. If G292.0+1.8 was experienced a strong mass-loss via binary interactions before its explosion, an oxygen-rich material produced in the He-burning layer is expected to be observed in the central belt-like structure formed by shock-heated CSM. Using the Reflection Grating Spectrometer onboard XMM-Newton, we detect N VII Ly$\alpha$ line (0.50 keV) for the first time in G292.0+1.8 and find that the abundance ratio of nitrogen to oxygen is significantly lower (N/O$=0.5\pm0.1$) than the solar value. This low N/O suggests that the progenitor of experienced strong mass-loss and ended up to a Wolf-Rayet (WR) star exposing the He-burning layer at the pre-supernova. Comparing our result and the evolution models of single stars and binaries, we conclude that the progenitor of G292.0+1.8 experienced strong mass-loss enough to occur a Type Ib/c supernova. Our finding is another crucial piece of evidence for a stripped-envelope supernova such as Type Ib/c as the origin of G292.0+1.8.</description>
      <author>Takuto Narita, Hiroyuki Uchida, Jacco Vink, Satoru Katsuda, Hideyuki Umeda, Takashi Yoshida, Toshiki Sato, Kai Matsunaga, Takeshi Go Tsuru</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.17542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ FTIR spectroscopy of epoxy resin degradation: kinetics and mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1476965</link>
      <description>Marianna Pannico, Giuseppe Mensitieri, Pellegrino Musto, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403901304

                We report on an in situ FTIR study of the thermo-oxidative degradation of a flexible epoxy resin. Different and complementary approaches to the analysis of the spectral data were employed, providing a detailed description of the process in terms of kinetics and mechanisms. A preliminary normal coordinate analysis, based on the DFT method, allowed for a reliable interpretation of the observed spectrum, increasing the amount of available structural information. Two-dimensional correlation spectroscopy provided details on the evolution of the reacting network structure. The relative stability of the various functional groups was ranked, and the most likely sites of initiation were identified. Oxygen fixation on the network chains produced amide and ketone groups, with the latter developing at a higher rate. The kinetic profiles of various functional groups were accurately simulated by a first-order, biexponential model, which allowed a quantitative comparison among their relative stabilities. The spectroscopic analysis allowed us to propose likely mechanisms and to identify those that occur preferentially.</description>
      <author>Marianna Pannico, Giuseppe Mensitieri, Pellegrino Musto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1476965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inclusive and diffractive neutrino-nucleus scattering at high energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.16705</link>
      <description>Anh Dung Le, Heikki M&#228;ntysaari, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403784375

                We calculate the energy dependence of inclusive and diffractive neutrino-nucleus deep-inelastic scattering cross sections within the dipole picture, focusing on the ultra-high-energy regime. We predict an up to $\sim 10\%$ nuclear suppression in the inclusive neutrino-Oxygen scattering originating from the non-linear QCD dynamics in the small-$x$ Balitsky-Kovchegov evolution. Diffraction is found to be a small $1\dots 4\%$ contribution to the total cross section across a wide range of neutrino energies relevant for current and near-future experiments. The diffractive cross section is calculated separately for the coherent and incoherent channels that are found to be of equal importance. Additionally, we include the dominant contribution from the $|q\bar q g\rangle$ Fock state of the $W^\pm$ and $Z$ bosons in the high-$Q^2$ limit, along with the lowest-order $|q\bar q\rangle$ contribution. The $|q\bar{q}g\rangle$ contribution is found to be numerically significant, reaching up to 40\% of the diffractive cross section.</description>
      <author>Anh Dung Le, Heikki M&#228;ntysaari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.16705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulatory Mechanisms and Applications of Rare Earth Elements&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts&lt;sup&gt;&#8224;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400578</link>
      <description>Q. Gao, Sheng Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Laihao Luo, Xu Li, Qiu Jiang, Yuan Ji, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403770835

                Comprehensive Summary Amidst the pressing environmental challenges posed by the prevalent reliance on fossil fuels, it becomes imperative to seek sustainable alternatives and prioritize energy efficiency. Electrocatalysis, which is renowned for its high efficiency and environmental friendliness, has garnered significant attention. Rare earth elements (REEs), distinguished by their unique electronic and orbital structures, play a crucial role in electrocatalysis. The strategic integration of REEs into catalysts allows for the fine&#8208;tuning of atomic structures, which in turn, significantly boosts catalytic performance. Despite substantial advancements in rare earth&#8208;based materials for electrocatalysis, a comprehensive overview of the regulatory mechanisms involving REEs is lacking. In this mini&#8208;review, we systematically explore the regulatory mechanisms of REEs within electrocatalysts and their pivotal roles in essential electrocatalytic processes such as the CO 2 reduction reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, and hydrogen evolution reaction. We commence with an elucidation of REEs, proceed to delineate their regulatory impacts on electrocatalysts and delve into their applications in key electroreduction reactions. We conclude with discussions on current limitations and prospects for further advancements in this burgeoning field of research. Key Scientists</description>
      <author>Q. Gao, Sheng Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Laihao Luo, Xu Li, Qiu Jiang, Yuan Ji, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backtracking Metabolic Dynamics in Single Cells Predicts Bacterial Replication in Human Macrophages</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.10.28.620606</link>
      <description>Mariatou Dram&#233;, Dmitry Ershov, Jessica E. Martyn, Jean-Yves Tin&#233;vez, Carmen Buchrieser, Pedro Escoll, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403880705

                Accurately tracking dynamic state transitions is crucial for modeling and predicting biological outcomes, as it captures heterogeneity of cellular responses. To build a model to predict bacterial infection in single cells, we have monitored in parallel infection progression and metabolic parameters in thousands of human primary macrophages infected with the intracellular pathogen Legionella pneumophila. By combining live-cell imaging with a novel tool for classifying cells based on infection outcomes, we were able to trace the specific evolution of metabolic parameters linked to distinct outcomes, such as bacterial replication or cell death. Our findings revealed that early changes in mitochondrial membrane potential (&#916;&#968;m) and in the production of mitochondrial Reactive Oxygen Species (mROS) are associated with macrophages that will later support bacterial growth. We used these data to train an explainable machine-learning model and achieved 83% accuracy in predicting L. pneumophila replication in single, infected cells before bacterial replication starts. Our results highlight backtracking as a valuable tool to gain new insights in host-pathogen interactions and identify early mitochondrial alterations as key predictive markers of success of bacterial infection.</description>
      <author>Mariatou Dram&#233;, Dmitry Ershov, Jessica E. Martyn, Jean-Yves Tin&#233;vez, Carmen Buchrieser, Pedro Escoll</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.10.28.620606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifestations of sulfuric acid speleogenesis in the Mulapampa travertine, Central Andes of Peru: evidence from the Gruta con Lago</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5038/1827-806x.53.2.2503</link>
      <description>Andrzej Tyc, Krzysztof Gaidzik, Justyna Ciesielczuk, Katarzyna W&#261;tor, International Journal of Speleology. 53(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403866293

                Sulfuric acid speleogenesis (SAS) is a form of hypogene speleogenesis characterized by the formation of caves in carbonate rocks due to the presence of sulfuric acid. This study focuses on the Gruta con Lago, one of three caves identified in the Mulapampa travertine, located in the central Andes of Peru. These caves are accessed through collapse sinkholes, and much of their morphology results from roof breakdown. The bottom of the studied cave is situated at the current water table. Despite the absence of typical solutional features associated with SAS caves, mineralogical and geochemical evidence of speleogenesis involving H2SO4 has been found in Gruta con Lago. Significant accumulations of gypsum deposits on the cave floor and replacement gypsum crusts on walls &#8211; both considered by-products of SAS &#8211; are present. Cave gypsum samples exhibit negative sulfur isotopic composition (ranging from -19.4 to -8.2&#8240;) and oxygen (ranging from -9.0 to -1.3&#8240;), which are indicative of sulfide (H2S) oxidation. This article discusses potential scenarios of SAS events in the evolution of hypogene karst in the Mulapampa travertine. It also considers the significance of the proximity of the active volcanoes of the Ampato-Sabancaya Volcanic Complex (ASVC) and seismogenic crustal faults in the formation of a thick travertine cover and the potential for SAS processes.</description>
      <author>Andrzej Tyc, Krzysztof Gaidzik, Justyna Ciesielczuk, Katarzyna W&#261;tor</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5038/1827-806x.53.2.2503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Ir-Doped NiFe2O4/TiO2 Heterojunction Anode for Decentralized Saline Wastewater Treatment and H2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01542-x</link>
      <description>Sukhwa Hong, Jiseon Kim, Jaebeom Park, Sunmi Im, Michael R. Hoffmann, Kangwoo Cho, Nano-Micro Letters. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403843481

                Abstract Wastewater electrolysis cells (WECs) for decentralized wastewater treatment/reuse coupled with H 2 production can reduce the carbon footprint associated with transportation of water, waste, and energy carrier. This study reports Ir-doped NiFe 2 O 4 (NFI, ~ 5 at% Ir) spinel layer with TiO 2 overlayer (NFI/TiO 2 ), as a scalable heterojunction anode for direct electrolysis of wastewater with circumneutral pH in a single-compartment cell. In dilute (0.1 M) NaCl solutions, the NFI/TiO 2 marks superior activity and selectivity for chlorine evolution reaction, outperforming the benchmark IrO 2 . Robust operation in near-neutral pH was confirmed. Electroanalyses including operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy unveiled crucial roles of TiO 2 which serves both as the primary site for Cl &#8722; chemisorption and a protective layer for NFI as an ohmic contact. Galvanostatic electrolysis of NH 4 + -laden synthetic wastewater demonstrated that NFI/TiO 2 not only achieves quasi-stoichiometric NH 4 + -to-N 2 conversion, but also enhances H 2 generation efficiency with minimal competing reactions such as reduction of dissolved oxygen and reactive chlorine. The scaled-up WEC with NFI/TiO 2 was demonstrated for electrolysis of toilet wastewater.</description>
      <author>Sukhwa Hong, Jiseon Kim, Jaebeom Park, Sunmi Im, Michael R. Hoffmann, Kangwoo Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01542-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclic electron flow and Photosystem II-less photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1071/fp24185</link>
      <description>Maria Ermakova, Duncan Fitzpatrick, Anthony W. D. Larkum, Functional Plant Biology. 51(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403854203

                Oxygenic photosynthesis is characterised by the cooperation of two photo-driven complexes, Photosystem II (PSII) and Photosystem I (PSI), sequentially linked through a series of redox-coupled intermediates. Divergent evolution has resulted in photosystems exhibiting complementary redox potentials, spanning the range necessary to oxidise water and reduce CO2 within a single system. Catalysing nature&#8217;s most oxidising reaction to extract electrons from water is a highly specialised task that limits PSII&#8217;s metabolic function. In contrast, potential electron donors in PSI span a range of redox potentials, enabling it to accept electrons from various metabolic processes. This metabolic flexibility of PSI underpins the capacity of photosynthetic organisms to balance energy supply with metabolic demands, which is key for adaptation to environmental changes. Here, we review the phenomenon of &#8216;PSII-less photosynthesis&#8217; where PSI functions independently of PSII by operating cyclic electron flow using electrons derived from non-photochemical reactions. PSII-less photosynthesis enables supercharged ATP production and is employed, for example, by cyanobacteria&#8217;s heterocysts to host nitrogen fixation and by bundle sheath cells of C4 plants to boost CO2 assimilation. We discuss the energetic benefits of this arrangement and the prospects of utilising it to improve the productivity and stress resilience of photosynthetic organisms.</description>
      <author>Maria Ermakova, Duncan Fitzpatrick, Anthony W. D. Larkum</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1071/fp24185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endometriosis development in relation to hypoxia: a murine model study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-024-00973-x</link>
      <description>Marta Hoffmann, Rados&#322;aw Maksym, Katarzyna Pucia, Monika Kuciak, Andrzej Ma&#263;kiewicz, Claudine Kieda, Molecular Medicine. 30(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403891593

                Abstract Background Endometriosis, due to its ambiguous symptoms, still remains one of the most difficult female diseases to treat, with an average diagnosis time of 7&#8211;9 years. The changing level of hypoxia plays an important role in a healthy endometrium during menstruation and an elevated expression of the hypoxia-inducible factor 1-alpha (HIF-1&#945;) has been demonstrated in ectopic endometria. HIF-1&#945; mediates the induction of proangiogenic factors and the development of angiogenesis is a critical step in the establishment and pathogenesis of endometriosis. Although the inhibition of angiogenesis has been proposed as one of the actionable therapeutic modalities, vascular normalization and re-oxygenation may become a possible new approach for therapeutic intervention. Methods Our goal was to investigate whether a selected murine model of endometriosis would be suitable for future studies on new methods for treating endometriosis. Non-invasive, high-resolution ultrasound-monitored observation was selected as the preclinical approach to obtain imaging of the presence and volume of the endometriotic-like lesions. The EF5 (2-(2-Nitro-1H-imidazol-1-yl)-N-(2,2,3,3,3-pentafluoropropyl)acetamide) compound that selectively binds to reduced proteins in hypoxic cells was used for hypoxia detection. The expression of Pten and other crucial genes linking endometriosis and hypoxia were also assessed. Results Using EF5, a pentafluorinated derivative of the 2-nitroimidazole that is metabolically reduced by oxygen-inhibitable nitroreductase, we confirmed that hypoxia did develop in the selected model and was detected in uterine and ectopic endometriotic lesions. Moreover, the changes in oxygen tension also influenced the expression level of significant genes related to endometriosis, like Pten , Trp53 , Hif1a , Epas1 , and Vegfa . Their strong modulation evidenced here is indicative of model reliability. Using high-resolution ultrasound-based imaging, we present a non-invasive method of visualization that enables the detection and observation of lesion evolution throughout the duration of the experiment, which is fundamental for further preclinical studies and treatment evaluation. Conclusions The selected model and method of visualization appear to be suitable for the study of new treatment strategies based on hypoxia alleviation and blood flow restoration.</description>
      <author>Marta Hoffmann, Rados&#322;aw Maksym, Katarzyna Pucia, Monika Kuciak, Andrzej Ma&#263;kiewicz, Claudine Kieda</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-024-00973-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Oxygen Reconstruction Enables Dual&#8208;Ion Active Sites in Carbon Cathode for High Energy Density Sodium&#8208;Ion Capacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417059</link>
      <description>Jie Li, Chang Liu, Xinyu Hu, Jieming Cai, Huimin Lian, Dongxiao Li, Biao Zhong, Wentao Deng, Hongshuai Hou, Guoqiang Zou, Xiaobo Ji, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403896231

                Abstract Carbon materials are the promising cathode material for sodium&#8208;ion capacitors (SICs) with high energy/power density, however, clarifying the evolution processes of functional groups in carbon materials and revealing their energy storage mechanisms are full of challenges. Inspired by the ancient practice of alchemy, which sought to purify Dan medicine and remove impurities through precise control of the refining temperature, the local oxygen reconstruction strategy, to alter the functional groups species in SP 3 &#8208;C, is pioneeringly utilized, achieving targeted regulation of carbonyl groups with increase from 27.9 to 43.3 at%, which efficiently change the electronic structure of the carbon framework and realize the dual&#8208;ion adsorption of Na + and ClO 4 &#8722; , according well with the theoretical calculations. As expected, the obtained carbon cathode delivers a specific capacity of 145 mAh g &#8722;1 , higher than that of the parent carbon material (95 mAh g &#8722;1 ). Impressively, the ex situ X&#8208;ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy and in situ Raman reveals that carbonyl can act as dual&#8208;ion active sites for Na + and ClO 4 &#8722; through pseudocapacitive behavior under different voltage states. Notably, the assembled SIC using the carbonyl&#8208;rich carbon cathode exhibits an ultrahigh energy density of 162 Wh kg &#8722;1 . This work opens a novel avenue for regulating the carbonyl content of carbon materials.</description>
      <author>Jie Li, Chang Liu, Xinyu Hu, Jieming Cai, Huimin Lian, Dongxiao Li, Biao Zhong, Wentao Deng, Hongshuai Hou, Guoqiang Zou, Xiaobo Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detection of [OIII]88$\mu$m in JADES-GS-z14-0 at z=14.1793</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.20549</link>
      <description>Sander Schouws, R. J. Bouwens, Katherine Ormerod, Renske Smit, H. S. B. Algera, Laura Sommovigo, J. A. Hodge, A. Ferrara, Pascal Oesch, Lucie E. Rowland, Ivana van Leeuwen, Mauro Stefanon, Thomas Herard-Demanche, Yoshinobu Fudamoto, H. J. A. R&#246;ttgering, P. van der Werf, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403816306

                We report the first successful ALMA follow-up observations of a secure $z &gt; 10$ JWST-selected galaxy, by robustly detecting ($6.6\sigma$) the [OIII]$_{88\mu m}\,$ line in JADES-GS-z14-0 (hereafter GS-z14). The ALMA detection yields a spectroscopic redshift of $z=14.1793\pm0.0007$, and increases the precision on the prior redshift measurement of $z=14.32_{-0.20}^{+0.08}$ from NIRSpec by $\gtrsim$180$\times$. Moreover, the redshift is consistent with that previously determined from a tentative detection ($3.6\sigma$) of CIII]$_{1907,1909}$ ($z=14.178\pm0.013$), solidifying the redshift determination via multiple line detections. We measure a line luminosity of $L_\mathrm{[OIII]88} = (2.1 \pm 0.5)\times10^8\,L_\odot$, placing GS-z14 at the lower end, but within the scatter of, the local $L_\mathrm{[OIII]88}$-star formation rate relation. No dust continuum from GS-z14 is detected, suggesting an upper limit on the dust-to-stellar mass ratio of $&lt; 2 \times 10^{-3}$, consistent with dust production from supernovae with a yield $y_d &lt; 0.3\,M_\odot$. Combining a previous JWST/MIRI photometric measurement of the [OIII]$\lambda\lambda$4959,5007$\mathrm{\mathring{A}}$ and H$\beta$ lines with Cloudy models, we find GS-z14 to be surprisingly metal-enriched ($Z\sim0.05 - 0.2\,Z_\odot$) a mere $300\,\mathrm{Myr}$ after the Big Bang. The detection of a bright oxygen line in GS-z14 thus reinforces the notion that galaxies in the early Universe undergo rapid evolution.</description>
      <author>Sander Schouws, R. J. Bouwens, Katherine Ormerod, Renske Smit, H. S. B. Algera, Laura Sommovigo, J. A. Hodge, A. Ferrara, Pascal Oesch, Lucie E. Rowland, Ivana van Leeuwen, Mauro Stefanon, Thomas Herard-Demanche, Yoshinobu Fudamoto, H. J. A. R&#246;ttgering, P. van der Werf</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.20549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of gas film formation and evolution on anode in microbubbles flow electrolytic plasma polishing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5303937/v1</link>
      <description>Juan Wang, Huanwu Sun, Rongzheng Fan, Dongliang Yang, Yuxia Xiang, Haidong Duan, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779450

                Abstract Microbubbles flow electrolytic plasma polishing (MF-EPP) facilitates controllable electrolytic plasma polishing (EPP) using a low-power supply. It is well established that a vapor gaseous envelope (VGE) around a workpiece is essential for EPP polishing. Nonetheless, the generation condition and its control parameter of a local gas film on the workpiece surface in MF-EPP is not fully understood. In this study, an analysis by the electrochemical and hydrothermal reactions revealed that the gas composition on the anode surface is mainly composed of water vapor, which is heated by Joule heat, and electrolysis gases such as oxygen, fluorine, hydrogen, and nitrogen. By analyzing formation conditions and calculating the volume flux of each gas, it was found that vapor is the main component of the gas film. For the vapor characteristics, the bubble nucleation and growth model has been established. On this basis, the main factors affecting the nucleation, growth, and coalescence of bubbles were then analyzed, indicating that superheating and heat flow density are the principal factors affecting the aggregation of bubbles and thus the formation of a gas film. It was determined that the presence of electrolytic gases exerts a beneficial influence on the nucleation of vapor bubbles. Additionally, a bubble dynamics model was constructed based on the conservation of energy, and the impact of processing parameters on the evolution of bubbles was analyzed. The threshold for the formation of a stable gas film under the conditions of this experiment was determined to be a voltage of 350 V and an initial electrolyte temperature of 80&#176;C. The applicability of the model was validated through experimentation, and the establishment of the model provides theoretical and experimental references for the formulation and optimization of MF-EPP machining process parameters.</description>
      <author>Juan Wang, Huanwu Sun, Rongzheng Fan, Dongliang Yang, Yuxia Xiang, Haidong Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5303937/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vapor&#8211;Solid Interface Synthesis of Highly Crystalline Covalent Triazine Frameworks for Use as Efficient Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407782</link>
      <description>Minghui Chen, Ji Xiong, Quan Shi, Weiwei Zhang, Zhuoran Chen, Li Wang, Xinyue Zhu, Kai Guo, Feng Ya-qing, Bao Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403778312

                Abstract Harsh synthetic conditions for crystalline covalent triazine frameworks (CTFs) and associated limitations on structural diversities impede not only further development of functional CTFs, but also practical large&#8208;scale synthesis. Herein, a mild and universal vapor&#8211;solid interface synthesis strategy is developed for highly crystalline CTFs employing trifluoromethanesulfonic acid vapor as catalysts. A series of highly ordered simple and functional CTFs (CTF&#8208;TJUs) can be facilely produced. In particular, the porphyrin&#8208;involved functional CTF (CTF&#8208;TJU&#8208;Por1) with high crystallinity is synthesized for the first time via this universal approach. The mechanism of vapor&#8208;catalyzed trimerization of nitrile monomers is thoroughly investigated through semi in situ characterizations. As a proof of concept, the photocatalytic performance of synthesized CTFs for water splitting is evaluated. CTF&#8208;TJU&#8208;133 exhibits significantly greater photocatalytic rates for hydrogen (4.35 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 ) and oxygen (2.18 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 ) evolutions during overall water splitting under visible light irradiations compared to other CTF&#8208;TJUs, representing one of the highest values among reported CTF photocatalysts. Further studies reveal that enhanced photocatalytic performance of CTF&#8208;TJU&#8208;133 results from optimized band structure, extended visible&#8208;light absorption, and high carrier separation efficiency. This study provides a promising strategy to synthesize various simple and functional CTFs, which significantly enriched diversities of CTF family for different application purposes.</description>
      <author>Minghui Chen, Ji Xiong, Quan Shi, Weiwei Zhang, Zhuoran Chen, Li Wang, Xinyue Zhu, Kai Guo, Feng Ya-qing, Bao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling CoIr Nanoalloys with MXene by Lewis Acidic Molten Salt Etching for Wide&#8208;pH&#8208;Environment Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401449</link>
      <description>Qingqu Zhou, Hongyu Zhao, Sheng Wang, Zilan Li, Ruidong Li, Linbo Jiang, Lintao Jiang, Jixiang Jiao, Shichun Mu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403846575

                Abstract Metal/MXene&#8208;based materials show broad prospects in energy conversation through the strong metal&#8208;support interaction (SMSI). However, the difficulty and harshness of synthesis heavily limit their further application. Herein, using Lewis acidic molten salt to etch MAX as a precursor of MXene, a more convenient and safer strategy is designed to in situ construct the MXene&#8208;supported CoIr nanoalloy (CoIr/MXene) catalyst through Ti&#9472;O&#9472;M bond. The special layered structure and oxygen&#8208;containing functional group of MXene regulate the SMSI upon CoIr nanoalloys. Moreover, the contact angle and in situ Raman test results exhibit good interface hydrophilicity of MXene, enhancing the water adsorption on interfaces, and accelerating the mass transfer process. As a result, CoIr/MXene shows high hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance, which only needs overpotentials of 34 and 50 mV to drive a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline and acidic media, respectively, with excellent stability. Especially, in alkaline media, CoIr/MXene possesses 6 times higher HER mass activity (4.297 A mg Ir &#8722;1 ) than commercial Pt/C catalysts (0.686 A mg Pt &#8722;1 ) at the potential of 50 mV, indicating larger active site density and intrinsic activity for CoIr/MXene. This work expands the application of the molten salt assist etching strategy and provides new insight for the development of metal/MXene&#8208;based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qingqu Zhou, Hongyu Zhao, Sheng Wang, Zilan Li, Ruidong Li, Linbo Jiang, Lintao Jiang, Jixiang Jiao, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;PfGSTF2&lt;/scp&gt; endows resistance to quizalofop&#8208;p&#8208;ethyl in &lt;i&gt;Polypogon fugax&lt;/i&gt; by &lt;scp&gt;GSH&lt;/scp&gt; conjugation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/pbi.14491</link>
      <description>Wen Chen, Dingyi Bai, Yuxi Liao, Qin Yu, Lianyang Bai, Lang Pan, Plant Biotechnology Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403828063

                Summary Populations of Polypogon fugax have developed resistance to many acetyl&#8208;CoA carboxylase (ACCase)&#8208;inhibiting herbicides. This resistance threats the effectiveness and sustainability of herbicide use. In our previous research, a field P. fugax population exhibited GST&#8208;based metabolic resistance to the widely used ACCase&#8208;inhibiting herbicide quizalofop&#8208;p&#8208;ethyl. Here, in this current study, we identified and characterized two GST genes (named as PfGSTF2 and PfGSTF58 ) that showed higher expression levels in the resistant than the susceptible population. Transgenic rice calli overexpressing PfGSTF2 , but not PfGSTF58 , became resistant to quizalofop&#8208;p&#8208;ethyl and haloxyfop&#8208;R&#8208;methyl. This reflects similar cross&#8208;resistance pattern to what was observed in the resistant P. fugax population. Transgenic rice seedlings overexpressing PfGSTF2 also exhibited resistance to quizalofop&#8208;p&#8208;ethyl. In contrast, CRISPR/Cas9 knockout of the orthologue gene in rice seedlings increased their sensitivity to quizalofop&#8208;p&#8208;ethyl. LC&#8211;MS analysis of in vitro herbicide metabolism by Escherichia coli &#8208;expressed recombinant PfGSTF2 revealed that quizalofop (but not haloxyfop) was detoxified at the ether bond, generating the GSH&#8208;quizalofop conjugate and a propanoic acid derivative with greatly reduced herbicidal activity. Equally, these two metabolites accumulated at higher levels in the resistant population than the susceptible population. In addition, both recombinant PfGSTF2 and PfGSTF58 can attenuate cytotoxicity by reactive oxygen species (ROS), suggesting a role in plant defence against ROS generated by herbicides. Furthermore, the GST inhibitor (NBD&#8208;Cl) reversed resistance in the resistant population, and PfGSTF2 (but not PfGSTF58) responded to NBD&#8208;Cl inhibition. All these suggest that PfGSTF2 plays a significant role in the evolution of quizalofop resistance through enhanced herbicide metabolism in P. fugax .</description>
      <author>Wen Chen, Dingyi Bai, Yuxi Liao, Qin Yu, Lianyang Bai, Lang Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/pbi.14491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The GALAH Survey: Data Release 4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.19858</link>
      <description>Sven Buder, J. Kos, Ella Xi Wang, Madeleine McKenzie, Michael D. Howell, S. L. Martell, Michael R. Hayden, D. B. Zucker, Thomas Nordlander, B. T. Montet, G. Traven, Joss Bland&#8208;Hawthorn, G. M. De Silva, K. C. Freeman, Graceanna Lewis, K. Lind, S. Sharma, Jeffrey D. Simpson, Dennis Stello, T. Zwitter, A. M. Amarsi, J. Armstrong, Kirsten Banks, M. A. Beavis, K. L. Beeson, Bin Chen, Ioana Ciuc&#259;, G. S. Da Costa, Richard de Grijs, Barbara B. Martin, David M. Nataf, Melissa Ness, Adam D. Rains, T. Scarr, R. Vogrin&#269;i&#269;, Zhujun Wang, Robert A. Wittenmyer, Yang Xie, the GALAH collaboration, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403814631

                The stars of the Milky Way carry the chemical history of our Galaxy in their atmospheres as they journey through its vast expanse. Like barcodes, we can extract the chemical fingerprints of stars from high-resolution spectroscopy. The fourth data release (DR4) of the Galactic Archaeology with HERMES (GALAH) Survey, based on a decade of observations, provides the chemical abundances of up to 32 elements for 917 588 stars that also have exquisite astrometric data from the $Gaia$ satellite. For the first time, these elements include life-essential nitrogen to complement carbon, and oxygen as well as more measurements of rare-earth elements critical to modern-life electronics, offering unparalleled insights into the chemical composition of the Milky Way. For this release, we use neural networks to simultaneously fit stellar parameters and abundances across the full spectrum, leveraging synthetic grids computed with Spectroscopy Made Easy. These grids account for atomic line formation in non-local thermodynamic equilibrium for 14 elements. In a two-iteration process, we first fit stellar labels for all 1 085 520 spectra, then co-add repeated observations and refine these labels using astrometric data from $Gaia$ and 2MASS photometry, improving the accuracy and precision of stellar parameters and abundances. Our validation thoroughly assesses the reliability of spectroscopic measurements and highlights key caveats for catalogue users. GALAH DR4 represents yet another milestone in Galactic archaeology, combining detailed chemical compositions from multiple nucleosynthetic channels with kinematic information and age estimates. The resulting dataset, covering nearly a million stars, opens new avenues for understanding not only the chemical and dynamical history of the Milky Way, but also the broader questions of the origin of elements and the evolution of planets, stars, and galaxies.</description>
      <author>Sven Buder, J. Kos, Ella Xi Wang, Madeleine McKenzie, Michael D. Howell, S. L. Martell, Michael R. Hayden, D. B. Zucker, Thomas Nordlander, B. T. Montet, G. Traven, Joss Bland&#8208;Hawthorn, G. M. De Silva, K. C. Freeman, Graceanna Lewis, K. Lind, S. Sharma, Jeffrey D. Simpson, Dennis Stello, T. Zwitter, A. M. Amarsi, J. Armstrong, Kirsten Banks, M. A. Beavis, K. L. Beeson, Bin Chen, Ioana Ciuc&#259;, G. S. Da Costa, Richard de Grijs, Barbara B. Martin, David M. Nataf, Melissa Ness, Adam D. Rains, T. Scarr, R. Vogrin&#269;i&#269;, Zhujun Wang, Robert A. Wittenmyer, Yang Xie, the GALAH collaboration</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.19858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Occurrence of gravitational collapse in the accreting neutron stars of
  binary-driven hypernovae</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.05767</link>
      <description>L. M. Becerra, Federico Cipolletta, C. L. Fryer, D&#233;bora P. Menezes, Constan&#231;a Provid&#234;ncia, J. A. Rueda, R. Ruffini, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403882973

                The binary-driven hypernova (BdHN) model proposes long gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) originate in binaries composed of a carbon-oxygen (CO) star and a neutron star (NS) companion. The CO core collapse generates a newborn NS and a supernova that triggers the GRB by accreting onto the NSs, rapidly transferring mass and angular momentum to them. This article aims to determine the conditions under which a black hole (BH) forms from NS collapse induced by the accretion and the impact on the GRB observational properties and taxonomy. We perform three-dimensional, smoothed-particle-hydrodynamics simulations of BdHNe using up-to-date NS nuclear equations of state (EOS), with and without hyperons, and calculate the structure evolution in full general relativity. We assess the binary parameters leading either NS in the binary to the critical mass for gravitational collapse into a BH and its occurrence time, $t_{\rm col}$. We include a non-zero angular momentum of the NSs and find that $t_{\rm col}$ ranges from a few tens of seconds to hours for decreasing NS initial angular momentum values. BdHNe I are the most compact (about five minutes orbital period), promptly form a BH and release $\gtrsim 10^{52}$ erg. They form NS-BH binaries with tens of kyr merger timescale by gravitational-wave emission. BdHNe II and III do not form BHs, release $\sim 10^{50}$-$10^{52}$ erg and $\lesssim 10^{50}$ erg. They form NS-NS binaries with a range of merger timescales larger than for NS-BH binaries. In some compact BdHNe II, either NS can become supramassive, i.e., above the critical mass of a non-rotating NS. Magnetic braking by a $10^{13}$ G field can delay BH formation, leading to BH-BH or NS-BH of tens of kyr merger timescale.</description>
      <author>L. M. Becerra, Federico Cipolletta, C. L. Fryer, D&#233;bora P. Menezes, Constan&#231;a Provid&#234;ncia, J. A. Rueda, R. Ruffini</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.05767</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially-resolved gas-phase metallicity in Seyfert galaxies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.20465</link>
      <description>Mark Armah, Rog&#233;rio Riffel, L G Dahmer-Hahn, R. Davies, O. L. Dors, Darshan Kakkad, Rogemar A. Riffel, A. Rodr&#237;guez-Ardila, D. Ruschel-Dutra, Thaisa Storchi&#8208;Bergmann, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403815847

                We explore the relations between the gas-phase metallicity radial profiles (few hundred inner parsec) and multiple galaxy properties for 15 Seyfert galaxies from the AGNIFS (Active Galactic Nuclei Integral Field Spectroscopy) sample using optical Integral Field Unit (IFU) observations from Gemini Multi-Object Spectrographs (GMOS) and Multi Unit Spectroscopic Explorer (MUSE) processed archival data. The data were selected at $z \lesssim 0.013$ within black hole mass range $\left[6&lt;\log \left(M_{\rm BH}/{\rm M_\odot} \right)&lt;9\right]$ with moderate 14--150\,keV X-ray luminosities $\left[42\,\lesssim\,\log L_X (\rm erg\,s^{-1})\,\lesssim\,44\right]$. We estimated the gas-phase metallicity using the strong-line methods and found mean values for the oxygen dependent ($Z \sim 0.75Z_\odot$) and nitrogen dependent ($Z \sim 1.14Z_\odot$) calibrations. These estimates show excellent agreement with $\Delta Z \approx 0.19$ dex and $\Delta Z \approx 0.18$ dex between the mean values from the two strong-line calibrations for GMOS and MUSE respectively, consistent with the order of metallicity uncertainty via the strong-line methods. We contend that our findings align with a scenario wherein local Seyferts have undergone seamless gas accretion histories, resulting in positive metallicity profile over an extended period of time, thereby providing insights into galaxy evolution and the chemical enrichment or depletion of the universe. Additionally, we argue that metal-poor gas inflow from the local interstellar medium (ISM) and accreted through the circumgalactic medium (CGM) onto the galaxy systems regulates the star formation processes by diluting their central metallicity and inverting their metallicity gradients, producing a more prominent anti-correlation between gas-phase metallicity and Eddington ratio.</description>
      <author>Mark Armah, Rog&#233;rio Riffel, L G Dahmer-Hahn, R. Davies, O. L. Dors, Darshan Kakkad, Rogemar A. Riffel, A. Rodr&#237;guez-Ardila, D. Ruschel-Dutra, Thaisa Storchi&#8208;Bergmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.20465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of third dredge-up on the mass loss of Mira variables</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.19604</link>
      <description>S. Uttenthaler, S. Shetye, A. Nanni, B. Aringer, K. G&#246;sta Eriksson, Iain McDonald, D. Gobrecht, S. H&#246;fner, U. Wolter, S. Cristallo, Klaus Bernhard, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403813224

                Context: The details of the mass-loss process in the late stages of low- and intermediate-mass stellar evolution are not well understood, in particular its dependence on stellar parameters. Mira variables are highly suitable targets for studying this mass-loss process. Aims: We follow up on our earlier finding that a near-to-mid-infrared colour vs. pulsation period diagram shows two sequences of Miras that can be distinguished by the third dredge-up (3DUP) indicator technetium in those stars. While IR colours are good indicators of the dust mass-loss rate (MLR) from Miras, no corresponding sequences have been found using the gas MLR. However, investigations of the gas MLR have been hampered by data limitations. We aim to alleviate these limitations with new observational data. Methods: We present new optical spectra of a well-selected sample of Miras. We searched these spectra for absorption lines of Tc and other 3DUP indicators and combined our findings with gas MLRs and expansion velocities from the literature. Furthermore, we analyse WISE MIR data and compare the broadband SEDs of Miras with and without Tc. Results: We find no systematic difference in gas MLRs between Miras with and without Tc. However, the gas envelopes of Tc-poor Miras appear to have a higher expansion velocity than those of Miras with Tc. Furthermore, our analysis of the IR photometry strongly corroborates the earlier finding that Tc-poor Miras have a higher MIR emission than Tc-rich ones, by as much as a factor of two. We model the IR colours with DARWIN and stationary wind models and conclude that Miras with and without Tc have different dust content or properties. Conclusions: We discuss several hypotheses of the observations and conclude that the reduction of free oxygen by 3DUP of carbon and iron-depleted dust grains in Tc-rich stars are the most convincing explanations for our observations.</description>
      <author>S. Uttenthaler, S. Shetye, A. Nanni, B. Aringer, K. G&#246;sta Eriksson, Iain McDonald, D. Gobrecht, S. H&#246;fner, U. Wolter, S. Cristallo, Klaus Bernhard</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.19604</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sedimentary Expressions of the Early Jurassic Jenkyns Event in an Inland Lacustrine System in the Yin'gen&#8211;Ejinaqi Basin, North China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1755-6724.15186</link>
      <description>Bing Yang, Guozhen Xu, Gangying Hui, Yi Wei, Xinzhi ZHANG, Jinjun Yi, Siyuan Sun, S. Zhang, Acta Geologica Sinica - English Edition. 98(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403881655

                Abstract The Jenkyns Event, more widely known as the Toarcian Oceanic Anoxic Event (T&#8208;OAE), is marked by globally distributed negative carbon&#8208;isotope excursions, widespread oxygen depletion, and large&#8208;scale organic carbon burial, which indicate major climate/environmental perturbations in Earth's surface systems during the Early Jurassic. Although extensive research has been conducted in European continental settings, particularly in the western peri&#8208;Tethys regions, the impacts of this event beyond Europe remains largely unexplored. Here, a multiapproach study including investigations into the spore&#8208;pollen assemblages, pyrite framboids, clay minerals, total organic carbon (TOC) levels, and organic carbon isotope ( &#948; 13 C org ) levels in a lacustrine borehole section (MED1) from the Yin'gen&#8211;Ejinaqi Basin, North China, provides evidence of the occurrence of the Jenkyns Event and its extensive sedimentary responses in the eastern Tethys terrestrial systems. Two distinct spore&#8208;pollen assemblages have been identified in MED1 (drilling depth: 982.4 m to 1267.5 m), with the Cycadopites &#8211; Protopinu s&#8211; Osmundacidites assemblage in the lower part (1267.5 m to 1132.9 m) indicating a middle Early Jurassic age and the Classopollis assemblage in the upper part (1132.9 m to 985.7 m) suggesting a Toarcian age. Framboidal pyrite data suggest more anoxic conditions during the deposition of black mudstone and shale intercalations in the lower part of the Classopollis assemblage (1132.9 m to 1066.9 m), which combined with organic carbon enrichment and negative &#948; 13 C org excursions, are considered the paleoenvironmental response to the Jenkyns Event in the study area. Furthermore, the evolution of vegetation groups changed from plant groups characterized by bisaccate and cycad pollen, as well as fern spores, to vegetation groups represented by Cheirolepidiaceae pollen across the Jenkyns Event, as evidenced by spore&#8208;pollen data, together with the clay mineral assemblage change characterized by a notable increase in illite at the expense of kaolinite, suggests that while a subtropical&#8208;temperate climate persisted, a change toward warmer and drier conditions most likely occurred in the early Toarcian in the study area. In contrast to the humidification evidenced in many coastal settings, this aridification trend in the Yin'gen&#8211;Ejinaqi Basin aligns with the conditions in many inland areas. It is hypothesized that the underlying cause of these divergent changes may be linked to certain patterns of spatially variable water availability on land, potentially driven by extremified hydrological conditions.</description>
      <author>Bing Yang, Guozhen Xu, Gangying Hui, Yi Wei, Xinzhi ZHANG, Jinjun Yi, Siyuan Sun, S. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1755-6724.15186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isotopic composition of natural waters of Kuzbass in coalbed methane production areas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18799/24131830/2024/10/4775</link>
      <description>&#1054;. &#1045;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1091;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Evgeniia V. Domrocheva, Bulletin of the Tomsk Polytechnic University Geo Assets Engineering. 335(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403903281

                Relevance. In Kuzbass, a coalbed methane production project is being implemented for the first time in Russia. Formation water extracted together with coalbed methane plays an important role, since it has been in contact with the coal-bearing rocks for a long time, therefore it contains rich geochemical information. Over the period 2002&#8211;2022, new isotopic data were accumulated both on the waters of the region coal deposits and on overlying waters, including surface waters. Aim. Based on the material accumulated on the isotopic composition (&#948;D, &#948;18O, &#948;13C, 34S, 3H, 14C) of natural waters in coal-bearing areas, create an evolutionary scheme for the formation of waters within the framework of the developed hypothesis on the interaction of water-rock-coal-methane. Objects. River, underground waters of the zone of active water exchange, upper and lower parts of the zone of slow water exchange (extracted together with coalbed methane). Methods. Studies of the isotopic composition of waters were carried out in several laboratories: in the Multielement and Isotope Research Center of the SB RAS, the Technical Branch of the Federal State Unitary Enterprise &#8220;SNIIGGIMS&#8221;, in the radiocarbon AMS laboratory based on the Center for Collective Use &#8220;Cenozoic Geochronology&#8221; and in the Pacific Oceanological Institute Far Eastern Branch Russian Academy of Sciences (POI) FEB RAS. Results and conclusions. The paper introduces the data on &#948;D, &#948;18&#1054;, &#948;13&#1057; &#1080; &#948;34S for surface and groundwater in Kuzbass in coalbed methane production areas. It is shown that all the waters under consideration are infiltration based on their isotopic composition (&#948;D and &#948;18&#1054;). The waters of the lower part of the slow water exchange, produced together with coalbed methane, are characterized by a positive oxygen shift and very light hydrogen. A diagram of the evolution of the isotopic composition of water-dissolved carbon in the region has been compiled according to the data obtained. It is noted that the atmospheric source of CO2 is characteristic only of river waters, and only biogenic carbon dioxide is present in groundwater. The wide range of &#948;13&#1057;DIC values of the latter is explained by the varying degrees of participation of light soil carbon dioxide and heavy biochemical carbon dioxide formed during methane formation in the coal seam. The heaviest values are typical for waters produced together with coalbed methane, which is associated with long-term interaction with coal and methane. The time of such interaction was determined using the radiocarbon method: 17&#8211;30 thousand years. In areas where coalbed methane is produced, an increase in &#948;13&#1057;DIC values for all natural waters is observed, which requires further study.</description>
      <author>&#1054;. &#1045;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1091;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Evgeniia V. Domrocheva</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18799/24131830/2024/10/4775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Intensity interval training improves global longitudinal strain in patients with metabolic syndrome and high risk of heart failure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae666.2660</link>
      <description>Elvis Camacho, M Gallango-Brejano, A Gadella-Fernandez, Lu&#237;s Jim&#233;nez-Alvarez, Alfonso Moreno&#8208;Caba&#241;as, Felix Morales&#8208;Palomo, RICARDO MORA-RODRIGUEZ, Juan F. Ortega, European Heart Journal. 45(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403832128

                Abstract Background Metabolic syndrome (MS) has been associated with the development of myocardial dysfunction which can lead to heart failure (HF). It is possible to detect early signs of myocardial dysfunction by assessing the global longitudinal strain (GLS) in a transthoracic echocardiography. A reduced GLS is considered as a predictor of HF development. Preventive strategies are recommended in patients with MS to avoid the progression to HF. Although exercise improves cardiovascular and metabolic health in MS patients, it is unknown whether exercise can affect the evolution of GLS in a group of patients with MS who are under medical treatment. Purpose To assess the prevalence of myocardial dysfunction (i.e., reduced GLS) in a heterogeneous group of patients with MS who are under medical treatment, and to test in these patients if 16 weeks of high-intensity interval training (HIIT) can improve the GLS. Methods Seventy-seven volunteers with MS and without signs or symptoms of HF were randomized in one of two 16-week intervention: i). HIIT in stationary bikes 3 sessions/week, 50 minutes/session + medical treatment (HIIT group), or ii). medical treatment (CONTROL). Maximal oxygen consumption (VO2max), and GLS together with rutinary echocardiographic parameters were assessed before and after intervention. The effect of HIIT compared to CONTROL was analyzed by a split-plot ANOVA to compare the effects of time (pre vs. post) and group (HIIT vs. CONTROL), and the interaction between the two factors. Results Before intervention 48.9% of participants from the HIIT group, and 46.7% from the CON group had a reduced GLS (i.e., &amp;gt;17% for men and &amp;gt;18% for women). However, none of them had a reduced left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF), signs of diastolic dysfunction or an abnormal VO2max (less than 80% of predicted VO2max). After the 16-week intervention, only individuals from the HIIT group improved their VO2max (time*group P&amp;lt;0.001). LVEF did not improve in any of the experimental groups (time P=0.278) HIIT group improved their GLS by 0.51%, whereas CONTROL group improved it by 0.05% without reaching statistical significance (time*group P=0.186). However, a subgroup analysis of GLS conducted among the participants from the HIIT group discriminated by their pre-intervention values (GLS normal or reduced), showed that individuals with reduced GLS improved significantly by 1,41% (P=0.001) whereas those with a normal GLS improved by 0.14% without reaching statistical significance (P=0.736, time*group P=0.009). Conclusions Myocardial dysfunction assessed by GLS is present in MS even in the absence of symptoms, diastolic dysfunction, or reductions in the LVEF. HIIT can reduce the risk of HF development by improving GLS in patients with MS and early signs of myocardial dysfunction.A. Overall changes in GLSB. Subgroup analysis of GLS pre vs. post</description>
      <author>Elvis Camacho, M Gallango-Brejano, A Gadella-Fernandez, Lu&#237;s Jim&#233;nez-Alvarez, Alfonso Moreno&#8208;Caba&#241;as, Felix Morales&#8208;Palomo, RICARDO MORA-RODRIGUEZ, Juan F. Ortega</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae666.2660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smooth muscle cell-specific deletion of S100A4 modifies smooth muscle cell fate and inflammation in murine atherosclerotic lesions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae666.3867</link>
      <description>P Azar, L M Cardoso Dos Santos, Marta Correia de Sousa, Michelangelo Foti, Marie&#8208;Luce Bochaton&#8208;Piallat, European Heart Journal. 45(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403818079

                Abstract Background S100A4, a calcium-binding protein, is crucial in smooth muscle cell (SMC) phenotypic switch, yet its role in atherosclerotic plaque development and SMC plasticity remains unclear. Our previous experiments using an S100A4 neutralizing antibody approach in ApoE-/- atherosclerotic-prone mice showed reduced atherosclerotic burden but did not establish a direct link between the various S100A4-expressing cells and atherosclerosis. Methods/Results Herein, we show that aortic Oil RedO staining in ApoE-/-; S100A4-/- mice subjected to a 12-week high-cholesterol-diet (HCD) revealed reduced lesion areas compared to ApoE-/- mice (Figure 1, from 21.29% of the total aorta in ApoE-/-; S100A4+/+ mice to 13.27% in ApoE-/-; S100A4-/- mice), highlighting a pivotal role for S100A4 in atherosclerotic plaque development. We then used a lineage tracing ApoE-/- mouse model, in which we induced an SMC-specific deletion of S100A4 (SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916;). After 12 weeks of HCD, SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; and control mice (SMC-S100A4wt/wt) were sacrificed, and aortas were processed for en face Oil Red O staining, immunohistochemistry, and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq). SMC-specific deletion of S100A4 reduced the necrotic core area (from 29.75% of total plaque area in SMC-S100A4wt/wt to 18.23% in SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; mice) without affecting total atherosclerotic plaque size suggesting a more potent impact on plaque composition. ScRNA-seq analysis from SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; and SMC-S100A4wt/wt mice showed that the inflammatory macrophage-like SMC phenotype was highly suppressed in the plaque and associated with increased SMC repair phenotypes as well as a global reduction of myeloid inflammatory cells. SMCs also retained specific contractile SMC markers, namely Acta2 and Myh11 (fold change of 2.285 and 2.492, respectively) hinting towards a more stable fibrous cap. Immunofluorescence staining on aortic roots plaque (Figure 2) confirmed those results with an increase of SMCs (from 11.02% to 16.18%) as well as a-smooth muscle actin (a-SMA, Acta2)-positive SMCs (from 3.25% to 5.1%) in SMC-S100A4 &#916;/&#916; mice. Furthermore, the Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) of scRNAseq data revealed that, in SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; mice, genes related to mitochondrial metabolism and oxidative respiration were highly downregulated in all SMC clusters. We investigated SMC mitochondrial fitness in vitro and showed that S100A4-/- SMCs have an increased basal oxygen consumption rate and an increased proton leak (fold change of 1.37 and 1.96 respectively) suggestive of differences in cellular metabolic adaptability. Conclusion Our research emphasizes the significant role of S100A4 in plaque development, demonstrating how SMC-derived S100A4 knockdown affects plaque evolution, reducing inflammation, and promoting stability likely through influencing SMC phenotypic switch through metabolic pathways.</description>
      <author>P Azar, L M Cardoso Dos Santos, Marta Correia de Sousa, Michelangelo Foti, Marie&#8208;Luce Bochaton&#8208;Piallat</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae666.3867</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variability of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; in a coastal peatland rewetted with brackish water from the Baltic Sea derived from autonomous high-resolution measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3246</link>
      <description>Daniel Lars P&#246;nisch, Henry C. Bittig, Martin Kolbe, Ingo Schuffenhauer, Stefan Otto, Peter Holtermann, K. Premaratne, Gregor Rehder, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403901945

                Abstract. Rewetting peatlands is an important measure to reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from land use change. After rewetting, the areas can be highly heterogeneous in terms of GHG exchange and depend on water level, vegetation, previous use, and duration of rewetting. Here, we present a study of a coastal peatland that was rewetted by brackish water from the Baltic Sea and thus became part of the coastal shallow Baltic Sea water system through a permanent hydrological connection. Rewetting suppresses carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions by preventing aerobic decomposition of organic matter. Conversely, the anoxic conditions in the soil lead to an increase in methane (CH4) emissions, which counteracts CO2 mitigation effects. Unlike to rewetting with freshwater, the effects of rewetting with brackish, sulfate-containing water are less studied, although positive effects are expected as sulfate-reducing bacteria may become established and might out-compete methane-producing archaea (methanogens) for substrates, resulting in lower CH4 emissions. Both aspects, environmental heterogeneity and the brackish water column formation, require improved quantification techniques to assess local sinks and sources of atmospheric GHGs. We conducted nine weeks of autonomous and high-resolution, sensor-based bottom water measurements of marine physical and chemical variables at two locations in a permanently flooded peatland in summer 2021, and derived GHG fluxes. Results show considerable temporal fluctuations of CO2 and CH4, expressed as multi-day, diurnal and event-based variability and spatial differences for variables dominantly influenced by biological processes. The multi-day variability resulted in a pronounced magnitude of measured GHG partial pressures during the deployment ranging between 295.0&#8211;8937.8 &#181;atm (CO2) and 22.8&#8211;2681.3 &#181;atm (correspond to 42.7&#8211;3568.6 nmol L&#8722;1; CH4), respectively. In addition, the variability of the GHGs, temperature, and oxygen was characterized by pronounced diurnal cycles, resulting e.g., in a mean daily variability of 4066.9 &#181;atm for CO2 and 1769.6 &#181;atm for CH4. The diurnal variability led to a pronounced discrepancy between the measurements during the day and at night as well as depending on the location, resulting in CO2 and CH4 fluxes that varied by a factor of 2.1&#8211;2.3 and 2.3&#8211;3.0, respectively. The rewetted peatland was further impacted by fast system changes (events) such as storm, precipitation and major water level changes, which impacted biogeochemical cycling and GHG partial pressures. The derived average GHG exchange amounted to 0.12 &#177; 0.16 g m&#8722;2 h&#8722;1 (CO2) and 0.51 &#177; 0.56 mg m&#8722;2 h&#8722;1 (CH4), respectively. These fluxes are high (CO2) to low (CH4) compared to studies from temperate peatlands rewetted with freshwater. Comparing these fluxes with the previous year (i.e., results from a reference study), the fluxes decreased by a factor of 1.9 and 2.6, respectively. This was potentially due to a progressive consumption of organic material, a suppression of CH4 production, and aerobic and anaerobic oxidation of CH4, indicating a positive evolution of the rewetted peatland into a site with moderate GHG emissions within the next years.</description>
      <author>Daniel Lars P&#246;nisch, Henry C. Bittig, Martin Kolbe, Ingo Schuffenhauer, Stefan Otto, Peter Holtermann, K. Premaratne, Gregor Rehder</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen uptake slow component: Enigma of the &#8216;excess&#8217; oxygen used during heavy and severe exercise</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1113/ep092326</link>
      <description>David C. Poole, Glenn A. Gaesser, Experimental Physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403826044

                In the 1980s, foundational physiology and exercise physiology texts considered that oxygen uptake ( V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ ) increased as a linear function of work rate (WR) on the cycle ergometer. Whereas this was true up to the maximum V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ ( V &#775; O 2 max ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{max}}}}$ ) for incremental exercise where WR was increased by 25 W or so per minute, for constant WR heavy- (i.e., &gt;lactate threshold, LT) or severe- (&gt;critical power, CP) intensity exercise there was an 'excess' V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ that manifested after the fast kinetics associated with the WR transition (Gaesser &amp; Poole, 1996). This excess V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ became evident only after 2&#8211;3 min and for heavy exercise stabilized within 10 or so minutes or, for severe exercise, projected V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ to V &#775; O 2 max ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{max}}}}$ auguring exhaustion shortly thereafter. In the extreme, this V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ slow component ( V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ ) can amount to 1&#8211;1.5 L O2/min, eroding muscle efficiency. For physiologists seeking to better understand muscle energetics and exercise limitations, non-linear behaviour often provides powerful insights into systems control. However, at the time, explanations for the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_{\mathrm{2}}}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ were less than satisfying. Typically, researchers in the field had extrapolated the estimated O2 cost of an array of physiological processes to calculate their putative role in the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ during heavy/severe intensity exercise (Gaesser &amp; Poole, 1996). Alternatively, the temporal correlation of these processes with the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ was assessed to try and establish cause and effect. Principal processes considered included increasing ventilation, body temperature, blood lactate and catecholamines. Neither approach was especially satisfying; the former could explain far more than 100% of the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ (!), and the latter could not discriminate causal from casual. What was needed was a technique that had the power to parse among candidate variables. The initial strategy was to independently measure leg muscle(s) V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ simultaneously with pulmonary V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ during heavy/severe intensity exercise. This procedure unequivocally identified the exercising muscles as the source of the majority (&gt;80%) of the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ , thereby discounting a major role for ventilation, body temperature, auxiliary muscles and circulating factors such as lactate and catecholamines that might raise the metabolic rate outside the exercising muscles (Poole, 1994). Based upon subsequent a priori investigations, lactate and catecholamines as well as temperature increases acting within the exercising muscles were also discounted in this regard (Gaesser &amp; Poole, 1996). Viable remaining candidates relating to the altered physicochemical milieu associated with heavy/severe intensity exercise included fatiguing muscle fibres, recruitment of additional, more fast-twitch, and less efficient muscle fibres, decreased mitochondrial P:O (i.e., ATP:O2) ratio and less efficient chemical&#8211;mechanical coupling. To date, most of these remain possibilities, though decreased P:O ratio &#8211; high O2 cost of phosphate production &#8211; seems unlikely (Rossiter et al., 2002) and, in dog and human muscles, the recruitment of additional muscle fibres is not requisite for a V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ effect (e.g., Zoladz et al., 2008). However, a tacit presumption of many previous investigators pursuing the mechanistic bases for the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ was that the external power produced reflected unchanged muscular input. One commendable novelty, among several, of a study by Macdougall and colleagues (2024), in this issue of Experimental Physiology, is that they considered and measured the biomechanics of cycling and determined how it changed relative to the generation of the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ in concert with (almost) real-time determination of quadriceps muscle fatigue. Their data reveal that, although power remained constant over 20 min or so whilst the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ was developing, biomechanical indices of peak total downstroke force, minimum upstroke force and the upstroke index of effectiveness were not constant and showed a weak correlation with the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ . Importantly, the observed association between muscle fatigue and the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ was highly significant, underlining the relevance of these findings despite considerable interindividual variability in the primary measurements. Indeed, even though all subjects exercised at a well-defined power output of 10% above their individually estimated second lactate threshold, time to task failure ranged from &#8764;10 to 55 min. This is not trivial as factors affecting muscle fatigue as well as the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ undoubtedly differ when comparing fatiguing exercise among subjects with a &gt;5-fold range in time to task failure. The relatively high pedalling cadence of 80 rpm may have contributed to the large response heterogeneity as cadence has varying impacts on CP (i.e., relative to preferred cadence) (Carnevale &amp; Gaesser, 1991). The metabolic stress of exercise may have differed across subjects as a result, making it more challenging to identify a specific cause for the associated V &#775; O 2 ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$ response across this substantial range in exercise duration. The road from scientific discovery to general acceptance can be fraught with hurdles. For example, Dr Barbara McClintock's identification of 'jumping genes' in maize in the 1940s and 1950s was initially disbelieved, then begrudgingly acknowledged, but dismissed as unimportant. It was only decades later, in 1983, when its fundamental relevance was appreciated and rewarded with an unopposed Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine for the discovery of genetic transposition. For her brilliance, tenacity, and multiple apex achievements, she became, in 2005, the only woman scientist to be lauded with her picture on a U.S. postage stamp. In like fashion, the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ has been disputed, ignored, dismissed as unimportant or inconvenient, and until relatively recently, has been underappreciated for its great potential to resolve key facets of skeletal muscle energetics during exercise. The intriguing findings of MacDougall and colleagues (2024) take us away from the Ockham's razor approach of looking for a singular driver of the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ and force acknowledgment that not only may multiple factors contribute to its evolution, but those factors likely differ considerably across individuals. Resolution of the mechanistic bases for the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ will not only enhance our fundamental understanding of muscle energetics but is also likely to have broad applications across medicine and society. For instance, if the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ can be controlled such that it does not progress the individual to V &#775; O 2 max ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{max}}}}$ , exercise tolerance can be increased. This is particularly pertinent for patients with heart failure or with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD, emphysema, chronic bronchitis) for whom the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ forces encroachment on their low and limiting ceiling for cardiovascular or ventilatory function, respectively, crippling exercise capacity (Gaesser &amp; Poole, 1996). In contrast, with the upwards spiral of obesity in the developed world, it is conceivable that the 'luxurious' calorigenic effects of the V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ could be marshalled to enhance the efficacy of exercise to restore a better caloric balance across affected populations. Specifically, targeting exercise that produced the greatest tolerable V &#775; O 2 SC ${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}{\mathrm{SC}}}}$ would expend more calories and thereby accelerate weight loss. All authors have read and approved the final version of this manuscript and agree to be accountable for all aspects of the work in ensuring that questions related to the accuracy or integrity of any part of the work are appropriately investigated and resolved. All persons designated as authors qualify for authorship, and all those who qualify for authorship are listed. None declared.</description>
      <author>David C. Poole, Glenn A. Gaesser</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1113/ep092326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are we prepared for the next pandemic: Monitor on increasing human and animal H5N1 avian influenza infection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1097/cm9.0000000000003375</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Yanxia Sun, Zhongjie Li, Weizhong Yang, Shuo Feng, Chinese Medical Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403891616

                Human infection with highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI) caused by certain strains of avian influenza A viruses, such as H5N1 and H7N9, results in severe acute respiratory disease with a high mortality rate, among which the former is pathogenic to birds.[1] In recent years, HPAI H5 has spread globally, causing human infections. The first reported case of bovine H5N1 infection, which was subsequently transmitted to humans, garnered significant international attention. Drawing on the historical influenza pandemic experience and biological characteristics of the virus, under specific conditions, such as reassortment with human and swine influenza viruses, avian influenza viruses (AIV) may achieve efficient human-to-human transmission, potentially leading to a global pandemic. Here, we aimed to review the historical trends of H5N1 avian influenza infections in humans and the recent developments in epidemiological situations, evaluate the transmission risk of H5N1 avian influenza, and propose avian influenza control recommendations for public health decision-making. Global trends in human H5N1 infection. The avian influenza A H5N1 was first detected in southern China in 1996. In 1997, a significant outbreak of H5N1 avian influenza occurred among farmed chickens in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, marking the first reported case of H5N1 crossing the species barrier to infect humans. This initial outbreak resulted in 18 human infections and 6 fatalities. Although the outbreak was controlled at that time, H5N1 persisted in avian species. It re-emerged in 2003 and widely spread among birds across Asia and subsequently to Africa, Europe, and the Middle East, leading to poultry outbreaks and sporadic human infections. By late 2003, Southeast Asia had experienced successive H5N1 outbreaks, with the number of infections and deaths peaking in 2006. Since then, almost all such cases have been annually reported. From 1997 to May 26, 2024, 911 human H5N1 infections were reported across 24 countries, with most cases reported between 2004 and 2016, predominantly in Asia and Africa [Figure 1A]. Between 2003 and 2024, 896 individuals were confirmed to have contracted HPAI H5N1 with 463 reported deaths, resulting in an approximate fatality rate of 52%.[2]Figure 1: The global trend of human infection with H5N1 avian influenza and H5N1 avian influenza outbreaks. (A) represents the global trend in human H5N1 infections from January 1997 to August 2024, sourced from https://www.cdc.gov/flu/avianflu/chart-epi-curve-ah5n1.html. The yellow from light to dark corresponds to the increasing number of human cases infected with H5N1. (B) represents the global trend in highly pathogenic avian influenza H5N1 outbreaks from January 2005 to August 2024, sourced from https://wahis.woah.org/#/dashboards/qd-dashboard. The blue from light to dark corresponds to the increasing number of avian H5N1 outbreaks. AFRO: African Region of WHO; AMRO: Americas Region of WHO; EMRO: Eastern Mediterranean Region of WHO; EURO: European Region of WHO; SEARO: South-East Asia Region of WHO; WPRO: Western Pacific Region of WHO.H5 has spread to &gt;150 avian and 50 mammalian species.[3] The H5N1 currently circulating among wild birds and poultry in most parts of the world predominantly belongs to the 2.3.4.4b clade.[4] Genetically distinct from earlier genotypes, it emerged in 2020 from previously prevalent H5NX subtype viruses and has spread primarily through migratory birds to regions, including Africa, Asia, and Europe. By late 2021, this clade reached North America and subsequently spread to South America by October 2022. The genetic flexibility of HPAI H5N1 from clade 2.3.4.4b allows for extensive reassortment with other AIVs, yielding a diverse array of H5N1&#8211;H5N8 viruses.[5] This efficient reassortment has led to the emergence of &gt;50 genotypes.[6] Although there has been an increase in HPAI H5N1 infections in mammals, reports on mammal-to-mammal transmission remain limited. Between 2021 and April 2024, 28 human cases of H5N1 infection have been reported globally. Among the human cases identified as hemagglutinin (HA) H5 clade infections, 13 were caused by the 2.3.4.4b clade.[7] The severity of human illnesses resulting from AIV infection widely varies, ranging from asymptomatic or mild illness to severe disease leading to death. Characteristics of the recent A(H5N1) outbreak. Recent analyses have highlighted that the emergence of H5N1 2.3.4.4b is associated with outbreaks in the United States. This lineage is characterized by increased pathogenicity at non-traditional interfaces, underscoring the ability of the virus to cross species barriers.[8] On March 25, 2024, the United States detected the HPAI H5N1 strain in dairy cows. Infected cows showed symptoms, such as high fever, dehydration, and reduced milk production.[9] As of August 9, 2024, at least 189 dairy farms across 13 states in the United States have reported H5N1 infections, and there have been four human cases associated with an ongoing multistate outbreak of A(H5N1) in dairy cows.[10,11] The patients were dairy farm workers with epidemiological links to infected cows who presented with conjunctivitis, representing the first instance of human infection following transmission from infected dairy cows. This contrasts with the first United States H5N1 case reported in 2022, in which the patient reported only fatigue and has since recovered. Genomic data suggested that the recent H5N1 outbreak in the United States likely originated from infected birds transmitting the virus to dairy cows in late 2023 or early 2024, with subsequent spread among cow populations for several months. The spread of HAPI H5N1 in cattle poses a risk to humans through close contact with farm workers. Infected lactating cows produce milk containing high levels of the influenza virus, which, if not pasteurized, can contaminate milking equipment and act as a transmission vector for dairy farm workers. The latest study also indicated that both bovine H5N1 and the human 2009 H1N1 pandemic influenza viruses remained infectious on common milking equipment surfaces for several hours.[12] The H5N1 2.3.4.4b lineage exhibits strong transmission capabilities, with the potential to spread between birds and mammals. Recent outbreaks have suggested that the 2.3.4.4b lineage may have adapted to infect dairy cows, leading to its spread and infection in cattle. This adaptation allows the virus to be transmitted from cows to humans, specifically in close-contact environments, such as dairy farms, which are highly pathogenic in birds and cause severe disease. In cattle, the virus causes noticeable clinical symptoms, such as high fever and reduced milk production. Humans infected with this lineage show more severe symptoms than earlier H5N1 infections, including conjunctivitis, indicating a possible increase in pathogenicity. Current information suggests that AIV, particularly lineage 2.3.4.4b, may have adapted to mammalian hosts, increasing the likelihood of human infection through interspecies transmission. Public health risk assessment. From a food safety perspective, the consumption of pasteurized milk and properly cooked beef is safe for the public. To verify the safety of the meat supply in the context of H5N1, the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Food Safety and Inspection Service (FSIS), Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, and Agricultural Research Service conducted three studies on the safety of beef from cattle affected by avian influenza. As of May 24, 2024, none of the diseased cattle culled at the slaughterhouses had entered the food supply chain, and ground beef samples collected from retail stores in the affected states tested negative for viral particles. Cooking beef to the FSIS-recommended temperatures of 145&#176;F (medium rare) or 160&#176;F (well done) can eliminate the virus, and cooking to 120&#176;F (rare) is sufficient to inactivate the virus substantially.[13] As of May 10, 2024, the USDA and Food and Drug Administration (FDA) have confirmed that the commercial milk supply is safe, as all sold milk undergoes pasteurization, and milk from infected cows has been either diverted or destroyed. Additionally, none of the 297 samples collected by the FDA at retail points tested positive for live HPAI H5N1.[14] Based on genetic sequencing of US-confirmed cases, the current risk of human-to-human transmission remains low.[15] The HA gene in the conjunctival samples from the Michigan H5N1 patient was identified as clade 2.3.4.4b. Each gene segment was closely related to the B3.13 genotype virus detected in cows by the USDA. These data indicated that the virus detected in both cows and humans retained avian genetic characteristics and lacked the gene expression necessary for efficient human-to-human transmission. However, specific mutations, such as PB2-M631L in Michigan and PB2-E627K in Texas, may enhance the ability of the virus to spread in mammals. Although H5N1 typically prefers binding to &#945;-2,3-sialic acid (SA &#945;-2,3), which is less common in humans, the PB2-E627K and PB2-M631L mutations may enhance the virus's ability to bind to SA &#945;-2,6 on the surface of human lower respiratory epithelial cells. This increased binding capability can improve viral replication efficiency, potentially enhancing the adaptability and transmissibility of H5N1 in mammals, leading to severe respiratory infections and pneumonia.[16] A pathogenicity study based on mice and ferrets revealed that HPAI H5N1 derived from lactating dairy cattle had dual receptor binding specificity, which may induce severe disease after oral ingestion or respiratory infection. Infection by either the oral or respiratory route can lead to systemic spread of the virus to non-respiratory tissues, including the eye, mammary gland, teat, and/or muscle.[17] The rest of the Michigan patient genome closely matched the sequences detected in infected cows, suggesting direct transmission from cows to humans. This sentence is almost identical to the previous statement, so it has been deleted. According to the World Organization for Animal Health, 13,755 H5N1 outbreaks were reported worldwide from 2005 to May 2024, with most occurring in Europe and North America over the past 3 years [Figure 1B]. H5N1 predominantly spreads among birds and poultry and occasionally infects mammals and humans. Prior to the reported cases of H5N1 transmission from dairy cows to humans in the United States, nearly all human H5N1 cases worldwide had a history of contact with poultry or exposure to live bird markets. Although some family clusters were observed, there was no evidence of efficient human-to-human transmission. Based on current data, H5N1 avian influenza outbreaks in wild birds, poultry, cattle, and other animals pose a low risk to the public. However, there is a low-to-moderate risk of infection for individuals who come into contact with H5N1-infected birds or animals or are exposed to environments contaminated by the virus. In addition, the eight major migratory bird routes worldwide can increase the risk of AIV introduction into countries along these routes. The continuous evolution and spread of AIV in animals indicate that the risk of human exposure persists. Consequently, the potential for sporadic cases or even small clusters of human infections remains a concern. Countermeasures for prevention and control. Recombinations and mutations suggest that H5N1 poses a potential threat to the pandemic, necessitating proactive preparedness. This involves focusing on the development and application of tools, such as vaccines, therapeutics, and diagnostic reagents, and capacity building in the areas of surveillance, early warning systems, and response preparedness. The "One Health" concept provides a comprehensive strategy for the control of HPAI, emphasizing the interconnectedness of humans, animals, and the environment. Promoting collaboration, interdisciplinary communication, and coordinated actions among veterinarians, public health experts, environmental scientists, and policymakers can enhance the effectiveness of disease surveillance, prevention, and control measures. Based on this "One Health" concept, current environmental monitoring of H5N1 avian influenza involves comprehensive surveillance strategies targeting both wildlife and domestic poultry, with a focus on detecting and mitigating outbreaks early. Surveillance includes testing migratory birds and poultry for H5N1; sampling environmental materials, such as water and soil; and using advanced diagnostic techniques to identify and characterize virus strains. Despite these efforts, global and local conflicts have challenged information sharing. International bodies, such as the World Health Organization, coordinate data exchange and facilitate global response efforts, whereas regional and local entities work to overcome the barriers posed by geopolitical tensions and conflict zones. Effective communication channels are maintained through public health messaging, collaborative networks, and emergency response planning to ensure the timely and accurate dissemination of information to curb the spread of H5N1 and enhance preparedness across affected areas. Based on this, we offer insights and recommendations for key linkage measures for further responses to H5N1 infection. "Human&#8211;Animal&#8211;Environment" multichannel surveillance and risk assessment. The proactive surveillance of severe syndromes among occupational groups in contact with animals is essential. This primarily involves health monitoring of individuals at a higher risk of exposure to animal pathogens, such as workers in large-scale animal farming, veterinarians, animal slaughter and processing workers, and staff in wildlife conservation areas. Additionally, surveillance for pneumonia of an unknown etiology should be initiated in the general population. Strengthening the reporting awareness of clinical doctors will help collect samples for pathogen identification and conduct epidemiological investigations in a timely manner once cluster cases or serious hospitalized cases are discovered, thereby identifying the potential risk of animal pathogens infecting humans as soon as possible. Close attention should be paid to the global dynamics of avian influenza outbreaks, with particular emphasis on surveillance in high-risk areas. Regular sampling and testing of poultry and wild birds in farms, markets, and natural habitats are recommended to monitor the transmission and mutation of AIV. Enhanced information sharing among the health, agriculture, and forestry departments is necessary to integrate data from various surveillance channels, such as public sentiment, drug sales, respiratory syndrome reports, testing, and imaging. Key monitoring focuses include the epidemiological characteristics of human infections with avian influenza, viral mutations, transmission capabilities, and clinical severity. Increasing the frequency of risk assessments, early warning systems, and the development of precise and effective early warning technologies enables multipoint triggering and timely implementation of relevant preventive and control measures. Conventional surveillance methods, including pathogen genome sequencing, laboratory diagnostics, and mortality surveillance, are inadequate in the face of complex and rapidly evolving threats. Wastewater monitoring is a critical tool, as demonstrated during the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic.[18] Strengthening animal disease surveillance is also highly recommended, particularly to gain a deeper understanding of the activities and movements of migratory birds. It is essential to enhance monitoring of poultry around migratory bird habitats, increase environmental and animal surveillance along migratory bird migration routes, and boost sampling proportions and frequencies. Utilizing monitoring devices and regular patrols enables real-time monitoring of high-risk areas, ensuring the prompt detection and management of outbreak events. Protection for occupational groups and objective Public Health education. For individuals who come into contact with infected birds or other animals owing to their occupation, including those working in wildlife reserves, poultry farms, or dairies, individuals raising birds, and personnel responding to avian influenza outbreaks in birds or other animals, it is crucial to enhance their awareness of protective measures. When directly or closely interacting with deceased poultry or livestock, they must strictly adhere to protocols for wearing personal protective equipment. Additionally, before entering spaces where these animals reside or have not yet been disinfected, they should undergo comprehensive personal protection training. Physicians should be alert from a clinical perspective to recognize a history of avian exposure, such as in cattle, in patients with associated H5N1 symptoms, such as conjunctivitis, and assist in confirming the diagnosis of H5N1 infection with polymerase chain reaction testing and lung imaging to assess the presence of pneumonia or acute respiratory distress syndrome. Following confirmation of the diagnosis, antiviral drugs, such as oseltamivir, should be administered immediately, and treatment should be initiated at an earlier onset if possible. Support, such as oxygen therapy or mechanical ventilation, may be required for critically ill patients and to prevent secondary bacterial infections. Patients should be hospitalized and isolated, and healthcare workers should be strictly protected. Influenza vaccination is recommended in high-risk occupational groups. Furthermore, to avoid unnecessary panic, we recommend providing the public with accurate and truthful reports on the outbreak and conducting objective and appropriate health education without exaggerating the situation. The public should be reminded to avoid contact with sick or deceased animals, including wild birds, poultry, domesticated birds; and other wild or domestic animals, and animal waste, litter, or materials contaminated with birds or animals that are suspected or confirmed to be infected with AIV. Additionally, it is important to avoid slaughtering or consuming diseased or dead poultry and livestock and to refrain from consuming undercooked foods, such as raw milk or cheese that have not been pasteurized. Development of novel vaccines and technological preparedness. Currently, seasonal influenza vaccines do not prevent the spread of AIV in humans globally. Several countries are developing H5N1 avian influenza vaccines for emergency preparedness. In the United States, three H5N1 vaccines, developed from earlier strains of HPAI H5N1 (A/Vietnam, clade 1, and A/Indonesia, clade 2.1), with (MF59-CSL, Seqirus, Melbourne, Australia or AS03-GSK, Brentford, United Kingdom) or without adjuvants (Sanofi Pasteur, Lille, France), are licensed and stockpiled for pre-pandemic preparedness.[19] A recent study showed that adults who received three licensed adjuvanted H5N1 vaccines generated cross-neutralizing antibodies against the circulating HPAI H5N1 clade 2.3.4.4b in humans.[20] Individuals vaccinated with the two licensed adjuvanted H5N1 vaccines generated cross-reactive binding and cross-neutralizing antibodies against the HPAI clade 2.3.4.4b A/Astrakhan/3212/2020 virus. Seroconversion rates of 60&#8211;95% against H5 clade 2.3.4.4b were recorded after two doses of AS03-adjuvanted-A/Indonesia or three doses of MF59-adjuvanted-A/Vietnam vaccine. Additionally, a monovalent messenger RNA (mRNA) lipid nanoparticle vaccine expressing 2.3.4.4b was immunogenic and protective in preclinical animal models, with H5-reactive antibody levels increasing approximately eightfold after the second dose compared with those before the booster.[21] The advantage of this vaccine is that it can be rapidly produced without the need to isolate and adapt to a viral strain that grows effectively in fertilized chicken eggs or cell cultures. The manufacture of a novel mRNA vaccine can begin within hours of sequencing a new pandemic viral strain. Considering the pandemic potential of H5N1, efforts should be made to develop stockpiled vaccines, antiviral drugs, and diagnostic tools. It is important to monitor the latest internationally shared AIV sequences, further survey relevant variants that may affect outbreak trends, and analyze key mutations and dynamic changes in virus sequences. For example, PB2-E627K and PB2-M631L in PB2 influence how well a vaccine protects against different influenza strains. If vaccines are developed based on strains lacking these mutations, they may be less effective against the strains carrying either E627K or M631L. Thus, inclusion of these mutations in vaccine strain selection is crucial for maintaining vaccine effectiveness. The presence of these mutations highlights the need for continuous surveillance and updating vaccines to ensure that they cover the most current and relevant strains. This may involve modifying vaccine composition or developing new vaccines to address emerging viral variants. This will allow for timely updates on vaccine strains, diagnostic primers, and sequences, thereby ensuring readiness for potential pandemics. In addition, continued support for the development of universal influenza vaccines is crucial. Establishing a stable pandemic simulation team for emerging infectious diseases can aid scenario-based pandemic preparedness and intervention evaluation studies and enhance decision-making capabilities for pandemic response readiness. Other valuable practices for reference. The "physical isolation and culling" strategy is commonly used in many countries. However, large-scale culling measures can cause economic losses to the poultry industry. For example, owing to recurring avian influenza outbreaks in the United Kingdom, over 5.5 million birds were culled between October 2021 and November 2022. In the United States, the avian influenza outbreak in 2022 led to the deaths of approximately 40 million animals, resulting in economic losses estimated between US$2.5 billion and US$3 billion.[22] As a large global producer and consumer of agricultural products, China has maintained its stability during recent outbreaks over the past 5 years. There have been no widespread poultry infections or culling, and poultry production has remained relatively steady, despite frequent global avian influenza outbreaks. Since 2004, China has implemented immunization against H5 and/or H7 HPAI in all domestically raised poultry. Furthermore, China mandates a 100% vaccination coverage rate and ensures that the annual qualification rate of immunization antibodies remains &gt;70%.[23] By the end of 2022, over 300 billion doses of various vaccines developed in China were administered, both domestically and internationally. Currently, two H5 vaccine seed viruses, H5-Re13, which targets the clade 2.3.4.4h virus that emerged in China in 2017, and H5-Re14, which addresses the clade 2.3.4.4b virus circulating globally, are used alongside the H7N9 vaccine seed virus H7-Re4 in the production of the trivalent vaccine.[24] Between 2002 and 2010, more than 113 billion vaccines were administered worldwide. Five countries have adopted national routine interpoultry immunization programs, accounting for 99% of vaccine use: China (90.9%), Egypt (4.6%), Indonesia (2.3%), Vietnam (1.4%), and Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (&lt;0.01%). The high vaccine coverage enabled the prevention of clinical diseases and deaths in poultry, such as poultry fowl, reduction of human cases, maintenance of rural livelihoods, and food security.[25] Thus, this "culling and vaccination" strategy, distinctive to China, has significantly reduced losses during avian influenza outbreaks and offers valuable lessons for global control efforts against highly pathogenic H5N1. Conflicts of interest None. Funding This work was supported by grants from the Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences Innovation Fund for Medical Sciences (Nos. 2022-I2M-CoV19-006, 2021-I2M-1-044) and the Science &amp; Technology Fundamental Resources Investigation Program (No. 2023FY100600).</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Yanxia Sun, Zhongjie Li, Weizhong Yang, Shuo Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1097/cm9.0000000000003375</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
