<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 01:21:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable oxygen evolution catalysis: Water-based fabrication of FeNi-MIL-100 on recycled stainless steel substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.077</link>
      <description>Zhong Li, Ni Wang, Liangkui Sun, Xingchen Xie, Lixiang He, Mingliang Xiang, Wencheng Hu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405301891

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhong Li, Ni Wang, Liangkui Sun, Xingchen Xie, Lixiang He, Mingliang Xiang, Wencheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancies-Riched composite of ultrathin NiFe-LDH nanosheets on the etched Prussian blue analogue: An efficient alkaline oxygen evolution electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.068</link>
      <description>Chao Wang, Luna Chen, Xinyue Xu, Yajie Liu, Yuan Song, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Guanjun Chen, Tianrong Zhan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405314359

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Wang, Luna Chen, Xinyue Xu, Yajie Liu, Yuan Song, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Guanjun Chen, Tianrong Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial built-in electric field in 2D Ni(OH)2 heterojunction with the sodium organic compound for enhanced oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158565</link>
      <description>Jiao Zhou, Mingyuan Zhang, Baiyu Ren, Qian Yi, Sheng Wang, Baoyue Zhang, An&#8208;Ping Li, Xinyi Hu, Zhong Li, Guanyu Chen, Yinfen Cheng, Rui Gao, Yange Luan, Jiaru Zhang, Yichao Wang, Yihong Hu, Z. Yang, Bo Liang, Haigang Hao, Jian Zhen Ou, Chemical Engineering Journal. 503(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405316505

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiao Zhou, Mingyuan Zhang, Baiyu Ren, Qian Yi, Sheng Wang, Baoyue Zhang, An&#8208;Ping Li, Xinyi Hu, Zhong Li, Guanyu Chen, Yinfen Cheng, Rui Gao, Yange Luan, Jiaru Zhang, Yichao Wang, Yihong Hu, Z. Yang, Bo Liang, Haigang Hao, Jian Zhen Ou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction of network structured Polypyrrole-NaBiO2 nanocomposite in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41779-024-01132-5</link>
      <description>Munirah D. Albaqami, Muhammad Imran Anwar, Saikh Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem, Journal of the Australian Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405317491

                When it comes to the ability of the water splitting process to create hydrogen, the challenging dynamics of the water-oxidation reaction (WOR) provide a substantial impediment. So, in order to start both hydrogen and oxygen production during water electrolysis, efficient catalysts are needed. Herein, we report the development of NaBiO2@PPy nanocomposite capable of oxygen evolution reactions (OER) in alkaline medium. The fabricated NaBiO2@PPy nanocomposite and its individuals are characterized via various techniques to confirm the structural, elemental, textural, and morphological characteristics. This material produces a current density of 10 mA/cm2 for oxygen evolution comparatively at low overpotentials of 227 mV and maintains its stability for up to 50 h. Furthermore, the fabricated NaBiO2@PPy nanocomposite also shows less Tafel slope of 30.8 mV/dec. Therefore, this catalytic material would be a good option for creating a cost-effective, and environmentally friendly alkaline medium. In order to enhance the performance of water electrolysis, this work offers a revolutionary designed material and electrode fabrication method for future applications. The NaBiO2@PPy nanocomposite is produced by a simple hydrothermal technique. The presence of Polypyrrole (PPy) improves the conductivity of the electrocatalyst by fast ion transmission rate. The NaBiO2@PPy nanocomposite displays an overpotential of 227 mV with a Tafel slope of 30.8 mV/dec at 10 mA/cm2. The NaBiO2@PPy displays excellent activity and stability of 50 h toward OER.</description>
      <author>Munirah D. Albaqami, Muhammad Imran Anwar, Saikh Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41779-024-01132-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Plasma in Catalyst Preparation and Modification for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00075</link>
      <description>Naeem Ahmed, Wei Li, Ruijuan Zhao, Qiu Zhang, Di Wu, Xia Zheng, Haorui Wang, Chunhua Cui, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405318450

                Plasma as a promising solution to catalyst synthesis and modification has received great attention in the field of electrochemical water splitting. However, a comprehensive overview detailing how plasma treatments of catalysts enhance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance is currently lacking. Here, we review the advances and challenges in cold plasma for catalyst preparation and modification. We discuss the underlying mechanisms responsible for enhanced OER performance on plasma-treated catalysts, where the surface area, active sites, vacancy type/content, heteroatom doping, etching, and surface functionalization could be mediated. This review aims to provide valuable insights into the role of plasma treatments in advancing OER electrocatalysis for sustainable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Naeem Ahmed, Wei Li, Ruijuan Zhao, Qiu Zhang, Di Wu, Xia Zheng, Haorui Wang, Chunhua Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled deposition of trimetallic Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;V oxides on nickel foam as high-performance electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.044</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ali Ehsan, Rashida Batool, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Sameer Ali, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Zaka Ullah, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405318518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ali Ehsan, Rashida Batool, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Sameer Ali, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Zaka Ullah</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Restructuring of Asymmetric Built&#8208;in Electric Field Catalysts Facilitates the Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202422734</link>
      <description>Wansen Ma, Yuhan Zhang, Liwen Hu, Xuewei Lv, Jie Dang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405325603

                Abstract Efficient and stable bifunctional catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction play an important role in realizing hydrogen economy. In this study, the multi&#8208;heterogeneous interfacial catalyst, Ni 2 P@FeP@Co 2 P (denoted as NFC), with an asymmetric built&#8208;in electric field is successfully designed and synthesized. Benefiting from the double charge balance effect, NFC exhibits superior hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic activity. Importantly, the NFC&#8208;assembled anion&#8208;exchange membrane (AEM) electrolyzer exhibits enhanced performance and remarkable stability at industrial current densities and high temperatures, reaching a current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 at the small voltage of 1.95 V. The results of the dynamic X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy tests indicate that the self&#8208;reconfiguration of the NFC during OER provides additional active sites for the reaction. The density functional theory (DFT) results demonstrate that the asymmetric built&#8208;in electric field (BIEF) induces an adaptive distribution of charge, which optimizes the adsorption and desorption of hydrogen/oxygen intermediates during the reaction, thereby enhancing the catalytic kinetics of the overall water splitting process. This work presents novel strategies for the design of highly active catalysts in the field of energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Wansen Ma, Yuhan Zhang, Liwen Hu, Xuewei Lv, Jie Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202422734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical NiFeP/CoP nano-arrays for efficient oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3054301</link>
      <description>Aobo Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405325991

                This paper provides a comprehensive overview of the development, working principles, and catalyst evaluation parameters in the realm of electrochemical water electrolysis, with a primary focus on the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER). The discussion encompasses the historical perspective, reaction mechanisms, and fundamental principles underlying water electrolysis, with a strong emphasis on the pivotal role of electrocatalysts in driving efficient hydrogen production. Furthermore, this paper delves into a specific study that involves the fabrication of 3D hierarchical NiFeP/CoP nano-arrays on conductive carbon cloth. This innovative catalyst architecture, realized through a combination of hydrothermal methods and phosphating treatments, showcases remarkable performance in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) electrocatalysis. The hierarchical structure of this catalyst maximizes the electrochemically active area, exposing a higher number of active sites and facilitating efficient reaction kinetics. The catalytic performance of NiFeP/CoP/CC is distinguished by its low overpotentials, a small Tafel slope, and exceptional stability over prolonged durations. This promising performance positions it as a potential substitute for precious metal catalysts in the pursuit of sustainable energy conversion. In essence, this research significantly contributes to the ongoing endeavor to discover cost-effective, resource-efficient, and highly active electrocatalysts. It marks a notable step forward in the journey towards achieving green energy transformation, aligning with the imperative for sustainable and environmentally friendly energy solutions.</description>
      <author>Aobo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3054301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering CoN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Dual Sites with Adjacent Nanoclusters on Flexible Porous Carbon Fibers for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418489</link>
      <description>Zhe L&#252;, Zhe Wang, Zhenbei Yang, Xiaoyan Jin, Tong Li, RuoJie Xu, Ke&#8208;Xin Kong, Shouxin Zhang, Yong Wang, Yipu Liu, Linxing Meng, Zhijuan Pan, Seong&#8208;Ju Hwang, Liang Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405337455

                Abstract Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) possess tunable electronic structures and efficient atom utilization, making them highly promising for catalyzing the oxygen reduction reaction/oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER). However, achieving high catalytic activity and stability for both ORR and OER in DACs remains a challenge. Herein, a flexible membrane of porous carbon fiber anchored with atomically scattered CoN 4 /FeN 4 dual sites and adjacent Co 2 Fe 2 /Fe 5 nanoclusters (Co, Fe&#8208;DACs/NCs@PCF) is synthesized. The local geometry and electronic structure of the CoN 4 /FeN 4 sites, which act as reaction centers for ORR/OER, are finely regulated by the neighboring Co 2 Fe 2 /Fe 5 nanoclusters. This unique structure imparts Co, Fe&#8208;DACs/NCs@PCF with exceptional activity and durability toward ORR/OER, outperforming the performance of single&#8208;atom catalysts containing only CoN 4 or FeN 4 sites, as well as commercial Pt/C and RuO 2 catalysts. Zinc&#8211;air battery employing a Co, Fe&#8208;DACs/NCs@PCF cathode exhibits outstanding stability, maintaining cyclability for over 1500 h, outperforming a Pt/C + RuO 2 air cathode. Theoretical calculations highlight distinct synergies between Fe 5 (Co 2 Fe 2 ) clusters and FeN 4 (CoN 4 ) sites, which optimize the coupling strength of Fe(Co)&#9472;OH at the potential&#8208;determining steps and thus improve ORR (OER) catalytic kinetics. This study lays a theoretical and practical foundation for rational design of heterostructure catalysts featuring coexisting DACs and nanoclusters within porous carbon fibers.</description>
      <author>Zhe L&#252;, Zhe Wang, Zhenbei Yang, Xiaoyan Jin, Tong Li, RuoJie Xu, Ke&#8208;Xin Kong, Shouxin Zhang, Yong Wang, Yipu Liu, Linxing Meng, Zhijuan Pan, Seong&#8208;Ju Hwang, Liang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct electrodeposition of NiFe-based high-entropy compound on nickel foam for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5328722/v1</link>
      <description>Yibin Yang, Yang Ji-tao, Xinghua Huang, Wang Chen, Yuhao Zhang, Xiaowen Zhang, Lijuan Dong, Zhihao Duan, Mingzhu Wu, Ying Li, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405338076

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting represents a highly promising avenue for sustainable energy conversion and storage, paving the way for a future hydrogen-based society. This approach necessitates the development of durable and cost-effective electrocatalysts for the OER. In this study, we report the as-synthesized NiFe-based high-entropy compound grown on nickel foam via direct electrochemical deposition. Remarkably, electrodeposition onto 1&#215;1 cm2 nickel foam was optimized by strategically varying critical parameters. Subsequently, the fabricated electrodes underwent evaluation for comprehensive water splitting within the identical flow cell under alkaline conditions. The best-performing sample, NiFe-2:1, required relatively low overpotentials of 232 mV to reach a current density of 10 mA cm-2 for the OER. The NiFe-2:1 hydroxides exhibit high entropy, which optimizes the flat-band potential (Efb) and carrier concentration (NA) in high-entropy NiFe-based electrocatalysts. This enhancement facilitates sensitive electron transfer, thereby reducing the kinetic barrier for the OER. Furthermore, this review thoroughly discusses potential degradation mechanisms of active sites and outlines corresponding mitigation strategies. It also offers insights into the discrepancies between research and the design of non-precious metal-based catalysts for the OER, as well as their implementation in practical devices.</description>
      <author>Yibin Yang, Yang Ji-tao, Xinghua Huang, Wang Chen, Yuhao Zhang, Xiaowen Zhang, Lijuan Dong, Zhihao Duan, Mingzhu Wu, Ying Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5328722/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photocatalytic and electrocatalytic properties of IrO2 nanoparticles via Cr and Co ion doping: Insights into surface oxygen defect structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162088</link>
      <description>Hyeri Jeon, Dung Thanh Hoang, Gyuri Kim, In Young Kim, Hangil Lee, Seungwoo Hong, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405338674

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyeri Jeon, Dung Thanh Hoang, Gyuri Kim, In Young Kim, Hangil Lee, Seungwoo Hong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallic Compounds for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch12</link>
      <description>Xiaobo Zheng, Yao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405352517

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) stands as a pivotal electrochemical process, playing a crucial role in various cutting-edge renewable energy technologies such as water-splitting and metal-air batteries. However, its inherent sluggish kinetics necessitate a substantial overpotential to drive the OER, which significantly constrains the widespread application of these devices. Consequently, a range of efficient, durable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts, including carbon-based materials, metals, and metallic compounds, have been engineered to reduce the OER overpotential and enhance energy efficiency. In this section, we provide a comprehensive discussion of the recent intriguing advancements in metallic compounds for the OER, with a deep exploration of the catalytic mechanisms and the underlying structure&#8211;performance relationships. Specifically, we systematically delve into metal oxides, hydroxides, and their supported single-atom/nanoparticle materials, showcasing their superiority in driving the OER. Finally, we offer some new insights into the remaining challenges and opportunities for the development of metallic compounds.</description>
      <author>Xiaobo Zheng, Yao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Materials for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch13</link>
      <description>Zhongjie Yang, D.J. Fu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405352615

                Porous materials, including metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) and covalent&#8211;organic frameworks (COFs), possess distinctive porous structural characteristics such as exceptional porosity, large surface areas, and well-organized nanoporous structures. These materials can be designed with specific structures and compositions to enhance their applications in gas capture, separation, catalysis, energy storage, and conversion. Recently, the development of pure MOFs/COFs along with their derivatives has paved the way for the creation of highly efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions (OER). This chapter discusses recent progress in the synthesis and the electrocatalytic applications of MOF/COF-based electrocatalysts toward OER, including pristine MOFs/COFs, MOFs/COFs composites, and derivatives. The primary section focuses on the advancements in the design and preparation of various MOF/COF-based catalysts such as metal nodes and organic ligand engineering, conductive substrates and active species composites, and metals into nitrogen-doped carbon matrix. Furthermore, the current challenges and outlook of MOFs/COFs-based OER electrocatalysts are also presented.</description>
      <author>Zhongjie Yang, D.J. Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Based Materials for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch11</link>
      <description>Mengyi Xu, Li Xu, Yurong Su, Meirong Song, Xian&#8208;Fu Zheng, Yuchen Qin, Guang-Xin Ru, Xiuhong Zhu, Li Wang, Sheng Xia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405352622

                Electrochemical water splitting is widely considered a promising method for generating renewable and sustainable hydrogen energy. However, the high overpotential required for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in this process has posed a bottleneck for large-scale hydrogen production. Therefore, there is an urgent need to develop efficient and stable OER catalysts to overcome this challenge. Metal-based materials play a crucial role in the OER, and they are essential for enhancing the efficiency and stability of the reaction. This section reviews different types of metal-based materials widely used in the electrocatalytic OER, including metal single-atom materials and metal alloy materials, from noble metal to non-noble metal materials, and introduces their synthesis methods, surface structures, and catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Mengyi Xu, Li Xu, Yurong Su, Meirong Song, Xian&#8208;Fu Zheng, Yuchen Qin, Guang-Xin Ru, Xiuhong Zhu, Li Wang, Sheng Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coral-like FeCoNi alloy/layered double hydroxides/nickel foam for enhancing mass transfer in oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158217</link>
      <description>Liang Ma, Zengyan Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Yaming Wang, Xiaoxiao Huang, Feng Ming, Peigang He, Dechang Jia, Yu Zhou, Xiaoming Duan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405356157

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Ma, Zengyan Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Yaming Wang, Xiaoxiao Huang, Feng Ming, Peigang He, Dechang Jia, Yu Zhou, Xiaoming Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158217</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Reaction Mechanism for Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch3</link>
      <description>Hao Ma, Yuanmiao Sun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405358246

                Electrocatalysis holds paramount significance in driving the progress of sustainable energy technologies, such as fuel cells, water electrolyzers, and batteries. The presence of various species on the electrode surface, such as reactants, intermediates, and products during electrocatalysis' usually gives rise to complex reaction pathways. A systematic understanding of various electrocatalytic processes in chemical reactions is required to untangle the complicated interaction of species on the catalyst's surface and their influence on the electrocatalytic process. Taking hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), and nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR) as examples, this chapter introduces electrocatalytic mechanisms, feasible reaction pathways, and fundamental concepts to readers and stimulates their interest in the various fields of electrocatalysts and their applications.</description>
      <author>Hao Ma, Yuanmiao Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the Electronic Structure and Spin State of Iron-based metal-organic frameworks for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.125144</link>
      <description>Dongyu Gu, Yue Yao, Xin Zhang, Yuanjing Cui, Guodong Qian, Journal of Solid State Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405364412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongyu Gu, Yue Yao, Xin Zhang, Yuanjing Cui, Guodong Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.125144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteroatom&#8208;Based Ligand Engineering of Metal Organic Frameworks for Efficient and Robust Electrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402112</link>
      <description>Hong-Yi Tan, Binghao Wang, Mengyi Xu, Zhiyong Peng, Wenjuan Wu, Sheng Shen, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405370336

                Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) are promising catalysts for the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their high surface area, tunable pore structures, and abundant active sites. Ligand engineering is an important strategy to optimize their performance. Here, we report the synthesis of NiFe&#8208;MOFs based on three different ligands: 1,4&#8208;terephthalic acid (BDC), 2,4&#8208;thiophene dicarboxylic acid (TDC), and 2,5&#8208;furandicarboxylic acid (FDC), to investigate the effects of heteroatom&#8208;based aromatic rings on OER performance. It is revealed that by incorporating electronegative sulfur and oxygen atoms into the ligands, the electron density at the metal sites is reduced, leading to enhanced metal&#8208;oxygen covalency and improved charge transfer kinetics. The NiFe&#8208;FDC/NF catalyst demonstrates an overpotential of 189 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8208;2 and stable performance over 1300 hours at 1 A&#183;cm&#8208;2. In situ infrared spectroscopy reveal minimal structural reconstruction in NiFe&#8208;FDC/NF, contributing to its superior stability. The NiFe&#8208;FDC/NF were then subjected to 3600 hours of OER operation and it&#8217;s metal elution was monitored. These findings offer a novel approach to ligand design for high&#8208;performance MOF&#8208;based OER catalysts, highlighting the potential of furan&#8208;based ligands for MOF ligand engineering.</description>
      <author>Hong-Yi Tan, Binghao Wang, Mengyi Xu, Zhiyong Peng, Wenjuan Wu, Sheng Shen, Shuang&#8208;Feng Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can NiFe-Layered-Double-Hydroxide Catalysts Suppress Carbon Corrosion in Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16113</link>
      <description>Yuki Takaki, Manabu Ishizaki, Takashi Nakamura, Masato Kurihara, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405371639

                Sustainable energy societies demand rechargeable batteries using ubiquitous-material electrodes of geopolitical-risk-free elements. We aim to develop low-overpotential oxygen-evolution-reaction (OER) catalysts that suppress carbon corrosion of gas-diffusion electrodes (GDEs) to realize two-electrode rechargeable Zn-air batteries (r-ZABs). Herein, single-walled-carbon-nanotube (SWNT) thin films are used as a scaffold for a benchmark OER catalyst, doping-free NiFe-layered double hydroxide (NiFeLDHs), operating in r-ZABs using alkali aqueous electrolytes. Metal compositions of NiFeLDHs are controlled with an atomic-level quality using Prussian-blue-analog nanoparticles of Ni</description>
      <author>Yuki Takaki, Manabu Ishizaki, Takashi Nakamura, Masato Kurihara</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical NiFe LDH/N-doped Co/Nickel foam as highly active oxygen evolution reaction electrode for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907190</link>
      <description>Jian&#8208;Sheng Wang, Yongsheng Wang, Xiaoxuan Guo, Mengting Chen, Jinjie Fang, Xiaojie Li, Wei Zhu, Zhongbin Zhuang, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405374956

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian&#8208;Sheng Wang, Yongsheng Wang, Xiaoxuan Guo, Mengting Chen, Jinjie Fang, Xiaojie Li, Wei Zhu, Zhongbin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g</link>
      <description>Huan Liu, Yue Han, Jinrui Guo, Wenqi Gao, Jiaqing Wang, Bin He, Zhihong Wang, Weiming L&#252;, Materials Horizons. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405375835

                The realization and subsequent control of emerging structural and electronic phases in solid materials has significantly enhanced their functionalities, thereby benefiting both fundamental research and practical applications. The grain boundary...</description>
      <author>Huan Liu, Yue Han, Jinrui Guo, Wenqi Gao, Jiaqing Wang, Bin He, Zhihong Wang, Weiming L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perchlorate Fusion&#8211;Hydrothermal Synthesis of Nano-Crystalline IrO2: Leveraging Stability and Oxygen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-31vk9</link>
      <description>Genevieve C. Moss, Tobias Binninger, Ziba S. H. S. Rajan, Bamato Jonathan Itota, Patricia J. Kooyman, Darija Susac, Rhiyaad Mohamed, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405375951

                Iridium oxides are the leading oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts for proton-exchange-membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). However, improving iridium utilization is crucial due to its high cost and scarcity. Crystalline rutile-type iridium dioxide (IrO2) offers superior stability in acidic OER conditions compared to amorphous iridium oxide (IrOx), but the high synthesis temperatures required for crystalline phase formation reduce OER activity by decreasing active surface area. Herein, we present a novel perchlorate fusion&#8211;hydrothermal (PFHT) synthesis method to produce nano-crystalline rutile-type IrO2 nanoparticles with exceptional OER performance. This low-temperature approach involves calcination 300 &#176;C in the presence of a strong oxidizing agent, sodium perchlorate, followed by hydrothermal treatment at 180 &#176;C, yielding ~2 nm IrO2 nanoparticles. The catalyst achieved a high mass-specific OER activity of 95 A gIr&#8211;1 at 1.525 VRHE in ex situ glass-cell testing. Notably, the PFHT-synthesized IrO2 demonstrated remarkable stability under harsh accelerated stress test conditions, outperforming commercial catalysts. The exceptional activity of the catalyst was confirmed with in situ PEMWE single-cell evaluations. This demonstrates that the PFHT synthesis method leverages the superior intrinsic properties of nano-crystalline IrO2, effectively overcoming the typical trade-offs between OER activity and catalyst stability, making it a promising approach for advancing PEMWE technologies.</description>
      <author>Genevieve C. Moss, Tobias Binninger, Ziba S. H. S. Rajan, Bamato Jonathan Itota, Patricia J. Kooyman, Darija Susac, Rhiyaad Mohamed</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-31vk9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvement in electrochemical performance of MnFeO3 using Nb-doping strategy for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1140/epjp/s13360-024-05868-8</link>
      <description>Saeed D. Alahmari, Arooj Fatima, The European Physical Journal Plus. 139(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405378685

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saeed D. Alahmari, Arooj Fatima</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1140/epjp/s13360-024-05868-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly portable electrochemical oxygen removal device for microenvironmental low-oxygen control</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907179</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Xingen Lin, Wanyu Shen, Yimin Li, Yi Tan, Zihan Wang, Peng Jiang, Song Gong, Kong Chen, Yu Zhang, Rong Yu, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405380333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Xingen Lin, Wanyu Shen, Yimin Li, Yi Tan, Zihan Wang, Peng Jiang, Song Gong, Kong Chen, Yu Zhang, Rong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907179</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous Ni-Fe-Si-B-O Nanosheets for Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s13391-024-00538-4</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Junjie Dong, Zhaolong Li, Jin Zhang, Zhiyuan Ma, Electronic Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405383814

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Junjie Dong, Zhaolong Li, Jin Zhang, Zhiyuan Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s13391-024-00538-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untangling enhanced performance origin of Ca-doped LaBa1-Ca Co2O5+ electrocatalysts toward intermediate-temperature oxygen reduction/evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2024.117940</link>
      <description>Haibin Huo, Zixuan Tang, Tian Xia, Yingnan Dou, Qiang Li, Li Wang, Liping Sun, Li-Hua Huo, Hui Zhao, Materials Science and Engineering B. 313(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405387654

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Huo, Zixuan Tang, Tian Xia, Yingnan Dou, Qiang Li, Li Wang, Liping Sun, Li-Hua Huo, Hui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2024.117940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392767

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392936

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrochemical Performance of CTAB-Assisted Zn-Doped Perovskite NiMnO3 Nanocrystals on Reduced Graphene Oxide for Supercapacitor and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04617j</link>
      <description>Suprimkumar D. Dhas, Geunchul Kim, Pragati N. Thonge, Amar M. Patil, Avinash C. Mendhe, Rabia Batool, Daewon Kim, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405398062

                This paper introduces a novel chemical reduction synthesis method for preparing bimetallic Zn-doped perovskite NiMnO3 ultrafine nanocrystals, which are further supported on reduced graphene oxide (rGO). These nanocrystals are synthesized...</description>
      <author>Suprimkumar D. Dhas, Geunchul Kim, Pragati N. Thonge, Amar M. Patil, Avinash C. Mendhe, Rabia Batool, Daewon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04617j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus Doping Engineering Induces the Oxygen Defect-Rich Metallic IrOx Layer on the Cobalt Oxide Surface for Efficient and Stable OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101772</link>
      <description>Xinyi Li, Guozhu Zhang, Junyu Nie, Haohong Chen, Feng Zhang, Fenghua Zheng, Guanghua Wei, Shuiyun Shen, Junfang Cheng, Junliang Zhang, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405404868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyi Li, Guozhu Zhang, Junyu Nie, Haohong Chen, Feng Zhang, Fenghua Zheng, Guanghua Wei, Shuiyun Shen, Junfang Cheng, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101772</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Fe2 and Ni Sites for Efficient and Durable Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421168</link>
      <description>Tewodros Asefa, Guiyuan Yang, Meihong Fan, Qing Liang, Xingquan He, Wei Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405412685

                Developing highly efficient, cost&#8208;effective, and robust electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is paramount for the large&#8208;scale commercialization of renewable fuel cells and rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries. Herein, a new ternary&#8208;atom catalyst that is composed of paired Fe sites and single Ni sites (as Fe2&#8208;N6 and Ni&#8208;N4) coordinated onto hollow nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon microspheres is developed. The as&#8208;synthesized catalyst exhibits remarkable activities toward both the ORR and OER in an alkaline media, with superior performances to those of the control materials that contain only Fe2&#8208;N6 or Ni&#8208;N4 sites. Density functional theory calculations and in situ infrared (IR) spectroscopic studies clearly reveal that the Fe2&#8208;N6 centers are the active sites for both ORR and OER, and their electrocatalytic activities are synergistically enhanced through optimization of their d&#8208;band centers by the Ni&#8208;N4 sites. This ternary&#8208;atom catalyst may be a promising, alternative, sustainable catalyst to commercially used Pt&#8208; and Ru&#8208;based catalysts to drive both ORR and OER in rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries and other related applications.</description>
      <author>Tewodros Asefa, Guiyuan Yang, Meihong Fan, Qing Liang, Xingquan He, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Fe2 and Ni Sites for Efficient and Durable Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421168</link>
      <description>Tewodros Asefa, Guiyuan Yang, Meihong Fan, Qing Liang, Xingquan He, Wei Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405412718

                Developing highly efficient, cost&#8208;effective, and robust electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is paramount for the large&#8208;scale commercialization of renewable fuel cells and rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries. Herein, a new ternary&#8208;atom catalyst that is composed of paired Fe sites and single Ni sites (as Fe2&#8208;N6 and Ni&#8208;N4) coordinated onto hollow nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon microspheres is developed. The as&#8208;synthesized catalyst exhibits remarkable activities toward both the ORR and OER in an alkaline media, with superior performances to those of the control materials that contain only Fe2&#8208;N6 or Ni&#8208;N4 sites. Density functional theory calculations and in situ infrared (IR) spectroscopic studies clearly reveal that the Fe2&#8208;N6 centers are the active sites for both ORR and OER, and their electrocatalytic activities are synergistically enhanced through optimization of their d&#8208;band centers by the Ni&#8208;N4 sites. This ternary&#8208;atom catalyst may be a promising, alternative, sustainable catalyst to commercially used Pt&#8208; and Ru&#8208;based catalysts to drive both ORR and OER in rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries and other related applications.</description>
      <author>Tewodros Asefa, Guiyuan Yang, Meihong Fan, Qing Liang, Xingquan He, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited binder-free oxy-hydroxide nanostructures as promising electrocatalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907102</link>
      <description>Danial Iravani, Ghasem Barati Darband, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405416801

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Danial Iravani, Ghasem Barati Darband</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering for photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00309h</link>
      <description>Yequan Xiao, Jie Fu, Yuriy Pihosh, Keshab Karmakar, Beibei Zhang, Kazunari Domen, Yanbo Li, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405419460

                This comprehensive review provides a holistic overview of recent advances in interface engineering strategies for photoelectrochemical water oxidation, highlighting their role in improving device efficiency and stability.</description>
      <author>Yequan Xiao, Jie Fu, Yuriy Pihosh, Keshab Karmakar, Beibei Zhang, Kazunari Domen, Yanbo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cs00309h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-redox-oriented electrochemical activation strategy enabling enhancement for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101196</link>
      <description>Haojing Zhang, Zhaoyi Jiang, Zhenhua Wu, Shibo Xi, Jiajia Song, Long Xia, Zhichuan J. Xu, Ye Zhou, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405425735

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haojing Zhang, Zhaoyi Jiang, Zhenhua Wu, Shibo Xi, Jiajia Song, Long Xia, Zhichuan J. Xu, Ye Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Correction: Novel synthesis of CuHCF/B-rGO composites for oxygen evolution reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-82947-x</link>
      <description>S. Swathi, R. Yuvakkumar, L. Kungumadevi, G. Ravi, Dhayalan Velauthapillai, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405427966

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Swathi, R. Yuvakkumar, L. Kungumadevi, G. Ravi, Dhayalan Velauthapillai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-82947-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaction Mechanism Investigation of Hematite Photoanodes for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting: Progress of In Situ and Operando Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06448</link>
      <description>Yiping Zhao, Guang-Ping Yi, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Tiger H. Tao, Pengyi Tang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405428911

                Hematite photoanodes, a promising candidate for photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting, are far from reaching their theoretical photocurrent limit. Further designing high-performance hematite-based photoanodes requires an in-depth understanding of the reaction mechanism of PEC water splitting. In situ and operando spectral characterizations facilitate the mechanism investigation, revealing the dynamic surface structures and intermediates of hematite photoanodes during the PEC water splitting process. Herein, in situ and operando spectroscopic techniques were applied for a mechanistic understanding of hematite-based photoanodes in the PEC water splitting system, such as UV&#8211;visible spectroscopy, Raman spectroscopy, infrared spectroscopy, transient absorption spectroscopy, transmission electron microscopy, X-ray absorption spectroscopy, atomic force microscope, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, and electron paramagnetic resonance spectroscopy. The recent progress on charge carrier dynamics and interfacial reaction intermediates of hematite photoanodes for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is summarized. An outlook on challenges and prospects of in situ and operando spectroscopic techniques for PEC water splitting is given. This review will inspire future mechanism investigation of photoanodes for PEC water splitting to achieve higher performance.</description>
      <author>Yiping Zhao, Guang-Ping Yi, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Tiger H. Tao, Pengyi Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Bimetallic NiRu@Ti3C2Tx Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution: The Impact of MXene Content on Ru Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145529</link>
      <description>Merve Buldu&#8208;Akturk, Thorsten Schultz, N. L. Sharma, Ursula Michalczik, Peter Bogdanoff, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405430541

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Merve Buldu&#8208;Akturk, Thorsten Schultz, N. L. Sharma, Ursula Michalczik, Peter Bogdanoff, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Needle-like Heterostructured Sulfide FeS/Ni3S2/NF toward Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178136</link>
      <description>Xiaolian Xu, Congmin Fan, Yang Pan, Tianchen Feng, Hui Lv, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405436600

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaolian Xu, Congmin Fan, Yang Pan, Tianchen Feng, Hui Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonequilibrium-corrosive engineering synthesis of Pt anchored on Fe3O4 with oxygen vacancy for efficient electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.094</link>
      <description>Silu Liu, Huilin Zhao, Hongdong Li, Yingxia Zong, Weiping Xiao, Zhenyu Xiao, Guangrui Xu, Dehong Chen, Guangying Fu, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405442441

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Silu Liu, Huilin Zhao, Hongdong Li, Yingxia Zong, Weiping Xiao, Zhenyu Xiao, Guangrui Xu, Dehong Chen, Guangying Fu, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid Etching Engineering Enhances the Activity of Oxygen Evolution Reaction in High Entropy Perovskite Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5059190</link>
      <description>Kaiteng Wang, Jun Zhou, Xiaoyu Deng, Shuo Wu, Ji Wu, Yuan Gao, Ke Deng, Jiaxi Niu, Kai Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405447736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaiteng Wang, Jun Zhou, Xiaoyu Deng, Shuo Wu, Ji Wu, Yuan Gao, Ke Deng, Jiaxi Niu, Kai Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5059190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effects of SrCeO3-ZnTe heterostructures on oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06640-1</link>
      <description>Kareem Yusuf, Tauseef Munawar, Nadir Abbas, Iram Manzoor, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Zobia Siddique, Jafar Hussain Shah, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405450186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kareem Yusuf, Tauseef Munawar, Nadir Abbas, Iram Manzoor, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Zobia Siddique, Jafar Hussain Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06640-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-alloy Anchored on Spent Coffee Grounds-derived N-doped Carbon Frameworks for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04934a</link>
      <description>Zihan Jia, &#23376;&#20581; &#39640;, Shaokun Zhou, Xinjie Gao, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405452774

                Development of efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction reactions from earth abundant resources is crucial for fuel cells. In this work, the biomass of spent coffee grounds (SCGs) was used as...</description>
      <author>Zihan Jia, &#23376;&#20581; &#39640;, Shaokun Zhou, Xinjie Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04934a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable synthesis of biomimetic wood stem nanoporous high entropy oxides catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907002</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Weiqi Wang, Huihui Wang, Xing Lu, Jinwen Zhang, Yunzhuo Lu, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405456208

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Weiqi Wang, Huihui Wang, Xing Lu, Jinwen Zhang, Yunzhuo Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triggering Oxygen Redox Cycles in Nickel Ferrite by Octahedral Geometry Engineering for Enhancing Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409024</link>
      <description>Yang Peng, Xu Zhao, Yiqun Shao, Xin Yue, Zhuofeng Hu, Shaoming Huang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405457900

                Abstract Spinel&#8208;type nickel ferrite (Ni x Fe 3&#8208;x O 4 , x&#8804;1) is a widely used electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Due to the lower hybridization of metal&#8208; d and oxygen&#8208; p orbitals, the OER process on Ni x Fe 3&#8208;x O 4 follows the sluggish adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM). Generally, activating the lattice oxygen to trigger the lattice&#8208;oxygen&#8208;mediated mechanism (LOM) can enhance the OER activity. Herein, to trigger the LOM pathway while maintaining high stability, iron foam (IF)&#8208;supported Ni 0.75 Fe 2.25 O 4 (NiFeO) with geometrical defects of [NiO 6 ] (nickel cation coordinated with six oxygen anions) units and higher ratio of Fe to Ni cations in octahedral sites ( d &#8208;NiFe HR O/IF) is prepared by ion&#8208;exchanging with polar aprotic solvent followed by annealing. As a result, as&#8208;synthesized d &#8208;NiFe HR O/IF exhibits excellent activity (at 295 mV overpotential to achieve 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ), fast kinetics (Tafel slope of only 34.6 mV dec &#8722;1 ), and high stability (maintaining a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 over 130 h) for the OER. The theoretical calculations reveal that the construction of octahedral defect in Ni x Fe 3&#8208;x O 4 enhances the overlap of Fe&#8208; d and O&#8208; p orbitals, which can activate the lattice oxygen. Therefore, increasing the ratio of Fe to Ni will further improve the lattice oxygen redox activity, and thus trigger the fast LOM pathway, ultimately facilitating the OER process.</description>
      <author>Yang Peng, Xu Zhao, Yiqun Shao, Xin Yue, Zhuofeng Hu, Shaoming Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earth-abundant electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01266-6</link>
      <description>Rendian Wan, Tenghui Yuan, Liuchen Wang, Bing Li, Meilin Liu, Bote Zhao, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405459584

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rendian Wan, Tenghui Yuan, Liuchen Wang, Bing Li, Meilin Liu, Bote Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01266-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure-Selection Dynamics of Cobalt Nanoparticles from Solution Synthesis and Their Impact on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c13143</link>
      <description>Greta R. Patzke, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, L.A. Reith, Kenneth P. Marshall, Wouter van Beek, Carlos A. Triana, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405465463

                Resolving the three-dimensional structure of transition metal oxide nanoparticles (TMO-NPs), upon self-restructuring from solution, is crucial for tuning their structure&#8211;functionality. Yet, this remains challenging as this process entails complex structure fluctuations, which are difficult to track experimentally and, hence, hinder the knowledge-driven optimization of TMO-NPs. Herein, we combine high-energy synchrotron X-ray absorption and X-ray total scattering experiments with atomistic multiscale simulations to investigate the self-restructuring of self-assembled Co-NPs from solution under dark or photocatalytic water oxidation conditions at distinct reaction times and atomic length-scales. Using the atomic range order as a descriptor, we reveal that dissolution of a Co-salt in BO3 buffer leads to a self-optimization route forming disordered oxyborate Co3BOx-NPs unveiling a high oxygen yield due to the formation of surface oxo/hydroxo adsorbates. Those Co3BOx-NPs further self-restructure into distorted Co3O4-NPs and, lastly, into distorted CoOOH-NPs through a rate-limiting step integrating Co3+-states during the course of a representative photocatalytic assay. Self-restructuring does not proceed from amorphous-to-ordered states but through stochastic fluctuations of atomic nanoclusters of &#8776;10 &#197; domain size. Our key insight into the structure-selection dynamics of TMO-NPs from solution offers a route for tuning their structure&#8211;function relationships for wide-ranging emergent technologies.</description>
      <author>Greta R. Patzke, Florian Keller, Marcella Iannuzzi, L.A. Reith, Kenneth P. Marshall, Wouter van Beek, Carlos A. Triana</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c13143</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge&#8208;Induced Synergy of Ni&#8208;Ni Defects in NiFe Layered&#8208;Double&#8208;Hydroxide for Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408266</link>
      <description>Rongrong Zhang, Qilong Wu, Yun Han, Yaowen Zhang, Xiaofeng Wu, Jianrong Zeng, Keke Huang, Aijun Du, Jun Chen, Dong Zhou, Xiangdong Yao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405466389

                Abstract Defect engineering is widely regarded as a promising strategy to enhance the performance of electrocatalysts for water splitting. In this work, defective NiFe layered double hydroxide (NiFe LDH) with a high density of edge sites (edge&#8208;rich NiFe LDH) is synthesized via a simple reduction process during the early stages of nucleation. The introduction of edges into oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts modulates the electronic structure of the active sites. X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) analyses revealed that the edges facilitated the formation of unsaturated Ni&#8208;Ni coordination, which is crucial for promoting the deprotonation of the OH * intermediate. Consequently, the edge&#8208;rich NiFe LDH exhibited a significantly lower overpotential of 228 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 , compared to 275 mV for pristine NiFe LDH. The assembled membrane electrode can reach a current density of 1000 mA cm&#8315; 2 at a cell voltage of 2.5 V. This study highlights the role of edge effects in defect engineering to enhance OER activity and provides valuable theoretical insights for the design of efficient electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Rongrong Zhang, Qilong Wu, Yun Han, Yaowen Zhang, Xiaofeng Wu, Jianrong Zeng, Keke Huang, Aijun Du, Jun Chen, Dong Zhou, Xiangdong Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Synergistic Role of Sm&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;3+&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Doped NiFe&#8208;LDH as High&#8208;Performance Electrocatalysts for Improved Anion Exchange Membrane and Water Splitting Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401655</link>
      <description>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Hemalatha Gurusamy, Harpriya Minhas, Arun Karmakar, S. Ravichandran, Biswarup Pathak, Subrata Kundu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476280

                Abstract Effective first&#8208;row transition metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts are crucial for large&#8208;scale hydrogen energy generation and anion exchange membrane (AEM) devices in water splitting. The present work describes that SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH nanosheets on nickel foam are used as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting and AEM water electrolyzer study. Tuning the Ni&#8208;to&#8208;Fe ratios in NiFe&#8208;LDH and doping with Sm ions improves the electrical structure and intrinsic activity. SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH has higher oxygen evolution reaction (OER), HER, and TWS activity, achieving 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 current density at lower overpotentials (230 mV, 95 mV, and 1.62 V, respectively). In AEMWE cells, SmNi 0.02 Fe&#8208;LDH as a cathode and anode pair exhibits outstanding activity (0.9 A cm&#8315; 2 at 2 V) and stability over 120 h. Density Functional Theory (DFT) investigations reveal that the Sm doping in NiFe&#8208;LDH surface enhances its bifunctional activity toward OER and HER. These findings emphasize the potential of non&#8208;noble composites for long&#8208;term water electrolysis in total water splitting and AEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Sreenivasan Nagappan, Hemalatha Gurusamy, Harpriya Minhas, Arun Karmakar, S. Ravichandran, Biswarup Pathak, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart Compositional Design of B&#8208;Site Ordered Double Perovskite for Advanced Oxygen Catalysis at Ultra&#8208;High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401480</link>
      <description>Maria Christy, Jiseok Kwon, S. Subramanian, Seunggun Choi, Junghyun Choi, Jung Ho Kim, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476385

                Abstract Perovskite oxides have been considered promising oxygen catalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER), owing to structural and compositional flexibility, and tailorable properties. Ingenious B&#8208;site ordered La 1.5 Sr 0.5 NiMn 0.5 Fe 0.5 O 6 (LSNMF) double perovskite is strategically designed by simultaneously interposing Ni 0.5 Mn 0.5 and Ni 0.5 Fe 0.5 into B&#8242; and B&#8243; sites. Controlling B&#8208;site cation systematically tailors the electronic structure of the B&#8208;site cation with a d&#8208;band center (M d ) upshift close to the Fermi level, increasing the overlap of the M d center and O 2p center (O P ). The strong interaction of M d and O p facilitates the adsorption of oxygen and activates the lattice oxygen to participate in the OER process, thereby enhancing the ORR and OER activity. For ORR, LSNMF exhibited an onset potential of 0.9 V along with a high limiting current of &#8722;8.05 mA cm &#8722;2 . At the same time, for OER at 1 m KOH, LSNMF effectively reached a maximum current density of 3000 mA cm &#8722;2 . Most importantly, the difference between E ORR (at &#8722;1 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and E OER (at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), &#916;E is 0.69 V, which stands among the best of recently reported perovskites. The as&#8208;designed LSNMF is stable, efficient, lucrative, and a promising candidate for practical application.</description>
      <author>Maria Christy, Jiseok Kwon, S. Subramanian, Seunggun Choi, Junghyun Choi, Jung Ho Kim, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Electronic Interaction with Oxygen Vacancies Enriched Cobalt-Oxide Support Boost the CO Production Yield of Nickel-Hydroxide Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202412.1129.v1</link>
      <description>Dinesh Bhalothia, Tingbi Li, Amisha Beniwal, Jagdish Parihar, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405477533

                The catalytic conversion of carbon dioxide (CO2) into carbon monoxide (CO) via the reverse water-gas shift (RWGS) reaction offers a promising pathway toward a sustainable carbon cycle. However, the competing Sabatier reaction presents a significant challenge, underscoring the need for highly efficient catalysts. In this study, we developed a novel catalyst comprising cobalt-oxide-supported nickel-hydroxide nanoparticles (denoted as Co@Ni). This catalyst achieved a remarkable CO production yield of ~5,144 &amp;mu;mol gcatalyst&#8315;&amp;sup1; at 573 K, with a CO selectivity of 77%. These values represent 30% and 70% improvements over carbon-supported Ni(OH)2 (Ni-AC) and CoO (Co-AC) nanoparticles, respectively. Comprehensive physical characterizations and electrochemical analyses reveal that the exceptional CO yield of the Co@Ni catalyst stems from the synergistic electronic interactions between adjacent active sites. Specifically, cobalt-oxide domains act as electron donors to Ni sites, facilitating efficient H2 splitting. Additionally, the oxygen vacancies in cobalt oxide enhance CO2 adsorption and promote subsequent dissociation. These findings provide critical insights into the design of highly efficient and selective catalysts for the RWGS reaction, paving the way for advancements in sustainable carbon utilization technologies.</description>
      <author>Dinesh Bhalothia, Tingbi Li, Amisha Beniwal, Jagdish Parihar, Tsan&#8208;Yao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202412.1129.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CATALYTIC ACTIVITY OF CONSTITUENT LAYERS OF MULTILAYER COATINGS BASED ON NI-ZN-CU ALLOYS IN THE OXYGEN EVOLUTION REACTION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32782/2663-5941/2024.5.2/06</link>
      <description>&#1040;.O. Maizelis, Scientific notes of Taurida National V I Vernadsky University Series Technical Sciences. 2(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405486192

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#1040;.O. Maizelis</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32782/2663-5941/2024.5.2/06</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering of NiVP/Fe+2Fe2+3O4 heterostructure for highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105650</link>
      <description>Yufeng Li, Rui Deng, Wei Gao, Weiwei Tang, Zhe Zhang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405492189

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yufeng Li, Rui Deng, Wei Gao, Weiwei Tang, Zhe Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of Fe Adsorption and Desorption from CoO&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;H&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; During Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04777</link>
      <description>Lu Liu, Liam Twight, Shibo Xi, Yingqing Ou, Shannon W. Boettcher, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405500679

                Iron plays a central and critical role in the water oxidation mechanism and the activity of transition-metal oxides and (oxy)hydroxides. Tracking Fe dynamics (deposition/dissolution/electrolyte transport) and unraveling the chemistries of various Fe active sites under oxygen-evolution reaction (OER) conditions are important for catalyst design, particularly for applications in alkaline electrolysis. Here, we use CoOxHy thin films as a platform to investigate Fe transport and reactivity at the catalyst-electrolyte interface and its impact on OER activity. We find that the deposition/dissolution of the surface-absorbed Fe species is governed by the transport of soluble Fe species and applied potential. Soluble Fe species in the electrolyte adsorb on CoOxHy under stirred electrolyte conditions. Accelerated Fe desorption is observed with a more-positive OER potential. The surface-localized Fe sites generated by absorption from soluble Fe species have a higher OER turnover frequency (TOFFe) compared to Fe in codeposited CoFeOxHy films. Operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy shows structural similarity between reference Fe oxyhydroxides and surface Fe sites on CoOxHy, contrasting with Fe sites within the CoOxHy structure made by codeposition, where Fe shows a different apparent X-ray absorption edge energy. The OER activity of the surface-absorbed Fe decreased by Fe desorption but was recoverable by redepositing Fe species under non-OER conditions.</description>
      <author>Lu Liu, Liam Twight, Shibo Xi, Yingqing Ou, Shannon W. Boettcher</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual&#8208;Doping Strategy for Lowering the Thermal Expansion Coefficient and Promoting the Catalytic Activity in Perovskite Cobaltate Air Electrodes for Solid Oxide Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410672</link>
      <description>Shijie Wang, Xiaoxin Zhang, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Fan Fan, Jiang Chang, Yongkang Xiang, Xiao Xiao, Yuan Fang, Abdullah Alodhayb, Jianhui Li, Jijie Huang, Yifei Sun, Zhou Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405502836

                Lowering the thermal expansion coefficient (TEC) and promoting the catalytic activity of cobalt-based perovskite air electrodes is crucial for efficient solid oxide cells (SOCs) devices. However, the co-achievement of both merits has usually been largely compromised in most scenarios. Herein, a dual-doping strategy to manipulate the properties of perovskite cobaltate electrocatalyst is reported in which a high valence element of Ta</description>
      <author>Shijie Wang, Xiaoxin Zhang, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Fan Fan, Jiang Chang, Yongkang Xiang, Xiao Xiao, Yuan Fang, Abdullah Alodhayb, Jianhui Li, Jijie Huang, Yifei Sun, Zhou Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of Lanthanum-Based Perovskites for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction at Industrial Conditions for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vm3q9</link>
      <description>Fabian Luca Buchauer, S&#248;ren Bredmose Simonsen, Mikael Jensen, Ivano E. Castelli, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405504330

                Perovskites are broadly considered a promising class of catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. In particular, lanthanum-based perovskites, like La0.75Sr0.25MnO3-&#948; (LSMO), LaFeO3-&#948; (LFO), La0.6Sr0.4Fe0.98O3-&#948; (LSFO), La0.6Sr0.4Fe0.8Co0.2O3-&#948; (LSCFO) and La0.6Sr0.4Co0.99O3-&#948; (LSCO), have been researched as catalysts for the OER showing high catalytic activity. Stability assessment, on the other hand, is rarely carried out at industrial operating conditions, despite it being a precondition for industrial uptake. In this study, the material stability and intrinsic activity were evaluated at industrial alkaline water electrolysis conditions. LSMO showed high activity but instability due to Mn leaching. LSCFO and LFO demonstrated high activity at 75&#176;C, but computational Pourbaix diagrams of both LFO and LSCFO predict instability at the operational potential window, which was confirmed during long-term stability testing. The overall findings highlight the importance of long-term testing at industrial operating conditions, as stability investigations at mild laboratory conditions are insufficient to qualify a candidate catalyst for industrial uptake.</description>
      <author>Fabian Luca Buchauer, S&#248;ren Bredmose Simonsen, Mikael Jensen, Ivano E. Castelli, Christodoulos Chatzichristodoulou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vm3q9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance by Anchoring Iridium Oxide Nanoparticles on Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18974</link>
      <description>Gege Tao, Zhi-Qiang Wang, Xiaohui Liu, Yanqin Wang, Yong Guo, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405508149

                The sluggish kinetics of the anodic process, known as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), has posed a significant challenge for the practical application of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers in industrial settings. This study introduces a high-performance OER catalyst by anchoring iridium oxide nanoparticles (IrO</description>
      <author>Gege Tao, Zhi-Qiang Wang, Xiaohui Liu, Yanqin Wang, Yong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c18974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrated Electrocatalysis: To Boost the Selectivity for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06083</link>
      <description>Pichaikkaran Raja, P G Vishnu, Tanmay Kumar Panigrahi, Ravi Sankannavar, Sai Phani Kumar Vangala, Ijjada Mahesh, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405509114

                The increase in the production of renewable electricity offers the opportunity to transition from the usage of fossil-based hydrogen to green hydrogen. While mass production of green hydrogen by water electrolysis demands substantial freshwater resources, the abundant availability of seawater provides a promising opportunity to directly use it as an electrolyte in a water electrolyzer. However, a major challenge in seawater electrolysis is the low selectivity for oxygen evolution compared to the chlorine evolution at the anode. To address this, we proposed a strategy to boost the selectivity for oxygen evolution by hydrated electrocatalysis, in which water is itself part of the catalyst. Water molecules that are coordinately bonded to the active catalytic sites play a significant role in enhancing oxygen evolution selectivity. This approach was demonstrated with Prussian blue analogue electrocatalysts in acidified simulated seawater electrolyte using rotating ring disk electrode voltammetry. Microkinetic modeling was employed to correlate the coverage by the reactants (H2O and Cl&#8211;) with selectivity. Notably, the crystal water coverage on hydrated electrocatalysts emerged as the partial descriptor for the selectivity of the oxygen evolution reaction. To gain insights for coverage by crystal water and Cl&#8211;, the thermogravimetric analysis combined with Rietveld refinement and microkinetic Tafel analysis was performed. In a nutshell, we explored the question: if the reactant molecule (H2O) is an integral part of the catalyst, can it promote the corresponding electrochemical oxidation reaction (O2 evolution) over its competitor (Cl2 evolution)?</description>
      <author>Pichaikkaran Raja, P G Vishnu, Tanmay Kumar Panigrahi, Ravi Sankannavar, Sai Phani Kumar Vangala, Ijjada Mahesh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral 2d Flakes with Single Atoms Inclusion for Spin-Controlled Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5063154</link>
      <description>Denis Zabelin, Anastasiia Tulupova, Peter &#352;vec, Alena Michalcov&#225;, Vasilii Burtsev, Marie Urbanov&#225;, Philipp H&#246;nicke, Vladislav Buravet, Tom&#225;&#353; Hrbek, Anastasia Skvortsova, Anna Zabelina, V&#225;clav &#352;vor&#269;&#305;&#769;k, Oleksiy Lyutakov, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405515183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Denis Zabelin, Anastasiia Tulupova, Peter &#352;vec, Alena Michalcov&#225;, Vasilii Burtsev, Marie Urbanov&#225;, Philipp H&#246;nicke, Vladislav Buravet, Tom&#225;&#353; Hrbek, Anastasia Skvortsova, Anna Zabelina, V&#225;clav &#352;vor&#269;&#305;&#769;k, Oleksiy Lyutakov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5063154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological modulation of Co-based Zeolitic imidazolate framework for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.11.036</link>
      <description>Haryeong Choi, Jiseung Kim, Taehee Kim, Vinayak G. Parale, Won&#8208;Jun Lee, Hyeon Heo, Hyung&#8208;Ho Park, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405515486

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haryeong Choi, Jiseung Kim, Taehee Kim, Vinayak G. Parale, Won&#8208;Jun Lee, Hyeon Heo, Hyung&#8208;Ho Park</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.11.036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantity effect of heteroatom incorporation on the oxygen evolution mechanism in ruthenium oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chempr.2024.11.005</link>
      <description>Hyunwoo Jun, Eunseo Kang, Jinuk Moon, Hoyoung Kim, Sunghoon Han, Seokhyun Choung, Seongbeen Kim, Seung Yeop Yi, Eunae Kang, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jeong Woo Han, Jinwoo Lee, Chem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405367030

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyunwoo Jun, Eunseo Kang, Jinuk Moon, Hoyoung Kim, Sunghoon Han, Seokhyun Choung, Seongbeen Kim, Seung Yeop Yi, Eunae Kang, Chang Hyuck Choi, Jeong Woo Han, Jinwoo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chempr.2024.11.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur&#8211;vacancy engineering of Co9S8&#8211;x/Ti3C2Tx&#8211;MXene catalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.118</link>
      <description>Liang Chen, Xinrui Li, Xu Liu, Liting Zeng, Yun Peng, Chenxi Xu, Shuangshuang Ren, Wei Wang, Zhaohui Hou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405494329

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang Chen, Xinrui Li, Xu Liu, Liting Zeng, Yun Peng, Chenxi Xu, Shuangshuang Ren, Wei Wang, Zhaohui Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic Conductive Metal Organic Framework Nanorods with Atomically Dispersed Fe and Co Sites for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00480</link>
      <description>Longxiang Wang, Jiahao Wang, Jiaxiang Man, Meiling Dou, Feng Wang, ACS Applied Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405499031

                Exploring efficient nonpyrolysis conductive metal organic frameworks with high intrinsic reactivity is critical for their application in the electrocatalytic field. Herein, we present electronically conductive &#960;-d-conjugated Co and Fe bimetallic MOF-CoFe-hexahydroxytriphenylene (CoFe-HHTP) nanorods with atomically dispersed Co&#8211;O6 and Fe&#8211;O6 sites for efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysis. The introduction of Fe not only increases the electronic conductivity of Co-HHTP with an order of magnitude favoring the electronic transfer during OER catalysis but also tailors the electronic structure of Co, leading to a downshift of Co d-band center that weakens the adsorption of oxygen intermediates on Co sites. As a result, the as-prepared CoFe-HHTP exhibits a significantly improved OER activity showing a lower overpotential (316 mV) at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in an alkaline electrolyte compared with pure Co-HHTP (370 mV), outperforming commercial RuO2 (329 mV). CoFe-HHTP also displays a superior electrochemical durability with only a slight change of potential after a 200 h test at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, outperforming pure Co-HHTP (140 h). The improved durability was due to the hindered dissolution of Co by suppressing structural transformation in the presence of Fe in the alkaline electrolyte. When CoFe-HHTP was used as the anode catalyst, a superior alkaline electrolyzer performance was obtained with a cell voltage of 1.821 V at 500 mA cm&#8211;2 and a stable operation of 50 h. This methodology offers insights into the design and synthesis of conductive MOF-based catalysts for efficient OER catalysis.</description>
      <author>Longxiang Wang, Jiahao Wang, Jiaxiang Man, Meiling Dou, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal atom supported on N-terminated diamond (100) surface as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution and reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242133</link>
      <description>Gaoxian Li, Yuanhang Wang, Nan Gao, Hongdong Li, Applied Physics Letters. 125(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405323235

                To alleviate the increasingly serious energy issues, it is essential to develop highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we employed density functional theory to investigate a broad spectrum of transition metal (TM = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Y, Zr, Mo, Ru, Rh, Ag, W, Ir, and Pt) atoms supported on N-terminated diamond (100) surface (TM@ND) as single-atom catalysts for their OER and ORR performances. TM atoms (Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Y, Zr, and Ir) show large binding energy with substrate and thermal stability, which is advantageous for electrocatalytic reactions. Especially, Ir@ND demonstrates high efficacy as an OER electrocatalyst, and Mn@ND is identified as an efficient ORR electrocatalyst, exhibiting the theoretical overpotentials smaller than 1 V. Consequently, it suggests that diamond-based catalysts could serve as promising candidates for energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Gaoxian Li, Yuanhang Wang, Nan Gao, Hongdong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392818

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392894

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392952

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Chenguang Liu, Yue Han, Jinrui Guo, Wenqi Gao, Jiaqing Wang, Bin He, Xi Wang, Weiming L&#252;, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenguang Liu, Yue Han, Jinrui Guo, Wenqi Gao, Jiaqing Wang, Bin He, Xi Wang, Weiming L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405393013

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C-modified amorphous NiFe alloy nanoparticle via simple room temperature fermentation for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907019</link>
      <description>Yanzhen Qiu, Lu Pan, Huimin Jiang, Mohammed A. Amin, Jianjian Lin, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405416182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanzhen Qiu, Lu Pan, Huimin Jiang, Mohammed A. Amin, Jianjian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus solvation induced deep reconstruction of phosphorus-doped nickel-iron oxyhydroxides towards efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158701</link>
      <description>Shengnan Tian, Zhiwei Li, Hongyu Wang, Xiaohang Du, Guihua Liu, Jingde Li, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405494993

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengnan Tian, Zhiwei Li, Hongyu Wang, Xiaohang Du, Guihua Liu, Jingde Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Reconstruction of the Fe-O-Co Interface Regulates the Active Co Sites of Cofe-Ldh with Decorated Feooh for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5060970</link>
      <description>Li Yingwei, Wei Wang, En Wang, Kuan&#8208;Guan Liu, Xudong Song, Baojun Ma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Yingwei, Wei Wang, En Wang, Kuan&#8208;Guan Liu, Xudong Song, Baojun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5060970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction: Construction of efficient Pb(&lt;scp&gt;ii&lt;/scp&gt;) carboxylate catalysts for the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90216e</link>
      <description>Janak, Vijay S. Sapner, Bhaskar R. Sathe, Sadhika Khullar, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405316906

                Correction for &#8216;Construction of efficient Pb( ii ) carboxylate catalysts for the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions&#8217; by Janak et al. , Dalton Trans. , 2024, https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02958e.</description>
      <author>Janak, Vijay S. Sapner, Bhaskar R. Sathe, Sadhika Khullar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90216e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of the diatomic-site electronic structure with alloy nanoparticles in hollow carbon nanospheres for efficient oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158579</link>
      <description>Yuxuan Liang, Dingyu Zhang, Yuan Zhang, Fengfeng Yan, Liang Sun, Xinyue Jin, Wei Wang, Lirong Zheng, Wei Li, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405316643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxuan Liang, Dingyu Zhang, Yuan Zhang, Fengfeng Yan, Liang Sun, Xinyue Jin, Wei Wang, Lirong Zheng, Wei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoPc-based donor-acceptor covalent organic frameworks with charge transfer for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.100</link>
      <description>Ruichen Li, Yang Tian, Jingjing Zhang, Ziang Xu, Shujun Chao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405328760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruichen Li, Yang Tian, Jingjing Zhang, Ziang Xu, Shujun Chao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stage development characteristics of oxygen-lean combustion of coal in fire zone. Part I: The evolution law of pyrolysis and combustion stage characteristics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10973-024-13865-3</link>
      <description>Guangyu Bai, Haihui Xin, Yi Yang, Junzhe Li, Xuyao Qi, Shouxin Zhang, Jiakun Wang, Jinhu Liu, Liyang Ma, Journal of Thermal Analysis and Calorimetry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405389716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guangyu Bai, Haihui Xin, Yi Yang, Junzhe Li, Xuyao Qi, Shouxin Zhang, Jiakun Wang, Jinhu Liu, Liyang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10973-024-13865-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; characterization techniques: main tools for revealing OER/ORR catalytic mechanism and reaction dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02179g</link>
      <description>Siqi Wu, Zexin Liang, Tianshi Wang, Xiaobin Liu, Shaobo Huang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405498245

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are some of the most important reactions in electrochemical energy technologies such as fuel cells and metal&#8211;air cells.</description>
      <author>Siqi Wu, Zexin Liang, Tianshi Wang, Xiaobin Liu, Shaobo Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02179g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing *&lt;scp&gt;OH&lt;/scp&gt; intermediate by fabricating &lt;scp&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;&lt;scp&gt;MoN&lt;/scp&gt; for scalable 5&#8208;hydroxymethylfurfural electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18690</link>
      <description>Shaowei Yang, Ying Guo, Jing Wang, Runze Gao, Zhi&#8208;Min Liao, Haidong Shen, Haoxi Wang, Lifeng Jiang, Buxing Han, Qiuyu Zhang, Hepeng Zhang, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405372360

                Abstract Achieving large&#8208;scale coupling of organic electrooxidation and the hydrogen evolution reaction, while understanding the competition between organic electrooxidation and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), is a significant challenge. In this study, using Ni 3 N&#8208;MoN/NF, an efficient heterojunction electrocatalyst as both anode and cathode in a 50 cm 2 continuous flow reactor, we achieved a total current of ~20 A at 2.6 V. This resulted in the highest single&#8208;pass 5&#8208;hydroxymethylfurfural conversion efficiency (0.049 mmol cm &#8722;2 min &#8722;1 ) and gram&#8208;level production of 2,5&#8208;furandicarboxylic acid. Theoretical studies revealed that MoN accelerated *OH formation and increased its deprotonation energy barrier, leading to *OH accumulation, effectively promoting organic electrooxidation and inhibiting OER. We anticipate that our foundation in understanding the reaction mechanism and catalyst design strategy can be extended to a wider range of anodic oxidation reactions.</description>
      <author>Shaowei Yang, Ying Guo, Jing Wang, Runze Gao, Zhi&#8208;Min Liao, Haidong Shen, Haoxi Wang, Lifeng Jiang, Buxing Han, Qiuyu Zhang, Hepeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral Metal Coating to Enhance Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04304</link>
      <description>Deb Kumar Bhowmick, Nir Yuran, Michael Fadeev, Shira Yochelis, Yossi Paltiel, Ron Naaman, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405431240

                Producing hydrogen through water splitting often faces challenges of overpotential, stability, and expensive catalysts, which limit its efficiency and hinder the advancement of hydrogen production technologies. Nickel foam and nickel meshes have emerged as promising materials for electrolyzer electrodes due to their high surface area and the ability to produce electrolyzers with a very small gap between the anode and cathode. This study presents a simple method for coating Ni-based electrodes with a chiral Ni&#8211;Au film, using electroplating, thus enhancing its efficiency dramatically. We introduce chirality to the electroplating layer by incorporating an enantiopure chiral reagent into the electroplating solution. The chiral layer enhances the oxygen evolution reaction due to the chiral-induced spin selectivity effect. By optimizing the chiral electroplating process, we demonstrate the reduction of the overpotential and an increase in the reaction efficiency by 95% at 1 M KOH at room temperature.</description>
      <author>Deb Kumar Bhowmick, Nir Yuran, Michael Fadeev, Shira Yochelis, Yossi Paltiel, Ron Naaman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Integration of Binary Functional Species Endows Directionally Optimized Kinetics for CoNiSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Based High-Performance Supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02565</link>
      <description>Qingjie Lu, Tong Zhou, Mingpeng Chen, Jianhong Zhao, Huachuan Sun, Bo Li, Baoye Zi, Jin Zhang, Zhongqi Zhu, Qingju Liu, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405366794

                Side reactions of water decomposition and capacitive reactions occur concomitantly in aqueous supercapacitors. To improve the energy density, integrated design modifications to address the impact of these two aspects on the reaction kinetics are theoretically effective. Herein, a two-step modification strategy for introducing binary functional species is designed to regulate the chemical environment and electronic structure of the metal active sites and further optimize the electrochemical kinetics comprehensively. For promoting the capacitive reactions, Ag nanoparticles were loaded to decrease the corresponding energy barriers. For suppressing the oxygen evolution side reaction, preintercalation of K+ ions was realized to increase the corresponding energy barriers. The assembled supercapacitor device shows an ultrahigh energy density of 143.2 Wh kg&#8211;1. Uniquely, in situ techniques, DFT calculations, and overpotential tests are combined to verify the suppression mechanism. This work provides valuable guidance for coordinating designs and studies on the electrochemical kinetics of transition-metal-based electrode materials.</description>
      <author>Qingjie Lu, Tong Zhou, Mingpeng Chen, Jianhong Zhao, Huachuan Sun, Bo Li, Baoye Zi, Jin Zhang, Zhongqi Zhu, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture and functional regulation of a plant PSII-LHCII megacomplex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq9967</link>
      <description>Jianyu Shan, Dariusz M. Niedzwiedzki, Rupal Singh Tomar, Zhenfeng Liu, Haijun Liu, Science Advances. 10(50)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405361367

                Photosystem II (PSII) splits water in oxygenic photosynthesis on Earth. The structure and function of the C 4 S 4 M 2 -type PSII-LHCII (light-harvesting complex II) megacomplexes from the wild-type and PsbR-deletion mutant plants are studied through electron microscopy (EM), structural mass spectrometry, and ultrafast fluorescence spectroscopy [time-resolved fluorescence (TRF)]. The cryo-EM structure of a type I C 4 S 4 M 2 megacomplex demonstrates that the three domains of PsbR bind to the stromal side of D1, D2, and CP43; associate with the single transmembrane helix of the redox active Cyt b 559 ; and stabilize the luminal extrinsic PsbP, respectively. This megacomplex, with PsbR and PsbY centered around the narrow interface between two dimeric PSII cores, provides the supramolecular structural basis that regulates the plastoquinone occupancy in Q B site, excitation energy transfer, and oxygen evolution. PSII-LHCII megacomplexes (types I and II) and LHC aggregation levels in Arabidopsis psbR mutant were also interrogated and compared to wild-type plants through EM and picosecond TRF.</description>
      <author>Jianyu Shan, Dariusz M. Niedzwiedzki, Rupal Singh Tomar, Zhenfeng Liu, Haijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq9967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation&#8208;Vacancy&#8208;Induced Reinforced Electrochemical Surface Reconstruction on Spinel Nickel Ferrite for Boosting Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417983</link>
      <description>Yuxin Li, Shouxin Zhang, Chun Guang Li, Xiangyan Hou, Jianrong Zeng, Xiaobo Chen, Zhan Shi, Shouhua Feng, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405421736

                Abstract Spinel oxides still exhibit unsatisfactory electrocatalytic performance toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER) given their low intrinsic activity, poor electronic conductivity, and limited exposure of reaction sites. Defect engineering has garnered intensive attention and become a promising strategy to enhance the reaction kinetics. In this work, spinel NiFe 2 O 4 nanospheres with rich nickel vacancies are prepared via simple one&#8208;pot hydrothermal synthesis. Combined electrochemical measurements and in situ Raman characterization prove that a relatively higher degree of electrochemical surface reconstruction is realized after the introduction of nickel vacancies in NiFe 2 O 4 , in addition to boosted OER electrocatalytic performance. Further theoretical calculations also reveal that the cation&#8208;vacancy&#8208;induced effect can reduce the difficulty for surface reconstruction by increasing the octahedral nickel&#8208;oxygen covalency in nickel ferrite. Contributed to the great structural flexibility and optimized electronic structure of the pre&#8208;catalyst, the reconstructed electrocatalyst presents desirable OER performance, accompanied by long durability in alkaline solution. This work provides a sound strategy to intensify surface reconstruction on spinel oxides and design electrocatalysts with high efficiency toward water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Yuxin Li, Shouxin Zhang, Chun Guang Li, Xiangyan Hou, Jianrong Zeng, Xiaobo Chen, Zhan Shi, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orientation Engineering of Nanoporous BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanodes Toward Boosted Glycerol Valorization and Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418294</link>
      <description>Zihao Wu, Kexin Ren, Jiayi Zhou, Shouxin Zhang, Limin Qi, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405455662

                Abstract Photoelectrocatalysis has the capability to utilize solar energy to produce hydrogen and valuable chemicals; however, their conversion efficiency remains to reach practical thresholds. Here, a rapid&#8208;ramping annealing strategy is reported to synthesize nanoporous Mo&#8208;doped bismuth vanadate (MBVO) photoanodes with (001)&#8208;preferred orientation. This approach leverages the enhanced carrier transport along the crystallographic [001] direction, optimizing the bulk photoelectrical properties of the MBVO photoanodes. By substituting the surface oxygen evolution reaction with the glycerol oxidation reaction, the photoconversion efficiency is significantly boosted, reaching a photocurrent density of 7.45 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V versus RHE and an incident photon&#8208;to&#8208;current conversion efficiency of &#8776;100% for hydrogen generation, accompanied by the production of value&#8208;added products in a high rate (&#8776;1700 mmol m &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 in total) with a total Faradaic efficiency up to 96%. These results shed light on the construction of practical photoelectrocatalysis systems by demonstrating the potential of bulk&#8208;phase engineering coupled with surface reaction design.</description>
      <author>Zihao Wu, Kexin Ren, Jiayi Zhou, Shouxin Zhang, Limin Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction Induced by Preconditioning in Different Electrolytes Impacts Electrooxidation of Solketal on Multi&#8208;Metal&#8208;Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419911</link>
      <description>Jian Zhang, Bhawana Kumari, Thomas Quast, Steffen Cychy, Ignacio Sanju&#225;n, Martin Muhler, Wolfgang Schuhmann, Corina Andronescu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405384345

                Abstract The electrocatalytic oxidation of solketal (SOR) as the anodic reaction can be used to enhance hydrogen production efficiency due to its lower overpotential compared to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Additionally, solketal oxidation yields besides formate also high&#8208;value C 3 products, providing an advantage over the typical alternative reaction for OER, glycerol oxidation. The multi&#8208;metal CoNiFeCu (1:1:1:0.5) catalyst is employed as electrocatalyst for SOR and different activation procedures are explored. The pre&#8208;conditioning of the catalyst in the presence of solketal supports a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 to be recorded at only 1.405 &#177; 1 mV versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs. RHE) during SOR, while promoting glyceric acid synthesis with 40% faradaic efficiency. Operando attenuated total reflection Fourier&#8208;transform infrared spectroscopy (ATR&#8208;FTIR) confirms that the activation of the catalyst contributes to an increased formation of products. However, most importantly, through utilizing the single&#8208;particle&#8208;on&#8208;the&#8208;nanoelectrode with identical&#8208;location transmission electron microscope (IL&#8208;TEM), it is unveiled that solketal suppresses Cu leaching and oxyhydroxide formation. Moreover, the structural transformations are correlated with the increased activity toward SOR.</description>
      <author>Jian Zhang, Bhawana Kumari, Thomas Quast, Steffen Cychy, Ignacio Sanju&#225;n, Martin Muhler, Wolfgang Schuhmann, Corina Andronescu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419911</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Integration of a Ru(bda)&#8208;Based Catalyst in a Covalent Organic Framework for Enhanced Photocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400653</link>
      <description>Marina Sicignano, Thomas Gobbato, Ruggero Bonetto, Paolo Centomo, Biagio Di Vizio, Federico De Biasi, Daniele Rosa&#8208;Gastaldo, Chiara Pierantoni, Alessandro Bonetto, Antonella Glisenti, Paolo Costa, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405455197

                Abstract To address the urgent need for sustainable energy processes, there is a growing demand for multifunctional materials that mimic natural photosynthetic enzyme functions, specifically light&#8208;harvesting, efficient photoinduced charge separation, and integration of molecularly defined catalysts, synergistically interacting within these structures. Herein, the successful synthesis of an innovative Covalent Organic Framework ( COF&#8208;TFPT&#8208;IsoQ ) constructed from optically active triazine (TFPT) and isoquinoline units (IsoQ) as building blocks is reported. Post&#8208;synthetic incorporation of a Ru(bda)&#8208;based water oxidation catalyst (WOC) is achieved through the IsoQ moieties acting as coordinating sites. Leveraging the synthetic flexibility of the designed COF architecture featuring binding sites on its pore walls, various Ru@COF&#8208;TFPT&#8208;IsoQ systems at different Ru:COF ratios are synthesized and tested in the photoinduced (&#955; &gt; 400 nm) oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under sacrificial conditions. All synthesized Ru@COF&#8208;TFPT&#8208;IsoQ systems demonstrate efficiency in the photocatalytic OER, with the highest turnover number (TON) of 9.1 observed for the system where the Ru&#8208;based WOC is incorporated every fourth COF&#8208;TFPT&#8208;IsoQ unit cell. This work provides valuable insights into the structural integration and catalytic behavior of Ru&#8208;based complexes within COF architectures, highlighting the potential of Ru@COF&#8208;TFPT&#8208;IsoQ as a robust, efficient, and synthetically flexible multifunctional material for light&#8208;induced water oxidation catalysis.</description>
      <author>Marina Sicignano, Thomas Gobbato, Ruggero Bonetto, Paolo Centomo, Biagio Di Vizio, Federico De Biasi, Daniele Rosa&#8208;Gastaldo, Chiara Pierantoni, Alessandro Bonetto, Antonella Glisenti, Paolo Costa</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400653</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Adapting Oxyanion Armor Achieves Highly Stable and Efficient Seawater Electrolysis at Ampere&#8208;Level Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418940</link>
      <description>Xingheng Zhang, Huili Zhang, Zengxuan Chen, Jillian M. Buriak, Sheng Wang, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Fangna Dai, Maohuai Wang, Xiaoqing L&#252;, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405417149

                Abstract Seawater electrolysis is an effective way for large&#8208;scale green hydrogen. Nevertheless, the anode suffers from the severe corrosion of Cl &#8722; and Br &#8722; during oxygen evolution, which gives rise to the issues of narrow&#8208;deep pits and shallow&#8208;wide pits, respectively. Herein, an anti&#8208;corrosion strategy is presented by self&#8208;adapting oxyanion armor to prevent the high valence active sites from Cl &#8722; and Br &#8722; corrosion. The core&#8211;shell FeNi 2 Se 4 @NiFe&#8208;Phy is reconstructed to active species NiFeOOH covered by an oxyanion layer composed of phosphoric and carbonate. The aimed anode exhibits remarkable efficiency, achieving current densities of 10 and 200 mA cm &#8722;2 at overpotentials of merely 220 and 277 mV, respectively. Notably, it shows unparalleled durability, enduring without any discernible degradation following rigorous testing for 400 h at 400&#8211;1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline simulated seawater, as well as natural seawater. A combination of density functional theory calculations and molecular dynamics simulations further confirms the bifunctional enhancement of oxyanion armor on NiFeOOH surface. At a current density of 200 mA cm &#8722;2 , the alkaline seawater electrolyzer has significant energy efficiency, consuming merely 4.61 and 4.27 kWh Nm &#8722;3 H 2 at room temperature and 80 &#176;C, respectively. This work offers an efficacious surface corrosion resistance strategy for anode protection during seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Xingheng Zhang, Huili Zhang, Zengxuan Chen, Jillian M. Buriak, Sheng Wang, Shuxian Wei, Siyuan Liu, Zhaojie Wang, Fangna Dai, Maohuai Wang, Xiaoqing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418940</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron and Oxygen: a Dangerous Mixture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003574811-5</link>
      <description>John M.C. Gutteridge, Barry Halliwell, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405328947

                During the chemical and biological evolution of the Earth, its atmosphere changed from a highly reducing state to the oxygen-rich state that we know today. Free molecular oxygen (dioxygen) probably appeared on the Earth's surface some 2 billion years ago as a result of photosynthetic microorganisms acquiring the ability to split water. Oxygen is now the most abundant element in the Earth's crust and the second most abundant element in the biosphere. The concentration of molecular oxygen (hereafter referred to as oxygen) in dry air has risen to 21%. Iron, the element of equal importance in this story, is the fourth most abundant element in the Earth's crust.</description>
      <author>John M.C. Gutteridge, Barry Halliwell</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003574811-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charting New Pathways to Form Wolf&#8211;Rayet Stars at Low Metallicities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25518/0037-9565.12319</link>
      <description>D. Pauli, Bulletin de la Soci&#233;t&#233; Royale des Sciences de Li&#232;ge. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405477024

                Low-metallicity Wolf&#8211;Rayet (WR) populations, such as the one of the Small Magellanic Cloud (SMC), are expected to be slightly influenced by metallicity-dependent effects, such as envelope inflation, which typically positions stars at cooler temperatures. Consequently, these populations should be easier to understand from a theoretical point of view. Yet, the observed bimodal temperature distribution of WR stars in the SMC cannot be explained by existing single-star or binary evolution models. To better understand the observed temperature distribution of WR stars in the SMC, the role of the evolutionary secondary and its response to mass transfer is studied here in detail. To achieve this, I calculated a small grid of binary evolution models at the SMC metallicity, that follows the evolution of both the primary and secondary stars in detail. The analysis of the new binary evolution models suggests that hot (T &#8776; 100 kK), hydrogen-poor WN-type stars are the descendants of &#8220;ordinary&#8221; primary stars or secondaries that have accreted less than a few percent of their initial mass. In contrast, moderate-temperature (T &#8776; 50 kK) WN stars can emerge through two channels: (i) as former accretors that underwent rejuvenation, altering their interior structure and leading to higher surface oxygen abundances (XO = 20&#215;10&#8722;5) after mass-transfer, or (ii) as luminous stars experiencing envelope inflation, that exhibit surface oxygen abundances in accordance with the CNO-equilibrium value (XO = 2&#215;10&#8722;5). The first observational evidence supporting this hypothesis comes from the WR star SMC AB 4, whose optical spectra can only be explained with a stellar atmosphere model having a surface oxygen abundance one order of magnitude higher than the CNO-equilibrium value. Following the binary evolution models, secondary stars that have accreted mass relatively conservatively and, thus, got rejuvenated will evolve at low metallicity into WN stars with moderate temperatures and should be accompanied by a compact object. This would imply that the WN-type star SMC AB 4 should have a so far unseen compact companion. Future spectroscopic surveys focusing on surface oxygen abundances and multiplicity among SMC WR stars are key to further understanding massive star evolution and the role of binarity in forming WR stars in low-metallicity environments.</description>
      <author>D. Pauli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25518/0037-9565.12319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Evolution Law and Prevention of Spontaneous Combustion &#8220;Three Zones&#8221; in Compound Goaf of Shallow Coal Seam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3233/atde241134</link>
      <description>Jianguo Wang, Shilong Luo, C. F. Zhang, Advances in transdisciplinary engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405376641

                In order to study the dynamic evolution of the &#8220;three zones&#8221; of spontaneous combustion and the distribution characteristics of oxygen concentration under different advancing distances in the compound goaf of shallow coal seam, through the field measurement of oxygen concentration in the goaf and the analysis of the development law and air leakage mechanism of the overlying rock fractures in the goaf, the calculation model of the compound goaf of shallow coal seam was established by using fluent simulation software. The depth, width, and dynamic evolution of the oxidation zone and oxygen concentration were obtained as the advancing distance increased in the lower and upper goaf, respectively. The results indicate that: in the secondary mining stage, with the increase of the advance distance, the oxidation zones on both sides of the overlying goaf and the lower goaf gradually extend backward, and finally form a &#8220;high on both sides, low in the middle&#8221; oxygen concentration distribution pattern within 100 m to 500 m of the goaf. At the same position, the width of the oxidation zone in the overlying goaf is less than that in the lower goaf, and the risk of spontaneous combustion is less than that in the lower goaf. After the advancing distance is greater than 100 m, the width of the oxidation zone at the air inlet side of the overlying goaf decreases with the increasing of the advancing distance, and the width of the oxidation zone at the air return side increases, and the width of the oxidation zone at both sides finally tends to be the same, The width of oxidation zone on both sides of the lower goaf increases first and then decreases with the increase of distance. The research results indicate that the evolution law of &#8220;three zones&#8221; of spontaneous combustion in the composite goaf during the mining process of shallow buried coal seams, and provide reference for preventing and controlling the spontaneous combustion caused by air leakage in the composite goaf in shallow buried depth.</description>
      <author>Jianguo Wang, Shilong Luo, C. F. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3233/atde241134</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mitochondrial Genomes of the Reef-Dwelling Spiny Lobsters Panulirus echinatus and Panulirus interruptus with Insights into the Phylogeny and Adaptive Evolution of Protein-Coding Genes in the Achelata</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14293/p2199-8442.1.sop-.pio36p.v1</link>
      <description>Alyssa Baker, Natalie Stephens, F&#225;bio Mendon&#231;a Diniz, Francisco J. Garc&#237;a&#8208;D&#233; Le&#243;n, A. Baeza, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405376035

                Temperature and oxygen levels drive the evolution of morphological, behavioral, and physiological traits in marine invertebrates, including crustaceans. Environmental conditions are also expected to prompt the adaptive evolution of mitochondrial protein-coding genes (PCGs), which are vital for energy production via the oxidative phosphorylation pathway. We formally tested for adaptive evolution in mitochondrial protein-coding genes in representatives of the decapod infraorder Achelata, including two spiny lobsters, Panulirus echinatus and Panulirus interruptus , for which we sequenced complete mitochondrial genomes (15,644 and 15,659 bp long, respectively). A phylomitogenomic analysis based on all 13 mitochondrial PCGs for 24 species belonging to the infraorder Achelata, plus an outgroup representing the infraorders Caridea and Nephropidae, supported the monophyly of the genus Panulirus , the families Palinuridae and Scyllaridae, and the infraorder Achelata. Over the strong negative selection background observed for mitochondrial PCGs in the Achelata, signatures of positive selective pressure were detected within PCGs in equatorial Panulirus spp. and deepwater Scyllaridae. In Panulirus spp. inhabiting equatorial latitudes with consistently high temperatures, the Datamonkey analysis RELAX suggested intensified purifying selection strength in 9 of the 13 PCGs and relaxation in purifying selection strength in atp6, while aBSREL, BUSTED, and MEME recovered signatures of positive selection on PCGs within Complex I, III, and IV PCGs. Likewise, in Scyllaridae species inhabiting depths with low oxygen levels, RELAX indicated relaxed selection strength in 6 of the 13 PCGs, while aBSREL, BUSTED, and MEME recovered signatures of positive selection on PCGs within Complexes I, III, IV, and V. Adaptive evolution likely retains mutations that improve protein stability at sustained temperatures and enhance mitochondrial capacity for energy metabolism in low oxygen conditions. These mutations likely optimize the ability of Complex I to pump protons into the mitochondrial intermembrane space, improve electron transfer and proton translocation in Complex III, boost the efficiency with which Complex IV transfers electrons to oxygen to form water, and refine the ability of Complex V to produce energy via oxidative phosphorylation. The newly assembled mitochondrial genomes of P. echinatus and P. interruptus represent new genomic resources to aid the conservation and management of lobsters targeted by major fisheries through applications such as bioprospecting using eDNA sampling and species identification via DNA barcoding. This study also contributes to our understanding of how environmental conditions drive adaptive evolution in spiny and slipper lobster mitochondrial PCGs and supports the notion that mitochondrial protein-coding genes can and do experience adaptive evolution to optimize mitochondrial function in a wide variety of organisms. Further research is needed to clarify which and how environmental conditions influence the adaptive evolution of mitochondrial PCGs in other crustacean lineages and beyond.</description>
      <author>Alyssa Baker, Natalie Stephens, F&#225;bio Mendon&#231;a Diniz, Francisco J. Garc&#237;a&#8208;D&#233; Le&#243;n, A. Baeza</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14293/p2199-8442.1.sop-.pio36p.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling H2 and O2 Release in Particulate Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting Using a Reversible O2 Binder</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420913</link>
      <description>Dan Li&#250;, Huihui Xu, Jinni Shen, Xun Wang, Qu Chen, Huaxiang Lin, Jinlin Long, Wei Wang, Wenxin Dai, Yuanxing Fang, Yanhui Yang, Xuxu Wang, Xianzhi Fu, Zizhong Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405412722

                H2 and O2 evolutions occur simultaneously for conventional particulate photocatalytic overall water splitting (PPOWS), leading to a significant backward reaction and the formation of an explosive H2/O2 gas mixture. This is an issue that must be addressed prior to industrialization of PPOWS. Here, a convenient, cost&#8208;effective, and scalable concept is introduced to uncouple hydrogen and oxygen production for PPOWS. Based on this idea, a three&#8208;component photocatalyst, Co(5%)&#8208;HPCN/(rGO/Pt), is constructed, consisting of a photoresponsive chip (HPCN), a H2 evolution cocatalyst (rGO/Pt), and a cobalt complex capable of reversibly binding O2 (Co), to achieve the decoupling of PPOWS under alternating UV and visible light irradiations. The asynchronous O2 and H2 evolution strategy have considerable flexibility regarding the photocatalyst structure and light sources suitable for PPOWS.</description>
      <author>Dan Li&#250;, Huihui Xu, Jinni Shen, Xun Wang, Qu Chen, Huaxiang Lin, Jinlin Long, Wei Wang, Wenxin Dai, Yuanxing Fang, Yanhui Yang, Xuxu Wang, Xianzhi Fu, Zizhong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilized Oxygen Vacancy Chemistry toward High-Performance Layered Oxide Cathodes for Sodium-Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14724</link>
      <description>Cheng Chen, Zengqing Zhuo, Xia Xiao, Tong Liu, Yihao Shen, Yuan Cheng, Pan Zeng, Duanyun Cao, Ying Zou, Jinghua Guo, Liang Zhang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405318406

                Anionic redox has emerged as a transformative paradigm for high-energy layered transition-metal (TM) oxide cathodes, but it is usually accompanied by the formation of anionic redox-mediated oxygen vacancies (OVs) due to irreversible oxygen release. Additionally, external factor-induced OVs (defined as intrinsic OVs) also play a pivotal role in the physicochemical properties of layered TM oxides. However, an in-depth understanding of the interplay between intrinsic and anionic redox-mediated OVs and the corresponding regulation mechanism of the dynamic evolution of OVs is still missing. Herein, we disclose the strong interrelationship between these OVs and demonstrate that the presence of intrinsic OVs in the TMO</description>
      <author>Cheng Chen, Zengqing Zhuo, Xia Xiao, Tong Liu, Yihao Shen, Yuan Cheng, Pan Zeng, Duanyun Cao, Ying Zou, Jinghua Guo, Liang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling H2 and O2 Release in Particulate Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting Using a Reversible O2 Binder</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420913</link>
      <description>Dan Li&#250;, Huihui Xu, Jinni Shen, Xun Wang, Qu Chen, Huaxiang Lin, Jinlin Long, Ying Wang, Wenxin Dai, Yuanxing Fang, Yanhui Yang, Xuxu Wang, Xianzhi Fu, Zizhong Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405412721

                H2 and O2 evolutions occur simultaneously for conventional particulate photocatalytic overall water splitting (PPOWS), leading to a significant backward reaction and the formation of an explosive H2/O2 gas mixture. This is an issue that must be addressed prior to industrialization of PPOWS. Here, a convenient, cost&#8208;effective, and scalable concept is introduced to uncouple hydrogen and oxygen production for PPOWS. Based on this idea, a three&#8208;component photocatalyst, Co(5%)&#8208;HPCN/(rGO/Pt), is constructed, consisting of a photoresponsive chip (HPCN), a H2 evolution cocatalyst (rGO/Pt), and a cobalt complex capable of reversibly binding O2 (Co), to achieve the decoupling of PPOWS under alternating UV and visible light irradiations. The asynchronous O2 and H2 evolution strategy have considerable flexibility regarding the photocatalyst structure and light sources suitable for PPOWS.</description>
      <author>Dan Li&#250;, Huihui Xu, Jinni Shen, Xun Wang, Qu Chen, Huaxiang Lin, Jinlin Long, Ying Wang, Wenxin Dai, Yuanxing Fang, Yanhui Yang, Xuxu Wang, Xianzhi Fu, Zizhong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and seasonal characteristics of organic vapors in urban Beijing: insights from Vocus-PTR measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-13793-2024</link>
      <description>Zhaojin An, Rujing Yin, Xinyan Zhao, Xiaoxiao Li, Yuyang Li, Yi Yuan, Junchen Guo, Yiqi Zhao, Xue Li, Dandan Li, Yaowei Li, Dongbin Wang, Chao Yan, Kebin He, Douglas R. Worsnop, Frank N. Keutsch, Jingkun Jiang, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 24(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405322441

                Abstract. Understanding the composition and evolution of atmospheric organic vapors is crucial for exploring their impact on air quality. However, the molecular and seasonal characteristics of organic vapors in urban areas, with complex anthropogenic emissions and high variability, remain inadequately understood. In this study, we conducted measurements in urban Beijing during 2021&#8211;2022, covering four seasons, using improved proton-transfer-reaction mass spectrometry (Vocus-PTR-MS). During the measurement period, a total of 895 peaks were observed, and 512 of them can be assigned to formulas. The contribution of CxHyOz species is most significant, composing up to 54 % of the number and 74 % of the mixing ratio of total organics. With enhanced sensitivity and mass resolution, various species with multiple oxygens (&#8805; 3) or at a level of sub-parts per trillion (ppt) were observed, with 44 % of the number measured at sub-ppt level and 38 % of the number containing three&#8211;eight oxygen atoms. Organic vapors with multiple oxygens mainly consist of intermediate/semi-volatile compounds, and many formulae detected were reported to be the oxidation products of various volatile organic precursors. In summer, the fast photooxidation process generated organic vapors with multiple oxygens and led to an increase in both their mixing ratio and proportion, while, in other seasons, the variations in organic vapors with multiple oxygens were closely correlated with those of organic vapors with 1&#8211;2 oxygens, which could be substantially influenced by primary emissions. Organic vapors with low oxygen content (&#8804; 2 oxygens) are comparable to the results obtained by traditional PTR-MS measurements in both urban Beijing and neighboring regions.</description>
      <author>Zhaojin An, Rujing Yin, Xinyan Zhao, Xiaoxiao Li, Yuyang Li, Yi Yuan, Junchen Guo, Yiqi Zhao, Xue Li, Dandan Li, Yaowei Li, Dongbin Wang, Chao Yan, Kebin He, Douglas R. Worsnop, Frank N. Keutsch, Jingkun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-13793-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering prolyl hydroxylase-dependent proteolysis enables the orthogonal control of hypoxia responses in plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.13.628401</link>
      <description>Vinay Shukla, Sergio Iacopino, Laura Dalle Carbonare, Yuehua He, Alessia Del Chiaro, Antonis Papachristodoulou, Beatrice Giuntoli, Francesco Licausi, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405414189

                Vascular plants and metazoans use selective proteolysis of transcription factors to control the adaptive responses to hypoxia, although through distinct biochemical mechanisms. The reason for this divergence is puzzling, especially when considering that the molecular components necessary to establish both strategies are conserved across the two kingdoms. To explore an alternative evolutionary scenario where plants sense hypoxia as animals do, we engineered a three-components system aimed to target proteins for degradation in an oxygen dependent manner in Arabidopsis thaliana. Applying the synthetic biology framework, we produced a hypoxia-responsive switch independent of endogenous pathways. When applied to control transcription, the synthetic system partially restored hypoxia responsiveness in oxygen-insensitive mutants. Additionally, we demonstrated its potential to regulate growth under flood-induced hypoxia. Our work highlights the use of synthetic biology to reprogram signalling pathways in plants, providing insights into the evolution of oxygen sensing and offering tools for crop improvement under stress conditions.</description>
      <author>Vinay Shukla, Sergio Iacopino, Laura Dalle Carbonare, Yuehua He, Alessia Del Chiaro, Antonis Papachristodoulou, Beatrice Giuntoli, Francesco Licausi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.13.628401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Mechanism of Exsolution of Silver Nanoparticles for Decorating Lanthanum Strontium Ferrite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04413</link>
      <description>M. Teresa Azcondo, Gloria Anemone, &#193;lvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Noval, Khalid Boulahya, Juan Rubio&#8208;Zuazo, Paula Rosendo, Ulises Amador, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405508168

                Lanthanum strontium ferrite (La0.85&#8211;xSr0.15AgxFeO3&#8722;&#948; x = 0; LSFO) and its silver-doped derivative (La0.85&#8211;xSr0.15AgxFeO3&#8722;&#948; x = 0.05; LASFO) are synthesized using mild conditions by a sol&#8211;gel method. Both oxides present a perovskite-like structure with orthorhombic symmetry due to octahedral tilting; thus, the incorporation of silver in the A-site does not significantly modify the perovskite structure. Exsolution of silver nanoparticles (AgNPs) from LASFO is induced under mild conditions, resulting in Ag@LSFO samples. X-ray absorption spectroscopy and synchrotron X-ray diffraction data reveal that the mechanism of exsolution involves the reduction of Ag+ and the concomitant release of oxygen, without altering the oxidation state of Fe, inducing the formation of oxygen vacancies in the perovskite matrix. Homogeneous distribution of AgNPs on the perovskite matrix is observed by high-resolution transmission electron microscopy. The thermal evolution of Ag@LSFO proceeds through the progressive increase in oxygen vacancies that become thermally disordered. The study clarifies the mechanism of silver exsolution and the structural changes in lanthanum&#8211;strontium ferrite perovskites, providing insights into their potential use in catalytic and energy-related applications.</description>
      <author>M. Teresa Azcondo, Gloria Anemone, &#193;lvaro Mu&#241;oz&#8208;Noval, Khalid Boulahya, Juan Rubio&#8208;Zuazo, Paula Rosendo, Ulises Amador</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Back Cover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12515</link>
      <description>, EcoMat. 6(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405409334

                This cover visualizes the microwave&#8208;assisted synthesis of platinum&#8208;nickel nanoalloys on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene and their practical applications such as water electrolysis and fuel cell. This research concentrates on the fast and facile synthetic procedure using microwave heating with reducing the amount of platinum and enhancing the catalytic performance by the control of lattice strain and nitrogen doping. These can lead to improved activity and durability in hydrogen evolution and oxygen reduction for hydrogen production and utilization in our daily lives. image</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using stable isotopes in deciphering climate changes from travertine deposits: the case of the Lapis Tiburtinus succession (Acque Albule Basin, Tivoli, Central Italy)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.ps8082</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405512563

                Quaternary stable isotope records of marine and lacustrine carbonate deposits as well as speleothems were extensively studied to reconstruct global and regional climatic evolution. This study demonstrates how stable isotope records of travertine provide fundamental information about climate and the consequences of its evolution on groundwater level fluctuations. The deposition of the Lapis Tiburtinus travertine succession occurred during the Late Pleistocene (150&#8211;30 ka), coeval with the last activity of the Colli Albani volcanic complex. Two boreholes (Sn1 and Sn2) were drilled into the Acque Albule Basin (23 km E of Rome), crossing the entire Lapis Tiburtinus succession. The Sn1 borehole in the central part of the basin crosscuts a travertine succession of 62.1 m in thickness, while the Sn2 borehole in the southern part of the basin is characterized by a travertine succession 36.3 m in thickness. Carbon and oxygen stable isotope ratios were analysed on 118 samples (59 samples both for Sn1 and Sn2 boreholes) representative of the entire Lapis Tiburtinus travertine succession crossed by the boreholes. Values, measured and correlated in the two drilled boreholes, permitted determination of the sensitivity of the travertine depositional system to glacial and interglacial cycles, unravelling the complex oxygen and carbon cycle dynamic recorded in such sedimentary succession. Moreover, the results obtained correlated with available pollen curves of the Mediterranean area (from the Castiglione crater, 25 km E of Rome). Regional and global oxygen isotope continental and marine curves, calibrated with the stratigraphy of the Acque Albule Basin, and available U/Th dating allow the identification of at least three phases of the last interglacial (Marine Isotope Stage 5-MIS5). The carbon isotope record, compared with CO2 flux reconstructed and associated with the volcanic activity of the Colli Albani volcanic complex, instead shows an influence from groundwater level changes. In particular, positive shifts that occurred during arid phases are associated with a lower groundwater level and increased CO2 degassing, inducing a major fractionation effect on carbon isotopes. Instead, the negative shifts occurring during more humid periods indicate the inhibition of CO2 degassing and increase in pressure, attesting to a rise in groundwater level. In this view, travertine deposits, frequently studied to define the tectonic setting and activity of the area where they develop, can thus also be used as a tool to understand climate changes and groundwater variations apparent in their stable oxygen and carbon isotope signature.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.ps8082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Electrochemical Method of Producing Environmentally Friendly Hydrogen Energy Carrier According to the Evans Diagram</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5123893/v1</link>
      <description>Mykhailo Sukhyi, V.G. Nefedov, Yuliya Polishchuk, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405413244

                Abstract The possibility of reducing energy costs during hydrogen release was realized using a system in which the anodic process of oxygen release was replaced by the process of dissolution of an electronegative metal (aluminum alloy). The rate of hydrogen release on aluminum, among other equal conditions (temperature and concentration of the electrolyte), depends on the polarization of hydrogen release. On aluminum - a metal of the third group of the periodic table of elements, it is high. The dissolution (corrosion) rate of aluminum can be increased by short-circuiting with an electrode with a low hydrogen evolution polarization, such as nickel. The ratio of hydrogen evolution currents on aluminum and nickel was estimated. The effect of alkali concentration and temperature on the current density, polarization and polarizability of electrodes made of aluminum alloy containing Cu, Mg, Mn and Fe was determined. It was shown that in a 0.1 mol l&#8722; 1 NaOH solution at a temperature of 20&#176;C, the polarization resistance of hydrogen release on nickel is lower than on aluminum, and the hydrogen release rate on Ni is higher. At high temperatures and sodium hydroxide concentrations, the polarizability of metal dissolution and hydrogen release on aluminum increases sharply and exceeds those on nickel.</description>
      <author>Mykhailo Sukhyi, V.G. Nefedov, Yuliya Polishchuk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5123893/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical nanoparticle formation in iron combustion: single particle
  experiments with in-situ multi-parameter diagnostics aided by multi-scale
  simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.08736</link>
      <description>Tao Li, Bich-Diep Nguyen, Yawei Gao, Daoguan Ning, Benjamin B&#246;hm, Arne Scholtissek, Adri C. T. van Duin, Christian Hasse, Andreas Dreizler, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405354530

                The formation of iron oxide nanoparticles (NPs) presents challenges such as efficiency losses and fine dust emissions in practical iron combustion systems, highlighting the need for deeper understanding of the formation mechanisms and thermochemical conditions. This study combines experiments and multi-scale simulations to analyze NP clouds generated by single iron particles burning in high-temperature oxidizing environments. The ambient gas conditions were provided by a laminar flat flame burner, with post-flame oxygen mole fractions varied between 20, 30, and 40 vol% at a constant temperature of ~1800K. High-speed in-situ diagnostics were used to measure particle size, NP initiation, NP cloud evolution, and microparticle surface temperature history. The experimental setup utilized three 10kHz imaging systems: one for two-color pyrometry and two for diffusive-backlight illumination (DBI), targeting particle size and NP measurements. The findings showcase the powerful capabilities of multi-physics diagnostics in quantifying NP initiation time and temperature, which depend on particle size and ambient oxygen concentration. CFD simulations revealed enhanced convection velocity driven by increased Stefan flow, which transported NPs toward parent iron particles under high-oxygen conditions. This delayed the detection of NP clouds, leading to higher microparticle temperatures at NP initiation. Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations uncovered FeO2(g) as a key NP precursor, forming when Fe atoms dissociate from the liquid phase. The initial temperature significantly influenced the resulting nanocluster composition, with Fe(II) dominating at higher temperatures and Fe(III) at lower temperatures. This integrated approach enhances understanding of NP formation in iron combustion, offering insights into the conditions affecting nanoparticle characteristics.</description>
      <author>Tao Li, Bich-Diep Nguyen, Yawei Gao, Daoguan Ning, Benjamin B&#246;hm, Arne Scholtissek, Adri C. T. van Duin, Christian Hasse, Andreas Dreizler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.08736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early&#8208;Branching Cyanobacteria Grow Faster and Upregulate Superoxide Dismutase Activity Under a Simulated Early Earth Anoxic Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/gbi.70005</link>
      <description>Sadia S. Tamanna, Joanne S. Boden, Kimberly Michelle Kaiser, Nicola Wannicke, Jonas Hoering, Patricia S&#225;nchez&#8208;Baracaldo, Marcel Deponte, Nicole Frankenberg&#8208;Dinkel, Michelle M. Gehringer, Geobiology. 22(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405322204

                ABSTRACT The evolution of oxygenic photosynthesis during the Archean (4&#8211;2.5 Ga) required the presence of complementary reducing pathways to maintain the cellular redox balance. While the timing of the evolution of superoxide dismutases (SODs), enzymes that convert superoxide to hydrogen peroxide and O 2 , within bacteria and archaea is not resolved, the first SODs appearing in cyanobacteria contained copper and zinc in the reaction center (CuZnSOD). Here, we analyse growth characteristics, SOD gene expression (qRT&#8208;PCR) and cellular enzyme activity in the deep branching strain, Pseudanabaena sp. PCC7367, previously demonstrated to release significantly more O 2 under anoxic conditions. The observed significantly higher growth rates ( p &lt; 0.001) and protein and glycogen contents ( p &lt; 0.05) in anoxically cultured Pseudanabaena PCC7367 compared to control cultures grown under present&#8208;day oxygen&#8208;rich conditions prompted the following question: Is the growth of Pseudanabaena sp. PCC7367 correlated to atmospheric p O 2 and cellular SOD activity? Expression of sodB (encoding FeSOD) and sodC (encoding CuZnSOD) strongly correlated with medium O 2 levels ( p &lt; 0.001). Expression of sodA (encoding MnSOD) correlated significantly to SOD activity during the day ( p = 0.019) when medium O 2 concentrations were the highest. The cellular SOD enzyme activity of anoxically grown cultures was significantly higher ( p &lt; 0.001) 2 h before the onset of the dark phase compared to O 2 &#8208;rich growth conditions. The expression of SOD encoding genes was significantly reduced ( p &lt; 0.05) under anoxic conditions in stirred cultures, as were medium O 2 levels ( p &#8804; 0.001), compared to oxic&#8208;grown cultures, whereas total cellular SOD activity remained comparable. Our data suggest that increasing p O 2 negatively impacts the viability of early cyanobacteria, possibly by increasing photorespiration. Additionally, the increased expression of superoxide&#8208;inactivating genes during the dark phase suggests the increased replacement rates of SODs under modern&#8208;day conditions compared to those on early Earth.</description>
      <author>Sadia S. Tamanna, Joanne S. Boden, Kimberly Michelle Kaiser, Nicola Wannicke, Jonas Hoering, Patricia S&#225;nchez&#8208;Baracaldo, Marcel Deponte, Nicole Frankenberg&#8208;Dinkel, Michelle M. Gehringer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/gbi.70005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of superconductivity in electron-hole coexisting
  Sr$_{1-x}$Eu$_{x}$CuO$_{2+y}$ films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.08213</link>
      <description>Hang Yan, Ze-Xian Deng, Xue-Qing Yu, Yanling Xiong, Qun Zhu, Ding Zhang, Can&#8208;Li Song, Xucun Ma, Qi&#8208;Kun Xue, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405301268

                We report transport measurements of infinite-layer cuprate Sr$_{1-x}$Eu$_{x}$CuO$_{2+y}$ films with controlled electron (by trivalent europium) and hole (by interstitial apical oxygen) carriers grown on SrTiO$_3$(001) with molecular beam epitaxy. An unusual enhancement of superconductivity upon moderate electron-hole coexistence in the films is found, which spans over the whole superconducting phase diagram and becomes more prominent in the underdoped regime. The superconductivity exhibits a two-dimensional nature with a thickness of approximately 5.2 nm, irrespective of the varying carriers, confirmed by angle-resolved magnetoresistance measurements and the Berzzinsky-Kosterlitz-Thouless transition. Nevertheless, the electron-hole coexistence enlarges the thermal activation energy of vortex motion that deviates obviously from the usual logarithmic evolution with the magnetic field. Our results offer a promising perspective to understand and enhance the high-temperature superconductivity in cuprates.</description>
      <author>Hang Yan, Ze-Xian Deng, Xue-Qing Yu, Yanling Xiong, Qun Zhu, Ding Zhang, Can&#8208;Li Song, Xucun Ma, Qi&#8208;Kun Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.08213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Properties of Type Ibn/Icn Supernovae and Their
  Progenitor Channels through X-ray Emission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.09066</link>
      <description>Yusuke Inoue, Keiichi Maeda, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405354908

                Type Ibn/Icn supernovae (SNe Ibn/Icn), which are characterized by narrow helium or carbon lines originated in hydrogen-poor dense circumstellar medium (CSM), provide new insights into the final evolution of massive stars. While SNe Ibn/Icn are expected to emit strong X-rays through the strong SN-CSM interaction, the X-ray emission modeling effort has been limited so far. In the present study, we provide broad-band X-ray light curve (LC) predictions for SNe Ibn/Icn. We find that the soft X-ray LC provides information about the CSM compositions, while the hard X-ray LC is a robust measure of the CSM density, the explosion energy, and the ejecta mass. In addition, considering the evolution of the ionization state in the unshocked CSM, a bright soft X-ray is expected in the first few days since the explosion, which encourages rapid X-ray follow-up observations as a tool to study the nature of SNe Ibn/Icn. Applying our model to the soft X-ray LCs of SNe Ibn 2006jc and 2022ablq, we derive that the CSM potentially contains a larger fraction of carbon and oxygen for SN 2006jc than 2022ablq, highlighting the power of the soft X-ray modeling to address the nature of the CSM. We also discuss detectability and observational strategy, with which the currently operating telescopes such as NuSTAR and Swift can offer an irreplaceable opportunity to explore the nature of these enigmatic rapid transients and their still-unclarified progenitor channel(s).</description>
      <author>Yusuke Inoue, Keiichi Maeda</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.09066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory for Electrocatalytic Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch2</link>
      <description>Wei Li, Yi Ding, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405358277

                Electrocatalytic technology plays an important role in advancing green and sustainable energy. Various significant electrocatalytic reactions, such as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR), have huge potential in green energy conversion. However, the conversion efficiency is limited by slow kinetic processes and high reaction overpotentials. Therefore, the development of electrocatalysts with high catalytic activity and selectivity is of paramount importance. Based on density functional theory (DFT), theoretical calculations can not only analyze the electrocatalytic reaction processes from the perspective of molecular structure and energy but also provide an in-depth understanding of the electronic structures of the catalysts and establish the structure&#8211;activity relationships between catalysts and electrocatalytic reactions. Thus, DFT calculations can offer theoretical basis and guidance for the design and preparation of efficient electrocatalysts. In this chapter, we will introduce some DFT calculation methods and several electrocatalytic reactions, aiming to help readers understand how DFT calculations are applied to electrocatalytic energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Wei Li, Yi Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAIN SOURCES AND SINKS OF ODD OXYGEN AND HYDROGEN FAMILIES IN THE MESOSPHERE&#8211;LOWER THERMOSPHERE DURING DAYTIME</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56820/oao30e29</link>
      <description>Alexey G. Chubarov, &#1052;.&#1070;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1083;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, Mikhail V. Belikovich, &#1057;.&#1054;. &#1044;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1100;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, A. M. Fe&#464;gin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405370326

                &#1042; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1077; &#1074; &#1088;&#1072;&#1084;&#1082;&#1072;&#1093; &#1075;&#1083;&#1086;&#1073;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1090;&#1088;&#1105;&#1093;&#1084;&#1077;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;-&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1085; &#1072;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1079; &#1074;&#1089;&#1077;&#1093; &#1080;&#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1095;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074; &#1080; &#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074; &#1089;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074; &#1085;&#1077;&#1095;&#1105;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1082;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; &#1080; &#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1072; &#1080; &#1074;&#1099;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1099; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080;, &#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1103;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1076;&#1085;&#1077;&#1074;&#1085;&#1091;&#1102; &#1101;&#1074;&#1086;&#1083;&#1102;&#1094;&#1080;&#1102; &#1101;&#1090;&#1080;&#1093; &#1089;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074; &#1074; &#1079;&#1072;&#1074;&#1080;&#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1086;&#1090; &#1074;&#1099;&#1089;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099;, &#1096;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099; &#1080; &#1089;&#1077;&#1079;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1083;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1088;&#1077;&#1079;&#1091;&#1083;&#1100;&#1090;&#1072;&#1090;&#1099; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1091;&#1102;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1076;&#1083;&#1103; &#1091;&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1072;&#1083;&#1075;&#1077;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1089;&#1074;&#1103;&#1079;&#1077;&#1081; &#1084;&#1077;&#1078;&#1076;&#1091; &#1082;&#1086;&#1084;&#1087;&#1086;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080; &#1101;&#1090;&#1080;&#1093; &#1089;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;, &#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1091;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1093; &#1080;&#1079; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1081; &#1092;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1088;&#1072;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1077;&#1089;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1085;&#1072;&#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1076;&#1083;&#1103; &#1074;&#1086;&#1089;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1083;&#1086;&#1093;&#1086; &#1080;&#1079;&#1084;&#1077;&#1088;&#1103;&#1077;&#1084;&#1099;&#1093; &#1084;&#1072;&#1083;&#1099;&#1093; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1089;&#1077;&#1081; &#1084;&#1077;&#1079;&#1086;&#1089;&#1092;&#1077;&#1088;&#1099; &#1085;&#1072; 50-80 &#1082;&#1084;, &#1074;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1076;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1080;&#1079;&#1084;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1081; &#1080;&#1083;&#1080; &#1091;&#1090;&#1086;&#1095;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1090; &#1092;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1081;. In this work, within the framework of a global three-dimensional chemical transport model, an analysis of all sources and sinks of odd oxygen and hydrogen families has been conducted, and the main chemical reactions determining the daytime evolution of these families depending on altitude, latitude, and season have been identified. The results obtained are used to simplify the algebraic relationships between the components of these families, derived from the conditions of photochemical equilibrium and intended for the retrieval of poorly measured minor impurities in the mesosphere at altitudes of 50-80 km, data validation, or clarifying the constants of photochemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Alexey G. Chubarov, &#1052;.&#1070;. &#1050;&#1091;&#1083;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, Mikhail V. Belikovich, &#1057;.&#1054;. &#1044;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1100;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;, A. M. Fe&#464;gin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56820/oao30e29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biological growth properties of marine Enteromorpha-diatom and its adhesion evolution on mortar surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1680/jmacr.24.00334</link>
      <description>Hui Rong, Yanan Wang, Zijian Song, Xiaomin Liu, Keqi Huang, Zhihua Guo, Zhihua Liu, Magazine of Concrete Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405513396

                Currently, most research on bio-corroded mortar focuses on cyanobacteria and microorganisms in the marine environment, but the specific mechanism of mortar performance at different stages of the specific biological system of marine dominant algae, Enteromorpha-diatom, is still lacking. Therefore, this paper investigates the growth characteristics of Enteromorpha-diatom proliferation organisms and their attachment evolution on mortar. First, the concentration of Enteromorpha spores over 0 to 15 days was studied. Subsequently, the effects of Enteromorpha-diatom on the properties of mortar at different growth stages over 0 to 360 days were investigated through changes in pH, DO (dissolved oxygen), microstructure, mineral composition, and microstructure in the culture medium. The results showed that Enteromorpha-diatom organisms significantly affected the pH and DO in water through photosynthesis and metabolic activities. Additionally, the adhesion of Enteromorpha-diatom organisms significantly impacted the mechanical properties of mortar, with compressive strength decreasing by 46.1% and flexural strength decreasing by 39.0% over 0 to 360 days. Furthermore, the formation of biofilm, deposition of CaCO 3 , and accumulation of organic and inorganic substances altered the microstructure of mortar, changing its electrochemical characteristics. The electric flux change rate was 46.1%, and the internal impedance decreased by 59% over 0 to 360 days.</description>
      <author>Hui Rong, Yanan Wang, Zijian Song, Xiaomin Liu, Keqi Huang, Zhihua Guo, Zhihua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1680/jmacr.24.00334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Clinical History in the Etiological Diagnosis of Diffuse Alveolar Hemorrhage Associated With Improper Adrenaline Use</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.75727</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Patr&#237;cio, Ana Rafael, Filipe Concei&#231;&#65533;&#227;o, Jos&#233; Manuel Pereira, Jos&#233; Artur Paiva, Cureus. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405402352

                This case involves a 21-year-old male healthcare student with a medical history of HIV-1 infection for two years and anxiety disorder. He presented to the emergency department with hemoptysis and dyspnea of sudden onset. A thoracic CT scan revealed multiple bilateral nodular ground-glass opacities suggestive of diffuse alveolar hemorrhage (DAH). Due to hypoxemic respiratory failure, noninvasive ventilatory support was initiated. A bronchoalveolar lavage confirmed the presence of blood. He also showed an elevated troponin I, peaking at 2,915 ng/mL, with no electrocardiographic or echocardiographic abnormalities. Assuming an immune etiology, high-dose corticosteroids were initiated, with three days of methylprednisolone 1 g. However, the entire etiological study for DAH turned out negative. During a follow-up clinical interview, the patient admitted to having self-administered 1 mg of intravenous adrenaline shortly before the onset of symptoms. The patient showed a favorable evolution, with no recurrence of symptoms, allowing for oxygen therapy weaning. A follow-up chest CT on the ninth day of hospitalization showed no significant alterations. This case highlights the importance of a thorough history in determining the etiology of a potentially fatal disease, adding intravenous epinephrine as a potential trigger of hemoptysis due to exogenous agents.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Patr&#237;cio, Ana Rafael, Filipe Concei&#231;&#65533;&#227;o, Jos&#233; Manuel Pereira, Jos&#233; Artur Paiva</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.75727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MnCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanostructure Anchored on Functionalized Carbon Black for the Enhanced Bifunctional Electrocatalytic Performance of OER and HER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bio.70052</link>
      <description>Sharmila Chandrasekaran, Shanmugam Vignesh, Muhammad Khalid, R. Mythili, Krishnapandi Alagumalai, A. Elangovan, Luminescence. 39(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405468353

                ABSTRACT The electrocatalytic oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions (OER and HER) are key processes used in energy storage and conversion. We have developed a highly efficient MnCo 2 O 4 nanostructure anchored with functionalized carbon black (MnCo 2 O 4 / f &#8208;CB), which has been characterized by XRD, FT&#8208;IR, Raman spectra, FE&#8208;SEM, and HR&#8208;TEM analyses as robust bifunctional electrocatalysts for both HER and OER. At a characteristic 10 mA cm &#8722;2 current density, the MnCo 2 O 4 / f &#8208;CB composite ECs exhibit low overpotentials of 330 mV for OER and 360 mV for HER, respectively. Furthermore, the MnCo 2 O 4 / f &#8208;CB composite ECs exhibit superior current density, the shortest Tafel slope, and admirable durable stability in OER and HER together. Due to the supported f &#8208;CB, the MnCo 2 O 4 composite catalyst has more active sites, effective charge transfer, and longer durability. A high&#8208;efficiency dual electrocatalyst can be developed from these highly efficient and dual ECs, which are comparable to standard noble metal&#8211;based catalysts. The synergetic coupling effects of high&#8208;activity f &#8208;CB and MnCo 2 O 4 composites with appropriate morphologies are critical factors for the enhanced catalytic performances of the MnCo 2 O 4 / f &#8208;CB composite.</description>
      <author>Sharmila Chandrasekaran, Shanmugam Vignesh, Muhammad Khalid, R. Mythili, Krishnapandi Alagumalai, A. Elangovan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bio.70052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal characteristics of ghosting flame in coal mine dead-end roadway pool fires affected by fire locations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241037</link>
      <description>Jingxin Wang, Baolin Qu, Meng Yu, Chenguang Zhao, Yongzheng Yao, Bing Wu, Physics of Fluids. 36(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405514639

                As an important phenomenon in the evolution of fire, the ghosting flame exhibits dynamic and irregular behavior in environments with limited ventilation. By ghosting flame, we mean the phenomenon where the flame separates from the fuel surface under certain conditions. This study investigates the combustion characteristics of the ghosting flame in pool fires within a coal mine dead-end roadway by small-scale experiments. Results indicate that the ghosting flame appears more readily and earlier when the fire source is closer to the heading face or when the oil pan size is larger. Additionally, the fire source's location significantly influences the type of ghosting flame observed. When the fire source is near the heading face, the flame predominantly exhibits horizontal-type ghosting flame; however, when the fire source is at the entrance of the roadway, only the edge-type ghosting flame occurs. Furthermore, dead-end roadway fires easily transition to ventilation-controlled conditions, leading to a continuous increase in the mass loss rate. The occurrence of a ghosting flame does not result in a sudden change in the mass loss rate. Moreover, the transient oxygen volume fraction when the ghosting flame occurs is related to the ghosting flame type and is also affected by ventilation conditions, fuel types, roadway structure, and the location of measurement points. Importantly, the root cause for the occurrence of the ghosting flame lies in the pressure differential generated by the temperature disparity between the two sides of the fire source.</description>
      <author>Jingxin Wang, Baolin Qu, Meng Yu, Chenguang Zhao, Yongzheng Yao, Bing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0241037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Array of metabolic pathways in a kleptoplastidic foraminiferan protist supports chemoautotrophy in dark, euxinic seafloor sediments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae248</link>
      <description>Fatma Gomaa, Daniel R. Rogers, Daniel R. Utter, Christopher Powers, I-Ting Huang, David J. Beaudoin, Ying Zhang, Colleen M. Cavanaugh, Virginia P. Edgcomb, Joan M. Bernhard, The ISME Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405386725

                Abstract Investigations of the metabolic capabilities of anaerobic protists advances our understanding of the evolution of eukaryotic life on Earth and for uncovering analogous extraterrestrial complex microbial life. Certain species of foraminiferan protists live in environments analogous to early Earth conditions when eukaryotes evolved, including sulfidic, anoxic, and hypoxic sediment porewaters. Foraminifera are known to form symbioses as well as to harbor organelles from other eukaryotes (chloroplasts), possibly bolstering the host&#8217;s independence from oxygen. The full extent of foraminiferal physiological capabilities is not fully understood. To date, evidence for foraminiferal anaerobiosis was gleaned from specimens first subjected to stresses associated with removal from in situ conditions. Here, we report comprehensive gene expression analysis of benthic foraminiferal populations preserved in situ on the euxinic (anoxic and sulfidic) bathyal seafloor, thus avoiding environmental alterations associated with sample recovery, including pressure reduction, sunlight exposure, warming, and oxygenation. Metatranscriptomics, metagenome-assembled genomes, and measurements of substrate uptake were used to study the kleptoplastidic foraminifer Nonionella stella inhabiting sulfur-oxidizing bacterial mats of the Santa Barbara Basin, off California. We show N. stella energy generation under dark euxinia is unusual because it orchestrates complex metabolic pathways for ATP production and carbon fixation through the Calvin cycle. These pathways include extended glycolysis, anaerobic fermentation, sulfide oxidation, and the presence of a membrane-bound inorganic pyrophosphatase, an enzyme that hydrolyzes inorganic pyrophosphate to actively pump protons across the mitochondrial membrane.</description>
      <author>Fatma Gomaa, Daniel R. Rogers, Daniel R. Utter, Christopher Powers, I-Ting Huang, David J. Beaudoin, Ying Zhang, Colleen M. Cavanaugh, Virginia P. Edgcomb, Joan M. Bernhard</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparison of the Electronic Properties of Selected Antioxidants Vitamin C, Uric Acid, NAC and Melatonin with Guanosine Derivatives: A Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29245944</link>
      <description>Boles&#322;aw T. Karwowski, Molecules. 29(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405476248

                Each cell in the human body is continually exposed to harmful external and internal factors. During evolution, cells have developed various defence systems, divided into enzymatic and non-enzymatic types, to which low-weight molecule antioxidants belong. In this article, the ionisation potential and electron affinity, as well as global reactivity descriptors of Vitamin C, Melatonin, Uric Acids, and N-acetyl-L-cysteine, were theoretically investigated at the MP-2/aug-cc-pVTZ level of theory in the condensed (aqueous) phase. The vertical ionisation potential and electron affinity are discussed in terms of non-equilibrated and equilibrated solvent&#8211;solute interactions. Additionally, at the same theoretical level, the electronic properties of canonical and oxidised derivatives of guanine were analysed. The presented results indicate that the selected antioxidants for this study (Vitamin C, Uric Acid, NAC, and Melatonin) exhibit the highest adiabatic electron affinity, while guanine derivatives (Gua, OXOGua, Guo, dGuo, OXOGuo, OXOdGuo) are more prone to adiabatic radical cation formation. A red-ox balance (redox homeostasis) is crucial for intracellular signalling pathways that are reactive oxygen and nitrogen species (RO/NS)-dependent. Should this gentle balance be disrupted, either by an overload or deficit of species, physiological consequences may result, which in turn lead to pathological outcomes. On the other hand, maintaining the stability of the above balance of antioxidants/radicals may result in the improved effectiveness and safety of anticancer radiotherapy/chemotherapy or combined therapies with a subsequent increase in a patient&#8217;s quality of life.</description>
      <author>Boles&#322;aw T. Karwowski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29245944</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underground Reservoirs Regulate the Composition and Metabolism of Microbial Community in Coal Mine Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c09348</link>
      <description>Yang Li, Min Wu, Haiqin Zhang, Binbin Jiang, Yixiang Bao, Jie Li, Jing&#8208;Feng Li, Peng Li, Xinyue Yan, Tianqi Qin, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405372559

                Underground reservoirs were used to purify water through filtration, adsorption, and biodegradation methods in coal mines. However, their effects on the composition and metabolism of microbial communities in mine water remain unknown. In this study, influent and effluent samples from underground reservoirs in seven coal mining areas were analyzed to compare their microbial community compositions and metabolites. The results indicate that the underground reservoirs can significantly reduce the chemical oxygen demand (COD) levels of mine water (values range from 7.79 to 8.50 for influent and 7.40 to 8.50 for effluent) and regulate water chemistry characteristics such as pH (values range from 7&#8211;1980 for influent and 5&#8211;20 for effluent). Since COD reflects the quantity of reducing substances in water, while total dissolved solids (TDS) indicates the total amount of dissolved solids, both parameters directly influence the physicochemical properties of water. This, in turn, affects microbial growth and metabolic pathways. Consequently, changes in these factors can lead to variations in microbial community composition as well as decreases in the Chao1 and Shannon indices. Underground reservoirs decreased the relative abundance of phyla Actinomycetota and Spirochaetota, and the decreased microbial groups were mainly belonging to phylum Bacillota. In addition, higher concentrations of metabolites, including lipids and lipid-like molecules, mixed metal/nonmetal compounds, hydrocarbon derivatives, nucleosides, nucleotides, and analogues were detected in the effluent samples, and most of them were related to taurine and hypotaurine metabolism, selenocompound metabolism, glyoxylate and dicarboxylate metabolism, riboflavin metabolism, and the citrate cycle. In summary, this study provided theoretical and experimental support for the evolution mechanism of mine water quality in coal mine underground reservoirs.</description>
      <author>Yang Li, Min Wu, Haiqin Zhang, Binbin Jiang, Yixiang Bao, Jie Li, Jing&#8208;Feng Li, Peng Li, Xinyue Yan, Tianqi Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c09348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: Role of the Southern Ocean in atmospheric pCO2 change: observations, simulations and paleorecords</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1531887</link>
      <description>Zhifang Xiong, Xu Zhang, Di Qi, Jun Zhao, Thomas J. Algeo, Frontiers in Marine Science. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405471327

                The Southern Ocean plays a key role in atmospheric CO2 sequestration, accounting for ~40-50% of the anthropogenic CO2 absorbed by the modern ocean (Landsch&#252;tzer et al., 2015;Gruber et al., 2019). The Southern Ocean also played a critical role in modulating variation in the atmospheric partial pressure of carbon dioxide (pCO2) in the geologic past on both orbital and millennial timescales (Anderson et al., 2009;Sigman et al., 2010;Gottschalk et al., 2016).Moreover, the Southern Ocean influences atmospheric and oceanic circulation in the tropics remotely, including low-latitude atmospheric CO2 exchange (Sarmiento et al., 2004;Hendry and Brzezinski, 2014;Sigman et al., 2021). Thus, the Southern Ocean is a key component of the global climate system through its influence on atmospheric CO2 variations at a range of timescales (Fischer et al., 2010;Rae et al., 2018;Dong et al., 2024) processes. These articles can be classified into the three themes explored below.Li et al. analyzed sea-surface temperature (SST) data from the Southern Ocean since 1870 to resolve why SSTs have been cooling since 1980 despite a global warming trend (Yang et al., 2023). They found that three main modes (i.e., the Global Temperature Anomaly, Atlantic Multidecadal Oscillation (AMO), and El Ni&#241;o-Southern Oscillation (ENSO)) can explain over 70% of SST variability. The negative phase of the AMO and the positive phase of the ENSO counteract the effects of global warming, resulting in a cooling trend in Southern Ocean SSTs since 1980.Zhang et al. identified strong seasonal variations of siliceous microplankton fluxes and radiolarian assemblages from a sediment trap, which are dominated by seasonality in sea ice cover and plankton community composition in Prydz Bay polynya, Antarctica. The results of this study provide new insights concerning the fluxes and assemblages of siliceous microplankton as carbon-cycle proxies in the geological past (Ragueneau et al., 2000;Tr&#233;guer et al., 2017).Fe (FeHR) and organic carbon in surface sediments from Prydz Bay and the adjacent Southern Ocean. They discovered that the FeHR to total Fe (FeT) ratios are lowest for the surface sediments in the global ocean due to weak bedrock weathering and slow glacier melting. They proposed that the influence of FeHR on sedimentary organic matter significantly varies across different sedimentary environments and sediment categories. high versus low FeHR/FeT, respectively), which are linked to lower Fe solubility and primary production in the water column and to greater carbonate dilution/dissolution at proximal versus distal sites. This study underscores the significance of Fe dynamics in regulating glacialinterglacial atmospheric pCO2 variation in multiple oceanic regions, particularly in the Southern Ocean, where variation in dust delivery on glacial-interglacial timescales is pronounced (Lamy et al., 2014;Mart&#237;nez-Garc&#237;a et al., 2014).The influence of the Southern Ocean on atmospheric pCO2 and global climate evolution is complicated, being related not only to the carbon cycle but also to the nitrogen and silicon cycles, sulfur and oxygen cycles, iron cycle, hydrological cycle, and icesheet/ice shelf dynamics. The articles collected on this Research Topic represent state-of-the-art investigations into the above-mentioned biogeochemical and dynamic processes at a range of timescales based on modern observations, paleoclimate data, and model simulations. These collective efforts are of great scientific significance in providing new insights concerning the role of the Southern Ocean in modulating variations in atmospheric pCO2 and global climate in the past, present and future. Despite the progress made by the studies in this Research Topic, key scientific issues remain incompletely understood and will require further investigation in the future in order to achieve a better understanding of the role of the Southern Ocean in global climate change from the perspective of the carbon cycle.</description>
      <author>Zhifang Xiong, Xu Zhang, Di Qi, Jun Zhao, Thomas J. Algeo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1531887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;ACS Applied Materials &amp;amp; Interfaces&lt;/i&gt; Family Early Career Forum 2024</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01740</link>
      <description>Xing Yi Ling, ACS Applied Bio Materials. 7(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405417287

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. ACS Applied Bio MaterialsVol 7/Issue 12Article This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialDecember 16, 2024ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces Family Early Career Forum 2024Click to copy article linkArticle link copied!Xing Yi LingXing Yi LingMore by Xing Yi Linghttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-5495-6428Open PDFACS Applied Bio MaterialsCite this: ACS Appl. Bio Mater. 2024, 7, 12, 7788&#8211;7790Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsabm.4c01740https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01740Published December 16, 2024 Publication History Received 19 November 2024Published online 16 December 2024Published in issue 16 December 2024editorialCopyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS PublicationsCopyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.BatteriesBiomaterialsCircuitsMaterialsThermoelectric materialsSPECIAL ISSUEThis article is part of the Early Career Forum 2024 special issue.We are delighted to present the 2024 ACS AMI Family Early Career Forum, showcasing 135 exceptional contributions from early career scientists worldwide (Figure 1). Among these, there are a total of 25 contributions to ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces, 22 to ACS Applied Energy Materials, 23 to ACS Applied Bio Materials, 18 to ACS Applied Polymer Materials, 17 to ACS Applied Nano Materials, 14 to ACS Applied Electronic Materials, 11 to ACS Applied Optical Materials, and 5 to ACS Applied Engineering Materials.Figure 1Figure 1. Geographical distribution of authors for the articles in the Applied Materials Portfolio Journals' Early Career Forum.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThis Forum highlights groundbreaking research and innovative ideas from the emerging authors in the scientific community. A broad range of topics are covered, among these, energy and biorelated research take center stage, with a significant number of papers dedicated to these fields. Given the diversity of the topics, it is challenging to single out individual contributions. Instead, I have approached this by analyzing the prevailing trends across the Forum.Energy research is undergoing a transformative phase, fueled by advancements in catalysts, photocatalysts, batteries materials, and fabrication techniques. These breakthroughs are driving innovations in energy storage, harvesting, and conversion technologies, offering sustainable and efficient solutions for the future. Multifunction catalysts and photocatalysts materials are unlocking new potential in applications such as zinc&#8211;air batteries, hydrogen production, and water splitting. (1&#8722;4)Progress in advanced photovoltaic materials, including perovskites and photonic nanomaterials, is accelerating renewable energy technologies. Thermoelectric materials enable the conversion of low-grade heat into usable energy, whereas lightweight, flexible materials, such as 2D structures and thin-film polymers, are paving the way for scalable solar films and stretchable thermoelectric generators. (5&#8722;7)In biomaterials, different types of nanoparticles are revolutionizing cancer therapy, imaging, and biosensor technologies. Stimuli-responsive materials are employed for targeted drug delivery and advanced medical applications. Meanwhile, bioinks and 3D-printed biomaterials are driving breakthroughs in tissue engineering and wound healing, combining biocompatibility with functional properties to support regenerative medicine. (8&#8722;12)I would like to highlight a few noteworthy articles in key themes such as energy, catalysis, and device technologies. In a perspective, Xin et al. discuss nonconventional electrochemical reactions in rechargeable lithium&#8211;sulfur (Li&#8211;S) batteries, addressing the challenge of unstable polysulfide intermediates. The authors review innovative strategies to enhance battery stability and performance, focusing on modifications to sulfur allotropes, electrolyte composition, and electrode design. (13) In a related study, Shi et al. investigate the nucleation mechanisms of lithium pits and their morphological evolution across large electrode areas. Their findings reveal that overpotential is inversely related to pit radius and exponentially related to nucleation rate, offering new insights for predicting and controlling surface area and roughness in lithium electrodes under various stripping conditions (Figure 2). (14)Figure 2Figure 2. Selected graphics from ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces Early Career Forum, showcasing energy-related research, including studies on lithium&#8211;sulfur batteries and lithium pit nucleation.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideIn the rapidly growing area of electronics, two particularly exciting fields&#9472;optoelectronic synapses and heat harvesting&#9472;are showcased. Xu and co-workers present an organic optoelectronic synapse with multilevel memory, enabled by gate modulation. It mimics synaptic plasticity with both volatile and nonvolatile states, transitioning between short-term and long-term plasticity through gate voltage and light exposure. The device offers program/erase current ratios and stability, making it a promising candidate for neuromorphic systems in image processing and memory retention (Figure 3A). (15) In parallel, Cai et al. introduce a heat harvesting system that combines daytime radiative cooling with thermally regenerative electrochemical cycles (TREC). Using nanoporous polyethylene and MXene, the system passively generates a 35 &#176;C temperature difference under sunlight, converting ambient heat into continuous electricity with a 50 mV cell voltage and over 20 mAh/g specific capacity, without external charging (Figure 3B). (16)Figure 3Figure 3. Selected graphics from ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces Early Career Forum. (A) Organic optoelectronic synapse with multilevel memory capabilities, demonstrating synaptic plasticity transitions between short-term and long-term memory states. (B) Low-grade heat harvesting system combining daytime radiative cooling with thermally regenerative electrochemical cycles, achieving continuous electricity generation.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideFinally, we extend our heartfelt thanks to all the authors, reviewers, and editors who made this third edition of the Early Career Forum a success. We look forward to continuing this tradition of recognizing early career researchers in future editions. Be sure to explore many other outstanding articles published across the ACS Applied Materials family journals. Access the full Forum at each of the family journals below:ACS Applied Bio Materials: Volume 7, Issue 12ACS Applied Electronic Materials: Volume 6, Issue 12ACS Applied Energy Materials: Volume 7, Issue 24ACS Applied Engineering Materials: Volume 2, Issue 12ACS Applied Nano Materials: Volume 7, Issue 23ACS Applied Optical Materials: Volume 2, Issue 12ACS Applied Polymer Materials: Volume 6, Issue 23Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!AuthorXing Yi Ling, https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5495-6428NotesViews expressed in this editorial are those of the author and not necessarily the views of the ACS.ReferencesClick to copy section linkSection link copied! This article references 16 other publications. 1Aziz, T.; Kumar, A.; Awasthi, M. K.; Kharwar, Y. P.; Karajagi, I.; Vishal, V.; Ghosh, P. C.; Dubal, D. P.; Dutta, P. A Multi-Interfacial Material Design Leading Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction and Water Oxidation Electrocatalysis to Zinc&#8211;Air Battery Application. ACS Applied Energy Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaem.3c03031 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.2Chaurasia, S.; Aravamuthan, S. R.; Sullivan, C.; Ross, M. B.; Agar, E. Investigating Manganese&#8211;Vanadium Redox Flow Batteries for Energy Storage and Subsequent Hydrogen Generation. ACS Applied Energy Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaem.4c00089 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.3Verma, R.; Rani, R.; Choubey, P.; Sharma, A.; Basu, m. Au Nanoparticles on In2S3/In2O3 Nanopyramids Increase Photoanodic Activity in Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting. ACS Applied Nano Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsanm.4c03123 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.4Shukla, G.; Kumbhar, G.; Bruggeman, C.; Curley, S. J.; Szczepanski, C. R.; Hickey, D. P.; Ferrier, R. C. Poly(vinylidene difluoride-co-hexafluoropropylene) Grafted with Polyether Amphoteric Ion-Exchange Membranes for Aqueous Redox Flow Batteries. ACS Applied Energy Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaem.4c00014 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.5Han, X.; Yang, X.; Zhang, K. A Conformable and Stretchable Thermoelectric Generator for Efficient Body Heat Harvesting. ACS Applied Electronic Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaelm.3c01851 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.6Pramanik, S.; Sengupta, C.; Sharma, S.; Mondal, S.; Goswami, D. K.; Mondal, T. Advancement of 2D Material-Based Moisture-Enabled Nanogenerators. ACS Applied Electronic Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaelm.3c01860 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.7Han, D.; Yang, X.; Liu, J.; Ye, L. Tuning the Aggregated Structure of Polymer Interlayers for High-Performance Quantum Dot Solar Cells and Photodetectors. ACS Applied Polymer Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsapm.3c03210 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.8Pe&#241;as-N&#250;&#241;ez, S. J.; Mecerreyes, D.; Criado-Gonzalez, M. Recent Advances and Developments in Injectable Conductive Polymer Gels for Bioelectronics. ACS Applied Bio Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsabm.3c01224 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.9Tricou, L.-P.; Guirguis, N.; Cherifi, K.; Matoori, S. Zeolite-Loaded Hydrogels as Wound pH-Modulating Dressings for Diabetic Wound Healing. ACS Applied Bio Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsabm.4c00332 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.10Thai, N. L. B.; Beaman, H. T.; Perlman, M.; Obeng, E. E.; Du, C.; Monroe, M. B. B. Chitosan Poly(vinyl alcohol) Methacrylate Hydrogels for Tissue Engineering Scaffolds. ACS Applied Bio Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsabm.3c01209 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.11Shin, J.; Jang, Y. Multicompartment Synthetic Vesicles for Artificial Cell Applications. ACS Applied Engineering Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaenm.3c00812 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.12Wang, Y.; Lyu, Y.; Li, Z. Constitutionally Isomeric Peptides: Subtle Changes Leading to Dramatic Differences in Properties. ACS Applied Engineering Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaenm.3c00787 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.13Tan, S.-J.; Feng, X.-X.; Wang, Y.-H.; Guo, Y.-G.; Xin, S. Nonconventional Electrochemical Reactions in Rechargeable Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsami.4c03201 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.14Zhang, H.; Ulusel, M.; Shi, F. Nucleation of Pitting and Evolution of Stripping on Lithium-Metal Anodes. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsami.4c01530 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.15Guo, H.; Guo, J.; Wang, Y.; Wang, H.; Cheng, S.; Wang, Z.; Miao, Q.; Xu, X. An Organic Optoelectronic Synapse with Multilevel Memory Enabled by Gate Modulation. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsami.3c19624 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.16Woo, H. K.; Zhou, K.; Choi, Y. Y.; Cai, L. Elevating Low-Grade Heat Harvesting with Daytime Radiative Cooling and Solar Heating in Thermally Regenerative Electrochemical Cycles. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsami.3c19498 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.Cited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferences Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsACS Applied Bio MaterialsCite this: ACS Appl. Bio Mater. 2024, 7, 12, 7788&#8211;7790Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01740Published December 16, 2024 Publication History Received 19 November 2024Published online 16 December 2024Published in issue 16 December 2024Copyright &#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesFigure 1Figure 1. Geographical distribution of authors for the articles in the Applied Materials Portfolio Journals' Early Career Forum.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideFigure 2Figure 2. Selected graphics from ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces Early Career Forum, showcasing energy-related research, including studies on lithium&#8211;sulfur batteries and lithium pit nucleation.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideFigure 3Figure 3. Selected graphics from ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces Early Career Forum. (A) Organic optoelectronic synapse with multilevel memory capabilities, demonstrating synaptic plasticity transitions between short-term and long-term memory states. (B) Low-grade heat harvesting system combining daytime radiative cooling with thermally regenerative electrochemical cycles, achieving continuous electricity generation.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideReferences This article references 16 other publications. 1Aziz, T.; Kumar, A.; Awasthi, M. K.; Kharwar, Y. P.; Karajagi, I.; Vishal, V.; Ghosh, P. C.; Dubal, D. P.; Dutta, P. A Multi-Interfacial Material Design Leading Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction and Water Oxidation Electrocatalysis to Zinc&#8211;Air Battery Application. ACS Applied Energy Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaem.3c03031 There is no corresponding record for this reference.2Chaurasia, S.; Aravamuthan, S. R.; Sullivan, C.; Ross, M. B.; Agar, E. Investigating Manganese&#8211;Vanadium Redox Flow Batteries for Energy Storage and Subsequent Hydrogen Generation. ACS Applied Energy Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaem.4c00089 There is no corresponding record for this reference.3Verma, R.; Rani, R.; Choubey, P.; Sharma, A.; Basu, m. Au Nanoparticles on In2S3/In2O3 Nanopyramids Increase Photoanodic Activity in Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting. ACS Applied Nano Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsanm.4c03123 There is no corresponding record for this reference.4Shukla, G.; Kumbhar, G.; Bruggeman, C.; Curley, S. J.; Szczepanski, C. R.; Hickey, D. P.; Ferrier, R. C. Poly(vinylidene difluoride-co-hexafluoropropylene) Grafted with Polyether Amphoteric Ion-Exchange Membranes for Aqueous Redox Flow Batteries. ACS Applied Energy Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaem.4c00014 There is no corresponding record for this reference.5Han, X.; Yang, X.; Zhang, K. A Conformable and Stretchable Thermoelectric Generator for Efficient Body Heat Harvesting. ACS Applied Electronic Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaelm.3c01851 There is no corresponding record for this reference.6Pramanik, S.; Sengupta, C.; Sharma, S.; Mondal, S.; Goswami, D. K.; Mondal, T. Advancement of 2D Material-Based Moisture-Enabled Nanogenerators. ACS Applied Electronic Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaelm.3c01860 There is no corresponding record for this reference.7Han, D.; Yang, X.; Liu, J.; Ye, L. Tuning the Aggregated Structure of Polymer Interlayers for High-Performance Quantum Dot Solar Cells and Photodetectors. ACS Applied Polymer Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsapm.3c03210 There is no corresponding record for this reference.8Pe&#241;as-N&#250;&#241;ez, S. J.; Mecerreyes, D.; Criado-Gonzalez, M. Recent Advances and Developments in Injectable Conductive Polymer Gels for Bioelectronics. ACS Applied Bio Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsabm.3c01224 There is no corresponding record for this reference.9Tricou, L.-P.; Guirguis, N.; Cherifi, K.; Matoori, S. Zeolite-Loaded Hydrogels as Wound pH-Modulating Dressings for Diabetic Wound Healing. ACS Applied Bio Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsabm.4c00332 There is no corresponding record for this reference.10Thai, N. L. B.; Beaman, H. T.; Perlman, M.; Obeng, E. E.; Du, C.; Monroe, M. B. B. Chitosan Poly(vinyl alcohol) Methacrylate Hydrogels for Tissue Engineering Scaffolds. ACS Applied Bio Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsabm.3c01209 There is no corresponding record for this reference.11Shin, J.; Jang, Y. Multicompartment Synthetic Vesicles for Artificial Cell Applications. ACS Applied Engineering Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaenm.3c00812 There is no corresponding record for this reference.12Wang, Y.; Lyu, Y.; Li, Z. Constitutionally Isomeric Peptides: Subtle Changes Leading to Dramatic Differences in Properties. ACS Applied Engineering Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsaenm.3c00787 There is no corresponding record for this reference.13Tan, S.-J.; Feng, X.-X.; Wang, Y.-H.; Guo, Y.-G.; Xin, S. Nonconventional Electrochemical Reactions in Rechargeable Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsami.4c03201 There is no corresponding record for this reference.14Zhang, H.; Ulusel, M.; Shi, F. Nucleation of Pitting and Evolution of Stripping on Lithium-Metal Anodes. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsami.4c01530 There is no corresponding record for this reference.15Guo, H.; Guo, J.; Wang, Y.; Wang, H.; Cheng, S.; Wang, Z.; Miao, Q.; Xu, X. An Organic Optoelectronic Synapse with Multilevel Memory Enabled by Gate Modulation. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsami.3c19624 There is no corresponding record for this reference.16Woo, H. K.; Zhou, K.; Choi, Y. Y.; Cai, L. Elevating Low-Grade Heat Harvesting with Daytime Radiative Cooling and Solar Heating in Thermally Regenerative Electrochemical Cycles. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsami.3c19498 There is no corresponding record for this reference.</description>
      <author>Xing Yi Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Australian and New Zealand Intensive Care Society Paediatric Study Group (ANZICS PSG): 20 Years of Collaborative Research</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1097/pcc.0000000000003653</link>
      <description>Kristen Gibbons, John Beca, Carmel Delzoppo, Simon Erickson, Marino Festa, Ben Gelbart, Debbie Long, Kate Masterson, Johnny Millar, Sainath Raman, Luregn J. Schlapbach, Warwick Butt, Pediatric Critical Care Medicine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405498380

                Despite the challenges posed by vast geographical distances and relatively small populations (Australia: 26 million, New Zealand: 5 million), Australia and New Zealand (ANZ) are renowned for their high quality innovative pediatric intensive care research. A strong culture of partnership across units led to the formation of the ANZ Intensive Care Society Paediatric Study Group (ANZICS PSG) in 2003, which has evolved since its formation into one of the leading international pediatric intensive care trial networks, along with two in the United States (1,2) and one in the United Kingdom (3). Here, we describe the factors leading to the growth of the ANZICS PSG, explore the current established research ecosystem, along with future plans to sustain success. ORIGINS OF ANZICS PSG The ANZICS PSG was established in 2003 as a working group of the ANZICS Clinical Trials Group (CTG), which had been in existence since 1993. This administrative change recognized the need for an organized research network of PICUs in ANZ. All PSG Member PICUs were based in specialist pediatric, nonprofit, public, university teaching hospitals. By 2003, ANZ already had established a centralized training body for pediatric intensive care medicine (initially as a Joint Faculty of the ANZ College of Anaesthetists and Royal Australasian College of Physicians started in 1998, and subsequently as a stand-alone College of Intensive Care Medicine in 2001). Recognition of the importance of clinical research for physicians in subspecialty training was underscored by the requirement that trainees had to carry out a research project. The College of Intensive Care Medicine set expectations and standards for ANZ PICUs, including recommendations for permanent Data Manager and Research Coordinator positions in all PICUs. Since the inaugural meeting of the ANZICS PSG in Sydney, New South Wales in 2003, representation was broadened to ensure inclusion of Research Coordinators and Nurse Researchers, as well as regional representatives. In 1998, the CTG had recognized the pivotal role of Research Coordinators in the design, management, and conduct of clinical trials in adult ICUs in ANZ. Soon after, it formed the Intensive Care Research Coordinators Interest Group to facilitate peer-led guidance necessary to support isolated individuals providing local clinical research infrastructure. In 2019, the PSG formally instituted a similar Paediatric Intensive Care Research Coordinator Interest Group. Between 2003 and 2023, the ANZICS PSG has endorsed more than 25 studies led by physicians, nurses, allied health professionals, and statisticians. ANZICS PSG studies cover a range of research designs, recognizing the importance of a pipeline capable of bridging observational data on burden of disease, consumer engagement, and pilot studies to generate the necessary steps toward high-quality clinical trials (Fig. 1). In 2004 and 2005, the PSG carried out multicenter, prospective observational studies on prevalence of acute lung injury (4) and hyperglycemia (5), which established collaboration between PICUs and processes needed for centralized study management and data collection. Then, from 2006 to 2010, we used this organizational infrastructure to carry out our first phase II multicenter randomized controlled trial (RCT) of hypothermia therapy for traumatic brain injury (TBI) in children (6). Invitation to the PSG to participate in the 2007&#8211;2011 phase III international "Cool Kids" (hypothermia vs. normothermia after severe TBI in children) RCT (7) followed and helped to establish the PSG as an international research partner.Figure 1.: Australian and New Zealand Intensive Care Society Paediatric Study Group (PSG) research ecosystem strategy. ANZPICR = Australian and New Zealand Paediatric Intensive Care Registry, ECR = Early Career Researcher, LTOs = long-term outcomes, MDT = multidisciplinary team.In recent years, like the U.S. and U.K. study groups (1&#8211;3), the ANZICS PSG membership has grown and diversified to include dieticians, pharmacists, and physiotherapists, as well as researchers from key academic partners. Working groups have been established to advance and coordinate the research focus and outcomes, the capacity given our population size, and the capability given our resources. We have also included consumer engagement, data science specialists, and new and early career investigators (Fig. 2).Figure 2.: Timeline of key milestones of the Australian and New Zealand Intensive Care Society Paediatric Study Group (ANZICS PSG) and Australian and New Zealand Paediatric Intensive Care Registry (ANZPICR). *Australian and New Zealand PICU trial run by a Paediatric Study Group member but not submitted for endorsement. ALI = acute lung injury, DAB = Dexamethasone and Adrenaline for Bronchiolitis, DAISY = Detecting Neurodevelopmental Impairments after Critical Illness in Young Children, HitBIC = Hypothermia for Traumatic Brain Injury in Children, NARES = Normal saline and lung recruitment with paediatric endotracheal suction, NITRIC = Nitric Oxide During Cardiopulmonary Bypass to Improve Recovery in Infants With Congenital Heart Defects, PIM = Pediatric Index of Mortality, PIRCIG = Paediatric Intensive Care Research Coordinator Interest Group, REDUCE = REstrictive versus StandarD FlUid Management in Mechanically Ventilated ChildrEn Admitted to PICU, RESPOND = Resuscitation in Paediatric Sepsis Using Metabolic Resuscitation, SPICE = Sedation Practice in Intensive Care Evaluation, SPLYT-P = 0.9% Sodium Chloride, Gluconate/Acetate Buffered Solution, and Lactate Buffered Solution for Intravenous Fluid Therapy in Critically Ill Children, THRIVE = Transnasal Humidified Rapid Insufflation Ventilatory Exchange in children requiring emergent intubation, WG = Working Group.THE ANZICS CTG: LEVERAGING PARTNERSHIPS Both the PSG and CTG operate within the organizational structure of ANZICS. This provides a strong foundation for embedding the pediatric intensive care research agenda in the broader aims of the Society and its members. In 2003, the PSG found a natural home within the ANZICS CTG, which provided administrative and secretarial support as well as the opportunity to observe and collaborate with the adult intensive care scientific community, which was rapidly gaining a reputation for clinical trials relevant to real world practice. In recent years, exchange between pediatric and adult clinical trialists has helped facilitate the design and conduct of RCTs in children, by targeting the gap between adult ICU and PICU trials, which has enabled pediatric trials to occur even though, previously, they seemed unachievable. For example, in the period 2015 to 2021, adult ICU-inspired pediatric RCTs have investigated the role of vitamin C in sepsis (8), early adrenaline in sepsis (9), a comparison of dexmedetomidine to midazolam for sedation (10), and the use of high-flow during intubation (11). Seasoned CTG trialists provide mentorship, not only for the conduct of trials, but also for early career research development. The CTG has demonstrated that the path to sustainable, world-leading intensive care research is developed by network wide collaboration, a strong sense of partnership, dedication to fostering novice researchers, and regular face-to-face meetings. The annual CTG Scientific Meeting, conducted in Noosa (a resort town in Queensland, Australia), enables pediatric researchers to propose study designs, develop ideas, seek critical input and support for trials, and leverage the expertise of both adult and pediatric research groups to enhance research methodology. THE AUSTRALIAN AND NEW ZEALAND PAEDIATRIC INTENSIVE CARE REGISTRY The Australian and New Zealand Paediatric Intensive Care Registry (ANZPICR) was founded in 1996. Its history has played an important part in the evolution of the PSG. It started with the development of the Pediatric Index of Mortality (PIM), a locally derived and validated prediction mortality score, requiring information from consecutive admissions to all seven specialist PICUs in Australia between 1994 and 1996 (12). This work was instrumental in enabling an international comparison between two models of PICU care: the distributed provision across Trent, United Kingdom, vs. the centralized model in Victoria, Australia (13). Based on 1994&#8211;1995 risk-adjusted mortality the authors demonstrated a possible excess mortality in the decentralized model of PICU organization. Subsequent iterations to PIM occurred in 2003 and 2013, PIM 2 (14) and PIM 3 (15), respectively. Now, the ANZPICR dataset is a health service mandatory requirement with central data quality checks that includes any and all ICUs admitting children. This process has fostered standardization of care, clinical collaboration, and benchmarking of practice. ANZICS PSG research using ANZPICR data has always been carried out as a collaborative undertaking between the PSG and ANZPICR. This activity has strengthened PSG productivity with observational studies in its early years and given ANZPICR clinicians' data to undertake secondary research. These investigations have assessed burden of disease (16), changes in therapies, diseases, and outcomes (17,18), and explored outcomes in specific diseases or populations (19&#8211;22). ANZPICR data are a frequently used and valuable resource for researchers providing accurate, contemporary, and population-based information about potential study participant numbers, use of individual therapies, and ICU and hospital outcomes. In recent years, the linkage of additional datasets with the comprehensive ANZPICR dataset, spanning more than 2 decades of PICU admission in ANZ, has uncovered in-depth insights into the risk factors and consequences of critical illness in children, which can inform future research and practice (23,24). Building on this extensive experience and sustainably funded registry, the focus of the ongoing PSG and ANZPICR partnership is now turning toward registry-embedded trials and how registry data and infrastructure might be used to collect short- and long-term outcomes for RCTs. As ANZPICR embarks on collection of long-term nonmortality outcomes (https://www.anzics.org/patient-reported-outcomes-and-experience-measures/), incorporation of core outcome sets to improve consistency and completeness of outcome data for clinical trials is gaining traction (25). EVOLUTION OF ANZICS PSG RCTs Over the past decade, the PSG has undergone an evolution in use of trial designs, marked by the transition from pilot studies, to traditional RCTs, with a more recent move toward incorporating digital and pragmatic trial strategies using innovative design (Fig. 2). This journey has been propelled by several success factors. First, the cultivation of a collective ethos, fostering collaboration and enthusiasm among multidisciplinary teams across ANZ PICUs and academic partners. Accordingly, in recent years, we have witnessed an increase in the diversity of professions leading ANZICS PSG studies. This has resulted in a balanced portfolio of studies addressing a more comprehensive range of clinical questions along the patient journey compared with earlier studies by our group. Second, our increasing familiarity with interventional trials has enabled confidence and a "can do attitude" that has led to increased sample sizes, and the ability to move from small-scale pilot studies to comprehensive trials that encompass diverse patient populations. Lessons gleaned from our catalogue of RCTs (6,8,11,26&#8211;28), and the timeline (Fig. 2), have not only provided invaluable insights into the development of robust trial methodologies, key criteria for successful collaboration, and utility of pilot work, but additionally fostered trust and collegiality in our collaborations, and created a spirit where performing RCTs in critically ill children is considered an essential component of PICU practice, rather than being burdensome. Third, the employment of pragmatic research designs (29) has facilitated empowerment and agency for PICU clinical teams and families, and has demonstrated feasibility of conducting interventional research in a high-risk context, such as acute cardiopulmonary bypass surgery where a consent rate of 73% was achieved (26). Fourth, we have benefited considerably from the implementation and research of alternative consent models, notably consent-to-continue (8,11,28), using similar approaches to studies led from the U.K. Paediatric Critical Care Society Study Group (3). By embracing novel consent frameworks, we have enhanced recruitment rates and streamlined trial processes while upholding ethical standards and safeguarding participant rights. However, consent-to-continue models remain challenged in some jurisdictions in ANZ, which represents an ongoing risk to the sustainability of effective interventional research in our setting. Finally, in the absence of a national trial unit comparable to the Intensive Care National Audit and Research Centre in the United Kingdom, we have sought to leverage each ANZICS PSG study to develop a more sustainable trial infrastructure, developing a comprehensive modular package of digital solutions, including a Research Electronic Data Capture-embedded platform for enabling high-quality data capture, optimizing efficiency in trial methodology and infrastructure. Additionally, the pandemic experience has underscored the importance of remote monitoring capabilities and propelled our methodological research investigating research monitoring practices (30,31). This research underpins innovation in best-practice approaches to risk-based research monitoring, can streamline ethical approval, facilitate effective interaction with Data Safety Monitoring Boards, and enhance reproducibility of trial data. These collective advances have strengthened streamlined data collection and standardization, enhancing the efficiency and reliability of our research endeavors. To enable more robust strategic planning and focus, in 2020, the PSG conducted a research prioritization exercise, to define key areas of research for children in intensive care in ANZ (32). A three-stage modified Delphi survey followed by face-to-face meeting with Hanlon prioritization was completed by 193 medical and nursing members aiming to rank key themes of research as well as important outcomes. Examples of key themes included fluid and vasoactive therapies, family experience, care of staff, respiratory therapies such as oxygen, and quality improvement initiatives. Key prioritized outcomes in terms of feasibility included short-term mortality, resource use (PICU and hospital length of stay, duration of ventilation), and, in terms of overall priority, long-term survival with good neurodevelopment and health-related quality of life (HRQoL) as patient centered outcomes. This process provided the groundwork for developing a common framework for future research design and collaboration within the PSG. WHAT HAPPENS AFTER PICU: TOWARD LONG-TERM FOLLOW-UP An increase in survival rates over the last 2 decades has seen a shift away from mortality as a primary outcome and inclusion of the longer-term impacts of critical illness (33). The identification of HRQoL and long-term neurodevelopmental outcomes as critical for progressing research in the field, led to the formation of a PSG Long-term Outcomes Working Group (32). Currently, ANZ PICUs do not provide PICU follow-up services; recruitment into PSG research studies offering long-term follow-up is thus providing an emerging model of care to an underserved population. Accordingly, long-term outcomes have been included as secondary outcomes in most recent PSG trials where acute outcomes, such as ventilator-free days, are typically the primary outcome (8,26,34). In addition to HRQoL, we have developed a suite of validated questionnaires for follow-up by proxy incorporating more comprehensive domains under the post-intensive care syndrome-pediatrics framework such as adaptive/cognitive and behavioral function as well as family functioning and post-traumatic stress (35). As our understanding of the risk factors, biology, and long-term effects of interventions during critical illness remains incomplete, we are currently conducting a 5-year follow-up of the Nitric Oxide During Cardiopulmonary Bypass to Improve Recovery in Infants with Congenital Heart Defects (NITRIC) trial population using annual surveys, followed by face-to-face neuropsychologic assessment (36). Complementary to the above studies, we have endeavored in recent years to conduct observational and interventional trials primarily focused on long-term outcomes; including surveys, cohort studies, data linkage, and clinical trials of follow-up models of care (23,24,36,37). Analyzing over 5000 PICU survivors, features related to socioeconomic status emerged as a key feature associated with long-term educational outcomes in addition to critical illness features in our population. While ANZ are considered high-income countries, inequalities persist and disproportionately affect the Indigenous populations of both countries, extending into worse health outcomes for critically ill children (21). A research agenda aiming to improve long-term outcomes for critically ill children in the ANZ setting thus needs to be optimized given the unique context of the ANZ population, geography, and consumer-identified needs to avoid recruitment and follow-up bias by social determinants of health. While parent-based questionnaires are not the gold standard of child development assessment, they provide the ability to collect the more nuanced outcomes of development that global assessments on HRQoL or overall function may miss, at a relative cost saving to the research budget (33). With growing evidence of significant premorbid impairments, our current studies to measure HRQoL and neurodevelopment at baseline aim to accurately determine the impact of the PICU admission and interventions above that already experienced by the child. INTEGRATING AND PRIORITIZING CONSUMER ENGAGEMENT In response to the increasing involvement of consumers in research development, design, implementation, and dissemination, the PSG Consumer Working Group was established in 2018. The group aims to encourage and support consumer involvement in PICU research by helping researchers to engage meaningfully with consumers and to identify the priorities and needs of patients and their families involved in PICU research. This process also provides an opportunity to build on previous experiences and iteratively improve the approach to consumer engagement, as well as avoiding uncoordinated contacts with families at risk of "consumer fatigue." This project has moved from a process of consultation with consumers on documentation and study videos (26) to their inclusion in study design, study oversight as members of Steering Committees (8), contributors to the critical care quality outcomes set (25), and follow-up design and conduct. The NITRIC follow-up study (35) has worked in partnership with consumers and consumer advocacy groups in elements of study design including development of study documentation and contact processes as well as designing the final aspects of the study aiming to explore families' experience of participation in the study. THE FUTURE: HOW ANZICS PSG WILL SUSTAIN AND GROW Four pillars form the core strategy of the ANZICS PSG for the coming years. These have been chosen to ensure ongoing growth in capacity and capability to deliver pediatric critical care research. First, to address trial costs. We are committed to pursuing digitalization of trials, including registry-embedded RCTs, from screening toward outcome capture. However, as healthcare infrastructure in ANZ remains heterogeneous in terms of electronic health records, achieving higher granularity of data (such as temporal resolution, details of treatment, and on pre- and post-ICU care) will require systems to enable reliable data extraction and linkage with ANZPICR. Second, we need to establish the infrastructure for platform and adaptive trials (38). We have successfully piloted a pediatric sepsis trial with elements of platform trial design, the Resuscitation in Paediatric Sepsis Using Metabolic Resuscitation&#8212;A Randomized Controlled Pilot Study in the PICU (RESPOND PICU) (39). The study investigates early inotropes and metabolic resuscitation on overlapping populations, using a standard education package, and harmonized screening and data collection modules (8,9), and confirms the feasibility and benefit of this approach. These developments can underpin the framework to incorporate arising questions, for example, on artificial intelligence-decision support tools, in a more agile way than previously. Third, these designs will become even more relevant as we seek to develop and validate precision-medicine strategies for critically ill children. Seeking to decipher the heterogeneity of patients in terms of clinical behavior and underlying biological mechanisms (40), we have committed to biobanking in several trials which are currently undergoing multiomic analyses. This strategy places additional demands on recruiting sites, brings additional ethical challenges to families, and is reliant on additional funding and external partnerships. Finally, while ANZ has the advantage of relative homogeneity of clinical practice within a well-resourced context supported by solid research infrastructure, this setting is not generalizable to the global PICU populations and, increasingly, even such a network will not be able to power trials adequately to answer pressing questions. Thus, ANZICS PSG in recent years has sought to strengthen international partnerships. We are convinced that commitment toward a sustainable International PICU Trial Network is essential. We therefore look forward to contributing to the ongoing learning of the international PICU community as it delivers better outcomes for critically ill children and their families across the globe. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS We thank the attendees of the Foundation Meeting in 2003 and those who established the Australian and New Zealand Paediatric Intensive Care Registry.</description>
      <author>Kristen Gibbons, John Beca, Carmel Delzoppo, Simon Erickson, Marino Festa, Ben Gelbart, Debbie Long, Kate Masterson, Johnny Millar, Sainath Raman, Luregn J. Schlapbach, Warwick Butt</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1097/pcc.0000000000003653</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
